Hey guys welcome back.
All right so we've finally gotten to the partner Video Marketing section are talking about production.
Getting it done as I mentioned in the last lecture video production comes down to three important elements
that mother's accessories and other things you can add on but in order to make something work you have
to have something for each of these three of lightning video and audio oftentimes with video and audio
for a do as a Wii.
And this is actually I'm going to talk about what I believe is probably the most important one of those
three production elements lighting.
Now when you watch movies or TV shows you'll see that lighting is used to create moods and artistic
type shots.
There might be different colors shadows and all kinds of elaborate design that's created using lights
and first cinematic videos you want dramatic lighting that creates moods and adds to the general atmosphere
of the scene.
That's great.
And lucky for us people in the movies Hogar they have to make really complex lighting setups to reflect
every single mood or feeling the audience is supposed to be feeling.
But for us the simpleton marketer we really do not have to go into that much depth when it comes to
video marketing.
Nine times out of 10 you want to do lighting to do really just do two important things.
First you want to illuminate the subject of the video.
Oftentimes this is just lingo you might hear in the talent even if you're the only one on the camera.
They call you talent which would be in this case any people speaking more objects being displayed.
The biggest goal here is to make sure that people don't have any harsh shadows on their face.
And the other important thing is to make the subjects look as good as possible.
Well that subject means any colors will be nice and bright and all details will be sharp.
Now you'll be amazed at how what a tiny difference in kind of a core component of lighting happens when
you go from cheap lights small lights to big fancy and complex lights.
Now when I said You have sharp shadows on your face what exactly do you mean by sharp while a sharp
shadow would be something that goes from lit to dark very very quickly in a short span of space.
Typically what you want is to have more of this gray area right where the light is soft enough such
that when you see a shadow it's more of a transition over a longer period or longer space.
When you have a longer gradient like that it's called Sharp because our eyes can't actually notice like
hey there's a shadow right here just because we're not making movies here doesn't mean we should skimp
on our lighting.
We want our marketing videos and the subjects in them to look great.
So that's why things can be pretty important.
Now the best kind of lighting and pretty much anybody is ever going to video school tell you this is
natural lighting and that means from God's given the sun.
Now if we could light everything with natural daylight honestly everything would look pretty awesome.
But ironically that kind of light is one of the most difficult to use with video.
If you plan on shooting videos outside to take advantage of that natural sunlight.
Good luck sir.
There are too many potential problems and you're outside because you can't control anything.
Clouds when weather insects nearby traffic people in the background people just yelling things.
I'm in San Francisco.
It's a huge hassle to shoot outside.
It's also something that requires a little bit more skill.
Which is what I've found.
Usually I think I'm going to go outside and it's going to be bright and it's awesome and on to think
about anything I'm just going to shoot and really that's just a misnomer because you get used to seeing
people outside and you know keep thinking to yourself Wow this is terrible lighting on this person I'm
talking to.
But as soon as you whip out a camera you will notice that person looks like crap but that has to do
with just the sun.
It's directly above us.
It gives us a really awkward angle down like this so it might have shadows on my neck when I talk to
you when it's a different angles or I could be in the shadow or I can be turned around.
There's also a what we call the golden period which is about an hour and a half before the sun sets.
And the reason why people call it the golden period is because when the sun sets.
Right.
So like let's say we're here on earth and here is the sun.
This is noon.
But as the earth twists and the sun's about to go away the sun actually gets farther away from us.
And as light gets to us it goes through more of the ionosphere.
I know I'm getting a little too technical with you but what that does is it actually softens up the
light.
It actually spreads it out such that it doesn't make those sharp shadows as much.
Now unfortunately we haven't spent an hour or two an hour and half a day I guess it depends on where
you live but if you can shoot during that time that's often the easiest time to do it because you have
fewer shadows to fight anyway shooting outside.
Way too many variables so please stay inside as my suggestion were you have control over your video
environment if you organise someone who actually knows what they're doing then yeah you can go outside
but remember it's not just going to be you and a camera outside you need things like reflectors and
scrims and a bunch of things that we're not going to talk about and you don't need to know about right
now.
So instead move it inside because if you're inside you can control everything.
It's kind of like being in a laboratory.
Now a viewer inside you might think to yourself while I can just turn on the lights in my room or my
office and I think we're covered right.
Well not really why it's used in homes and offices are generally different from the types of lights
that you want to use to illuminate subjects and videos.
And if you're the driver that has their mind blown by really small mildly interesting things try this
on for size.
Look at the light bulb next to you if you're in a home or a house and ideally not like a hospital and
just look at the color of the light.
Now you think might think light is light what are you talking about.
Light has color.
But if you're in a home generally speaking it's kind of a warmer color.
It's going to look orange.
I don't know since I have students in 130 countries.
Do you guys have different colored light bulbs.
Take a photo and post it in the Q&amp;A.
I think that would be really interesting anyway.
Take a look at it and you might now notice that it's actually kind of yellowish orange.
Now the reason why it's yellowish orange is because companies that manufacture lights know that producing
light at a lower heat lower Kelvin scale produces this yellowish glow and then that's pleasing and relaxing
and it's supposed to be kind of homey the color temperature of a light bulb is measured in degrees Kelvin
which is what I just mentioned at the guys spaced out in science class.
We have Fahrenheit.
We have Celsius.
And then we have Kelvin.
Kelvin is just the absolute measurement of temperature.
Zero is called absolute zero where atoms don't even move.
And then it goes up.
Kind of I don't know actually I think it goes up infinitely.
Anyway the point here is that the lower the color temperature on the Kelvin scale the more yellowy it
is.
Why does light make a different color to our eyes.
I don't want to get into that.
And the higher the temperature is though will be more bright white.
Now here's the range of different color temperatures.
You should really care about many soft white palms as little call that you buy for your home or shine
around the lake.
Twenty five hundred to thirty two hundred Kelvin scale.
Then of course you have your brighter bulbs which may be called things like bright white or cool white
and those are a shine around 3500 to 40 200 and then when you get into the 5000 to sixty five hundred
K range you have bulbs that are bright bright white and sometimes these stores actually call them natural
white.
But the term you should probably refer to them as is daylight.
Now these daylight bulbs are the types of bulbs that you might see in like a hospital.
The light looks kind of lousy because it lacks that like warm the lower temperature bulb has and it
can be really sharp on the eyes.
If you swapped out your bulbs like above your head or to actually did and one of my apartments today
light bulbs all of a sudden you'd be like wow I can see so much clarity and anyone standing in it just
looks worse.
The plus side of this is that it provides more visual clarity because it's bright white.
There's no interference.
That's why for instance you might have lights on the outside of your house.
They like the motion detector lights or whatever.
Those are generally going to be in daylight.
We use this when we need to see detail to the human eye in these different bowls produce light but the
colors sometimes blend into each other depending on where the lights are positioned and how many you
might have.
But when you see these lights through a camera.
Now the difference is really obvious.
Now let's check out these three shots of the same person.
The first one is lit with regular household lamps and a cooler temperature light bulb.
Looks fine.
And the next one is lit with higher temp bulbs and gives off a bright white look.
You can see the difference nicer colors and nicer detail.
The reason why this might work is because the lights are probably in front of them as opposed to just
directly above them directly above them.
Yeah I can create really harsh shadows.
Now here's another set up where one lamp has a high temperature bulb.
Another has a regular household lamp.
Oh my God.
I want to throw up the two types of light are actually creating this really weird color effect.
So this kind of tells us two different things.
One don't mix the color temperature of your bulbs into where you place the bulbs and where you point
them makes a big difference.
If you just turn on the lights in your room coming from directly above or coming from say a lamp those
aren't really made for lighting subjects and thus the lighting is going to be quite poor.
And then the second thing is you can't mix the two.
So say you got some lights for filming and they're daylight's and you're trying to film in your living
room needs more light and you turn on your overhead lights which are lower temperature or warm and well
that's when you get that gross look.
Now the risk of confusing you too much and I'm sorry some people ask me will.
OK.
So daylight is for filming and warm white is for your house.
No that is actually not entirely true.
In fact most film crews up until recently shot in that lower Kelvin temperature soft white color and
they used what are called in incandescent bulbs to do that.
The technical term used in video is tungsten.
So if you're looking at lights you might see tungsten lights and those that make an orange color.
Lower temperature then you have the option of using daylight bulbs which come out of fluorescent light
bulb tubes or Ltds.
The point here though is that you have to pick one or the other.
You're either a Capulets or a monarch.
You can't be both either shoot only with daylight's or shoot them only with incandescent tungsten lights.
Mixing the two.
Bad news bears.
OK.
Now we have an idea of how color temperature works exactly what kind of lights are we looking for.
Well I could talk for hours about the intricacies of lighting but we're video marketing purposes.
Let me cover the types of bulbs that you'll want to consider.
Well the first one where the tungsten incandescent bulb.
Let's go over the pros and cons of that one because it's a warmer light more yellowish.
It's actually easier on the eyes.
So you're staring into a camera for a long period of time.
It's actually quite easier.
You don't fatigue as much.
Number two is that they're generally going to be cheaper for whatever reason incandescent bulbs just
in general are cheaper to work with.
Now the cons of it are pretty much that they're hotter.
Often times I'll call them hot lights because they'll really if you leave them on for too long they'll
really heat up the room you're in.
Now I know it's really counterintuitive because they run at a lower Kelvin temperature however has more
to do with the technology of the bulb it just emits too much heat.
Now the other bulbs are fluorescents which you often will see used in office buildings warehouses and
hospitals but for film purposes they're also used quite a bit.
The pros are really that they don't admit as much heat.
So if you're sitting in a room for a long period of time then they don't.
It's not going to cook you like an oven.
But then of course the con is that the bright white actually can be kind of straining on the eyes.
We use them too much.
Now you might ask if I use daylight or tungsten colored bulbs.
What happens when I film I have a tungsten bulb Volt the footage I make come off as orange ish or daylight
will be too bright actually.
Cameras have a thing called Color Correction.
And so what you're doing is just telling the camera which bulb you're using and it will automatically
adjust the temperature for us as it turns out our brains automatically do this for us whereas cameras
are almost too literal and they don't know how to translate the colors we have to tell them to.
All right so we have the tungsten incandescent bulbs hot easier to look at and pretty cheap.
Then we have the daylight bulbs a lot of variety to choose from.
Not as hot and kind of medium range price although they will kind of blind you if you have to stare
at them for too long and then the last thing I have which is still relatively new or Ltds Now Ellie
DS can come at a specific color temperature or you can buy kits that can change their color temperature
on the device itself.
That's not something that I think you'll ever really run into unless for some reason you were mixing
and matching video equipment with a buddy or something but it could be helpful in a pinch.
For instance if you were filming next to a window well the sun's temperature during the day is closest
to daylight and it's not to look anything at all like tungsten.
So if you use sheeting with tungsten being able to flip to daylight could be a lifesaver.
Now the best things about Ltds are one they're incredibly compact.
They're tiny there.
You don't waste a lot of effort in space storing them and carrying them around.
Number two is that they don't produce any heat whatsoever.
So you're not really going to sweat in front of them.
And number three is oftentimes they can be battery powered which is pretty cool.
The biggest thing with Ltds is portability and flexibility.
Now the cons are two things.
One price they can be extraordinarily expensive and even for the most basic stuff it's really getting
more expensive than your daylight's and your Tunks and bolts.
And then secondly kind of related to price is that if you want more affordable LSD's you can get them
how ever they have some issues with color temperature.
Oftentimes you can get Ltd's if they're too cheap with the bulbs don't actually match each other and
color temperature and Darkon kind of slow can kind of degrade the quality of your video.
So that being said try to avoid all cheap Ltd's because they in general look awful.
Don't buy that your hardware store chances are those are not video grade lights.
OK so right there you've got your common light bulb types.
We've got the incandescent also known as tungsten fluorescent which you can also call daylight.
And then Ltd's and one's understanding of color temperatures you'll know which types you might want
for your video but there's another way to measure these lights beyond color temperature that can help
you choose which one you want.
Now the other way to evaluate bulbs is called CROI or color rendering index.
Now the C-Drive of bulb measures is the ability to basically produce accurate color.
This is the term that people use constantly with Ltd's to determine how good they are.
All you need to know is that our eyes are rated from 0 to 100 in 95 percent of situations your tungsten
and efflorescence are going to have high enough CROI that you have to worry about it.
But with Ltd's highboy you can get some low ones pretty much anything over 90 is going to be good enough
and it's not going to create any issues with our camera or when you try to edit this later.
So we have color temperatures.
We have different types of bulb.
We have different price points different portability.
And then finally we have different see our eyes.