All right guys welcome back to the course.
We're just starting our SC watchers here and before we dive into the next steps you take to start creating
and paying for ads online.
Let's use this lecture to cover some of the groundwork and the basics that you should know about SVM
topics things like how PPC words work.
And yes we don't know what PPC is and we're going explain that.
Now first off you might hear people refer to search engine marketing or SVM as paid search and it's
just a way to help distinguish it from organic search results.
Now remember that organic search results are the main part of those as the rpms or search engine result
pages.
But at the top and the sides of those SERPs you see ads and those are where Paid Search Ads will show
up now on google those ads come from Google Adwords system being in Yahoo.
Also have their own advertising system they're almost identical.
So if you want to be seen on their search engine pages then really you just take the exact same thing
you did for Google Adwords and then you go do it for bing.
It's just just SEAGE search being advertising.
One thing you might notice though on Google when you search and you see organic results and that ads
ads are very clearly marked.
They're in a different color.
They have different background color or sometimes even just say add right above them whereas with Yahoo
and Bing these the same marketing platform.
Now sometimes you can't tell which ones and at.
And Yahoo.
I'm not sure 100 percent they still have this but for the longest time they had paid placement.
So you could do is pay and have your thing show up as organic and it would even look like an ad but
then every time someone clicked it they would get paid.
It was like like a shadow and you can understand why Yahoo.
Probably not so popular if you're constantly feeding in search results that are just paying you the
most money.
People don't want to use a search engine that's going to give them the highest bidder.
They want the most accurate search results.
So you know one of the big types of paid search advertising out there is known as pay per click or PPC
for short.
Now the name of this ad type really is accurate.
By the way you pay when the user clicks and the amount you pay is based on a bidding system so you never
pay more than what you want to.
It's a little tricky.
So let me describe how it works in a little more detail.
So first you decide what you want to advertise.
What is it you're trying to sell or get people to check out on your Web site.
Are you driving them to a landing page.
OK.
A landing page you guys for God is just a one web page web site that is very focused on one singular
thing.
The most commonly used with ads so when you click there and you go to a page that's focused it's not
distracting it doesn't just throw you on a home page and then you know you have to figure out where
you're trying to find the product is being advertised.
Delaney page might ask for them to buy something.
It could ask them to sign up for something.
You could ask them to download an app download an ebook whatever.
So if you're trying to do that well then you have to take that in consideration with your advertising
efforts.
Or let's say are you trying to raise awareness of a new product that you're launching.
Well with an ad you generally don't just lead people to your home page.
Right you're going to have to bring them to a landing page.
So next you should decide which keywords to advertise for to reach your audience for your ad to work
which se R.P. would make sense for your ad to appear on.
When people Google phrases or terms or questions you want your ad to show up for the right one so there's
an obvious connect with their needs.
For example if you're trying to advertise your web hosting services it makes sense to advertise for
someone looking for web hosting solutions.
So you'd select keywords related to web hosting though you and a thousand other companies will be competing
for that same audience.
Competitive keywords are the ones that people bid the most for since the biggest audience is seeing
ads on those the R.P. pages being able to select specific keyword phrases with high relevance for your
audience.
But less competition will give you a chance to actually win bids for ad placement and hopefully not
pay an exorbitant amount of money for them.
Now as far as search ad placement goes you've probably seen ads on these as the RPF before like let's
say on this page for Wordpress hosting.
Now the best placement is at the top where a few links might appear.
And then at the bottom of the page below the first group of organic search results.
Now by the way Google stop placing search ads on the side of the page for most SEPs saving space for
related information and links.
Now as you're watching this now it could actually change.
Google seems to reorganize this quite a bit.
So how do you figure out what you want to advertise and which keywords you want to advertise for.
You need to set a budget and start bidding on your keywords through outwards.
Google gives you different options on how to control your advertising.
You can tell them how much you want to spend each time someone clicks your ad how much you want to spend
and total.
And when you want to start and stop advertising none the question becomes how can you get that sweet
top paid position so that your ad appears first.
Well Google ranks paid ads based on how much you bid.
But also here's the kicker.
The quality of the ad and the format of your ad especially the relevancy to the keyword.
Yes you heard write it's not completely about how much you pay.
That's what Yahoo and being do.
Google on the other hand wants to match your users with ads that actually appeal to them and help them
with their search.
Now that ad placement or what it's called is ad rank with capital are like capital a capital R is determined
by something that we call a quality score.
That's a very important concept.
Now the quality scores a number of Google assigns to each and based on how much you bid and the quality
of the ad now the quality is based on a bunch of factors which go beyond your ad it can be affected
by the quality of your landing page.
It could be your current click through rate even your past ad words campaigns now click through rate
or CD-R is the rate at which people click on your ad when they see it the better and more relevant it
looks to them Well probably the higher your rate should be.
So if you show your ad to a hundred people and five people click it you're click through rate is 5 percent.
So keep in mind that the average C-T are just generally OK.
This is just a big blank.
It's not going to.
It's not specific to any industry but generally the big blank it would say that 2 percent is the average
click rate for a search engine and that means on average 50 people will see the ad before one person
clicks on it.
And I mentioned something about the format of the ad to deny.
Well as don't just come as text although on those SEPs they are only text.
But as you're planning your and think about your audience and figure out how to get the people to click
How do you specifically entice that audience to be interested in what you're talking about.
You should be aware of other ad formats as well that you might want to use depending on what you're
selling.
It could be the case that Texas doesn't work very well for you.
So it might be the case you try it on that other stuff.
Here's some examples of the other things you can use through onwards.
We have display ads which are basically just banner ads that have been around for forever.
Basically they can be images or rich media that includes some animations or interactive features of
some kind of Google even created a gallery of rich media ads you can browse to see how they would appear
on certain pages and platforms.
People do some really cool and crazy stuff with display ads now.
So keep in mind there's decently high bar but you know it's just a it's just like a blue box that you
have to design so it's not too expensive or too time consuming.
Mobile Ads are ads that get displayed only on mobile devices.
Now these ads need to be formatted for a smaller screen but they can be really useful if you want to
reach customers when they're out shopping.
Say keeping in mind mobile ads get higher click through rates but their error rate is incredibly high
because it's a tiny screen and people have fat phones so a lot of times they accidentally click what
you're trying to advertise.
So yeah also people who are on mobile are just less likely to buy something on their phone.
So you have to kind of keep that in mind as well.
And the last thing our app ads which are ads you create specifically to promote ads on mobile devices.
Now instead of driving people to a landing page you can push them right to the download page and your
iOS or Google Play store instead.
So not a web page.
It's basically the same thing as a mobile ad but you just send them right to the iOS or Google Play
store.
Now makes a lot of sense if people are searching on their phone obviously they want to go look at a
page then reconvince to download it then click through and then find it and download.
Once you do get your ad placed on the search engine result pages SEPs not only will you begin to see
your click through rate but you'll get a cost per click again which is where you will from now on we'll
refer to a CPC member.
CBC is how much you end up paying every time someone clicks your ad that cost is going to be determined
by how competitive the search term is how much you bid.
And then also your quality score in general if Google says you've a really high quality score they really
like your ad they think it's super relevant it's not spamming they like your landing page.
You'll actually pay significantly less.
You can also evaluate your app based on how many conversions you get.
Now you're probably familiar with conversions at this point in the course but just to be clear every
time someone completes a specific task you've outlined for yourself as a goal like making a sale or
getting a registration through a landing page.
Well that's called a conversion and it's something you can track in the Edwards system.
Pretty straightforward.
So the process we discussed here planning your ads picking your keywords and audience and then budgeting
and bidding.
Those are the steps you'd follow for pay per click advertising and our lectures to come we'll talk about
how to place bids in the ADD words system and how to make your ads the best they can.
But I was wondering what about like CPM or CPA.
You forgot to CPM cost per.
And that's the French word for a thousand like me I can't pronounce it but it means for every thousand
people do you pay a certain amount so every thousand people who just see it has nothing to do with clicking
on it you pay a certain amount.
Google still offers this and you can do it but it's just really inefficient and it's not really something
you want to do especially at the beginning.
It's very very rare cases where doing CPM is make more sense.
CPA means cost per action.
That basically means you pay once someone converts.
Google doesn't play that game.
Buger only going to CPA is if you have some direct affiliate relationship with someone selling a product
or some really nice exclusive advertising platform.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.