Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Remember the 19 things we talked about last lecture?
Well, we only listed them off rather mysteriously.
So, in this lecture, called "The 19 channels explained,"
it's actually two lectures, or as I like to call
it, "How many can Evan explain before getting tired?"
Probably 10.
Why only 10?
Well, because 10 of these 19 are the main ones,
and coincidentally, it's what we cover in the course.
The other nine stragglers are kind of weird,
too specific I think to be helpful in this course.
So at the end of this lecture you'll know the basics
of the 10 main ways people get customers.
I would imagine you know some or most of these,
but please just suck it up or skip the lecture.
The other nine we'll include as a resource
either in this lecture or the next.
Seriously, they're kind of weird.
We're talking about things like giant posters on
the highway, used primarily to guilt you into going
to church or which exit to take to blow
your life savings on slot machines.
Also known as billboards.
Was that only a thing in America?
If you are disappointed that we are not
covering billboards, I apologize.
Also, good luck with that, you billboard-preneur.
All right, let's get this started.
Number one, SEO. SEO, for the non-initiated,
means search engine optimization.
People search for things online and they
do so through places like Google
and... really it's just Google.
If you use Bing, then your family needs
to have an intervention, because... that's nice,
I also bet you're still a proud user of Hotmail.
When you search for things, Google will
present you with a list of relevant results.
A company that pursues an SEO strategy is going to
focus on finding ways of changing the language on
their site or planning certain keywords, titles, tags,
and pages in a way that gets the most exposure in
those search results.
These strategies generally consist of, one, tweaking
your page, two, getting people to link to you, and three,
researching keywords before
you actually create the pages.
Yes, I know, recently it's changed quite a bit.
We'll cover that.
How many searches are there on Google in a day?
3.5 billion, with a B. That is 40,000 searches every second.
SEO, if done well, can be an absolute monster of a channel.
#crushit.
Number two, SEM.
Following up on that last one, when people search
on Google, they will be shown ads mixed in with the
search results they get.
With Google, it's pretty obvious what is
an ad and what is not an ad, and with Bing,
well, I'm kind of assuming it's all an ad, because
Bing is terrible. SEM goes something like this.
SEO can take forever,
so why not skip the line instead?
Companies pay for these ads in the hopes that
you'll click them and get diverted to their page.
That's why we call it search engine marketing,
SEM. The way that this works is that companies will
place bids for placement in key positions they want,
and when someone clicks on that ad, then they pay.
If you want to be a terrible person, go search
mesothelioma and then click an ad. You just charged
a law firm about $140. Seriously, just for that one click.
Anyway, hence the acronyms for cost per click,
CPA or cost per action, and CPM, cost per mille.
Just kidding, literally no one on earth knows what
the M in CPM stands for. Pro tip: the order that the
ads are displayed in correlates to,
number one, how much they bid,
and number two, how well
their website relates to your search.
We will cover this in the course.
Number three, content marketing.
This is when a business creates free or very low priced
content and distributes it online with the idea
that they can, one, pitch their business somewhere
inside of that content, or two, increase their exposure
and attract people to check out the rest of their site.
Content is a term developed by the government
to drive you crazy by its sheer lack of specificity.
Your blog - content, your YouTube comment - content,
your cat learns how to type - content. And it is said so
often that some - mostly me - say
that it is the vegan of the internet.
Please stop talking about it.
The number one thing people do this through,
can you guess it?
Blogs. Blogs, spelled B-L-A-G-S and actually pronounced blags,
are essentially free content that is shared with the public,
and in return the business gets email addresses,
or leads, or just traffic to their site. Number four, PR.
When I say PR, I just mean public relations.
It's what we mean when we say "get press."
It means media outlets primarily, but you can extend it
to larger blocks and sites that have a following.
Primarily, these are topical,
"Your company did something," but there are also entire
strategies built around getting more mentions and
how to keep media outlets talking about you forever.
This is probably the closest
you'll ever get to being famous.
Number five, social and display advertising.
Remember when we talked about search engine
marketing, it was like, I don't know, 3 minutes ago?
Well, if you're interested
in search, you'll probably be interested in social.
Social advertising is when you take out ads on sites
like Facebook or Twitter.
The advantage of this is that you can base
your ads instead of on what they search for,
you can base it on what they like or their demographics.
Are you a 24-year old white male in a college town?
Well, if I were working for Chipotle,
I would be all up in your news feed.
You can even do creepy things like target by behaviors.
Facebook, for instance, can let you advertise to people
who are looking to move from their home soon.
Yes, I know, it's incredibly weird.
Now, the second part of this is display advertising, which
basically amounts to things like banner ads and Google AdSense.
These are big blocks of images
or text that you see on your page
trying to get you to click them.
Do they work anymore?
Maybe. I lump these two together why?
Well, because in both cases you are in fact displaying
some sort of an image, unlike Google, with obviously
the exception being Google AdSense.
All right, are you out of breath? Because I sure am.
Next lecture, we'll wrap up the remaining five.
See you then.