Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
So we're wrapping up our group of lectures on how to figure out what to write as part of our content
strategy series.
We just talked about how to organize ideas different places to find ideas of how to rank those ideas
and ranking ideas is important because well we'll know which ideas to start on.
Well there's another way to identify the better ideas that you've got.
And that's to test them and before you actually try them.
Now what exactly are we talking about.
Basically instead of spending a lot of time creating say 20 pieces of content based on 20 ideas you
have.
What do you get instead just validate those ideas upfront Yeah there's no Idea validator app out there.
No one's created that yet but there are real people out there that you know and you can actually use
to get some feedback.
At least I assume you know some real people right.
I hope I'm not the only person you know because I've got bad news for you.
I'm actually just character on a TV show and I'm not real.
I mean it's
not anything anyway.
What if you could run your ideas by people who might be interested in them and then you could find out
that out of those 20 ideas maybe only 10 of them are in real demand.
And the other men not so much.
That means you could save half of your time and produce a bunch of blog posts and other materials that
are more likely to succeed.
Great.
Now I'm all about saving time and succeeding when I make stuff and I hope you are too.
Because in this lecture I'm going to go over some of the ways to test your ideas so whatever you produce
has a better chance of succeeding.
Now the first way to test your ideas is to email people you know and just simply ask for their opinion.
So this is where those real people I mentioned before come in handy.
First you're going to need some people who have similar interest as your audience.
That way they can truly represent a sample of who you're trying to reach.
Otherwise if the e-mail your roommate for instance which is weird because he's right there in the same
room with you or your mom or a friend and if they don't really have the same interests as your audience
this test really isn't going to work and it's actually going to give you a lot of false signals as an
example if you're a Web consultant for small business owners then you might need some small business
owners to e-mail.
So who is your audience.
You know maybe 10 people who have similar interests as your audience is a great place to start but you
don't want to just copy and paste your entire list and drop it in email and say What do you like about
it.
I actually put some thought into this.
Maybe you choose the 10 ideas you personally like best and then ask each person of these 10 ideas please
choose that three you'd want to read the most or maybe the top five or you could ask choose any of the
ones you'd like to read about.
I don't know.
It's your choice what you're hoping to get back from this is some kind of consensus or trend like maybe
two or three of these ideas are most popular.
Then you've got some obvious winners.
But if interest seems pretty evenly spaced across the 10 all then maybe they'll get a bunch of votes
and that's the case then maybe all 10 of your ideas are decent.
If you want to take this e-mail testing tactic a step further you can email those trusted people with
a link to a survey instead that has the ideas in it.
For example you can go to Google form Google or Tom slash forms of Google Docs and list out your 10
ideas.
Ask them to check off what they liked the most.
And then you don't have to actually collect any of the votes.
The survey form does all that for you.
It's a lot actually easier and it's quite a bit cleaner either right.
When the surveys done you've got new ideas that have been vetted by real people.
You can have more confidence in the idea that scored well and you can expect more interest in them when
you publish them for real.
Now another way to test your content ideas for you make them is by sharing them on things like Twitter
and Facebook.
Now I saw this pretty simple experiment where a blogger was trying to figure out which topics his blog's
audience wanted to read about.
But instead of e-mailing blog posts ideas like we just covered he found blog posts that were similar
to his ideas from other sites.
Following suit.
One of these ideas was let's say to write about all the free alternatives of Photoshop.
He would go out and find a blog post someone else wrote about a very similar topic.
Got it.
Then what he would do is he shared a link to that blog post on his Twitter.
The reason he shared someone else's post instead of burning his own was just to see if the share Got
any engagement.
People liked it or shared it or reply to it.
That meant that there was an audience for that type of content.
It means that blog post idea is actually a good one but have nobody reacted or engaged with the share
that the audience probably isn't interested.
And now you can probably cross that idea off your list.
It saves you the trouble of writing it and now you can concentrate on the ideas that have a better chance
of succeeding.
All right so try sharing links to content related to your ideas.
Try doing it on Facebook and Twitter it's great because you don't have to write anything just borrow
someone else's content.
You never really know what your audience will react to.
So it's worth a shot.
Now there's one more experiment I want to tell you about that you can use to test your ideas and that
is a little more elaborate but it's Facebook ads.
You can specifically use Facebook ads for AB testing.
Now Will email and Twitter can be decent testing grounds testing on Facebook and be really valuable
because something like 70 percent of shares in General happen on Facebook.
What I mean is when someone writes a blog and they have a thousand shares generally speaking 700 of
those were on Facebook.
So that's where most of this stuff happens.
That makes Facebook a great place to figure out which ideas work since it's going to end up on Facebook
anyway.
So how do we.
AB tests or ideas on Facebook.
Well one thing what you can do is you can run Facebook ads on your headlines before you actually write
them.
OK so the process generally goes like this.
It does kick some a little bit of a Claytons of Facebook ads but you can learn it in ten minutes or
you can skip ahead to the next section or we go over the M and social ads and check it out there.
The process generally goes like this.
OK.
First look at your list of ideas and create a headline for let's say three or four of your favorite
ones next.
Start up a Facebook add test based on a previously established target market.
Basically just just try to target the best demographics Geographic and socio graphics of your identified
audio as you can then what you do is you run the ad and put the headline as the title of the ad and
pick a generic image that fits all of them.
OK.
So it's one ad that has four or five or three or four whatever you selected alternate headlines all
using the same generic image.
It's not five separate ads it's just one and with multiple copy and in face looks very easy to just
set different and copy.
Then the last thing you do is have the added lead back to either landing page or your blog home page.
That part's not actually really that important.
Now the point is here.
When you run these ads you're not actually looking to see necessarily how much it cost to get your clicks
or how much visibility you get.
We are actually trying to see is the click through rate based on the headline once you run it you can
very easily with a $10 you can show it to four or five hundred people four or five hundred CPM.
And then you can see which one has the highest percentage of people looking at it and clicking it.
Now I generally suggest you only do three or four headlines at a time and you do this otherwise you
have to spend more money.
Right.
Because 400 views spread over 10 headlines is probably not enough to be statistically significant whereas
three or four it actually is.
Once you have a clear winner out of that group with three or four or four or five then you now have
an idea that's probably worth running about or at least putting your efforts towards first.
And now in fact if you like that Facebook Abts idea you can actually take it a couple steps further
and then use the same testing's system to come up with the best headline for an idea or even the best
angle or the best image.
Really all you can do is once you find out that say number.
Idea number two is your winner.
You could rerun that test but now instead of three different headlines for three different articles
you do three different headlines for the same idea just sit down and try to think of three different
headlines you could think figure out which headline attracts the most clicks and then do the same thing
with images.
Then when you do the image you only change the image and you keep the same headline.
Again each Facebook test costs money but depending on your budget and the size of your business and
your audience it could really be an option worth considering and you don't have to spend that much just
to get people to look at it because you're not paying for clicks necessarily.
So there you go.
You can e-mail people you know you can share similar content on Facebook on Twitter and see how people
react or you can use a more elaborate Facebook AB testing system and then you know use three different
testing options to see which one is the champion.
And you whittle it down to figure out what's the best headline What's the best image.
And that way you pretty much just leave it up to your audience to pick the topic for you.
All right guys.
That's it.
There's three different ways you can test it before you try it.
So in the next lecture.