Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So I just talked about all the reasons you should create canonical long form content so if you're here
that means you want to see how it's actually done.
So let's get actually down to it when you're thinking about putting together a long form piece.
You have some choices to make while five choices to make in fact.
First off what is your goal with the piece.
What do you want to accomplish with a big piece of content to it more leads you know lots of downloads
more registrations your newsletter or for a web in our what is it.
This goal needs to be crystal clear and actually measurable.
For example I want 1000 new sign ups is much clearer than I want to get more subscribers.
And whatever you create should support this goal.
Secondly what is your topic going to be what's this long form piece going to be about.
Just like any blog post you want to make sure whatever you choose is relevant to your audience's needs
and interests.
But if it's a long form piece it'll need to be something broad enough you can devote a big chunk of
attention to.
You're probably not going to do a long form definitive guide to signing up for Facebook but you might
do one for how to create an e-mail marketing strategy for a band you might do it for an expert's guide
to launching a successful Kickstarter or even how to install a dishwasher.
I could be an ultimate God.
There needs to be enough depth to the subject so that a long form piece would make sense.
Third what is the format going to be and by formant I do mean is this an ultimate guide or a definitive
guide type of document or something different.
But I also mean how will it be published.
Is it one big blog post.
A section of pages on your site.
A mini site that a PTF download or some combination of those in some cases you might see this as a special
super long blog post and that's perfectly fine if it makes sense on your blog.
That's great but maybe you're putting together something that you anticipate will be searched for and
viewed many times like reference material long form walkthrough guides of how to use your photo editing
app might make more sense and a Resources section of your website rather than a blog post.
You want to ensure people find the peace plan to put it somewhere special.
The same goes if you want to be able to download it.
You'll need to produce a PDA for some kind of downloadable document that looks good reads well and just
be OK with the fact that some people might actually share it with their friends.
Print it out or I don't know post it on some file sharing Web site.
And of course that reminds me.
Number four which is what kind of access will this piece have.
You need to decide whether or not this will be available to anyone and everyone.
Or will you get it requiring an e-mail address or other fields of data to download it.
It's relatively easy to add an email gate onto your blog post.
You can also do it with videos as well so you can't launch into the type in your email address.
Either option is perfectly reasonable.
You just need to decide this based on your goal.
Are you creating this Ultimate Guide to collect more leads.
Well then you probably want to get it.
Are you trying to get as many people to view this content as possible.
Then don't gate it.
Consider your goal and then just make your decision based on that.
And the last of choice that we need to go through is that you need to decide when you're creating a
long form piece.
How are you going to make this thing bigger content projects sometimes require the help of others.
Maybe you're an artist or designer.
Another writer to help you research it an expert answer your questions are some let's say current customers
to help you test it out.
Consider the resources you'll need to create this long form piece and whatever cost or time constraints
you might run into.
So just to recap there's five important questions you should answer.
What's your goal.
What's your topic.
What's the format going to be what kind of access will this piece have and how are you going to make
it.
What's considered a quick example so you can better understand these questions.
Let's say that you provide consulting services for small businesses and specifically their email strategies.
Now this could be individuals with newsletters they're trying to create or grow or it could be actual
companies with clients and customers they're trying to reach through sales and marketing e-mails.
You know a lot about this topic and all the tools out there.
And while you have some clients you decided you like to put yourself out there as an expert.
Maybe someday speak at some events write a book someday.
But before you do all of that you want to create some big content and get yourself noticed in the industry.
OK so what's your goal.
You want people to share your content and you hope that will lead to more opportunities as your profile
grows.
But let's be more specific.
Let's say you want to get five hundred shares across social media platforms.
You can measure that.
And for example that will actually work.
Then what is our theoretical topic going to be.
Well you've got one in mind already so let's just roll with that.
The Ultimate Guide to email marketing for small businesses now it's pretty clear what this is going
to be about it's an ultimate guide and it needs to be comprehensive.
So we can expect to cover a lot of ground here.
We have to cover things like how to get started.
We have to do things like tools and platforms to use reprogrammed to judge which ones we like better
how to design emails how to write them probably how to build lists so on well you have all of this experience
presumably if you're writing the guy in on it and you know where to look online for more information
if necessary so you probably shouldn't be worried unless you're a fraud and you're writing about something
you have no idea what you're doing.
So on to the next question What's the format going to be.
Well so the goal here is five hundred shares then this needs to be shareable and maybe you don't want
a PTF because it's a hassle to create and that's perfectly fine.
You're probably leaning towards having all of this live on like a resource page on your site because
you like the idea of people coming to your site and maybe contacting you after they see it maybe if
you and social sharing buttons to the page then you can get shares that way and you can certainly support
your goal is specifically getting shares.
So then what kind of access will you put on this content.
Let's say you decide on free open access free love for everybody.
So no gating of the content you want as little friction as possible when people arrive.
You want them to jump right into this guy.
Now that's up to you.
But certainly the fewer barriers in the way the more people will check it out.
No gating means you may not know who visits and maybe competitors will see it.
I don't know.
Who cares but if you're concentrating on Cher's new gaiting will obviously improve your chances.
People don't like to share stuff that their friends go to you know like oh they're just bait for my
email address.
And then finally how are you going to put this together.
We already establish that you have the knowledge and experience right.
Most if not all of it you might have to refer to some online sources for the latest info and a few things
you know you can do it all yourself.
Now it comes to whatever long form content project you create your answers to these questions could
be completely different.
But it's important to answer them all.
As you've seen in the previous example the goal can help you figure out the format and access and certainly
the topic will help you determine if you can actually do it yourself or if you need help.
So now that we have our examples here let's keep walking through this and go through the first few steps
and how you would at least put something like this together.
Now I obviously can't write it for you but I can kind of walk you through the creative process of how
you go by section by section.
So for a long form canonical piece of content you might be tempted to just open up a new Google doc
or something else and just start typing.
However comfortable you feel with this topic you've chosen by all means get to work on it.
But one thing I suggest is before you dive in you need to check first at what already exists out there
and then use those as kind of a baseline to make your god your guide has to be better and more comprehensive
than what's already out there.
One of the first questions you ask yourself at this point is has anyone else created this exact same
piece of content.
I want to make.
If the answer is yes it doesn't mean you should hit the brakes on the idea what this search will do
though is help you see how many people have tried to create the same content before.
You'll see if they were successful or not.
And what's even cooler is that you'll see how you can outdo them.
You just look at it and just see how you can do it better and ask yourself that can I do this better.
All right so let's fire up the world's only search engine Google and search for e-mail marketing small
business guide.
OK so what I search for this is what I see I see shopkeep dot com has one on their landing page.
I can see a brief outline of it.
Why email marketing matters.
How to Choose the right email marketing tool for your business.
The anatomy of a great e-mail is a lot of the things that we covered before and you're theoretically
choosing our topics how to measure the success of your emails and then if nothing else do this and this
is like the.
Email marketing.
The kind of catering to people who just want a crash course a shorter version to get in and out more
quickly.
Now it seems interesting and it's something I want to check out.
So while their guy is gated and they ask for your name and email and they also asked me if I was looking
for a point of sale.
Thank you just the guide please.
So I submit that and I get an email from them with a link to the guide.
I open it download it and I can save it for later.
There's you guys out there who don't want to give out your e-mail address.
There's some pretty cool apps out there.
One's called throttle.
You sign up and then it ends up happening as you give a good fake auto generated e-mail to all of these
newsletters.
It still makes it to your e-mail inbox.
But then you can log in to throttle and just turn them off when you want to stop getting stuff from
that sender.
OK so the next search result I see is from the U.S. Small Business Administration.
Well this is actually a government Web site so honestly my expectations are pretty low here.
A lot of times government websites are pretty badly outdated badly designed and it's really hard to
find anything on them.
But I'm going to click through anyway just to be sure and well yeah you can see it's one page about
email marketing with some questions not exactly what I was looking for.
OK we're going to hightail it backwards back to the search results.
OK.
And I'm actually going to stick with the results that have guide in the title.
I want something comprehensive.
So I'm skipping this overblow one because it just looks like a blog post not an actual guide.
I don't know why they call it a guide.
So let's click on this hatchback one.
It's called the small business owners guy e-mail marketing introduction or because I'm scanning this
to see what kind of structure this has if I can spot what they're offering here I mean it looks like
a post is an introduction and offer some decent advice small businesses should keep in mind.
Make your copywriting count.
Don't be passed things like that.
And then here at the bottom the rest of the series covers different kinds of e-mails.
So we have introductory lead nurturing upswell referral and Windebank.
OK.
So that looks like some helpful content but it's not how I would have set up an Ultimate Guide.
However this kind of content might be great for a section in the guide about email design or messaging
so I'll certainly keep a link to this.
Let's go back to the Google results and keep looking.
OK.
Further down I see a source that I know should have good content.
I'm going to click through here and what we find is a guide for small business on how to use MailChimp.
That's not bad.
Yes this will have a lot of MailChimp specific info but also I'm saying a general outline that can be
helpful as well.
So let's go back to Google and let's look at one more.
OK here's a result I see from thrive high culture email marketing for small business owners exactly
what we're looking for.
We'll click that one and give it a look right.
It says right here in this ebook you'll learn how to develop your you know marketing program and it
includes e-mail newsletter basics types of e-mail newsletters advanced email marketing techniques how
to measure email success and more.
I might be tempted to download this but this form asks for a lot of information at once.
Name Company email and phone and those are all required so I'm just going to say no on that one.
It's really not that important to me.
I can probably find the content I want elsewhere.
Well once you've researched what's out there already you can get an idea whether or not anyone else
has covered your topic the way you want to or has thoroughly as you want to.
So far I've found a few different long form pieces where each one has a different focus.
Shopkeeper is more general hatchbacks book focuses on types of emails you'd send like in an actual sequence
and male chimps kind of focuses on while MailChimp for example I like we should probably start with
that shopkeep example and use that as a guide to make our guide.
Now it doesn't mean anything is set in stone.
We just want to get something started.
We can build off of that.
So let's open up that document and tear through it.
Well we can see it's like a 20 page PTF and we've got those five second section as we mentioned before.
Why email marketing.
How to choose the right email marketing tool for your business.
We have the anatomy of a great e-mail how to measure the success of your emails.
If nothing else do this to me.
Cheater's guide to email marketing essentially without all the fancy words you could boil their outline
down to the benefits of email.
The tools you could use.
How to Design emails how to measure emails and tips to help you get started.
OK I like that outline and it's something I can start with I might decide I want to add more sections
later.
Like something about building email lists or how that specifically works or maybe you'd like a quick
thing on AB testing emails outside of the design discussion.
Whatever I decide to do though I can get inspiration from other sources I've already created and use
their examples to help me decide what to do and what to cover from here perhaps what I do is I open
up a brand new Google doc copy in that basic version of a shopkeep outline and then start fleshing out
with details from there.
Then as I keep developing it I can look at those other sources I found.
Or do new more targeted searches like you know if I wanted to develop a section about email design I
could search for email marketing design or specifically email design small business see what comes up.
Ultimately what you want to do is make content in your own.
No matter what topic you are covering.
It's certainly been covered by someone else before but who cares.
Bring your own angle and bring your own experience to it.
If you're down with creating a long form content piece about whatever anything then you clearly have
something you want to talk about.
Keep that core message in mind when they are trying to make email marketing easier for small businesses
or dishwasher instillation easier for do it yourselfers.
Make sure that message gets delivered in the long form piece you make.
Now remember you want it to be canonical meaning.
Final word final word when it comes to this topic so make sure it is the final word.
It's better than all the guides are using as reference.
Got it.
OK great.
Well then my final word is going to be peace.
I'll see you in the next lecture.