Is when I come back to the course so for the last couple years we've been discussing landing pages.
Well so far we know what they're use for and well we just checked out a bunch of really good examples
and the immediately previous lecture.
Now this one I'd like to share some of the important do's and don'ts for landing pages.
Things you should always do or include and then things you should really always avoid because they will
secretly kill whatever page you're making.
Now let's start with five things you should always do on a landing page.
Now reverse tip is to use your headline to highlight the value of your offer.
Sounds a little Obviously repackaged for you.
Use your headline to immediately tell them what they're going to get from the actual magnet that you're
offering.
If you delay telling them what the value is to something else the subtitle or description you'll get
a lot of people who just bounce.
The first thing people read is the headline and a lot of them will only read the headline.
So convincer visitors whatever you're selling here is worth it with a clear statement of value.
What will you do for them if they say complete the form what download will they get.
And why is the thing you're giving them so special.
Or what knowledge will they get from signing up for this event that you're promoting.
People need to know what's in it for them as soon as possible so use the headline to make it as clear
as possible.
For example buffer offers a 25 day email course it's called the 25 experts social media growth strategies
and they use a headline on a landing page that is very short and sweet.
Now the title is clear the tone of the message is friendly and the form is super short.
It's a solid landing page.
Look at that headline.
Now here's another landing page.
Tip provide all of the details needed to make a decision as good as your headline might be.
Don't rely on that do all the convincing for you.
If you're providing something to download include a description of the piece with specifics on what's
included.
Is there a helpful checklist a set of steps to accomplish something or a template they could use to
create something.
Make the value obvious.
Now notice I'm not giving you a word count or limit here.
When I say provide all the details certain pieces like e-books or email courses might require a lot
to convince people so give them as much as you can.
Here's the thing.
If you give them a lot of stuff it's not going to deter anyone.
People will read until they are satisfied and then they'll sign up so the more information you give
the longer you can continue to convince some of the holdouts founder.
Magazine and founder dot com it's like founder without an e.
Lavern ebook on how to get your first 10000 Instagram followers by breaking down all the info you'll
get in the book and easy to read.
Bullets leave it tell you they tried these tips themselves and it worked better than expected.
This is a pretty decent example of explaining as much as you can about why you should do this.
Now on the other hand if you want people to register for let's say a weapon are all they need to know
all the basics as well as like the date and the time how long it's going to last.
How they can attend just from a technological standpoint and what it's going to be all about.
Also who's in it.
Availability is another consideration here so be sure to include the web in our details as well.
All right here's my third tip for things you absolutely need to do.
Make your call to action obvious and pretty much on an voidable if you guys came for my MVP course.
Remember we talked about B-F BS and that sounds for big effing Borton.
It basically means that your call to action should be large.
I mean when you look at the page be one of the most obvious things on it that Google has some standard
for their buttons where if you stand six feet away from the screen and you look at it.
If you can still see the button you're good you can't it's not big enough.
So once you've convinced your visitor with your dynamite headline a convincing copy what do you want
to do on your landing page.
A download a white paper.
Register for webinars whatever that action is.
There should be a very clear and eye catching to action or CTA sometimes call it and that should allow
the page visitors to do that thing.
Now is there any mystery where the call to action on this page is.
Maybe it's bordering on noxious but its spirit is in the right place.
Tell people exactly where to click and what will happen so there's no doubt about what you want them
to do.
Now here's tip number four on the landing page to do is the user with a friendly confirmation.
Now once the visitor completes the landing page I'm trying to show a confirmation message so they know
it actually worked and then provide immediate details on what happens next.
Download your e-book here or you can get an email with wemen are details within the next few minutes.
And obviously thank them for trusting you with their personal info.
Take the opportunity to provide helpful links to other things I could download or more information on
a related topic.
Try not to go too crazy with that because you might actually end up distracting them from consuming
the thing you gave them.
Here's the confirmation page for an email course from enchanting marketing.
You pretty much know that an email will be on the way to get you started because the confirmation is
basically a thank you letter and it's a decently nice personal touch.
Here's Tip number five and it's something a lot of businesses surprisingly forget about.
Make sure your landing page used to work in the future now say with me I know that sounds a little obvious
but it's especially important if your landing page is a webinars that you make sure that it works going
forward.
After that event happens well you should use that landing page to provide like a recording of the web
or you could even use the same lead form to give visitors access to a public version of it.
Then you add a link to a page with an upcoming webinars so they can attend a live one if you want.
If you just take the landing page down but there are links to it from somewhere else.
Well visitors might arrive on a broken page until you lose a chance of getting a lead.
In fact a lot of marketers what they do is and this is really shitty but it's what they do for webinars
is they'll record a seminar and they act like it's live but it's not.
It's actually a prerecorded one.
So then anytime someone comes in they sign up for it and has a script that just keeps pushing the date
in the future they get an e-mail sequence and they watch the live webinars.
They ask questions but oh man they never seem to fail to get their question.
And I guess that's one way to do it.
For example here's a web page on physical education that took place sometime 2016.
Now shape America added Taxil visitors no recording was now available free for members or for purchase.
Blow your landing page is for a downloadable e-book white paper or an email course and you decide to
discontinue access.
Use some kind of redirect to get people on another page that can keep them interested in whatever else
you have to offer.
So those are the five pretty important tips that I think you should pay attention to for landing pages.
So just to recap news your headline to highlight the value of your offer.
Make sure that it's in the first sentence to provide all the details necessary to make a decision.
Don't leave anything out.
There's really nothing that can go wrong by giving more information.
Make a call the call the action your CTA as obvious and unavoidable as possible.
Number four make sure that you think the user at the friendly confirmation again you know they trusted
you with their information and then five make sure that it continues to work in the future and then
you have a plan for what happens after.
Let's say your webinars runs or your e-book is now out of date.
So following these tips should ensure your landing page is at least informative and effective now and
hopefully in the future.
Now the flip side there are plenty things marketers and designers do to make their landing pages less
than ideal and frankly just screw it up.
So here are five things that go over quickly to avoid with your own landing pages.
First of all don't force people to think too much.
People landed on your landing page for a reason.
They want what was promised to them and they clicked on a link in an email they got.
So they already have expectations or what they should find on the page.
Don't confuse them with a different headline or page copy that makes them hesitate about giving you
their info.
For example if you search for it landing page guide on for a Marchetto e-book shows up Marchetto landing
page guide.
Learn from the industry best practices.
Now this clearly sounds perfect so when you click through you naturally arrive at a page called The
Definitive Guide to digital advertising.
What the hell.
Now a quick scan of description shows no mention of landing pages whatsoever.
Did I just hallucinate.
Did Marchetto Just promise me a guide for designing waining pages and then take me to a completely different
landing page.
What's going on.
So the lesson here is make sure your headline your ad matches the one on your landing page in fact trying
to make them as close as possible.
The same goes for any links images or other elements you use to direct people to your landing page.
There should be no confusion whatsoever when they arrive.
Otherwise you interrupt your own momentum and make the visit or doubt pretty much everything they're
doing or the next thing to avoid on landing pages is don't ask for more than what you need.
In terms of the form gathering leads is an important process for your business but you don't need 50
fields of information about a lead for it to be a good one.
You especially don't need to ask for too much information about a person in the first time you meet
them on a landing page.
The friend introduces you to someone you know immediately ask them for their address phone number and
blood type.
Understand that landing pages can be and should be considered one of the many potential times you can
connect with someone.
So if all you get from a person in exchange for an e-book is their name an email address will consider
that a win.
Then build upon that first interaction in the future if you need it you can get more information to
get a collection of white papers on the future of battery technology from Enter tech.
You're required to enter your physical mailing address and I wonder how many junk mailings enter text
sends out to one to three fake street in Yemen because while forums like this what's the point.
Again if you want to do more with a lead Well then keep talking to them and offering them value.
If your work is truly worth something they'll be happy to give you more data or more information.
So be conscious of what information you need and just keep in mind you can get more from them later.
Business to business companies.
You can ask for a little bit more upfront because you don't need as many leads but if you're a consumer
company why are you asking them their age or their mailing address or their high school mascot.
It just doesn't make sense.
So don't ask for too much info and while you're at it here's another tip don't make the landing page
experience overly complex.
Now first there's a between long and complex you might need a long page packed with a lot of info that
kind of goes.
Tip number three.
But if it's presented in a simple way can still be very effective.
We're talking about a page being too complex.
I mean don't annoy them with extra steps.
Your landing page should be where people land to get what they want.
It shouldn't be a stop and a series of hoops you have them jump through.
Engineering and Technology Magazine has a white paper called a drone's life airborne battery management.
OK fair enough.
I'll just click the downloaded free white paper here button and now another landing page goddammit.
Same description although the bullets are slightly different.
Now there's a form a one and the cover of the White Paper says drones 2017.
Not drones the life.
I don't know if I'm in the right place know all the details need to be consistent in each step your
visitors have to go through but at the very least in this case engineering and technology magazine should
combine these two pages into one save us that extra unnecessary click and it will eliminate a bunch
of confusion and dramatically up their conversion rate.
All right here's another thing to avoid on landing pages.
Don't rely on a block of text to sell your lead magnet landing pages are perfect opportunities to use
the available space on the page you spell out all the benefits for your visitor.
You cram all the info into a block of text.
You're not really making things easy to digest if you're promoting an ebook or white paper or show a
picture of the cover.
You've got details to share with them break them out into bullet points or a very loose outline.
Show a few pictures of your messages from your email course or pictures of the speakers in your webinars.
Don't trap yourself within a landing page template thinking you can only put text in one spot.
Think outside the template.
For example the pages promotes their weekly webinars with all the details and highlights written out
but also includes a video preview as well.
It's a great selling point because videos are way more fun to watch than text is to read.
Plus it's short unengaging.
I personally like it.
Now here's one more thing to avoid and landing pages don't distracter visitors with competing called
actions when you design a landing page for your lead magnet.
Make sure the page has a clear focus and one.
Yes that is one called Action took up his landing page from training magazine training mag.
The goal of this page is to get people to sign up for Webinars on how to manage training costs.
However training man has loaded up the page with so many different calls to action.
You don't actually know where to look now above the details for this webinars.
And for another weapon or over on the right is a big.
What would you like to do menu but none of the choices are to actually register for the webinars.
The reason why I came here and registration button is pretty boring.
It's grey and in the middle of everything.
No training that should remove as much of this noise as possible including that stupid banner at the
top and perhaps even those buttons on the right.
As for the call the action are as you might remember from the first to do item.
Make a called Action unavoidable and obvious.
The main call to action on this page should be a bright color their blue orange or green or whatever
you guys want to argue about the best color for buttons.
Go ahead.
I'm going to step out of this.
The point is gray is way too easy to miss.
So let's recap the landing page no nos.
One more time.
Number one.
Don't force people to think too much.
Number two don't ask for more than what you need.
Figure out what you need ask for that.
Get the rest from later.
Number three don't make the landing page overly complex.
Now remember the difference string long and complex enough the same thing and before.
Don't rely on a block of text cell of the magnet.
Break it up.
No one wants to read a block of text.
They're trying to get a book they don't want to read a book to get a book.
Number five Don't distract visitors with competing CTX that one should be obvious.
Don't put a bunch of buttons and then expect them to only do one of them.
Make your learning they just focused.
Simple but rigid in the relevant details.
Answer questions for your audience to convince them of the value of what you're offering.
If they're not compelled to click your call to action wealth of failure so make your landing page a
success with these best practices in mind.
All right guys I'll see you in the next lecture.