Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
Now in the last couple years we've been covering the bare basics of this thing called Content Marketing.
In this lecture and in the next few lectures we're going to go over a piece of the strategy that I and
many other content gurus would consider essential.
This oh so essential piece of the strategy pie is known as understanding your audience.
Now it might seem obvious at first but you'd really be surprised how little you or common bloggers and
content marketers out there know about their audience and just how often people go right into publishing
content putting a lot of work into it without doing the basic diligence upfront so that being said ask
yourself what people or businesses out there.
Should you be creating your content for who will appreciate your content connect with it and be compelled
by it to take action.
Another way to ask this is who would be your ideal customer or client.
No we did a little bit of this back and like second two or three but we need to kind of expand on that
specifically for content marketing because it's a little bit different of a process you need to know
more for content marketing notifying our audience more specifically helped us think about creating content
with a purpose.
We can't sit back and think that anything good will automatically work for us.
Yes.
All of our stuff needs to be good.
But if we have an audience in mind when we create it at the beginning that's kind of the important part
our good content will actually have a chance to resonate with the right people resulting in low points
the content marketing which is to get sales at the end of the day.
So a key benefit here of defining our audience is that it will help us focus our content.
Adverts it can help us validate ideas before we even begin writing we'll choose topics that we know
our audience wants and avoid ones we know they probably won't care about.
That way we know whenever we create is always going to benefit our audience in at least some way.
That consistency is really important in your content strategy.
Let's say you have an idea for a blog post on marketing automation tools.
For example we might think Hey that sounds like something I'd like to read but the reason we define
our audiences is so that we can create something that they would like to read.
A lot of things I like to read that I had my audience and my students probably couldn't care less about.
So think about that idea you had for a marketing automation tools post could turn into something like
10 ways for higher ed to attract more students via automation but your audience might be say startups
and small businesses or you might come up on your own with a video walkthrough of a tool and post it
on YouTube but maybe your audience actually didn't spend any time on YouTube and they spend their time
and let's say LinkedIn and Facebook maybe they don't like video and they'd rather have an ebook or something
to download.
This is crucial information to have knowing your audience and writing content for them is kind of like
a tree falling in the forest saying but in this case it's like a great piece of content gets written
and posted and nobody wants to read it.
Is it still great.
And the answer is No.
No it is not.
So by defining our audience instead of a tree falling in an empty forest it'll fall or a forest full
of people we want to connect with and sell things to.
And they'll be crushed by this tree because of how good this content is because it was created just
for them.
They'll think you're psychic.
We need to cross our customers with greatness.
And that is pretty much the perfect metaphor.
Yeah I think so.
They're defining our audience helps us focus.
But what other benefits can we get out of it.
It also helps us.
I did a fine with our audience and speak their language.
When we start writing knowing our audience helps us think of the words we'll use the terms or abbreviations
we know they'll understand and the examples we'll pick because well we know they'll appreciate them.
And ultimately it helps us figure out what actions we want them to take.
Part of speaking their language will help us decide how to bring the values so to speak.
Like for instance when we run down all of these marketing automation tools and our marketing automation
poser's talking about before do we have to define the basic concepts or do we need to define the basic
like features.
Or will our audience already understand what they are.
We'll know if we were writing for beginners or more experienced people.
For small businesses or for large businesses for audiences in Africa or Australia these are details
that make a difference between the reader finding the content useful or thinking that you're talking
down to them and just ignoring it another benefit of defining your audience is that it saves you time
effort and money.
Imagine yourself in front of a dart board and you've got one dart in your hand or a gun on a firing
range whatever or maybe even a bazooka.
You decide.
But here's the point if you don't define your audience you're essentially putting on a blindfold before
you try to hit the target.
And when you throw that dart or fire that bazooka who knows where it will hit.
Chances are you'll miss and miss badly but these darts are really good you might say or you know the
bazooka.
So great it puts such time and care into making it.
I know it's going to be great.
Well yeah you're going to you're still going to keep missing eventually you run out of things to throw
or shoot but probably you'll also run out of patience money or Sadly both.
So take off your blindfold save yourself lots of time effort and money and lock in on the target by
defining your audience and then blast it with a bazooka full of great content.
Sound good.
OK.
Well the next series of lectures we're going to cover how to define your audience using different types
and sources of data.
We'll discuss where you can find your audience wants you to find them and how you could focus those
efforts even more through the use of user personas.
Great.
Now go reload your content bazookas and I'll see you in the next lecture.