Hey guys welcome back to the course.
Now with these last few lectures on how to write controversial post topical posts in long form content.
I don't know if you noticed but those are types of content that are a step up from your basic blog post
or tweet.
If you were to start creating long form content for example you're showing that you're ready to dedicate
a more significant amount of time to the content that you're creating.
The nice part is that you can then expect bigger results because of that extra effort.
I only point this out because the type of content I want to tell you about in this lecture also requires
an extra amount of attention but like those other three types of content it can pay off in a big way.
So you have to kind of justify it to yourself up front so just keep watching promises is a good one.
In this lecture I want to tell you about how to create round up posts.
Now we mentioned roundups earlier in the section as one of the 10 different common types of content
people use need a reminder round ups are where you ask a group of experts one question.
Collect their answers and you share them all in one big post.
Salvias he got some good benefits to the experts come up with all the great content for you.
It's a great way to get links and shares because those experts usually share the posts themselves and
it can lead to lots of new followers and engagement.
Because you've got all of the experts followers checking out your post as well.
Basically by creating a successful round up post you can introduce yourself to a bunch of experts and
their followers and a signal to them that your blog could be a source of information they'd want to
check out in the future.
So how can you create one of these round up posts.
Well it all starts with a question.
What would you ask an expert in your industry.
That would be of interest to your audience and to be honest that's the question you ask yourself in
order to come up with the question you'd ask experts.
I know if that really makes sense.
There's a lot of questions.
So what is that question going to be.
What's something that you would find interesting and your audience would find interesting as well.
Well let's go over for common types of question.
You could use for a round up post.
First of all you could ask experts a yes or no question but only if you also asked for an explanation
afterwards.
Basically you're asking for them to take sides on an issue.
So you want to know why they would or would not support a given scenario or option.
For example you could ask a group of tech experts if you are in charge would you redesign the iPhone.
Why and how would you part of the question is clearly looking for a yes or no answer.
But the second part of the question demands more detail.
A simple yes or no provides no value by itself to the reader.
The explanation that comes afterwards will provide actual Great insight.
Now the same goes for any multiple choice type question you ask.
You can get your experts a list of options to choose from.
You know like Option A B C or D and then ask for an explanation and if necessary give them the option
of choosing a different answer.
For example you might ask a group of app developers which platform should a new app developers start
developing for their brand new iOS Android or both.
You didn't ask for reasons but of course you leave the door open in case there's some other options.
Like I don't know Windows Phone is going to make a comeback so maybe they'll say Windows Phone.
Probably not a lot of times round up post authors will instead just go with an open ended question.
Now this is a question that has no yes or no answer but instead it leaves the answer completely up to
how the expert wants to respond.
For example you might ask diet experts if someone's trying to lose weight.
What's the most important change they should make in their lives now.
The answers could range anywhere from like cutting out specific foods to lifestyle changes like waking
up early or exercising.
It could be really anything but it could not be a yes or no.
You might ask a group of writers what tool or platform do you use to write your books.
You might hear about 10 different apps but some of them might also say get a pencil and paper and start
writing.
Who knows.
That's kind of the nice part about open ended questions you're not restricting the experts in any way.
But there's another question type that's kind of interesting.
Now that's the fill in the blank which is basically a question but it's disguised as a statement of
some kind.
For example you could ask project managers to complete the sentence.
The thing that keeps my team's projects on schedule more than anything else is blank.
Maybe it's an app or maybe it's a way of doing things or maybe it's a person that just is really good
at keeping projects going let them surprise you.
The more novel The format generally the more interesting the article be.
In all four cases yes knows multiple choices and open ended questions and fill in the blanks.
The response you get from your expert is far more valuable within an explanation in tow.
Why did you choose that answer over another answer.
After all the reason you're asking experts these questions is because of their experience and the reasoning
behind their answers.
What will make your post really insightful and help people actually learn.
So let's say you came up with a great question.
You wish you could ask all the experts in your industry.
Well now you just need to follow these steps for creating your Round-Up.
First you make a list of experts on how to contact them.
You prepare how you'll collect their responses create a template message or email asking your question.
After that you can contact the experts and in the end collect your responses put them together into
a post and then let them know that you've published it.
It's really not that hard.
The only hard part and there is maybe finding their email address but we've covered that several times
in the course already where we talk or e-mail hunting.
There are some details in each step that you could know about that will still make it all a little bit
easier.
So first Once you have the question you've settled on a question that you want to ask you need to identify
your group of X parents but also make note of the best way to get in contact with them.
Making a list of experts means going out to industry blogs and finding people who write about these
topics regularly what you're hoping for experts with an actual following on their blog and on social
media.
Part of the reason you're doing this is to open your blog up to a bigger audience.
So make sure at least some of the experts you're asking have their own audience themselves.
It's OK to choose some experts without a big following as long as you know they'll be able to provide
some valuable information as part of your research on these experts and you figure out how to contact
them.
Do you have e-mails for them or Twitter handles.
Ideally it would be easiest for you if you could send your message to everyone the same way like sending
them on e-mail but there might be a few experts who just can't find e-mails for or maybe they are on
Twitter.
You might be stuck submitting a contact form on their blog.
What are the method is.
Figure out how to contact them.
So you know what to do when you actually go to send your message.
The next step is to figure out how you'll be collecting responses to your round up question.
Yes you could just send an e-mail and ask experts to answer right there in the message.
But let's consider some alternatives first.
You could create your own google form which is really easy to do and then share it.
You could also use an online survey tool like Survey Monkey.
Asiri has been around for years and they do have a free plan that easily colonnades what you need to
do for a round approach which is not much the advantage of using an online form or surveys of all the
responses is get stored for you in one place.
It's a little bit easier than sifting through your inbox looking for answers.
Since Google form and Survey Monkey are both free options give them a look and consider using one of
those.
It also makes you look more prepared when you reach out to them.
If you go with one of these offerings then create the form or survey now because you'll need the link
for whatever message you send ask your question and put in the proper response fields you need.
Make sure to include a confirmation page.
But thanks them for their time and a way to get back in touch with you if they want.
Perhaps Actually they'll ask when the post is up.
Or they might want to know more though or maybe they'll ask you to participate in their own round up.
So that brings us to the next step here.
Do yourself a favor and come up with a message template that includes the body of your message including
a request to answer your specific question and if necessary links to anything that's relevant such as
like the Google form or survey we're going to collect the responses when sending your message.
You of course want to be polite and professional.
You know these experts aren't obligated to do anything so if you're rude or demanding it's easy enough
to delete your email and just ignore you.
So try to follow a couple simple rules.
Try to greet them in a warm way.
Don't just put their name and then a hyphen.
Try to say Dear Steve or Dear Mr Jobs and please don't try to email Steve Jobs he's obviously not going
to answer.
The next thing is that you just need to get to the point and assume that your expert has basically zero
time for you.
So make your request quick and relevant.
I follow your blog and I really enjoy your post about whatever the topic is.
It's a mobile technology or app development.
I'm running a post about this topic I was hoping you'd answer this question.
I'd love to include your response to my blog and we'll add a link to your blog in my post and then you
might even put relevant things like how much traffic you have and then ask your question and be clear
about what you want from them.
That multiple choice is open ended.
Whatever it is tell them exactly what they need to do and when.
Again experts have no time for your foolish games so make this stupid easy.
Please email or reply with your answer by Friday.
My first so I concluded in my post or please answer the question on my google form by Friday March first
and then include the link.
Make sure you leave yourself enough time obviously in case you want to publish this by a certain date.
A few extra days obviously is usually good enough to get the responses from any late responders.
With that being said it's a good chance that some of the experts just simply don't respond.
So if you plan on getting 5 experts email 10 then the last thing is just thank them again.
Again be polite and thank them for their time.
Chances are you're going to use them in the future.
This is a great way to open up doors for networking and Co promotion.
If they want more info than they'll reply or get in touch somehow on the survey itself.
Make sure that you are very crystal clear about what's going on.
Write some introduction tasks explaining again what the relevant information is.
Make sure you have clear instructions so that they know what to do when they click through.
Now here's another important thing to keep in find if you can't find an email for the expert you want.
You can actually share a link to your survey instead in a tweet just at mention them and ask them politely
if they'd answer a question about your topic.
But obviously since you can include every detail in 140 characters on Twitter make sure the page where
they give a response has those details already and then obviously be careful that other people aren't
filling it out and you might get confused.
So when you have your message in your survey form ready to roll.
Contact your experts.
Send your e-mails or your tweets.
Once the responses start arriving you can begin work on your post.
The tool like Google form or Survey Monkey you can basically go to a dashboard type page and see what's
arrived.
Take the responses them again drafting up your purse if necessary reach out to any experts who are late
and remind them or even if your deadline has come and gone.
If you have the time you can reach out again and say there's still time to be included or I don't know
some kind of job to get them motivated.
When everything is all set and your post is good to go publish that thing and then reach out to your
experts tweet out a link to your person and make sure to at mention the people that are in it.
You're bound to get obviously likes and read tweets along with some new followers.
You can also just e-mail experts personally and thank them.
Don't skip this step especially if he hope to do more round ups in the future.
This is a great time to start a relationship with them.
So there you have it.
All the steps for creating a round up post before I sign off I want to mention one alternative because
there are actually two ways you can create a round up post.
Here's the way I mentioned which is basically read out.
Reach out to experts personally either through email or social media.
Ask them your questions collect their answers and then publish your findings.
But the other way of doing this.
Another way of creating a round up post is instead you curate answers from online public sources.
This case you don't actually ask anyone questions what you're doing is just finding answers to a question
you would ask if you could.
Now how is this a good idea.
I hope for example and you can ask obviously ask Steve Jobs or Alfred Hitchcock or Meyer Angelo your
really cool question about creativity.
Sadly they're gone through quotes and other resources online you could probably find a relevant quote
from them.
It's also a great way to tie this up with something topical or timely.
Can they help you promote your post.
Obviously not.
Can they give you a custom response to your question due again.
Is this an ideal way to do your round up and just kind of depends.
It depends on how much work you put into it.
How you can even mix it up by taking past experts and comparing their quotes to real life experts and
then showing the difference.
It would be interesting to see other responses from today's experts match up with those experts who
are around anymore right.
I know that some of the things about.
OK so that's it for round ups.
I'll see you in the next lecture.