Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
All right let's talk more about that concept.
We kind of just got into the last lecture.
Guess posting.
If you are interested in guest posting maybe you heard my last lecture and we're like now or maybe you
fell asleep on your keyboard and this is actually playing to the top of your head.
Then go ahead and skip the next couple of lectures.
Also you may be narcoleptic.
So once you've decided you want to write posts for other blogs and sites the next step is to find those
places interested in guest post.
Not every site wants them which is fine.
We don't need to be part of your popular table.
You just have to look around.
The first thing I think you should do is start with the blogs and people who already know or are familiar
with.
You might have an idea if you could write something that you couldn't see being posted at such place.
For instance if you're interested in marketing you might have stumbled upon a blog called business grow
by Mark something something for example.
Yes I know it's called business grow and not business growth but I'm assuming the extra two letters
in his domain are probably out of his budget or this is just a shameless play as CEO.
I don't know.
Anyway on his site mark and a group of guest bloggers write all about things.
Marketing So if you have some expertise and see marketing automation tools you might ask yourself the
question.
Could I write something about marketing automation that would fit in with all the other posts I see
here.
So then the question becomes would magical mark or marky mark or the owner of the blog owner is that
you're looking at.
Would they consider an article for their blog.
If you can create something good something that's relevant to the audience of the target blog and not
just your audience and the blog is open to submissions from guest posters.
Well then you have a great chance of having your posts being accepted and then the rest of it's really
just a mechanical process.
The easiest way to get a post accepted somewhere is through I'll admit personal connections.
I know that's not necessarily what you want to hear but sadly a lot of guest posts are done through
knowing someone.
So if you know the blogs owner that definitely helps.
It might be the case that maybe they've read your stuff already but regardless the probably more willing
to give you a chance than a place that doesn't know you.
Quick side note.
Most blogs will ask you for previous examples of your work.
Obviously they need to be posted somewhere not just in a Word doc.
So if you can get a couple of posts up it'll actually make this process a lot smoother.
Now beyond the people you know you'll need to do some digging to find guest post opportunities that
make sense for you.
You can start by just searching on Google and be specific when you search.
Start with the topic you want to write about and then add the keywords guest post or guest blogger or
maybe even marketing guest post or design guest blogger.
If you want to be more specific those searches can return results for sites that focus on those topics
and either have guest post and that's why it picked up on the word guest and the keyword or are looking
for someone to participate.
If you're not finding the sites you want then you can try other search terms like writers needed guest
post guidelines right for us or blog for us.
And those should help.
Those key phrases are kind of a hack right because not everybody says we need guest bloggers but they
might have a button that says right for us.
That's a very common one you'll see on web sites are blocked for us or even just guest post guidelines
if they have a guest post guidelines link.
They probably take s post but that's not really all you can do with Google.
Sort of searching for those blogs that accept bloggers.
We can also search for the guest bloggers themselves and then reverse engineer this process to figure
out where they've gotten access to.
We don't even have to know their names for this to work.
All right.
Check this out.
Let's talk about to google for the sake of this example let's say you want to direct guest post somewhere
about your favorite subject search engine marketing.
That's your favorite thing in the world.
God save you.
Everyone says you're so good at that search engine marketing man.
You should write about it and I can see you're excited about it so here on Google you can type in search
engine marketing and then add in the addition of my guest post and close to zero.
I'm going with this.
We're looking for places where people literally talk about their guest posts on your topic and they
do all the time because guess bloggers guess what.
They promote their stuff.
Putting those quotations tells Google to search specifically for this phrase and not other loose variations
of it which can kind of get you down the wrong path.
So try out that search.
And here within the first results we've got where I contribute and guest post as CEO smartly.
So bingo.
That's what we were looking for so let's click through it and yeah here on this page.
Guess what.
We have a whole bunch of sites where and Smarty never heard of our writes about SEO related topics.
We have Internet Marketing ninjas for the Web site SU chat entrepreneur magazine crazy egg search engine
journal and so on right there you've got a bunch of leads curated for you and if you can write as good
as this silly lady will then you have a good chance of getting in these publications.
So once she finds a promising Web sites or blogs you'll need to evaluate them to make sure they fit
your needs.
Chris metrics actually shared a pretty good four question list you can use to evaluate a blog or website
for guest posting.
So number one first question you should ask is that blog's content focused on the same topics you write
about.
Number two is that blog's audience interested in your industry now or three.
Does that blog have engaged readers like you know lots of comments and shares and in the last one in
number four is the blog owner active on social media such that they will share your posts and help you
promote it.
If the answer is yes to all of those questions well then you have a good opportunity.
If you're not so sure will try to figure out as much as you can.
Some sites will have guest post pages set up already.
Makes it easy for you.
Others will not.
That doesn't necessarily mean they don't guess PPOs do your best though and try to look through their
posts.
You can't find any information there.
Check out their contact page and you might have a form or section specifically for guest post inquiries.
Now here's an example of a site that's doing it correctly it's called right mix marketing.
I know there's tons and tons of these marketing websites that go on.
They've got a page set up for people interested in guest posting with info on who their audience is.
Topics they like examples of guest posts they have performed well.
Basic requirements how to submit and what happens after you submit it.
I think you right mix.
Now what if you've got your sites aimed really high and you want to contribute to a blog that's got
a really big audience.
It's like the Huffington Post for example.
Well sites like that also have their own requirements and unique processes for submitting work of PPOs
the cool kids call it.
I actually asked you to send them a finished draft of your post and in peer lingo we called that on
spec if you don't remember that you need to send that along with an idea for the title your name.
You have to give a bio and a couple other pieces of information.
If pitching your idea like this doesn't interest you that's OK.
Do more research and you'll see there are other ways to do it but unfortunately some places just only
want you to do it this way.
But maybe find a way around it.
So if you Google like write writing for Huffington Post now if you find more detail info on how to make
contact the more traditional way.
There's even a core of post about this subject that we link to in the resources that outlines a few
ways to pitch and write for Huffington Post and includes responses and advice from longtime contributors.
Turns out it's not super hard so it is possible to write for bigger more mainstream sites.
It might require more digging and research but even if you're not ready you can book market a note.
All of these details for future reference.
Remember for the PR section reintroduced a concept called laddering up which is basically means that
while you can't really get into the New York Times without first getting into let's say Tech Crunch
you can't get into tech crunch until you've gotten into who know some smaller publication.
The same applies here.
You have to start small and easy and then use that example to ladder up to a progressively larger outlet.
People want to see proof that other people have published you that's a way that they save themselves
time are good so start working on your search for blogs that won't guest post.
Your list will get you started and help you get everything you need to actually contact them and pitch
your idea.
The last thing I'll say about it is that depending on the industry you're in.
There are some pre-made lists of blogs that guest post out there.
I will try to include some in the resources.
However they're usually specific to like technology or I don't know it's usually something really specific
so it might not match you but it's a good place to start.
All right guys.
More on that in the next lecture.
See the.