Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So if you've got our list of sites to approach it's time to prepare your pitch now.
Accepting outside submissions are kind of like hiring managers.
They don't have the time to figure you out.
You need to tell them exactly what you can do for them and in the right format.
So a great way to start is by meeting any basic requirements you can find.
You might find information on a guest blogger page or a contact page or a sidebar on their blog.
Most places that accept outside work will say something like we accept this or tell us this or that
about yourself.
For example on the ninety Ninety-Nine you contact page there is another blog.
They've got a short well section of the top that says what to write for ninety nine you do include writing
samples from other publications on a specific pitch on what you like to write about.
So right there you know what you need to include samples and a pitch that can include that.
Well then just don't bother.
Quick side tip.
What if the requirements include links to online samples of your previous post and you don't have any
yet.
Well one option is to write an article and instead of posting it on someone else's blog or your page
posted on Linked In.
It's actually a quick and easy way to get something online for free.
Maybe get some engagement that at least shows something you can add to your new and growing list of
online posts.
It's a great stopgap and a lot of people see it and think that it was published by Linked In.
I don't know for some reason it works is the same thing goes for using medium dot com.
And here's another tip that I think worth remembering every blog is different so every pitch you send
to them should be different.
Please do not email the same thing to ten different places.
You're just wasting your time.
Take the time and create a unique message each time and call out those relevant topics on their site.
Mention a recent post of yours you thought was cool and perhaps related to your idea.
Showing that you have been to their site and actually read some of their material can really help you
because you'd be amazed how many people pitch and they've never read the blog.
Now you might have one great idea.
You are really excited about.
You want to go all in on this idea but when you get to their contributor page here in the form it asks
What are two or three specific article topics you would write.
Well be prepared to pitch multiple ideas.
You might also have to dip into that list of ideas we generated before.
But remember make them relevant to this site not just your audience.
If you need help validating an idea then just do a search on the site's blog and look for similar titles
or post you might see something that covers your idea or an opportunity for you to present it.
The point is you just want to make sure that you're pitching something that's not completely in outer
space.
Remember that a Gor a pulse blog from our last video will block covered all kinds of social media topics
and relevant categories.
So they asked you what are two three things you might write about.
Don't say well I can write about social media.
Email Marketing and viral marketing.
Don't go outside the scope of what they want.
Look at their posts in categories and find inspiration there and be specific when they ask for ideas.
Give them actual titles you're thinking of using Not big topics.
When you think about the headlines go back to the best practices we covered with headlines console that
they don't have to be the best thing ever.
In fact most publications will edit them for you now when you're ready to submit your information or
send your email.
Your pitch should be short and sweet and cover all of the basics from those basic requirements you talked
about earlier.
Double check and make sure your messages include them all.
As an example let's say you wanted to write a tech post somewhere because you're an app developer and
you've got some experience you want to share about say I don't know ways in which developers use mobile
apps that are different from other people.
Fascinating one of the blogs you follow is business insider which writes plenty about tech topics.
In fact though bright about anything that's Takk And guess what they accept a guest post a lot of them
actually their site says send the final draft of your piece.
A proposed headline brief bio and links to any other pieces you've published to contributors at Business
Insider dot com and I'm OK giving out their email address it's public.
So if you were to respond to that email what do you think you would say.
Well here's what an email could look like Old Business Insider.
I'm a longtime reader of your blog post about app development are really helpful especially in insert
title here.
You don't have to go into too much detail you just add something quick like love the checklist or refer
back to it all the time or he was a quick thought.
I had on the value delivered then you could say I love to contribute a post to Business Insider and
as an apt feel for myself I think it speaks to the needs of your audience.
It's called.
This is where you actually would say this is my headline for what I'm proposing and then give it a short
description because it's not immediately obvious from the headline.
As requested I've attached a copy of my post and a Bible as a Word document.
You can also just use a Google doc link or Dropbox or whatever you want.
Generally speaking I prefer to send out a link to like Dropbox or Google Docs for this information because
if you attach it to the email it's more likely to go to spam.
But it actually reminds me check out tool attached I can actually tell you when you send an attachment
if the other person opened it and read it.
I think it's pretty neat.
Anyway back to the e-mail also.
Here are a few guest posts I've written before to give you a look at my style and engagement your links
right there.
Thank you for your consideration.
Please let me know if you have any questions for me.
Cheers me.
Now obviously don't use that one word for word but that is basically the template you should use.
Try spicing it up and but for the most part just meet the basic requirements.
So in the end your message should be professional and concise.
Of blogs actually tell you what to expect after you submit such as how long you might have to wait.
Be patient no matter where you pitch your idea.
Some of these blogs are just ridiculously busy and you might not hear back from them for weeks if at
all in fact a lot of them will not respond.
Other places may get back to you right away.
Either way be prepared to actually write the piece if you've offered a pitch and in the case of other
larger publications Well you already wrote the pitch.
If they don't like it then maybe try pitching it to another one.
It's in our next lecture We'll talk about actually writing the piece and making it fit for the blog
that it's going to find a home on.
All right I'll see it.