Hey guys welcome back.
All right so we're in the homestretch here in our talk about guest posting now that we've research places
we might want to write for and we've contacted those places and we've gotten our awesome pitch approved.
Well now what do we do.
Now it's time to actually write this thing when your pitch gets approved the blog or web site might
send you along some like boiler plate type information that they copy and paste into an email back to
you.
That might include basic guidelines like make sure your blog post has a word count of such and such
number or falls within a specific range.
There's a pretty easy guidelines so please don't ignore it.
They might say make sure your post is original and has not been published elsewhere.
They request this than whatever you write needs to be new.
Don't include more than one link to your own website and the body of the post.
Now some sites won't care if you link to your Web site if you link multiple times and others are more
serious about it.
Some will take them at all and some are kind of in the middle like this or they'll say you can only
do it once but I'm Dymes they don't want posts that look ultra promotional because you you know put
a dozen links to different dozen different product pages.
In fact I have seen some of the companies just reject articles because you pitch something or mention
something and it was too obvious and well guess what.
That's their prerogative.
I didn't really lose a lot of sleep over it.
Besides you probably have a bio anyway.
So then you can usually mention what you're working on are oftentimes linked to your site.
You might also see something like don't include screenshots of the product.
If there's branding of any kind in it because it is under these sites what they allow.
Much of these rules have to do with maintaining a certain level of quality.
Secondly the quality expected by their leaders and followers.
Remember you're writing for them not you.
So another tip to remember is you need to meet the expectation of that Web site's audience.
Now some blogs will provide tips for this.
They'll share links to posts that have performed well.
They might highlight topics or concepts that the readers want more information about the blog might
even give you a suggested format like provide at least one industry example or end it with an open ended
question the readers can answer in the comments.
If you're unsure just go through the blog yourself and look for posts that have generated a lot of engagement.
There might be some ideas right there and you can grab for yourself to make your post more appropriate
for that specific audience.
In fact helpful way to improve the focus of your post and to earn some brownie points.
The editor of the blog to add links to recent posts on their blog.
In your post since this will be going on their site anyway it makes sense for you to link to other posts
and help keep readers on their site.
For example I wrote a post about e-mail open rates and giving tips on how to improve them.
Perhaps you can find a couple of posts on their site that touch on the same topic or related topics
like recommended email platforms or email design tips.
If you're going to mention these topics anyway linking to those older posts can make your posts look
like it belongs on the site and also gives the editor more reasons to like you.
Now once you start writing your posts you need to do something else really important stay focused on
whatever the pitch is you provided.
This might seem obvious but again it's a pretty common mistake.
Once your post gets approved just don't change your mind or switch things up because you thought of
something better.
Stick to the idea description the talking points or whatever it is that you provided.
Some current event or breaking news affects your idea that you can always contact the blog or the editor
who ever responded to you in the first place then tell them how you'd like to change it and why.
If there's something related to the current event by the way then it's a good chance that I could generate
more traffic or engagement so sometimes that blog editors will go for it.
It also just depends on how many times you've written for this outlook.
First time you might not be able to get away with it.
You've done it several times.
I don't know when you got a finished draft remembered or view your post to make sure you met all of
those guidelines.
Can't say this enough word count.
Links visuals whatever it is that they've stipulated and review the content to make sure that it matches
your pitch.
What is a little bit of obvious information is that Meeke should include a bio for yourself with the
article you write.
The blog might give you guidelines about how you can display your information but try to at least get
the important stuff in there.
Things like a company name you owl maybe and your Twitter handle whatever it is that you want to drive.
The actual traffic too.
You've decided to gasp blog for reasons if you want to gain social followers for example and put your
social media handles in there.
Most editors are aware of this that people don't guess blog just for the fun of it.
So now by this point you should hopefully have a completed draft.
You'll have to submit it through whatever channel the blog tells you to.
Then you might have to play the waiting game.
Your post will probably go through some like editorial review meaning that people from the blog and
even go through it check for formatting check that it matches your style.
Check out the links that you used whatever.
If there are any issues with your post the editor might get back to you and then work with you.
It's actually pretty common that you go through a couple rounds of editing.
Now if your post gets approved you might hear back about when it will go up.
They might tell you a date which would be great.
Or they might say something some time next month.
Again it's up to them.
But if you politely find out the date of your post that can actually help quite a bit with preparation.
Blogs will generally expect you to do a little bit of promotion yourself.
So it's pretty helpful to know when you need to do that.
Another key thing to keep in mind is that once the post is up make sure that you monitor the post for
comments and then participate when people have questions.
There are a lot of blogs out there that look for people that do this and they don't like it when they
have a dead beat writer who writes something then people follow up in the comments and they just disappear.
They like having people who nurture their audience so be sure to check it regularly at say pretty much
every day for at least the first seven days and then obviously in the comments don't try to be combative
or try to tell people that they're wrong just try to be constructive and thank people if they say what
you've written is good.
That goes without saying that people are disagreeing with you just be polite.
They might actually have a point.
Maybe they're just arguing for the sake of arguing.
That does actually happen.
Just remember this is not your blog or website you kind of have to act like you're a guest there so
behave you unsure of how to deal with someone.
And it's better just to check with the blog editor of the site owner and also don't just monitor the
blog posts for comments.
Make sure to look at where it's also been posted elsewhere.
Screen posted on Twitter it's me posts on Facebook see where the comments are there and also try your
best to participate.
If you use a tool like TweetDeck you use before you can actually set up custom feeds that tell you when
this post gets mentioned or shared.
One way to do that is pretty easy.
You just set up a search for the actual post title.
So if it's called Five Easy Steps improve your email open rights then you just search for that and TweetDeck
you'll see who is retweeted and perhaps find more comments that you respond to.
The last thing I would say that's pretty necessary to do is make sure that you send a thank you e-mail
to the person that you worked with.
I know it sounds old fashioned but it's a great way to end the relationship on a positive note because
let's be real.
You probably won't using them in the future if this actually worked out.
The Post as well for them all that it's an easy way for them to reply back and tell you about it and
perhaps even ask you to write for them again.
So after all of this work research pitching writing or watching all that happens.
How do you know if all of this was worth it.
How do you define success here.
Well in order to see if you are successful you have to go back to your original goal.
Why did you decide to guest post in the first place.
Or why was this specific blog or web site your target.
Were you trying to raise your profile as a writer or expert.
Or are you trying to get your company or web site or product discovered by a new audience.
You look at your social followers and see if there is some kind of uptick.
But in reality unless there's a mega viral hit probably I can see a huge change there.
But in general you should try to monitor engagement looking for basic things like likes and mentions
and retreats and comments are quite a bit easier to spot.
One of the more concrete ways that you can track the performance of the posts you made is to just track
how many people click the link that's in your bio to go back to your page and you can either do that
by adding like UTM parameters to the end of it and then looking at a Google Analytics or you can just
go to Google Analytics and sort by referral.
So referred from this site or this page that's generally a good indication.
So there you have it in the next set of lectures we're going to talk about ways in which you can promote
your content in order to reach as many people as possible.
Too many people forget about promoting the content as opposed to making it and I'll be honest with you
promoting is probably more important.
We'll leave you with that cliffhanger.
I'll see you next lecture.