Is welcome back to the course too we've started talking about the three elements of production lighting
audio and video.
Started off with lighting because I think it's the most important although it's kind of odd that we
start with lighting.
Don't worry about it from lighting audio then we'll end up with the mainstay.
The thing that most people think is the only thing that happens in video marketing video is that our
last video did lighting talked about lighting equipment lighting setups lighting types and in some of
the basic concepts behind it.
So in this lecture will cover that second one which is audio.
What kind of cover the same topics.
Member what I said like 3 seconds ago that lightning is the most important element of production.
Well you could easily make the same argument for certain types of production where you could say Audio
is the most important.
If for instance you have a video where someone is explaining how to do something offering advice or
simply walking you through the process well being able to hear them is going to be a necessity.
What happens if you can't understand them like you know if the audio drops out for a second or if they
mumble or if the audio just flat out isn't clear
then you might rewind it or skip it back 10 seconds or so maybe you wait and see if it all makes sense
after you hear some more.
Or maybe you go find a different video that looks and sounds better.
Realistically it's probably going that last option only the most dedicated people will actually sit
through bad audio better or you can really just take you out of the experience.
And this is why along with video and light and good audio is an essential part of your marketing videos.
It's an essential requirement now lighting I think can take you in a bigger range from really low quality
unbearable to world class production.
So much of that rests on the lighting whereas audio you kind of just hit a point where it sounds great
and then very few people besides audio files or people that work in video production are really going
to notice anything past that point.
However if you're lightings awful Yeah it'll look pretty bad but it's not necessarily a game ender or
as if audio's bad Ah but manage it especially with walkthrough and tutorials and things like that.
You might as well just give up.
Stop now in movies and on TV you can create moods with a mix of dialogue music sound effects and other
like instrumentals.
But for the most part in marketing videos getting good audio means we're really going to focus on two
things.
One we want to make sure that we're clearly capturing what people say and making sure we don't hear
anything else that's in the background.
Other considerations like adding music or sound effects are entirely secondary and you can really figure
them out once you get to the post-production and the editing process.
For now we're really just going to focus on the capturing and recording of audio since we're in the
production section and how we can get the best quality audio we can up front.
So most of your concern when you think about capturing audio is going to be what microphones will you
need and how we will record that audio.
So we're talking about two different things microphones and audio recording devices microphones pick
up the sound and recording devices.
Record it when you're done with a shoot.
You can take the audio files from your recording device and then sync them up with your video before
you start editing.
Now 90 percent of productions.
This is the way it's done.
You have an external recorder and then you have a microphone right now that's actually how I'm doing
it.
As Parnell's zoom micro it's a recorder and then it's attached to what's called an SLR attachment to
this right here if you see it.
That's the boom mike.
However it is actually possible skip the recorder part.
You can in some situations run a microphone directly to your camera and that's great because it'll actually
sync up the audio with the video automatically.
When I first started filming ice film that way I had a recorder that would go directly into the camera
and I didn't have to deal with it.
Now there's two downsides obviously doing that one is a little bit of a hassle when say you're far away
from the camera.
Right.
So if I have an audio Mike say it's close to me and the camera's far away when in a cord that goes all
the way to the camera or off to spend a lot of money on a wireless one.
The other thing is that if it goes directly into the camera because those recording devices have to
use external batteries they create these low frequencies that can actually create kind of a Halma or
a buzz in the actual set.
It's not a problem with that one of my courses where I had an adapter that took a mike to my camera.
Something is wrong with the read it and realize afterwards but there is this low level hum through all
the videos it was awful.
So let's talk about microphones and that's really where the only variation is specifically we're talking
about what do you need for a marketing video.
Now quick dip the mike on the camera or.
It's called It's also known as the onboard microphone.
You might be tempted to use it on your camera.
You might say well my camera takes audio when I notice that.
Oh my God.
Don't use it.
It's absolutely awful.
I don't know if we can switch the onboard audio right now.
Maybe you can hear me but oh my god.
It's just really low quality it's really flat.
It's got a lot of noise in it.
It sounds like it kind of coming from a distant location.
Now the first part of my going to talk about is called the shotgun mike.
I referred to it as a boom mike but you know explain that in a second.
The shotgun is a long thin Mike and it's good for capturing the sound in a specific direction and then
not picking up sound in other directions.
Usually you attach a shotgun mike to a stand and you point it at someone speaking.
Now I have it pointing directly at me right now and it's on a boom stand so often times you'll just
refer to it as the boom mike because it's on the boom.
General idea what does that you want to set them as close as possible to the person so it's not visible
on screen.
Closer it is the more of that person's voice it will get and it will get a lot less from elsewhere.
Now if I had this it was farther away while it would have to travel farther it's spread out and be less
concentrated.
But it also could pick up other noises that are kind of happening around.
Now if there's two people close together while you can point the shotgun in between them just make sure
both people speak towards the mike and not away from it.
Otherwise Lord help you.
Now shotguns are probably the most commonly used microphone and it can be a little expensive but they
do capture nice directional sound as long as the person speaking doesn't move around too much.
So all you really have to do is positioning the mike in front of your speaker and then point the end
of the mike towards their mouth.
Personally a shotgun mike is the only ones you know right now.
They're my favorite.
Why.
Because I think the audio quality is the best.
The reason why I think the audio quality is best is because it captures in one direction but it also
grabs a little bit of the sound around and that gives it kind of more of a natural full feelings and
you hear them it's almost more similar to what you'd actually hear if you're in the room with them.
Now I already mentioned booms and shotguns often come hand-in-hand with booms.
Booms are basically poles that are elevated up above someone and they dangle the shotgun at the end
of it.
Now it can either be on a stand like I use or big productions.
Unfortunately there are some poor bastard usually in turn that has to carry it and literally physically
like hold their hands over the scene and pointed at someone.
Now the pros of having a single person operated boom is that.
Well you get the boom closer to people more often especially if you're walking they can move with it.
You can't do that with a stationary boom.
The other thing is if you have two people talking.
Well they can take turns pointing at it.
Who's talking so that the people who are talking don't have to conflict point and try to find the shotgun
to make it sound right.
You could also always have two microphones.
But again if you have someone holding it or just operating a standard one that saves you from having
use to so shotgun mikes are probably the most common I'd say you see there's probably 60 percent of
the time the other 40 percent are what we call Lavell Lear.
Mike's also what cruel people in the know call lavs voyeurism and call it a laugh Mike to slap them
because that's not right.
Because you wouldn't say lavalier the law will here therefore law here is a small microphone that you
can clip onto a shirt or a jacket usually below the person's chin sometimes it's directly out of the
shot and sometimes it's actually in the shot and you see it.
No it's.
Mike for law is usually going to be attached to a small battery pack to put in a pocket or they attach
their belt.
Then the audio can go wirelessly to the camera or in some cases it's a wired version where you actually
have a line running directly to the audio capture device.
Now what are lawful is use for that.
You know shotguns can't be used for.
Well shotguns are best for set scenes where you know exactly where they're going to be talking and you
have the time to set up a boom pole.
Whereas a lot of this year is going to be better for if you're out in the field walking around and you
need the audio to travel with someone or if you're just in a situation where it's unrealistic that you
could get a boom pole all the way into their face a lot of times you'll shoot something and it's too
wide.
You can see too much therefore would be too ugly to constantly have a boom pulsing over someone's head.
Now you know to look for it next time you're watching anything like a TV show.
And I was just watching Seth Meyers is the late night TV show.
And you can see right in the middle of the shirt clips a leer right there.
Why.
Because they often zoom out or change angles.
And I think probably because it's too easy to catch a shotgun which did just look bad.
If you're trying to zoom out and just see the stick can hanging over someone.
Now one of the good things about all the love of yours is that they can capture good sound and they
can be relatively expensive really really cheap shot gun problems in a minimum like $100 or is a really
cheap lavalier $20 $30 and get you almost a similar sound.
The other person obviously is really portable.
Once you get someone set up a lot of Llyr they can move around.
They're pretty much miked up as long as they're on the scene.
You can even carry it with you to the next scene if you're using a wireless one at least and then you
don't have to get set up again.
Now what kinds of law tears are in my opinion.
The upper range for the sound you can get from a law is just not going to be as good as a shotgun.
If you have the opportunity to make the best audio you can or you have an ideal setup you're going to
want to go with a shotgun though I think it just drives me nuts about law Lears is that you can see
them on the screen.
A lot of times it's just impossible to hide them.
I mean the idea is that it needs to be close to the person's mouth talking and aides generally point
towards them.
OK.
Most people if you don't get the best audio you have to put it here which means you can see it.
Some people really get really tricky and put it like in your caller pointing towards you or in your
shirt like you're putting up.
But then when you move certain directions then you can see it.
I personally find it distracting.
There's a really funny video where they make the entire videos that to how much they hate lavalier microphones
because it just kind of takes people out of the video makes you look at it and go oh right this is a
video production.
Now some of you might think well that's obvious anyway.
But I mean if you're trying to really go for an immersive experience or really training gauge them in
your script or your content it's one more thing that just kind of sticks out.
Now here's a protip.
And this is something I'm relatively proud of that I figured out how I managed to do it because it what
I become a marketer series of Justin Maiers the way that we used Lovelle liras and every single scenes
that we could cause scenes really quickly and it was really easy to do wasn't We both wore button ups
but we chose button ups so we didn't really like as much because what you could do was you could go
in the back of your shirt.
I don't have a pocket on this one but usually are pockets right.
And so you can do is cut a tiny little hole in your shirt in between the outside of the pocket and your
actual sure you can run the law clear through your shirt and then through it and then tape it with Velcro
tape into your pocket.
Right.
So it have a clear line of shot at your mouth.
So it's the perfect ideal position and the velcro tape would stop it from moving around too much.
Anyway I was quite proud of that but it also does remind me of one of the other cons with the lavalier
is that motion.
If you don't set it up correctly it will create a like a rumbling noise and a lot of times it's really
hard to know when that happened.
So if I have it right here and I brush it remove my shirt it'll pick that up because it's so close to
that motion not I might not be a big deal to some people but if you're filming by yourself or just two
people or what are three people you don't have someone monitoring your audio constantly.
You could end up with an interview that's constantly full of noises.
All right so those are the two main ones you're going to see Chuck.
They're usually stationary or are held out by some poor bastard and they create the best audio.
However they do have a tendency to pick up some sound and anything towards them they'll pick up.
So you want to get them as close to your mouth as possible.
They're harder to move around so you have to set them up and they're bigger and they're easier to see
which sometimes precludes using them when you're doing filming where you're moving around a lot.
Like for instance what's called run and gun where you just walk around filming or in productions where
you want to use multiple camera angles and you might see it and one of the angles lavalier is they'll
give you more portability.
They're easy to hook up to someone and they're more versatile so you can change scenes if you zoom out
if not really an issue.
However the problem is you have rubbing noises is harder to get as good audio as a shot gun and you're
still going to get way better with a shot gun at the end of the day.
And they're they're kind of distracting.
I find that hard to actually hide.
Now another type of Mike that's worth mentioning are called us be microphone's.
Now normally I wouldn't mention USP monks but if you're going to be recording things on your laptop
like a quick video or a walkthrough then you're probably going to actually invest in an external microphone
you know what to record just in your built in mike on your computer because again like the built in
mike on your camera it sounds like crap.
Now US and the mikes are the cheapest by far of all of them.
And you can get external mikes for dollars that are decent $50 that are good and hundred dollars that
are fantastic and you probably tell right from the name that they just plug right into your USP and
then you can record directly to your computer.
Now the artist benefit of doing this as if you're recording a screencast.
Well the best place to put a mike probably on your computer where you're talking into looking at the
camera you can obviously do a screen cast and then film in a different direction like film in front
of you while you record on the computer.
In that case what you do is you just use the same thing you can use a lava leer or a shotgun.
However if you're doing more of a simple screencast will than usually the best way is just do the audio
directly in your computer using the USP microphone.