Hey guys welcome back to the chorus and the last actor we talked ad nauseum about the benefits of defining
your audience.
And there were a bunch of really good reasons why you should do this.
If I may say so myself.
So if we're going to define our audience well how exactly do we do that.
How do we determine who our ideal customer or client is.
Now your first thought might be well I want everyone to be my audience and OK.
Yeah.
There is a whole world of people out there and they all technically have money.
They could just as soon spend it on your app or service instead of shelling out money to go see another
comic book movie or buy a homemade pasta maker that they might use once and realize it's too difficult
to clean.
And then just store it in a cabinet for two years.
I've done it.
The people are willing to buy that crap then they'll buy your app right.
Well no not necessarily.
What's important here is not whether or not anyone can buy your product or service.
What's important is who would want to buy it who would use it who would pay for it.
Who would benefit from it.
Not only do these questions help you figure out who do want your product but they also help you figure
out who would want your content to.
Now it's OK to have a lot of questions here in fact but there's a really good thing.
The more questions you ask about your ideal audience the closer you can get to identifying them.
But we need to answer those questions somehow.
The bottom line is we need data we need real information in the form of numbers evidence responses anything
you get your hands on to help us paint this picture.
Well there are three types of data that we can use at the beginning.
Number one is geographic.
Number two is demographic.
Number three is psychographic.
It's a lot like a trilogy of movies that takes you deeper and deeper into the universe.
And by the end you'll understand the characters really well what they like and dislike what they do
in certain situations and who you'd want to hang out with or who you probably just avoid geographic
data.
Now the first one of the three refers to location.
It can be country region city states street address you name it.
If we know where our customers are we can plan better ways of reaching them.
And more people like them with content they'll appreciate there are issues that might affect people
in specific regions that don't matter to others.
They could be related to technology whether travel the economy politics were a mix of all of these things.
For example if we discover most of our customers are located in the Bay Area of California like myself
it might make sense to do a live event or a meet up in San Francisco or if we can see we're getting
a lot of customers in England perhaps we'll do some marketing campaign specifically for people in London.
Sports teams often focus marketing efforts on their hometown and the surrounding areas and for good
reason.
Most of their fans are located nearby.
Does it make as much sense for the Oklahoma City Thunder basketball team to create content for say the
residents of Toronto Canada.
Now you can see the examples I mentioned as just a star.
They're not fully formed ideas yet and that's because geographic data is really only one part of what
we need to define our audience.
Now the second one was demographic data and it's another type of data that can help us define our audience
demographics referred to the basic ways that marketers are.
Many of them in other industries can define and group people.
They use things like age gender marital status household income education level language that they speak
and many more things like that.
And these might sound familiar if you've ever completed a survey online or a long registration form
for something you probably answered personal questions about these pieces of data.
Now it's not hard to see how this data comes in handy for example double HRP are.
Is a nonprofit group founded to benefit retired people and anyone over the age of 50 can be a member.
So clearly art would create content for that specific age group and avoid probably writing blog posts
for millennials or teenagers for example.
Then there's.
Let's take for example Heal's dot com which.
You can guess what they sell.
They sell high heeled shoes for women.
So you can guess at their blog and video series focuses on issues most of their female customers care
about including the latest fashions shoe designs and other things I don't really know or don't read
it.
And that's also kind of the point.
I'm a guy so I'm probably not going to care about that stuff.
But for the people they're trying to target.
It works but demographic data also includes other details such as what kinds of devices people own and
use it might also define how they check their email or shop online what sites they visit and what apps
they use.
Knowing all of this gives you a lot more insight into who these people are that read your content and
buy your products data might tell us that those Oklahoma City Thunder fans I mentioned earlier might
turn out to be mostly ages 25 to 39 mostly male and use use phones more often than any other device
the access the Internet.
This makes me wonder about what content we can create specifically for them based on who they are or
if there's a way to take advantage of the fact that they use their phone so much.
Maybe I'll consider creating more video and less interactive graphics which don't work as well in phones.
So planning and creating content for an actual audience becomes a little easier when you have geographic
and demographic data in mind.
What we get from those two groups of data is a lot of numbers and facts.
This is what we call quantitative data.
These are all numbers and other measurements that get dynamically collected and displayed in dashboards
platforms and other reports.
Google Analytics.
You remember that from S.R.O.
Remember this point is a main source of quantitative data for many people because while besides being
a free tool it collects as much data as possible from web site visitors.
Now those numbers and facts are important but they're only half the picture.
They tell us who what where when and how people check out our content or made a purchase.
But they don't really tell us why.
And that's where we start talking about psychographic data.
Now psychographic data the third one that we mentioned beginningless lecture might sound like the name
of a German heavy metal band but it refers to the psychology behind our target audience.
It tells us why they do things instead of quantitative data.
It gives us the qualitative data focusing on three key aspects.
Usually it's their interest their activities and their opinions.
Let me break those three down real quick because they go a long way towards explaining why psycho graphics
are so useful.
Interest are the types of things that drive us everyday like our family our job or getting fit.
Interests are the things we're always thinking about and they kind of drive a lot like the decisions
we make.
Activities are more like hobbies or occasional things we do like taking vacations creating craft beers
becoming the best call of duty player in your squadron or clan or whatever they call it.
We take part in these activities because we enjoy them but they don't necessarily drive our everyday
decisions.
Now opinions in the case of psychographic refer to the things around us that we have opinions about.
These could be certainly things like the government human rights or let's say education but they might
also be about more specific issues like what we think about the lack of a headphone jack on our new
iPhone 7.
Or what kind of chain of coffee we prefer to go to.
If we knew this information about our audience the things they were interested in activities they participated
in and their opinions about other things we'd have a much better chance at creating content geared for
them instead of guessing that our content ideas might be a good fit.
We know there is an interest because we have psychographic data.
Ok then how do we get this psychographic data.
One way to collect it is a survey a bunch of people in your target audience.
You give them statements about relevant things and ask them if they agree with them.
Kind of like do you agree or disagree with the following statement.
Apple products have a better design than any other company.
That's an example.
You could also ask open ended questions like What's your opinion of Toyota vehicles.
And then note what people say about it.
Open ended if you're not familiar with the term.
It's a question where the answer is not just a yes or no better or worse.
It means that they have to respond in somewhat of a paragraph explaining themselves.
It's open ended because the person answering can go anywhere they want with it.
Now you can actually talk to people in real life or chat with them as well and ask them these questions.
You can also collect information through observation by following and basically stalking your users
on your Facebook page.
You could look into their lives or at least their social lives on their social network.
You might be able to see things like number one.
What do they say about your product service or company.
Do they like it.
Do they hate it.
Do they cite lots of problems or offer help and solutions other customers.
Number two you might find out what kind of content they themselves post.
Is it fun that instructional pictures are mostly text or is it only videos that you might find out.
What sites or influencers do they frequently reference or share a post from.
So really you have three options you can ask questions your customer is sitting out something like a
survey or just asking them or you can try talking to your customers either through a live chat option
or right after they buy something you email them or you can just observe people look at their Facebook
page look at the stats you see on Google Analytics trying to go and see how your customers behave out
in the wild.
If you can collect psychographic data about your audience who will be much better positioned to create
content that's more focused like highlighting features.
You know people care about because of their interest or writing about issues you know people have strong
opinions on.
But now what do you do if you don't have any customers yet or just say enough data to know anything
for sure.
Well if you can't define a current audience you can define the audience you want to have.
Think of a competitor or a Web site you want to be like and then research them instead.
Or you can even think of a Web site where you think your product or service would be a perfect match
on.
Maybe they don't compete necessarily.
They could easily see what you're doing showing up on their site.
Let's say for example you built an app that combines recipe lists shopping lists and Amazon Prime.
Making it crazy easy to pick a recipe click a button and then get all the ingredients you need liver
to your house.
Maybe this makes sense because hey blister hard and nobody likes to shop.
So people who check out recipe Web sites might be interested in an app like this.
In this case the audience that visits the recipe Web site let's say serious Edes Dotcom for example
could be the exact type of audience that you want.
Now if only you could look at serious Edes Dotcom's data and see who these people were.
Well put that Web site you can but you have to use a market research website to do it information about
every site isn't always publicly available but you can create a free account on a market research site
like Quantcast dot com and find data on some of the biggest sites around.
Shows a long list of detailed reports on traffic demographics geographic data interest and more on the
sites that they can measure.
I think a clock cast kind of like Google Analytics for someone else's web site not your website.
Serious Edes dot com which you can see here pull it up on the screen just happens to be one of those
sites.
So what data can you see about serious Edes.
Well there are a whole bunch of categories and indexes telling you the specific information about the
Web site visitors the site gets mostly U.S. visitors which you can see at the top.
Demographics is next and if you click on composition you can see the data for serious each Dotcom's
actual visitors.
Slightly more female than male mostly in their 20s and 30s.
However if you can click on index you can see if the site appeals to certain types of demographics more
than the average web site.
In this case serious eeds has a larger concentration of 25 to 34 year olds and college graduates than
the average web site and especially users of Asian descent.
Whatever reason as you keep scrolling down you'll find other insights that could be helpful.
But 70 percent of Web site visits are mobile.
So whatever you create better be mobile friendly under shopping interests and packaged goods.
You can see a higher index of interest in baby related products so we probably have a group of moms
and dads visiting the site and there's interest in other food and recipe related websites like say save
your doc.
I hope I said that right.
Lucky Peach dot com and Splendid Table dot org.
Discovering this we can research a few more Web sites and see the type of content they produce for the
same audience.
So what do you do with all this market research data.
Record the interesting pieces of data like the items we found and make it available to anyone else who
helps create your content or even markets and sell your products.
This data can help you make decisions about what to create or avoid.
However discovering that you have let's say like a lot of Asian readers for example doesn't mean you
should only cater to that group specifically what data like this means is that when the opportunity
to present content relevant to that user group comes up it makes sense to try it but not necessarily
to only do that with so much data is so many different forms the demographics the geographics and the
psycho graphics.
It would really help to put everything into an easy to use convenient kind of package wouldn't it.
Well our next step will be to take this data and turn it into something useful to help us come up with
ideas and content what we call a user persona.
All right we'll cover that in the next lecture and I'll see if.