Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
So how is it that a new company gets customers?
Well, I mean, every company on the planet has started
out at some moment in time with zero customers.
So how did they go from zero to the first one, and then
to their first hundred, and then their first thousand?
In this lecture, I'm going explain how virtually all
businesses start out getting their customers and
how we're going to use that exact
model as a guide for this course.
Now, I'm sure all of you know someone that has started,
let's say, a small business, and I mean started, not
inherited, not bought, started from scratch. And yes,
we are technically talking about people like Richard
Branson and Donald Trump,
who did start their businesses,
but, I mean, they started it with a couple hundred million
dollars in inheritance, which tends to make things easier.
Let's use the example of a normal person
that has started an online clothing shop.
Let's say he likes to design clothes,
so it was a natural fit for him.
When you look at that business from an outsider's
perspective, it appears that they are doing several
large things that get them customers.
Maybe they're buying and designing magazine
ads, maybe they're putting out flyers,
maybe he has sponsorship somewhere, etc.
What you need to understand is that you are looking
at this business as it is today, and what it's doing
today to get customers is almost never
the way it got customers when it first started.
It's very, very rarely the case that you'll see someone
conceptualize a business and then just go all in
with full blown marketing.
I would say you've never seen a brand
new startup make, say, a Super Bowl ad,
but I'm sure Silicon Valley has
plenty of embarrassing examples.
Or I guess I should say you very rarely see
successful businesses that do that.
When your friend started his clothing shop, he didn't
write those magazine ads on day one, he didn't pump
out the flyers by the hundreds.
He probably did things that were much, much
smaller, and required more manual effort.
And this is no different for you.
Your business will go through distinct phases where
you get your customers from different sources, means,
and different strategies.
But the one thing that ties all of these phases
together is this lovely graph. Enter the all-knowing
graph of business growthdom.
Now, this is a way of understanding all of the marketing
strategies you're going to learn in this course.
Some strategies are going to be low effort, uncomplex,
and as a result only get you a few customers,
and then some strategies are going to be really hard,
really complex, long term, but if done right
will get you a metric ton of customers.
What you need to understand is this:
all entrepreneurs start small
and over time get complex. When you first start out
with your business, you will not have a great idea
who exactly your customers are, what they want to hear,
if your product is great or only meh, if your page is
optimized, if you're even going to be profitable. And
this uncertainty means you need to try to preserve
your resources and test the waters a little bit
before you jump right in. To do this,
you're going to focus on manual strategies, and
that's everything we're going to do in section 1.
It's also known as "Your first 10 customers." After
you've gotten your first 10 customers, a little more
feedback, a better, but not fantastic understanding of what
people are responding to, how to angle your messaging,
you move up the chart and start some mid-term strategies.
This is what we do in the next section.
We focus on strategies that are still pretty easy,
but will get you a hundred customers if done right.
They're also less manual and generally
more complex, but only slightly.
Then you can pretty much guess
where I'm going with this.
We now have more data,
we know roughly how popular our product is,
what are the major consistent complaints from
customers, how to match their needs after they use the
product. You're going to start going for more long term
strategies at this point, and that is our section 3.
It's "Getting your 500." Finally, we'll move on to phase number
four, where we know decently well what we are working
with, and we have the confidence to spend a large
amount of time on some more long term strategies.
These are the strategies that carry you from
the 500 to the thousand plus and beyond.
There really is no end in scope
for these strategies, if done well.
These are kind of the end all be all.
You can support these long term growth strategies
at this point because you will, you know, have cash
from the previous strategies. Over time, you'll add
complexity, effort, and a more long term focus to your
customer acquisition strategies.
That's how you minimize risk, lower how much money
out-of-pocket you have to pay, and quite frankly, make
sure that you have a tight well-oiled machine that's
ready for thousands of customers, and you won't
have any major surprises when you actually
go out there and get a big surge in traffic.
So that's exactly how our course works. Four phases,
four different types of strategies that fit on this continuum.
Now, I know some of you might be saying "I don't want to do
manual strategies if I'm just going to get rid of them later.
manual strategies if I'm just going to get rid of them later."
"That doesn't scale." Well,
as it turns out, businesses that refuse to do these
manual grunt work strategies in the beginning of
their business are something like
five times more likely to fail.
There's actually an article attached in the resources,
I strongly suggest reading it, it's from Paul Graham, the founder
of Y Combinator, called "Do things that don't scale."
You can kind of guess what he says.
In the next lecture,
let's hit on a quick concept about growth that will help
you understand how these later strategies work together.
All right, see you then.