Hey guys welcome back to the course.
All right.
So last lecture I talked to you about a whole bunch of different types of videos you might be able to
create necessarily a variety you can choose from.
You can make explainer videos you can make your kids you can make product demos walk through customer
video testimonials are actually quite a bit.
Really cool things about the different types of video marketing content you can make is that each one
can help you reach different goals.
Now which goals am I talking about.
Well they're very similar to the goals we talked about in our content strategy lecture.
But here's a quick reminder.
Whatever industry your and your business is going to have many of the same goals that other businesses
do.
One of these goals is to increase your customer base.
You always want more customers coming in and checking you out.
Now that's usually achieved through what we call brand awareness.
We create content to make people aware of us.
We let people know we exist.
We explain who we are and what we do.
Now the more awareness we have the better our chances of being noticed by the audience we're trying
to reach out there.
Our common goal is increasing customer satisfaction so your customers will stick around longer.
The recommended to friends and they'll trust you when you've got happy customers you'll get a lot of
brand engagement.
That means they'll engage with your posts and other content by liking them commenting on them and sharing
them.
The more engagement we get the better our chances are reaching more people and understanding what they
want.
And then of course there's the goal to make more money.
Whether that's by selling products or getting people to sign up for services.
So when people take those actions of buying something signing up for something or completing a task
that's important to us that's a conversion we can measure and that's another key goal for businesses
generating conversions.
So when we talk about content in general and why we're creating it because we want to try and work towards
those three types of goals building brand awareness increasing engagement and generating conversions.
Now you should be able to create any type of content and reach these goals and yes video can help you
accomplish that as well.
So let me tell you how first that we have the goals of brand awareness.
Now how can video help us reach those goals.
Well in order to build awareness you need to create videos that are not only interesting but that people
want to share.
We want to get our video in front as many eyeballs as possible.
So with a goal to build awareness we're not necessarily looking to create something long and detailed.
We want to create something short and powerful and worth sharing.
You could create 30 second ads that promote your product or even something as long as two minutes where
you show your product in action.
Ultimately these videos are helping you create a first impression.
So if you look professional sound good and people should be excited to share it.
To measure our effectiveness here we'll want to see as many video views and shares as possible.
The more the merrier.
So that brand awareness getting more people aware of the fact that you exist.
Now what about increasing engagement through videos.
No engagement is usually measured through the number of likes or favorites your video gets as well as
things like comments.
Now this is a step up from someone just watching your video.
It's an additional action they take that shows they found your video interesting in some way.
The more engagement you get the more you'll understand which of your videos are really engaging your
audience.
But in other words engagement is a way to measure video quality.
And if you can generate more comments in particular you increase your chances of building some kind
of community within your audience.
Videos that feature people speaking naturally in them you know Blake in a conversational type way are
pretty good at generating comments if you can create that feeling where it's like you're speaking to
the audience through the video and they feel like it's personal.
One on one experience they'll be more willing to comment when you ask questions or ask for their feedback
in the video.
Comments are always a great way to help understand how people are feeling and what they're thinking
about.
So if you want increase engagement you'll want to produce videos that are a lot less advertising and
a lot more delivery of value.
Maybe you're talking people through a process giving them a walkthrough of how something works or it
could be a video where you're discussing a concept and it leads to you asking some open ended questions
to see what your viewers think.
Whatever is value is going to be the key here.
All right so we talking about using video to build brand awareness and increase engagement so that leaves
us with just the last one which is how do you use video to create more conversions while video can be
great for this as well but it helps to know which types of conversions you're talking about.
Sometimes a conversion is a pretty simple one for example maybe you won't increase the subscribers on
your YouTube channel.
Well when someone watches your video on YouTube all they have to do is subscribers just press a button
near you that says subscribe.
It's like a red button.
An easy way to make this happen is just to ask nicely.
That's why if you watch YouTube it is out there you'll notice that many of them make the same call out
at the end of each video.
Hey if you like this video please subscribe and then yada yada yada.
And by the way that's why we call those buttons the call to action you're calling upon people to take
action.
Shocker.
Yes I know we covered this last section.
Other times other conversion you might want is a purchase or some other call to action that takes place
on your Web site.
You can still use video in this case if you want to generate sales of a product or video showing that
product makes a lot of sense.
Show how that looks how easy it is to use how fast it works.
Even if it's you might want a highlight.
You can show these in the video even if your product is a cloud based platform or an app.
You can still create screencast that show the same thing how cool it looks how easy is the use how fast
it is.
You get the idea kind of covered that last lecture with the walkthrough videos.
Now each of these product videos though don't leave your audience hanging.
Make sure they understand how to get your product whether you tell them which store to go to which website
to visit or which button to push.
If you're trying to get sign ups or something give your viewer access to whatever form they need to
complete.
Hopefully your great video explaining how awesome your service is on the same page right next to the
forum.
People need to complete theoretically.
Now some video services like with idea of a feature where you can add a simple email form in your video
so people can watch the video and complete the conversion right there.
Either way I keep this in mind the conversion you want your viewer to complete needs to be clear and
obvious and easy to get to.
So your video can communicate the benefits of taking whatever action is necessary.
You have a better chance of generating more conversions.
All right got the idea.
Different kinds of videos can definitely help you better when you have different goals in mind.
So you can consider those types of various videos we've talked about in the last lecture adds explainers
product.
When I was inside and connect them to the different types of goals we talked about in this lecture because
awareness engagement and conversions can absolutely be achieved through video content.
Okay that's all for now.
I'll see you next lecture.