Hey guys welcome back to the chorus.
OK we're nearly done with our content strategy series.
I promise.
Now we just talked about how to figure out if your content is working and using measurement and metrics
to discover which content pieces are doing well and which ones not so much.
Well even now after your content has been published and got some results your job still is not done.
It's like that last movie in The Lord Of The Rings trilogy.
You know if you like that ending well you'll love this ending as well.
And then this ending.
Yeah.
We're not done yet.
There's another strategy you should always be thinking about as you're creating a piece of content especially
after it's been published and that's how to repurpose it repurpose in content and means finding a new
place and or a new function for your content.
In other words you can use what you've created somewhere else with very little effort and basically
create something new out of something all.
And this is what we're going to talk about in this lecture.
Let's say you write a killer blog post in the top five reasons Wordpress is the best platform for new
bloggers.
You've done your research cited some data maybe added some screenshots.
It's a post you believe has value for the beginners out there.
When you repurpose content you could either reformat the entire piece for a different channel or you
could clip out an excerpt a specific value and post or share just that.
But you might be asking well if I made such a great blog post in the first place why bother repurposing
anything.
Shouldn't that be all I need to do.
And don't I want to drive people to that one piece of content while repurposing is really about extending
the value of that original piece.
If that content has value it makes sense to milk it for as much as you can get out of it for all the
hard work done after you've written it with different formats you might reach new people who just didn't
want to read a blog post or are more happy to say watch a video made with that same original stuff.
And your audience members will be found in different places so publishing in only one place means those
people who really live on other platforms might miss out.
So let's say for that five reasons to use Wordpress blog we just talked about.
You could turn it into a video where you deliver everything on camera.
Maybe mixed in some visuals and then you post that instead on YouTube.
You could turn it into let's say an info graphic with big bold graphics and share it on your blog or
some infographics friendly platform like Linked In or even Pinterest.
You could reword it into an answer on Quora.
Look for a question where someone asks what beginners should use to start a blog and then reformat your
words so they can work as an answer.
Now keep in mind this is not a cut and paste job but also it really should not take you as long to just
reword the material as it would to just write it from scratch.
I'd generally like to think of it kind of like an 80:20 you wrote the original post that took 80 percent
of the effort.
Now you just need a little bit of 20 percent to then spread it from one spot to potentially 15.
So there are a few options for repurposed you create images or a slideshow and put it on Instagram.
You take the quotes or images and you can post on Facebook or Twitter.
You even combine a post with others and create an e-book available for download on your site like a
chef in a kitchen full of ingredients.
It's up to you to decide what to make.
If you repurpose content though you want to consider a different format or platform it promises some
opportunity.
That is if none of your customers or your audience really like videos or hang out on YouTube.
Well then repurchasing your content into the video format.
Just talked about probably doesn't make a lot of sense.
How do you know what platforms your audience uses.
Well that just comes back to doing your basic demographic research your basic Geographic and your basic
psychographic.
You can always just ask them.
That's very common.
Ask them Do you have a link.
Do you watch YouTube when you want to find something out.
Do you Google it.
Or do you search on Google or do you ask someone in general look for places or content types that appeal
to your audience where they hang out online.
What content types are performed well for you before if generally post a blog that was a video to begin
with and it didn't do well you probably guessed that repurposing your stuff and sticking it on video
on YouTube doesn't have as much promise as something else.
Look to your measurements and your metrics and even your social media analytics to see if you can spot
some trends you might discover that certain posts really engaged people and that can lead to some ideas
on how to repurpose your stuff.
Now you might discover that it's easier to share a piece of your original content of reformatting the
whole thing.
That's definitely an option.
Also worth considering in your five reasons use Wordpress blog post.
You could take the five reasons and then make a short video or graphic listing of the reasons but leave
out the best details.
For example here are the five reasons but if you want to learn why these reasons are important or how
to use these your advantage and follow the link in the original blog post.
Not only are you repurposing your content in situation but you're also really promoting it.
Some other easy ways to repurpose pieces of content are to share key statements or quotes key pieces
of data or graphs or screenshots or video excerpts whatever pieces you share.
Make sure you always focus on promising value and driving people back to your original blog post or
piece of content.
So consider what other platforms people will use to look for the value offer or where Ask questions
that need to be answered.
Remember that you might have spent a great deal of time researching and drafting and perfecting your
content so it deserves some extra attention and promotion.
Or maybe you didn't spend a lot of time creating it at all it doesn't matter.
Value is value right.
If it's good you need to get it out there in different places in different spaces so that's it guys
repurpose your content and make the most of what you've created.
Next up we're going to start talking about video marketing how to market specifically video content
and how that differs from everything else.
All right guys I'll see you then.