All right here we are back again talking about adverts in our last lecture.
We went through the first steps of setting up a campaign.
But now we're at the point where we need to consider the money.
How much do we want to set for a budget and what kind of good strategy do we want to use.
One of the first things to do is figure out how much you can afford to spend on advertising to begin
with PPC again pay per click with say 100 times you'll be paying every time someone clicks your AD.
So let's take this scenario and just do a little math.
Let's say you want to do an ad to increase sales of a product.
So let's say it's the I don't know the smart scooter with Wi-Fi that's built into the tracks how far
you scoot every day somewhat cool every time you sell your smart scooter.
Let's just say you make 20 bucks in profit.
Yes I know you probably make more on the smart scooter but don't whatever you have a page set up on
your site where you sell the smart scooter.
And according to your stats the conversion rate on the page is let's say 2 percent like two out of every
hundred people who come to the website end up buying it.
So with that in mind ask yourself how much would you be willing to pay Google to make a sale.
Do you make $20 with each sale of a smart scooter.
Are you cool giving Google let's say four dollars or where you go say a 20 percent cut.
How about $6 or 30 percent cut.
The more you're willing to give Google the more you can afford to pay per click.
If you do some basic math you can figure out the amount to spend on adverts at least for cases where
you're trying to drive direct sales multipole your profit per sale by your conversion rate.
Then by the percentage you're willing to give Google not to say the percentage want to get Google but
really it's like how much can you possibly spare to make this worth it.
You know your costs right.
You know it's time and effort went into doing this.
So now in our case let's just do that formula.
That's Tony Ahlers times 2 percent or point O2 going to do a multiplication.
Then you multiply that by let's say the 30 percent cut that we're find getting to Google.
So that is Times point 3 Tony box Times point 0 2 times Point 3 is 12 cents.
So in this case you be willing to spend 12 cents per click to increase sales of your smart Skooter now
might not sound like a lot but when you think of the number of clicks you might need to generate a sale
on the page you're 2 percent conversion rate.
In this case it can add up if you don't set a limit.
Now that's where your budget comes in.
And since you did this math already you can figure out a place to start.
So let's say you're willing to spend 12 cents per click and you want to try this out for say two weeks
or 14 days.
Well if you got say 25 clicks a day it would add up or multiply up 35 clicks a day times 14 all at 350
clicks in total.
Now multiply 350 total clicks times your 12 cents per click and you just got a total campaign budget
that's about $42.
Not bad I guess.
Now how many sales would you get with those 350 total clicks Well multiply those clicks by your conversion
rate of 2 percent and all the answers about 7 7 sales.
So with all your numbers hold true especially your conversion rate and keep in mind guys it constantly
fluctuates and it changes.
This is something you might not even know right now.
Then by the end of two weeks you'll have to spend $42 or less to hopefully generate seven sales of your
smart scooter.
Now seven sales while you make 20 bucks each.
That's a total profit of $140 than minus $42 so you owe Google.
So basically it's like like a hundred dollars in profit.
Now the important part here is that you need to have the information to guide your budgeting.
If you know things like how much you make per sale and the conversion rate on the page where you'll
be sending people well then you can very easily put yourself in a position where you could budget your
advertising pretty effectively.
Now of course this is never it's never that simple.
Now you might have a conversion rate they established before that conversion rate might be based off
as zero or on our Facebook.
Now it's not the case that it's always this straightforward.
In fact it's usually got other layers of complications with it.
So let's say you thought your conversion was 2 percent.
Well what does that actually based off of a you could be 2 percent of SEO traffic converts.
Well as the traffic is going to be different than your at the Emerald sites like Facebook or shares
or something like that you kind of have to use it as a guide but then immediately adjust and say Actually
my ads are converting at this percentage now it could be higher because people are knowingly clicking
something because they know they want to buy something or it can be lower because people just don't
trust ads as much.
Now might be a good time to review your own numbers and plug them into that equation that we had before.
How much profit per sale times your conversion rate on your page.
Your best guess at your conversion rate times how much you're willing to give away to Google to make
this worth it.
So now I know we've covered some of the math to help you prep for this bidding adventure.
Let's jump back over to Google Adwords and that first screen where we were setting up our campaign.
We're looking at good strategy now if you click it you'll see two categories.
Automated bid strategies and manual with manual and you decide exactly how much your bid will be and
set your budget per day.
The automated bid strategies allow Google to change your bid pending on what kind of goal you're trying
to achieve target search page location means you want to get to the top of the search ranking page specifically
target CPA will place bids to try to get you the most conversions possible.
You actually pay per the conversion not per click but the cost per conversion will be higher.
We probably won't actually cover that in this course because it requires a lot more.
You have to really set this one up and again if you knew how many people would come to your page and
how many would convert then why wouldn't you just just do it based off of clicks.
So why don't you just say I'll pay this much for a click.
Now there's also oftens recreating ads simply to outrank ads from another domain.
They want to battle a competitor for the Arpey turf.
Go for it.
Then of course there are often you simply maximize clicks and maximize conversions.
All of this depends on what you're trying to accomplish.
Keep in mind some of these are budget conscious like you just say don't ever go over this budget and
then some of them are just going to focus on getting you the most traffic.
So if you just knew that you are a wide range you could pay well then maybe you go for that.
And that would give you a lot more growth sooner.
Now in our case we're trying to increase sales of our smart scooter so we could go to the manual strategy
route or try an automated option like the maximize conversions for example.
Now if you already have conversion tracking set up on your site well you could try this out conversion
tracking is actually some you set up and Google Analytics and it communicates directly with Google AdWords.
It's the same company and same system.
Now let's just assume are really new at all of this and just go with that manual option.
So all we have to do is tell it our default bid and our budget per day.
Remember how we talked about running a campaign for 14 days and maybe spending let's say $42 in total.
Well $42 divided by 14 days is you do the math about $3 a day.
So we could use that $3 as our daily budget and $3.
I don't obviously suggest it's not really enough to make this work but OK go for it.
Now you can go higher if you want to see how it goes.
It's all up to you.
I think I'm personally going to go higher because why not are smart Skooter is worth it.
Let's see $5 a day.
But our default bit.
Let's start with 50 cents.
Now it's more than 12 cents.
We you know figured out before but for the purpose of our example let's just start with a round number
and let's just see how it does.
So we've done this whole example with the assumption that we're selling a product and doing advertising
to increase sales.
Your goal and specifics will be different.
You might want to drive traffic to a page to get e-mail newsletter registration through a form not a
sale but a different kind of conversion.
But e-mails obviously don't generate money like a sale.
So how much is that going to be worth it to you.
In most cases what people do is you run it to a page you sign up for an e-mail newsletter and then they
give you a drip of e-mails over a long period of time and they know how many people who sign up.
Eventually we'll buy on that process and that's usually going to be higher than people who go on your
page and clicking buy.
So how much would a 100 sign ups be worth.
Well you'd have to run this test beforehand to know that number then obviously how many clicks would
it take to get those 100 sign ups.
This is why it takes a little bit of time to get the OEM machine running smoothly.
Now if you don't know things like conversion rate or dollar amounts well it'll make it tougher to figure
out your budget for ads.
So then what's the number you're willing to spend to try to see if this works at all and to get your
baseline numbers.
If all else fails pick a total dollar amount you're just comfortable with in general.
And then just go with that.
So the last piece on this page is the ad extensions part.
This part is interesting because it deals with some extra Google features you can have a peer with your
and if they apply to you.
Number one if you have a physical location you can check off the location box and Google will display
an address and phone number for your store.
Pretty nice if you expect people to look for someone like you while they're out shopping.
Number two if you have specific pages on your site that would help a customer better understand your
product or service.
Well you can check off the site links box filings or those extra links Google sometimes ads below your
link on the search engine page that leads to important sections or pages of your site.
Now it's up to you.
You can add something that makes sense for you.
For example if you were searching for let's say a server power system well you'd see IBM ad listed at
the top with site links below it.
That's a site link and then lastly number three if you have a phone number you want to include with
your ad click the call box and will that at it.
If you're comfortable taking phone calls and doing direct sales well then it might be the case that
you can up your conversion rate significantly.
So once you reach this point well you set your bid strategy you've set your daily budget your bid amount
if it was necessary and you checked all the other options.
Now once you flip all the switches on this page the next one will be all about creating your ad groups.
And for that info sadly you'll have to tune into our next lecture.
Right CNN.