All right, guys, welcome back.
So we've been discussing the term PR throughout
this section of the course, talking about what the deal
is with reporters and other members of the press.
Well, when you hear the term PR, now you might think
of press releases, and that's really the old school
way of getting coverage for your company. The
way it used to work and still somewhat does work
now is that you'd probably hire a press agency or a PR
firm who would work with you to write up an official
press release, those releases then would be written
using strict templates, and dates, and names, and a
lot of boilerplate text, or blurbs of information that
would be included every time, like your company
mission, your product description, and other official filler.
Then the agency would send out this release through
its official channels to newspapers, magazines, any
other journalists who ask for it, as well as personal contacts
they have with people they might think are interested in it.
Now, that's how it used to work
pretty much all the time. You have a story, you make
a press release, you try to get someone to pick up
that press release, and you might work with an agency.
Nowadays, you do still see press releases.
However, they're usually going to be used by larger
companies when, let's say, a new CEO comes in.
For instance, Udemy has a new CEO.
They release a press release.
They're not actively going after people trying to get
this covered in the press or in outlets or in blogs,
but they do want to have the first say and provide
all the information, should anyone want to cover it.
Now, one reason reporters used to like press releases
is that they were basically pre-written stories.
Reporters could take them word for word and then
publish them as stories in their newspaper or wherever.
A lot of them did. It used to
work that you had wires and so journalists or reporters
would listen to the wires, which would come from
things like, you know, the Associated Press, or like,
Reuters, and these companies would send updates, and
then journalists would just comb through these press releases
or these updates and then pick what they wanted to cover.
Now, I'm sure you can see the problem though with
this method of distributing information, especially with
the age of the internet and mobile technology that
we now live in. Old school style press releases and
that method of disseminating information
just doesn't really work as well anymore.
And I can think of a few reasons why. Number one,
thanks to technology, anyone can publish content online
now, so the need for an agency to help spread your
information for us isn't really needed for a lot of companies.
Number two is official press releases
are traditionally really boring.
I mean, they're written to communicate facts and information.
If reporters copy press releases verbatim into a
story on their site, well, they might be the first to
post something, but the result is lazy
and it would be really repetitive if
other reporters did the same thing
with the same information.
Now, today's audiences are looking for relevance in
addition to the facts, and audiences want reporters
to give it to them.
The third reason is that traditional press
releases are written from one point of view.
Again, they just communicate facts,
but reporters have their own opinion,
style, and angles they prefer.
Remember, we talked about those in the last couple
of lectures, well, press releases might offer some basic
information, but reporters will have their own questions
about what things mean for their readers, why it
matters, and so on.
And the last reason I would say is because press
releases are kind of, it kind of reminds me of like, inbound
versus outbound marketing.
Press releases are an outbound effort, where you
make a press release and you just throw it out there
and hope someone picks it up.
Well, unfortunately, there's too many people trying
to write about too many things to be that passive.
Nowadays, you have to actually go after people, pitch
them specifically, and make sure that they say yes or no.
I wish it was the case that you could just write a press release, what you wanted everyone to say about you, publish it somewhere,
and then sit back and just watch the press
roll in, but it doesn't work that way anymore.
So press releases are no longer the way
to get information out to the press.
How do we do it now?
Well, today, the process of getting coverage is
about getting to know the people with audiences,
people like reporters, bloggers, and more, and then
pitching those people individually your ideas. In 99%
of the cases, you'd do it through email, you literally
will email them, try to get their attention,
try to get them to agree that this is an interesting idea.
Oftentimes you'll pitch them a headline, oftentimes
you'll just write an article and send it to them in hope
they say "I like it." Now, rather than allow some
agency to write material and send it out as needed,
you prepare the information yourself with
specific members of the media in mind.
Now, instead of waiting for people to pick up on what
you provided through a press release, you actively
target and approach reporters with something relevant
to them and their audience. As we talked about,
reporters need all the help they
can get finding good story ideas,
so pitching them your idea is a way to help them
and help yourself. But pitching is not a secret tactic.
You can pretty much assume everyone out there like
yourself with an app to promote or a product to sell
is thinking and doing the same thing, they're looking for
reporters and writers and people with an audience
and trying to get those people to write about them.
Some reporters get dozens of pitches a week, while
other more high profile ones will get hundreds a day.
So how can you break through the noise?
Well, this is what we're going to get
into in the next part of this section,
four steps for finding, researching,
contacting, and pitching reporters.
By the end of it, you'll have a decent idea for where
to look, what to do, and how to pitch yourself.
It's really all about seizing on the three or four seconds
they will afford you and your e-mail and doing
the best you can with it.
Sound good?
OK.
See you in the next lecture.