Hazor Welcome back and we've been talking about how to create a landing page.
Last actually took us through the basics of what you need to prepare and create.
Now I want to take you through a solution that could be useful for a lot of landing page needs you might
have to actually create the landing page.
You either need web design and development skills or you can go the easy route.
Pretty much everybody does and use an online tool and there's a lot of it.
There's a bunch of landing page solutions out there.
Now two of the good ones I've seen are on bounce and lead pages.
Now there's a lot of them out there and everybody kind of has their own preference.
You guys come from the MVP course where we used launch rock n Alternatively use Kickoff labs but then
we use insta page launch for our kickoff labs are really simple pages.
They don't give you a lot of control and it's not generally something I would use for a webinars or
a lead magnet you want to do something a little more robust insta page.
It's kind of expensive.
It's like $70 a month but it pretty much gives you all the tools you need.
Any idiot can put together one of these pages.
There are other ones of course there's like and bounce and there's lead pages.
I believe they both have 30 day trials.
I think they're both kind of the same thing that and like the 70 or 100 dollars a month range.
And there's also lander which is a 14 day trial but they have a smaller feature set and at the end of
the day I think they're a little bit cheaper.
Lander's easy if you don't need to do anything super complex.
What general advice though is just look at their templates instead to see if you like what the templates
are and then you know check out their videos and demos to see how easy the interface looks and then
just consider the specific needs you have.
They're all pretty much the same thing.
They might all have different techniques for doing the same stuff.
So just look at the template to see which ones you like the best and see which one things is the most
straightforward.
If you have a lot of time to spend old and tackle unbalances the most complicated one.
But if you aren't trying to make something super complicated and maybe you just use lander on any page
platform like these generally makes sense for promoting an e-book or white paper because you can you
know send an email to whoever signs up at the link to the document they want.
Really easy to do.
Promoting a seminar you might consider using the registration features inside whatever platform you're
going to use to do the web or like any meeting is a good one or zoom as another example for e-mail of
course courses you should probably look at autoresponder features from places maybe like a Weber which
is one of the ones I've seen recommended the most for e-mail courses.
Those are the most straightforward.
I mean you can also do it with like MailChimp and pretty much any other email marketing tool.
Personally I like a lever whatever solution you use at some point you'll probably have to design your
landing page.
So since we are symbol all of that copying important info from the last lecture while we're in decent
shape really now is just putting it together.
So it's a landing page solution to try and I'm going to pick lander which doesn't require a credit card.
And like I said it's the easiest one to get in and get out of.
So go to the lander app dot com and just click the try lander for free button below.
Enter your name email phone and create a password if you guys only want to do that.
You can use companies like privacy or a buying tool called blur.
And what these can do can give you fake email addresses.
The zone called throttle.
They give you auto venerated email addresses so that you can unsubscribe very easily to the emails they
send to you and you don't have to give out your actual e-mail case you're afraid of it being sold.
Anyway check those out.
Throttle privacy and Ablin are ones that you won't want to check out.
They'll send you an activation email that all you do is just click on that link in the e-mail.
Now back on the site well you'll need to choose a folder name for all your landing pages so just put
I don't know what your business name then click the new landing page icon up on the left.
So we'll just jump in here with the landing page using info we put together in our last lecture.
We'll give our new page a name I'll call mine.
Oh how to design a great logo ebook.
Then click next.
Now we'll see a whole bunch of templates you can use.
Now the simple categories are pretty much made for exactly what we're doing.
We have one called webinars and events which is going to come in pretty handy or we don't have ones
like products and services and that's that's probably what I'm going to use for my ebook webinars are
made specifically for webinars.
My thing is technically a product go product.
Now you try to find something similar to what you roughed up in your document but browse through and
see what you like.
The way I do it is I just look for which one looks the closest the way I see it in my head and that's
how I figure.
OK.
Well this one's willing to take five steps to get to where I want as opposed to this one which would
take a lot of modification of the colors and images and text and things like that.
But keep that in mind.
You can change colors images and fonts and really do whatever you want.
So it's really up to you.
So you know I'm just you know she is the first template here which I can preview by clicking the double
arrow button in the upper right corner.
Looks good also like that template and it the create button in the lower right and it takes me to the
Editor page.
Now you've got a lot of flexibility here.
You want to change anything just double click it you mess anything up all there is an undo button.
Looks like an arrow pointing left and it's in the upper left corner.
Now every landing page platform is going to be different.
But generally I think you'll find they a lot like this.
So let's put this to work.
Let's open up a Google doc or wherever that information input is and let's just copy and paste everything
into the roughly the appropriate spots.
First I'll copy my headline go back to Landauer to look look the headline into the template and then
paste in the text window that shows up below.
Now you might have to play with the fonts and sizes.
Get it right.
But that's basically the process does take some tweaking because they have bugs but they all have bugs.
But OK I see that another ten minutes.
Anyway once you start working on the template you might decide some things aren't needed on the page.
One of the first things I do is I just start deleting sections I don't want.
Now you can easily click the X box to get rid of that section.
Maybe you'll see a trash icon.
Other design platforms is usually kind of the same thing as you get it.
You might have to move some things around so they fit.
You can also drag and drop items from the toolbar on the right.
Explore it a bit and you'll see it's got some nice features.
One of those things is your form which you can find under the advanced part of the toolbar on the right
so click and drag that over.
And for our forum we're asking for a name and email you just check off the fields you want.
You can change what the button says you can change the color.
It's really up to you.
Just remember to make your form button nice and bright.
Remember that people don't miss it as you're editing click the save button in the upper left at any
time to save your progress.
I don't think Lander automatically does it.
Some of them automatically do it.
Insta page does not say if you exit out you are screwed anyway so once you're happy with what you have
hit that preview button to check out what it's going to look like.
This is of course after some finagling and some moving around but if you did all the stuff in your google
doc first really you just plug and play.
Now the page should come up and you'll see what it looks like.
If you're ready to launch this thing then just click Finish in the upper right and then you'll have
the landing page dashboard.
You'll see the name of your page and that you are aware of will be.
Now lender allows you to change your L if you want so you can use your own domain.
I strongly suggest generally it looks kind of weird when it's the name of your company.
Daut need pages of COM.
It kind of looks a little easy.
Although some marketing companies will do that because they just seem all the people setting up Erny
know what lead pages is.
I just suggest make your own.
Just make your own domain.
Now I've already have a domain you can just do it from your domain.
Slash the name of a landing page or you can go buy a new domain for this.
I generally go with the second but it's really up to you.
So on the dashboards page the most important feature that you can hit is it going to the published bottom
to the top to make that page live.
So click the arrow next to the publish button to see your live page.
Olah again many landing page platforms have similar features but the basic process I shared with you
really works the best.
Prepare all that information first completely agnostic of the design know what copy and images you want
to use what details you need to have prepare and then just use a template and a design feature inside
the landing page provided to make everything fit.
I don't generally like to change these pages a ton because they put a lot of research into their templates
so they know these templates work.
The more you screw with that the farther you kind of move away from the proven science.
Now once you've got a design you like or view your page before you launch it just remember our tips
from the earlier lectures about making sure your page is clear providing all the details your visitors
will need.
Making your form friendly and your call to action obvious.
I generally like to go through a checklist and just look through it.
The color action is easy to find.
It's immediately obvious what this is does it match my aunt as my headline.
Immediately explain what the value of the magnet is.
Now after you launch your landing page make sure to watch the stats you get how well is your page converting.
Now you might decide to test out an alternate design such as a page with a different headline for example.
No landing page software let you do what are called split tests or Abts where you can see which works
best you can get more leads.
The general process behind that is let's say you made a page you launch it and you don't like the conversion
rate so you might go back and let's say you changed the headline.
Make that a separate A-B test run it and then see which one tests better.
The one that test better.
Well there you go.
Now you have a better headline then what you can do is systematically go and start editing more and
more things.
Generally speaking try to only change one major thing at a time you change two things and it improves
or gets worse.
You don't know which one caused it anyway so there you go.
Now that we've discussed how to create landing pages Let's discuss some of the different lead magnets
you can create to generate that interest and those leads will start that discussion in the next lecture.
I'll see you then.