Hey guys, welcome back.
Quick lecture here before we go on to scouting out the subs
we've selected. Reddit unfortunately is really, really distracting,
and so if you're trying to optimize your time,
then you really need to streamline this process.
So there are two things I'd suggest doing at this stage.
Number one is go to reddit.com/subreddits and
look on the side of the page where it lists out all
of the subs you're already subscribed to.
Well, as it turns out, most of those are by default
and added when you signed up for everyone.
This is most likely what populates
the front page for you when you log in.
Do yourself a favor and just unsubscribe from all of the
ones that are not in the list we made in the last lecture.
While they are great comedy gold,
they're not really helpful right now.
The second thing I want you to do is add a quick
extension called Reddit Enhancement Suite to whatever
browser you are using.
If you're using Chrome, then it's perfect, just google it,
and you can add it in two seconds, and if you're on
Firefox, do another google.
Pretty sure it works for Firefox as well.
OK, it's also linked over in the resource section.
So just check it out.
Now, what this does, amongst many, many things, is it
allows you to better organize and keep track of what's
going on in Reddit.
It lets you, for instance, have multiple
accounts, which will come in handy later,
it lets you quickly keep track of where
in the comments an OP posts,
but most importantly of all, it lets
you tag and highlight users.
Why is this useful?
Well, because in the next couple of steps we're going
to start participating in the subs, and you'll start
to notice the regulars and the moderators,
the ones that are routinely posting.
It's always helpful to keep track of these people to make sure
you have an established at least some basic rapport with them.
So get that installed and play around with it for a second.
You can toggle it on and off by
clicking the icon in your browser.
That way, you can see what it is actually doing.
The way you tag someone is by clicking the tag next
to their name and then putting notes in colors or
whatever or not, or whether you want
notifications every time they post something.
All right, cool stuff.
See you in the next lecture.