Hey guys, welcome back to the course. In this lecture,
we're going to talk about origin source sorting.
Now, this is one of the most important concepts in
Google Analytics, because understanding it will help
you figure out which one of the 19 traction
channels we went over earlier is working for you.
Now, do you remember those or do I need
to grab my shocker pen again? No,
I'm definitely not going to do that, so if you don't remember,
can we just throw it up on the screen?
Can we throw it up on the screen, please?
Okay, thank you.
So what exactly is origin source sorting?
Well, that's where you figure out where your
traffic originated from, hence origin source,
and then you sort it, so they aren't all lumped together in one
giant masked anonymous group, like the band Slipknot.
Luckily, we just learned about Google Analytics,
where we can do this relatively easily.
And since we kind of blew right through it in the lecture,
let's go into a little bit more detail.
All right.
So this should look a bit familiar.
It's the Audience Overview screen that Google Analytics
always starts off. When it comes to origins source sorting,
we want to be in the Acquisition section.
There's the pie graph we saw before, and when we scroll
down we see bar graphs with the same information. Yay
for graphs! The information on the overview
screen is, well, basically just an overview.
We're going to want to go a little deeper to learn more
about where we're acquiring customers, which,
again, is why we're in the Acquisitions section to begin with.
For example, if I wanted to learn which
social network is working the best for me,
well, then I could click on Social and then figure that out.
It might be the case that your traffic
from Instagram is not buying,
whereas your traffic from Facebook is.
Without doing this, you would never know that.
Now, here there's a breakdown of the different social
networks where people discovered my project, 25
days of ideas. Now, it looks like Twitter is far
and away the top origin source for social.
I don't know why that is. So that's
great, but we can go even deeper.
We can filter the data down even more
by adding a secondary dimension.
Now, this basically means we're going to add another column
with an additional filter applied so we can hopefully
figure out which channel is the best, since the total
number of users doesn't really tell me the whole story.
So we can slice the data up even more to help us learn more
about the users that are coming from different sources.
I wanted to know which social network
was acquiring my most engaging users,
I could add a secondary dimension like,
let's say, I don't know, session duration,
so then I could see how long the users
stayed on my site before they left.
And we see that some people immediately
left at the sight of my face. I'm sorry.
Now, some of these secondary dimensions are more
useful than others, and some may even require exporting
the data into a spreadsheet to really drill
down on the information you're looking for.
It really just depends on what you're trying to learn
and how much time you're willing to spend on it
to figure it out.
So if you find yourself wanting to know a little bit more or you
have a question you think can be answered with the data,
you can browse through the menu and see if there's a secondary
dimension that might help you get to that answer more easily.
OK, but social is kind of an obvious example, since
there are only a handful of social sites out there.
And Google Analytics does a decent job of tracking
all the different social channels right out of the
box without you having to do that much.
Now, let's talk a little bit about this elephant
in the room back on the overview page.
I'm talking about the biggest number, which is labeled
Direct. So direct is supposed to mean that users
are directly typing in your website URL,
but there's absolutely no way that
5,820 people did that on 25 days of
ideas, which just launched last month.
So there must be something else going on here.
When I click into it, I can see that the bulk of the traffic
came directly to my home page at the25daysofideas.com,
that's what just the slash there means.
But again, this cannot possibly be people
actually typing it into their browsers.
And that is because Google will also show just the
slash when they click on a link from an e-mail, or
from a text, or from Slack, or from when their, you know,
grandma sent it to them in an AOL Instant Message.
Basically, Google sort of treats direct as a catch all for
when they can't determine exactly who the referrer is.
So how do we figure out where all these other direct users are
coming from, since they're probably not all typing in the URL?
Well, unfortunately, you can't control it that much.
My best guess is that a large amount of them are
coming from the daily e-mails that go out to users
who subscribed. Now, if only there was a better way
for me to track those users from the daily e-mails.
Well, stay tuned to the next lecture, where we talk about
what I should have done better to help understand
the people that are getting to my site.
OK guys, I'll see you then.