Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So the last two lectures to be talked out the fundamentals of lighting and audio and both of those were
marathon lectures books.
Oh God bless you if you made it all the way through.
But it kind of just brain dumped everything I know about laying in audio.
So now where did the same thing that we're going to do it for the final and third a central part of
any video production and that is the most obvious part video.
Now we're going to go over the essential things you need to understand about video as well as cameras
camera equipment and then generally just recommendations on what to use to create marketing videos or
is let's just jump in because well there's more than enough to cover.
Now the first thing we should cover about video or some of the technical details.
I know right to the boring stuff but that's actually not that bad.
Now there are some key numbers you need to know.
The first one worth knowing is the concept of video resolution.
So if you for instance walk into a Best Buy or shop for a TV online you'll see flat screens and you'll
see curved screens and all different types of TVs listed with different resolutions resolution refers
to how much detail a screen can show or that a camera can record.
Now the standard as I'm speaking right now if you're watching is five years in the future I'm sorry
but Zander now is 10 ETP and that's kind of what we consider full HD or high definition.
Another 10 to 80 essentially refers to how many individual pixels of information are in each image.
It's kind of like if you're painting a canvas and you want to make a painting and instead of making
broad strokes you just put dots over and over and over again until you had an image.
It's kind of like an inkjet printer or something like that.
Well that's basically how TV screens and monitors show what you're viewing and how many dots there are.
Well that's the resolution 10 80 right now usually looks pretty crisp.
You're watching this and see what the P intensity P stands for is progressive scan.
And I don't think you necessarily need to know that but that's a technology that TVs used to scan all
of the pixel and then display them back to you.
Now of course there's 10 A.D. II which is not progressive scan and actually Tany II is considered lower
resolution and looks generally worse.
All you really need to know is that progressive scan is the improved way of creating the image and it
keeps the screen from flickering on like the older TVs used to do.
So the 10 18 resolution is just how many lines of pixels high you have well the width of whatever screen
you're viewing it on can actually be variable based on what you're viewing it on.
But what you can do is let's say you have a regular TV and it's one 9500 twenty pixels wide and then
it's tennents.
So it's 10 80 high.
Well if you do a little math what that basically means is that the ratio of the width to your height
is 16 to 9 ratio.
Now video peeps will call that an aspect ratio and that is a term you will run into if you're in video
and it's basically the shape of your video frame.
That aspect ratio could be different if you wanted something like a widescreen image or a wide angle
image.
Okay I know that's way too many numbers for talking about cameras and this isn't math class so why exactly
is this important.
Well knowing pixel aspect ratio will help you set up your video editing projects that also help you
be informed as to what equipment you need to buy and what standards you should be shooting for 8:44
ratio.
The one I just randomly mentioned is actually the standard ratio in 1920 by 10 JTP pixels is also the
standard in general if you for some reason wanted to shoot with multiple cameras you just need to make
sure that they're both shooting in the same resolution and the same aspect ratio.
Now of course there are other resolution types out there.
OK we have 720 P which is an older resolution only has 720 lines of pixels.
And when HD TVs first came out that's what they were usually And they're usually in 720.
We didn't actually have 10:8 for a while.
And then it's 10 80 now you can only really at 720 if you buy like a cheap one.
But the newest thing on the market right now is what we call for k.
OK.
I Eric quoted that because for AK is not really new it's been out for at least two three four years
and soon it will be replaced by I think 8 K or something else but that is kind of the front tier currently.
Now why do we call the newest highest resolution for K and you guys might have noticed that like on
YouTube some videos you can actually select the quality setting and go to for k although most monitors
and most TVs now cannot display true for AK.
And if you're watching us in the future it's probably laughable anyway for k displays at 21:16.
P right now that's about double what we just said before which was 10 80.
So you might think to yourself Well if it's 21 60 and the old version was 10 80 you're watching 10:18
Rimmer then it's just double the resolution.
Right.
Well actually no for k is not twice the resolution.
It's four times the resolution four times as many pixels.
Now the reason why that is is because it's twice in height.
But because as you go up you also go over the same amount it's kind of like dragging and scaling an
image you're actually growing it for X not to x and you were the boy with four K's.
It's an enormous amount of detail and when you watch something in Torquay it is creepily clear.
Now what does this all mean for marketing videos.
You might wonder well the question is really less about what resolutions you can record or view videos
and and more about what your viewers and customers will use.
Now we talk about TVs but not laptops or phones which are probably where your audience will watch the
videos you're making.
Today's phones and laptops can play back video in HD at 720 pee or 10 ATP but not at 4 yet.
Unless of course you're a gamer and you have like a sick video card and monitor.
You probably don't have enough resolution on your screen to do it.
So then the question just becomes why do people shoot for k as opposed to 10 ATP.
Well and this gets a little bit complicated but bear with me here.
OK.
For carry is twice as many pixels right.
So if you take an image of my face you'll have twice as many dots to work with.
Now why is that a good thing.
Well when you edit your videos it's a lot easier when you have more information.
You can change the colors of things you can warp it you can move things around change the aspect ratio
because you have more on your plate.
It's less likely that you can end up with a blurry or degraded image.
For instance if you shot in any p and then he found out that oh well we really should have zoomed in
on this person's face when he talks and you try to do it and you might zoom in on my face.
Well there's not enough pixels then to make it look as crisp and clear as if you were looking at the
normal and zoomed out view with four K..
It has so many pixels that you can zoom in for days and you won't even notice the difference.
So there's obviously benefits for editing for four.
OK.
But there's one other concept in this is totally extracurricular but it's worth understanding if you
want the clearest video you possibly can nowadays knowing that virtually no one can actually display
true for OK what you do is actually a process called downsampling.
Now what that means is you shoot for OK.
Actually right now I'm shooting for OK but you're watching it 10 ATP what I did is I took the four K
and then I use a computer program like Adobe media and.
There's a lot of the free ones that I'll do it.
And it took the four OK and then got rid of half or get rid of three quarters of the pixels and moved
it down to 10 a.p.
Now how exactly is that better than just shooting and a.p and this is actually something that for the
longest time did not actually understand until I finally did.
What happens when you down sample is that let's say that it's looking at a pixel of my eye right and.
It might have one pixel one four it's going to four pixels.
So when it goes from four to 10 ATP it's only to pick one of those four because it chooses one of the
four basic computer algorithm can choose which of those pixels is the best.
So really what's happening is it's going to construct 10 ATP again but it's going to pick all the best
clearest pixels that have you know the best color profile and are in general just higher quality.
Did that blow your mind.
Maybe I don't know.
All right hopefully you've got the gist of resolution aspect ratio and downsampling.
Today the frontier is for k but most people watch everything and 10 ATP currently laptops and phones
can only show 10 a.p but it is only a matter of time before they can show or show for K for k is 4 times
larger than 10 80.
Why.
Well it's just because of math.
Basically it's twice as tall but when you go twice as tall you also go twice as wide.
Therefore it's four times as large.
How do you get the crispest image possible while you shoot it for can you do a process called downsampling
down to 10 ATP and that's how you get stuff that looks really really crisp.
But it's only Tany P.
I could probably link to a really short clip of me talking and for k and then you guys can go look at
it if you want.