Hey guys welcome back to the course.
So now that we've established what landing pages are and you know checked the last few lectures and
you honestly need a reminder at this point let's discuss what we're going to create to attract people
to those landing pages and to get them to take action.
Our hope in creating these landing pages or our goal is probably going to be we want to collect the
leads so we can then sell to later.
To get leads we need people to fill out a form with their personal information.
At the very least their email address and to compel them to do that specifically will we need to offer
them something in return.
We need to create something of value to the audience we're trying to attract something that will help
them make a decision understand a concept better and make us look like experts at the same time.
Basically we need to create a lead magnet.
Now as a reminder a lead magnet is a piece of content we create that attracts people you know like a
magnet to a landing page and that we give away in exchange for some personal information and information
allows us to sell them whatever our stuff is later usually then send them newsletters or promotional
stuff.
So there are four types of lead magnets.
I'm going to cover in this lecture and then the next lectures and each one offers a different format
with different ways to show off your expertise and value.
Now they are white papers e-books email courses and webinars.
It'll be up to you to pick which one you think you can pull off and which one fits your business the
best.
So let's get started.
So the first I believe that we're going to cover here are white papers so white papers are well researched
written pieces created for customers to address key questions or points relevant to their business.
They're usually written in a more formal tone and they have a structure that includes a summary at the
beginning.
They state a problem and a solution and include data graphs and some written analysis along the way
to help prove some point or some series of points.
Now in the end most of them are in the neighborhood of let's say 10 to 15 pages long.
They're usually offered as PTF.
Now that's not to say that you might see longer ones there are ones that will be 50 pages but you rarely
see one that's for no recook example evolved media this white paper about backup and disaster recovery
super sexy content.
When you arrive on this landing page for it on their site you get a short description of the white paper
and in this case there's no form to fill out to get it you just click the button below that opens a
nicely designed PTF which if you scroll through it kind of looks like a chapter from a book.
Flat out nice and it's easy to read and it'll look nice if you print it out.
So what's so special about the white paper format specifically what benefits does it offer that something
else wouldn't.
For one thing white papers can help establish what's called Thought leadership meaning it can cast you
as an expert in whatever the papers about you've done the research you've produced your findings so
people should come to you with questions and new business.
You can also reinforce your recommendations and findings in white papers with customer success stories.
So if they use your product to succeed then you look supersmart white papers also provide a lot of detail
in one place for prospective customers about a pain point or a common problem they have.
They don't have to dig around Google or through multiple blog posts.
Instead they can download a white paper which gives them ideas on how to fix whatever problem they're
specifically facing.
Another benefit for you is that white papers are usually so rich with information and detail that they
can use to create other types of content you can repurpose them pretty easily.
You can take excerpts from and create blog post social media images or tweets and if you can use those
things that promote the white paper as well.
So Ghana has its own marketing built into it by design why papers are designed to get downloaded and
or printed so they should serve as a reference materials over a long period of time.
Every time someone goes back to it your name and you are all are constantly going to be plastered all
over it or it should be.
So they'll come back to you later for more expertise.
So in that sense a kind of a double whammy.
Right.
Like get their information so you can contact them.
But then also if they do end up reading it they'll assume you're an expert and if they need you they'll
come out of the woods for you.
Now here's another example the white paper that's worth checking out.
Now a place called Data Ramah data over me I to dinner on a published this white paper on Seven Steps
to an integrated marketing analytics strategy.
And what does it data Ramah make a marketing analytics platform.
So it makes a lot of sense that they write a piece that offers helpful information about the concept
of integrated marketing analytics and they give you the steps to take to use it in your business.
But part of these steps include using the tool they offer so not only is this an educational reference
time piece but it's also a Trojan horse type of promotion.
Yes I know this one might sound like a listicle But what makes it a white paper is just generally that
it's going to be more databased and it's going to be a hell of a lot longer than a listicle.
So I would imagine each individual piece of the seven is multiple pages.
Now you can see they wrote this to get leads but also you know to get sales.
Now does every white paper have to be educational and promotional.
Now not really that's actually up to you.
Sometimes it's just nice to offer help with information as a way of establishing you're an expert makes
you look good.
But if there's a logical not to use sales the way of including your own product or service in there
as well why not just start to think of it from the reader's point of view.
If your white paper addresses a problem and the only solution presented is your product then people
might feel like they're just repeating a gigantic brochure.
So in terms of topics why papers work really well when they focus on a problem like how can I start
using analytics in my marketing decision making.
They can also be used to describe the benefits of a type of product or solution.
If you've created a social media scheduling app and you know all the benefits of how an app like that
can help social media managers for example.
So how can you create a White Paper.
Well in the next hour we'll discuss the steps you can take and some tools and templates out there to
save you a lot of time.
All right guys see the.