They all know you all.
Welcome back to our little miniature break full of data living and this lecture.
We're going to cover linking strategies and how they can give you an additional layer of tracking that
you just can't get with basic analytics systems that we covered before.
OK so with each of those analytic systems we have to install them on our page.
That means if a person comes to the page we can then track whatever they do when they're there.
But how exactly do we know where they came from.
If you missed previously all of these systems try and try their best track or the referrer of the traffic
is and if you're using Google Analytics you probably noticed you have 10 links from Facebook Tony from
Twitter and 400 from this mysterious person called direct direct.
Unfortunately could be anywhere.
Technically it means they type the name of your website or your app store into the browser bar.
But I honestly call B.S. on that.
Some of them do that but it's really never the case that 90 percent of your visitors memorize the name
and then typed it in their browser.
What we can do to get a better grip over what's happening when we're posting and promoting our link
is that we can use a number of linking strategies.
So the way that this works is we can do specific things to each link.
We can modify them we can tinker with them and we can make it so that each link is unique.
The benefits of doing this is well let's say we posted a bunch all over read it and if you're following
along with the course you probably did that.
How do we know which post is getting attention and which ones are being pretty much ignored.
Google Analytics would just say the traffic came from Reddit but how do we know if they click the link
say in the body of our message or in the footer.
These are really interesting things that are worth knowing which tweet for instance got more clicks
which called action gets more clicks in general these are things we need to learn and refine such that
we can increase the efficiency with which we can acquire customers or users.
And that is incredibly important going forward in the course.
So let's cover three or four I can't remember different ways you can do this.
Keeping in mind that really all we're going to do is modify the links themselves.
There's no crazy software.
The first act is by using what's called a web wrapper.
No not a YouTube video of someone rapping.
If you've actually followed along and tried using Twitter and you included a link and then tweeted it
out.
Well what happened.
OK.
You're beautiful puppies and porcupine playhouses info got replaced with a weird looking t dot SEO slash
a whole bunch of other gobbledygook.
That right there is called a web wrapper and Twitter for some reason doesn't always apply it to your
tweets.
But most of the time they do.
I honestly think they use like a pinball machine for determining who gets the web wrapper and who doesn't.
That's a wrapper and Twitter isn't the only one out there that can do this.
Google has its own system.
You can use to change your links to something that looks like Goo dot G.L. hourly is a wrapper that
changes it to Ousley and PITI is the one we're going to talk about how to change all of your links to
something that looks like Billy B.
T L Y.
And bitterly was its name so Billy represented by their mascot a pufferfish because Titli rhymes with
pufferfish is the most well-known system out there and almost everyone online will recognize it the
way you use it is pretty simple and you can create an account at bitterly for free and then paste your
u r l into the box that says create custom link up at the top right.
It will then spit out a bit like Slash jibberish link and there you go.
You believed your link if you were then to go out and use that.
Then whenever someone clicked that link you could see when it happened where it happened and you know
where the location of the person who clicked it is.
You can also see things like general trend lines of how well it's getting clicked.
It's data overload but it could be useful.
You can also label and organize your links for quick viewing.
I personally suggest that you make little folders and or little groups for each site that you're going
to target and then make sure that use a custom link for each post you do or each attempt you make.
OK.
Yea we can go a little bit farther down the rabbit hole and learn how we can customize each link.
Beyond that flash jibberish they give us all you do is click the link and you'll see in the slide out
tray you can change it to really whatever you want.
So bitterly slash the name of your product would probably work decently well.
Now why do we customize these links.
You might ask well because the sad fact of linked short owners are Web wrappers nowadays is that when
you use them people often think you're trying to track them which you know is true.
Or they think you're hiding a link within them trying to track them is OK but it has a tendency to feel
like it's a little in genuine It's kind of like hey I want honest feedback and I'm personally tracking
whether or not you click this link.
And because the Internet is a giant mosh pit of human vice it's often the case in unregulated forums
that people linked to bad things and then hide it with a link or so people accidentally click it.
If you customize the link then it looks a little more legit.
And the more unscrupulous ones out there just won't even notice.
Now the issue with these links looking weird is legitimate and it might affect you depending on what
you're using it for.
If you want to spend the time and effort we can actually go a step farther and use what's called a custom
branded link shorter if you're not interested in this please God just skip this lecture.
This is totally extra credit.
Have you ever seen any of my tweets.
Course you haven't because you don't care about me.
Well when I share links they come through as Evan K. dot and slash some jibberish.
My web site is my name dot com.
And then Kimbrell dot com.
Now when you look at my custom link there's a better chance you might actually confuse it with my real
domain which is good and that's all we want.
Realistically I use my short term places where it's perfectly fine to use a shorter I do in emails surveys
and places like tweets.
But if I was going out in the wild trying to do this personally like in forums I would probably instead
want to get as close to as possible my real domain.
So when they click through there's not this huge gap between what they clicked and what they saw.
So ideally if I had something like Evan Kimbrell But the domain extension was Dotti L-L or something
like that like that would be nice.
Even something like every red dot net would be fine because then they get there and dot com.
Now if you want to go this route I've included a link to an extensive guide of how to do this with Billy.
It's going to cost you anywhere from $7 to 30 depending on which domain you end up buying and from where.
And it's also probably going to take like an hour or an hour and a half to do it.
It took me about an hour.
It really just takes too long to explain in detail so follow that guide.
But here is the gist.
Every country on Earth plus some other territories have a unique domain extension.
The reason we use dot com is just because it was the original and has the most people on it.
Eventually as the Internet expanded.
Other countries wanted to differentiate their links by making it obvious which country it was coming
from either by changing the extension itself like Dot am for our media or G-B for Great Britain or by
just appending it to the dot coms like the United Kingdom is.
So oftentimes dot com dot uk.
Now the first example is what we call a country level domain not country style like the buffet or country
strong like Chevvy but country level country level like Dot A.F. for Africa.
Yes.
They don't match exactly.
Great Britain isn't a country I know of Africa.
I can't really remember.
But next time you see someone with say a dot I O extension ask them what it's like to live in the Indian
Ocean because that's what that stands for.
Also I know Africa is not a country trying to take a two to three letter combination and see if there
is a corresponding match.
Just google whatever the letters you want are if you're creative you can probably find one that works
or just end up creating a domain that is similar enough using one of the available extensions.
Once you find one you just need to buy it through whatever vendor you can find that's selling them and
it's always someone different.
This might take 30 minutes or so to figure out who actually has it but after some googling and some
clicking through and people passing you to other pages you'll finally figured out that it's really just
a matter of changing the settings and setting it up in your bitty account.
Once it's set up all you have to do is change the settings.
Every time you copy a link you get a link instead with your custom extension.
With that you can make your links look even more incognito and reap the benefits of link tracking and
link analytics.
All right we've talked to way too much about Billy next lecture.
We're going to go over two more manual techniques.
You can also use to add link level tracking.
See the.