Hey guys welcome back to the cause.
It's our last lecture.
I mentioned that Snapchat and Instagram are emerging platforms for marketing opportunities.
Well in this lecture let's talk about Snapchat.
Now Snapchat begins with a very common concept.
Sharing pictures or videos with a friend or a group of friends.
But the big difference here with Snapchat is that when you post something after a certain amount of
time it disappears.
The idea is that it makes the post ephemeral which makes it more attractive more raw and more genuine.
It also entices people to share things that they wouldn't want posted publicly forever.
So while most platforms come with that assumption that your data and your content will be safe forever.
Snapchat like No let's just delete it immediately.
Now this point I have to say guys if you know how Snapchat works and you use it and you're an active
user skip this lecture because I don't want to hear you complain about it.
I don't even know what I'm doing here.
We're wasting our time.
But if you haven't.
Well we can continue along.
Now let's look at the data.
Two thirds of Snapchat users are under 25 and according to research these younger users really embrace
this idea that you post whatever you want but know that it will actually be gone soon enough Snapchat
is a platform that encourages spontaneity looking into the past doesn't matter on this platform.
It's really all about what's happening right this second.
And to add to that when you post your snaps or the pictures you put on Snapchat you can apply fun filters
and effects to the photos themselves.
So the vibe on Snapchat is generally going to be casual and fun.
You don't see a lot of high production stuff because it's spontaneous.
The whole point is you didn't have a lot of time to prep.
So Snapchat now supports something like one hundred and fifty million users daily.
But how exactly Snapchat an opportunity.
Well with a platform where pictures disappear how exactly can you create a lasting presence.
Well this is what our group of lectures coming up now will explore in our next lecture.
Will start by creating a Snapchat account for your business and then we'll run through a few tactics
you can try to create some awareness of your brand and then grow your audience.
Now before we do that though let me run down some of the lingo you'll hear when we discuss what you
can do on Snapchat.
The first one is snap.
OK.
Well Snapchat when you send a picture or a video that's just called a snap.
The next thing is a story.
And this is relatively new defense when you guys are watching this but it's a collection of snaps.
You can share with followers.
Now instead of sharing one picture you actually can share a whole bunch.
And it's both of them lasting like 90 seconds or nine to 15 seconds are thinking actually are shorter
like six to 15 these last 24 hours.
Next thing is live and why.
Well it's just a variation of that story where you can see the world through someone else's Snapchat
right this second.
Then we have things like filters now filters are overlays for your snaps allow you to decorate your
pictures with text graphics and by applying color and contrast effects all sorts of special filters
that can only be unlocked if you like say go to a specific location.
Those are also called like geo filters then you filters that unlock.
The more you use it they also have the special filters that transform your face into a dog or a panda
or something like that.
Those are fun for Friend to friend but as a business while you kind of be careful with that stuff.
And that brings me to that term.
It's actually called a lens.
So when you're trying to take a photo of your face if you tap the screen while you're doing that it
brings up your available lenses.
And that's where you have the opportunity to look like a panda or a dog or whatever you have activated
the next thing worth doing is the snap code.
And this is essentially a profile badge including your photo.
That's scalable by other Snapchat users.
This can be very useful in building your brand.
More on that later.
The next term worth exploring is discover that's just a snap a section on Snapchat that's designed for
brands and publishers.
They're able to share stories there to larger audiences.
But this is things like you know ESPN or Cosmo or BuzzFeed.
People have direct relationships with the company.
So once you jump into Snapchat with your own account you'll get familiar with some of these terms very
quickly.
But your first step is to create an account.
So we're going to do that the next lecture.
See you then.