All right guys we're back we're now we're talking about video equipment.
OK.
Now one of the pieces of equipment that we need to talk about is the tripod.
Now you might be thinking of a tripod.
Well that means that thing with three legs you put a camera on right.
Why exactly is that important.
Can't I just set the camera on a box or table or something like that.
Absolutely.
You can set it on a table or a box or whatever.
But here's why a tripod is really more useful than just being a three legged camera Holder.
Well it provides stability for your image so there's really no shaking while you shoot cheaper tripod
might be made of plastic and can shift.
They can bend they can wobble and especially the more you use them that can actually be dangerous because
you can drop a lot of your stuff and break it.
Now more expensive tripods remunerative like aluminum alloys or even carbon fiber like a tennis racket
and it can provide great stability for much longer times.
And also they can hold heavier and heavier sets on top of them.
What I generally say is invest in kind of like the second cheapest tripod at first.
So if you go on to Amazon for instance and your tripod there are ten dollar ones for called Amazon basics
and those are absolute garbage like they break so quickly.
Having them little break in the process of mailing them to you what I generally say is just suck it
up and spend I suppose 10 spend 30 maybe 40 50 and whatever you end up getting will last you for ever
and you can end up reselling it if you get out of video and essentially recoup your costs.
I use what's called the Proline Dholakia.
It's just what it was which is a camera that's in that range it's really easy it's small it's compact
it's pretty easy to work with within tripods you have two different types you have ball heads and then
you have pan heads and that's honestly the tripod but it's a head you attach to it and a ball head.
You can guess it's basically at the top is going to be attached to a ball.
And that means that you can move your camera in any direction you want.
Right you can put it sideways.
You can put it up and tilt it down.
You can twist it which is a great thing if you want to do some artsy shots or something fancy you want
to do or if you want to save space because that actually is really small.
However it can be kind of a pain if you don't tighten it correctly or you have a cheap version of it
because your camera can slide and you won't notice.
Now the other one is a Panhead and really all that means is that the place where you attach the camera
is flat and then it has a handle.
And the reason why it's called a Panhead is because with that handle you can pan the camera left and
right.
And that's called a pan when you go left right like this.
So it's easy to make turning motions and do that smoothly.
Those are generally the tripods you see if you plan on having someone behind the camera the entire time.
Now on another piece of equipment we should talk about his memory.
So some cameras will store recorded footage internally using what they call flash memory which is basically
a hard drive or you could also record straight to memory cards that go in a slot which will call removable
flash memory.
Now in prosumer level cameras the SLR is almost always going to be recording to a camera in general
memory is pretty cheap.
You can get a 32 gigabyte memory card for oh man I want to say it's like 20 bucks $25 something like
that and if you really want to go crazy you get 128 gigabyte card for about $100.
Now if you're shooting in teniente P then 32 gigabytes is more than enough that a lot of time you're
using it for however 32 gigabytes is not going to give you much time at all.
You get to fill up well with under an hour of actual footage and you know there's not a whole lot to
say about memory cards if you're shooting for K you have to make sure that you have the right memory
card.
Usually they're just ones that are called Class 3 cards if you ever forget that you can just Google
what kind of car do I need for for k.
And usually they're just going to be the ones that are called like super fast or hyper speed or extreme
speed.
Usually they have some angle or they try to make it sound like they're super fast and that's usually
are talking about that we have batteries.
Right.
Well most cameras are going to run on batteries and that's generally kind of the standard.
Whenever you shoot you are using you to remember to bring as many batteries as you can because you run
on batteries entirely while you're kind of just grew and you're done until you can charge one and then
shoot again every time you charge a battery it takes at least an hour.
What I personally like do and this is going in my hand because I like to use what are called DC adaptors
for camera and what those are are they're actually like look like little fake batteries with cords sticking
out of them you stick them in body or camera and you plug them directly into an extension cord or your
wall.
That way I don't ever have to think about batteries being done.
Personally when I shoot I like to make sure I have everything covered.
So I'm not constantly stopping because the memory cards fall or the batteries dead or you know the light
changed or whatever it is.
So that just removes one extra thing I have to worry about.
Only you know to that is while you have a cord somewhere sometimes you might not access to power if
you're shooting like out doors or something.
Which case unfortunately you have to use a battery.
You can also do this thing called battery Grip's which friends and like the Canon 17 dieter's battery
Grip's and what those do doubles your battery capacity.
Basically there are these attachments you put on the bottom and they hold two batteries as opposed to
one in that situation.
You can actually get the cheap Chinese knockoffs of those.
And there are only like 40 bucks or 30 bucks or something like that.
They actually work perfectly fine.
Don't buy the on brand ones the Canon brand wants to charge you 100 bucks for the same thing.
No way it's not worth it.
Now what else do you need.
Well you might need camera bags.
It's really important and to go into that.
The other thing is the lenses now.
A lot of people ask How important are lenses.
Well it's kind of debatable.
I'm not a video professional so I'm going to say they're medium and.
If you have a really nice lens Well that could actually make up for having a cheaper camera.
And you have a really bad lens.
Well I can create a problem for even a nice camera.
The main thing with lenses is that they allow you to have different shots styles and that's really it.
Right so some lenses are going to be great for close up shots and some lenses are going to be great
for a wide landscape shots.
It just kind of pends on what you need.
Really the only thing I think is probably worth paying attention to you when you get into lenses because
you're doing marketing videos don't get too crazy with this.
Also this is not a cinematography course.
We could spend an entire course on lenses just look for the millimeter length.
OK.
Now what the millimeter length is going to tell you is how wide or how narrow the shot is.
Now I don't know if you do a wide angle is but a wide angle image is just an image where left and right
you can see more.
Right.
It's just a wider shot but condensed down into the same frame.
Now the extreme version of this is what's called a fish eye.
And basically that means that you can almost see 90 degrees left and right in the image and what it
does is it kind of warps the way that the image looks because how else can you fit all of that into
an image that should only cover say like 45 degrees each way of my vision.
So generally speaking Whiting lenses are going to really low millimeters and then zoom lenses are going
to be way up at the top.
You know they can be 100 millimeters plus etc. So if you for some reason want to shoot and you want
to use that effect or it's wide well then yeah look for something in the low millimeters.
In fact they're usually called wide angle lenses or super wide or ultra wide.
My advice is don't get into the super weeds and Ultra's but it is fun to have a wide angle lens.
In general I get to say avoid those because 90 percent of marketing videos.
Unless you're shooting outdoors you're just not going to want to use a wide angle lens because it's
not good at focusing in on one specific thing.
It's good at taking in all of the possible things you could see.
So I usually say is go for something in the middle.
Right.
So right now I'm shooting on a 30 millimeter Sigma and basically what that means is that it's going
to start there and it's going in there.
OK.
I could have gone more narrow in which case you would see me but you'd only see here and here and it
could have gone wider or you could see what goes beyond the bookcases.
But I knew that this is the shot I want.
Therefore I just want something in the middle.
Now one other thing that's worth talking really quickly about Lindsay is you are fixed and you have
zoom lenses.
Now the difference being that a fixed lens cannot zoom in or zoom out.
It has one literal zoom and that's it.
If you want to zoom out you got to move the camera backwards.
You want to zoom in your two forwards.
Now a zoom lens you can twist a little ones most you are familiar with that's going to zoom in and zoom
out.
OK well fixed lenses are less flexible.
Right so you need to keep in mind that if you're shooting with fixed lenses or prime lenses they're
also called with a prime lens.
Well you just need to know that you don't have to consciously move the camera if you need to zoom in
and out.
Generally those are really hard to shoot with unless you have someone in a fixed position and they're
not moving around or constantly changing or doing different things.
Obviously the advantage of the zoom it's more flexible.
Now here's where the cons come in prime lenses have better image quality.
That's it.
I mean I don't know if it's super noticeable but they do definitely have better image quality.
Zoom lenses don't.
And this just a function of how the Lynde's extends itself that it just doesn't have the same clarity
of refraction onto the sensor to get the same image.
So if you're going to shoot something like an interview right or you're going to shoe like a talking
head video explainer like I'm doing right now or even a screen cast for the same thing.
Or you know or like a talk show type style prime lenses are usually fine.
You're not going constantly moving the camera around but you are moving the camera.
You're doing multiple scenes and you're doing different things unless you know what you're doing.
It's a lot easier to just get a zoom lens cause I'll give you a lot more flexibility you can zoom in
when you want to zoom out when you want to.
All right so that's it for now.
That's the crash course you need to know about cameras.
Now no resolution and aspect ratio is now at 4 in 10 A.P. is you now know about three different levels
of cameras and then within each one what's important then we also talked about the equipment which really
just comes down to things like memory your bag your lens and whatever you're actually going to hoist
the camera on.
Our guys in the next section we're going to talk about how to work within a budget that you've set so
you can put together a complete equipment package that actually makes sense for you then or going to
it is going to talk about how to use all the different set up especially some of the easier and more
common setups that a lot of people use.
All right.
So in the next lecture.