Alright, guys, welcome back to the course. In the last
lecture, we went over some Snapchat basic terms,
but you'll need to see these things for yourself,
so, in this lecture, let's create your account
and get familiar with the app itself.
If you guys have a Snapchat account, either scan through
this at 2x to see if there's something different that
you missed, or just skip the lecture.
First off, Snapchat doesn't have
a special account for businesses.
Instagram, on the other hand, does.
So when you create an account, it's generally going to be
the same process that you'd follow for a personal account.
Hence when I say Snapchat is emerging, it hasn't yet
figured out how to let marketers use their platform,
so they don't even facilitate it.
The first thing you need to do is just download the app,
so, you know, if you're on Android go to Google
Store, if you're on iPhone, go to the Apple Store.
Once you do install it, go ahead and just follow these steps.
First thing you do is you just start up
the app and then you click Sign Up.
Next, you'll be asked to enter your name and at
some point you'll have to choose a username.
Since this account is going to be for your business,
well, then put your business name in there, and if
possible, choose a username handle that's the same or
similar enough to the other social accounts you've created.
Generally speaking, if someone is interested in what
you're doing and they see your Facebook account, they'll
look to see if you're on other platforms as well.
So let's say you sell dog food and
you're @megachowfood on Twitter,
then try to get @megachowfood on
Snapchat. Again, Snapchat is emerging,
so there's actually a lot of open handles,
wouldn't be surprised if you got exactly what you wanted.
The next thing is that during the set up,
you'll also be asked to enter a date of birth.
So since you're a business,
well, you don't really have one.
So really, you just need to make that one up.
And yes, I know, that's technically illegal
by an obscure law somewhere,
but anyway, the whole reason you put this in there
is you have to be at least 13 years old to have a
Snapchat account, so put in a birth date that meets
that requirement, maybe put in yours, it doesn't matter.
Moving on.
Next up, you have to set a password,
so obviously pick a good one that's not password12345.
Don't be one of those people,
especially with a business account.
My god, the amount of damage and extortion people
can do to business accounts is really quite shocking.
The next thing they'll do is they'll
ask you for your phone number.
The reason why they do this is because when people
sign up to Snapchat, one of the ways they'll add
other people is they'll add their contact list and then
it matches the phone number, it's very similar
if you've used WhatsApp, it kind of uses your
phone number as your single identifying ID.
Now, if you have a mobile phone for your business with
a unique number, obviously go ahead and enter that one,
but a lot of people don't, so just know that you don't have
to necessarily put in a phone number if you don't want to,
but you have to do some other things.
Part of the reason why you put the phone
is also for verification purposes anyway,
but you can actually just use an email address instead,
you're just foregoing the opportunity that someone
who is in your contact list could add you. Anyway, just make
sure that you enter a business email, not your personal one.
Otherwise, you can get stuck. Either way, phone, email,
whatever, Snapchat is going to send you that verification
message, make sure you validate it,
and that's pretty much it.
But before you actually start using it,
let me give you a few tasks to do that will help you
essentially learn this in a much more accelerated way.
The first thing I say is just make
sure to set up your Snapcode.
Now, most platforms allow you to set up a profile
picture and put your logo up there, but not Snapchat.
If you tap the Snapchat logo in the upper left, you'll see
a yellow square with a ghost, and that's the Snapchat
logo inside of it.
Well, this is your Snapcode, and you'll
see little dots inside that yellow square.
People can use this to directly follow you,
so make sure to tap on it and download an image of it.
Then what you can do is you can post this to different
places, like other social media accounts, to let people
know how to connect to you on Snapchat.
One common thing to do is when you just open your
Snapchat account, you take your profile photo and you
change your other profile photos to that, like on Facebook or on
Twitter, and that lets people know, hey, we just joined Snapchat.
Obviously, don't leave that there permanently,
but it's a good way of getting other people to join.
Now, here's the second thing you should do right now.
Sign yourself up for an app called GhostCodes.com.
What is GhostCodes.com?
Trust me, we will get into this later.
Now, one of the things about Snapchat
that kind of sucks is discovery,
meaning it's not really that easy
to find other people's profiles.
Ghost Codes is essentially a directory of Snapchat
users organized by topic, and a much easier way
to find and follow people in your
industry or wherever you want to look.
Remember Product Hunt, for example?
Well, you can find them under the Entrepreneur category.
Ghost Codes also has a point system called kudos,
where users upvote your profile in your category, making
it easier to find you.
So make sure you put yourself in the right category.
Navigating around Snapchat isn't so
much menu-driven as it is swipe-driven.
One thing that drives me a little bit nuts about
Snapchat is that all apps out there like to follow
the same general rules for how
you navigate around them,
and the reason why they do that is
so it's easier for people to use it.
We get used to certain things, having a menu button
in the top right or the top left, having a profile
icon somewhere that I could click
and takes me to the home. Snapchat
decided to purposely not do that.
And the reason why, and I think this is kind of
hilarious, is that they know their demographic,
they're usually under 20, these people
didn't grow up with Facebook,
they want to actually make it difficult for people
who are not in their demographic to learn it.
* Oh wait a minute. *
* What did I do? Ugh, that's ugly. I think I hit the wrong thing.
Dude. What's this stopwatch in the bottom? Is that my timer? *
* Who would ever do one second? *
* That would be just rude.
Now, where are my filters? *
So it's kind of like sitting down at the lunchroom,
you don't want your parents to sit down with you.
How do you do that?
Well, I don't know.
You spray water on the ground around it and make
it freeze into ice so they literally can't get to it.
That's the Snapchat equivalent.
Yes.
I personally think it's ridiculous,
and if you agree with me,
you can post in the Slack chat,
but hey, that's what they did.
Now, when you first create your account, you'll probably
end up on that camera view where you'll be basically
in the camera mode, but with a
big white circle at the bottom.
Now, guys, they change the UI for this all the time, so if it's
slightly different when you're watching this, don't freak out.
Now, that's your snap button, that is what you use to
take photos with. Camera options are at the top right.
Keep this in mind though, you don't always have
to take your photos through the Snapchat app,
you can actually take it through your regular
camera and then upload it through Snapchat.
The other sections of the app are Chat, Stories, Discovery,
and Memories. Now, Chat is where you can add
your friends, the people you want to connect with and
follow, and then send pictures or videos to them directly.
Stories is where you can create a story.
Remember, it's a collection of pictures and videos
which is available for your friends to check out for
I think it's 24 hours.
You can also see their stories, if they post any,
along with some featured stories which come from,
you know, the big brands. Now, Discover is basically the
sponsored section of stories with a much longer list of
brands ranging from National Geographic to Esquire
to Comedy Central to Wired, whatever, many, many more.
We only go to these for inspiration on what to post
and otherwise they're pretty much worthless. Now,
Memories is a section where you
can view any saved snaps and stories.
So, in reality, Snapchat actually doesn't
delete all of your pictures and videos.
You have to choose to save them, of course,
and when you do, well, they're going to show
up here. To get to each Snapchat section,
think of the camera screen as like your home screen,
and then you swipe left or right to go to a new section.
It's like an invisible navigation bar.
You can also just use the icons
at the bottom of the screen,
although... Snapchat drives me crazy.
Anyway, to get to Memories, you go to the camera
mode and you swipe up or click the small circle on the
bottom center of the screen.
Yes, anyway, so that's basically the app. You can take
pictures and videos and you can send them to people
through chat, save some to your memories, and
view other people's stories or sponsored posts.
Now, this is a good place to pause, because if you haven't
been in the app before, it's really worth checking out,
testing out some of the features, and seeing what everything does. It's designed to be counter-intuitive,
so it's worth spending 10 minutes
just kind of messing around with it.
In our next lecture, we're going to talk about what to
do first as a brand on Snapchat, including advice
on snaps you can take and how to connect and
promote yourself specifically on their platform.
Alright guys, see you then.