Hello this is Kirill from Fredericksburg dot com.
And welcome back to the course on for X-raying.
Today we will talk about the X market participants.
So here's the farmer's market.
And who are the major players here.
Well first of all of course it's governments.
Governments use the Forex market to meet certain economic goals whether it's to have a lower exchange
rate compared to a certain currency or a higher exchange rate.
It all depends on where the company countries importing or exporting goods and many various other factors
.
Also the central bank in most cases the central bank is the financial arm of the government but sometimes
the central bank is more independent.
For some countries and the Central Bank also uses the Forex market to move around its reserve currency
and monitor the situation and things like inflation interest rates and so on.
Next we've got normal banks normal banks trade for X-Mas trade on the forex market to define which exchange
rates should govern the exchange of currencies and those like when you and I we go to a bank and we
do exchanges there or do so in transactions those transactions are minuscule compared to what banks
deal at an international level.
They throw around billions if not trillions of dollars just to make sure that they have the right currencies
that they need for their activities.
Also other financial institutions participate in the Forex market and an example of that would be the
pension funds in the US.
They have massive massive companies who have lots and lots of money and sometimes they need to make
transactions on the forex market as well.
Other players in the market include normal companies such as BMW Coca-Cola General Motors and any other
multinational company that you can think of.
And that's because these companies have operations across the globe and therefore they are forced to
convert currencies all the time in order to pay suppliers pay employees and so on.
For example Coca-Cola might be paying someone please that it has somewhere in India and have to convert
dollars into rupees or for instance BMW might be ordering some cars from Japan and that way they have
to convert euro into yen and pay for those parts.
Another good example is when BMW might order the parts from Japan and get them but they only have to
pay for them in one year.
So in that situation they have two options they can either create the product sell it and then one year
later pay for the parts but then they will have to convert euros into yens.
One year later and the price of Yan's might have gone up by then and that will mean that BMW will lose
on this foreign exchange transaction and this loss will eat into its profits from the normal operations
.
So in those cases most companies do something which is called a hedge.
And what they do is they instead of waiting one year to convert their euros into yen they will actually
create a forward contract with a bank saying that they will need yens in one year and they will create
a fix or agree on a fixed price.
Now with that bank.
But to buy those yens one year from now that activity is called hedging and therefore these companies
are sometimes referred to as hedgers so not.
These are instances when they don't need to buy the other currency immediately but when they will need
it later on.
And so they're called hedgers because they're hedging themselves or protecting themselves from this
foreign exchange risk.
Actually a lot of companies across the globe undertake this activity and other type of major players
on the French market is hedge funds.
Hedge funds are actually funds that are or organizations that are designed to speculate on the forex
market and bring profits to their investors.
So even though they're called hedge funds they're mostly all now they've kind of developed to become
very aggressive and profit seeking.
So they take on a large funds from investors and then they try to trade these this money on the market
to make profits and they earn fees.
And plus they earn commissions if they do create profits.
And finally the normal traders such as you and I and George Soros just people who speculate on the forex
market to make a profit.
So they're also participants of the Forex market.
And for example George Soros was able to make over a billion dollars of profit in one month.
That's that's one of the reasons why what he's famous for.
And so all those participants together as you can imagine create massive and massive volumes of money
and to be more precise the volume of the folks market is five trillion dollars.
That is five.
And all those are is behind it.
And that is her day five trillion dollars goes through the 4 X market.
That's an unbelievable amount of money.
And just to put that into comparison the largest stock exchange in the world is the New York Stock Exchange
and the total market capitalization of the New York Stock Exchange.
And means if you take all the companies that are listed on the New York Stock Exchange and you put all
of their values together then you will get only eighteen point seven trillion dollars and that's a total
capitalization of that exchange.
Whereas on the forks market you have five trillion dollars going through the market per day and that
just shows that the Forex market is by far the biggest financial market in the world.
So that sums it up for today.
I look forward to seeing a next tutorial.
And until then happy trading