Hello this is Kirill from Forex boat dot com.
And welcome back to the course and for extruding in today's tutorial we will be talking about paper
value.
Now we really know what a pip is.
It represents a unit of change in the quotation of a currency.
Value will allow us to translate pips into dollars.
It will help us understand how a certain number of pips means a certain amount of profit on her account
.
It will allow us to calculate these profits losses and ultimately Forex risks.
So as you can imagine today's tutorial and the next tutorial are very important for us to continue and
pursue with this course and proceed to live real trading.
So to start with let's imagine an example let's imagine that we entered into a trade and the market
has moved a certain number of pips which is represented by the pips variable here on the left.
Also we know that we had a specific WM of options action which is represented by the Lotts variable
on the right.
So together these two variables combined will determine p value for this transaction.
So this is important to understand that people value is not just a function of the currency pair that
you are looking at value depends on the number of pips the currency pair has moved.
And also on the volume of the transaction.
So if you enter into a transaction with a higher number of lots then your value will be higher if you
enter for a lower number of loss.
Your value will be lower.
Let's have a look at this in a basic conceptual example.
So here we have the Eurodollar chart on the right.
The price is 1.2 3 2 to 8.
Price moves up a bit and goes to one point 2 3 4 7 8.
There's approximately movement of 25 pips.
So now let's imagine that we had entered into the market with a buy order at the low level and exited
the market at the higher level.
So if our buying order had a volume of 0.1 lots then we got a certain amount of profit from this transaction
.
If our buy order was 1.0 lots then we got much more profit.
In fact ten times more profit from this transaction if our buy order was five lots then we got even
more profit from this transaction 50 times more than in their original case.
So that is exactly what we mean when we say that value is both a function of how much the currency pair
has moved and how much you have invested into this particular trade.
Those are the basic concepts around pick value and if you understand that then that will be well and
truly enough for you to grasp the concepts of live real trading.
When are we going to do now in this tutorial is we going to look at this particular example of the euro
dollar in more detail and actually go through the calculations that will tell us the how to translate
pips into dollars and then we will proceed further to derive a general formula for value.
So if you don't want to get into the mathematics then by all means keep the rest of this tutorial and
move onto the next one.
At the beginning of the next tutorial I will bring up the result that we'll get in the current tutorial
and you'll be able to just move forward with the result.
However if you do want to participate in the maths then feel free to stick around.
We're going to dive into it right now.
So let's look at this example that we talked about just now in more detail.
There is our chart on the right and the price moved up 25 pips.
So let's calculate the value of the Euros that we bought at the moment when we entered into the transaction
the value of the euro so we bought it calculate as the number of Lotts times 100000 units of base currency
times the price at point 1.
So if we replace those that will be a one lot we'll look at an example where we bought one lot.
So one lot tons €100000 times 1.2 three two to eight dollars per year.
And that gives us a hundred twenty three thousand two hundred and twenty eight dollars.
Now let's calculate the value at Point two at the top value point 2 is calculated in a very similar
fashion.
One lot times 100000 euros times one point two three four seven eight dollars per year.
So here we are using the new price and the new value is one hundred and twenty three thousand four hundred
seventy eight dollars.
Now let's calculate the change in value.
The change of value is equal to value to minus value 1.
And in this case it's $250.
And obviously the value is going to be equal to the change in value divided by the change in pips.
And in our case it's $250 divided by 25 pips because as you can recall the price moved up by 25 pips
and then gives us a pick value of $10 per Pip.
That is quite simple and straightforward.
All we had to do was take the difference in values which we calculate separately and divide by the difference
in pips.
Let's look at a general form of this calculation.
So to start off with we calculate the change which is value to minus value one value too is lots times
100000 units of base currency times price to value one is lots times 100000 units of base currency times
price one. We can bring in the brackets and live price to minus price one within the brackets and take
lots times 100000.
A based currency outside of the brackets.
Next we can replace price to minus price one with Delta pips and we know that regardless of whether
we're using a four digit or five digit broker pips is always 0.00 0 1.
So here we are replacing price tumor's Press one of Delta pips times 0.00 0 1 and next we get rid of
the 100000 tons 0.00 0 1 which gives us 10.
So the change in value is always equal to lots times ten times Delta pips and is measured in the units
of quoted currency.
So now if we proceed to Kalvik value we need to take the change and divided by the number of pips that
the currency has moved.
So if we plug in the previous results into this formula we'll get lots times 10 times Delta pips divided
by Delta pips and if we simplify this 4000000 further it will get lots times 10.
So this gives us a result that Pipp value is always equal to lots times 10 and is measured in units
of quoted currency.
So this is a very important formula to remember and we'll talk about it further in the next tutorial