Hello this is Kirill from spot dot com.
And welcome back to the course and for its trading today we'll be conducting our next trade on our real
life Forex account.
So today we'll be trading the Australian dollar Canadian dollar one already time frame and I'd like
to mention that the strain of Canadian dollar currency pair is quite interesting because it consists
of two commodity currencies the kabaddi currencies on the market are the Australian dollar Canadian
oil and New Zealand dollar and their cold sides because the economies of the respective countries heavily
depend on commodities such as grain timber oil natural gas and so on.
And so the movements of these currencies are often dictated by and correlated with the movements of
those commodities.
So trading that trillion dollar Canadian dollar has its own specifics and it's quite quite interesting
and time so I think this will be a good example to kind of illustrate what other currencies they are
that are currency pairs that don't involve the American dollar.
So as you can see on this account we already now have $595 on 81 cents.
If we go to the county's history we can see our two profitable trades from previously.
And what we're going to do today is we go into conducta or third.
So on this chart I have highlighted some things and right away you can see that the Australian dollar
Canadian dollar currency pair has recently been in a channel so are really the currency standard bouncing
around in this shorter channel.
And then the channel expansion that sometimes happens.
And so the low boundary became the middle line of the channel and now the currency has been bouncing
in here for a couple of days actually since since Christmas.
So now we're in January 2015.
Happy New Year by the way.
And so we're going to conduct this trade now.
One more thing if we zoom on we can see that generally speaking it is a downward trend so what's happening
right now is a retracement and we should be very careful when trading these because the currency can
turn around at any point in time.
So that's why we're going to trade quite conservatively setting I'll take profit.
Not even at the very end of the Tuborg of the channel but rather around this high that we had seen previously
over here.
Also what you will see is that there is a level here zero point ninety six.
So I'll just point it out here just above the blue line is zero point ninety six and that level is quite
strong quite strong resistance level as you can see here here here.
Traders are generally afraid of it.
So I'm quite skeptical about the price crossing this level so we're definitely going to see it take
profit below that level.
So we've got to take profits where we will set the profit here.
We'll enter at market price and the stop loss well the loss.
I chose to said just below the zero point ninety five level because the zero point ninety five level
was quite a strong support level and we can use it to protect our investments are included in our strategy
and I expect if the price does go down then it might bounce back off around the 0.25 mark and that level
has proven like you can see here and around these areas here you can see that level has proven to be
quite strong when it comes when the price comes towards it.
So without further ado let's move on to calculating the risk and then we can open the order for Kalka
and the risk we will need to know Stop-Loss and pips.
So here we have approximately seventy pips of of for our stop loss soldiers bring up slides from there
we're familiar with.
So we need to take the risk in dollar terms and divide by 10 times Stop-Loss and pips.
So in our case we wanted the risk in dollar terms to be approximately 10 percent of the balance and
that's because we're taking a very short trade we're not going to ask for a big movement and it is quite
a good signal even though it is in the counter-trend movement.
But at the same time we are headed towards the top of that channel.
So 10 percent of $595 81 is approximately $60.
So we put that into the formula and now we can also plug in our stop loss and pips which was approximately
73 pips.
And now if we calculate that I'll just bring up the calculator here.
So 60 divided by 10 times 73 makes it a zero point zero eight lots.
So that's good.
Now we can exit this presentation screen pops up and so will type 0.0 lots Stop-Loss.
Is there a point 9 4 8 0 tech profit 0 9 5 9 0 comments.
My search for X order and it's an execution.
We want to create a buy order.
Everything is ready just double check very quickly currency pairs correct.
Click buy and avoid the orders ready.
Zero point zero eight lots.
If we go into the trade tab over here we can see that the orders up over there.
And right now we're in a bit of a minus.
And that's because the spread.
So we'll leave it at that and check back in hopefully maybe today so these vertical lines is a period
separate as that means and New Day according to server time.
So maybe today maybe maybe the day after.
Hopefully we'll get a result and hopefully we'll get a take profit on the order.
I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial.
Until next time happy trading.