Hello, everyone.
My name is David Tucker, and welcome to the course,
Implementing and Operating AWS Machine Learning Solutions.
I'm a CTO consultant, and I help organizations every day plan,
build, and implement custom software and data solutions in the cloud.
I have over 15 years of experience in software architecture and development.
Machine learning implementation and operations is one of the four domains
covered by the AWS Machine Learning Specialty certification exam.
In this course, Implementing and Operating AWS Machine Learning Solutions,
you'll learn key areas from this domain that are covered in the exam.
Now, when working in machine learning, training a model is only the first step.
In this course,
I will teach you about what happens when you're ready to
deploy the model that you've created.
First,
you'll explore different AWS services that can support a
machine learning solution in production.
Next,
you'll discover how to deploy and scale a machine
learning model with Amazon SageMaker.
Finally,
you'll learn how to implement security best practices for
your machine learning solution with AWS.
When you're finished with this course,
you'll have the skills and knowledge in this domain that you need to prepare for the AWS Machine Learning Specialty certification exam.