So here within this module,
we're going to be talking through how we deploy a SageMaker model.
Let's quickly revisit the overall SageMaker process. We can start off
with labeling our data, then building our models,
training and tuning those models, and then ultimately
deploying and managing our models.
So if we look here,
we're going to be focused here on this deployment
section of the overall process.
And to do that, we're going to be going through several things in this module.
First, we're going to be examining different deployment approaches for SageMaker,
and one of those will be reviewing the capabilities
of batch transform for inference.
And then, we'll be reviewing capabilities of SageMaker Hosting Services
for inference. We'll also cover how you utilize multiple production
variants when you're using SageMaker Hosting Services, and we'll look at
how we actually deploy a model. We'll walk through that process on
SageMaker Hosting Services.
So first, let's discuss the deployment approaches that exist within SageMaker.
And when we're talking about deployment in SageMaker,
we're generally talking about two different approaches.
First, we have hosting services.
This means you're going to deploy an inference endpoint to integrate your
inference process into an existing workflow or application.
This is also sometimes referred to as online inference.
Then, we have batch transform,
and this means you're going to perform an inference job on an entire
dataset that's already stored within Amazon S3.
And sometimes this is referred to as an offline inference job.
So let's look first at hosting services.
So what are some of the use cases that exist?
Well, if you need to deploy inference to a secure API endpoint,
meaning you're going to integrate that end with
data that's coming from elsewhere, hosting services can be a great place.
And if that's into an application or workflow,
it will totally work using this approach.
Also,
if you don't have all the data that you're going to need
to perform inference on in the future, hosting services is a good solution.
However, in some cases, batch transform makes sense.
First of all, if you don't need that exposed endpoint for inference,
and part of the reason you might not need it is that you already have the
entire dataset on which you want to perform inference, or if you
potentially need to process an incoming dataset to remove records prior to
inference, batch transform makes sense.
Now we're going to dive into each of these in a bit more detail, and the first one that we're going to approach is batch transform.