So now that we've walked through the process of deploying on SageMaker,
we're now going to take a step back and discuss how we
secure our SageMaker implementation.
Now before we do,
we need to cover a couple of topics that you're probably already familiar with,
and one of those is the shared responsibility model.
But it's important to revisit it and understand what aspects apply to
working within SageMaker on your machine learning solutions.
So first of all, let's revisit what AWS says about security and compliance,
and they clearly state that they are a shared
responsibility between AWS and the customer.
So in this case,
we can't simply leverage SageMaker and assume that everything is
going to be secure with our implementation.
So here, within this module, here's what we're going to be covering.
First of all,
we will be reviewing the shared responsibility model in
terms of SageMaker and even more generally just your machine
learning efforts on the platform.
We're going to be examining some high‑level security
and compliance considerations.
We'll be exploring VPC configurations for SageMaker,
as well as controlling access to resources and data using
IAM or identity and access management.
We'll also be reviewing how you can secure your SageMaker notebooks.
So with that being said, let's look here at the shared responsibility summary.
So there really are two different categories.
We have some things that are the responsibility of AWS,
and this many times is phrased as the security of the cloud.
But then we have the other side.
Those are the things that are the customer responsibility.
And we'll generally call this the security in the cloud.
And so if we look at these high‑level items,
which again, if you've taken an AWS associate‑level certification exam,
you've certainly walked your way through this or
even the cloud practitioner exam.
So here we know that it's AWS responsibility to do things like
access and training for Amazon employees,
for their global data centers and the underlying network,
hardware for global infrastructure, configuration management for infrastructure,
and patching cloud infrastructure and services.
So when we think about this in terms of SageMaker,
in terms of the network that it's actually communicating on,
in terms of the software that's actually running as
a part of the managed service, those things are handled by AWS.
But we have several areas of responsibility as well,
and here we're going to take a lens to focus on those
things that relate to machine learning.
So first of all, we have individual access to cloud resources and training.
Now the access to cloud resources,
this is going to be specific to how we leverage identity and
access management, or IAM, to control access to both
SageMaker and resources like notebooks, for example,
and even our data that's stored in Amazon S3.
And we'll cover that later within this module.
Then, we have dataset security and encryption.
And here, we're talking about both in transit and at rest,
and we'll be covering this next here within this module.
But then we have things like operating system,
network, and firewall configuration.
Now one of these things that really applies when we're working with SageMaker
is the network and firewall configuration. We can launch SageMaker into one of
our VPCs and then control what has access into that VPC. And we can also look
at how we handle communication within that VPC to AWS services like Amazon S3.
We also here have the responsibility for all of the code that we deploy onto
cloud infrastructure, as well as patching guest operating system and custom
applications.
So at a high level, when we look at how we leverage the platform for
machine learning, here are the things we need to be concerned with,
data protection. That has to do with the data security and encryption
that we discussed earlier.
We need to look at authentication and authorization,
and this has to do with IAM and the work that we'll do there.
It also has to do with compliance because for many of you,
depending on the industry or vertical that you're working in,
this can be a key area of concern.
So we will spend time later in this module talking
about compliance. But also, monitoring.
Now we'll be jumping into monitoring within the next module, but
this is an area that you need to be focused on. But also, securing
infrastructure and, especially here, the network configuration around our infrastructure.