So now that we've reviewed batch transform,
we're going to be looking at how we leverage SageMaker Hosting Services.
Now SageMaker Hosting Services provides a scalable real‑time
inference REST endpoint for your models that can be integrated
into your applications and your workflows.
So let's, at a high level, understand how this works.
So let's say, for example, we have a client mobile application,
and it's going to need to interact with our SageMaker model for inference.
Well,
our client application will need to interact with something, which
probably in the beginning will be API Gateway.
Now there are multiple ways that we can handle how our client
applications interface with our SageMaker model.
But for now, we're going to choose a normal case approach.
So API Gateway will handle things for us like authentication and authorization,
and then it will work with a lambda function.
Now this lambda function is not a part of SageMaker Hosting Services,
and to be honest, it can be optional.
But most implementations that I have worked with have leveraged this
integration function. And part of the reason is is that it is going
to exist within a virtual private cloud,
and we'll talk more a later module about how this factors in to the security
approach you're taking for securing your SageMaker models.
Now this lambda function will be what ultimately
interacts with SageMaker Hosting Services.
So first, this lambda function will reach out and invoke the endpoint.
And the endpoint is what we have configured to work with
any outside application or workflow.
Now the endpoint itself is going to reference a load
balancer because one of the great benefits of SageMaker
Hosting Services is that it can scale.
So this load balancer will be able to communicate with many
different instances that have been spun up that are able to
perform inference on our model.
So the load balancer will know how to then integrate with each
of those instances that have been spun up.
Now each of those instances will need to have
access to get to our trained model,
which is going to be served within an S3 bucket.
Now later within this course, we'll talk about approaches where this can
be more tightly integrated into the virtual private cloud that we've
created to secure our SageMaker deployment. Now let's talk about some
general notes about how we actually deploy to SageMaker Hosting Services
and actually make this work.
And there are three key steps that we need to take.
The first is that we need to create a model within SageMaker.
So even if we have trained a model within a Jupyter Notebook,
we need to have away to actually register this model so that it can be
used from other infrastructure that SageMaker spins up.
So we need to give our model a name,
and we need to specify where it's stored within Amazon S3.
Then, we need to create an endpoint configuration,
and this is going to specify details about our endpoint,
including things like the model that we're going to be deploying,
as well as the instance size and the number of initial instances
that need to be launched for that endpoint.
And then once we have this configuration in place,
we can then go through the process of actually creating
an endpoint from that configuration.
And once the endpoint is up and running,
we can then integrate it in with our applications.
Now let's talk about those endpoints.
There's a few things we need to note. First, endpoints are
secured with HTTPS, and we'll talk more about different
security approaches in a later module.
Also, endpoints can autoscale based on defined minimums and
maximums. So you can set a minimum and a maximum number of
instances that it will scale to. Now in addition,
endpoints can be updated without downtime. So you can update
your endpoint configuration for an endpoint.
And it supports A/B testing through using multiple production
variants. And in the next clip, we'll walk through what production variants are and how you leverage them.