So next,
we're going to talk about how we control user access using a
service called IAM or Identity and Access Management.
Now we're going to do a bit of review around some best
practices with IAM here within this module.
And the first best practice we need to review is least privileged access.
And we should use this,
whether we're doing machine learning or whether
we're doing any other tasks on AWS.
And at a high level,
what this means is we're giving a user the minimum permissions that they
need to accomplish what they need to do and no more.
This helps us make sure that we're not granting access based on,
well, this person's in this team,
and we just want to give them access to everything.
No,
we need to scope the ability for what they can do down to only what they need.
Now let's talk about the two different areas of responsibility for AWS IAM.
The first is authentication,
and authentication just validates that a user is who they say they are,
and it usually does that by validating the credentials that they submit.
Now the other side of IAM is authorization,
and we'll be looking at this quite a bit because this controls what the
users can do do once they have been authenticated.
Now as a general note here,
one of the things that you need to enable for your account is
what we call MFA or multi‑factor authentication.
This provides additional security by leveraging either a physical or
virtual device that generates a token for login.
Now there are ways to enforce MFA on all of the
accounts within your AWS account,
and I would encourage you to look at that if you're an
individual who manages IAM for your organization.
Now at a high level,
there's some IAM concepts that I want to be sure that you're familiar with.
First of all, there are three different types of identities within IAM.
The first and probably the most logical is the user.
So you can have a user account within IAM and within that have access to
specific features on AWS and then not have access to others.
Now in addition to users, we also have groups.
And groups allow you to manage permissions for a group of IAM users.
So, for example,
if you have data scientists and they all need to have access to specific
S3 buckets that have some of your organizational data,
you could configure that with a policy on a group.
And the next identity type is the type of a role,
and the role enables a user or AWS service to assume
permissions for a specific task.
So, for example,
we'll have roles that SageMaker can leverage so that SageMaker can perform
actions against resources that we have in AWS. Now the way that we assign
permissions is through the use of policies within IAM.
And now policies are written in a JSON format,
so that's just a JSON document that defines those permissions.
And it defines both the services that the identity can access
and what actions can be taken on that service.
So it's not like, for example,
everyone that has access to SageMaker can go in and delete endpoints.
You can choose who has access to what actions in what service. And
these policies can either be customer managed,
meaning that you create them and you keep them up to
date, or they can be managed by AWS.
AWS has some things already in place in policies that they manage.
Now let's look at some of the example SageMaker actions that we
have already leveraged within this course.
And this would be things like creating an endpoint,
creating an endpoint config, creating a model,
updating an endpoint, and creating a training job.
So you need to think about the different actions
that your users would need to take,
and then you go through the process of defining those within a policy.
Now here is an example policy that's going to be specific for SageMaker. And
we can see here that there are two different statements.
This first statement is allowing an action. We can see here
that the effect is allow. And in this case,
it's going to be enabling all actions for SageMaker.
So when we look at action,
it's going to take the format of a service and then a colon.
And then after that colon, it's going to be the specific actions on the service.
Now if you choose to use this asterisk in place of a specific action name,
it will apply to all actions within that service.
Now we're also specifying the resource that it applies to.
So maybe you want to give a user access to a specific notebook.
You could configure that for that resource. But in this case,
we're using the asterisk,
which means that this enables this, it allows it,
for any resource within SageMaker.
Now the next, we have a different kind of statement,
and this enables the user to actually pass a role to an AWS
service. For example, here, we're specifying that we want to
be able to pass this for SageMaker.
Now where would this apply?
Well, for example,
when you use a notebook instance, you're actually passing a
role that allows that notebook instance to access services on
AWS through that role's behalf.
Now let's look at some best practices for how we're using.
IAM with SageMaker.
First of all, as mentioned earlier,
you should define least privilege access for each user using IAM policies.
You also should make sure that your users are leveraging
multi‑factor authentication or MFA.
In this case, SageMaker supports identity‑based policies,
not resource‑based policies.
So you're going to be defining those policies like
we've done before based on identities.
Now other services like Amazon S3 give you the ability
to define resource‑based policies,
but we're not going to be doing that here. Now one of the great
things is you don't have to start from scratch.
AWS has provided some sample policies within the
documentation that are specific to different use cases you'll encounter when you're using SageMaker.