So next, we're going to discuss some additional deployment considerations.
So first of all,
we're going to be looking at the concept of Amazon Elastic Inference.
Then, we'll be looking at multi‑model endpoints.
And finally.
we'll be looking at inference pipelines.
So first, let's look at Amazon Elastic Inference.
So Elastic Inference gives you access to a fractional GPU as opposed to
fully dedicating a GPU to your inference instances.
In this case, you get that fractional GPU,
which is also a fraction of the overall cost of a fully dedicated GPU.
Now it's important to note here, this isn't supported in all use cases,
and it only works with frameworks that have been pre‑configured to work with it.
So the support here will vary,
and you need to look at the documentation if you're considering this to see
if the framework you're planning to use is supported.
Now next, let's talk about the concept of multi‑model endpoints.
Now this is a bit different from something that we discussed earlier,
and that's using multiple production variants.
But in this case, endpoints can serve multiple distinct models.
So let's say you maybe have five or six different models that
you use within your organization. Instead of having to spin up
infrastructure for each of those,
you could choose to deploy all of them to a single endpoint and be
able to serve each of those models distinctly.
It also supports multiple production variants on multiple models. So you
theoretically can have four or five distinct different models and then have
each of those with multiple production variants on each.
But note here, it doesn't support serial inference pipelines,
and we'll talk more about inference pipelines next.
It also does not support GPU instance types or Elastic Inference,
so there are some limitations there.
But this can greatly reduce your overall cost by leveraging existing
instances instead of having to spin up new ones for each model.
Now next,
an inference pipeline is an Amazon SageMaker model that is
composed of a linear sequence of two to five containers that
process requests for inferences on data. And in certain
situations, this can be a very powerful feature.
Now as mentioned, it supports two to five containers.
So we do have some limits here on how much we can do. And the communication
actually happens as HTTP requests between the containers.
So just like we kick off the process with an HTTP request,
it just continues chaining those requests together through each of
the containers that are a part of the pipeline.
Now the containers are located on the same EC2 instances,
so this really minimizes latency overall. There's able to be fairly
seamless communication between those containers.
And what it can do is it can enable a complete workflow
without you having to worry about doing any external data
pre‑processing or post‑processing. You can just integrate all of that into the pipeline.