[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
My name is Kevin Jones.
Welcome to my cause.
Architect ING web Applications With Spring I am a
developer and owner at Rock Solid Knowledge,
a software development company based in the United Kingdom.
There are many ways to structure an application this course
concentrate on something I call horizontal design.
With this, rather than break a project down into its layers,
such as database and services, we break the projects down into components.
Which component project contains all that component needs?
Some of the major topics we will cover include breaking a
spring application down into components.
Using spring repositories to access database is securing
the application with spring security,
separating concerns with met annotations and using
migrations to manage your database.
By the end of this course,
you understand the benefits of designing application around
components before beginning the course.
You should be familiar with Java,
and some familiarity with spring would also be helpful.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn how to design
spring applications with the architect ING web applications with spring course at Pluralsight