[Autogenerated] So I want to add a new project here on the project.
I'm going to ad will be our first component when we go in to
add a component that manages the articles.
I'm going to do most of this from insides Intelligent idea.
It's gonna be a great URL project,
so I need to create a greater bill file on import that
bill file in to idea sort of do that.
I'll do new directory here.
I will call our directory jacket articles and then in here I'll do new far on.
I'll call that build our cradle on this will obviously be
the bill file for this particular project.
So much of this bill file will inherit from the base project.
We'll see that fall in the moment,
but within here we need to specify a few things I
specify in the repository musing, which is J center.
I'm enabling the building of a jar file on giving that a name.
I'm turning off some of the spring features here's are not allowing
this particular project to build a boot jar file.
We only want to do that within our web project.
So once I have this bill fall.
I can now configure the root project.
And if I go into setting stock cradle,
you can add jacket articles as a project here,
a project to be included in our route project.
And then I also need to make some changes to the root build grade URL file.
So I need to specify dependencies here.
So currently, Jacket web is dependent on jacket repository,
so that's going to change.
Jacket web will be dependent on jacket articles and then,
for now, jacket articles will itself be dependent on jacket repository.
As we go through this particular module, we will get rid of Jackie Repository.
But baby steps also in here.
I have some integration around integration, testing.
We haven't talked about this yet.
We'll come back and cover this later in the course,
but I just need to add jacket articles to this.
Okay, So given that if I refresh grade URL on reimport all the greater projects,
then jacket articles is now seen as a project,
so the import hasn't created the source file structure for us.
Let's go and do that now.
So in here I want to create a new directory called SRC on.
Then underneath there.
I want to create all the appropriate sub directors.
So integration test Java integration test resource is main Java
Main resource is test Java and test resources.
Okay,
so one of the points of having this component is that this component will
contain it's own service code on its own repository code.
But the moment the repository code is in jacket repository on inside main.
Here we have calm.
Pluralsight jacket, data repository, and then article repository.
I want to move that repository code into the jacket articles project.
So inside Main Java, I create a new package.
This package will become Docker Pluralsight jacket article repository and a.
I'll move the article repository code into that package and it
will update the package name for me as well,
so that make sure it's in the right place on if I
do this and a rebuild the code.
The code still compiles as idea is smart enough to have updated
all the usages off this repository as well.
So remember we were using this in this controller,
so in here it now imports com Pluralsight jacket,
article repository.
So everything is compiling as it should be.
So now that we've added the repository to this component, let's go now to service to it