[Autogenerated] So I'm going to add a new sub project to this project.
This is going to be jacking security.
Obviously, this project is where will rely on our security.
So I'll do this in a similar way,
the way we added jacket articles earlier in this course.
So in my settings,
great URL file here will include a new project called Jacket Security and then
in the build greater file for this project will create a new project entry for
jacket security and then set up the dependencies.
So my jacket security project will depend on jacket entities.
Jacket articles will depend on jacket security on jacket.
Web will depend on jacket security.
I also need to update the integration tests,
so jackets security can also have integration tests if needed.
So, on my far system, create a new directory called Jacket Security.
And if I go back into idea and reimport the greater project build,
we see the Jackie security is now recognized on here as a project.
So inside here, I need to add a build file.
So I do a new file.
We call this build Docker cradle and a Bill find Looks like this and a.
It's the One difference here is that we have a compile time
dependency on spring Bootstrap charter security.
So this gives us the basis of our security project.
We also need to create the source directories here.
So in my jacket security,
I quit a source directory with integration test main and test in.
Each of these has a java and resource is subdirectory inside it and back inside.
Intelligent idea.
If I reimport cradle, then these directories are now correctly recognized.
So we've said the Jackie Security relies on Jack and entities.
And that's because inside Jack and entities is a Java class.
Come up onto the user's table.
We righted a class here called User.
This is the first name last name email in our password.
We've also added the relationship between our art class and a our users class.
That's the one to many relationship.
And then in the art class, we've added the corresponding change.
Added the minutes.
One relationship between article in user that a joint column to see how these things are joined together