[Autogenerated] So what about displaying the image is,
at the moment we can see the titles in the browser,
but we can't see the images that we've saved into the database.
So every time somebody adds a link to Jacket,
we capture a screenshot of the page.
They added the link from when they display the list
of links that they've captured.
We want to display that screenshot on the page, and so is part of our database.
We've got an image column that's a blob.
So we say the data in there we can then write a
method on the service to retrieve that data.
But we haven't implemented that yet, so it's just returns null.
Currently, this is what you want to implement now.
So to do this,
I've IDE to help a project here called Jacket Image and Jacket Image just as,
um,
methods on here to basically taken image or a bite
array on convert one to the other.
So if I get a set of base from the database,
I can convert those base into a Java image.
If I get a stream of the database I can convert that
stream into a job or image I can, use that in my service before I do that,
I need to update my entity so that the entity is able
to read the image from the database.
So I'm going to have a bite every object here with an annotation off
large object and then some getters and setters on this to allow me to
retrieve the image data from this article object.
So the gett article image method in the service looks like this.
We call fine by IDE on the repository to get back to the article.
This is an optional article.
So it's empty.
We throw an exception.
It's not empty.
We get the article from the option.
We then called get image on that article and then call get image
from Beit Array to return that bite right back to the caller on
that caller will be the controller.
So in the controller,
we can had a method that will be called from the browser to retrieve this image.
We are another.
You are all mapping for image slash image IDE which will be 123 or four.
This will be the IDE of the entity in the database we call
get article image on a service True.
Turn the image.
We know it's a buffet image.
Get the bite rate from that.
Turned this into a buttery resource on.
Then we returning the response bodies we return.
Okay.
HTTP.
Status see the content length to be the length of the bite.
Ray, we've retrieved see the content type to be image slash PNG.
That's the type of saved in the database.
I just populate the body with the base that we get back.
If I look in in next or HTML then the HTML AD DS an image tag on the source.
Attribute of that tag is slash article slash image on, then an IDE vary.
That's enough to send that request into the controller and the controller.
It'll hit this method.
The method will then reach up into the database,
pull out the data and return that data back to the page.
So if I say for that and we start the app if I go back to the browser,
just refresh.
We now see the snapshots.
So for each of these pages,
you get a snapshot of the page at the time the page was captured so
we cannot retrieve these images from the database. And it's all part of the articles component