[Autogenerated] So now that we've seen how to build our database schemers,
we now need to understand how to access the data in the database.
To do this, we can use a mechanism called spring data repositories.
So what are these things?
As we see on the slide?
It's an abstraction that provides access to different data stores,
which is not just about SQL we can.
Use this with no SQL stores, for example, it's interface based.
So for each interface, spring generates a proxy,
and that proxy contains functionality based on the
names of the methods in the interface.
So basically, it looks at the interface looks at the method names on then,
based on those method names, generates code that will do what those methods say.
So, for example, I've gotta find articles by title.
It will gender the SQL that we're reaching to the articles
table on pull out an article based on the title that I pass
to it Repositories are extensible.
We're going to use them in a fairly simple way here just
to give you an idea of exactly how these things are used
on where they should be used.
So the way we do this is we define our interface called something repository.
In our case, we can have an article repository and in this example,
here we see it extending a based interface called Repository.
We're basing this on an entity called article on.
We'll see what essentially looks like in a moment and a long.
This is the primary key for the table.
We saw that when we created the article to previously we indeed set upon ID
column on that ID column was a long value on that was set as the primary key
well and repository code to a repository project.
To do that inside here.
The first thing I want to do is to create two packages.
So a lot of package we'll have one called com Pluralsight jacket data models.
We'll have one called com Pluralsight jacket Data repository.
The data Models package will contain the entities for the database.
And a repository package will obviously contain the repository code.
So the first model we're going to have if I had a new class
to this is going to be called article.
This article class will contain the fields that will map
onto the columns in the articles table.
You've got the title field and URL field on the other fields that we need.
We need to tell it that it's an entity.
We used the entity annotation for this on.
We're going to tell it also that the table name is articles.
So I'm sort of following a similar convention again that the Ruby folks
use whereby table names of Pluralsight and entity names.
A singular so select article from articles seems to make sense to me.
It's the table.
Name is articles.
Our entity name is article.
Now notice in here.
I don't have an IDE value for this class.
Well, im going to have is all of my entities extending a class called base model.
My base model class is the one that will contain things that all my models need,
such as an ID.
So if I generate, that class is going to go into my model's name.
Space on that class is gonna look like this.
It has an IDE.
I'm telling you that the IDE is a generally feels that this is an
identity field inside my SQL and it's a long value.
Remember that the repository is going to use a long for its IDE.
We have a get ID method.
There's also an equals method and a hash code method as part of this class.
If I save both of these than all this code now compiles and
there's no errors or warnings anywhere in the code,
So these will be our entities.
Now that we have these we can go on and design a repository to do this,
I'll first added interface called articles repository to repository package and
in this interface will extend the base repository interface.
I'm making sure I bring in the right name spaces.
So if I look at the repository interface, I'm extending here, we'll see.
This is an interface of tighty and ID.
ID is gonna be something like long Orent or whatever.
Our primary key type er's then tea is a type of the repository holes.
So article in our case.
So it's just a market interface.
I noticed that are no defined methods on here,
So any work we want to do with this repository we have to
do by adding methods to our interface.
If we do that, spring will generate a proxy for us.
Based on those method names.
However,
we can choose other base classes that we already contain
method names that we might want to use,
so let's take a look at one of those first.
So the first these repositories and a one will make use
of here is called Cried Repository.
You can imagine with credit repository.
It has methods such as create, read, update and delete for us.
So let's take a look at how we can use that in our code.
So to use the crowd repository ID, simply say credit repository here,
updating the packages on.
Then,
if I browse the crowd repository type will see the crowd
repository as various methods already defined on it.
There's a save method that saves a single entity.
There's a safe method that saves a collection of entities because they find by
IDE method on exist by IDE method of final method and so on.
So just useful methods that we could use this part of our already valid code,
which means that just by using crude repository on extending,
it will get a proxy that will implement those methods for us. We could then use those within the application, so let's see how we do that now