[Autogenerated] so in summary,
then we know that our application will consist of different layers.
They could be physical layers.
They could be logical layers on.
Traditionally,
we've built an application functionally to follow the physical layout.
What I'd like to do in this course is to show how we maybe should use the
logical layout on Build the application out of components.
We know that functionality cats across layers,
but ideally, we'd like to structure the application functionally.
So build it off these components.
I will see over the next four or five chapters how we do that.
So we know the application letter user interface.
We know we'll have some services on.
We know we'll need to access data.
One of the key things you ever think about when building these
applications is how we manage the database.
Now it might be within your company.
You have a full database team on a design the schemers and lay
out exactly what the schemer should look like,
and you can't touch the database.
But in many companies, large and small, that's not always the case.
We as developers, are also responsible for the database schemer,
so we'll see how we do that.
It's also true that within the application will need to know how to
access that schemer how to access the database.
So what?
APIs what mechanisms to be used to do that, and that's what we'll cover in the next chapter.