[Autogenerated] So how do we bring this together?
Well,
there are a couple of things we have to do to plug
spring security into the Web application.
To make sure we get the password and code it set up
correctly For the web application configuration,
we have to add another method.
So we have a method called Configure Global.
The prime it has passed this method are passed in automatically by spring.
Here we're passing in authentication manager builder.
I use a detailed service and a password encoder.
We take the authentication manager builder and tell it
what use the detail service to use.
And that's going to be an implementation off our user details services.
And we also tell it what password encoded to use by calling
Docker password encoder on Use the detail service.
This will configure the web to use whatever use a
detail service has been set up for it,
so they use a detail services configured here.
This is our user repository user detail service on its market.
The service again, that's something we've seen before.
So this is a named instantiate,
the IOC container that's managed by spring and that will
be injected as it implements jacket.
User service on jacket users services extends user details
services that we plugged into our configure global.
The authentication manager builder comes from spring.
So what about the password in coda?
We need to specify the past winning code A we'd like to use when
we do that by configuring spring security.
So I go back to my jacket security project.
I'm going to add a new package here.
This would be my security config package ID into here.
I'm going to create a new class on.
This will be my security configuration class.
We'll use this class to configure our password encoder to notice.
Here we say as a configuration class, we want to enable auto configuration again.
I'm scanning the packages.
I'm scanning the com dot Pluralsight dot jacket dot security packages here.
The key thing here is we provide a bean,
which is a type of password encoder for that bean.
We returning a newbie crypt Password encoder.
So it uses be crypt to hash the password to place into the database for us.
It also uses be crypt to compare hashes when the user authenticates.
So what will this look like?
Well, if I run the application.
If I now browse to local host 80 81 it will now ask me to authenticate.
Now I can't get to the main URL.
I've set up the configuration to say everything other than log in,
log out and register must be authenticated.
Notice is still bringing back my HTML.
Still bringing back my CSS.
We've used matches to say I don't need to
authenticate when I access those things.
If I go to the register link,
I get my register page I can Fill this in so Kevin Acknowledge Spike Com,
then Kevin Jones and then enter a password and click on
register and a get taken to the main page.
There are no articles on the page.
We deleted the articles when we moved to this part of the course.
We'll have some more.
In a moment.
We'll see how that all works, However, following inside my SQL.
Look at jacket DB users you can see.
Indeed, I've got username Jones.
The email Kevin acknowledge bike dot com But notice the
password That password field is encoded.
That password field is encoded in a way that decrypt understands.
So I tried to log in.
I type in my password be crypt will again hash the password I type in and
compare the hash it create with this value in the password field.
If those two values match, then I'll be able to Log it TIFF.
I log out the application and go back to local host 80 81.
I should be able to log in so I type in my username type in my password,
Click on Logging on. Sure enough, we get back to the same place in the application.