[Autogenerated] We can also extend these repositories so we can
do that by adding our own methods to them.
So, for example, here we can have a fine by title method.
On this was January code to do a search in the articles table
for any article with this specific title.
We got to see how to do that now.
So back inside the code inside the articles repository I cannot.
Another method here without a fine by title method,
so find by title will return a list of article this will take.
A string on that string will be the title off the article.
Be trying to find what will happen when I add this and we compile.
The code is that spring, when it generates the proxy will generate this method.
For me, it knows there's a title property,
you know, a database,
and it will generally code to find things in the database based on that title.
So let's see if we can use this So in the article controller,
rather than doing a final here, let's do a fine by title on passing news on.
Then, if I rerun this code, then go back to the browser and a refresh.
Then we only get the one entry is this is working on its
returning the correct values from the database.
So what if we try and add something that doesn't exist?
So if I go back to my repository, duplicate this line rather than find by title,
that's are fine by person.
Now there's no person property in my database on If I rerun this so notice,
I don't even need to use this on spring blows up.
If I look in the console window here when we get an error,
which is this unsatisfied dependency exception,
we can't create the being article controller.
The reason we can't create the article control of being is
that we can't create articles repository.
So even though idea doesn't detect, this is invalid.
This blows up a runtime even before we even try and use the method.
So spring is very powerful in the way that it can detect these methods
forests and generally code based on the method names. So long as those properties exist