[Autogenerated] So now that we have all these pieces in place,
once the user is authenticated,
we'd like to be able to use that user and a only get back the
articles for that user we can do that in the controller.
So currently, in the controller,
we have a mapping for slash article from which we call our index method,
which is here.
What we'd like to do here is to say I want to map the currently
authenticated user to a parameter of this method,
then use that user to go and get the articles associated with them.
So what I could do is that a parameter here on market
with the act authentication principle, which is a spring security annotation,
make this parameter of type authenticated user and call it user.
The problem with this approach is that authentication principle
comes from spring security ID like to isil it my use of spring
security into the security project.
I don't really want spring security to be directly
used inside my web application.
So instead of using that annotation,
what we can do is to create our own annotation
something called a meta annotation.
So back in the spring security project,
if I create a new package that I'm going to call security annotations
and in here we're going to create a new annotation.
So if I do new annotation,
the annotations good to be called current user and annotation Looks like this.
These key thing here is that this annotation is itself annotated
with the authentication principal annotation.
So this is a met annotation that we can then use elsewhere in our code.
This sanitation is specific to our application domain.
We can use this elsewhere in our code.
Our code is now only indirectly related to the spring security.
If we decided to take out spring security and do something else we can do
that without changing the annotations in our own code.
So to use this inside the controller,
I add the annotation AD CS current user authenticated user user
So user is a type off authenticated user.
Then when I call,
get all articles I can pass in the user IDE So I say username get IDE
So we need to change get all articles so it takes an ID Then we have a
method on the article services caught find by user ID which uses that
ID This method will pass back.
All the articles associated with that ID will then pass those articles
back to the HTML to be displayed inside the browser.
So I can now go to the browser and try this out.
So now I've added some articles and I've added to users.
So if I go in and log in as the first user is my
knowledge spike address type in my password,
we get three articles under that user.
If I log out of that,
use their and then log in with my rock solid knowledge dress.
We get one article without user we can.
See how we use this authenticated principal inside our code to deliver the user information to the application that we need.