[Autogenerated] So what have we done?
We've written an application where we code mostly to logical layers.
We tried to break out the components.
We've broken out security.
We've broken out articles.
Anything else you regard is component.
Should have broken out in the same way we've added testing.
We've done integration testing.
We've done unit testing.
We've also integrated security into the application as well.
To even a security is a cross cutting concern.
It cuts across all parts of the applications.
We can still isolate security into its own project.
So thank you for listening.
I'm watching. And I hope you enjoyed this course.