Welcome back everyone in this section of the course we're going to focus on flasks deployment actually
getting our local class applications to live live on the web.
So in order to do this we're going to be using the Heroku platform since really it's one of the easiest
to use for initial deployment.
Now before we use Heroku we'll need to install some command line tools and create our application.
The basic steps we're going to do are the following.
We'll start by installing some libraries and command line tools that will actually allow us to connect
our local application and then push it to the Heroku platform then we're going to need to create a flask
app you can use any of the applications you've already been building throughout the course or just create
a simple Hello World app it's up to you then you create a requirements that text file.
So you make sure all the requirements for the application are going to be pushed and installed live
on the web that will create what's known as a proc file or a process file essentially just the list
of process commands and we'll talk about that more in detail later.
Then we're going to create a Heroku account and then we'll push and launch the application.
So let's get started.
The first thing to do is visit our command line and I'll visit the command line at Adam and we'll kind
of do create in the flask application and install in the command line tools at the same time.
So for this deployment I'm going to be deploying just a very simple Hello World app that where we can
really focus on the deployment process.
Let's get started hopping over to Adam.
OK.
Here I am at Adam.
I've opened up a new folder it's called deployment example.
And right now it's totally empty.
So we're just going to create a new file right here and I'm going to call it app dot pi.
So I have this app that pi is just a very simple python file and I'm going to do the following.
I'll say from flask import flask.
Then we'll say app is equal to flask underscore underscore name and then we'll create just the very
simple route for the home page.
So the home page route is just going to be index and we're not going to have a template.
We're just going to return right off the bat saying this is working.
So if I am able to launch the Web site and see the text this is working that I know everything's working
and you can expand this deployment process to any of the applications we've created throughout the course
we're just using a really simple one here so we don't have a bunch of files to deal with.
OK then we're going to say if name is equal to mean go ahead and run our application.
So save that we have an application that's basically the main step.
And again you could have used any of the applications we've done so far.
The next hour to do is really to create a virtual environment.
So we'll do the following.
I'll say Konda create dash n and I'm going to call this flask deploy and then we'll add in that I want
flasks to be installed.
So notice the spacing here and basically saying create this new environment called Flast deploy and
then install flask in that new environment.
So hit enter.
And what should be happening here is it will create the environment for us and then install flask in
that environment.
So I'm going to jump forward in time until this is done.
Installing it may ask you if you want to proceed.
Go ahead and say why.
All right so my virtual environment has now been created.
So if you scroll up here there should be instructions on how to activate it for Window users.
It's just activate Flast deploy and then deactivate if you're on Mac OS or Linux you're going to need
to say Source activate or source deactivate.
So let's activate this flasks deploy and make sure everything's working well see activate flask deploy
enter and then you should see that it is now activated.
So what are you going to do here is with your virtual environment activated you're going to install
any required libraries for your flask application.
So those can be things like flask in or flask sequel alchemy.
In this case I'm really just using Flash.
So I already installed everything I need.
But for larger applications this is where you would begin to install all the required libraries for
your application.
Let's make sure that our application is actually working by quickly running it locally.
So say Python app that PI enter and lets visit our browser to make sure that we don't have any local
issues.
If I bring in my browser I can see this is working.
So we successfully launched it locally which means it's ready for primetime on the live web.
So I'm going to exit this Control-C then we have one more thing we want to install in this virtual environment
and that's green unicorn or G unicorn.
So we can say pipin stall G unicorn and that's basically going to allow us to correctly render this
on the web green unicorn or unicorn is a python web server Gateway Interface for Unix that is basically
a pre fork worker model.
You don't need to worry too much about how it works in the background.
Basically you just need to worry that you installed that or not to go ahead and Pipp install unicorn.
And we'll be using that when we actually the player application.
Next up we want to do is save all of these requirements to a requirements that text file that way for
using other libraries like Flast log in or flasks sequel alchemy.
We have a requirement a text file that basically has everything ready to go that we need to install.
So we'll do the following.
We're going to say Pip freeze and then pointed to requirements.
Make sure you spell that right requirements.
Textfile it's going to zoom in so you can see this all in one line or zoom out Pip freeze two requirements
that text enter and then after running that command you should see that you've created a requirements
alt text file in the same folder that has everything you need.
OK so now that's ready to go.
The next step we want to do is create a proc file or a process file.
So in this same deployment example folder I'm going to say new file and then call this capital P R O
C f i l e and this has to be spelled correctly so you don't make any typos here enter.
And this process file you can already see it looks like a kind of Heroku logo here on ATOM.
All we're going to do is type the following and I'm going to zoom in here so make sure you don't get
any typos.
Are you going to say is web colon space unicorn space app Colan app and then save those changes.
So all this is just basically telling us hey we're going to use green unicorn to run this flask application.
So this is just like one line per process and this is what this is basically roughly translating to.
So again make sure you spell all of this correctly and get your spacing correct.
Now we have two things left we need to do locally before we can push this to the Web.
And that is installed get and install the Heroku command line interface tool.
So in order to make that we have to come over to Heroku see Elyse if you just google search Heroku Seelye
or go to this link right here under the Data Center the Heroku dot com.
You should see the download and install link.
Now as mentioned the Heroku command line interface here it's going to require gets which is a version
control system.
So if you if you do not already have it installed you're going to need to install it before.
So they have links right here for installation so you can just click on that link and they also have
instructions for first time get set up.
So right here and get it says getting started installing it you're going to follow the instructions
notices instructions for Linux Mac.
And if you keep scrolling down.
There's also instructions for installing on Windows and there's several ways to do it.
So go ahead and follow the instructions from this Web site on the fly on how to install gets and then
set up get for the first time again.
It's all just here really you just need to worry about installing it.
You don't really have to set it up to the specifications here.
So once you've installed already then you need to install the Heroku command line interface or that
command line tool.
And then we have different installations so if you're on a Mac OS you can download the graphical installer
or if you use homebrew you can brew install it on Windows and if you are on 64 bit 32 bit just click
on one of these installers or if you're on a YouTube you can just run this command right here.
Pseudo snap install Heroku dash dash classic.
And that right ran and running that on your terminal will install the command line for Ubuntu.
Now there's other insulation methods in case none of those work for you as well including tar balls.
OK.
So just follow these instructions on how to install a command line interface for Heroku.
And again you have to install it to make sure that works.
I've already installed the command line interface so I won't need to install it myself.
So once you've installed that then we're going to do is go straight to Heroku and set up an account
there.
So go to w b w the Heroku dot com and create a free account and then log in.
Once you create a free account on Heroku on their main Heroku dot com sign up page after you've logged
in.
It should take you to dashboard that Heroku dot com.
And then by default it goes to forward slash apps.
We're going to do is create a new app so we know our app is using Python.
So if you want you can click on Python and this will give you an introduction on kind of full step by
step including a lot of stuff we've already gone over.
This one's on jingo.
You can search the documentation for the flask applications.
For now we're going to walk you through it.
So we're going to sit here and create a new app.
So all these are getting started guide but we'll hit the create new app button and then go ahead and
give your app a name.
So I'm going to call this my cache flask deploy a demo app.
I'm going to select a region United States.
Keep in mind this has to be kind of uniquely available and then go ahead.
You don't need to worry about adding to the pipeline.
You can just hear create app and this will basically instantly create the application for you.
Now what you need to do is take what we have locally and deploy it to this flask application that's
living on Heroku.
Once you've done this what we're gonna do is we're going to use the Heroku command line interface in
order to actually deploy this.
And the directions we're going to follow are actually all right here first.
Again you have to install the Heroku Seelye.
Once we've done that you're going to log in at your command line.
So let's go ahead and do that.
All right.
So the first thing we need to do is Heroku log in after running this line.
It's going to ask you to enter your e-mail and your password.
So go ahead and do that.
So now you should see that you're logged in.
So I'm going to clear my screen now.
And now that we're logged in make sure you've seeded into your actual project folder.
I'm already located in my diploma example folder.
So I'm good to go there.
Next we want to initiate a get repository.
So I say get space I an I.T. Remember you can basically just copy and paste these lines from that last
website we're on.
So we just initialize an empty repository.
So now what I'm going to do is type out Heroku space get colon remote space dash.
And then the name that I chose from my flask application which was my dash flask that deploy dash them
up yours is going to be slightly different depending on what you actually called your application.
Remember I'm essentially is copying and pasting everything from what Heroku is telling us to do on this
web page.
So again you can always copy and paste that.
So I enter and it looks like we're good to go there.
So the next thing is to actually begin to the player application.
So we have this empty get repository.
We're going to commit our code to it.
We'll say get space at DOT.
So then after that we say get commit space dash am and you can just leave yourself a little message
here and quotes such as first commits or make it better or every happened to type in there they enter.
And that's going to add in those files of the repository and then we'll say get push Heroku master enter
and then it's going to deploy our application.
So notice it's right now installing everything that was in that requirements file.
Once that's done you should see somewhere that has a phrase saying your application has been deployed
to Heroku.
So now actually have this URL I can visit and it should be deployed there.
So let's copy that.
All right click copy.
And let's actually see if it worked.
So I'll copy and paste that in if I come over here.
This is live on the web.
This is no longer local notice it's my last demo app Hiroko outcome.
And I see this is working.
OK.
So that's the application deployment process for flask with Heroku.
Hopefully you saw that it was actually really easy to set up and most importantly it was all free.
So there are paid tiers of Heroku if you intend to have a really large application of a ton of visitors.
But really for very simple applications where you just intended to be visited by just a few people the
free tier could work very well for you.
So keep that in mind if you have any questions.
Definitely check out their fool guides.
What we did here was kind of just a quick guide to the playing of Heroku but rUK Heroku has really full
detailed guides on using things like preexisting databases like a postscript sequel or my sequel database.
They even have guides on how to use an existing get repo.
So if you already had an existing repository you could clone it.
And that's actually the same instructions that are on here.
So remember we just follow these instructions.
But it also has instructions later on if you want to connect to get a hub or even connect to things
like Dropbox so lots of different guides here that documentation is actually really really good and
Heroku.
So it would definitely tell you to check that out if you want to do some more complex tasks.
But for now we've successfully deployed our simple application to the web.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.