Welcome everyone to some level 2 section of the course in some level.
We're going to discuss some more advanced topics such as scope object oriented programming.
We'll have a quick project to test your O.P. skills.
Then we'll talk about decorator's.
We'll talk about this name equals mainlined that shows up in a lot of Pi scripts and then we'll talk
about how to create your own modules.
I'm going to assume that actually a lot of people are probably have some sort of experience with Python
and maybe just jump directly to Python level too.
I just want to make clear that if you're jumping straight into Python level two you should already have
an understanding of how functions and basic data types and data structures work with Python.
So if you don't feel comfortable functions quite yet maybe go back and review Python level one.
OK but that being said let's get started and start learning about these advanced topics.