Welcome everyone to Python level one section of the course.
Let's have a quick review of what we're actually going to cover in level 1 and in the next section.
Of course we'll start with Python level 2.
But for this section level one we're really starting off with the basics here.
And if you're watching this I'm going to assume that you have very little to no experience in Python
because this really is going to start off with just the basics.
So we're talking about basic data types such as numbers strings lists and then will go on to discuss
basic data structures such as dictionaries tuples sets and we also talk about booleans.
They'll have a quick exercise go over those solutions then we'll begin to talk about control flow.
Basically if Elsin Elif statements and then we'll end the section by talking about functions and give
you a couple of tasks for you to complete.
And then the solution is for them.
OK.
So again if you already have enough Python experience where you feel really comfortable with functions
and just basic things like an if and else statement then you can probably feel free to just skip this
particular section entirely.
Maybe you can jump over and do the functions tasks first and then if you can pass all those then you
know you're ready to go to Python level 2.
OK.
With that all being said if you have any questions as far as what we cover in the section feel free
to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But if not let's go ahead and continue.
We'll see at the next lecture.