Welcome back everyone in this section of the course.
We're finally going to embark on a larger project that incorporates a lot of what you already learn
in the previous sections of the course.
So we're combining all the skills into a singular project.
We're going to be creating is a company blog page where multiple users can each log in with their own
user credentials.
They can create their own blog posts up they or delete their existing blog posts as well.
Plus we're also introducing some new concepts such as how to handle image files so every user is going
to have their own profile image.
Also show you how to add pages.
So for example if you ever go to a Web site where you can cycle through pages of many blog posts.
So in this case if we have more than five blog posts we'll go ahead and just shift those over to another
page.
We'll show you how to do that.
And we're also going to show you how to use modals which is basically a way that bootstrap allows you
to create pop ups.
So know step by step in this code along project so all of this code along that we can follow through
with us and see how to structure a larger project that will have multiple users on it.
So let's take a look at what the finished product is actually going to look like.
That way we can understand or building it head over to the browser now.
All right.
So this is the final product that we're actually going to be creating.
Looks wise we're not going to focus too much on the actual styling.
So overall it's not the most attractive web site.
Really what we want to focus on is the functionality so we can think of this as some sort of company
blog where multiple employees of the company are going to be able to create their own blog posts.
So notice here we have a home and about us page some log in page and a registration page.
So where you're going to be able to do once you complete this Web site it's going to be able to click
on register.
Here we have a registration form.
Again not the most beautiful looking registration form but here are just really focused on being able
to add the functionality with flask.
So let's go ahead and register and your user will say brand new at new dot com the username will also
have that be brand new password are you going to keep it simple keep it as brand new.
Same here.
So brand new We'll go ahead and click register then that takes us directly to the logon page.
We have an email and password.
Again very simple aesthetics wise.
So the email was brand new and you dot com and the password was brand new We'll click log in and now
we're logged then we still see the same home page but notice here now I can create a post so if I click
on Create a post I get a title for my post such as brand new title.
And then I have text so brand new text and I can just you know fill in whatever text I want here.
And then when I click on blog post essentially posting this.
Now I can see on the main company blog page as well as these other blog posts.
I have this brand new title written by brand new published on this etc..
Now if I read a blog post since this is my own blog post since I'm right now logged in as a brand new
user I can click update and then add some new stuff to it.
Maybe change the title.
Post this again.
Or I can also delete it and so happens when I click on delete.
I get this nice little pop up so I'll be showing you how to use bootstrap to create these pop ups as
well.
Cancel that deleting and if I go back to my home page right now if I take a look at other blog posts
written by someone else that I don't have the update and delete functionality.
So we're going to be able to smartly say OK only if you're viewing a blog that you created.
You can update it or delete it.
You can edit other peoples blogs as you would expect.
Now we can also check out the About Us page which is just info about the company.
And notice also how my own account page.
So if I click on my account I say welcome to the page for brand new.
I see this little profile image and I can update my username.
Update my email and I can also update my profile picture so I'll be showing you how to choose files
by uploading things and then updating it.
We have the default image but if you take a look at other users if we come back to home take a look
at written by 6.
This is the page for 6 against same profile image.
Since that's the default image but if we take a look at some other ones we've uploaded some other profile
images.
So if I take account pages I can then read other blog posts by the author.
So this offer just happens to be named 3.
We click on this and then we see the blog post.
OK and then we can always log out and come back to the company blog page.
All right.
I'm really excited to get started with this project.
It combines pretty much all the skills we've covered so far.
Whether it's authorization different views templates and a lot more we're also going to cover things
like those bootstrap methods that we haven't seen before and we're having to cover things like how to
make your own 404 pages.
So if you try to go to a page that doesn't exist we'll see how to customize our own for 4 pages to show
whatever we want to show.
OK let's go ahead and get started.
The first thing to do is just get an overview.
However setting up art projects will see you at the next lecture.