To finish off this section of the course I want to discuss these two ideas of name and then the string
main so often confusing part of Python is when you start looking at larger dot pie scripts that you
haven't written yourself you often see at the very bottom this mysterious line of code that says if
underscore underscore name underscore underscore is equal to the string underscore underscore main underscore
underscore colon and then there's a block of code to be executed.
So sometimes the whole idea behind that line of code is that we're importing from a module.
You would actually like to know whether a modules function is being used as an import or if you're using
the original but py file of that module.
So we're work to do is explore all of this a little bit more.
But make sure to check the full explanatory text file that has a written explanation of everything we're
going to cover here.
Well we're going to do basically is just create two simpled up postscripts and try to show you the idea
behind that.
If name is equal to main block of code that is usually at the end a larger dot PI script files.
Let's get started.
OK let's begin by actually creating two new files will create them at my desktop.
I will say for this first file save as and I'm going to say this as one dot pi.
So this one is one of pi.
Then I'll create a new file and I'm going to save this one as to that pi to that PI again at my desk
will level this one to that pi.
So make sure you have those saved.
So let's think about what actually happens when you call a Python script at your command line.
You go to your command line you type python space the name your script the PI.
So what's actually happening when you call Python my script that pi all the code that's the indentation
level 0 essentially something like this is going to get run.
So that means any code that takes the level 0 is going to get run.
And that would mean that your functions which are automatically usually going to be defined in the notation
a little 0 in your classes.
Also the indentation level 0 are all going to be defined.
So unlike other languages in Python there's no main function that you call somewhere at the top of your
script that gets run automatically.
Instead what happens is just implicitly all the code at the indentation level 0 gets run when you call
the script file and you probably have an intuition of that by now since we've been working through that
strategy.
The entire first half of the Course now in Python there is actually a built in variable called name.
So just like there's built in functions this is a built in variable and it's quite obvious that it's
built in because we have two sets of double underscores in the beginning and in the back of it.
So that would allow you to have to really try to overwrite it by accident.
So what happens is this variable name gets assigned a string the pending on how you're running the actual
script.
And if you run the script directly.
So if I went to the command line and I wrote out Python space one that PI with Python is going to do
it's going to assign this builtin variable called name to be equal to
underscore underscore mean.
So Python does this in the background.
Well it really does this.
It assigns the string to the name variable.
When you run it directly and that allows you to have an IF block to check if they're equal to each other
so often will you do something like this.
You say if name is equal to Main and then you can do something because you know that this particular
pipe file is being run directly.
And if you ever run something directly of Python you know this case happens to be true.
So happens is often people just at the very bottom of their code they'll say if name is equal to Main
and then they say kind of run a bunch of functions that they defined here.
So at top they do a bunch of function definitions so function of one function and two so on and so on.
So you can imagine hundreds of lines of function definitions or classes and then all the way at the
bottom they're actually organized or code on what they actually want to execute and they know that they
want to execute it because they say if this built in variable called name happens to be equal to the
string main then I know I'm running this py file directly.
So we're going to explore this whole idea a little further and to do that we're going to do the following
in one pie.
So let's go back here.
This is one that pi.
I will write out the following code.
I will say DPF create a function and this function is going to be very simple.
It will say func in one PI.
So when you call that function it says func in one that pi just printed that out and then I'm also going
to do here is at an indentation level of 0.
So outside of this function I will say top level in one dot pi.
So now I have a function definition as well as a global print statement top level and one that pi.
Then at the bottom of this I will say if you'll notice that's a blind text that will actually autocomplete
this for you if name is equal to mean.
I'm going to delete this.
So I have an IF block of code here.
So if name is equal to made that I know I'm running this directly.
So I will say one that pi is being run directly and then I'm actually going to lineup in ELSE block
with this if statement.
You don't see this that often usually you see if and then you execute your code.
But just to make it clear how this variable is working will also add in an else there will say.
Else.
Prince one PI has been imported.
So I'm going to save that.
And let's take a look at what happens.
I defined this function.
I print out this statement whenever you call 1 that pi and then depending if one PI is the main script
meaning and calling one PI directly at the command line I will print this out else that means the variable
name was not sent to Maine and I will print this out when that pie has been imported.
So now let's work with our second file to that pie what do here is say import 1 and I will print out
at the very top level.
Let's print out something like top level in two dot pie and since I just imported one let's execute
the function that's from one or say one that funk and here are going to have an if statement will autocomplete
this if name is equal to mean.
I will print two.
The pie is being run directly else.
Prince to the pie has been imported.
So let's save the changes in both of these and then open up our command line.
All right so the first thing we're going to do at our command line is actually run one up PI directly.
So we run this.
And we notice what happens.
We get that print statement top level in one PI and then we see from that if name is equal to mean one
that pi is being run directly.
So we can see here that that built in variable underscore underscore name underscore underscore has
been assigned that main string.
So Paice on the nose and the entire script canel that one that has been called directly.
But now let's check out Python to that pi.
So now when I run this notifier happens I get back toplevel and one that PI.
But now one that PI it's built in variable name has not been set to mean because it's been imported.
So now we get back one that pi has been imported and then I get top level and to that pie funk in one
pie and then to that Pye's being run directly.
So that built in variable actually allows you to see whether something is being imported or run directly.
So that's the idea in concept behind the variable name name and checking in physical to main.
Typically however what you see is people they don't really do it the way we've done here with a check
is something being run directly or not.
Instead if we come back to Sublime Text Editor what they do is instead of having an L statement here
since they just say if name is equal to me this is the same thing as saying run the script right.
Because we already know that if this happens to be the case and someone is running one that PI script
directly.
So what they do is they define a bunch of functions up here or find their classes.
So here's another function pass.
You write some other function function to say and then down here at the bottom what you end up doing
is you just call your function so you'll say OK execute function to then execute function 1 and then
maybe have a little bit of logic here but the main idea is that this is more for code organization.
You have all your functions and classes defined up here and then your logic where you actually execute
things are defined.
Here at the bottom and this is a really common structure you will see for larger that by scripts especially
when you begin to use modules and packages.
All right.
That's the basics of this line.
If name is equal to main.
Definitely check out the explanation that textfile that goes along with this lecture.
And if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'll see you at the next lecture.