Welcome back everyone.
So we just created a bunch of views.
Now it's time to actually connect those views to the corresponding templates for the blog posts.
Once you've done that we should pretty much be ready to actually explore the full web site.
There's going to be a couple of things that we're going to introduce as new topics during these templates
so let's get started.
All right if we take a look back at the views we created there's really just two templates that we need
to create.
One is to create post template and we're going to be using that both for updating the post and creating
an original post.
So how.
Create postdates smell is used in both of those.
Then the other one we're gonna have to work with is the blog post today.
L.
That's the code for just showing a single blog post.
Remember that we actually already created these files at least the basic HTL file for them in the previous
lecture.
Now it's time to actually fill them in.
I want to start with the Create post because that one is much simpler than the singular blog post.
So we're going to say extends from base that each team L and then we'll create our content BLOCK And
since we're just creating a post this is essentially just passing in that form.
So if we take a look back at creating that blog post Remember that are really doing is just passing
in that form.
Given the title the text and user ID so we just need to display that form on this page for the user
to fill out.
I'll go ahead and lead this as a container and then have my form here.
So I'm going to keep the class as a form group and then the method will be post and form group.
This class comes from the bootstrap documentation.
It's just going to make it look a little nicer.
So our method to post and we need to put in our hidden tag here so say form hit and tag so that security
tag can then work and then just so this looks a little nicer and do the same thing here and create divs
for form groups.
For each major section or field of the form so that will be for form title label and again will set
the class here to something from Bootstrap.
In this case it's going to be let's see form dash control dash label and then right after that we'll
say form that title class equal to form dash control space form control LG for large then just grabbing
these class names from the bootstrap documentation for forms.
It's really up to you how much in depth you want to go.
But I noticed that at least for the Create post it looks a lot better if we added these divs So I went
ahead and did that.
Then I do this one more time here.
So that's for the title.
The other one is going to be for the text so I'll say the text label and then the text as well here
and we can go ahead and keep the same classes.
Then finally one last div as a form group and this is going to be for the submit button so just say
form submit.
Class equal to.
In this case will be say between BTs and ash outline dash info OK we'll save that and that's actually
all we're going to do.
For the Create post template.
Now it's time to move on to the blog post template.
So we'll go to the blog post.
H tim l template that we created last time and we'll start off with the basics.
Extending from base each time L. and then creating our content blocks so say block content.
And this is the view that just shows a single blog post.
So we're going to start off with the following.
We'll create the vision for actually a Jumbotron here.
Up to you really how you want to style this.
I'm going to create a jumbotron and as the heading 1 I'll say grab the post title because remember passing
in the post and as it referenced when we're actually building out the views.
It's kind of up to you how much you want to pass back because if you check out our views and if we take
a look at the singular blog post view.
So this blog post viewer here actually already passed in the title as blog post title so I could just
say appear just title and that would be the title I passed back in.
It's up to you what you want to do.
Some people like passing it in individually over here on the Python side.
Other people just like keep passing in just the Singler blog posts and then you would call that they
thought title yourself off the template.
Again totally up to you how you prefer to style that.
So just to make sure we don't get confused.
I'll do everything off the post.
But remember we did passen title and date.
Individually you can play around with.
So kind of just trying to show you multiple ways of doing this.
Again there is no wrong or right way and they're both kind of just as efficient.
So they we want to say who this was written by psyching say grab that post grab that author grab that
username.
Again you can do this here at the template site or on the View site and then let's make header 3 and
this will be the publication date.
So say published and again we can say either grab that date that we did sent and manual in the views
or you could grab the date here and then you can even do things like structure it the way you want.
So I can say as TRF time and then passen print sees how I actually want the structured doots code so
I could say something like this.
And this basically says give me the full month the day and then comma the year so you could do it that
way again.
There is no right or wrong way to do this.
And then finally we actually want the content of the post so create paragraph here that has post text.
Ok so essentially just shows a single blog post.
However if the author matches the currently logged in user will want to display a button that allows
them to update or delete the post.
So we are going to do is right after this paragraph is at in a little bit of logic here.
I'm going to say if postop author is equal to the current user.
And remember we have access to this current user object because we're using Flast logon.
Then I will do the following.
And I have another little division here and this division is not going to be class just helped me organize
this and will have an anchor tied and will say the following.
I'm going to say that this anchor tag is going to be for updating and I'm going to create another anchor
tag.
It's actually going to be a button you a HDMI button and this one is going to be for the elite and you'll
see why in a second I'm using a button for the lead and just an acre tag for update.
So what's going to happen is if I click up here it's going to take me to the update view which means
my ref is going to be the URL for and then we're going to say blog posts.
Whoops.
The blog post blueprints grab the up the view and then pasan blog post ID is equal to the post ID and
I don't zoom in just a little bit so we can see the whole thing.
OK.
So that's just an anchor tag.
It's going to set up.
If you click on that it will come back to be used up high and then send you to this update by passing
in that blog post I.D. which basically kind of shows you things filled in already that you can then
start changing.
OK.
So that's if you the site to update if you decide to delete.
This is where we're going to introduce some new topics specifically modals with bootstrap.
So there's a link in the actual notes in case you want to check it out yourself.
But if you go to bootstrap com or get bootstrapped dot com and then check out the documentation and
check up the components and go down.
Eventually you should see something called a modal.
And basically this is a little bit of Javascript.
Basically javascript it's already included in Bootstrap to have a little dialog that pops up.
So what you end up seeing is a little button that pops up like this.
And when someone wants to delete their block posts we're going to have this Modal pop up that says hey
are you sure you want to delete and then you can either cancel it or you can selectively.
So this is kind of what we're using as a base code.
I'm going to type it out myself but in case you obviously in your own work don't want to manually type
that off you're going to come to the documentation.
Come to motile and then kind of copy and paste here.
Remember all these examples have a little convenient copy to clipboard button and you can see the other
type of models that are available here as well.
So we're really just using this one as our skeleton code.
So the model title body and then some cancel button and some yes confirmed delete because maybe someone
accidently clicks that delete button when we don't want them to delete right away.
So that's the basis of what we're going to be adding in right now.
And that's also the reason why we're using a button I'm going to connect these actions to the button.
So let's see how that all works.
Again if you want to reference where I'm actually in his code from you can either use our notes or just
use the actual bootstrap documentation.
So I had this button right here what I'm going to do is keep the type button and I'm going to add in
a couple more things here.
I don't need to actually give it a name and give it a class for the bootstrap classes just so it looks
a little nicer.
We'll say between and then Beati endanger.
So it's going to be kind of this bright red danger button which makes sense is really.
And then I'm going to add two important things here.
I'm going to say data toggle is equal to motile and that connects this button to pop up instead of straight
deleting.
And the lesson here to do is say data target is equal to.
And this is where you decide on an ID.
So we'll say hash tag and then we'll just give it some name again this name is totally arbitrary what
I'm doing because this is going to be the ID I'm going to use for the idea of the motile I'm going to
create.
So again zooming out here I gave it a class for styling.
So the type is button data toggles motile that gives the little pop up.
And then we have the data target linked to an ID so now it's time to actually create the modal object
and against that make it very clear when we're ever using bootstrap.
We're not memorizing anything.
All we're really doing is coming to documentation looking at an example that more or less looks like
what we want to use and then copying it over.
So I'm actually going to do that myself.
I'm actually going to copy straight from the documentation and then really the things I want to end
it is the title text this body text and then what these two buttons actually do because right now they
don't do anything.
So I'll close that remember I've already copied it so I copied it to my clipboard and then I'm going
to come over here and we'll say if that's still going on here and that and then I have the model for
Papa.
So let's put that in there.
And in fact we're going to put it after this Jumbotron live.
So it doesn't look weird.
So there's the modal code.
And in order to actually link this to this button.
So this is it going to show up unless you actually click this button because it's kind of a data toggle.
I need actually label it as the same ID.
So I gave it the delete motile ID.
So that's when I'm going to provide.
So right here at the very top where it says class modal tab index negative one roll dialog I'm going
to add in one more thing which is the ID equal to.
And then you're going to set it equal to whatever you set here without the hash tag.
So in this case I'll just say DTL underscore motile something want to make very very clear is that this
DL underscore motile.
That's a totally arbitrary ID name.
All I need to worry about is that this right here after the hash tag matches this right here because
that basically tells the h time L when this person clicks this delete button it's going to toggle this
Modal to pop up.
So it's going to toggle all this h t m l along with the javascript to pop up and the modal you're going
to be looking for is the one that matches this idea.
And the reason for that is maybe you want multiple modal so pop up on update or delete.
So you're going to need some sort of data target to make sure you select the right modal OK.
So we added that idea.
So that's good to go and we're going to keep a lot of this one going to change here.
Is this title and instead we're going to just call it maybe delete.
Post a question mark so I'll save that and then we'll have the same sort of button here and then this
is going to stay the same.
This is going to stay the same.
The modal body text would say something like.
Are you sure you want to the post question mark so that way when this pops up I'll say delete posts
on top ask the person are you sure you want to delete the post and then all we need to do now is worry
about these two buns because these are the ones that are really going to do all the heavy lifting.
Deciding if you want to cancel and not do anything or actually delete the post.
So in the case of canceling this is actually all you need to do because it says they dismiss modal and
we're just going to say cancel and you actually don't need to change anything here because all the work
is being done by this line of day to dismiss.
That means when this button is clicked then you dismiss the motile that's currently open.
So all this HTL code goes away.
The last one which is the harder one is trying to figure out what what are you actually going to do
if you decide to delete the post.
So instead of save changes here and I say delete.
So in that case where instead of using a button or actually going to put in a almost like a mini form
that just contains a single submit button.
So I'll show you how we do that we first create this form and it's going to have we don't need to worry
about the class.
Instead we'll say that the action is to take you to the delete post your.
So the action here will say the following.
You are L for blog posts.
Dot delete.
View.
Actually actually I think it's the post view.
Let's make sure we'll come back to views.
So it looks like yes is delete post so upon submitting this form it's going to take you to delete posts
which remember when you automatically call that view.
It's going to delete that blog post and then redirect it to the home page.
You don't really get a second chance there so ill delete the post and we just let them provide it.
What post to delete and the post is going to delete is the post you're currently looking at.
Which happens to be the posts ID that we passed in.
So say poster ID.
All right so that's what's going to happen with this little tiny form and then we're going to do is
have an input button here and the type is going to be submit
and then we don't really need to worry about the name or value.
Actually the value should be whatever it says will say confirmed delete or something.
I'll just say delete and we won't need this button anymore and name.
I don't need to worry about the name going to make it look a little better.
Adding in a class call here with bootstrap and we'll just have it be in between danger.
Save that and then you're done.
So there's a lot going on here.
Specifically it is modal so it's kind of a review.
All these moving parts going to scroll back up here and let's review the following.
So the very beginning is actually pretty straightforward.
We're just showing the actual blog post.
I showed the title I showed the author username I showed the publication date and then issue the post
text.
Then I say if the current user is actually the author of that then they're going to have the option
to update it which then just links them to the update view.
Or they'll have the option to delete and delete button is going to toggle the motile that I've created
here at the bottom and then it's going to link it specifically to that model with this ID data target.
So this line and this highlighted line those are the ones being linked together.
So if we want to delete the post then they can click on that and it says.
Are you sure you want to delete the post as the title.
Delete post this is the body of that motile and then we have two things going on here inside the actual
modal footer which are those two buttons one button is just cancel.
Which is just going to call the Smiths closing the modal.
The other one is actually an entire form in one submit button which if you click on it it will call
delete.
Post on that post ID which if you take a look at that views remember delete posts.
All it does is it says hey is the current user or the author.
If so them are ready to delete.
Will just delete that commit it and then go to the index page and that's all this is doing.
It's just using this modal logic that we haven't actually seen before.
All right.
So we created our blog post each time L and R create that each tiem l file.
Those are the major components that we had left last.
We're going to do in the very next lecture is finishing up any last minute touches such as setting up
blueprints or setting up that home page to actually show all the blog posts and then we'll run our site
test and make sure everything works.
So we're almost at the homestretch here really finishing off to some last minute things to make sure
the site works and functions.
But other than that we've pretty much done about like 95 percent of the work to get everything up and
running.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Well we kind of finish this off.