Welcome back.
We just talked about in general using Python and databases.
Now we're going to dive into the details of actually working of databases with flask to begin working
of databases with Python and flask.
We essentially follow three main steps.
The first one is to set up a sequel like database in our flask application.
The next step is create a model inside a flask application and the last step is to perform basic crud
on our model.
And cruds stands for create read update and delete.
Those are the four main actions you're going to ever do on a table in your database.
Creating new rows reading your rows updating a row and then deleting a row.
So let's start with that first main components step which is to set up the sequel like database in flask.
So to create that we first create our flask application as we've always done by saying app is equal
to a flask name then reconfigure our flask out for Sequel alchemy.
That's going to be really similar to the way we configured a secret key when working the forms.
And then we pass our application into the sequel alchemy class call.
So all of these steps.
It's just essentially four or five lines of Python code and those lines of Python code are going to
be the same every time you set up a school like database for your flask application.
So it's relatively straightforward because of the abstraction libraries we're using that flask sequel
alchemy allows us to do all of this in just a few lines of Python code and we never have to get our
hands dirty with the sequel database.
Now the next step after that is actually create a model in flask and the term model directly links to
a table in sequel database.
So one will work with a python and flask.
We refer to models.
But on the actual back end of our database a model is just a table inside of our database with rows
and columns.
So keep that in mind whenever we say model we're just referring to a table in our database.
And luckily because again of these python abstraction libraries we don't need to go manually create
the table with sequel.
Instead we simply create a model class in Python that generates the table for us.
So pretty much a life saver here because we can do it all with Python.
Now actually creating that model class is also quite simple.
It's going to feel really similar to the way we created a flask form.
Except in this case we're doing it for a model.
So we just create a model class we inherit from db that model it's optional.
You can provide a table name the sequel alchemy will actually automatically generate a table and for
you depending on what you call your class but you can overwrite it and we'll show you how to do that
as well.
And then you just add in table columns as attributes and then you also add in methods for in it and
our EPR Reaper and we're going to talk about that in more detail when we actually code it out.
And just a little bit after that we're going to walk through a basic example of performing credit which
is creating reading updating and deleting from that model or that table.
So we're going to show our code operations being performed manually and adopt by script.
Keep in mind this is just to understand the syntax.
Typically a lot of this is actually going to be automated with a flask.
In real life we're not going to be manually doing crud operations ourselves.
That's going to be all handled automatically for this lecture we just need to understand the syntax
of how we perform crud that we can write that same syntax code in scripts later in the future.
OK so there's a lot to cover here.
Let's get started.
OK here I am at the text editor I have an empty basic thought py file and I'm going to start by doing
a couple of imports.
First off I'm going to import O S and this is allowing us to actually grab directory names and file
pathnames programmatically with Python.
We'll show you what that means in just a second.
But then I'm also going say from flask import flask and then from flask underscore sequel alchemy import
sequel alchemy.
OK so those are all the imports we need for right now and then we want to set up our sequel like database.
So for our base or database we need to choose a directory of words to actually put it.
So what I'm going to do here is the following.
I will say base directory and I'm going to collapse my side bars.
We get a little more room here.
I'll say based Diyar based on victory is equal to OS that path that absolute path for ABS path and then
O S the path directory name and then underscore underscore file underscore underscore again just in
case you made a typo here you can copy and paste this from the actual files you provide for you.
Let's quickly break down what this line is actually doing.
In case you're not familiar of the OS library assent to what's happening here is we have this underscore
underscore file underscore underscore that is essentially what a module is loaded in Python.
This file variable is built in and that's set to the name of the actual file.
So in your code underscore in the score file is going to be automatically set to the name of the file.
In this case that's going to mean that it's set to basic not pi because that's what I call my dot PI
script.
Then I want to get the actual directory name for where the file is.
So that's what this is doing.
Oh fastpath rectory name.
It's grabbing the directory name for basic that Pies so that could be something like my flask examples
for basic about pi.
So that's grabbing the directory name and then I want the absolute path for that directory name.
So that's essentially going to fall out or give the full directory path for this py file so that could
be something like for my computer.
Maybe C users Jose.
I think it's on my desktop for slash my fossick examples.
Basic pi etc..
So here I have this really long file path that instead of having to write out manually as a string I
can use the OS library that's already built into Python to grab that myself.
And the reason it's really important to use OS is that of manually typing up the strings yourself is
one.
It saves you a lot of work because you don't need it.
Look all this up and secondly now it doesn't matter what operating system I'm on whether I'm on Linux
Mac OS or Windows.
This os library is going to take that into account and provide the correct format for this base directory.
And if you want you can even say something like Prince base directory to see what this looks like.
So going to save that and then let's say Python basic thought PI enter.
We'll see.
Now it's showing me that entire based on victory.
So I see C users desktop flask examples.
So in this case is just getting the absolute path to where my file is located.
And notice here I'm not actually saying forward slash basic about pi.
So the reason we now have the space directory this is where I want to build my actual database.
So we have our base directory ready to go.
Let's go ahead and continue and we create my flask application by saying app.
Let me zoom in here just a little bit.
Well say Apple is equal to flask.
Pasand the main variable we've seen before.
And then we need to connect our flask application to our database and we do this on that configuration
step we discussed.
We say app config.
And here the key we're going to grab is siecle alchemy in all caps underscore database underscore.
You are I and then we set that equal to the following sequel White's colon three forward slashes plus.
And then we say oh yes stop path join and then we're going to say the base directory and then we'll
say data Eskew a light.
So what that line does for us is it basically sets up the database location.
So it tells the app our database is going to be set up there and then the last configuration we need
to do app that config is say sequel alchemy.
Underscore track underscore modifications.
I'm going to set that equal to false because we don't want to have to track every single modification
in our database.
By default it could do that for you.
But instead it's often just set to false.
That way in case there's an update you don't need to track all the changes.
Now you could track modifications if you want.
It's really up to you as you become more experienced with databases.
Right now we're keeping things simple.
We're just setting up our path and then saying track modifications equal to false.
Once you've set up your configurations the last thing you need to do is say D-B is equal to and then
we're going to call sequel alchemy and pass in our application.
OK.
So that essentially finishes up finishes up setting up our sequel like database.
These simple lines of code here specifically lines 5 9 10 and 12 here.
Those actually create a sequel like database for us purely through python.
Now we're going to put a bunch of comments here it's kind of separate this the next step.
It's time we actually create our first model so to do this we set up a class we're going to say class
and remember model is just setting up a table in our database.
So what we do here is you decide on the name of your model or call it puppy and then you inherit from
D-B dot model.
So when you pass on your application through sequel alchemy this D-B is now going to have a model class
for it.
So your database model is going to go into the class of your choosing and then a default table name
will be provided based off your class name.
But if you don't want that you can override it by saying underscore underscore table name underscore
underscore is equal to puppies or whatever you want the table name.
So this is how you manually overwrite the table names.
This is a manual table name choice and don't worry if you forget this line.
Basically sequel alchemy will automatically take your class name and it automatically adds an s to it
and just makes the table name OK.
So that's a manual table name choice we'll call it puppies.
And then up next we're going to create the columns for the table.
So I'm going to create a primary key column which is essentially going to be a unique ID for each puppie
will say ID is equal to and they've been called D-B Culp's.
That's not what I wanted.
D-B column and then we say this is an integer.
So say D-B integer and we'll set primary underscore key is equal to true.
OK so what we're doing here is within our puppy class which is a model we have an attribute called ID.
And we're setting that equal to a column inside this table.
And then the actual column type is the first argument.
And we set it to an integer type later and we'll explore other types so we can have.
And then we set primary key equal to true.
And what a primary key means is that is a unique identifier for the actual rows.
So what does that actually mean then.
Let's imagine that we have a table full of puppies.
Now there are some really popular names out there for puppies such as Rufus or no.
Spot is another really popular name.
So what happens is you may get confused if you have two spots inside your database.
So what you want to do is make sure they have at least one column be a primary identifier for the puppies
in our database.
So this idea is going to be unique for each puppy and it's essentially just an integer.
So the first puppy in the database gets an idea of zero.
Second puppy idea of one and so on.
OK.
So we have these here and we'll just check in a little bit whether it starts at zero or 1 off the remember
full say name is equal to the name of the puppies.
D-B call them and then we'll say D-B text so we have text there and they will say age is equal to D-B
column and here will passen again integer because it should be an integer type.
And like I said We'll discuss these various types so we can pass them to columns in more detail later
on.
But these are three main columns a unique ID the name of the puppy and then all the puppies so name
and age then we want to do is set up an init method for our class and we'll say self name and age.
Notice how we don't need to pass an e ID that's going to actually going to be auto created for us later.
So we don't need to add it here and we'll say self-taught name physical to name and then self-taught
age is equal to age.
And then after that we're going to say DCF underscore underscore and you'll type R E P R underscore
underscore self and this is going to give you the string representation of the object.
So what that actually means is often when you're debugging stuff you want to print out a row of the
column and if you just set it up like this there's actually going to be a string representation that
exists.
So what I'm going to do here is return one of my own choosing.
So we'll say we'll use a string here will say Papy and then say self thought name is and then we'll
say self the age years old.
All right.
So that's a string representation of printing out a puppy from our table.
We'll just say puppy Rufus is seven years old or something similar to that and we say that and that's
our main file here.
Let's do a quick review.
And then the next lecture or we're going to do is actually set up the database and add some information
to it and then go through crud.
But I want to quickly review have done so far.
We did our imports including oDesk and flask with alchemy.
We set up the base directory essentially asking for whatever folder I was located in with my flask application.
We set up these two configurations for our application.
We passed in our application into the secret alchemy class creating the D-B object which essentially
stands for a database and then from there instead of a database we're going to be creating models or
tables.
We manually set up the table name.
We set up the columns ID name and age and then we have this method that's going to take in the name
and age of a puppy.
And then also the string representation of a puppy.
So that's all in basic pie.
The next step that we need to do is create a new file right next to basic thought pie.
So I'm going to say instead of my flask examples folder I'll say a new file and I'll call this set up
database that pi and I hit enter.
So notice again basic about pi is in the same folder location as set up databased up PI.
So going to be using a different thought Paice group in order to actually import this D-B object.
And this puppy class but that's just really to separate the certain steps that we're going through right
here.
So if you want to do any checks against the notes this file base about pi It's called basic model app
inside of our notes under the model and crowd basics folder.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to set up this database and this set a database up pie will also show you
how to do basic code in another python script.
We'll see at the next lecture.