Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about form fields pretty much every possible H.T. male
form field has a corresponding W.T. forms class that you can then import.
And these are fields like selecting a date time on your HTL form or just inputting text and W.T. forms
also has validators that you can easily insert and validators can perform checks on the form data such
as requiring a field to be filled or checking to see if a password meets certain requirements.
So we're also going to talk about how to use flasks session object to grab the information provided
in the form and pass it to another template.
Keep in mind later on we're going to show you how to save this information.
Once we understand databases with flask.
So right now all we know how to do is grab the information that he provides in the form and then display
it back in another template in the next section of the course.
We'll show you how we can actually then save that information or check it against a database.
But right now we're just going to show you how you can grab that information temporarily and show it
in a template.
OK let's get started by heading over to our text editor.
All right.
Here we are with our text editor right now.
I just have basic pie.
It's an empty Python script and I have an index that it's Tim L and a thank you that is T.M. pretty
much our index home page is going to have a form with various fields.
The user fills them out and then we think them a report back.
The information on the thank you page.
Let's get started by filling out this python form.
I'm going to collapse that sidebar to give us a little more room.
I will start from scratch.
So I'll say from flask import and then we'll ask for a flask render template.
We're going to also ask for a couple of new things we haven't seen before such as session.
Redirect.
And then also your L4 we've seen your L4 in the template side but there's also a corresponding function
on the python script side.
So we're going to be exploring both session redirects and you are a for in this lecture lots of cool
fun stuff to learn.
Then we'll say from flask underscore WDF import flask form and then from W.T. forms.
I'm going to import that bunch of fields.
So we're going to import a string field a Boolean field a date time field.
So there's dates and date time field and then we also say let's say a radio field so just to show you
the gamut of all the options here.
And then we'll do a select field we'll do a text field and let's do a text area field.
And then finally we need a submit field.
OK.
So just a quick note when you have a bunch of imports like this and you don't want them all in one line.
Well you can do is you can wrap them with parentheses and that we can do the imports over multiple lines.
So the sort of syntax is really common when you're running out of space.
So there we go.
Now we don't get an error with a multi-line import.
OK so we have our imports from the various fields.
The last thing I want to do is show you a simple validator we can say from W.T. forms validators import
and there's various validators you can do one of the simplest ones is data required.
Notice there's other things like email so you can check if a actual email was passed in for an e-mail
input.
For example check things like it has an at symbol there and it ends with dot com or dot org and all
those sorts of things will keep revalidation simple for now.
Just data required.
It basically says hey we need you to fill this out in the form before we can hit submit.
So I'll say that we have our imports ready to go.
So let's create our application will say flask and then we're going to passen name and we're going to
configure our secret key.
So we do this by saying app that config and then we Passons secrets underscore key in all caps.
And then you set this to any string you want.
So I'll say my secret key or my key does really matter for our local purposes right now.
We have our application ready to go.
So we're going to now create a form class recall that usually for larger applications we have a separate
forms up-I file for this but we're keeping everything from just one simple pie file and we're going
to create again in info form and we inherit from flask form and then we're going to have a bunch of
attributes here.
So the attributes we're going to use.
Let's have a breed so kind of make this puppy thing again.
Springfield we'll ask what breed are you.
So remember that's the label for that string field.
And I can also pasan a parameter for validators.
So by default the validators are none.
Boy you can do is send pass any list of validators that you imported from W.T. forms validators and
I've imported data required so that basically says you need to fill out this actual form here.
Or at least this part of the form in order to submit it.
So what we do is validators is a list of validator objects.
So I say data required.
And then I have open close princes.
So actually create an instance of the state a required object to pass into validators and then through
the magic of W.T. forms it will end up requiring the person to provide data there for the Breede input.
All right so we have a breed.
Let's go ahead and create an object for neutered souls.
Check if the puppy has been neutered so I'll say Boolean field have human neutered for it's puppy you've
been neutered it's kind of up to you ask this question.
There we go.
And then let's continue on with mood Sofer mood.
Let's have this be a radio field selection.
So the way radio fields work it's a bunch of radio buttons and they will say please choose your mood.
Remember for radio buttons.
You can only pick one.
So as you pick one all the others get de-selected So what you do here is you pasand choices and choices
is going to be a list of tuple pairs and tuple pairs essentially give a value and a label.
So it starts off with a value.
So we'll call this mood underscore one.
And I'm going to zoom out a little bit and start choices on a new line here so you can get an idea just
for better reference.
So again we have a radio field choices.
It's going to be a list of tuples pairs.
And the first value or the first string is your value and then the second one is the actual label that
a person is going to see on that radio button.
So we can say happy and then let's add one more we'll say mood to
and we'll have that be excited.
So puppies are either happy or excited and then we'll do another attribute here.
And this attribute is going to be called let's see.
Let's have it be food choice.
And for this we'll say select field and here we're going to ask to pick your favorite food and something
that may happen depending on what OS you're using.
Sometimes this needs to be a unicode string.
So what you can do is put a you right in front of the string to make sure you don't get any errors.
That doesn't happen on every OS.
Just keep in mind I'm going to put it here just to make sure you don't get any errors.
Often you can just provide the string and you'll have no errors but will put in Unicode here for select
field just to make sure it works for us.
And then the select field it's going to be really similar to radio field.
As far as the choices parameter so you have these choices parameter and it's going to be again a list
of tuple pairs where the first item in this tuple pair is the value code that you're going to be using
throughout your Flast group.
And the second one is what the actual user Seasonale Web site.
So something like chicken is what the user sees.
And on the back end we just call it CHC for short.
And then we can have something like B.F. and we'll have that be related to the beef option that the
user sees and create some more options here on our list.
We can say something like fish as a value and have that label fish and it's good provide one more we
have chicken B fish actually should be enough.
So let's put this in the mixture.
We have that on the list.
There we go.
So we have our list of choices as duple pears.
And now we're ready to go.
Let's just have one more option here.
And the last one is going to be as far as the attribute.
To make sure we get it lined up correctly.
There we go the attributes going to be feedback and we'll just have this be a text area a field which
essentially just a large box where someone can write whatever they want.
And they'll have a submit button so I'll say submit field.
I'll say just submit.
All right.
So this is our form.
As you can see this form is quite complicated given what we've done in the past which is why usually
you're going to have a separate forms that file where you'll set up your info form and then your application
you'll just say from forms import info form.
But right now we set up the form in the same application that profile we have this if a form has an
option for providing your Breede notice that's going to be required.
So a user has to provide that before hitting submit.
It will have a Boolean field which is up to you to choose one or the other.
And then we have radio field select field text area of field and then a submit button.
So we set up our form.
Now it's time to actually set up our index page with the form.
So the next step here is to set up our index page will see the routes or go to the home page by saying
just forward slash and then the methods.
Just like last time it's going to be a list with get and post
and then we'll say the index and we'll start setting up our index function.
Let's add some new lines here.
Remember you can always copy and paste from the provided notes KCA any syntax errors.
But we're going to create an instance of our form object we'll just call it form and it's going to be
an instance of our info form and then we'll say if form dot valid day on submit.
So once they hit the submit button essentially we're going to do is going to grab data from the Breede
on the form.
Now the way we can do this in order to pass in all this data into another template automatically We're
going to be using if we scroll back up here the session object we imported from flask.
And unlike a cookie basically session data is stored on the server and a session is just a time interval
from when a client is logging in or connecting to that server and then logs out of it.
So it's not going to be permanently saved.
It's just a particular obsession for the user who filled out that form and then went to another page.
So the data which is actually needed to be held across the session is essentially stored in a temporary
directory on the server.
So this is not a way to permanently store something.
It's just a way to hold information for a particular session for a user.
And we actually have even talked about official user authentication or registration yet.
So think of this kind of a very basic way to report back information that the user provides in a form
later on we're going to learn how to save it and how to actually attribute it to a specific user that's
logged then the start of the basics here.
So we're going to do when we say form validate or submit.
I'm going to grab that session object and you can essentially treat it as a dictionary.
So we're going to create a new key in the session dictionary called breed and we're going to set that
equal to form read data.
Remember that the general syntax is to say your form the created appear form is to perform grab whatever
attribute you're interested in number all these attributes are essentially as fields and then you say
data and that grabs what the user provided for that actual field and keep in mind your data for things
like radio field and select field.
That's going to report back your internal value.
It's not going to report back what the user saw.
So often you may want to keep these the same.
That way there's no confusion.
But maybe if you have a really complex choice that the user is going to see it might be easier to give
it a shorter value maybe chicken is just too large to store around.
So you want to say CHC again this is starting to get to personal preference as far as how you like to
combine your value label pairs here.
So just something to keep in mind and we'll see this in more detail in just a little bit.
I'm going to say session.
And then let's add an neutered and we'll say form neutered data.
So it's going to be a boolean value whether or not they're neutered.
Let's see we also have mood of the dog or the puppy.
It's going to be form mood data.
And they'll keep adding more stuff to this.
We also have their food choice.
So I'm going to call it food for the key we'll say form through choice.
Grab the data on their food choice and then I believe they also have feedback that they can get back
I will say the feedback he is equal to form the feedback that data.
All right.
So once that's all done what I'm going to do is I'm going to return and this is where we're going to
use the redirect and your all for though we just imported so appear at the top.
Remember I imported redirect and your all for this is really useful when you want to just automatically
have a form redirect upon submission instead of messing around the DML code to make sure that works.
You can actually use redirect and you are all four from your Python script.
So that's a little nicer that way.
Your template files are as simple as possible and you really leverage the power of Python over here
in flask.
So we're going to do is say return redirect and essentially linked up with that action on submitting
and HTL form.
And then we say your L4 and then we passen a string of whatever the function's going to be called for
the other view and I'll say thank you.
And then I haven't actually created this view function yet but I will in just a little bit.
So notice here the actual indentation of this is going to zoom out so we can see this indentation clearly.
I'm saying the F index for info for.
And then if the form is valid on submission I grab all the data and add it to that users session and
then I return a redirect for the thank you all what I'm going to do for the overall return of this function
is say render template and then pasan index.
H T M L and then say form is equal to form.
All right.
So why do I have a redirect return.
And the rendered template turn.
Well that's because when I have my index page the very first thing they should see is the form.
So I want to render my index outdates HTML page and pass in that form.
It's only upon submission of the form where I want to grab the data and then redirect them.
Which is why I have two returns this bottom return.
That's the original rendering of the home page and then the second redirection return only happens when
they submit the form.
So keep in mind here the indentation what matches up with what this redirect return that's only for
this if statement.
This rendered template that's for the entire function.
So that's the first thing the user sees and then they get redirected for the thank you page only upon
a valid submission and this validate on Submit.
Well that's going to do is it's going to check for these validators.
So it's going to check that it makes sure to actually provide data for the Springfield here.
And if they did not then it's not going to be valid on submission and they're not going to be redirected.
So that's really start to leverage the power here of these W.T. forms.
OK.
So I just mentioned that I have a redirect you are all for a thank you page which means I should probably
make a thank you page.
So we'll say routes is thank you.
And we'll have that function here just say thank you.
And we're going to return render template for thank you.
T.M. save that.
And at the very bottom of all this will say if name is equal to Main take my app and run it it will
say de-bug is equal to true.
Just in case we have any issues there.
All right.
So that's everything we need to do for actual flask application.
In part 2 of this series of lectures we're then going to fill out the templates and match it up with
the views that we set up here.
So let's just do a quick review of everything we've done.
We did our imports and we have a couple of new imports so we haven't seen before such as redirect and
you are a 4 as well as using that session.
We imported a bunch of different fields from W.T. forms and you can always look up in the documentation
the various forms and fields that are available.
And then we also are using a validator and the one we're using right now is data required.
There's also lots of different validators you can check for in the documentation.
Then we create our application set up a secret key in our configuration then we set up a form inside
of this basic thought PI file of a bunch of different fields.
One of them has that validator Roamer that a validators parameter is a list of validator objects that
have been created so that's where we need to open close parentheses there.
And then we have this route for index page methods equal to get posts.
We create the form and say if the form is valid on submission then we save all this data to the session
object the session object can be basically be treated like a dictionary and we're saving it and then
we're going to send it back to the thank you page.
Later on you'll see that we don't need to actually say sessions equal to session anywhere in the template
it's just automatically through our fast flask application available to us in the template page.
So we're going to see that in the next lecture and then we just have a redirect for you.
Upon submission and the original render template is just the home page with this form that we have that
think Page.
OK.
So in part two we're going to be filling out this index that simple and this think that Ishmail will
see next.