Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss basic routing in our web applications.
We just saw how to create a web application with a single page.
In this case it was returned in the form of a string with a single header line.
Now let's see how we can add a multiple routes that is to say multiple pages on our web application.
The key to this is in the decorator app route the string parameter that we pass into that decorator
determines the Yoro extension that will link to the function.
Otherwise known as a view currently our home page or domain is locally represented as 1 2 7 0 0 1 colon
and then 5000 where that 5000 number may change depending on what ports are available on your local
machine.
What we do is we use decorators to add onto this.
So we say at apt that route and then as a string we pass in whatever your L extension we want to K'NEX
offer this domain name.
So for example if I decorated a view function with forward slash some underscore page then I would be
able to visit in my browser our domain name.
In this case the local Yoro slash some page and actually see the view represented there once a page
is actually deployed the web that local 1 to 7.0 points or 0.1 that's going to be replaced by your actual
domain name whatever domain you happen to purchase online.
You can say something like site dot com forward slash and then some page or whatever other pages you
have on your web application.
The main idea here is that we're just passing in a string to connect that view function to an actual
routing in your application.
Let's create an example of this by going to the actual text editor and showing you how it works.
All right.
Here we have the application we were working on last time fact I'm going to just expand it here and
I have from flask import flask and right now I just have one view function called index which stands
for my index page and notice how its route is just a single forward slash indicating that this is just
going to go to one to seven point zero point zero point one colon 5000.
Let's imagine that I want another page in my web application.
Let's create a page and we're going to call the View function for info.
Technically you can call this function whatever you want.
And this one is going to return in other.
Will say something like just some information about puppies let's say Puppies are cute and we'll close
that heading one tag.
Then all we need to do is call app route.
So that's a decorator forward slash and then whatever extension you want here.
So for instance we can say information and now when I visit my page to seven point zero point 0.1 colon
5000 forward slash information or whatever the string code is here.
I'm going to call this view function in which case I should see.
Puppies are cute.
So let's make sure we save this and let's run our file now.
I'll say Python basic but pie or whatever you happen to call this file Mikuru don't call it Flast that
pi and enter here.
Notice it's running.
So let's check it out in our browser and to bring in my browser.
It says Hello puppy.
I refresh this.
It still says hello puppy.
Now I'm going to ask for forward slash information to enter and now says puppies are cute.
So what it did is using that route decorator.
It said OK call the view function info since that's the function that's being decorated and then return
back whatever it says there.
In this case those puppies are cute.
If you end up trying to visit a route that's not the fine.
For example say slash not the find you enter.
It's going to get not found.
Essentially this is a forum for saying the requests you're L was not found on the server which means
this hasn't been defined within your actual flask application.
OK so just a quick review.
All you're doing here is passing forward slash and then the string code you want for your actual routing.
Let's go ahead and go to the next lecture where we're going to discuss dynamic routing.
That is to say this information is actually dynamic depending on what information is passed the page
we're going to discuss that in the next lecture.
We'll see you there.