Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to expand on what we just showed and build out a basic crud API application basically being
able to create read or daily items.
And in this case we're just going to keep items in a list inside our Python script later on we're actually
going to build out a full database and show you how to connect the flask Web site database to a rest
application.
But let's learn a couple of more functions or really methods inside of those resource calls.
That's up over to the editor.
All right.
Here we are back at this the PI file.
I went ahead and cleared everything just so we can get a little more practice setting everything up
again.
Basically for a start again from the top we'll say from flask import flask and then we'll say from flask
restful import and we'll import resource as well as API.
And let me collapse Left-Hand time.
We're just dealing with one file.
We create our application as always passing in the name variable.
It's built in.
And then we wrap that into the API call and then set that equal to the variable API.
Notice the capitalization there.
So we're going to do is we're basically going to have a list of puppies and each puppy is going to have
a name sort to say puppies is equal to an empty list.
And we're going to use the rest API in order to get a puppy name or Dilley a puppy name or post new
puppy names as well.
So we're going to create a class here called Puppy names and that's going to inherit from resource and
then the main methods we're going to say here is def get.
And then also have the post.
And right now we'll just say pass for all of these so we don't get any errors here.
There is a colon.
So we have get and post and then we'll also do delete.
So Def delete pass and then start filling these out.
So we want to be able to do here is using the rest API we'll do our calls from postman.
I want to be able to get a specific puppie given the name of a puppy.
So what I'm imagining here is that puppies is going to be a list and inside a single puppy will have
the following format.
It's going to be a dictionary with the key name and the name of the puppy for example.
Rufus So we're going to have each puppy have this format.
So our list of puppies is then going to look something like this.
Get a copy and paste from the notes here for a second.
But basically we have a dictionary here named Rufus.
Then the next one named Franki and so on.
So that's what this list looks like.
The list of dictionaries.
So we have puppies.
So if we actually want to get a puppy you need to cycle through the puppies list.
So before we do get let's actually show how we would post a new puppy.
So all these methods should have self and something that's important to know is when you're building
out your API the get methods post methods methods they all need to take in the same parameters as arguments.
So in this case if we want to get a puppy by its name then we need to make sure that the rest these
also have the exact same parameters.
So let's start with post since that will allow us to post a new puppy to this list the puppies that
will show you how to get a puppy and they will show you how to delete a puppy.
And then we will actually create a new class to just get all the puppies.
But start of actually posting a new puppy.
So how do we actually add something to that list.
Well first to say pup is equal to name and then name what's going to happen here is our resource is
going to take in a name through an API call and we'll clarify that in a second through the euro.
But basically we're going to pass in a Yoro for a name and then we're going to create a dictionary that
looks like this name and the name that was passed then.
Then we'll take that pup and we'll say puppies penned that particular pup that is going to return pup.
So you can think of this as we're essentially treating puppies here as an in memory database which is
really just a list.
So when we post the new puppy based off name we create an instance of a dictionary called name with
that particular puppy's names who would pass and something like post Rufus.
Then we get the dictionary we append that dictionary to that list of puppies and then we return that
pup basically to tell us Hey this was the actual dictionary passed then and then we can later on get
it.
So imagine that we just posted a new puppy.
Let's go ahead and get a puppy.
So hard to make that happen when you say for every pup in that list of puppies.
Well say if pup pups name because remember pup here is a dictionary in the sort of format.
So if we want to get a particular name of the puppy we'll go through every dictionary in puppies and
say if that pup name is equal to the name provided.
So for example maybe we're searching for Rufus.
So I'll say it's up to good dictionaries value for the key name happens to be equal to Rufus them or
turn the pup.
However what if we actually try to request a puppy that isn't actually in the puppies list yet.
Well in that case when you go through an entire for a loop this will never be true meaning you'll never
return anything.
So after the for loop has been run I'm going to add in one more return statement and this return statement
only executes if this for loop never has a hit with the same puppy name.
So they will say return name and we'll say none essentially indicating that hey it was empty.
Now we're going to add a little more to this later on but just keep that in mind.
So all we're doing here is we want to post the new puppy we create this dictionary.
A pen that pup puppies and then returned pup.
If you want to get a puppy.
We go through every pup in that list of puppies.
So then we have these dictionaries.
Each pup has a dictionary.
We check that tickler dictionaries name value.
So that would be something that would be like Rufus or Frankie or whatever happened to call dog.
You check that same name that was requested and if so you return that pup which you're going to look
like adjacent object essentially a python dictionary.
If you go through the tire for a loop never find the match then return.
Name.
Finally let's show you how to delete a puppy.
So for this it's going to work really similar.
It will do the following we'll say for index position and pup in enumerates puppies so remember enumerate.
Basically pass along a counter sordidness say Little did a tuple and packing here this will be a counter
like 0 1 2 3 4.
Pup is going to be the actual dictionary.
So say for index position come up any numeric puppies if pup name is equal to name.
So we have an actual match then we're going to do is say deleted pup
is equal to puppies that pop at the index essentially since we're dealing for less we're just going
to pop at that particular index or there happened to be a match and then if that happens we're just
going to return note
delete success.
OK so all we're doing here for Dilley is someone is going to pass on the name of the puppy.
We're going to go through the entire list of puppies and see if we find the matching name.
They're going to pop that puppy and then we're going to send the note that hey the delete all successful
if you want you could have also return more information like the actual deleted pup.
In fact you don't really need to save this you could just do this command if you want it to but maybe
later on you want to have a little print message here like print deleted pup just so you can keep track
of things.
It's really up to you.
So we're going to save that.
And those are the three basic methods that we can play around with right now since we're just dealing
with a python list.
So again we can post the new puppy we can't get a single puppy and we can Dilly a puppy.
Now what I want to do is create one more resource in case you want to get a list of all the puppies.
So say class all names resource.
And this is going to have its own get call and we're going to say return and we can't just return puppies
because that's a list.
So what we want to do is return it in a Jaison type form.
So we'll say puppies Colan puppies so knows this is going to be a dictionary of puppies and it is going
to be a list of more dictionaries.
So it's going to be kind of a nested J song structure.
All right.
And then what we need to do is we need to register these resources essentially add resources to the
API.
So we're going to say API dot add resource and then we'll start with the puppy names class that we created.
And this is where we get to choose your l.
You can actually connect to.
So if I just head forward slash don't connect directly home.
But again we probably want to have something that works if these actual methods.
So notice all these methods take in a name as a parameter so you can think of this very akin to when
we said app route we're essentially saying API add resource.
And so then we're going to put in the your L or or someone should connect to this particular API call.
So I'll say puppie and then we'll make sure it's a string.
We've shown this before in the course and then we'll passen name.
So essentially what this means is someone is going to be able to programmatically reach the home your
elves for Slash puppie forward slash the name of a puppy and that connects to puppy names which then
you can call either delete method or a post method or get method and we'll be playing around with that
and just a little bit.
Then I also want to add and this all names resource so I'll say API add resource.
All names and this one will have it go to a different you or I will have this one go to puppies.
Then once that's all done we'll say if name is equal to mean go ahead and run our app and we'll say
that debug is equal to true.
All right.
So that's what we have so far.
Let me zoom out just so we can get an idea of everything we just made same as before we set up our flask
application.
Connect that to an API.
Right now we're just storing everything in a Python list keeping things simple.
And we created our class puppy names and because it's a list we're just going to able to do a get a
post and delete for the posts we create this little new dictionary based off what was provided at this
url.
We added it as a resource then we append that particular dictionary to the list and then we return it
just so it's a confirmation that yes we did post this then if we want to grab a particular puppie based
on name we go through every dictionary in the puppies list and if we get a match we would turn that
puppy.
Or else if we went through a for loop and then didn't get a match we say name was done.
Then if we wanted to see a puppy really similar process to getting a puppy except we're also keeping
track of the index so that we can pop that puppy out of that list.
Then we have class for all names.
And so same thing as a resource except the what it's going to return is just the entire list of puppies.
OK then we added those resources and then we're good to go.
So let's actually run this will say Python.
I'm calling the simple API that pi will go ahead and run that.
And then let's bring up postman.
So now I have postman first thing I'm going to do is I'm going to try to get a puppy that does not exist.
So say our home your L forward slash puppy forward slash and then you can type in any name here because
technically there are no puppies that exist in the list right now.
So let's go ahead and hit send and see what we get back.
So you notice we get back.
Name no.
So essentially what happened is we returned back an empty dictionary and now we're receiving that as
Jason.
So the python nun gets returned as a note of Jaison.
So that makes sense we just asked for a puppy that's not there let's try posting some puppies.
So say post and now I make such a keep in the you are all the same but saying Hey post Sammy to that
list the puppies so we'll send it and then it sends the request over and now I see name Sammy.
So that looks like it worked.
Let's go ahead and add Frankie.
So these are my two dogs are going to add them to that list of puppies.
So we're going to send that as well.
Now I see named Frankie.
And let's add one more.
Let's go ahead and Cindy has a puppy name.
We'll send that.
And now I see named Cindy.
OK.
So now we have three puppies.
Let's go ahead and try to get one of them.
Let's make sure that this is all working on the say puppy Max.
That puppy isn't something we posted.
So if I send I get back.
My name is nals.
That makes sense.
Now let's try one that we did actually put in which was Frankie.
And if I send that now we actually get back name Frankie.
So it looks like that's working.
Finally let's try getting all the puppies.
So you say gets in a of puppy for Slash name.
We're going to say get puppies.
So remember that was the all names class that was connected to four slush puppies.
So going to send this and noticed when I get back I get back puppies and then a list of these Jason
objects Sammy Frankie and Cindy let's tried deleting Sindy using our delete method.
So say delete forward slash puppie forward slash Cindy.
We're going to send this and notice it says delete success.
So now let's try to get all the puppies again and see what we get back.
So I'll say get puppies send this.
And now I only see Sammie and.
Since we removed Sindhi from that list of puppies.
So it looks like everything's working and hopefully you can tell that the actual method calls are pretty
straightforward.
You just put in the method call make sure it matches and flask restfully is taking care of everything
else on the back and for us something I want to know is.
Let's imagine if we tried to grab a puppy that again isn't in our actual database so we're going to
say a totally new name of puppy.
Let's go ahead and say Davy isn't there a puppy.
We're going to try to get Davy and noticed we get back named Noel.
But take a look over here where it says status.
So status 200 OK is the standard response for a successful request.
What we can do is instead of just passing in or passing back Jason.
When you actually don't have a puppy we can also use tuples to pass out a status.
So let's go back to our code.
So when I come back to our code and we said here return name none are going to come back to this and
I'm going to say comma also for 0 4.
Let me save that.
And notice this is now updated again and then I'm going to again request puppy Davey.
Remember Davy is not actually in the database.
And when I send my request to get Davey I get back again.
Name No.
But now look this is changed to say four or four not found so that how you can actually send back HTP
statuses as well because in this case you probably want to send that a 4 or four so the program knows
hey you're asking for something that doesn't exist.
Keep in mind because we're storing puppies as an in-memory list every time you restart your python script
is essentially going to wipe clean that puppy's list.
So keep that in mind if you keep restarting the lists because if you had a typo or something you may
accidently request Papy that you thought was there but then got wiped clean when you restarted the python
script.
All right.
That's the very basics of getting things posting things and deleting things.
You should note however that pretty much anyone was allowed to get post and delete items from that list
in the next lecture.
We're going to discuss authentication which means we're going to need a special key in order to actually
access this rest API which is always good practice in a more realistic situation.
So we're going to cover that in the very next lecture.
We'll see if.