All right so we're right where we left off last time.
I have a basic PI file with all my code in this.
And then I created a new that PI file that says setup database.
Pi.
What I'm going to do is say from basic import D-B and puppy.
So again you may be calling this slightly different in our notes that we provide to it's called from
basic model app right now for this video lecture I just called the Basic about pi.
So that's where this basic is coming from and D-B and puppy.
Well they're right here.
Debes right here on line 12.
And the puppy is only 15.
So that's what I'm importing from this file and everything that comes along with that.
And the next step is actually to set up our database.
We're going to say D-B dots and we're going to call create underscore all.
Keep in mind usually we're not going to run a separate PI file to actually create the database.
There's some command line tools that make that a lot easier.
But right now just for lower starting out we're going to manually create that database.
So what this line does right here at the create all that creates all the tables essentially transforming
your model class to a database table.
So that's what that line is doing D.B that create all.
From there we can create new entries in the database.
So the way we do that is going to create a puppy object we'll see Sam as an instance of puppy where
the name is Sammy and he's three years old and they say Frank is equal to puppy.
And I will say Frankie and we'll have Frankie be four years old.
OK.
So I have these two puppy objects.
What I'm going to do is check the IDs of them going to say Prince Sam.
The idea that I'm going to say Prince Frank thought Id.
So this is just to kind of prove to you that I haven't added sound Frank to the database.
So both of these should be none because remember if we come back here inside of our in that statement
it's just taking name and age.
So it's only going to have the name and the age.
We haven't added it to the database yet at this line.
So Id these should be none.
So first we should see none and none on this print.
Then all we're going to do after that is the following line will say D-B session and I'm going to say
add underscore all and I'm going to pass in a list of my puppy objects so that will be Sam and frank
as an alternative you can add them individually.
So it's also common to see something like D-B session ad and then you can add Sam and then say D-B session
at Frank.
So Line 14 is the same as line 16 and 17 put together.
So you can either add objects individually one by one or by just saying D-B session and or you can add
a list of objects in one single line by saying at all and then passing in a list of those objects.
So we'll just use at all.
So we're saying Sam and Frank are now in the database and what we're going to do then is say D-B session
and I'm going to call commit and they actually will then save those changes to the database and then
I'll say print.
Sam ID and then I will say print.
Frank ID OK so I'm going to save this.
Let's really quickly go over what we just did.
We said from Mike that Paice grip this basic one over here.
Import my database and import this puppy model.
So once it imported the top I say create all my database which essentially converts all those models
into tables.
Then it created to put the objects Sam and frank with their names and their ages and then ask hey can
you print out their IDs and what's going happen is going to say none because we never really provided
them with IDS.
Then I called D-B session.
I'm going to be able to add Sam and Frank when I want a call like this.
We're passing it into a list.
The alternative is to add them one by one to session.
And then I'm going to commit those changes to my database and then I'm going to ask for their ID's again.
Now keep in mind there's a lot of stuff going on in the background that siecle alchemy is taking care
of us.
So this is just a couple of lines of Python code.
When you look at this I did this all in about less than 10 lines really.
And there's a lot of heavy lifting that sequel alchemy does for us.
So things like adding the ID at the end of this you can kind of think about that as a little bit of
magic that's happening in the back and it's going to save this.
And let's try running and see what happens.
So to do that I will expand right here to clear my window and I'm going to run Python and I call this
set up database stop pi.
Your name may be slightly different.
And it looks like I get the results.
None none.
One and Two.
So that matches up with what I expected.
The Ids actually created until I added them to my database.
So then when I print Samite the end Frnk ID I get back 1 and 2.
So I think I previously mentioned a 0 as an index.
I should correct myself and say that indexing for these databases starts at once so sequel.
Your first index or ID is going to be at one.
So keep that in mind it's like exactly like Python there.
And then you'll also notice that some files got created for you.
You should now see after running this script a data that sequel lights you aren't really going to be
able to read it too much but notice here there is some sequel code along with some stuff that Adam's
having a hard time reading.
So that's her data that sequel line.
And then you should also see a PI cache and that essentially is just some Python code that automatically
gets created that way in case you want to run your python files again.
They run slightly faster.
So we set up our database and the database is this file right here.
Data at that school.
And that's actually holding the information.
Again it's not a data type that you can directly read in your text editor but you can kind of make out
what's happening here.
So make sure not to make any edits on the data that sequel like file.
Ok so we just created our database.
Now it's time to talk about crud.
So we want to be able to create read update and delete from our database.
So to do that I'm going to create a new file and I'm going to call it crud that pi and we're going to
go through each of the main phases so our table that was just created and we're going to do now is say
from basic import D-B and puppie that should be a comma D-B and puppy.
There we go.
And then we'll start off with create.
So show you how to create an entry into this table and it's going to be essentially what we just did.
We're going to see my puppy is equal to and you create a puppy object or whatever kind of object is
related to your actual model or table.
And here let's make rufous Rufus will be five years old.
Then we take that database session and then we can add in that puppy object and then we're going to
save it by saying D-B session commit so it's not technically say until you call this commit.
All right.
Let me close this off.
So you can see this in a little more detail.
So that's creating Should it be anything new because we created two entries when we actually ran the
database.
Next we want to be able to read so reading is where we can actually introduce or filter options rember
or m c the object relational mapper and there's lots of different options here and we're going to cover
them in a lot more detail later on.
But I'm going to show you some of the most basic ones we're going to be using throughout the course.
So again this is for reading your database first.
Imagine I wanted to grab all the puppies.
So essentially I wanted to grab everything that was existing in my table.
The way I could do that is I would say puppy dots queery the all.
And this is going to return a list of the puppy objects in the table.
And then I could say prints all puppies I can also select by the so if I wanted to select by either
way I could do that they say puppy 1 is puppy queery get.
And then I could say one there and then I could print for instance that puppy's name so puppy one name
and that should be the very first puppet we added which if we go back to set up database it should have
been Sam.
So we should see Sammy be printed out here.
So that's how we could select by the.
And the next thing we can do here is filter as well when reading.
So let's imagine I wanted to filter out by name.
I only wanted to select the puppies where the name happened to be equal to Samie.
What I could say is puppy or let's do Franki will say puppy Franki is equal to grab our puppy model
and we'll say queery and then I can use the filter underscore by method.
And here is where I provide a column name such as name equals or age equals start with name.
And then I set it equal to whatever value I'm looking for.
For instance let's say I'm looking for where it happens to be equal to Franki.
This command this filter by command that will actually produce some sequel code for us and then if I
want to actually grab the product or the result of that sequel code what I can do is say puppy Franki
and then call all of this and that should print out a list.
It's going to print that out.
That's going to print out a list of all the puppies with the name happens to be with the Franki.
In our case that should just be one singular puppy.
And remember when we're printing up puppies it's going to be printed out in this form puppy name is
age years old.
So you should see a list here that looks something like like Frankie is three years old.
So that should be the result of this line right here.
Going to comment that that line.
And then finally what we can do is we can start updating.
And then after that we can show you how to delete.
So if you want to update what we do we have to first grab our data so we'll grab the first puppy in
our database or set that equal to puppy queery get one and let's change that puppy age so we'll see
that first puppy is now going to be 10 years old.
I will say D-B session and then we add in that same puppy object and then we call D-B session and we
commit that change.
So that's how you can update.
You just grab based off either filter or buy or queery that get.
Again we're going to spend a lot more time talking about or M and reading in general there's a lot of
executer options and then we'll also talk about updating it a little more detail later on.
But essentially you just grab that object add whatever attribute you want update it and then you can
add it back in and commit those changes.
Then for deleting it's kind of similar.
We can grab another puppy Salt's grab the second puppy in the database and say puppy will see Cleary
gets to that grabs a second Papu of ID to Elisei D-B session and then we call deletes on that puppy
on that second pup and then we just commit those changes will say D-B session come at and then check
for changes.
So we'll just go ahead and print out all the puppies again.
We'll say all puppies is equal to or puppy model grab all of them and then print out all the puppies
OK so I'm going to save that.
Let's run this and make sure it works and I it clear that and say Python crud up high.
Well enter and it looks like a printed out.
So let's make sure that it matches up what we expected.
OK.
So here we see Papy Sammy is 3 years old.
Frank he's four years old publisher of his five years old.
We take a look at the first thing we printed.
All the way up here it's going to be prints all the puppies in our database.
So make sense that we have Sammy and Frankie.
Those puppies were created when we actually set up our database on at all.
And then Rufus.
Well that's the one we create an added at the very beginning.
So now we have all three of them.
That's the first print statement here on line 10 then selecting by id I want it to grab the ID of puppy
one.
That should be the first puppy that was put into the database.
And if we check database again that was Sam over here.
So when I print out Papy one name I should see Sammy which I do.
Then for filters we can say puppy queery filter by name where it's Franki and then print out all the
results of that.
Notice how it actually gives us a list here.
So it says puppy Franki is four years old.
This itself is inside of a list.
So if there were more puppies than named Frankie it would return back their name as well as her age.
Then finally what we end up doing is we update Samis H.
And then we actually delete the second pup which was Franki.
So when we print out all the puppies I now see that Sammy is 10 years old instead of three years old
due to my update to his age and I no longer see Frankie.
Now I just have Rufus.
Now if you want to play around more with crud that's totally OK.
But something to note here is you're going to have issues if you try running this cruds script again
or if you try running the script multiple times.
So I want to show you what happens if I try running Python crud that pagan it's going to say unexpected
mapping issues are going to get these errors.
And that's because you started to ask for puppies that are no longer in your database.
So if you start scrolling back up here they'll say for instance delete the second pup will you already
believe the second pup when you ran your CRID script the first time around.
So you can't run up the lead line more than once otherwise you're going to get an error.
So notice here we're saying get ID 2 and then delete that.
Well that puppy no longer exists.
We deleted it off our database.
So let's imagine that you want to keep playing around and proxy crud but unfortunately you deleted.
Now you're starting to get errors and you would just like to restart.
That happens to me all the time as I especially as I was practicing crud with Laskin sequel alchemy.
The best way I figured out how to do this is especially in the very beginning at this stage is to just
open your tab up here go to stated that sequel like and then go ahead and just delete the sequel database
that you made.
And then we just need to run Python setup database again.
So say Python set up a database that adds in the first two puppies and then we have no problem rerunning
credit pi.
So we get the same results here.
Again you only need to run that if you're kind of messing around and you're trying to delete puppies
that you already deleted or those kind of things.
OK.
So that's a work around for that particular issue later on.
We're not really going to be using these manual Crudup by scripts instead will kind of be incorporating
these into selections on forms and other features in our flask applications.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post that Q forums.
We'll see you in the next lecture.