Welcome back in this lecture we're going to walk through the steps to have rest API authorization.
We can use the flask JWT or Jason Webb token library to require authorization before being able to create
a rest API call.
Users will need to provide a username and password to an authentication page then they'll receive a
key or token that they can attach to the rest of their API calls.
That way we can make sure only authorized users are able to access our API.
Now we're going to need to install the flask JWT library and you can do that simply command line with
Pipp install flask cache JWT.
OK let's get started.
We're going to be working with the same file as last time but we're going to add authorizations to certain
API calls right before we get started.
As I mentioned you're going to need to install flask dash JWT.
So already have it installed so go ahead and make sure you have it installed as well.
And we're going to create two more dot pite files inside of this flask example folder.
We're going to create one file called Secure underscore check.
Technically you can call it whatever you want but this is going to have two functions one for authentication
and another one for identity and we'll have one more file.
And this one is going to be called user dot pi.
So as we've seen before we can store our own user class inside of models.
And typically that's how you would actually perform a authorisations storage.
But for our use case we're kind of keep things simple here.
So inside this user that PI file what we're going to do is we're going to create a really simple user
class and then we're going to import it into our simple API.
So say class user.
And then these are users that are inside our database.
So we're going to say users have an ID a user name and password.
Very similar to what we've done in the past.
And then we'll just say self-id is equal to ID self-taught user name is equal to user name and then
self-taught password is equal to password and you can build on top of this given what we already know
about flask authorization flask log in.
You can hash the passwords and keep it more secure.
We're doing a really simplified approach right now and then just in case we ever want to print out a
user.
We'll go ahead and make a string method here that just returns user ID and then we'll say ID again using
f string notation here.
Not technically not necessary but it's helpful for debugging.
They can print out the users.
OK.
So we definitely seen something like this before and now it's in this special user that pi.
So now we're going to do is we're going to come over to your to secure check.
So a secure underscore checked up pi and you can technically call this file whatever you want.
Let me give ourselves a little more room here and we're to create some users.
So I can to say from user import user essentially from that user profile import that user class and
let's create a list of users so will have a list and let's create a user.
We'll give them I.D. one will go ahead and say this user is Jose and then we'll say my password is the
password.
And again you'd probably be storing these users in a database somewhere.
But we're keeping things simple for now.
So say create one more user.
Let's have this user be Mimi and then we'll have their passerby's secret.
OK.
So we have this list of users and then we're going to do is create some mapping in order to quickly
access users based off their I.D. are based off their name.
So in order to do this and essentially directly from the documentation for flask JWT they have this
kind of simple example.
What they do is they say you dot user name Colan you for you in users and this may be a comprehension
style that you haven't seen before.
But essentially this is a dictionary comprehension that's creating a dictionary that's mapping these
users to a user name.
So we're saying is for you end users.
So we have this list and for every user here I'm going to grab their user name because remember that's
literally an attribute of theirs.
It's going to grab their username and then link it to that actual specific user object.
So then if we actually have user name and table what it should look like is Jose.
And then this user Mimi and then this user object.
So that's going to allow us to look things up by the username.
It's going to be able to then say user name table and then look up Jose in order to get back this user
name object.
OK so have a user name table and then I'm also going to have user id table and it's the same concept
except I will say you ID and then say you.
For you in users the exact same thing.
Building a dictionary here based off the ID for every user.
OK.
So if you haven't seen those sort of comprehension before it's just an easy way to do it.
You could also do this manually for a for loop if you wanted to.
And then we have to do is create two function functions.
One is authenticate and the other one is identity.
Authenticate is going to take a user name and password check to make sure that username and password
match someone in our list.
And you would do the same thing with your database and then it's going to return the user.
So say authenticates let me collapses.
We get a little more room here takes in a username and password and then the main idea here is that
this function should check if user exists.
If so return user.
So in our case for instance for storing it as a symbolist and we already have this nice user name table
as a quick look up unless a user is equal to username it's true it's an equal sign user name underscore
table.
And then I can just say get user name.
And the reason I'm using get instead of just a call such as user name underscore a table and then say
user name.
Technically this would work but if you try calling a key that isn't in the dictionary will return an
error.
So what I can do is instead of doing a call like this with the dictionary that we created up here what
I can do is say Dot get username comma with another option to return in case we actually don't find
that user.
So I can say none.
And this basically says hey try to grab that user name key from the username table which is just the
dictionary that we created right here.
If you can't find it username that does return on.
So that's what that's doing.
And then we'll say if user and the password matches that particular user's password so equal sequel's
user password then what we're going to do is return the user.
OK so again all we're doing here with authenticate is later on we're going to use this function.
The person using the rest API is going to provide a username and password then we'll look up that username
if it exists then we'll say the password they provide it matches and then return that user if that user
doesn't exist and we just mark user as none.
So if none that immediately fails and then we're not actually gonna return a user.
So they didn't get authenticated.
OK then we have one more function to create and that's going to be an identity function.
And basically we're going to be copying the structure from the documentation for flask JWT because the
JWT object we're going to call requires a function in this format.
So sure more details on it.
You can take a look at the Flast JWT documentation.
In fact they basically have the full QuickStart example that we're going through.
It's a very similar example to what we're doing here except it's kind of all in one file with the authentication
and the identity.
And essentially what we want to do is we need to grab this function right here.
So what it does is we zoom in here it takes in the payload grabs the identity which is going to be the
user id and then just grabs up to gular entry in the User ID table and we created it using essentially
the same terminology to that here user id for you and users.
And obviously this could be a call to your model or your database instead.
So let's come back here and we're going to fill out that function ourselves centrally the exact same
thing and it'll make sense in a little bit why it has to be in this particular structure because both
authenticate and identity will be passed in to the JWT call that we're going to see in the simple API
file.
So here we're going to say user ID is equal to payload and they're going to grab identity from that
payload and then when a return user id table gets an old say user id Khama none.
OK so basically doesn't really change anything there from the documentation.
But again what we're doing here is a really simplified example.
And it's not a whole lot more to connect this to your own database.
You'd have your own database of your own models and what you do is for these commands of user name table
gets or user id table get these would just be calls to that particular database so you would say import
user from model or from models import user and you want to be dealing with this list or these tables
right here.
It's kind of just a mimic those models themselves.
OK.
So we have the security check functionality ready to go.
All we do now is come back to simple API.
We'll come to the very top and we're going to do a couple of more imports we'll say from secure check
or whatever we happen to call that file import authenticate an identity.
Those are two functions are created and they will say from flask underscore JWT import JWT and then
JWT required.
So JWT is essentially going to be the Flash version of this API.
So what you do is after you create your flask and after you create your app you create a W.T. object
and say JWT passen your app and then passen the authenticate function and then pasand the identity function.
So because JWT expects and authenticate an identity function that's where we had to create them in a
kind of specific format.
Over here it's secure check pie.
So we created those two functions and then we also passed in our app to JWT because we're going to basically
be using a kind of a form style configuration where you do is after we create our app we need to add
one more line which we've seen before.
It's app config and then we need to set up our secret key.
So we've seen this before especially when talking about forms and you can essentially call this whatever
you want.
So I'll say my secret key.
OK now you're wondering well how do I actually make certain rest API calls require authentication.
Well that's where this JWT underscore required comes into play.
In fact all you need to do is once you set up your authenticate an identity function based on how you're
storing your user information and you set up your secret key if you want to make sure something requires
authentication such as a call or a post call then you just highlight it with a decorator.
So for example here we have the get for all the names in the database.
I just say at JWT underscore required open and princes and that's it.
Now if you want to grab all the names for puppies then you're going to need to provide your username
password and get authenticated.
However if you want to delete a single puppy post a single puppy or get a single puppy.
Right now we're not requiring authentication for that.
So you can see how easy it is to you know add and subtract authentication to whatever functionality
you want because maybe you want people to be able to get anything but you only want authorized users
to be able to post things so that decorator functionality really makes the whole thing a lot easier.
And everything else essentially stays the same.
So let's see if this all worked using postman.
We're going to try to do is we're going to create two puppies into the list and then show you how you
can get your username password authenticated with a key.
So before we run postman we need to do is actually run our Web application.
So here I'm going to say Python and I'm still calling this simple API.
So we'll run that.
There we go it's running.
Now let's go ahead and go to postman.
OK so here I am at postman.
I'm going to post a couple more puppies.
So let's go ahead and post Sam.
Say send.
And then we have named Sam.
And let's go ahead and post Frankie again.
Remember every time you run this because we're storing the puppies as a list you don't actually get
saved.
So we'll post Frankie as well.
And so now I have Sam and Frankie.
Now let's try to actually get all those puppies.
Remember that we specifically required puppies with a Jason Webb token.
So if I try to get the puppies and send this request notice it says hey requests does not contain an
access token authorization required status code for 0 1 an authorized.
So how do we actually get our authorization token.
Well the first thing to do is register with the website to get a username and password so we can do
that.
A variety of ways on a template using class logon and everything is covered so far.
Keep in mind we manually created 2 users in our users that pi file Jose and Mimi.
So we'll be using them.
So if we come back to our actual Of Pi I already know whoops I mean secure check.
I already know that there's a user Jose whose password is my password.
So that's what I'm going to log in with.
So we actually log in as we go to our Web site and we're going to say Auth. so we never actually routed
this you r l that gets created automatically with flask JWT.
Again it's just for Slash a.
Th.
And then we're going to do here is in our header we're going to send a key and a value.
So the key we provide is we say content type and then we're going to give a value of application forward
slash Jaison because we're going to provide the content of our username and password as Jason.
So we also need a change sort of get to post.
So essentially we're sending or posting our username and password as Jasen to this authorization and
we receive back a token.
So the next step we need to do is click here where it says body and then we're going to select raw and
then remember we already specified we're passing this in as Jason so we're going to set up our Jason
which essentially looks like a python dictionary and we're going to set this up to have our username
and password.
So we'll say username Jose Khama password and we set it up as my password and then use the double quotes
here.
So once that's ready to go again in hetero's we have Content-Type.
Application forward slash Jason.
And then here in body we cook raw.
We have user name Jose in my password.
I remember we have post and we're sending this to us.
And in case you messed up in this process we can't see these parameters.
You can always just close this and start over again.
But let's go ahead and send this and see what we get back.
So now that I've sent that to off notice I get back this giant access token and I'm going to use this
access token in order to now get all the puppies.
So what I'm going to do is changes to get inless try reaching all those puppies again.
But now what I'm going to do is in my request Anglia's say headers and it's sort of this content type
application and said we're going to do is I'm going to create a header with an authorization key and
the value for this one is going to be JWT space.
And then what you need to do is copy this entire access token without the quotes.
So those are copying all the way up before and after the quotes.
Copy this and then JWT space go ahead and paste that in.
It's kind of easy to mess this up because how big it is but there it is.
JWT.
So once we have that data with space and then the access token go ahead and send your get requests for
the puppies.
And now that you sent it you should see all the puppies available which in this case are Samie and Franki
and now we can see that only authorize users with a username and password first need to get authorized
and then they'll get back the token and then they can use that token to actually make the request for
things that require that Jason web token and that's the very basics of using flask JWT.
You can check out the documentation.
They have tons of more examples there.
In order to expand this to your own use cases.
All right.
Coming up next we're going to work through an example of how to use flask rest API with instead of in
memory things like lists and dictionaries with actual models.
So should be pretty simple to answer that model stage.
And I think what you see that you'll be able to add in flask rest API to any of the projects we've done
in this course.
Okay we'll see at the next lecture.