Hi everyone.
Welcome to the installation and setup lecture before we can continue if all the awesome technical material
and content and actually start coding.
We need to get your environment set up first.
However if you've already taken some technical courses or maybe you've already taken some of my own
courses you may already have what we actually need.
So I want to quickly go over just in general what we actually need to be able to do.
And if you're able to do these forming ideas you may be able to just get this installation lecture entirely
so me quickly describe what you should be able to do by the end of this install and of lecture first.
You're going to need to have access to your command line either through the command prompt in windows
or terminal in Mac OS or Linux and you pretty much already have that built in.
You'll need to know where it is.
Then you should have some sort of text editor such as Adam sublime notepad plus plus visual studio etc..
We're going to be using and installing Adam for this course something I want to make very very clear
is if you're an experienced developer and you already have your preferred development environment maybe
you really love sublime or you really love visual studio please feel free to use it.
Don't feel constrained.
Adam We just happened to use it for this course because it's open source but really you have full freedom
as far as what editors you want to choose.
All the code we do here is going to work on any editor.
Once you have a text editor then we just need to install Python.
We don't use Python immediately.
We're going to enter by H.M.S. SS and bootstrap first and the crash courses then we'll touch upon python.
And then lastly you need to be able to install Python libraries through either a condo install or a
Pippin's stall.
We actually provide a requirements that textfile they can easily run in one simple one line command
to create an environment that has all the libraries we use in this course.
OK.
So here I have some time stamps because maybe you don't need everything we just covered in that list
but you may want some of that.
So look at this slide and then go to the time stamp for what you need if you need all of it then just
continue watching and come along of us for this entire lecture.
But in general we're going to set up Python.
We're going to set up Adam which is our text editor.
We're going to show you how to add a terminal to Adam so there's a little plus but you can click and
have a terminal directly and Adam will show you how to add plug into the adult to make your life a little
easier when you're editing text.
And then we'll also show you how to style it.
Adam things like adding particular color schemes to Adam.
And then finally at the end we'll try to create an environment for flask.
OK let's get started.
All right.
Here we are at the Anaconda com slash download page and it may look slightly different for you.
As far as styling is concerned but there should be three main links one for Windows one for Mac OS and
one for Linux.
On this page Anaconda's going to come with lots of data science packages.
That's why it's a distribution.
It also comes with package management as well as environment management with Conda.
So that's a tool we're going to be using as well.
So go ahead and click on the operating system that's relevant to you.
For Windows you're going to want to install the Python 3 version and I recommend the graphical installer.
There's a 64 bit version and a 32 bit version that depends on your computer.
Then for Mac OS if you're a Mac OS I would also recommend doing the graphical installer here.
So go ahead and download that graphical installer.
And if you're on Linux there is an installer right here for you for 64 bit as well as an installer for
32 bit.
OK so once you've downloaded that actual installer in order to receive instructions on how to download
it after you click on whatever your relevant operating system is you should notice that there's a link
here how to install Anaconda.
Go ahead and click on that link and it will take you to Dock's and Akala dot com slash Anaconda slash
install and then slash your operating system.
So here we have the instructions for installing on Windows.
And for most of these it's quite straightforward especially for the graphical installers you're just
clicking along.
The only thing I want to clarify is as you go along you'll notice that there's an advanced installation
option set and this is going to ask you if you want to add anaconda to my path environment variable.
If you click on this it will turn red and say Not recommended we personally recommend clicking on that
and adding anaconda to your path environment variable.
That way you can actually call Python and Konda at your command line.
So again we highly recommend that you add anaconda to my past environment variable.
That way you can call Python at your command line.
So even though it says not recommended go ahead and check that box anyways you'll see the text turned
red and then hit install.
So again if you're ever asked at Anaconda to my path var. variable.
Make sure you select that option.
OK so that's the option for Windows.
Again if you click on here for any of the other operating system such a Mac OS and click on how to install
Anaconda it will take you to the Mac OS graphical install instructions page which is right here again.
Essentially it is following along.
And again if it ever asks you to add anaconda to your path go ahead and select yes to that.
Even if it says it's not recommended for Linux users it's not going to be a graphical installer.
If you click on how to install anaconda it's basically just going to be a bash command to wherever you
happen to have downloaded that h file.
OK so that's the very basics of downloading.
Anaconda.
Once you've downloaded anaconda you should be able to run Python at your command line after you've finished
the installation process.
So let's go ahead and show you what that should look like.
OK we're going to quickly show you how to run Python.
This is going to be a confirmation that you've already downloaded and gone through the installer for
Anaconda.
All we need to do here is open up our command line for Windows users.
Are going to do a search for see M.D on your computer and that will open up your command prompt.
If you're on Mac OS or Linux you can search for terminal and that will open up your command line.
Let's do this.
I'm going to win this computer right now so I will search for ACMD and then open up my command prompt.
All right here I am at my command prompt.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux you should be at your terminal in order to check the Anaconda installed
correctly directly into your command line.
Type the word Python.
Hit enter and then you should see Python.
The version number and then some sort of clarification of Anaconda.
And once you've done this then you've successfully installed Anaconda in Python on your computer.
And if you want to keep testing things out you can print something like Hello enter and you have hello.
Hopefully you've already worked with Python by the time you reach this course since this is a course
for more experienced Python users.
I'm going to quit out of this and we're ready to go.
Remember that for basic command lines.
In order to actually change directories you can use the see the command.
And this works in either Mac OS Linux or Windows.
To go back up at the rectory you just say change directory thought and that will move back up at the
Rectory to move forward into another folder.
You can say CD and then the name of the folder.
So for example I can move back into that folder where I was by using CD.
That's really the main command you need to know for this course.
Just change in the rectory.
That way you can run your python script wherever it's located.
Let's now move on to setting up our environment.
Since you've already set up Anaconda and Python all right.
Now let's set up our development environment and this course we use the Adam text editor.
If you already have your preferred development environment such as sublime or pi charm or any other
number of ideas that are available Feel free to stick with those as long as you can run a PI script
at your command line.
You're pretty much good to go and you can skip this part of the lecture.
If you do want to explore falling along in this course with the added text editor.
Keep watching and go to Adam.
Oh and let's show you how you can install atom and set up the plugin as well as the terminal command
line there.
OK here am Adam the I O.
You should notice that somewhere on the screen there going to be a download button that's going to automatically
detect your operating system and you can just click here on this download and it should download some
sort of executable installer file and then you'll just double click that.
Follow all the defaults and install Adam.
It's a simple text editor comes off a lot of really useful features especially if you're a big abuser
Adams.
Open source and it was created by it.
So that's one of our reasons for choosing it for this course.
As I mentioned you're free to use any platform you like.
They also notice there's packages and themes so packages are basically other packages that can help
you work with Adam.
Things like Python autocomplete so I'll be using those as well.
Themes are things that can help you change the appearance of Adam such as fonts or coloring so you can
do that all.
Adam as well.
So there's packages and themes.
Go ahead and download and install Adam onto your computer and then let's open it up and show you how
you can install plugins and packages.
All right.
Once you've downloaded and installed Adam following along the defaults for the graphical installer you
should see something like this when you open out them.
However you may notice that my font or coloring is a little different than what you see as the default.
And that's because I've customized Adam to my liking.
So let's show you how you can do the same for your installation.
You'll just come to file and then go down where it says settings and you should see the core settings.
Open up.
I notice you have here packages themes and then install as well as updates so packages are things that
help you actually work better with whatever programming environment or programming languages you're
using.
So I have autocomplete Python which we're going to be using during this course.
I will show you how to install just a second theme's that's going to be things like colorization or
syntax themes.
So I have added material in a one dark as my user interface theme and as my syntax theme so you can
copy and use those as well.
They do updates once you've installed packages or themes you can update them and then you have install.
So go ahead and come to install and then we need two main packages.
Go ahead and search for Python with packages selected here.
It's going to search packages for Python and then you'll eventually see someone at the very top autocomplete
Python and I've already have it installed so you don't see the install button here but you're going
to use something like this install button.
So go ahead and install autocomplete Python as I'm coding along and this course you'll notice a little
bit of a drop down selection that helps you autocomplete your Python functions or Python commands.
That's the package that allows me to do that.
The next package you'll probably want is the a terminal package.
So go ahead and search for terminal with packages.
Select that and the one we like to use is platform you.
Ideally dashed terminal and again install this package.
What this allows you to do is once you've installed this.
If you click here on the plus button it will open up a new terminal inside of Adam.
That way you can call Python here right from inside of Adam without having to change anything.
So I can quote here and then we're going to be doing is we're going to say Python and then be running
scripts inside of atom as such.
What I want to point out is for Windows users by default it uses the power shell and usually the power
shell has issues with the Anaconda installation.
So what you're going to want to do is after you've installed the platform in the terminal what you should
do is especially if you're on a Windows computer.
Edit this so that instead of using your power shell by default it eases your command prompt by default.
Again this is only for Windows users.
It's a very quick fix.
You just come to packages and either search for terminal or scroll down to you'll find terminal.
The number you already installed terminal at this point click on settings and then somewhere along this
you should see Shell override where you're going to do is write this command right here.
You're going to have a point to see Windows system 32 C M D E X.
E because by default it's going to point to power shell.
Again this is only for Windows users.
If you're a Mac OS or Linux it's going to automatically point to a terminal and you shouldn't have any
issues.
All right so that's a shell overwrite and that's an important step for Windows users.
Using the terminal inside of Adam the last thing I ought to point out is editing colors and themes.
As I mentioned if you come over to the core settings and click on themes I'm using atom material in
one dark as my syntax theme.
If you ever want to install those you just come to install click on themes and then search whatever
themes you want such as one dark enter and you can see the one dark you find that I have installed.
So that's an option for you.
A lot of times you can play around if you like a light setting you can do that as well if you like a
darker setting.
You can do that and if you google search more Adam actually has the ability to put custom CSSA scripts
so you can color this however you see it.
OK that's really all there is to Adam.
The main thing here we're just installing it setting up Python autocomplete setting up this terminal
so you can call Adam and show you how to install themes and syntax themes.
All right.
Now they've installed Anaconda in Python to computer.
It's time to set up the environment now technically it's optional to set up a virtual environment with
the com the command line tool a virtual environment basically allows you to create a version of Python
and certain library installations on your computer that will hold that actual versioning of the pit
installed libraries.
That way you don't need to worry in case Dasch has an upgrade later on into the future.
You're going to be able to run our notes securely and make sure they work in your virtual environment
so we're going to be using Pipp install to install the required libraries.
You can use pitmen staw with or without that virtual environment.
However we do recommend using that virtual environment.
That way you basically have a container that can hold the specific versions of dash and you can play
around future versions of plotline in a separate virtual environment.
So for convenience we've already created a requirements text file that you can use this requirements
that textfile is essentially just a list of libraries to install with Pipp so it'll be really easy to
use that at your command line to just have a single line that installs all the libraries will be using
in order to actually use that requirements that textfile at the command line you're going to need to
see the or change directory at your command line to wherever you see the unzipped version of the court's
notes or files.
So make sure you've already downloaded the unzipped version of the course notes files.
So usually we provide them as a zip file.
You'll download them unzip and then there should be a requirement that text file in that actual folder
that was unzipped.
So let's go to our command line find the requirements that text file and show you can create a virtual
environment and then easily install all the libraries required for the course.
OK here I am in my downloads folder I've already downloaded the flask bootcamp zip file from the course
overview lecture which has a resource there.
If you're wondering how you get this zip file please go back and watch the course overview lecture.
We explain they're all there.
It's also linked as a resource in the fake Q lecture.
Once you have this zip file you can need to unzip it.
You can use any program you want to extract or unzip this.
So I'm on Windows so I'll just click extract all.
If you're on Mac OS there is something called the archive utility which will automatically extract this.
OK so once you extract that I'm going to fast forward in time and here underneath my extracted flask
bootcamp folder I have another folder called flat's boot camp so you can see it's kind of a double nested
naming scheme and we have all the folders for the course in order so we start off with the team L C
Ss and bootstrap.
We have some command line options here for text.
Each team Allen crash course CSSA etc and everything's numbered in essentially the order you would take
it in the course.
So if we come back here then we have the python sections by I level 1 level 2 then we get into floss
basics template basics etc. and so on.
At the very bottom you can see a requirements not textfile.
If you double click on that let's not rename it just double click and open it you'll see it's essentially
a list of Python libraries such as flask or flask log in and then the particular version number what
we're going to do is we're going to create a flask environment and then install all these requirements
into that environment.
That way when you activate your environment you can have the exact same libraries and code that we did
when we were developing this course and what that means is you're going to have in an environment where
we guarantee that our DOT PI scripts will work.
So you can always use or thought postscripts with an environment to make sure and double check.
In case you ever get a problem with your code.
So this is really for your benefit.
So in case you ever have any issues all you need to do is actually our environment and Brunner's that
postscripts correctly and it's guaranteed to work.
So let's get started and actually show you how you can create an environment and set up the requirements
to do this.
You're going to need to go to either your terminal or command prompt depending on what your operating
system is.
I'm on Windows so I'll go to my command prompt.
So what I need to do is CD into Downloads.
And then I'm going to change directory into flask boot camp and in my case because of the way I unzip
it I need to C.D one more time.
It's a flask boot camp and remember it should always be checking this against the file path where you
just saw in your Windows Explorer or your finder on Mac OS and then we're going to do here is confirm
that our requirements that txt file is there so I'm going to type D I ArcSight on Windows and Mac OS
or Linux type ls.
And when you do this you should see a list of all those folders we are just talking about as well as
the requirements that txt file.
Now that I know I'm in the right location it's time to create my environment.
I do this at the command line by typing Konda create dash and and then whatever the name of the environment
I want keep in mind if you already have existing environments this name needs to be unique.
So I will call this my new flask envy and then I'm going to say space Python and I'm going to set Python
equal to 3.6 or the time of this recording Python 3.7 is not released yet.
So we're just going to use 3.6 will hit enter and what's going to happen is condescension going to ask
you hey you want me to set up these new packages for Python 3.6.
In this environment.
So I type wife yes I enter and then it's going to set everything up for me.
Ok this may take a little bit of time.
A couple of minutes at most and we're going to fast forward in time until this is done.
All right so all of that just finished installing I've gone forward in time.
And then once it's all done installing we should be able to activate our environment.
If you're on a Mac OS or Linux you're going to type out source activate and then the name of your environment.
If you're on Windows and you're using the command prompt you don't need to type out source.
You just need to type out the word activate.
It was my new flask.
And we went to enter and if you successfully activate in your environment they should be able to see
in sees some indication saying hey right now you're working inside your environment.
Perfect.
Now what I want to do is install all the libraries in the requirements that text file into my new environment
the way I can do this quite easily is by saying Pip install dash are and then requirements dot text
make sure you're able to autocomplete by just hitting tab requirements that text if you're not able
to tap autocomplete that it means you're in the wrong directory or your requirements are text file isn't
in that directory.
So when you change directory until you're in the correct one.
So then enter and this is going to automatically install all the flask libraries we use in this course.
Pretty sweet huh.
OK let's forward in time until it's ready to go.
Once it's done installing all those libraries you can test it out quickly by just typing up Python.
Hitting enter and then type out.
Import flask.
Hit enter.
And if you don't get any error that means flask was successfully installed using the requirements saw
text file and you're good to go.
All right.
We finished setting up everything and now we're ready to go and continue on the course.
If you got stuck on any of these parts please make sure you review the video carefully and if you're
still confused and you can't find your solution on stack overflow then just post the Kewaunee forums
and we're happy to help you out there.
Make sure you also do a search in the Kewney forums because it's very likely the other students have
already probably asked and have answered similar questions.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.