Welcome back everyone to this lecture on strings strings are sequences of characters and the syntax
of either single quotes or double quotes.
So here we have a couple of string examples the first one uses single quotes of Hello.
The second one uses double quotes of Hello.
And the third one.
Notice what's happening here.
We have a single quote already inside the string.
I don't do that.
So in order to make sure your string doesn't prematurely stop with the single quote inside of don't
what we do is we add two double quotes and block it off.
That way we can understand with Python that we don't want the strings and at don't.
Instead we can wrap it in the other quote tight.
So that's why we have the use of both single and double quotes.
If one of your double quotes or some quotes is planning to be inside of your string you just wrap it
again and the other quote type Now more importantly because strings are ordered sequences.
It means we can use indexing and slicing to grab subsections of the string indexing notation.
Use a square bracket notation after the string or after the variable assigned the string indexing allows
you to grab a single character from the string.
So what does that actually mean.
Let's see some examples of that.
So again those indexing actions and the slicing actions are going to use square brackets notation and
we do as you pass in a number index instead of the square brackets to indicate the positions of what
you want to grab.
So here I have the string hello and now I have a corresponding index for each of these characters.
So zero goes of H one goes if e to the first L three at the fourth L or second L and then for the Oh.
So there we have hello and if I want to grab back the letter H.
All I need to do is pass an 0 into the square brackets.
Keep in mind Python also has the ability to do a reverse indexing so we can go starting at age 0 and
then go all the way to the end of the string and that's negative one.
Then we have it too.
And so on.
So reverse indexing is really useful when you may not know the string length and you want to grab maybe
the last character string.
For example if someone's registering for a web site and they provide a user name and the user name is
not going to be known beforehand.
And for whatever reason you wanted to grab the last letter of the username instead of trying to guess
the index position of the very last letter where you could do is just pass a negative one and that will
automatically grab the last letter.
Regardless of how long the string is.
So that's indexing which allows you to grab a single character element from the string.
Slicing allows you to grab a subsection of multiple characters otherwise known as a slice of the string.
So slicing has the following syntax.
You start with square brackets and then you have a start colon a stop colon and then this step.
So start as a numerical index for the slice start stop is the index you're going to go up to but not
include and then step is the size of the jump you're going to take between start and stop.
OK.
So that's going to be more clear when we actually work through those examples.
For now let's go to Adam and explore these concepts overcoached strings indexing strings slicing strings.
And then we'll also talk about string properties methods and how we can't print format variables inside
of her own strings.
What to cover so let's get started.
OK here I am back at home and I have my exampled up my file open.
Let's go and just type out a string.
Hello.
And again notice what's happening if I run this python my example that pi actually doesn't get any output
in order to see the output.
I'm going to need to print this out.
So say a print and then pass in the string you want to print hello with double quotes or single quotes
and then we see Hello as the output.
So keep that in mind as you're working if not postscripts.
It's easy to forget.
They need to print things out in order to see them as output at your command line.
So that's the basics of printing a string.
I also want to show you a really useful function called Alien which checks the length of a string.
And we'll also see how it's able to check the length of many object types.
But if you want to know the length of the string you just passing that string inside of the end function.
So I pass in Hello.
Inside the length of this function and then print out the result.
Now tell me how many characters are inside of this string.
In my case it's 5.
So 0 1 2 3 4 5.
You should know it's going to count spaces as well.
So if I add in three spaces there and then run this it's now going to report 8.
Because these three spaces also count as part of that sequence of characters.
OK.
So that's printing out a string and that's checking the length of a string.
Let's talk about indexing now.
I'm going to start for variable assignment.
I'll see my string is equal to hello.
And then I want to get it to do is let's imagine I wanted to print out the first letter of the string.
What I would do is say my string and then I have this square bracket notation for indexing you pass
in the index number of whatever character you want.
So if I want h.
Remember that's going to start at zero.
So then I pass an 0 here and then I can print out that result.
So let's do that then a print out my string 0 run this.
And now I get back in h over here.
Let's imagine.
I want it.
E Well that's going to be 1 over so 0 1.
So I just pass in one save that and when they run this I get back.
Let's imagine I want it.
Oh there's two ways I can do that.
I could go 0 1 2 3 4.
So capacity a four here save it run it and I would get back in 0.
Or alternatively I could use negative indexing to say hey go to negative 1 essentially grab the last
letter in that string and then that also gives it back.
So that's indexing describing a single element or character from the string.
The next thing I want to talk about is slicing.
So we just talked about here was indexing.
Now let's talk slicing a string.
So in order to slice a string we're going to use a little bit of different syntax and I'm actually going
to type in something like a b c d e f g h i j.
There you are slicing and to be more obvious.
So right now we know how to grab a single letter from the string but would have actually wanted to grab
a slice of letters such as ABC.
Oh what I could do is the following.
I'll say my string and the syntax is going to be your start colon and then your stop.
So let's imagine I want to grab ABC.
That means I want to start at zero colon and then you're going to go stop up to the index you want to
grab two.
So I want to get a b c so that's 0 1 2.
And the way Python works is you're going to go up to not including index position 3 to go 0 1 2 and
then up to but not including three so that's important to know that the start position is inclusive
and the end position or stop position is Xclusive.
So that sometimes confuses a beginner so just keep that in mind.
I'm going to print out the results of this and it's go all the way to the end.
Close off that parentheses run this.
And now I get back a b c Let's explore for another example let's imagine I want to grab the F G what
I'm going to do is figure out where I'm going to start.
So start is inclusive starting to go 0 1 2 3 4.
So there's that e.
So say for colon.
And then I want to go grab F.G. up to and including index h 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
There we go for seven.
And let's see if that grass is f g.
We run it and there we go F G again.
Careful note here on the stop index.
It's again going up to but not including that top index is included.
Stop goes up to and not including it.
That's a really common point for beginners to kind of get confused by.
Now I also want to show you that it can add in the step size here so for.
Let's go from 0 up to let's say G.
So we go from 0 to 7.
So if I run that that gives me back ABC D E F G.
But let's add in a third parameter here and I say colon again and then pasand to remember goes.
Start Colan stop colon step.
So now that I have that what it's going to do is by default it takes a step size of one goes a then
one over B than one over see if I pass and two as it's third parameter it's going to go a go to over
to see go to over to E and so on.
So then when I print out this result I get back a C E G again it's going in step size of two and you
can play around with the step size to keep making larger and larger jumps.
So they want to make a jumps or steps or three because a.
One two three.
The one two three to G and so on.
OK.
So that's the start the stop and the step size now because it's so common to start at the very beginning
of a string let's go back here to this example 0 7 which gives us everything up to this sort of command
is really common.
Starting at the beginning of a string and then going all the way to some index that you can actually
if you remove 0 it will default to zero.
So if say colon and some number that's going to say starting at the beginning of the string go all the
way up to but not including that index.
So running that is going to get you ABC the BFG.
Now just like starting from the very beginning.
You can also say go all the way to the end.
So if you put a number down and then type in a colon that's going to say starting in Expedition 7.
Give me the string all the way to the end so that you get IGY.
So this one is pretty nice that you don't need a count over what the last index position of the string
is.
So you say start here colon go all the way to the end and the opposite is colon start at the very beginning
and go all the way to this particular index position.
OK.
Now the last thing I want to know which is kind of interesting thing is if we say colon colon that means
start from the very beginning and go all the way to the end.
Now that by itself isn't really useful because it's basically just asking for the whole string back.
But often what people like to do is they like to then add in the step parameter so that says starting
all the way from the beginning going all the way to the end going to step size of two.
So when I run that we should see a step size of two to see step size to eat and so on.
All the way until we get to the end the string which in this case is going to be I given our step size.
OK.
So again colon colon start from the very beginning all the way to the end.
And give me a step size or two.
What's really interesting is that you can actually then use a reverse step size and we want to do this
too often.
Basically still in time we're going to show it but you can reverse the strain quite easily using something
like start from the very beginning to the end.
But give me is the size of negative one.
So it's going to basically start here and then go backwards to J I h.
And so on.
So when you save it and run it you actually get the reverse of the string.
So this is a really quick way to reverse a string in Python.
Again won't be doing it too much in this course but just keep in mind that it's available to you.
Finally I want to talk about some string properties and string methods as well as how we can use what's
known as string interpellation to print out strings.
So we talking about indexing and slicing.
Very important things.
I also want to talk about the fact that strings are immutable.
Meaning if I wanted to change the character here a to z what it cannot do is I cannot do the following.
I can't say hey my stream index position zero.
Go ahead and assign that to Z.
In fact if you just try to do that it's going to say hey type error an SDR object a string object does
not support item assignment.
So that means we see a string like this.
You can no longer mutate it or change it.
So this is known as E mutability the unability to mutate the actual object.
Later on we'll learn about different data types and different data structures that we can mutate that.
But keep in mind strings are immutable.
You can't however concatenate strings.
So that's kind of cool.
So I can say my string plus my string and that's going to concatenate it together so that you'll see
your string once and then it's going to concatenated again off itself.
So then that means you can do something like this.
Hello space concatenated with which is just using the plus sign and then someone's name for example
Hello Jose.
So that's a really quick way to do some print formatting of strings just concatenate them together like
that.
Just keep in mind.
You'll have to be aware spacing because if I just said hello Plus Jose there's technically no space
there.
So when you run that you just see Hello.
Jose is one giant string.
So keep that in mind.
You can concatenate strings in that fashion.
Now I want to talk about some string methods.
So there's lots of methods available on strings so I'm going to change just say capital H.
Hello world.
So if I ever want to capitalize every single letter in the string basically make everything uppercase
I could take my string and then call up or on it.
And if I just call Upper like this with no print C's it's actually going to give a weird response which
will take on just a second.
But in order to uppercase everything you call the variable name dot and then this method upper open
and close princes.
So these are known as methods on an object and we'll talk about methods and a lot more detail when we
discuss object oriented programming.
But right now just kind of keep these things in mind that they are available to you.
So notice now.
Hello world.
Everything's uppercase when I called the upper there now.
Likewise there is a lower so I can say lower save that.
And when I run this back.
Hello world.
Everything's in lowercase now so H and W now become lowercase.
Now if I forget those print C's and I just print out my string the lower what's going to happen is Python's
going to report back hey you have this built in method called lower of the string object at this location
inside your memory to actually execute that method.
Essentially make it run.
You have to have these open and close print C's and that method of open or close print sees versus no
parentheses.
It will make a lot more sense when we actually learn how to create our own functions which is happening
at the end of this section.
OK so those are two methods.
Upper and Lower that are really useful.
Last one I want to mention which is going to kind of be a precursor to our next lecture is the split
method and what happens is the split method will split the string on whitespace to create a list.
We don't technically know what the list is yet so it's kind of when to show you this hello world.
And notice making a list now based off the two strings here separated by the whitespace and then you
can technically expand on that by providing the actual letters you want to split on.
So if you wanted to split every time there was a w such as its capital W I would just say capital W
inside a split.
Run that and then I get to see it split on W..
OK again this is more of a preview than something you need to really learn right now.
Main thing you should be aware of is that you can index and slice from strings and then finally I'm
going to talk about print formatting.
So there's two main ways to do print formatting.
There's actually lots of different ways but the two main ones were going to be using the first one is
let's say we have a user name and we'll just set the sequel to Sammy as the username and then let's
say they have a favorite color so will create a color variable and their favorite color is blue.
Let's imagine I wanted to print something out that said this user names.
Favorite color is blah blah blue.
So that's a little tricky right now because right now I have a user name and color as variables.
What I can't do is say this.
The username save favor it is color.
If I just run this then that's what I'm going to get back to the stream that username favorite is color.
So that's not really helpful because Python doesn't realize I'm asking for the variable username not
the string user name.
So in order to actually make that work I have two options.
One is using the dot format method so I can replace what I want to insert with curly braces so I'll
say the curly braces favorite is curly braces and then right after that double quote I can type that
format and then pasan what I want to be filled in to those curly braces such as username and color.
So what's happening now and you can really see this in the syntax highlighting user name and color here.
Now these are variables in Python using the format method is going to insert them in order to wherever
the curly braces are.
So we'll save that.
Run this and then I get to see the Samie favorite is blue.
So takes the user name Sammy format's it sticks it in there takes the color variable blue formats and
then sticks it in there.
OK the last thing I want to mention is the ability to use f string literals for printing.
And this is something we will see in the course.
However I want to make it very clear this is only available on Python 3.6 and above.
So if you're running Python 3.5 maybe you downloaded Python in early 2018 and 3.6 wasn't available free
yet you may get an error when running this line.
So double check that your version of Python is 3.6 or above.
So this is going to be F string literals.
Is called F string.
Literals and this makes it actually really easy to print format stuff.
So what you do is you type in an F and then a set of either single quotes or double quotes and then
you just pass in your variable names instead of curly braces directly.
So we can say something like the user name
chose color.
So that's going to do is because these are now curly braces and decided to have an F in there.
When I run this I now get back to see the Samie chose blue.
If you forget that f and try running this you're going to get the actual string itself the username
chose color.
So you let Python know hey I'm referring to variables by starting that string with an F outside of the
quotes.
So again it's called F string literals and it's only available in 3.6 and above and you'll be seeing
us using the course because this is essentially the most compact way.
It's more compact than using the dot format method.
But if you don't have 3.6 yet you can always use that format.
OK.
That's really the basics of strings.
We just covered and actually index strings slice strings a few properties of strings and some methods.
And then as well as print formatting if you have any questions feel free to post the Cunio forms.
We'll see at the next lecture.