Welcome back to this lecture on Temple inheritance.
We already know that we can create view functions that are directly linked to an HTL template but that
still means that we need to make an html template for every page that we link to using that render underscore
template function.
Usually pages across web application already share a lot of features things like navigation bars or
footers aren't going to change drastically from page to page.
In fact it's almost always the same code.
For example when you log into Facebook that navigation bar at the very top is going to be the same regardless
of the actual page you're on.
Within Facebook.
So it would be nice instead of having to retype that same navigation bar code to every single HTL metafile
or HTL template instead of a web application.
If we could have a base HTL file and then use that to extend to every other template file.
So this solution is called template inheritance.
And as I just mentioned what we do is we set up a base H.T. template file with the reuseable aspects
of our site.
Then we use extend based on HCM syntax in the extended HTL file and then use the block syntax statements
to extend these reusable aspects to other pages.
Let's see the quick example of what this would actually look like.
Inciter templates folder.
What we end up having is a base the same file and within this base h html file is where you put your
reuseable aspects of code things like the footer your linked to a CSSA file links to bootstrap or your
navigation bars.
These are components you expect to be on pretty much every page of your web application.
Then once you have those reusable components you set up a block and you set a block and then the content
name of your block.
By convention it's usually called content but technically you can call it whatever you want and then
you have an end block statement after that in another each time I'll file essentially another template
file.
What you do is you say extends from your base h tim L and then you call the same block and then you
insert your code that specific for home.
The T.M. into that block.
And what happens is once you actually run this in your web application your application will grab the
code from base about H.T. mail and then insert where you set your block the home the H.T. mail or whatever
specific template each time you have there.
And then you get back a final result where you don't have to constantly be retyping that base HTML code.
Things like navigation bar into every single template page.
So we're going to be walking through an example of this later on in the lecture.
Finally in this lecture We're also going to briefly introduce the concept of filters.
Filters are a really great way to quickly change or a variable passed into a template instead of having
to edit it back at your flask Python script.
So what this actually looks like is when you pass in a variable you can also use the pipe operator and
then pass on the name of the filter.
And a lot of times these filters share the same names as Python methods on normal objects such as a
string.
So for example let's imagine that we passed in a variable called Name and by the time we got to the
web application it was an all lowercase and we wanted to somehow called capitalized on it.
Recall that capitalized is actually a method you can use on the Python string.
But instead of having to go back to your Python code figure out where the actual strings being manipulated
and then add the capitalized method call what you could do is use the filter instead.
And then inside your actual HTML temple of file you would just say the name of the variable pipe operator
in the name of the filter.
For example capitalized and then when it's right there on the page you would see something like has
a capital G.
All right.
Let's see these concepts in action and head over to a text editor.
Or a text editor.
Notice how now underneath my templates folder I have three female files.
One is a base.
Each time I'll file and then we're going to extend that to home HTL and then puppie thought each T.M.
Let's first connect these with our flask application will just simply be calling the route.
We'll start off for home page and we'll say index and here we're going to return render a template and
we'll just pass an home that H Timo then for our second view we'll see the route.
And this one is going to be puppy.
And then the user can provide a name for the puppy so we'll call this new name and then we're actually
going to pass in that name and then we're going to return render a template we'll say we thought HVM
El her name is equal to name.
Notice that I'm not actually creating a specific view for base h tim L and that's because we never called
base HTL directly from flask.
Instead we're going to extend it using templating.
So we're kind of come to base himself first and this is where you want to set up things that you know
you're going to use for essentially most of your pages and you have multiple base each team else that's
also no problem.
Typically with last use can have one.
And let's start off by just typing out a T.M. notice I have already say that as Nates HTML file which
means I have autocomplete with a title.
This is going to now be the same title across all pages.
We'll call it puppy rock.
And let's also add in some links when adding the links for bootstrap for showing to copy and paste these
in here you can do the same from the notes or from the bootstrap Web site.
If you also want to use the older version of bootstrap that's fine as well.
As long as you copy the right script going to collapse the left hand side here.
And what we're going to do now in the body is set up 8 navigation bar.
So I'll say now of and then I'm going to set up a class and I go to copy this class from the notes because
it's kind of long.
So essentially just a bunch of code that I copied and pasted from the bootstrap documentation as we
discussed during the bootstrap lectures.
And let's go ahead and add in an anchor tag.
We don't actually really need to link it to anything.
Later on we'll show you how you can link tags within your navigation bar to other pages on the Web site.
But right now keep things simple we'll say class and then say nav bar dash brand.
So it's kind of the brand page and then we'll just have it say puppies rock.
All right so I have my navigation bar.
And typically what we would have to do is copy and paste all this code into home that each time.
And puppy that age HTML.
But that's not really good practice for dry principles.
That is don't repeat yourself.
D are white.
So instead we're going to do is once you have selected and have an idea of everything you want to use
for your base template you're going to say block and then the name of your block and by convention it's
usually content you're going to have a matching and block
and notice because this block is actually named content.
It does leave out the possibility to have multiple blocks within your base team file will keep things
simple for now and we'll just use a single block which is extremely common.
So now what we need to do is since we have our base template page all the stuff that we want to then
extend to the other HCM l files.
I'm going to say this and then underneath home but each time I'll I'm going to say the following.
At the top with my syntax I'll sameas zoom in just a little bit here.
Extends.
And if you actually have a particular library just start typing extends it will autocomplete this for
you.
But that's actually not what I wanted.
I will just say extends manually and then as a string you pass and the actual name of the file inside
templates are extending from sual say extends based on each T.M. and then you call the block and then
the name of the Block.
In our case we called the name of the block content and then we say and the block as one word.
All right.
So what that means is in between your first block and after your end block is all this code.
All this code is going to be inserted as we just showed through that visual example.
Inside the slides.
So that means we can then insert stuff inside or block.
So this is the home page where we're going to say something like this is the home page and then we'll
say go to slash puppy slash name
save that and let's do this one more time for a puppy at that age T-Mo.
So on the puppy page we're going to do the same thing.
We're going to say extends we're extending from that base team I'll file and then we set up our block
and depending on what plugins you have you can just type out block and it will autofill block and block
and then you just need to provide the name content.
And here will have a header say this is the page for and then we're going to insert the name number
and passing in this name variable all the way back in my flask application.
So that's the name that the user provided at the end of the.
Main thing to get here though is our use case of content and end blocks here as well as the keywords
for extending.
All right.
And you can always use are provided notes where we have a very similar example to this.
We're going to do now is actually run our script.
Make sure it works I'll call Python basic about pi enter.
And it looks like it's running.
Let's make sure we have no errors they're going to come over here and I'm quite zoomed in.
But you'll notice here I have this navigation bar at my home page so this navigation bar is again not
actually defined inside of home but each time.
There's nothing here that says set up a navigation bar.
Instead all we're saying is extend from baseline h tim L and that baseline smell that has the code for
this actual navigation.
It's also a link.
So if I click on it technically nothing happens but later I'll show you how you can use that link to
go back to the home page.
Since that's the home page I want to get a forward slash puppy name.
So it is a forward slash puppy.
Let's go to Rufus and then it says this is the puppy page for Rufus and to finish off this lecture.
I just want to show you quickly how you can use filters with your template variables.
So the way we do that is we're actually inserting this variable.
I say a pipe operator and then I can pass any filter.
There's lots of different filters you can use and you can check out the documentation link in this lecture
to see the various filters.
A lot of them actually match up with method calls from Python objects.
So they'll feel pretty familiar.
We're not going to be using them a whole lot in this course but just know that they're there for your
convenience.
For example capitalize was one that we discussed.
So let's go ahead and use it or to come back with our browser after we've saved that.
And I'm going to say lowercase is the name of my puppy.
And now when it says this is the puppy page.
Notice how the L has been capitalized because I have that capitalized filter back over on this line
right here.
All right.
That's really the basics of temporal inheritance.
I hope you found that useful.
Now you don't need to copy and paste so much code between all your template files.
We'll see you at the next lecture.