Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss how to inspect elements on a Web site the Chrome
browser comes the ability to inspect elements on a web page.
In most modern browsers do not just chrome we can use that to then explore the web pages each time.
And CSSA components and even edit them on the fly.
Let's quickly see how this works in the browser.
Here I am at Google dot com and you can perform the sort of inspection on any Web site.
What you do is you pick an element that you're interested in.
For example let's choose this about button over here on the nav bar.
I'm going to right click on about and then select inspect.
Upon selecting inspect either on the bottom of your browser on the right hand side you should see this
doc show up and if you want to change the location of the dock you can click these three buttons and
then choose where you want it.
You can have it dock to the bottom to the left or even open in a separate window right now I'll just
keep it on dock to the right and then what you notice is it will actually highlight in the raw H.T.
mail that's being served from Google dot com.
What is the reference to that particular button.
So you notice here as you scroll down you can even see the styles.
So you can see display padding left color and more.
So I can actually edit these colors.
In fact let's click on this little box and that opens up a color picker and I can decide to make this
maybe a bright orange.
So then upon selecting that that's a bright orange if I take a look back I'm actual nav bar.
I've changed that now pure orange for me.
Keep in mind we're only editing our particular view of Google dot com as it's rendered right now in
the browser.
I'm actually editing the real Google dot com for everyone else.
And you can see here the various other CSSA style components the value pairs that are being displayed.
That's really all we wanted to show you here for the inspect element.
It's really useful when you're exploring other people's Web sites and maybe you want to take some ideas
from their Web sites and implement them in your own sites.
All you need to do is right click inspect and you could see both the HVM mail as well as the styles.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
I hope you find that information useful and I encourage you to play around with the various styles of
Web sites you're already familiar with and see how they change the Web site.
If you ever want to go back to the original site all you need to do is just refresh and you'll see the
original colors and styles.
OK that's it.
We'll see you at the next lecture.