Welcome back.
We're going to finish off this section of the course with a little coda long project with forms and
flash.
We want you to expand the code from the previous lecture to do the following.
I want to add a string field for Breede save that input for the breed to the session and then send the
Flast message to the user indicating their choice of breed.
Upon hitting submit so because there's really only a few extra lines of code needed to do this I want
you to first try to add them on your own and see if you can get it to work.
This lectures also going to serve as a code along lecture for example solution because they're really
just a few lines you need to add.
We're not going to bother splitting this into an exercise or solution.
We're just going to now continue on to show you what the solution should look like.
Let me briefly introduce what the final web page is going to look like.
I'm actually just going to bring it over here.
So what are you going to do.
It's going to ask you what Bredar you are going to be able to enter whatever breed you want hit submit
and then you should see something that says you just change your breed to and then whatever the user
submitted.
So if I change this to be something like pootle and hit submit the update to poodle and I should be
able to dismiss that flash message again.
Not that many actual lines of code from the previous lecture to actually add in that functionality.
So go ahead try to attempt this on your own.
It's up to you if you want to start from scratch or just out on the few extra lines to the previous
lecture.
OK let's code along an example solution to get this effect.
All right.
Here I am at the text editor I have the code from last time where we just have a simple submit button
and then we flashed.
You just click the button and redirect to the home page with that flash and then on our index Tim L..
Basically the same thing for messaging get flash messages.
We replay that message here and then we have the form.
So the first thing we need to do is in our simple form I'm going to add a breed and call this string
field and then we'll ask what breed are you question mark.
Let's make sure we actually import it string field and it looks like we did.
So there will be two forms we just need to add in Springfield.
Now that I have that field what I'm going to do is come down here to form that validate on submit.
Notice that if we scroll back up I've also imported session.
So I'm going to use that to grab the Breit and then I'm going to set that as part of my flash message.
So how can I do that.
Well instead of saying Just flash you click the button I'm going to say if for for the session set the
Breede key equal to form outbreed data and then I will say flash in here I'm going to say you just changed
your breed to and then I'm going to answer session breed and in order to use this sort of insertion
I'm going to use string interpolation So this only works if Python 3.6 or higher.
Keep that in mind.
The alternative to do that is to say that format and then format it that way.
So right now we're just going to have that.
So I have an F string literal.
I'm grabbing formed outbreed saving it to my session and then flashing.
You just change your Breede session outbreed or excuse me session Breede here.
That's actually all I need to do in my H HTML file.
So I'm going to save this come back to my index study each time.
I actually don't need to change anything for the get flashed messages because it's just going to pass
in get flash messages and this mess is then going to be this flash right here you just change your breed
to whatever that breed in the session is chosen.
What I have to do is just add in form dog that label and then form that Breit.
OK so now that we have that ready to go.
Let me make sure we save that and then I'm going to say Python.
They basic that PI enter and let's check to see that everything ran well and that we don't have any
bugs.
So bringing in my browser if we're running that says what breed are you going to choose pootle I'll
just click me.
I get this flash message change of read to pootle I can dismiss it because that bootstrap code if I
choose lab hit click me.
It says you just change your Bre to laugh.
OK.
That's really all you had to do for this project.
Again the main changes we did is we added a new field to our form.
We saved that form data to the session and then in our flash message we report back that session Breede
remember just using string interpolation here as discussed in the structure in the Python section of
the course.
Lots of different ways you can formatted this and then back in the h t m l.
The only thing we really change here is just adding that breede to the form.
OK that ends our discussion of forms and fields and all that good stuff with flask and hopefully now
you get to see how easy it is to create forms and connect them from your temple of H-2 mill to your
actual flask application.
Well we haven't really discussed yet is actually saving that user input data to a database.
So the entire next section is just going to be a discussion on databases.
So let's get started.
I'll see you at the next section of the course.