Welcome back.
To finish off this section of the API we're going to show you how to connect the actual things like
get posts and delete methods to a database.
So far we've been dealing with things just held temporarily in memory such as a list.
So what we're going to do is we're going to convert our previous guest posts and delete methods inside
of our rest a resource class and we're going to use it to actually change his methods to grab objects
from a database.
So all we really need to do is create a model and then replace the methods with what we've already learned
about basic applications of sequel alchemy based models.
Essentially we're really not going to learn anything new in this lecture.
We're just going to see how to connect what we already know about basic crud with models to our rest
API functionalities that we just learned.
So we're going to work at the same files as we did in the previous lecture.
We're just going to create a model and then edit the methods.
Let's get started.
OK.
Here we are at our simple API that py file.
We're going to keep the same files for secure check as well as user pie.
Keep in mind if you want to expand on what we're showing in this lecture you could convert this user
to be a model itself and then just call those models from the secure check file and set of these tables.
But really what we want to focus on are these three methods right here get post and delete.
And essentially all we need to do is connect these to the methods that we already learn when manipulating
models and databases with flask.
So in order to do that let's go ahead and create a flask model.
So we're going to say up at the top from flask sequel alchemy import sequel alchemy.
So nothing new here.
And we're also going to use flask Miree so say from flask migrate import migrate.
So we've seen all that before we set up our app.
We set up our configurations and we have a couple of more configurations to set up.
And these are the ones related to our model so say base directory is equal to OS path.
Absolute path.
And then inside of that we'll say OS path directory name and then we'll pass and file.
So we do this every time that we create models and then we'll set up the configurations for the model.
So one will be sequel alchemy underscore database underscore.
You are.
I will set that equal to sequel.
Colon three forward slashes plus OS not path.
Join and join that base directory.
Data sequel.
Essentially saying go ahead and create that database you or I in the same location that we're currently
in.
They'll say app config and then will say sequel.
Alchemy again underscore track modifications and we'll set that equal to false.
OK so we have our configuration set up.
Next we're going to do is we'll say D-B is equal to sequel alchemy in our app and then we want to be
able to call the migrations from the command line.
So say migrate Hassen the app to connect it to the database.
Okay perfect.
So this takes care of our database configurations and this takes care of our API as well as authentication.
Now what we need to do is instead of storing things in this puppy's list to create a section here for
the model and we're doing this all in one file.
You could just create an other file called models that Pizer them in the past and import it from there.
We'll keep things simple.
We'll just say class puppie say D-B model and then here will say name is equal to D-B column and.
But Beezer is going to have a name that's a string type column let's say 80 characters is the limit
and we'll just have this be their primary key.
Obviously you could expand this to whatever you wanted it could have IDs breeds and so on is it done
before.
So we have the name will say in its self common name and we'll just say when you create a puppy give
that puppy a name.
And in this case it's a little unrealistic because every puppy has to have a unique name.
So but what really need to worry about the IDs here we'll just say DFI Jaison because we want to do
is when we have an instance of a puppy we can actually return back a puppy instance with flasks.
API are not going understand that we return back something that basically looks like adjacent objects
so when we say def Jaison return we're going to say return back name with self-taught name.
So when we actually return calls we're not going to return a puppy object we're gonna get that puppy
object and then called J son off of it in order to return a on a representation of the object.
And if we have more stuff here you could say then breed.
Self-taught breed.
And so on.
There's actually lots of examples like this in the flask restful documentation and at the very end we'll
kind of show you some of those as well.
OK.
So we have this puppy model we initiated and then we have the Jason.
So now when you do just go through the method calls and fix them so they are actually linking to this
model.
So if we want to grab something from a model database then we already know what we need to do.
We need to basically not have this list for that anymore.
We'll say pup is equal to puppy and we run a query that also filter by name is equal to name and then
grab the first one and then if we actually get a puppy out we'll say if there's a puppy return.
So if pup return pup Jaison and that's where it's really nice to have that Jason method built into the
model class.
So I would recommend that you're building up models and you think rest API is going to be a big part
of your web site.
Go ahead and add in that Jason method call built into the model.
OK.
So else.
So there's no puppy there.
We're just going to say return.
Name none 404.
OK.
So that's our simple guess.
Again we just filter by whatever unique identifier primary key you have and then return that based on
version for a posting.
It's going to be kind of similar to what we've done before we'll say pup is equal to.
And then here we're going to do is create a new instance of a puppy.
Her name is equal to name that's passed in.
When someone's posting a request and they will say D-B session go ahead and add that up and then grab
D-B session and then go ahead and commit the changes and then we're just going to return d.j some version
of the pup as essentially a confirmation that hey we added it and then we're putting them in the j's
on OK then for deleting a puppy or we're going to do here.
Say pup is equal to essentially the same command so we therefore queery filter by then we're going to
filter by name as equal to name grab the first one that shows up grab or database session and then we'll
just call delete that pup and then commit that delete.
So say D-B session commit that delete and then we're just going to actually and overturn the same thing
it did before.
We'll just go ahead and return hey little success.
OK so last one for all names though.
We can do that is if you want.
You can authenticate this or not authenticate this.
Let's go ahead and just cancel out that authentications we won't worry about it for guess what we're
going to do here is we're going to say puppies is equal to puppy and then we can say queery all in order
to grab every single puppy.
So keep in mind this is going to be a list of puppy objects.
And as I mentioned we can actually return puppy objects when we return the Jason version of them.
So what we need to do here is I can use list comprehension to say pup Jason for pup in puppies because
this list of puppies is just a bunch of puppy objects.
So going to return them all is based on in this giant list and then return that for all the names.
OK.
So we could keep everything else the same.
And now we've connected this two models.
So really this should just serve as a reference for you when you want to add in rest.
API calls quickly using this resource method you can already have your existing projects that we've
already done throughout the course and then just add these special methods.
OK the final step though we have to do here is actually register our model using the migrations.
So if you call flask D-B in it as you've done before and enter you may actually get an error the pinning
on what you named your file.
So if you named your file something other than look at that pie it may say something like Hey I couldn't
locate that flask application.
You forgot to provide that flask app environment variable.
So we've seen this before we actually had a whole discussion on this and you can go back to the models
lecture's to see it.
All we need to do here is depending on your operating system you're either going to say export flask
app equal to and then the name of your application so simple API that pie.
So you can run that.
However export that's for a Mac OS or Linux computers.
If you're running a Windows like I am here going to say set flask at equal to and in this case you just
choose it over the python.
So now I've said it so that my environment variable tickly can also find Python with some OS calls.
But we've done that.
We definitely seen this before so check back the models lecture's.
If you don't remember this error there's a whole discussion about it in the notes.
But once you've done that then we can run flask VB in it enter and it looks like we forgot one thing
which was to import os.
So let's go ahead and add that in so say.
Import os.
Say that.
That would make sense because we have those OS calls plus the BE IN IT.
Ok that looks like it ran correctly will say Flast DBI migrates and then just have a little message
here.
The quotes will say first migration or first migrate they enter the migrations occur centrally adding
in that name column for the puppy and then to make these actually happen say Flast DBI upgrade hit enter
and now our database should exist.
And if you open up this Left-Hand tab you should now see somewhere here like a folder for migrations
and the data that sequel like nothing you definitely done this before many times throughout the course
and Altes actually run our simple API OK it looks like everything's running.
Let's go ahead and see if we can add puppies and puppies and read all the puppies and that will be the
end of this so let's open up postman.
So here I have postman open.
First thing I'm going to do is I'm actually going to try to post the puppy.
Right now nothing is authorized or nothing requires authorization as such thing.
So let's go ahead and add in Sammy to the database.
Keep in mind now that we're using a real database I can add in the puppies and then close off my Python
script and then run my Python script again and the puppies will still be in that database.
Unlike before where every time you restarted your python script that list was completely wiped out because
it was in memory.
Now we're actually dealing with something that's more secure and more permanent.
So we're going to add in puppies so let's send the request.
We got named Sammy so it looks good.
It's going an add in Franki as well so I'll say Franki send it.
We get back Franki So looks like that's working.
Let's go ahead and get the puppies.
So I'll say get all the puppies.
Let's see if this works.
Remember I commented out the authorization and it looks like that's working as well named Sammy named
Frankie.
That's working well let's try deleting a puppy.
So say delete or say puppy and let's go ahead and delete Sammy will send that.
Looks like the delete was successful so that method also worked.
Let's get all the puppies again and see if it was actually removed from that database.
So I'll send that.
Looks like we only get back Franki So that's working well.
OK so it looks like we were able to test out the commands for getting posting puppies grabbing all the
puppies and deleting puppies.
And if you want to update the puppies all you need to do is add in a method call called Put And then
just use the update methods that we've already gone through multiple times throughout the course.
Now something I want to mention is that the flask restful documentation actually has some really nice
examples for you to check out.
So if you come over to flask restful and expand this here you can check out the Quixtar but you can
also scroll down and then check out the zoom in here.
They have a bunch of examples that you can then extend flask restful intermediate users usage for Project
structures.
How you can use blueprints and so on.
There's lots of really good resources here and I would really recommend you just check out the QuickStart
guide and then go through out these different examples here because they're really useful as far as
learning how to deal things like formatting.
You know they have different full examples here that have an example here which is kind of a To Do list.
You can then build off of and you can play around with this so this one page has lots of examples and
the documentation is just pretty good in general.
OK so that's it for flask restful applications.
I hope you found that useful.
And hope is a good jumping off point.
In case you intend to use flask rest for any of your future projects we'll see at the next one.