Welcome back everyone to part two.
A flask loggin in this lecture.
We're going to set up our forms both a registration form to register new users as well as a logon form.
We'll also show you a couple of new things with forms such as checking to make sure that two fields
of a form match such as when you're providing a password and then you're prompted to confirm your password.
OK.
Let's get started.
Welcome back everyone.
Here we are we left off last time.
Previously we filled out our PI file as well as our models of Pi file and created the user model as
well as this load user function.
Now we're going to need to set up some forms for the user to log into the Web site and register it to
the Web site.
So we're going to come to forums up high and start creating some forums here in order to do this will
we'll start for basic imports for forms which is going to be flask underscored that be T.F. will import
flask form and then from W.T. forms are going to import the fields we're going to be using We'll be
using a string field a password field and they submit field then we're also going to be using validators.
So from W.T. forms validators I'm going to import data required e-mail and equal to.
So essentially these validators can be passed in two instances of string field password field or submit
field and they're actually a little bit self-explanatory based off their names that basically data required
means you can't leave that specific field in the form blank e-mail checks to make sure that you're actually
using an e-mail so it checks for something like an at symbol.
It ends and dot org or dot com that sort of thing and then equal to.
We're going to be using that for a password confirmation.
So often when you're registering you're going to want to make sure that you confirm the user's password
so that they don't accidentally mess it up.
OK so we have our lips.
One more important issue is those Aksel validation errors to from the witty forms import validation
here.
OK now I'm going to start off by creating our registration form.
Since that's the more complicated of the two will say class registration form and we're going to inherit
flask form and in order to register we're going to have a couple of fields.
A user is going to provide their e-mail.
So we'll say string field call it e-mail as it's label and get a pass and some validators.
So remember the validators it's going to be a list of instances of Daval dater.
So we're going to say data is required for the e-mail so they have to provide an e-mail.
And we'll also say e-mail validation which basically checks that it is an actual e-mail they'll say
user name.
This is also going to be a string field and we'll give it the label user name.
And for this we'll just have the validators be that it's required.
So even if it's just a single validator it still goes inside of a list data required.
Open and close print sees so it's an instance of data required then we're going to have the passwords.
So say that the password the user provides is going to go inside of a password field.
That way it's hidden from you as you begin typing it in and will say password as the label and the validators
we're going to have here are data required an instance of that and will also have equal to.
So we're going to actually leave equal to blank for now but we will come back to this in order to sync
it with another field called Pass confirm.
And it's kind of up to you what variable names you choose over here on the left hand side but technically
should come choose something that looks like this it matches your user model but this will also be a
password field.
And we're going to say the label on this one is confirmed password and the validators will be data required.
OK so essentially what I want to do here is I want to link this password field the first one to my past
confirm essentially checking that these two match which is where the equal to validator is going to
come into play.
So by itself equal to won't do anything.
We have to do a couple of things here.
We have to provide actual attributes of our form.
It needs to be equal to.
So we passed it as a string.
And we say pass underscore confirm basically matching this first string here that we're passing into
equal to to whatever field you want to make sure it's equal to.
So right here we have passed confirm.
So maybe you want to also confirm their e-mail.
It would be the same thing you would create a new field called email confirm and then you would just
match it up there.
So right now matching this equal to to pass confirm.
So this password field must be equal to the date you supplied here.
And as a second argument inside of equal to you can give a message to give in case the values are equal
to.
So I'm going to say passwords must match.
OK so if equal to is it actually meant I send them back a little message saying Hey The password is
much much must match a little bit of a tongue twister there.
OK.
So we have our e-mail username password and our confirmation for the password.
Finally our form should have a submit button with it.
So this will just be a submit field this is our registration form.
I'm going to go up and say register OK.
We have our fields ready to go.
Let's add in two methods.
One is going to be called the check email method.
So say self field and this is going to check if not none for that user e-mail.
So watch what I'm going to do here I'm going to say if user queery and then I will call filter by essentially
or or am calls that we discussed during or database lecture will say if user thought queries that filter
by email is equal to field the data
first.
So what is this actually doing.
Basically this function is going to check to see if that email has already been activated or registered
and if it has been ongoing say raise a validation error which is what we imported up here from W.T.
forms.
And then we can send back a message as a string here so we can see your e-mail has been already registered
registered.
OK.
So there's actually a lot going on in the back end for us due to the fact that this validation error
is just simply imported.
But the main idea here again is that this method check email is going to query our user model.
Essentially our user table and it's good to check hey where's that e-mail.
Matching the field of the data that was passed in.
So in this case going to be the e-mail data grab the first one since we only expect there to be one
e-mail and then say hey if that already exists.
So essentially if it's not none then raise a validation error.
If that email is not already in the table then this will be essentially false and we won't raise that
validation error and we're going to do the exact same thing for check.
Username so I'll say the F check the username self and the field that's passed then I'll say if user
queery filter by where user name is equal to that field data that's passed then off the first one then
raise the validation error and we can just say user name is taken.
OK.
So again just checking if the e-mail is valid and checking if the user name is valid and this field
does data.
Again that's just how we're grabbing the data off the form once it's submitted.
OK.
So we have a registration form now.
The user after their register should be able to log in.
So we're going to create a log in form here and will inherit again from a flask form.
And this is going to be quite similar.
Well just speak email is equal to a string field will give the label email and we'll have some validators
here.
Basically they'll have to provide an email so say that are required and it should be an email so I'll
say also e-mails validate or their Then we're going to create a password field instead of a log in form.
So this will be a password field label will be password and then we'll set the validators equal to just
data required.
An instance of data required.
And after that they'll just submit using a submit field and we'll have it say just log in.
OK.
So we set up our forms again.
All we're doing here is setting up a form for registering the user and logging in the user.
Notice here how we're using validators in order to make sure that they're providing data and also that
the data is in the right format.
We also showed you how you can have one field make sure to match another field by using equal to.
And then we set up these two methods to check the email and the username to make sure they're not already
in our tables and we'll be using those later on.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture.
Again this lecture is pretty much just on setting up the forms.
Coming up next is where we actually start setting up our views.
We'll see you there.