Welcome back everyone in this lecture room is to talk about how the flask website works but we're going
to do is go over in general Huff Lusk Web sites operate specifically the types of sites that are going
to be building in this course and what I want to show you is a connection to each major idea in a flask
web application to a section or topic in this horse.
So as we go along with the actual functions of a main flask web application I'm going to connect it
to certain libraries that will be discussing throughout the course.
The main idea here is as you go along through the course if you arrive at a section you already understand
the context of why you're learning about that particular topic to create a flask web application.
So let's get started.
Let's imagine you're going to visit a Web site and this Web site happens to be written in flask.
You're at your computer.
You open up your browser and then the first thing you're going to see is the front end of the Web site
rendered in the browser.
Now there's a few fundamental front end technologies.
And those are H.T. mail which is actually going to display the page elements.
So for example that could be something like the actual text on the Web site.
Then CSSA will style the elements.
So maybe change the fonts that text or color the text.
Then the site may also use Bootstrap which is going to provide automatic styling and components through
the use of C Ss and some javascript and Jake Query calls.
So again HTL that's actually the splaying those page elements CSSA for styling and then bootstrap to
provide some automatic styling.
And we have a crash course in these three main topics h TMLC SS and bootstrap for the kind of actual
web sites we're creating here.
We don't really need to dive in that deeply into javascript or Adjaye query.
Instead we're going to do that in conjunction with bootstrap So we're going to have crash courses in
these front end technologies.
So after that you're going to want to add some sort of level of interactivity.
Technically right now you're just going to have a static site.
If you only have the front end technologies now interactivity What do I mean by that.
Well every major Web site performs some sort of variation of these main operations.
Most web sites are going to be able to one except information from a user to retrieve information from
a database.
Three create update or delete information in that database and then for display information back to
the user that's relevant to them based off of step 1 what they requested or what information they provided.
Now in order to perform that sort of level of interactivity being able to connect a request from the
front end user to some sort of database we're going to need a web framework.
So the idea of a web framework just in general is to accept user information from the Web site use it
may be connected to a backend database and then report back something relevant that could be stored
in the database back to the front and the user can see it.
So flask is a framework of choice and that's going to allow us to use and connect Python code to the
web and flask is a great choice for a web framework because it's super simple to use if you have a very
simple web site.
It just takes a few lines of code to get your website up and running a flask and then because of this
simplicity flat's sometimes has a reputation for being too simple or not scalable but it's actually
not true.
There's tons of third party libraries for flasks that allow you to easily add some way more advanced
functionality flask and be able to scale flask.
So often people ask when should I use flask or when should I use Shingo.
And really at a certain point it's going to be up to a personal choice because there's more than enough
third party libraries that are open source that can make flask do everything that Django can.
So just keep that in mind and we'll talk about the differences between flask and jingo later on in more
detail but we have flasks as our choice for web frameworks because it's so simple to use and it's really
awesome for beginners so we'll be using flask in Python to connect HTL templates and then retrieve it
or return information.
So let's talk about that first step that most major Web sites do and that's accepting user information.
This can be as simple as just collecting a form of information for a survey or accepting something like
an email or password combination.
Or maybe your query into google search.
Those are all the instance of a user filling out an information inside of a form and then the Web site
retrieves that information.
So in our case in order to create these forms we're going to use a library called W.T. forms.
That works really well with flask in the crash course.
We first learn about HMO forms and then later on the course will know how to actually create those automatically
with flasks.
So we're going to learn two ways of doing these forms.
The next step is actually communicate a database and retreat information.
So in our case we're going to be using sequel like as our database of choice.
It's a very popular database already comes of Python meaning there's no additional installs.
You don't have to have any headaches over getting a database ready and working.
And again despite its name and reputation sequel I can actually scale to quite a large web site and
if you're in this course dangerously about flask and Python then it's highly probable that it's going
to serve all your needs.
So it should work fine for us.
And in addition to this we're going to learn about libraries such as sequel alchemy which allows us
to write Python code instead of the Rex sequel statements.
And we'll also learn about flask migrate which allows us to automatically update any changes to our
database.
Again all through python now a big part of working the database is called crud and that stands for create
read update and delete.
So if any database we're going to want the ability to create a new row read a row that already exists
up the row that already exists or delete a row or information entirely from our database if necessary.
And already here we can get this idea that flask is serving as sort of a middleman between the front
and then what the user sees and the back end and the information that's stored.
So once we actually connect these two in some sort of capacity we're probably going to want to return
or display information back to the user.
So in order to do that we're going to use something called Jinja templates which actually grab information
from Python and flask and send that information back as HVM L.
So that's the actual method.
Syntax wise there we're going to be using as the glue between flasks and the front and so this is a
super high level overview.
There's lots more possibilities that we're going to talk about in this course that we haven't discussed
here.
Things like accepting payments rest a pis user authentication and log in and so much more.
But this is the level I want you to be aware of.
That way when you start learning about these different sections such as the forms or template sections
or database sections of flask you already understand the context that we're talking about as far as
how flask Web sites work.
OK so a very quick overview.
The front end that's rendered in the browser that's going to H.M.S. SS and bootstrap.
Those are the three main crash courses for the front end that we cover.
There's also things like javascript and Jey query and there's lot of other javascript libraries that
also work in the front and before our use cases.
We're not going to need any of that.
We're still going to be able to create lots of really awesome web sites without those more advanced
javascript functionality and a lot of the functionality that we need is already integrated into bootstrap
for and then Python is going to be the coding language that allows us to use the flask with Framework
flask.
It's going to render HTL templates then we can edit them with Jinja and communicate a database through
the use of libraries such as sequel alchemy and in particular we're going to be using flask sequel alchemy
which is specialized for flashbulb framework.
Now don't worry about memorizing all these terms.
This is just a high level overview to put the course topics in context and we're going to be building
up very slowly starting from the front end and working on all the way back and then creating larger
applications such as a social network project.
Then once we understand how to connect the front and the back end fully with flask will slowly introduce
other topics such as user registration authentication API payment systems and more.
So don't worry again about memorizing all of this.
This is just a general high level overview.
If you have any questions feel free to post and to the Q&amp;A forums and we can answer them.
But keep in mind a lot of questions are probably going to be answered as you go through the course.
So maybe just jot them down or keep them in the back of your mind because as we learn and dive into
a lot more detail about each of these topics we're going to clarify things a lot more.
But first before all of this we've got to get a handle on the basics so in case you need them let's
get started with a crash course on the front end technologies like HTL see SS and bootstrap.
I'm super excited to finally start typing and getting the code.
Let's get started.