Welcome back.
Let's go over some solutions for the bootstrap project.
All right.
Here I have my age HTML file.
I'm going to work on the main page first and then come back and fill out the sign up page.
So step one was to insert the bootstrap for links.
Lots different ways you can get this one quick easy way is just to go to the documentation page.
Copy and paste them in.
Actually already had them in the Sign-Up page.
So it's going to copy and paste them from here.
So I will copy this and then paste that into the head.
There we go.
Save that change.
Step two was to add a dark nav bar here linked link to a separate sign up page.
So in order to do this let's grab the documentation page.
So I'm going to put it up here and then we'll go to the documentation.
Check out the components.
Scroll down to a nav bar and then basically keep looking until you see the actual color schemes.
Or you can check out over here on the right.
There's color schemes.
So click down and you'll see right here.
The one we want to use is nav bar.
Now Barbash dark B.G. dark.
So we're going to copy that.
And then let's bring the documentation aside and let's put that class in right here.
So say class is equal to nav bar nav bar that Starc B.G. dark.
OK.
And then if you keep looking at the actual NAV or documentation you should then see that you can end
up adding a div here with something like nav bar header and then add an anchor tag.
Technically that nav bar header that can be optional depending on what you actually want the links to
look like.
But let's add a brand the page so we can say class is equal to nav bar dash brand.
And let's have this be the welcome
and that outside of this div what we can do.
Still in the nav bar is I can make an unordered list and here I'll have a list item with an anchor tag.
Let's make sure that anchor tag actually gets in there with an anchor tag and inside this anchor tag
will say sign in let's save that and then check to make sure it's working in our actual page.
So if I bring in my actual page I get to see this nav bar as well as the links that I haven't actually
done anything with yet.
So I see.
Welcome and then seinen.
So what I want to do is actually link these pages are these Walkmen sign and links to the other pages.
So let's do that as well.
So when I come here right now we have class have our brand a.
So for the ATRA for the welcome page let's just have it come back to the current file I'm in.
So right now I'm in Bootstrap solution may let each team know.
So we'll have that link and then for this Tref what I'm going to do is have it be bootstrap solution
underscore Sign-Up.
H Tim L.
And remember you're going to call this whatever you happen to call your age l files for the sign up
page.
OK.
So let's save that.
And that finishes off our navigation bar.
So again what we did here is we have this brand and then we have this list item inside us an ordered
list.
All of this goes inside this nav bar.
OK so lots of different ways you could have also done that navigation bar.
That was probably the simplest way.
Step three is to create a Jumbotron here for a header and some lorem ipsum.
So that's actually pretty straightforward.
We just take a div created class out of it and it's optional if you want to put it in a container or
not.
I like putting things in containers.
But more importantly we really wanted to do is make sure we have a Jumbotron inside that class container
basically has it centered.
If you don't have the container it will just spread out to the entirety of the page.
Either is totally fine.
Then let's add in a heading one here will say cool puppy looks and we'll add in some form some in two
paragraphs.
So just Lorem up some.
And then we'll create another pair of tagged and we'll put in some more lordships on there.
So those changes and let's check it out.
By refreshing our page and bringing it over.
So if I refresh my page and look at it I get to see cool puppy looks larm Epson Laura ipsum.
And then this walk up and sign in.
So we're going to bring that back out here and actually let's check the sign and see if that link is
working.
If I click sign in it's taken me to a blank file.
That makes sense because there's nothing on that sign up page yet.
We'll go back and now we need to do is add in that carousel.
So how do we actually do that.
Well we need to do is check out the bootstrap documentation.
So welcome back to the bootstrap docs which actually have open right here and in the bootstrap box will
come the documentation and I can search for carrousel eventually they'll find their way here.
Carrousel it says how it works you can read through these examples.
I can see the slides only I can see the slides with controls and then with indicators as well.
Lots of different options here with captions.
It's really up to you what you wanted to do it fade away.
We're going to go ahead and maybe choose the simpler one just with controls.
So we just copy this code
and then we're going to bring that over to our project and then we're going to paste that in.
So now let's take a look at what's actually happening here.
I have these divs.
So the outermost div says Id carrousel example controls class carrousel slide data right.
The other div than another div than an image.
And then the source.
So notice here here's the image.
And here's the source.
So this is what I want to replace of my own images.
So it's nice that we added some spacing here so we can clearly see what's happening here.
Essentially each slide in the Carousel.
It's this div with an image tag in it pointing to the source of the image.
So what we need to do is replace these with our own source images.
So we're going to exit or cut this out and then paste it in here.
There we go and we're going to do that for these other images as well.
So we'll cut that paste it from the source here
and we have a couple more so we'll cut this paste that as well.
And you notice here these divs are actually a little different.
Here's an anchor tag and here's another eight or 10 but these are outside of this div.
And that's because these are the actual controls.
This is the previous.
And here's the next.
So we want to actually keep those.
So we're going to do is copy and paste these a few more times so many images we have left we have three
images left.
Let's put them in one two and three and we're going to copy these.
So we'll cut this out.
Grab that source image paste it in let's do it for two more get this guy out.
Grab this guy paste it in.
And last one Arap source cut it out highlight it paste it in.
Let's save that and make sure that all works by going back to the Web site and the browser.
I'll bring in my browser refresh and I see this puppy at the bottom and I can cycle now perfectly great.
So now the last step is to actually implement a form when I click seinen.
Right now it's blank.
So let's fix that.
Coming back to the other sign up page it says copy and paste.
Now apart from the other page here as well.
So let's do that.
I was going to grab the entirety of that Nev..
So grab all of this now of copy this paste it in.
That change.
Let's see that that change was affected coming back here.
If I click sign in now I see the same nav bar.
Now we just need to add in the form.
So it's up to you how much you want to go into this but what we can do is back of that documentation
come down check out the forms click on that and this one looks good.
Email address and password.
So I'll just copy that form come back to the sign and Page HTL and put that right here save those changes.
Refresh my project and there I see this.
OK.
So let's put this whole form inside of a Jumbotron of class.
So I'll say this.
Now we can also put it inside of container say container the Jumbotron.
Let's grab this entire form
cut it and then stick it here.
Save that if I refresh this page.
Now it looks a lot nicer.
OK.
That was the basics of the bootstrap.
Main thing to understand is you can always leverage the documentation and then edit it to fix your own
examples.
So I would click welcome we come back to the home page and I could see this nice carousel of these funny
puppy pictures.
OK.
That's it for the project.
And that's it for the crash courses.
Coming up next we'll start learning about Python.
We'll see you there.