Welcome back.
In this last part of our CSSA crash course we're going to quickly discuss Funk's we can apply custom
fonts to our Web sites through the use of font properties in the CSA.
Let's quickly explore how we can use the Google font API to add custom fonts as well as we can explore
various font properties such as font sizes and font families.
We'll get started by jumping over to the text editor and later we'll head over to the browser.
OK here we have a basic thought HCM elf file.
I also have a master that see SS that it's linked to with no actual links right now.
Any tags or any styles that are basic H-2A smell.
Let's add a few element components.
We'll have a Heading 1 and we'll just have the same header one.
And then let's quickly add two paragraphs so I'll say a paragraph.
And if you begin typing Lorem you should see larm some pop up enter and then will autocomplete that
generic Lorem of some text which is just filler Latin text and create another paragraph except this
one will give it a specific ID of two.
That way we can make sure to differentiate it from the first paragraph tag and then we'll say warm gypsum
enter and save.
So basically we just have three components here a heading and then two paragraphs one of them with a
specialized ID.
Let's refresh our page and I get to see no header Lorem Ipsum and then ipsum.
Now let's mess around with the actual C Ss.
So let's imagine that we want to actually change the font being used.
Keep in mind that is available on every OS so only certain fonts are available on Windows and certain
fonts are available on Macs and you can check out the CSSA file for this particular lecture for wikipedia
links on the list of typefaces that are included of Microsoft Windows and Elyssa type places that are
included with Mac OS so let's say I want to change the actual font of the header.
I can say H-1 and then I'll say Fonte dash family and I can change it to be cursive.
So I'll see cursive there save.
And then when I refresh notice now it's technically in cursive.
Now this may not look like cursive but it's the way the browser is going to represent this particular
style of cursive.
We can also do other font families like monospace save that hit refresh and then I see a monospace font
for that heading and the previously mentioned inside the CSSA file we have commented links as far as
the list of typefaces that are included that differ operating systems.
So if you go to one of those links for example the one for Microsoft and zoom out here a bit so we can
see it.
I can see the list of typefaces included Microsoft Windows.
So since I'm running on Windows I could technically choose any of these for my actual styling.
So for instance let's choose this font right here.
Colibri.
So I'll say font family and paste it in.
Save it and then for the basic one for refresh.
Now I have that specific font.
I can continue it down maybe use something like console this grab that.
Copy paste save it refresh and not showing that font type.
OK there's other things we can't continue to edit.
Let's do this on our paragraph Ted so we can edit the font size so I can say font size and then specify
the font size in pixels.
So if all my paragraphs appear larger I can say show them as 20 pixels.
I'll come over here and refresh and now I can see that my paragraphs are now larger.
Keep in mind I'm zoomed in here.
We can also do things like affect the font style or font white so I can say font weights and make this
bold or normal.
Some of these won't be actually effective on certain families.
Just keep that in mind.
Not every font family can be made bold or italics but most normal ones can.
So if I refresh Now I could see everything in bold and maybe we can also say font style will say font
style then it can have it be a taluk or normalized.
So say it taluk refresh.
And now I see everything that's paragraph in bold metallics and there there's also text properties.
That's the last one I want to mention.
So you can align the text give it shadow transform it so a text line is probably the most commonly used
one and it just whether you want to align it left right justified or center.
So let's go ahead and do Center here.
And if I refresh this now I see everything center along my browser center here.
OK so those are various font parameters or attributes that you'll be playing around with in your C Ss.
The last thing I want to explore is actually grabbing a font from online and then implementing it into
your web site.
And the best site for this is the Google font API and the best way to find this is if you go to your
browser and expand the right here.
And if you google search Google fonts you should be able to find here.
The Fahnestock Google dot com.
Go ahead and select the and then you'll be able to see a list of all the Google fonts so we can see
here.
Sunflower open sands.
And you can actually search so there's a search capability and you can sort it by trending.
Most popular alphabetical search ones that look more like handwriting.
See different categories.
You can choose so let's choose a very unique one.
The specifica looks pretty unique so once you actually want it you can actually edit by typing in here.
So let's say we like the specific font.
We want to include it in our Web site.
I could just click here on the plus button select this font and you should see a little one family select
that pop up over here on the bottom.
Expand that and this will inform you on how to actually add this into your website to notice.
Do you have this link.
And that's basically a style sheet reference to this particular font.
So there's two steps of this one is adding this link to the HVM L and the second one is specifying the
font family insider SS So let's grab this link.
We're going to copy this.
We're going to come back here to basic thought Tim L and in addition to our master that see SS.
I'm going to add in that link to the stylesheet.
So let me zoom out so you can see this here.
I'm just copying and pasting that same link that Google fonts provided.
So link a reference to the Google fonts API and then we see the family relations style sheet.
Save that change come back to your C Ss over here and the for the font family.
You're going to again copy and paste the command was given to you by Google fonts.
So here we can specify font family Pacific go cursive.
Copy this.
And now let's apply it to the heading 1.
So we'll save that and in fact let's apply it.
Everything on the page.
So I'll say it for the paragraph as well.
We'll come back to our basic h him l that's linked here and I'm going to refresh.
And now I see everything in that Google fonts API font family style.
Pretty easy right.
So now you have full access to all the Google fonts simply by adding a link to your HVM L and then by
adding in the font family call inside your CSSA file again.
Let's quickly go over those steps.
All you need can do is come to Fahnestock Google dot com.
Select the fonts you like and you can select multiples just add with the plus signs.
Expand this window you'll get a list for what link you should provide in your stylesheet and then how
to specify these font families inside your C S S call.
They just add that link to your mail and then specify that C Ss is the font family.
OK that's it for this lecture.
Hope you enjoyed it.
Coming up next we'll have a quick crash course assessment to make sure you understood all these new
skills and see assess will see.