Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss HTL attributes some element tax attributes that
you can directly manipulate such as adding a link or adding a source image.
Well we're going to do is actually use the smell of the two main common examples and that is how you
can actually show an image on your Web site and how you can link to either another page or another outside
Web site inside your HTL.
Let's get started.
All right here you have my text editor and this text editors open right now it's a basic the h t m l
and in my browser I also have basic body it's T.M. file path linked to I'm going to create one more
each time I'll file.
So there's different ways you can do this.
One easy way to do it is just duplicating my existing HDMI file and calling it something different.
So I literally just call it different thought each time.
And now I have to edit html files basically HTML and different age HTML.
Let's start with the basic h T.M. so I'll type out HVM L and then inside the body I'll have a heading
1 and then I will say basic h tim L. This is just so I remember what actual file I'm looking at.
I've connected it already to my browser.
So if I refresh I.S. basic page T.M. and notice these are both located in the same folder and I defer
to him all right now it's blank.
So we'll keep it that way back to the basic H.T. mail.
But we're going to do is show you how you can actually link to an image inside of our age T.M. images
there are specific tab is known as a self-closing tag.
You'll see here that a lot of these other tags have both in opening tags such as H-1 here and then a
closing tag.
Again H-1 has a forward slash.
You noticed the same for this head tag as well as the body tag.
However this HTL tag actually closes by itself as well as this medtech an image tag works the same way
as you begin to type I am g which is an image tag and enter.
You'll notice that it's actually self-closing meaning there's no corresponding closing image tag.
Instead we just need to provide the source of the image.
You can actually provide the source of the image either locally or online.
So you should do is inside your browser go to a Web site called and splash dot com.
So actually have it open here again it's just an splash dot com.
These are beautiful free photos and they're all gifted so you don't have to worry about any copyright
issues.
Let's look up a picture of a puppy.
So I'll just say search for a puppy and find one that you like.
So this guy looks pretty cute.
Let's get him and then I'm going to just right click this and I'm going to copy the image address once
that copy the image address.
I'm going to put it here as the source.
So as our C stands for source so this basically is telling the image tag what the source of the file
is for the image.
So if we zoom out a little more so you can see the big file path here.
You'll notice here I have an image tag.
And in this case it's a super long source because it's a really long link for the splash image but there
it is.
OK.
So again just copy and paste that address that the image is hosted at.
When we come back the basic HMO let me save the image change refreshed my basic each team on site and
if I collapse this you'll notice now I have this picture of the dog.
You'll notice that it's actually huge.
It's a high quality image so it's a really big picture.
Later on we discuss CSI.
We'll tell you how you can resize this.
But right now you know how to link a basic image using images.
OK.
So let's actually then show you how you can link to a local image.
So to do that I'm going to download this image so they save images and they'll save it to that same
folder where I have the flask examples and say save it as puppie underscore pick.
So I'll save that as a JPEG file.
And if you take a look now with basic H.T. mail and different bodies to mail I now have that Papy underscore
pick a pig and it doesn't have to be a picture from this Web site.
It can be any jpeg or PAGG file.
The idea is sort of now linking to something online.
I'm going to show you how you can link to something locally.
So this the image we had earlier.
And then let's zoom in a little bit.
So here we have basic HMO type image again from an image tatic AMG enter and now wants the source since
my JPEG file is in the same location as the HD Metafile.
All I need to do is provide the name of that file which I've named puppy underscore pick that jpeg will
save that.
And then when I come back to basic each T.M. when I refresh notice nothing changes because now this
image right here it's not actually from an splashback com.
It's instead just being shown locally and pretty much will always be showing our own images hosted on
our own servers.
But you can actually link both locally and on the Internet.
So keep that in mind.
You probably also noticed this a LTE parameter or Allt that basically stands for alternative which intends
to show something else in case you can't find the actual peg.
So for instance Let's type in the source as missing that jpeg.
Now I don't have a file called missing that jpeg.
So I should see some sort of broken link so I will save that change.
Refresh my browser and notice right now it's broken.
There's actually no image to show.
So what I can do is have an alternate either an alternate image link or even just a string.
I can say oh image no image or image not found.
So I'm going to collapse my bar here my left hand side panel.
So I'm saying image source is missing touch pad again I don't actually have the file called Missing
a peg.
So I have an alternate and it'll say oh no image.
So when I save this and refresh I see oh no image.
And that little broken image.
OK.
So that's the main idea behind Image that.
Essentially there's two main components.
The source which is either a local file that you're hosting or a link to an image online.
Keep in mind I was able to do something like puppy underscore pic because I have this file in the same
folder as basic but aged him l if I have this Pyg file somewhere else on my server on my computer I
may need to actually provide the whole file path which maybe something like on Windows see user Jose
probably pic or something similar to that later on when we actually learn about Flast we won't be hard
coding these paths ourselves.
OK so we have images down.
The last thing we want to show you is how you can actually create hyperlinks inside of her age HTML
file.
So I'll delete this image tag and I'm going to not use a tag or an anchor tag which allows me to see
a link to another Web site.
So right now we have a ref and just a hash tag.
And notice this anchor tag is not a self-closing tag so has an opening tag and a closing tag.
And what happens is you can type in something to the anchor tag.
So my link here saved this and then I refresh the page here I see miling here.
The hyperlink created when I click on it nothing is actually going to happen because it doesn't know
where to link to which is what this HFS for.
So I have two options.
I can either link it to another HVM all file I'm hosting locally or I can even link it to another Web
site for example I can type out HTP colon for Slash forward slash W.W. dot and then just the Web site
name for instance Google or Facebook dot com or NPR dot org et cetera.
So let's say that for NPR the OR and I'll say go to NPR
and then if I refreshed this I get to see this link.
Basic HTL go to NPR and when I click on go to NPR it will actually take me now to whatever link I said
which was the NPR Web site npr.org and now it can link to other web sites on the Internet.
Let me go back here often we won't be linking to other Web sites.
Instead we'll be linking to other web pages on our own server so notice that I have this different age
l.
Let's go ahead and link two different rates T.M..
First off let's type out HVM L and have it fill in that skeleton code for us.
And in the body of different thought T.M. I'll have heading one and Ill just say that I can remember
what actual Web site I'm looking at.
So I have my basic Steimle which has go to NPR.
So we'll come back here and instead of saying go to NPR for my reference I'm actually going up put in
that file path which is different h T.M..
Again keep in mind if different that is smell's located on a different part of my computer look at different
folder I'd have to provide the whole file path.
But since it's in the same folder as basically the HTML I just didn't provide its name so let's save
that change refresh here and it still says go to NPR.
So let's change that as well.
Let's say go to different save that refresh.
All right now it says go to different.
And when I click on it it's different.
So it was able to take me to that other team out page.
All right.
That's really the basics of using image tags and anchor tags.
Again image tags can either have a source that's a local image or linked to an image online an anchor
text and a very similar manner can either link to another Web site online by providing the HTP file
path for it.
Or you can provide a local ASML file and link to your own web sites or web pages or own templates.
OK that's it for the basics.
H simple attributes the main idea behind attributes is that again inside of these tags we have attributes
we could define such as the SIRC source or a Tref.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.