Welcome back.
Let's finish off this section for a quick assessment of your new skills.
So in order to master new skills we have an assessment exercise.
You'll notice that there's three files inside that CSSA folder.
Two of them are the C Ss assessment that h t m l and the CSSA assessment thought see SS go ahead and
open those and your text editor.
There's a corresponding solution file that we're gonna go over in the next lecture.
So don't open that yet unless you actually want to view the solutions.
Let's jump to the text editor and see what the assessment looks like.
All right.
Here we have the assessment.
Al file opened.
So this year assess assessment and you'll notice that it's actually linked right now to the solutions
so you should link it to your own assessment.
That way you can actually edit the CSSA file.
So basically what we have here is an H-2A HTML file for a bunch of different objects and elements and
it has a Heading 1 Welcome to the puppy blog division right here called with a connection to some class
that we have a heading to a paragraph an ordered list.
Notice there's a link to Google dot com here and then we have another heading.
Please log in.
And then a form that can take in some inputs and at the end we have another division class called Exit
another paragraph and then a text area and that's it in the body.
Well your job is to come over to the CSSA file for the assessment see assess and you have a variety
of tasks.
For example the first task is to give the entire body element of the site a light gray background using
a hex code.
So what are you going to do for each of these tasks is basically come in grab the element that it's
referring to and then adjust the property it's referring to.
So in this case it would be your background their background color and then you would find the hex code
to make it gray.
So all you need to do is go along through each of these tasks and edit the actual properties.
H team L and keep it open in your browser so you can adjust and check to see if the changes are occurring
as you would expect.
What I would recommend doing as well is right clicking on one of these and then saying split right or
split left and then if you close the sky you can have both of them open at same time.
And if you zoom out you're able to directly compare tasks here in the CSSA to the actual elements in
the HTML file.
All right I hope that's useful to you if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But again the main idea here is to just follow the tasks in the CSSA file and complete the assignment
in the very next lecture.
We'll go over an example solution for completing these tasks.
We'll see other.