Welcome back in this lecture we're going to connect our databases to views.
We finally learned enough to make a real web site with the key features of being able to display templates
except user information reform's save supplied information in a database and then report back that saved
the information from that database.
We'll be creating an adoption site with some templates and we're going to have the ability to add new
puppies list puppies and puppies from the database all by directly interacting of forms from templates.
So let's get started.
This is a big lecture for us.
We're essentially connecting everything we've talked about already into one single web site project.
So let's head over toward sex ed..
All right.
Here we are at the text editor.
I'm going to start completely from scratch so you can get a feel for how it would be to start a Web
site from the very beginning.
The first thing I want to do is create two up-I scripts so don't underneath this folder flask examples.
I'm going to say create a new file.
The first one I'll just call it adoption underscore site dot pi.
So again this adoption slimly mix has a comment adoption underscore site that pie.
So I have that one pie script and since we're going to be creating forms I'm actually going to have
those be in a separate file so I'll create a forms that py file and this will contain my forms.
So this forms that file that's where I'm going to have my form classes instead of having everything
in one large dot PI script.
Then we're going to create a Templates folder say new folder templates and then inside of this we're
going to have several templates.
The first one that we pretty much always have is a base template so a new file based on HTL.
And then once we have that we're going to create a couple of new files.
Let's create one for our home page so we can call this either home that each female or index or a smell
whatever you prefer.
And then we're going to have views to add puppies list the puppies and delete the puppies.
So let's go ahead and add a template view for each of those we'll say add the H T.M. and that's going
to have a form to add puppies.
Then we'll create a new file here will say delete each T.M. that's going to last to remove puppies from
our database.
Finally we'll create a list that each Tamil which allows us to list puppies from our database.
And these are the fundamental views you're going to have in any major Web site the ability to add information
remove information or list information that you've already saved.
So we have our template set up.
Let's get started by setting up our adoption site up pie and then we'll start connecting it to our templates.
Again there's no real right or wrong way as far as creating your templates first and then creating your
thought script to connecting it through review functions or doing it the way we're going to do now.
Setting up your python script first and then setting up the html files or doing a mix of match both.
So I'm right now in adoption site that pie.
Let's get started.
The first thing I want to do is start with my imports at the very top.
Import os.
And then I'm going to at some point in time say from forms import and I'll create an add form and they
delete form.
So on keeping this commented out for now because if I take a look landforms up my file that's actually
totally empty.
So I'm going to later on add a form and add a delete form and I'll say from flask import flask and we're
also going to be rendering templates will be using your L4 and then we'll also say redirect then will
say from flask underscore sequel alchemy import sequel alchemy and then from flask underscore migrates.
We're going to import migrate then we'll create our application.
So I'll say flask name and then we're going to set up a key for forms soci app config and then we'll
say create the secret key and you can set that equal to any string you want.
So I'll say my secret key again this is just from the forms section of the course where we set up a
secret key.
So now we're going to do the sequel database and models part delicious combat this sequel database section.
And as I mentioned often for larger projects you have this in a model's not pi script but we're going
to talk about that in a future lecture Frinton else.
Keep everything in one pie script.
We'll set up our base there victory base directory set to OS path absolute path and then just as before
we say OS path groud the current directory name and say underscore underscore file underscore underscore
ok don't say app config.
And then we'll say sequel alchemy underscore database underscore you are.
I and I'm going to set that equal to sequel like colon three forward slashes plus OS that path.
Join in I'm going to join my base directory with data dot sequel like OK.
And just to get a little more room here going to collapse this left hand panel.
There we go.
So we have our base directory.
There's one more configuration we do.
And that's the track changes one so we'll say sequel alchemy underscore track modifications and I'm
going to set that equal to false then we'll say create our database by passing in our application into
sequel alchemy and then we're going to migrate the whole thing or basically give the ability to migrate
connecting our application with our database.
OK.
So the next step after this is to actually create the models.
So we just have one model in our particular site.
It's going to be the model for a puppy.
Let's go ahead and create that now.
And it's up to you how much comments you want to put in here.
But we'll say models and often this will be in a separate file called models not pie.
But since we're just dealing with simplicity we'll just say class puppy D-B model moins create a table
name for this we'll do it as last time we'll just say it's puppies.
So make sure we set up puppies let's give each puppy a primary key id say D-B call them D-B integer
integer
and then for that we'll say primary key is equal to true and puppies.
One other Actually you can give them as a name so say D-B column and we'll say D-B text.
Ok so when you give in that method and arts create a puppy so IDF underscore underscore in that underscore
underscore self and then name and they will say self taught name is equal to name and let's finally
give a representation of the subject we'll say self and using string formatting we'll say return puppy
name self-taught name string formatting.
OK so that's our puppy's model.
Up next we need to do is create the actual views and then connect them with the forms.
But right now I think we've done enough for just one video.
We'll continue this off in a part do.
Bill let's do a quick review of what we've done so far in this video.
We set up our template files and we set up our two pi scripts one of them is going to hold forms which
will fill out at a later lecture in our adoption site that pile what we've done so far is we've done
our imports.
We're still waiting on one for our form and delete form creator application.
Did the configuration so that we can successfully use forms that are templates.
Set up our SQL database configuration set up our DVR checked as well as set up migrations and then we
created this puppy model which later on we'll see how we can connect to it add puppies and then delete
and remove puppies as well.
All right we're going to continue this in part 2 right where we left off.
We'll see you at the next lecture.