Welcome back everyone to part 4 of the flask log in series of lectures in part for what we're going
to do is just finish off by completing those actual templates.
Let's get started.
OK so in the last lecture we finished off this large app that PI file.
Now it's time to complete the HVM files.
We'll start by fixing our base.
HVM l file.
So as a quick note I fixed a little mistake here from our previous lectures.
I forgot to import this as an anchor tag that I stuck the ref inside of the list class.
So go ahead and go back and check on that or just copy and paste from our notes.
So I set up an anchor tab.
I have my nav bar and right now it's sending it home.
So we have this class and this should be nav and we have this nav link.
Now I'm going to do is I'm going to have an if statement here that says if the current user thought
is authenticated
that I'm going to show the link for logging out.
So I create a list item and I'll give it the class.
Now underscore link and then I'll create an anchor tag here and Atra for that is going to be the URL
for log out.
And that's actually why we didn't need a separate HTML file for logging out.
Basically once they click log out it just executes that log out view and then it's redirects them to
another page.
So if we come back to Apple Pie.
Notice how our log out view actually just logs out the user and then redirects them home.
There's no actual HFM file associated with that.
So there's no log out the T.M..
OK.
Coming back to base that is Tamil.
The other thing to notice is the way we're able to grab this item current underscore user is from using
the flask logging library.
So remember we are creating our models were able to have this load user functionality Flast log in is
essentially handling everything on the back end for us.
In order for us to just in the template say grab the current user and check their authenticated.
So if that's the case if they're authenticated I'm going to given the option to log out else or we're
going to do is given the option to either log in or register.
So I have a list item here again Olby class nav link and it's going to be an anchor at and it's going
to have a URL for.
And before we fill that one out what I'm going to do here is just copy and paste this Cargan have one
for log in and one for register.
So we'll do the log in one first.
I'll say log in and inside of the tag I'll just have it say log in and then here will have it say register
to match our registration view and then in here we'll just have it say register.
OK.
So now our NAV bar is complete and it will actually change depending if the user is logged in or not.
So if the users log in they see the log out button on the net for if they're not logged in then they
see log in or register.
OK.
Now let's check back on the home page so our home team L right now show us the Jumbotron.
So let's go ahead and do the same sort of check.
We'll say if current user thought is authenticated then we'll do is we'll just walk up that will say
paragraph and we're actually going to grab the current user and grab their user name.
So again the way I'm able to just call this current user is from the fact that we set up this load user
in the models that PI file.
So that comes automatically when are using Flast logon.
If you're not using the flash logging library you wouldn't be able to just call it like that.
OK then we're going to say.
Else.
And if they're not we'll just say Please log in or register.
So again if you go to the home page and your log then you'll see something like.
And I will say hi.
Your user name else will see a sign that says Please log in and register.
So now our home page is done and we're going to do now is set up our log in T.M..
It's going to look really similar.
We're going to extend from base HVM El and then we'll set up a content block and then after that we'll
just set up our form.
So I'll create our form and we don't need a class or action we'll just keep the method as post and then
everything else will just fill in with our form tag calls soci form create the hidden tag for this SRF
security feature just to make sure that the forms are legitimate and they will say form grab the email
label and then say form.
Email and then also accept the password.
So remember this is the log in view so see if form password label and then form that password
and then finally will submit the form form submit.
OK so this is the log in form on the logon page.
Just a hidden tag it for security.
And then it's enter your email enter your password submit then we'll go ahead and fill out our register
page.
So register we're going to extends from base T.M. to get that nav bar there will say block content's
and we'll go ahead and start a form here.
This form going to be really similar to our blog page except it's the registration form.
So we're going to have a couple of more things here.
I'll say form he didn't tag just like we did last time and then we'll set up for email able and then
the form email will also grab their username so form user name label and say form user name and order
for this to all look good and to add some breaks in here.
So let me add a couple of breaks though.
This all doesn't just appear on one line especially when you zoom in like I do.
And they'll say for password label and they'll say form password I'll go ahead and insert another break
there.
And then let's also add in remember they're registering to confirm their password.
So we say a foreign password or actually we call it pass underscore confirm the label for that one and
then form past confirm one more break and then we'll have the submit button.
So form submit.
OK so those are just all the fields from the registration form.
OK.
We just filled in a lot less.
Hopefully we didn't make any mistakes.
I'm sure we may have made a typo somewhere so let's go ahead and try this all out.
I'm going to start by saying flask D-B in it to actually create that user model.
So we'll run this make sure we get no errors.
Ok looks like I may have gone in there.
Let's see.
Module is not callable.
So looks like all my apps config.
I have a small typo here.
Let's go back and check it out.
So let's come back.
It looks like it's on line 14 him-I in it that PI file.
So I'll come over here come in at that pi.
Check this out.
So I have online 14 app config sequel alchemy database sequel.
Oh estopped path.
And that should have been oh stop have thought join.
So my apologies for that typo.
But you're bound to make many typos for such a larger structure project.
Let's try this again.
Let's make sure we save those changes.
Run fast and it's and looks like it all worked out.
So now I'll try this flask.
D-B migrate and will give the message of greeting users run that.
OK looks like that will work though.
Finally I'll say flask.
DBI upgrade and looks like everything is running so let's run our application and check that it works.
So going to bring in my browser and see if I can create a new user so register as a new user and that
log in.
So bringing in my browser and already kind of zoomed in here so it says Please log in or register looks
like that's working if a hit the home page brings me back to the home page.
Click logon.
I see the log in form.
It's kind of ugly right now but you get the idea.
Never click register.
I see this registration form all right so let's try registering.
I'm just going to say.
Example.
Email.
So example.
Example dot com username.
This will also be example password.
I'll just make a really bad example of password as well.
And will make example confirm password or register and it looks like I didn't get redirected upon registering.
So let me make sure that my password actually matched.
So I'll say password password register.
There we go.
So I had some error there my password wasn't matching that was just a simple typo on my part and now
is try logging in since we were successfully rerouted to the log in page.
So again.
Example at exampled dot com is the email I'm using and I just typed in password as my password log in
and I'm getting this error.
Name error.
None is not defined.
So let's try to debug this when I scroll down here.
It says if user check password if user is not none so I should capitalize that and there let me go back
and fix that.
Come over here too.
Let's make sure we figure out what that's on apple pie of our view.
So if user is not that should have been a capitalized and OK there we go save that and now let's try
refreshing our logon.
We're going to go ahead and submit our form and there we go it says compress your are logged in.
So we come back to home and it says hi.
Example.
Perfect.
OK.
And I'm not seeing any laga views so let's go ahead and check the nav bar make sure that's OK.
Coming back to our base h team L.
It looks like when I set up this nav link I forgot to actually write some text here for log out.
So let's make sure that they're going to save that spring in our page again refresh.
OK now I see log out.
So is practice logging out.
There you go.
Now that says Please log in or register.
All right.
So we had a couple of typos but none of them were anything we couldn't handle.
But hopefully now you understand how you can actually add user authentication to your websites that
quickly go over the main points so the main points is you're going to set up a user model as well as
a load user function.
So this will allow you to access the user authenticated method.
You can check our models up-I file in the notes for more methods that are available to you.
So we set up a user.
Usually it's going to be ID email username you're going to have their password or password and then
be able to check their password.
Then the apps on my file we just went ahead and we were able to use these decorator's like logging required
as well as log out user and log in user in order to perform logging in and logging out and all of that
comes conveniently with flask log and library.
All right if you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums and I'll see you at the next
lecture.