Welcome to this lecture on decorator's we're not going to discuss a more advanced Python topic which
is known as a decorator and a decorator allows you to decorate a function.
So this is just what that word decorate actually means in this context.
Imagine you just created a function in Python.
You have the simple function and it does some stuff and then return something.
Now imagine that you wanted to add some new capabilities to the function you wanted to keep the original
simple stuff but now you want to add more abilities by doing some more things and then returning something
else.
So I have two options.
You could just add that extra code that extra functionality to your old function just like we did here.
It took that same function and then added some more stuff to it.
Or you could create a brand new function that contains the old code and then add the new code to that.
But what if you then want to remove that extra functionality.
So neither of these solutions is actually pretty good because then you'd either have to use the old
function or delete the new code manually.
So is there a better way.
Maybe if we can have some sort of quick on off switch to quickly add this functionality or remove it
at our leisure.
So Python has decorator's that apply to tack on this extra functionality to an already existing function
and they're going to use the at operator and are then placed on top of the original function snake actually
easily add on extra functionality with a decorator.
So here we have our original simple function and then we can decorate with some decorator to add in
that extra functionality to the function.
So this idea is actually pretty abstract in practice of Python syntax.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go through the steps of manually building a decorator ourselves
to show what the operator is actually doing behind the scenes.
Again when we're actually using the operator and decorators with flask we're pretty much just going
to tack on the operator and it's just going to be a single line.
But to really understand what's happening behind the scenes in this lecture we're going to build out
that decorator process completely manually.
OK let's begin by thinking about functions within other functions.
So remember I could have a very simple function such as a function called Hello.
And all this function does is it just prints out Hello.
So if I save that and I actually run it at the bottom here and I run this file I get back up one line.
Let me expand this a little bit.
I get back.
Hello.
OK.
So now let's have hello.
Accept a parameter such as a name.
So by default the name will be Jose and instead of printing Hello we're just going to say the hello
function has been run
and then we're going to find a function inside of the hello function and it does seem strange to you.
Go ahead and review the scope lecture from earlier.
But I'm going to have another function here called greet.
And in this function instead of printing something I'm going to be returning and I'll say space is here.
This is inside
and then what I'm going to do here is I'm going to print the result of calling greet.
So that means when I call hello and execute that function I'm going to print out the hello function
that's been run then I'll define discrete function and then I'll actually call and print that function.
So let's check it out.
Let's run hello and see what happens.
So here I'm getting the hello function has been run and then this is inside the grid.
So to you if you want to have this extra spacing I kind of like spacing because it's enough.
It's a good way to visualize that great insight.
Hello.
And in fact let's do this one more time.
We're going to say create a welcome function that's going to return.
This is inside let's say this insight welcome save that and then I'll call greets and also call welcome.
So now when I run this I get back to the function has been run.
This is inside.
This is inside a welcome.
So I'm both calling Hello function defining greeting welcome functions and then executing those greet
and welcome functions.
Notice all of this Lines 2 through 11.
Those are all happening within the helo function itself.
So zoom out a little bit so we can see the whole picture.
But again all of this codes inside this one helo function.
Now let's talk about actually returning a function.
This is something we haven't seen before.
So we've briefly seen already functions within other functions that we haven't actually seen the idea
of returning a function.
So I'm going to do the following.
I'll see if the name provided is equal to Jose then return grete
else.
Return welcome.
OK so let's think of what's actually going to happen here.
I have this halo function and it takes an unnamed parameter.
It just goes ahead and prints Hey hello function has been run then it's going to find the function to
find the welcome function and then if the name is equal to Jose it's actually going to return the Greek
function itself.
Notice it's not executing it.
It's actually returning this entire function for you to then play around with.
Otherwise if the name is not easy it's going to return the entirety of the welcome function.
So let's see what happens.
I'm going to set X equal to hello and then I'm going to say execute x.
So when I run this knows what happens I get back the hello function has been run and then I'm going
to print the result of executing X..
You can clearly see this.
So I get back to hello functions and run.
And then this is inside green.
So what's actually happening here.
Well the name by default is Jose.
So then we print out the hello function to run.
So we just executed line 15 the hello functionals and run.
Then we define the function.
We find the welcome function and as the name was he called Jose.
I'm going to return the function then upon returning the function I set that equal to x.
So this line right here x is equal to Hello.
This is basically saying x is equal to
because I'm returning great here and because I'm not executing it that means I can later actually execute
X and print out the result which is going to return.
This is inside the Greek.
So this is an idea that we're going to be able to use to actually manually build out decorator's.
So again this idea is called returning a function.
I am just going to literally return a function by calling another function.
So let's try this again.
I'm not going to set my name equal to let's say Sammy say that and let's run it.
And now I see the halo function has been run.
This is inside welcome.
So why is it saying this is inside welcome.
Because my name provided is no longer equal to Jose.
So then this else executes and it returns the welcome function.
Again it doesn't execute the welcome function only returns the welcome function.
It's only when actually execute X here and print out the result that I get to see this is in sidewalk.
So this is known as returning a function.
Now we can also use functions as arguments.
This is the other main idea we need to understand for creating our own decorator's.
So so far we've reviewed functions inside functions returning functions and the final thing we need
to talk about is functions as arguments are going to create a function called hello and this one is
just going to return.
Hi Jose.
I'll create another function called other and it takes in a parameter func and it's going to print some
other code.
And then we'll print out phunk but knows what I'm going to do here.
I'm actually going to execute phunk so I'm going to assume that func flips assume that the func passed
in is a function.
So again I'm taking this as a parameter instead of my function and then I'm actually going to execute
it.
So let's say that and see what happens when I say other passen.
Hello I'm going to run this again and I see.
Hi Jose and some other code.
So what's actually happening here is I've defined this function.
Hello which returns.
Hi Jose.
And then I'm passing in that function notice here I'm not calling it I'm just passing it in and then
this other function is going to take it in.
It's going to print some other code and it's going to grab the function that was passed in this case.
Hello.
Execute it to return.
Hi Jose.
And then print out that result.
Which is why when I run this I see some other code.
Line 5 and then.
Hi Jose.
Which is the product of line 7 which is passing in the hello function executing it and returning Hi
Jose to be printed out.
So this is known as passing in a function as an argument.
Now that we understand these three fundamental ideas of functions within functions returning functions
and using function as arguments we can now actually build and create our own decorator.
So let's try this out.
I'm going to create a function called new underscore decorator and it takes an some phunk than inside
of it.
I'm going to create what I would call wrap func a wrapping function and it's going to print some code
before executing phunk then I'm actually going to execute phunk.
So remember this is the phunk that's passed in here.
So that has to do with the global scope I'm going to be able to call it and then I'm going to print
code here after executing phunk And then when I'm going to do is my new decorator function is going
to return rap funk Sozzi and try to understand the idea of what's happening here.
This function new decorator accepts a function then inside of the new decorator function I create a
wrap function that can add some code before I call func execute func and then add some more code such
as printing code here after executing func and then this new function which has effectively decorated.
Or add more functionality to phunk is then going to be returned.
And then finally I'm going to create a function that needs this declaration.
So I'll say this func needs a decorator going to say just prints please decorate me.
OK so let's see what happens when I say just call phunk needs a decorator by itself.
So if I run this code and I get myself a little more room here it says please decorate me and that's
it.
Which makes sense because that's all it's being printed here.
It says Please decorate me.
I call Falconis decorator and that's it.
Now let's try the following.
I'm going to say phunk needs a decorator and I'm going to assign it to new decorator passing in phunk
it needs decorator so what does this is doing is I'm taking what phunk needs a decorator currently is
which is just printing out please decorate me.
I'm taking this entire function right here and I'm passing into new decorator the new decorator is going
to take the funk needs decorator and it's going to build it into wrap function.
It's going to print some code before executing it then it's going to execute it and then it's going
to print some code after it and it's going to return that new repped function and I'm re-assigning that
to function means decorator.
So now let's see what happens when I actually execute phunk needs decorator.
I run this and if I expand this I can see the results and I'll get back some code before executing the
function.
Please decorate me and code here after executing phunk.
So this is basically what a decorator does all the decorator does is it takes in the function that you
want to decorate.
It creates a new function out of it with some extra functionality either before or after it or both
and then execute the function as well.
And this new wrapped version of your function gets returned.
Now instead of doing this sort of re-assignment which can be a little ugly and said well we can do is
we can use the app notation to say new decorator and that performs the exact same thing that we just
saw earlier.
So that line performs essentially what line 16 is showing here.
So Line 12 just tagging this function with that new decorator is the same as doing this right here.
Except this is really easy to turn off anon.
We can just commented out if we don't want it to be decorated or commented in.
If we do want it to be decorated.
Now we no longer need to add in this code manually or copy and paste this entire function and have kind
of two versions of it instead.
I can have this decorator function which I can easily then turn off or back on.
OK.
So let's see now that decorator in action I'm going to save this.
Run this file again.
And if we expand this to see the results I get back some code before in the function please decorate
me code here.
After executing function again let me just walk through everything here because this is basically it's
all decorator is we have a function that needs decoration.
And what we do is we decorate it with this at symbol new decorator and then that's going to be passed
in to this new decorator function which is then going to construct inside of this entire new decorator
function.
It constructs this new wrapping function.
You can execute some code.
Call the function then execute some more code after it and you return this new like souped up or decorated
version of your original function.
And then if you ever want to actually wrap or decorate your function you just tag your original function
with this symbol.
And then the name of this decorator and that's it.
OK I know this can be pretty complicated.
And luckily we're never actually going to build manually our own decorators.
Instead we'll be using the built in decorators that flask provides for us and we'll just be tagging
them at and then decorator.
So if you didn't understand this fully and wouldn't feel comfortable building out your own decorator's
I would pretty much say don't really worry about it because you'll never have to actually do this when
working with flask yourself instead you'll just be doing what we have here on line 12 adding a simple
decorator line of code.
But I do want to show you what's going on behind the scenes in case you are interested in it.
All right that's it.
We'll see you at the next lecture.