Welcome back.
In part two of our databases views lecture.
We're going to continue right where we left off last time by adding in the views and the routes to the
templates.
Let's head back to our text editor and continue.
All right here we are back at the actual text editor.
We just create our Papy model.
Now we're going to do is after this entire adoption site thought py file I'm going to create the actual
view functions in this view functions are going to have forms with them.
So that's going to allow us to actually take in user information and then save it to the models.
So we're gonna have quite a few views.
The first one is the home page.
So say app that route and it's just going to go straight to the home page.
Will say the death index and we're going to render or return rendered template and we're just going
to connect it to home.
H T.M..
And let me collapse this left hand sidebar so we have our home page and in the next couple of viewers
who wants is going to be a view for adding a puppy and another view for listing all the puppies from
the database.
And another view to remove a puppy or say app route and let's make the view for adding a puppy will
say forward slash add and you can technically call that whatever you want as far as your L extension
then we'll say methods and also the methods equal to get and then post.
And then here after this gets couple more lines here we'll do the following.
We'll say DMF and underscore pup we'll create a form and this form is going to be an added form which
means we should go to our forms that PI file and create the forms.
So we have an ad form that we're going to need.
So let's take a quick break and then come over here to forms that pi and actually create that form.
Because if you remember up here from the top we said from forms import add form and delete form.
So we should probably now create those cycloid to uncomment that out come to forms that pi and then
fill this out with those forms.
This is actually pretty straightforward it's the same thing we've done in the forms section of the course.
We'll say from flask underscored WITF import flask form and then from W.T. forms import and the fields
we're going to be using is a string field in integer field and they submit field that here will say
class add a form will inherit from flask form and or senator is going to have a name option to add the
name of the puppy or say String Field name of puppy and then we'll just have them submit the actual
puppy names so there will be a submit field it'll just be at puppy.
So that's the ad form and a little bit we'll connect it to a template.
And then the other one or the other class we're going to do is a delete form.
So say the form and this inherits from flask form we'll say ID is equal to integer field and this will
be the id number of puppy to remove.
So we're going to have the user instead of passing in the name of the puppy they want to remove because
puppies could share the same name.
Instead they'll provide the ID number for the puppy they want to remove from the database.
They will say submit is equal to I will say submit field remove.
OK so now that we have our add a form or delete form created we can come back to adoption site and then
begin to use those forms inside of these view functions.
So we set up our home page view that's no problem.
And now with add up we can get that out of form working.
So what we're going to do after we have the ad form will create an instance of it and then offer that
will say add a new puppy to the database.
So if that form validate on submit then we're going to grab the name that they provided for the puppy
from the form name.
Data and then we're going to add a new puppy to the database.
So I'll say that will say new pup is equal to a puppy object name.
Remember this puppy right here.
That's just a model we created up here in a much larger scope.
You'll have a separate models up profile and then say from models import puppy and then it's very similar
to the way that it forms here will say puppy.
Take that name then we'll say D-B session and we'll add a new pup then we'll say D-B session and we'll
commit those changes they'll say return and we'll redirect to your L for.
And we're going to make of you for listing all the puppies.
It's all a list pup.
We haven't created this puppy yet but we will that's if the form is valid on Simitian the default view
for at pup should go to the page.
So we'll say return rendered template ad T.M. and then we pass in the form as form.
All right so if we zoom out a little bit here we can see the whole view.
I have this add put view I create a version of the ADD form which remembers just this form appear in
the forms that py file.
Then I say it's a form as validation is valid on submission.
Then grabbed the name that they provided create a new puppy with that name.
Add that puppy to the database and commit and save those changes and then redirect them to a list of
all the puppies.
Let's go ahead and create that list pup.
You know it's going to zoom back in a little bit.
Come back down here.
It's the following will say app route will say forward slash list and then TGF list underscore pup.
And we're going to grab a list of puppies from the database so we'll do the following.
We'll say puppies is equal to puppy dog queery the all.
And then we will return render template list.
H T.M. where puppies is equal to puppies.
Save that.
So we have our list pup and then we're going to grab all the puppies in the database and then just pass
them on to this list HTL template now that we have that going.
Let's go ahead and create a view to remove a puppy.
So I'll say this at the forward slash deletes the methods here are going to be get and post because
now we're going to have a delete form or say this delete pup view create a form that's delete form that
we created.
So create an instance of that form and if the form is valid when they hit submit or we end up doing
is we say Id equal to form the ID data because remember if we come back here to forms that pi we just
pasand the idea of the puppy that we want to remove.
So he grabbed that from that ID and then will create a puppy say puppy dog queery get and then will
say id and we dont need to say that first or all because the ID is a primary key.
So the ID should only uniquely identify one puppy to remove.
Once we get that puppy we're going to say D-B session delete and then we're going to say pup will commit
those changes.
All right after that we're just going to return redirect your L4 and this case will say list up.
And then for the overall delete puppy page we're going to render the template for delete that each team
T.M. and then we say form Ezekial to form and then finally we'll say if name is equal to mean take the
app and run it and we'll say de-bug is equal to true.
And now you've completed everything that we need to do inside of our adoption site that py file.
So let's do a quick review of all this.
And the next lecture will fill out all the HTML templates and then we'll help debug anything that may
have gone wrong or may have been missing.
But I'm going to zoom out just looking at the whole picture of everything we've done so far.
We've done our imports set up our flask application set up the configuration seeker key for forms set
up the configurations for a sequel database set up the database then the migrations create a model for
that database.
Then we have two functions for the forms.
Our home page the puppy page and then we actually create an instance of a form which you remember we
created to form here in the forms up-I file in add form and the leaf form.
Just a way to grab a name and an ID from a user and then from there we have a list puppie view which
grabs all the puppies in our database and then we also have the delete view which grabs the ID that
the user submits in the form and then delete some from the session.
And that's the main idea of connecting templates forms and your database.
Since you do you create an instance of a form and then use the information that the user provided.
Queery your database somehow and then interact with it through a session and then redirect them to some
other page.
That's the main concept that we need to really understand.
For this particular lecture.
All right.
Once we done that we can then begin working on connecting all these views to their prospective html
files.
So we have base 30 smell that we still need to fill out the home page the ad page daily HTL and then
list h HTML so will be filling out all those template files in the next lecture.
We'll see if.