In the previous lecture recreate a view to show all of the blog posts that a user has now this clinic
that view to a template.
Let's head over to our text editor or a we're back at the text editor.
Previously we had created this user posts view and we also want to show you how we can actually keep
track of the pages so we don't show all the blog posts on a single viewing.
Instead we can go through them with pages.
So I'm going to expand the left hand tab here and underneath my templates or create a new file and will
call this user underscore blog underscore posts.
H Tim L so that it matches the actual render template command that I had in that views that py file.
So it matches here user blog postdates T-Mo.
OK.
Not going to collapse this.
And let me zoom in a little bit so we get a clearer idea of what we're doing.
We'll start off the basics which just means extending that base h T.M. and then we'll say block contents
and we're going to start off by just creating kind of a welcome thing.
So I'll say give a container and then create a little Jumbotron that contains some walking material.
And we'll also want to align everything here.
So I'll say a line is equal to center.
This is going to look really similar to the account page will say H-1.
Welcome to the page 4.
And in this case we're not looking at the current user.
We're just looking at any particular user here take a look back at views up high.
Remember we're looking out for Slash user.
So we come here that's the user that's here.
So say user thought username.
So again take a look at this.
If we look back at the view we're passing in this user right here.
So it's the user that we actually queried using this line 90 coming back.
Here we have that user user name.
And then let's grab their image.
So we'll create an image tag and the source is going to be Yoro for all we're going to grab from the
static whoops.
We do that right from the static folder the file name are going to be looking at is under profile pics
forward slash concatenated with that user's profile image string OK.
And we all have an alternative.
We'll just have that done.
So here's an image.
It goes head looks in the static folder under profile pics grab that profile image.
Next up we're going to do is actually use some template syntax here a little bit of logic to go through
those blog posts and way we're going to do that is create a little for loop here.
I'll say for post in blog posts and we actually can't just say blog posts like this because we take
a look back at the views that Hi-Fi all the blog posts that are being passed in here.
This is actually a specialized object that's being passed back and we actually just want to grab what's
known as the items off of this query so what we'll do here is let's say in block posts thought items
so that allows us to actually loop through the individual blog posts and then here we can present the
blog posts how we prefer.
Second make a little header too with an anchor tag.
Make the anchor again with an anchor tag here and the ATRA is going to be the URL for that particular
post.
So Hirose blog posts the blog post and that's a view that we're going to be making later on.
And we also provide a blog post ID to make sure we actually link to the correct blog post so we'll see
blog posts ID as equal to post ID.
Now we haven't really created any views or templates for our blog post.
So this link right here is going to make a lot more sense.
We actually create those views.
Basically we're going to have is underneath the blog post to set that up as a blue print and we'll have
a view called a blog post which essentially connects using a post ID so that allows you to then click
and view an individual blog post instead of viewing all of them at once.
So that's the two that's going to be displayed here and we'll just play the title of that blog post
as the actual text for the anchor to say enter the post-Idol right.
So that's the header to zoom out so we can see the whole picture.
This all essentially is going to display the title and that will link to the specific blog posts individual
page that will say something like written by
and then we'll insert an anchor tag for the actual author.
So here will say Post the author thought username.
So every blog post has an author that's basically just the user and they will grab that username should
match the ST username as here and then we'll do the following.
We'll say a Tref you are all for and we'll link to that actual user.
So say you're up for users thought user underscore post and then here will say that the username is
equal to post.
The author thought username.
OK.
So that essentially links to that particular author page.
And then there's one more thing we're going to display for every single blog post.
And that's just going to be the publication day as well as the text.
So say paragraph let's go ahead and have it kind of have a nicer class so we can make it a bit muted.
You can say text muted bootstrap class you can play around with that.
We'll say published on and then we'll just grab that post dates and then we can format the time using
as TRF time.
And you could pass in any format you want.
You can check out the formatting codes online just google format plus SDR time to understand what these
codes mean.
But basically I'm going to have the year dash the month dash and then the day sort of have it display
the publication that will create a break and will show the text so we can say post the text.
And then will create another break there.
OK.
So essentially for every single blog post we're going to show the title linked to that particular individual
blog post view which we haven't actually created yet but we will soon.
Then right below that you'll see the post author which is going to link for that actual user post and
then we'll see the published on.
And then we'll post some text.
Okay.
And then we have a break here after this.
That way there's a break between every single blog post.
So after that we're going to do is actually set up our page capabilities.
So we have that and for make sure we have that as well.
And in fact let's put all of this in the blog post.
Inside of that container Sherman we have this container and that's this right here.
Do you kind of select your cursor you should see the div underlining highlighting it.
I'm going to cut this and then paste it after this.
And for that way this for loop happens inside that container.
Everything is nice and centered.
So before the end block though I want to add in the capabilities for page navigation and the way you
do this is essentially copy paste pasted from the bootstrap documentation.
The hard part is actually doing the view code.
So remember back on our views we have these two lines of code line 89 and line 91 to do this page an
8 or pagination.
We're going to do is using the documentation is we bring in over here real quick if you come over to
components and then go to page nation you'll see some examples so you'll see all the examples here and
the different class calls you have to make.
So if I zoom in now you can see that there's different classes of page items and page links and you
can work with these different icons.
There's lots of different ways you can do this but that's essentially where these class calls and where
the overall structure is coming from.
A lot of this I'm just copying and pasting from the actual documentation.
And in fact I'm really going to just be copying pasting from this first example right here where we
have these labels and this class and these page item links.
So keep that in mind if Ffion actually referenced where I'm getting this from.
It's essentially just from the documentation of bootstrap go down to page nation OK.
So that's right it's ago.
Let's go ahead and fill that out.
So again kind of come back to user Blackhurst say Ario label and set that equal to.
And here this is such as copy and paste it was call it page navigation example.
So we create an unordered list and the unordered list is going to have a particular class call to work
with bootstrap.
We're going to say page nation and they will say justify content center.
So it appears at the center that way it's not all the way to Lefter all the way to the right.
And you can check that out also in the Flast documentation.
They have a nice link and it's linked to you in your notes.
There's a little snippet of code there that I got it from.
And then for the unordered list I'm going to create the pages.
So this requires another for loop.
And this was a little more complicated.
So I'm going to say for page number in blog posts dots and because blockhouses kind of the specialized
object that we're passing back.
Not only can we call items from it but we can also call the specialized method of itor underscore pages
and you can check out the link in the flask documentation for more information about this.
So you can provide different parameters to decide how much of a left edge and right edge you want to
actually provide for the number of pages because maybe if you have 1000 blog posts you don't want to
have if you only are showing 5 blog posts per page so many numbers at the bottom.
You may only want to kind of show two to the left to the current one and then to the right.
So these are the kind of parameters you can adjust.
You won't be creating so many blog posts but I want to show you the parameters and keys you want to
mess around with them so we can give a left edge of one to see one item or one number on the left hand
side and same we can give it right edge of one and then we can say left Currence of 1 and then right
Currence equal to 2.
Keep in mind we're not really going to have enough blog posts otherwise we have to keep making them
over and over again to really take advantage of these parameters.
You can check out the documentation for it or pages to get a better understanding of how these parameters
actually work in conjunction with these bootstrap classes of showing the numbers.
Essentially what this is going to do is at the end of the day it decides how many numbers you see at
the bottom the just two numbers left the such number and then two numbers in the right.
Or do you see maybe 10 numbers in total etc..
So you can mess around these parameters to justify that.
OK so we're going to save for page number and then we'll have an if statement.
Will say if the blog posts page is equal to the page number.
So what that means is if I'm currently on the same page of this blog post as I'm looking at so kind
of the number I want filled in what I'm going to do is create a specialized list saw create a list item
this list item is going to have a class called Page cash item.
This table and the reason they have it as disabled is it's going to look like you can't click on it
because that's the current pager on.
So all this statement doing says hey if you're on the current page that actual number in this page is
going to look disabled so you can't click on it which kind of makes sense.
You don't want to have them click on it and then keep refreshing the page so they only be able to click
to the left or to the right of it.
So inside of the service tag we're going to create an acre site and that's also going to have its own
class.
So let's set that up.
Well say class is equal to page Ashley and then the H ref here before we do that let's fill in what
this is going to be.
It's just going to be the page number so say page thumb and then a Tref is going to be your URL for
will say users.
User posts and then the user name is equal to user the user name and page is equal to page underscore.
OK.
So what's that doing is going to link to the correct page number and all of this is happening in conjunction
of the special three lines of code that we set up here in our views.
So basically this page parameter and this blog post parameter.
So now we have the kind of presentation it's going to look like if you're actually on the same page.
We'll say else we're actually going to copy and paste the exact same thing here.
So let me grab this and paste it.
The only thing we're going to change is that it's no longer going to be disabled because what these
lines are doing is that's a list item link that's going to make the number appear like you can't click
on it because that's the current page you're on.
So if this isn't true then that means it's a you're not on.
So it should look like a normal page item so that class is going to be a little different.
And that's all you actually have to do to make this work and that all goes inside this navigation bar.
And again if you're wondering where are these classes and where this actual structure comes from.
It's just combining some Jinja templating syntax with these forms and statements but the documentation
examples from Bootstrap So definitely take your time with this one.
It's kind of complicated when you first see it.
But I think when you actually end up using it in practice it becomes a little more clear.
So what I would recommend doing is going to the bootstrap documentation copying and pasting it over
to our notes and then seeing if you can fill in the blanks for these actual Jinja template lines.
This for loop and this if loop again really all we're doing here is saying okay for the page numbers
in the specialized pages go ahead and check if we're on the same page as we're basically for on that
page.
Make sure the items are able to they can't really click on it or does it look like you can click on
it.
Otherwise it's just an old page item and they'll click on it.
OK.
So technically you may not even need an Atreus here but it's just for the convenience of copying pasting.
So that's it for the user.
BLOCK close each time.
Later on we'll debug this to make sure everything's working.
But the main idea is to set up the Jumbotron that shows the user and then iterating through the blog
posts and then showing the pages.
OK.
Definitely check out our notes because there's a lot of stuff going on here.
So it's really easy to make a typo.
We'll see you at the next lecture.