Hello and welcome to this new tutorial this one is very special and very important because we're going
to do two essential tasks of an LP which are tokenization and filtering the non frequent words.
We're going to do that at the same time by creating two dictionaries.
One that is going to map each word of all the questions to a unique integer and one other dictionary
that is going to map all the words of all the answers to a unique integer and while creating this dictionary
we will add an if condition that will check if the number of arguments is of the word.
We'll be dealing with in the loop will be higher than a certain threshold that we will choose in the
same tutorial and if that's the case we will include that word in this dictionary this word will be
one of the key under-fire of the dictionary.
And on the other hand if the number of arguments is of the word is below the threshold.
Well we will not include this word in the dictionary so that at the same time we proceed to the process
of tokenization by getting separately all the different words of all the questions and all the answers
and attributing a unique integer to each of this word and at the same time we filter out the words that
don't appear frequently in the dictionary that is there or below the threshold that we're going to choose.
And speaking of the threshold this is the first thing we will do in the tutorial we will choose a number
for that threshold and for the words having a number of occurrences below the threshold we will exclude
them.
So let's do it.
Let's start by choosing this threshold.
So we're going to call it naturally Trece hold and in general when doing this kind of task in LP I recommend
to filter out the 5 percent that appear the least in the whole corpus of words and considering the total
number of words in our corpus of words.
Well a good threshold for our situation would be between 10 and 20.
Remember you can experiment with different hybrid parameters different values for the hyper parameters.
The threshold is one of them.
So I'm going to choose 20 here that will give us a removal of 5 percent of the least appearing words.
But feel free to either increase it increase the threshold that will reduce the training time.
Or if you have a powerful computer you can also try with a lower Tressell but not too low because then
it will be too overwhelming for the model to learn.
So here we're going to choose 20 and there we go.
Let's create now are two dictionaries one dictionary that will map each of the questions words to a
unique integer and one other dictionary that one that each of the answers words to a unique integer.
So let's start with the dictionary for the questions words.
And in the spirit of making all our variable names clear we are going to call that dictionary questions
words to and because we're mapping all the questions words to a unique integer.
So questions words to end and as usual we initialized it with some brackets like that.
All right then we are used to directly getting to a full loop.
But for us we need to initialize a variable to zero which will be the number of arguments as of the
word we will be dealing with in the loop because we are going to loop over the word in the word to count
dictionary that we created before.
You're going to see but we need to introduce a new verbal right now that we're going to call word number
and we will initialize it to zero because basically we're counting from zero.
And now we can start to flip.
So for as we say we loop over the words of our previous dictionaries so loop variable word and also
count because for each of these word we're going to get the number of arguments as of these words which
will get things to our word to count dictionary that we created before.
So a word count in.
Well we can get the words and the count of the words in that same entity the word to count dictionary.
So that in Word to count and to get them we need to adhere to that and items with parenthesis and this
will get us the word.
Which are the key identifiers and the number of your answers which are the values of the cat and the
fires in the word to come dictionary.
So Cullen and then let's start the for loop.
So as I said at the beginning of this tutorial now we have to make an IF condition to make sure we include
only the words that appear.
A number of times higher than the chosen threshold which is equal to 20.
So what I'm going to add here is an IF condition that check if the count which is the value of the dictionary
associated to the key identify word the word we're dealing with right now the loop.
So if count that is the number of arguments as of this word is larger than the Trece hold.
Well what are we going to do we can even include the threshold if we want to keep the words that appear
at least 20.
That's not a big deal that won't change much but we can include it.
And if that's the case what do we do.
Well we will include that word in the dictionary that we're creating right now and that we're calling
questions were to end and therefore Right now I'm taking this dictionary.
I'm copying that and pasting them here.
And so you know the trick I'm going to create the key and the value at the same time.
And the key which appears in the square brackets is the word we're dealing with right now and that we
choose to include in this dictionary because it's number of occupancies is larger than a threshold of
20.
So questions were in that word we just created the key and now we must associate it to it the value
and the value as we said is a unique integer.
Right because our dictionary maps to questions word to a unique integer and that's what this word number
will be useful for us right now.
It's because we're going to simply create these unique integers by starting from zero.
So the first word that we find appearing more than the threshold will be associated to zero then the
next one that we find appearing more than the threshold will be associated to one then the next one
to two then the next one to three.
Well you get the idea.
We will increment the word number.
Each time we find a word appearing more then the threshold and therefore the value associated to this
key identify words in our questions words.
In dictionary is the word number variable.
For the first word zero then we will incremented right now so that the next word we find appearing more
than the threshold will get the incremented value of the word number variable.
So right now what we get to do is increment word number and that's why M and N here plus equals 1.
Which is exactly the same as word number equals number plus 1.
Therefore the next frequent word will have to identify 1 then the next one after that we'll have to
keep it in the fire two etc..
All right and that's it.
That creates our questions where to the dictionary.
So we get this dictionary that encodes each of the words of the questions by at the same time only including
the frequent ones.
Or at least the 95 percent most frequent one and now we're going to do the same for the answers we are
going to create a new dictionary that we're going to call answerers words to end and that will do the
same it will not only include the 95 percent most frequent words of the answers and at the same time
associate them to a unique integer and so you get that.
This is exactly the same logic.
We just need to copy this copy and I'm going to paste that just below.
There we go.
And like before we just need to replace question by answer and we will be good to go.
So questions words.
I'm going to replace that by answer.
Answers words to end.
Perfect word number we can keep that because it was only used for the previous for loop and therefore
we can re-initialize it to zero because that's it by this code section here we get our dictionaries.
We can just use it again.
That's fine.
So we're numbers.
Fine then for word count in Word to count items.
All good.
If count is larger than the threshold.
Well our answerers words to int.
Dictionary will create the word key that was accepted because it appears more than the threshold and
the value word number which is its unique integer identifying and coding it.
And here eventually that's the same we just need to increment the word number so that the next word
that we find appearing more than the threshold gets a new unique integer to be encoded with.
There we go our two dictionaries are created.
We not only removed the 5 percent less frequent words and at the same time we encoded all the words
of our questions and of our answers.
That's a good thing done.
So now we're going to execute this section to have a look at our two dictionaries that we just created.
There we go we have them all good so let's have a look.
First let's have a look at the first one corresponding to the questions which is right here.
Questions words to it and there we go we get all the words of the questions and for each of them a unique
value identifier which is of course an integer right.
So you get all the words here and that will be very useful for our future to say model and in general
way that's the common task to do in natural language processing.
Of course you understand that right now we are only doing natural language processing.
We have not attacked deep.
And yet the deep part will come when we get to the deep neural networks.
That is when we get to the SEC to say all this what we're doing right now is just the common process
in our people.
That's of course very important.
Next have a quick look now at that and his words to the dictionary.
That's the same you have all the words and a unique integer for each of these words.
All right perfect so let's close this.
And now let's move on to the next step which will be quite simple actually it will be to add the final
unique tokens to our two dictionaries that we just created.
And that's basically the end of strings Storen string.
So as well the last unique tokens that we need to add to our dictionaries which are essential tokens
to consider when building the sector second work.
So we'll do that in the next tutorial.
And until then I didn't know the.