Hello and welcome to this new tutorial I'm super excited because we are two steps left from the big
training and the two remaining steps that we have to do is first split the data into batches of questions
and answers.
And that's what we're doing this to toil.
And then the second step is to split again the questions and answers into training and validation data
because we will do some cross validation during the training to keep track of the predictive power on
new predictions which will be 10 or 15 percent of the data.
All right so let's take care of this first step in this battle which is to split the data in two batches
of questions and answers.
That's a fundamental thing to do in deep learning to work with batches.
And basically in the Titor we're going to make the batches.
All right so we're going to do that into a new function that will use the previous function because
of course inside each of these batches we will pad the questions with the pad tokens so we will make
a new function and then of course in the training we will apply that function to create the batches
and feed the neural network with these batches of inputs and targets.
I remind that the inputs will correspond to the questions and the targets will respond to the answers.
All right so let's do this let's make this function we're start with death and this function is going
to be called split into batches.
I think that's clear.
This way split into batches and you can naturally guess the arguments that this function is going to
take.
Well that's going to be of course first are questions then are answers.
And finally of course the inevitable batch size because we have to choose a batch size for our batches
so split into batches.
Questions Answers batch size then Collen And let's go inside the function.
All right so we have to create several batches depending on the total length of the questions that is
the total number of questions and therefore we will have to figure out this total number of batches
we have to create which is a simple mathematical formula.
And then once we figure out this number we can store for loop to loop over each one of these batches
and then inside these batches we will get the batch of questions which will be our batch of inputs and
then the batch of answers which will be our batch of targets and of course inside of each of these batches
we will apply the Apply banding function to make sure that the sequences in our batches whether they
are questions or answers will be padded with the token so that they all have the same length.
So let's do this let's start with this for loop.
And so we have to loop over well let's say we're going to loop over some batch indexes.
So for batch index that's how we'll keep track of the batch.
So for batch index in range it's going to start from zero.
The first batch will have next 0 naturally with Python index it started 0 from 0 2 and that's where
we need to figure out the number of batches we'll have in the end which depends on two things.
First the total number of questions which is also the total number of answers because for each question
we have it's answer.
And the second element on which it depends is the batch size of course.
And so the number is naturally the total number of questions divided by the Vetch size that will give
us the number of batches we have to create because basically this will split the data into batches of
size batch size.
All right so let's do this.
It is from 0 up to the number of questions which I can get.
Thanks to the len function that I apply to the questions that gives me the number of questions and also
the number of answers.
But we need to divide that by the bedside but in order to get an integer we're going to use this double
slash double slash and that divides the length questions by batch size.
All right.
So this line questions divided by bite size.
We are ready to start the fall.
All right.
So we're going to start with a start index this start index will be the first index of the question
we're adding in the batched.
Now we're dealing with a specific bet right now that has a specific batched index.
But this start index here is the index of the first question.
We are adding to this back and therefore also the index of the first answer we're adding to this bet.
So start index.
And how can we get it at a specific step in the loop.
Well that's going to be equal to our batch index multiplied by the batch size.
All right.
Let's explain that with the first indexes.
So we started back in there 0 right.
That's our first batch and therefore the first question we'll add is the first question the very first
question of all the questions and we'll have the index 0 that index times batch size.
So that will be the start index of the first question we'll add in the batch.
And then when batch index equals 1 which is the next step in the loop Well that's where we'll deal with
the second batch with the next one.
And therefore the index of the first question will add to this second that will have to be the best
index one times the best size which is for example 64 we chose 64.
This first question will add to the second batch will have to be the next questions after all the questions
we added into the first batch.
And therefore since there were 64 questions in the first batch.
Well the index of these first questions were adding to the second batch must be 64 because the questions
in the first batch had indexed from zero up to 63.
So that's how it works and that's how we can get the start index that is the index of the first question.
We are adding to the batch we're dealing with at each step of this iteration so start index equals batch
index times batch size.
And now we are ready to add our questions in the bed and our answers in the batch because basically
we just needed this start index.
So first let's get our questions in the batch.
So I'm calling this variable question and that.
I think that's pretty clear.
These will be the questions we add to this specific batch.
We are drilling right now in the loop so questions and batch equals and now very simply we wanted to
take our questions our whole list of questions and just get the right indexes of these questions that
have to go into the batch we're dealing with right now in the loop and that we can get things to this
start index.
And of course the bedside because these questions that we want to add right now have their indexes starting
from start index up to start index plus batch size.
And there we go.
We have our questions in batch.
All right perfect.
And now let's take care of our answers.
Answers in the batch were basically going to add the answers to those previous questions here in the
batch to this same batch we're dealing with right now in the loop.
And so I'm going to call this new variable answers in batch which same will contain the answers in this
batch and therefore that's going to be exactly the same here.
We just need to copy this and just below paste it and replace questions by answers.
All right.
And that gives us the answers to those previous questions in the batch.
Great.
And now what do we have to do.
Well that's very simple.
We just need to apply padding to each of the questions we added in this batch.
And also each of the answers we added in this batch.
And that's why we had to do this apply padding function before.
Because basically now what we're going to do is apply the Apply banding function to each of the questions
in our questions in batch.
And each of the answer is in our answers and back.
And so I'm going to introduce two new variables first bad questions in batch and battered answers in
batch.
All right questions and that and better answers in batch which will contain the same questions and same
answers in the same batch.
But with the padding applied with all the pet tokens and so to apply this well we simply need to take
our apply padding function which I'm copying here and pasting it here.
And same here as well apply padding and inside.
What do we need to do.
Well as you can see the applied bellying function takes two arguments.
First the batch of sequences which is exactly this batch we're done with right now.
So for the questions it's going to be two questions in batch.
And for the answers it's going to be the answer is in batch.
And then the second argument let's not forget it.
It's a word in a dictionary.
And so you know what dictionaries will take for respectively the questions and answers for the questions
will take the questions words to the dictionary and for the answers we'll take the answers words to
a dictionary and there we go we will have a polite pairing to both our questions and our answers in
this specific but we're dealing right now.
The loop.
All right let's do this apply padding to our well let's copy this.
That's to our questions and Bache so questions and Bache and with the questions word to and dictionary.
All right.
And then same for answers.
We're going to apply that to our answers and that on that.
Here with our answers.
Words to and dictionary.
And there we go.
That applies to padding to all the questions and answers in the batch.
But now we're just going to add one more thing to this data structure we just got this data structure
is actually a list.
You know we returned our padded functions in a list a list of sequences.
But we actually need an umpire because then when working with tons of flow we need to start with an
umpire right.
So what we simply need to add here which will and blow all this apply padding of the questions and answers
we simply need to add the non-Thai array function which we need to apply to the whole thing here.
And same here.
I'm taking a number that has a shortcut and P and the array function.
There we go.
That takes the whole bed and answers in batch here.
All right.
And that's OK.
Now we have our batch of Pelet questions in our same batch of Pettitt answers and non-payers which will
be ready to transfer soon to 10.
All right.
And finally we have to return our Pettitt questions and back and our panel answer in bed for each of
the batch.
So we have to stay in the loop but this time to do this we're not going to use the return syntax we're
going to use the yield syntax to yield and Python is like a return but it's better to use it when dealing
with sequences.
I will provide them the resources of the Statoil.
Nice explanation of the differences between return and the old.
All right so yields.
And we want to return our battered questions and batch and also are bedded answers in batch and there
we go we are done with our split into batches function.
So now we're going to select all this code section and execute to get our split into batches function.
All right.
Amazing.
We are now one step left from the big step of the training.
We have another split to make which is to speed the questions and answers into training and validating
data.
We'll do that in the next oil and then eventually we'll get to the training until then.
And so it's been on the.