Hi guys and welcome to Pardes zero installing Anaconda and getting the data set.
So in this for Statoil we will install the Anaconda ID which contains spider on which will implement
our Chad.
But.
So just like me go to right now and then type in the research bar Anaconda.
Here it is.
You take the first link and I go on the cloud.
And then here you click on download an icon.
All right then you will end up on a new page.
And on this page I need to find your system Windows Mac OS or Linux.
I am on my quest so I'm in the right tab and you need to click on download here for Python 3.6 and not
Python 2.7.
So there we go let's click on download then the download will not take long just wait for it to be completed.
And once that is the case you're ready to install Anaconda.
So the download will probably go to your download folders.
That's where I'm going to go right now.
Here I am.
That's an icon that installation files.
Double click on it and then very easy.
You just need to click on continue continue continue agree and install for me on the continue.
And there we go install the installation is on its way so it should take a couple of minutes so I'll
see you at the end of the installation.
It will go without any issue.
Perfect.
The installation is done so now just press close and then if you want can move the installation file
to the trash.
So I'm going to do it.
And there we go.
Anaconda is now installed and now we are almost ready.
What we need to install is tense afloat because tenso flow is not already integrated in the neck under.
However I know that some of you work on a specific environment that you wouldn't want to interfere with
this course.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a virtual environment.
And besides it's important to do it because tests flow has some issues with Python 3.6.
So we're going to create a virtual environment with Python 3.5.
So we're going to downgrade to Python 3.5.
And inside this environment we will install tens of them.
So to do all this we need to open either a terminal for Mac and Linux users or the anti-canuck prompt
for Windows users.
So for Mac and Linux users what you need to do is to open a terminal so I'm not here so I'm going to
open it from the spotlight search terminal.
There we go.
For Linux users please open your terminals as well.
And for Windows users what you need to do is go to the bottom left corner of your screen.
Click on the windows button here.
Then in the list of programs you have to find Anaconda and inside an icon there you just need to find
Anaconda prompt and that's the equivalent to the terminal.
So click on Anaconda prompt.
This will open it and then now we are on the same page.
We are ready to enter some commands to create this virtual environment with Python 3.5 inside which
we will install transfer.
So let's do this to create a virtual environment in Anaconda.
What we need to start with is Condor.
Then we add create and then minus and and after that we need to give a name to this virtual environment.
And so we will call it chat but.
All right Chad.
But and so inside this virtual environment we want to install Python 3.5 so make sure to enter Python
equals 3.5 and then Anaconda that's to specify We want to create it in Anaconda and then that said you
just need to press enter.
All right so now it's going to take a while it's going to install several packages with Python 3.5 inside
Anaconda.
So it should take a couple of minutes.
As you can see here you just need to press y for yes enter.
And now as you can see it's installing all the different packages that you will need to implement the
chat but and executes different code.
So it's going to take a while so I'll see you once the installation is done.
All right perfect.
Now the chat but virtual environment is created.
And so now what are we going to do is we're going to go inside this environment.
We're going to activate it.
And then inside of it we will install tens of flow.
So to activate it you need to use the activate command.
However for Mac Linux users you will need to start with source activate and for Windows users you will
need to start with only activate.
So for Mac Linux users you need to type here source activate then you need to enter the name of the
virtual environment which is shut.
But and that's it.
And for Windows users you need to just type activate without the source and then chat.
But all right so here since I am on Mac I need to start with source before activate and there we go.
Now you just need to press enter.
All right so now as you can see I am inside my virtual environment Chad but.
Right.
Perfect So now I'm ready to install tens of flow inside this virtual environment and to do this.
Well that's very simple we need to answer the IP then install sensor flow double equal one point zero
point zero.
We are installing this specific version of tens of low that's important for implementation.
Right and then you just need to press enter and there we go.
This will collect sense of flow 1.0 zero.
Downloading it and then installing it inside the virtual environment that we called Chat.
But I had perfect successfully installed tens of floor 1.0 plans are great.
Now you can just close the terminal and now eventually we're ready to go inside under.
So for Windows users you can find an icon then the list of programs and for Mac or Linux users same
I'm going to use the shortcut here I'm going to open from the spotlight search and conduct navigator.
There we go.
Found that Anaconda is opening and now I'm going to show you what you have to do.
That's very important.
This is now this we're going to connect to the virtual platform that we captured.
And to find it in it to go to applications on here.
Then click on the arrow here and you'll find chat.
But Judd but which is our virtual environment that we just created.
And then you just need to click on lunch here on Spider the spider window here because this is the I.D.
in which we will implement our Chad.
But this is for me the best especially when you're beginning because this is like a studio with many
features many cool tools and everything at your disposal to implement them are all the deeper any application
or nay.
This is very practical.
Then another one that I highly recommend is Jupiter notebook.
And that's especially if you want to add some let's ask you know if you want to write some mathematics
especially if you are writing a report.
I wrote all my papers and research projects on Jupiter because I included some mathematics but we won't
include the mathematics here.
So Spider will be perfect.
So let's open our studio spiders 3 inside the chapbooks virtual environment.
Perfect.
Now welcome to spider.
For those of you who are discovering it for the first time so I'm going to quickly describe it.
This is the editor.
This is where we will implement the code.
This is the console.
This is where the code will be executed.
So for example in the end when we test Shadbolt Well we will see the questions that will answer here
in the council and the chair but answers as well.
All right.
And then here you have another window that welcomes three features.
Explorer which contains all your files.
That's important we'll see the second variable Explorer which will contain all the variables that you
create during the implementation and help to get some help about the different objects we use or create.
All right.
So the first thing we're going to do now and that's very important is to get rid of this term that fell
by opening at the top you click on file and you file so you open a new file and then you get rid of
this by clicking on close tab here.
All right then what you're going to do is you're going to go to fully explore and I recommend to create
a new folder in desktop.
That's what I did.
I created the deep end LP is that folder.
You can just go deep in and if you want or any other name but that will be the folder that will contain
the python files that will implement.
Basically that's the father that will contain the checkbook.
And also very importantly this folder will contain the data set that we will download in the next tutorial.
So let's open it.
There is nothing inside because I'm starting from scratch with you.
We're going to do the whole implementation from scratch together.
And therefore that's why it's empty right now.
So what we're going to do is save this new python file that we just created and we're going to call
it shut but that way and this will be the file that will contain the whole implementation of the child
the four parts of the Shadbolt including how we build it how we train it and how we test it.
All right.
And so this voucher that you will you will of course save it in your deep end LP is that for them that
you just created.
So that's why and going into it deep in LP is that and then you just need to click on safe.
All right.
And there we go.
Now you're ready to start.
So we can remove all this.
We can give a nice title to our file we can call it building a chat but with deep and I'll be all right
you can click on Save and there we go.
Now you're ready like me to start the implementation.
Now your folder contains the shadow that I fell in which will implement the whole model and now what
we need of course is the data set on which will train the checkbook.
And that's what we'll get in the next tutorial.
And until then and depend on the.