Heyes welcome to this new tutorial in the previous one we installed Anaconda tenso flow and our chat
but virtual environment.
And in this new d'hotel we're going to get our data set which is the only thing missing right now.
We already created our Chad but that fell in which will implement the whole more all that is the whole
Chad.
But but to do this we need a data set to train this jet but and this is what we'll get to toile.
So this dataset is called the Cornell movie corpus data set and it's basically a data set containing
thousands of conversations from 600 plus movies between many characters.
So let's have a look at this data.
Let's enter here in Google Cornell movie dialogue corpus.
That's the one just press enter and just take the first link.
So you just need to add to a Cornell movie Diala corpus then take the first link and there we go.
That's the dataset.
So let's have a look as a description says this corpus contains a large meta data rich collection of
fictional conversations extracted from raw movie scripts.
So in total two hundred and twenty thousand five hundred seventy nine conversational exchanges between
10000 pairs of movie characters.
Not that then it evolves nine thousand thirty five characters from six hundred and seventeen movies
and in total 340000 713 utterances are perfect so let's download it to download it.
You simply need to click on the zip file here and this will start the download which you should get
in a matter of seconds.
I just got it.
So let's go to my download folder on my computer.
Here we are.
And here is the Cornell movie dialog's corpus Doucette.
So let's double click on it and zip it.
And there we go.
It contains several files.
So now we have to make the difference between meta data and the real data.
Meta data is like the data I will not use for the training.
So it's things like to ratings or the movie that comes from like some description or data and we don't
need that of course we just need.
Well basically the conversations between the characters and that's what we'll get now and that's what
will directly put in our deep and anti-father there because we just want what's necessary for us.
But feel free to have a look at the other files like this one you can see an interesting paper that
will give you some relevant information.
Then you have some meta data here about the movie characters then some other method data here about
the movie titles then some read me script that will give you some more descriptions but the things we'll
need for a chat but is actually just two files.
These are the movie conversations that me and the movie lines here.
The rest.
We actually don't care because we actually won't use it for the training.
However let's have a look at these two hour movie conversations that the XTi and movie lines that tasty.
Let's start with movie lines.
Some movie lines as you can see contains some extracts of scripts taken from movies.
So for example I'm going to open it with let's see Sublime Text and let's have a look.
So as you can see it contains several columns separated by these strings here plus plus plus dollar
plus plus plus.
So that's the first column second column third column force column and Fix column the first column is
just an idea.
It is the idea of the line said by some character in some specific movie.
Then the second column speaking of the character is actually the character.
Eumenes user here.
So for example if we take these first two lines here that a conversation between user zero and user
2.
Then the third column is the movie.
So it is indexed by and a number so that movie Zero here.
Then the fourth column is the name of the actor while the character and this is actually some meta data
which we won't use to train our chat but.
And finally the last column is the line.
So what does this line mean.
Well it means that Bianka who is indexed by use of zero in movie Zero says they do not.
And then if we take the second line well that's taken from the same movie.
Movie zero.
But this time it's used to named Cameron that says they do too.
And actually the script goes this way.
Kamman starts to say they do too.
That's the input and Bianka replies.
They do not.
OK.
So that's an extract from a movie Zero between two users use zero and you to younker and Cameron and
that's one conversation.
And we have other conversations with most of the time.
One input and one out but not all the time.
As you can see for example here we have a huge conversation starting from here H-60 to eight sixty two.
So we have a long conversation here between the young can camera Blanquette Cameron the young guy Cameron
young.
Cameron Well that's actually from the same movie with the same users obviously but a different extract
from the movie.
I don't know if you recognize the movie.
I don't but this is a conversation on which Archie had but will be trained.
All right so it's important for you to understand well the structure of the data set.
This is movie lines that THC which basically contains several conversations between some characters
taken from different movies.
All right.
So we're going to close this now.
And we're going to open the other interesting dataset which is movie conversation that takes me I'm
going to open it with Sublime Text as well.
And there we go.
So as you can see it's almost the same except that this time we don't have the lines.
We have the conversations.
Each row of this dataset corresponds to one single conversation.
So as you can see in each conversation we have several lines and these lines in one same conversation
are all the lines composing the conversation.
And this is important because the previous dataset didn't somehow separate the conversation so we need
this data set to make sure we distinguish two different conversations on which Archibold will be trained.
All right.
So let's close this.
And therefore that's all we need.
So what we're going to do now is take these two three XTi fell these two datasets.
I'm going to copy them.
I just copy them Kamensky or Control-C on Windows and I'm going to go to my desktop where I created
the deep end and it is a folder.
So let's go inside and let's just paste the dataset composed of movie conversations RTX the movie lines
that TSC and congratulations you have all you need to implement the chad but just one shot that you
fell.
Which will contain the whole implementation of the job but including how we build it how we train it
and how we test it.
And these two files which compose the day is it.
That's it.
So if you're ready let's start from the next tutorial.
And actually in the next story we'll start part 1.
Data Processing.
This is not the funniest part but let's try to make it with enthusiasm so that we can get to part two
without even noticing.
All right so I'll see you the next it's oil.
And until then and even I'll be.