Highs and welcome to this new tutorial and this one we're going to get separately the questions and
answers.
So as we explained in the previews to all these are going to be respectively the input and the target
of the new one that work there is the questions will be the inputs and the answers will be the target.
And so we're going to get them separately before cleaning all of them all the questions and all the
answers.
So that's the last step before starting all the cleaning process to make the data set as simple as possible.
All right so let's do this.
And before we start.
Well it's important to understand where we're going to get separately these questions and these answer
and how are we going to put them together.
Because what we want to get is two separate huge lists.
One for the questions and one for the answers but of the same size because for each index I have these
lists.
Well the answer of index I should be the answer to the question of index I therefore it should be well
aligned and to make sure this is well aligned.
What we need to understand here is that in our conversations IDs huge list that we just made in the
proof that Tauriel well in each conversation.
The first element will be the question.
The first question the second element will be the answer.
So basically the key identifier of the answer is the next key identifier of the question just before.
So that's what we need to make clear.
And if that's the case we'll it will be easy for you to understand how we get these questions and answers.
So let's do this since we're going to make two separate lists one for the question and one for the answers.
We're going to introduce here to lists that we're going to initialize an empty list.
And of course we're going to call them very simply questions and answers.
And so as we just said we are going to initialize them as empty list which like before is with a pair
of square brackets.
All right so our Toolis are now initialized.
And now we're going to make them with of course a for loop so for.
And now according to you on which object on which list are we going to iterate on.
Well that's of course what I've just showed you the conversations IDs because the conversation is not
only contains all the conversations but mostly it contains two key identifiers of each line of the conversation.
So we will get the key identifiers in each conversation and using our dictionary that we made before
we will get the text of the line because we no longer want to get the key.
Now we want to get the real text because this will be the input and the target of the neural network
so we want to get the real text and therefore we have to use a dictionary to map the key identifiers
to these text but to make sure we get well aligned by taking the answer as the next key identifier of
the question we need to use.
Does this conversation IDs list because this is where we get the conversations.
Therefore we're going to iterate on these conversations IDs list let's do it and therefore we need to
choose a name for the loop variable we're going to call it.
Well conversation this is still a conversation only just contains the lines IDs for conversation.
And as we said conversations underscore IDs right.
CULLEN And let's start the loop.
Ok so now according to you and actually I recommend you to do that.
Well during the course is to guess what I'm going to type.
You know what we want to get.
We want to get separately the questions and the answers.
So try sometime to make pause on the tutorial and try to guess what I'm going to type next.
So right now we want to get separately the questions and the answers then first we know that in conversations
IDs the key identify of the answer comes right after the one of the question and besides we have this
idea to line dictionary that can map these key identifiers to the real text of the questions and answers.
So we need to use them both.
And therefore what do we need to do.
Well not only do we need to iterate again on each of these conversations because right now we're dealing
with a specific conversation in all the conversations IDs so we need to iterate through all the key
identifiers of this conversation and then once that is done we will map these key identifiers to the
real text.
And therefore what we need to do now is a second follow up.
We need to iterate on the key identifiers of the conversation we're dealing with right now and therefore
the second loop is going to be for I in range of.
Well basically we need to put the number of elements of that conversation.
We're dealing with right now and this we can get it with the length that we can get with the len function
of this conversation we're dealing with right now.
Len conversation however since we're also going to get the answer in the second loop Well we are going
to add here a minus one because you know we'll take the index plus when we will take the I plus one
here and therefore it shouldn't go beyond the upper bound of the range therefore the minus one here.
All right so with this second loop we iterate on all the elements of the compositions that is all the
key identifiers one after the other and so call and again.
And now let's enter this second loop.
And the good news is that right now we are ready to get our questions and our answers and of course
since we already initialized them an empty list.
Well we simply need to use the append function to append what we have to happen in respectively the
questions and the answers.
So let's start with the questions questions that are banned and now try to guess what we need to append.
Exactly.
Well remember we want the text this time.
We're getting closer and closer to the neural network so we have to get the some day.
And so you know what to do we need to use our dictionary I need to learn because this is the one that
maps these key identifiers that we're about to get to the text of the lines.
And so here we go let's take our dictionary into line and in square brackets we need to put the key
identifier of the line which is going to be well conversation of index i because i is a loop variable
that goes through all the elements of the conversation here which is one of the conversation in the
whole list of all the conversations.
Perfect.
So by doing this we just append it and you question and now we have to append the answer corresponding
to that question and therefore.
Well let's maybe take this copy and paste it here because it's going to be almost the same.
We're going to take care of the answers now.
So I'm taking my answers list and now it's going to be the same.
We have to append the answer to.
The answer is this.
But remember that everything has to be aligned at a specific index.
The answer of that index should be the answer to the question of that same index.
And as we just explained the answer has the next index after the one of the question.
This index corresponds to the index of this first element here.
That's zero for example and therefore the index of the answer that we want to get that we want to append
now and that should be aligned with our previous question.
Must be the next index that is index here and therefore it should be I plus 1 and so the only thing
that we need to replace here is just this.
I by I plus one and that's it.
We just happened that the proper answer to our previous question.
So now we're going to have a look.
We're going to check if everything's OK.
We're going to be able to check that by checking the relevance of the questions and answers.
So let's do this let's execute now.
And there we go.
Well executed.
Now let's have a look.
At first the questions yes and the answer's yes.
All right.
Now let's check if our questions are well-aligned with our answers so let's say for example this one
how do you get your hair to look like that.
That's the question and the answer is Ebers deep conditioner every two days.
And I never ever use a Wherever So that looks correct and that's another example I can see some French
here semi at.
This is my head.
So this is my head is a translation of smattered.
And the answer is so same index Stenton right.
See you're ready for the quiz.
I suppose this is a French quiz I don't recognize any movies in these lines but it indeed looks like
some movie lines.
And anyway we aligned correctly our questions and our answers so congratulations you're getting closer
and closer to the right structure we're trying to get.
And so now actually we can start cleaning all this text because as you can see these will be difficult
for the chat but to train how to talk like a human because we need to do a lot of cleaning for example.
I don't we will replace that by.
I do not.
So that's all the Don't do not are associated with one same common token and same for your.
We're going to replace that by you are.
And that that is.
Anyway we're going to do a lot of cleaning like that and we're going to put everything in lower case
as well.
And that starts from the next tutorial.
And to learn and Jaideep deep LP.