All right.
Welcome back.
Muddiest student in this section here we are going to be upgrading our application to 5.3 version 5.3
or Lero bell.
Now in this lecture here that you're watching right now just going to give you a little bit a little
overview on what's new and what a find this information right now.
We're now going to cover most of this stuff because we do not apply this in our application here.
All right.
Most of this stuff or a little bit more advanced that is beginner's course so I'm going to create another
course for this.
All right.
So just pay attention to that.
Stay tuned for that news because I'm going to create another more advanced course too just to cover
some of those aspects of Larabee.
But right now in is beginner's course.
I'm going to show you exactly how to upgrade to the next version.
And I'm just going to go over a little bit of the changes that the biggest changes that are actually
affecting our application.
Because right now we've got a couple of changes that are breaking our application entirely if we try
to upgrade right now.
All right.
So let me just open this.
I got this page here that I found on the river News.com which is I think I recommended a lot if you
guys are intolerable.
All right.
To subscribe to the news where you can find out.
So some of the things that are new.
All right.
This is this is the page.
A lot of the news out common you can see it.
We got the mailable that's a big thing here because now we don't have to send an e-mail the long way
like we did before we all do this.
We can just create a class with the artist in command and then inside that class we can find the from
in and in some more parameters even the view in this build Mantid are right inside that class which
is pretty cool.
All right so now you can send the mail like this.
All right so the is a big thing.
Notifications are making it easier for US passport that's a little bit more advanced.
All right.
So it's just a package.
We can roll back migrations.
Instead of doing the whole batch we can just do one instead.
Bley for each array has the loop variable now that we can you know like say for example here is saying
OK if loop first I want you to do this.
Basically if the first iteration.
Now it's actually they included some more features into this.
Right.
So this loop is just you know detecting the iteration.
So he has like the first iteration the last iteration has some more mentors that you can use more properties
.
So collections have change a little bit and this is just stuff that we are not culverin entirely guys
but I want you to be aware of them all right.
So I wanted to go over a really quick about it right.
So this is stuff that you can actually come and look out of yourself right.
Look at can you cash helper would not cover in cash either in this course.
But anyway I wanted to show you give you a little bit overview some of the big changes and show you
where to get them.
All right.
So that's one place where are what actually they he describes I think is arrogant self.
Yes.
He described some of the changes in self in day here in this website Scotch Dyo.
I know you can go actually go in deep really dig deep really deep into that or dive like they call it
right into the features.
Each of them.
All right so this is going to describe the features entirely up to you.
I mean Charlie said look they're talking about the loop variable here.
All right showing you the structure and telling you some of the methods here.
Look at this are the properties I mean you're right.
Pretty cool stuff.
I think this is the best Web site to actually get all this information from.
So anyways stuff that you can actually get yourself and you can take your time with it.
All right.
My job here in this section is to help you upgrade to 5.3.
So we started doing that in a net lecture