Welcome back many students is time for us to learn about migrations and migration.
So one of the coolest thing Clarabelle has available for us to use.
Where are they.
Well they are kind of table generators.
Call them generators.
Basically what we do is we find the table insight or application side Clarabell we define the table
and we find the columns in how we wanted the columns and then we run a PH BE adducing command and then
we create a table where ever that table software is.
So if we are using my Escudero in that in this example you're going to be able to see that table in
ph we my out me in whatever other program you use to see your tables right.
Well if we are using the F-Secure light a file base database then you are a you're able to go and see
those that information in those files is going to be pretty cool.
You're going to love it.
And why is it so important to do migrations.
Because imagine that you have to share your project.
Now you don't have to go to PH be my admin or support your database you don't have to do that or you
have to do is just give the project to somebody else.
And what we do is they just run up BHP adducing command and Whyalla.
They have their tables created for them automatically on their site.
So it's going to be pretty cool if you're really tidy.
I want you to get more excited because migrations are really cool.
So if you're ready I'm ready.
Let's do it.
And please go over there and do some work.
Write the code.
Don't just watch it right.
Thank you.
Rabbi