All right welcome back.
I stood and so we got the categories working here.
One of the things that we are missing here in this application is the ability to THE LEAD image.
So we're going to start creating that section here where we can delete the images because we have a
couple of images that are not doing anything on our servers and we would like to delete them.
Right.
So just for demonstration purposes only you can look at the polls and you can see age polls has the
categories that we create.
All right so they are working.
Cool.
All right.
So let's going create a media page or photos page whatever you want to call it.
And I don't believe we have that for them here.
So this created media and it's
now awry.
This is a good time to do a commit good ad and good commit
categories working 100 percent.
All right cool.
All right.
And guys you want to be a little bit more descriptive on what you're doing and when you're working with
a team I'm doing this just to force you to actually do it but be a little more descriptive when you
are actually making comments.
Remember that if you're working on a team they going to see this and they wonder why in the world he
just meant with that you could say all day the categories added the L Day features and delete it and
delete features or something like that.
Ok cool.
Let's actually take all of this out of here.
We're going to create is pretty fast guys.
All right.
We are the media here with let's do it stands and we're going to say layouts and then whoops
content.
All right.
This to this table.
What are we going to have here.
Well we're going to have an I.D. for a picture and the name of our picture that say maybe they created
they if you want.
That's up to you.
OK.
So
the name of it and the maybe created they it's up to you.
All right.
And we don't of course want to see this on unless we have photos.
I'm going to build in this already because we already know while we're going to do.
Right.
So
we just know that we are going to have all this year's I'm starting from the back.
All right.
I'm starting from the view we should start from the controller usually but we already know this stuff
right.
So for those for whom
and then we get to close it up here and I'm doing this pretty fast because I know you guys know this
already.
You should if not you need to watch some videos and get it down.
All right.
It's about time you know this stuff and very well
forward on this story at all.
If conditions here
so we find the name actually
if we find a photo this play let's play the photo file.
And if not
actually this is going to be an image here that's fine.
We'll we'll come back to that.
Well this is not going to be an image.
This is they create it.
Sorry about that.
We already have that on top.
All right.
Create it out.
So if we have a create that we're going to show one we'll show it.
If not then no date.
And you might do this for the file as well.
Just in case.
But if we are actually going out or the images they should have something right.
So I don't think we should have a problem with this one.
I don't think we will have a problem with that one.
All right.
So let's go and create Well we don't have we have a false model here but we don't have a Fodor's controller
I know and we can name it whatever we want for us control over media media controller OK.
So artists make
controller and we're not going to create it with the resource we don't need it we just need and that's
really that's all we need.
All right.
So we're going to say the media's media controller
the media's controller helps misspell something they're not.
This is not a class.
Here we go.
OK then let's go to rouse real quick and make sure that we have our routes there for media even though
we're not creating a resource.
Let's just do it
because we have we might in the future so admen
media.
Ok cool.
Let's also fix the link in the lay out.
Let's go to actually no.
It's right here
media right here
.
It just froze on me real quick.
All right.
Ad Man media and it's OK.
And this would be a no blow page here so this is going to cost them away.
Could
we could give it make it for the show.
All right let's just say ad men media overload.
All right we'll fix that in a minute.
We'll make it.
We'll make a custom rule for this.
A custom rap name.
All right cool.
So let's go to the controller
that's synchronizes
carrying public function in its
turn
whether we call it Fotos.
I think we did right.
I'm asking you but you never asked for me back.
All right let's add this here
and let's do this compact
Fotos.
All right let's see if we got something here.
Let's refresh this.
And of course add mean media overload.
Now the fine let's go and find out real quick and.
All right.
Admin
media
overload.
Oh Lord.
And then we need to.
So sorry my dog just came in the room.
I had to post a video.
But anyway.
So let's just do this and we're going to say ass
we'll give it a real name.
I mean what do we call it media overload
and end users
give with the controller admin media's controller.
OK.
All right that should be good.
Let's see Vallet row action
.
I mean media overload controller is missing the where the method is going.
I think that this should be going to overload.
All right.
Even though this should be going to store because we're going to be storing this.
So that's what it should be going.
All right let's try this now.
There we go.
So media
you
mean media in this.
That's an invalid view.
That's we're BHP artists and raúl list
in media and that is the name.
So we don't have it.
OK.
I think we don't have any admin guys.
Let's check real quick views and we don't have media there.
No we need to take them farther back here.
But for some reason I would to your raggie socks.
All right let's just create.
I was able to drag it before I don't know what's going on with my editor.
I don't know what's going on with my computer.
He says that's fine.
Add it up.
All right says I guess we'll copy everything from here to this fall here and then we'll delete the media
outside.
All right my bad guys.
So make sure that the media fall there is it is in there in the end that is there.
All right.
Cool.
There we go.
All right.
We shouldn't we were seeing something now.
Boy we need to actually show a picture.
So let's do that.
All right.
I'm trying to do everything in one lecture.
I don't know how you guys like this.
Let me know.
And
whoops there we go.
Oh those big with my face right in front of me.
I was huge.
All right.
Fifty.
OK.
All right look all the photos we got weaving up.
None pictures in there.
All right let's just delete this e-mail stuff there.
All right we got it going guys.
We really got it going there.
We got to work on this guy here.
We'll do that in the next lecture OK.
All right cool.
At least we got this going there.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.