All right.
Welcome back.
My students saw the last lecture we have our polls here and I wanted to fix this a little bit before
we go on Araya I wanted to actually have some type of category here just to show something.
And for now until we create the category and I wanted to also have a picture here you know let's just
fix it up a little bit.
Right.
All right.
So first of all let's go and fix that create
file that has the category there we have a an array here which with options let's just change this and
let's just say then we're going to have a value of one here and let's call this guy BHP or something
like that.
All right.
And
I don't know let's just say that we have another value here and this one would be Javascript.
OK.
Now if we go back to
create we can see that we have those two there.
All right.
So now we create a new pose my third post choose a file not a placeholder of this or I could say
all
right we can see that there are polls we have a category there.
So that's working.
We know that we just got it created categories later and pulao those pull it out from the database right
.
So for all we know that's working too.
But we are displaying a id so let's actually go back to in it's here and instead of photo ID we're going
to display that we also can display the category name here if we wanted to but we're not gonna do that
now.
All right instead of photo ID.
And let's actually create a condition here just in case we can't find the photo right.
So.
Image tag actually image tag.
This is put this in the source.
Oops.
Right.
And then we're going to say if Paul's photo is there.
Whoops I think it came out of there.
All right.
So post photos there
we display the photo name.
And I think that's the name that we have in a database or the title photos file actually.
All right.
If not then we display some type of placeholder.
Right.
I think we already have that.
We know we don't have that logic in the
in the user model do we.
We don't have the logic.
No that's OK then.
OK.
We're just going to put a placeholder here.
HTP
please hold it.
And like I said I recommend getting your own images as placeholders right because you never know when
the server is going to go down.
All right.
I want to create a height here of Honduras fine.
Let's see how this looks for a quick
refresh.
Whoops.
We have a variable here that does not exist just because it's post photo now photo pose.
All right there we go.
OK.
I think that's too big.
Let's make this 50 guys.
All right.
There we go.
That's OK.
That looks a little better.
All right.
OK what else we do need here.
All right we're good here for now.
We got the updated the body the title the photo.
I think we should move the photo to the front here.
Let's do that real quick.
So let's move this whole thing to the front.
After the ID and
here
category type of body.
OK that looks good.
All right.
That looks a little better.
We got to replace this little guy right there.
OK.
All righty.
All right.
Perfect.
I think we're done with this lecture here.
I'll see you the next one.
Take care