All right welcome back my students so let's make sure that this route is working and that we can actually
route the requests to our Controller.
All right.
So let's go here.
Our Terman on the say BHP areason route calling list that what we can see that you are I hear as you
can see they all have to be starting with admin.
And then the next world will be users and depending on what you're doing you have an idea you don't
have one.
All right.
The only one that doesn't have an ID is create a.
Here everything else like the show meant as an ID that destroy has an idea of the edit.
All right cool.
So the first thing that I want to actually make sure that his that is working is the end it's all right
.
So let's go back here to Amin Azmin const controllers and let's return the view for admin.
So if you remember we have a folder called admin.
Then we have inside users and then we have an index.
All right let's go back and check this out real quick so you can say admin users enter and yes you can
see is empty right now.
And that's because we don't have anything but let's just test it out real quick and let's just put something
in there resources we go.
And just put this it's working or something like that.
Let's go back Antar.
And as you can see it is working.
All right.
So beautiful.
We know that it's working.
All right cool.
So what is the next step the next step is actually to get a master Leo right.
That's the next step to do.
And what we're going to be doing is we're going to be copying some files that are going to give you
the last lecture because I have this special Basrah father's already ready with our admin styles.
Mariah we're not going to be dealing with a lot of styles in this course because this is not a CSSA
or booster of course.
By the time you get here you guys should know how to use bootstrap in some type of template so that
you can create you application discourses of our Laro in dealing with frameworks.
NASA says styling.
All right.
So I care more and more about the functionality of the website than actually the styling we can we as
a developer program and we can actually hire somebody for a couple of bucks and create a Leo and build
this crazy functionality in the back which will make us money we'll who will make our boss very proud
of us.
Right.
The functionality is the most important thing.
Now if you are a designer or a graphics person you can create is super easy if you're not.
All right.
You can actually buy one which are really cheap or you can even use the free ones out there.
So the next lecture we're going to download it right on the lecture and is going to be pretty fun and
I show you some really cool features and we're going to be installing.
No Jay.
Yes if you don't have it and giving you a heads up right now but don't worry about it.
I'm going to give you more details on the next lecture OK.
So make sure that all your routes your work song when I'm going to do is I'm going to we can either
write it all we can copy and pasted.
All right.
And we're going to say man that users create.
You can do the rest if you like.
Super easy stuff
.
All right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.