All right welcome back my students so on this lecture here which kind of Contini you some of the things
that is suggested in the upgrade guide.
Right.
So one of the first things that we are going to be changing is just go to the kernel real quick here
in the kernel we're going to have this error here just because we need to change this to another class
and I'm going to show you you can follow the guy guys.
We already got the application working.
It's just a matter of following the guy and changing the rest of the stuff.
All right.
My major goal for this section here was to make the application work.
So what's application work.
And then all we have to do is just do some cosmetic stuff.
All right.
So here is telling us that we need to change the can middleweights namespace.
So we need to go here to our kernel and do this change right here.
There we go.
All right.
Another thing that we need to change is the bindings and saying that we need to do this.
So let's go and do this and this should be the bind that should be re.
They should be in the middle where is
the middle where groups and middleware.
Let's go back here let's check it out exactly where it is
made aware group in your kernel to your weap made aware group.
This is my web made aware group.
All right let's just add it here.
This shows actually that those and go there.
Sorry about that.
Let's go back here.
Sometimes you've got to double check this stuff.
All right.
There we go.
Let's have this here and let's see these two the route me to where
I would go and make sure it has that single call there.
All right what else.
And then it says are you to add this to you A.P.M. in a way.
All right bindings.
It's this little one here.
And here we go.
All right cool.
I think we're good here.
Let's see
all
right now Dorise would change that already.
And she's telling us what it does by Indian substitution.
I think we're good to go here.
Guys you are.
You're welcome to keep playing around with this and making it work a little better for you.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching guys.
I hope we will get you up and running with your application.
We're going to keep adjusting some things in the in the application if you're able to fix some of the
bugs if we have any bugs posted in the discussion.
Help you a classmate to help the course.
And I'll see you in the next lectures.