All right welcome back my students I hope you guys are having a lot of fun.
I know this is pretty exciting.
When I was first learning it I was reading it really excited because you know I'm sure it just opened
doors to a whole new world of building applications and focusing on your creativity focusing on the
actually on the application itself instead of all the functionalities right instead of the complexity
because Lero makes it really easy.
But anyway on this lecture we're learn how to delete data.
All right.
So we already know how to do that.
Well let's actually do it with a form which is different.
OK so you're if you're taking any of my courses or some of the courses on line with procedural BHB and
some of the other applications within the stuff sometimes we put the idea on top right.
That's not a very good idea.
All right.
So in this time in this case we're going to do this as a post met requests actually delete requests
with Claribel.
So as you can see right here on your route list when we destroy an object or destroy a record we use
that the lead method.
And this uses of course post but we get to hit him feel as well.
Clarabell said delete.
So that way we can send that data securely.
OK.
So let's go back to our controller real quick and the Destroy is very similar to the edit and update
we find the record.
So we just find it and don't be lazy like me like I do right now.
All right.
Just write it down.
OK.
And once we find that we just go ahead and delete it.
Simple as that.
And if you have if you want to just delete certain things of course you can put the where method in
here.
OK.
And then you should return the redirect is super simple.
I don't have to even tell you how to do that one.
OK.
And we're going to delete two posts.
I mean redirect.
OK.
You can also do this here.
OK you can do this where Id calls this you just delete it.
That's it.
So you can save a couple of lines of code there.
All right cool stuff.
And you can also chain that up here as well.
OK.
You can make this very you know not many lines.
All right cool.
So let's go and try to update this.
Delete this all by the way we need to create a form I almost forgot.
So let's go to our edit form and just leave it like does this create another form right here.
All right.
And this is going to have an action of let's just check it out real quick.
They destroy.
Same thing as we have the edit.
So we're going to have less use take this out of here.
This small resolution here is killing me guys skilly me suppose.
And then we will pass the I.D. here.
All right.
We'll have an input.
Very similar to the one we have on tap because we need to tell a lot about that this is going to be
the least mad method instead.
The name is going to be method and the value is where we put the delete like this.
All right.
And we need our input submit.
And let's just create a value here that we say like delete so that what we know is deleting and let's
change the value on this and submit.
Here to say something like that.
All right cool.
So I think we're making progress here let's check it out real quick and see if it works.
OK let's click there of data BHB Let's update it.
It's updated.
Let's go back and delete it.
Oops.
OK.
Make sure that your form array has the method.
Pause here.
If it doesn't it's going to think that is a get request and we don't want to write a post.
Even though you still declaring this an alarm bell here.
All right.
As delete.
You still have to send the post because this is what a backup browser recognizes.
OK.
That's the only thing the browser recognizes the post and the get.
So let's go back here.
Refresh let's leave it as you can see is deleted.
Let's delete this one to delete it.
OK.
Of course we can created java of the Java to enter it go.
The IT.
Beautiful.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much I hope you learn a lot on this.
Couple lectures with the forms we're going to continue with some other forms functionality so that where
you learn how to validate and and create more advanced stuff.
It was a pleasure like always and I see you in the next lecture.