Welcome back to the students in this lecture here we are going to be updating our pretty or else we're
going to make it work right because in the new version we've got to change a couple of things just to
make this work.
So I found some documentation right here on hub actually.
And it's in this you are.
And it talks about a new version if we go back to our project here you can see that we have version
3.1.
So they did kind of upgrade it will not kind of they did a great upgrade upgraded to 4.0.
So that's what we need.
Let's see if he has the same name he says Rock.
Hello quants luggable OK.
So all we have to do here is just I guess change it to 4.00 and the composer of the I don't know that
would work NIXEY this.
All right.
I think it might fail because I think they have a new class that we have to think this class in the
class we got is not the same.
Let's just double check it.
Whoops I think I got an error already.
Let's see.
Yeah you see there's a different class.
So let's go back to app providers noise nothing apparatus.
Sorry about that.
In Conficker actually there we go.
So this class is now the same.
Let's take this off and let's try with this new class.
Copy that.
So this and let's see if it works b doesn't work we just require the whole thing guys.
Right.
No biggie worked.
All right so let's go and check out our composite Jason.
Beautiful.
It looks like it worked.
So what is the next change in the next change is OK publishing this from here.
All right let's see what what this does.
I guess this is going to publish a package that we need a file class.
So let's just say here let's do this.
OK I see it's a copy from this from the vendor folder.
This class here to this can fix luggable.
All right.
Let's go.
There we go.
All right.
So we got some.
I like this a lot better than what we have before because we can set our options here.
Pretty cool.
Look at this.
Has an option on update.
So let's set this to true because we know we know we need this update reserved.
If you are doing some of the leads and stuff like that you might want to do that unique.
That's true.
OK.
Matt lenth it's up to you but I'll go with what we got right now what else will we need.
All right so we need to use this guy here in order for this to work in our model.
So let's go to our post model whatever model you have you're using.
Let's go right here and
let's just replace those two there.
Let's take this implement out
and
we've got to use it right here.
Oh very cool.
And I guess this is not there anymore because I see that they have a method and we just use this method
.
Based the right there.
So I guess this is a log the source is the title if you want of this source that is something else you
put it right here.
I guess this is falling from the column name.
All right.
So this looks good.
What else we need here
.
Vince.
All right.
So this is good.
Let's check it out.
All right.
Let's see our application
and let's see if we can get this going.
Real quick.
Man is created post created polls so let's go here and this is created.
And let's just say that when Laro though course
recording faculty who
create.
All right.
So now this is where we see if it works.
And I see how it works cause is pulling from the slug.
But we have a problem here.
All right
fine by Sluggy is having an issue.
Let's see if we can find this into the communication.
Real quick
command fine fine by slug rice.
It looks like we need to add a tray a tray to it.
All right so let's come here and open this file here to see what it says.
I see.
So we need to add a tray to a less at it.
One of the sculp helpers.
Let's go to our models right here and we need to use it of course.
And just below here.
All right.
And then we need to use Let's just try.
All right refresh.
And this looks like it worked.
Now the reason why we're getting this problem is because we don't have an image in our.
Let's look at the post.
Go to your HPR I'm using sequel Prawle for Mac which is a pretty cool client for database software as
you can see here trying to pool forward those who have one.
So we need to kind of play around with that and set some if condition so that if he doesn't find a if
he doesn't find a photo or doesn't find a category we wanted to do something else if we haven't done
that you need to do that.
All right so let's come here let's do refresh as you can see it's working now.
All right.
So forget that.
You know try to get from a known object type of thing is because you're missing one of those fields
here.
I think he might be the category or the four to one of those in your index.
Let me show you for that.
That's the post we have.
Let's go to our control real quick and we have a controller for that.
Man pulls I think is this guy right here.
View Post.
All right.
So let's go to resources
views and then post
his other comments down here.
So this is the pulls up here.
It's full in the polls username post created for the file.
It might be a photo.
All right.
A photo file there.
If it doesn't find it then they might give you that.
I'm trying to pull from a non object type of error there.
So you might want to put a condition here.
If it doesn't have a photo file then replace it with this.
You know that's one thing that you can do or you can go to your database and make sure that this field
is not level.
All right this column.
So anyway so we got a pretty Oriel's working.
Pretty cool stuff.
Now our projects back to normal again.
There is nothing else that there is not back to how we had it before now because we have a lot of the
5.3 is actually a lot better right.
So we still need to create some more features in the cores and then you know I'm open for suggestions
we could refactor some code right now that we have created this project we got the major thing out of
the way right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this course guys and this lecture and I'll see you in the next
one.
Take care.