All right welcome back my students.
It's time for us to find out how to actually delete something permanently.
So now we have converged converter.
This application is now really an application.
Yeah but let's say for example it is right.
So we in our application we can actually delete an item anymore right.
Because every time we hit that the method is going to actually trash it instead of the leading it permanently
.
So how do we delete these items permanently take it off from the database immediately.
Well we need to use another method.
I'm not gonna tell you until I get there so I'll wait for me to finish writing.
Right.
And I.
I wish you can guess the name of this method.
You guessed it.
What is it.
No that's not it does not it is code for the league.
You're right.
Yeah you're right.
He is not.
All right.
But anyway so all we got to do right now is do the same thing with the here.
Right.
I'm just going to this time I'm really going to to do it like this guys.
And then all we have to cold is this guy right here for us the lead.
All right.
So let's do it.
Fours the lead Antar right there.
Why la.
Oops I forgot my worst.
Guys I'm so sorry.
I deleted everything that was is admen so it not only deleted the ones that were deleted but deleted
.
What's with with the is out of me is 0.
Oops.
All right so as you can see if you make one simple mistake and you don't pull that worst you can delete
all your data from the database.
Right cool.
Anyway you must be like pulling your hair right now because you had a lot of data and I mess you up
the night.
Well that's cool so that way you can write more stuff right.
Don't complain please.
All right.
Let's go ahead and create some data real quick.
Super easy.
We already have those met the guys.
Come on don't get lazy we create it.
And let's actually put a different one here.
Let's just put a number in front of it guys whatever number it doesn't matter.
Don't be picky right.
All right.
And then enter again refresh.
Right now all we've got to do is deleted delete one of them.
Super easy guys don't complain so much.
Please actually let's find number
that's fine we can do use of the leave method doesn't matter.
As you can see that solved the lead and this the lead is the same.
That's just fine number four.
In my case number four I don't know what it is in your case and delete enter refresh.
And of course is not really deleted.
So now
this forcedly is going to be used differently.
While we're going to do this we're going to say only
only trash items yes.
OK
Antar
and refresh as you can see only that the Leidy items that trash items were deleted.
So cool re.
Anyway I want to thank you so much for watching the series of the leading stuff were eloquent which
is pretty cool I think and I'm just going to show you some more stuff.
All right so in the next.
Stay tuned for the next lecture is going to have a lot more fun right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lectures.