All right welcome back my student.
So on this lecture what we've got to do is we are going to be displaying the categories right here in
the category names and we are also going to create the pull out the data pulao the categories from the
database and put them here and put them here.
All right let's try to do that.
All right.
So we are in post and it's right here as you can see and here was his category ID.
I'm going to modify this and I'm going to say if you find any category I want you to play it the name
if you don't I want you to display something like categorize it.
I think I'm spelling that correctly but it's actually telling me that it doesn't exist.
Is this now a very good ph B storm.
I know categorize I exist.
All right.
So categorize as you can see and then with flame ph B because that's what this one has in mind are opposed
.
All right cool.
All right.
Let's go to admin post controller and and create
an impulse control or create method.
We are going to pass in the categories so we're going to say something like categories and we need the
category model and the less we get a person the name and the ID makes sure that you you include your
category on top.
OK.
Obviously I already did mine.
But make sure that you import this right here.
Your category make sure you have your photo you pulls all this in poultry imported.
Now you're going to get an error OK but the error is easy rider error is very readable it's going to
say the app category does not exist.
The class category does not exist if it does not exist is because you're not including it.
So make sure you include it.
Let's use a compact
function here.
Very useful stuff.
And this pass the categories.
OK.
All right let's go to our creative impulse and right here.
This array we're going to change this a little bit.
We're going to make it a new type of array
right.
Going to take this off here and we're just going to say choose categories and we we've going to concatenate
the categories right here.
Check it out.
Create polls and we have supported open types.
That means this is now working for some reason and that's because we forgot this little guy right here
.
All Yep.
See that if I don't get any arrows guys that will not show you much.
But if I get errors it shows you how to fix it.
As you can see we're pulling out all the categories.
Beautiful beautiful beautiful beautiful.
Now let's let's choose another category here.
Clarabell is the bomb
right.
I love Florida well
and because it makes it easy for me
.
Leches to a placeholder there we are at the polls.
And as you can see we have a new category there are our application is taking place.
Guys is taking form.
And as you can see things are just looking really good.
All right thank you so much for watching this lecture.
It was a pleasure like always.
Keep it up.
Don't fall asleep if you're falling asleep.
Wash your face.
Get some type of natural energy drink or something.
Let's get to it right.
See you in the next lecture guys.