All right welcome back my students.
Just a precaution here.
And I just wanted to get you know make this lecture used to make you aware that when you're pushing
projects right you are also ignoring some of the when you push you to get help you're ignoring some
files.
I want to remember that if you go to get the ignore you are ignoring the vendor the mall use all these
files right here.
All right.
That you will need in order for you to actually recreate this in another scenario.
So for example you push just to get help and you want to actually clone that and use it somewhere else
.
You're going to need your vendors your money is you going to need these files.
OK.
So if you're working on this yourself take them off OK take them off.
And as a matter of fact you can take all of these off if you're working on those files yourself.
I don't recommend taking this off though you can recreate that in the other.
In the other application.
So just take all these off and and you know blow those files.
The reason why we take these off is because those vendor files these are these are a lot of files in
there.
I remember the vendors have all the dependency That's a lot of files for you to be pushed in to get
help.
OK.
Of course you can you know recreate those files into other application.
Just be aware that you need those files.
You don't need to know this if you're working on that yourself.
All right.
You can recreate this in other publications as well.
Remember that you are also ignoring this file here.
So when you try to clone this phone the other side.
All right.
To an operation you're not going to have all of this.
You're going to have the example here.
All right.
So remember to save this as this and then you change your.
You give access to the application to that database.
All right.
Also you're going to need to generate a new application key.
When you transfer this if you see the example here that simple doesn't have a key.
All right.
So you're going to need to actually generate a key and the rate the way that you generate a key for
your applications like this.
BHP areason key generator.
All right.
And that will create a key for you if you go to Beechfield is an issue should have it right here somewhere
.
Let me see if he has the command so you can see it right here.
You see that.
So you generate a new key and you're good to go again.
OK.
Just remember that you are ignoring these files just in case you have a problem and you try to clone
this project from somewhere else and you like OK this is not working.
Remember that you are ignoring these files.
All right you're going to need that in the next application.
All right.
So anyway now that we are clear I just wanted to make you aware of that.
OK.
Now that we're clear which should go on with the Course.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lectures.