Welcome back the students I hope you guys are having a lot of fun if some of you are frustrated.
That's OK.
OK good frustration because that's going to help you become better.
You get frustrated you try to find a solution to a problem you find the solution to your problem.
All of a sudden you are you become a better developer OK.
So don't worry about it's just a matter of time before you understand it or you have to do is just keep
practicing keep making the same thing over and over again until you find the solution and once you do
go through that period of frustration then you want to pull your hair out even if you don't have much
.
When you go through that and you finish going through that stage you're going to feel relieved because
you don't know the information.
OK so that's OK.
In this lecture here we're going to be learning about the many too many polymorphic relations.
All right.
And I don't want you to be here if you didn't understand the last relations.
Want you to go back.
I understand him even if he has to make a separate Laro Bell application right.
Even if you have to install a separate Laro Bell installation go back and create that project.
1.
All right so for example what I mean is if you're having a problem with our relationship let's say you
having a problem with polymorphic relations on the last lecture go back and create a new installation
of Clarabelle and just try that relationship until you understand it.
If you got a problem with one to one or many to many going create a separate installation Clarabelle
and practice that relationship until you get it down don't come here.
If you don't understand them because they're going to be very important for us to build any application
on line we're dealing with databases all the time.
So you got to understand relationships in Claribel OK.
All right.
So now we're going to be dealing with maybe too many polymorphic relations.
And we're going to be following some conventions and we're going to be also following so many examples
on the Larabee dot com Web site.
I'm going to give you some links here are the end of each section so you can refer back to that.
But anyway so we can to create.
We already have a pool stable so we're going to leave that on.
We're going to create a migrations for videos and we're also going to create a tags in a tag Abeles
table and basically many to many relationship for polymorphic relations are they.
They share a single list of unique records.
OK those records are I'm on you know the rest of the other tables.
So if we have a post in a videos
of tables OK they're going to be sharing tags in our little program that we're going to create.
Right.
Well not a program but this.
You know all this code that I'm showing you.
All right.
So anyway let's go ahead and do that right now.
So let's create a migration starting now let's clear our terminal.
If you are using the terminal cleared it out and let's do this now.
So we already have a post.
Let's create a video table by doing a migration so let's do BHB artisan OK make migration.
And as a matter of fact let's just create the model right away right.
Just in case we need it.
All right.
So the model will be video.
OK.
And hyphen M for Migration.
OK create it.
Now the next one would be tags so I'm going to press my up arrow key and I'm going to see a tag Antar
.
All right.
So we have the model and the migration already together.
All right so the next one after that.
Believe it or not it's going to be the toggles.
Right.
And that's going to be another table and I'm just going to call it like this game.
All right.
I'm going to create a model and the migration even if we don't need it later that's OK.
All right we have it there.
Beautiful.
So now let's go undefine those migrations and let me take this off.
It's opened up a little bit.
Let's go down to app City.
Nice TTP.
We need actually database migrations and let's start with the whoah.
I don't even see them yet.
So let's do synchronized real quick.
All right.
So let's start with a one on top first the videos.
So the video the only thing that we are going to be adding here is a name column OK for the video name
and for the tax table we are going to be adding a name that's well bring me.
There we go.
Now the target was this is where the fun begins.
All right.
So where are we going to be relating the post and the videos with attacks is by creating this column
C or in the target.
Right.
So we got the we don't even we don't even need this increment here.
To be honest with you.
OK.
So all we need right here is table.
We could however how the target will have an incremental ID as a matter of fact if we wanted to.
But that's ok i don't we don't need it here.
So this is going to be an integer and this is going to be called the tag ID with this
array.
Now then that's when the table is another all integers.
All right.
And this one would be the target ID.
Now explain to you in a minute.
Boy you know I'm trying to spell it correctly guys.
And the next one is Tiger will type
Tiger will two G's actually type and I hope you see
right now and we don't even need a time stamp guys.
I just leave that there all the time but we don't need that.
And an extra feel for no reason.
OK.
So I hope you see how we can relate them now in a way here.
We're going to have let's say the tag ID that's in the tax table here we're going to have the taxable
ID dummies.
Let's say we have a video with idea number one.
That's where this is where we go OK in there.
Here we're going to have the model right.
The target will type.
So he's going to be a nap backslash video.
All right so we're going to put the model in our column here.
OK.
All right.
Perfect.
So the next step here is actually making linking everything with functions or methods right in the models
.
So we're going to do that in the next lecture just to keep things a little divided that way I don't
overwhelm you with information.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture and I'll see you in the next one guys.
Take care.