All right welcome back my ideas stood and so we got our admin working right we got this admin adding
here just to let us know that we are actually receiving this view properly.
All right cool.
So what we're going to be doing now is creating demat or mark up for the rest of the views.
So for the create for the editing or for users.
All right well we want to do is not hearing Adam and we're going to know we're not going to work on
dashboard right now.
We're going to leave this dash for maybe for last for the for laughs for the for the course because
we can incorporate a lot of features here later on maybe some you know users settings or post settings
or category settings or something like that later on.
Right now what we want to worry about is users.
So that way we can create users we can edit users of the users polls and categories and all that right
.
So let's get to it right now.
All right.
So let's open up your editor open up the project and let's get it going.
So let's go to resources real quick.
Resources admin users.
All right.
So we've got to worry about this guy right here.
This is where we are going to be showing our users so we already have the resource for that right.
We have our methods our control is set up for that.
So if we go to your app it's the ATP controllers we've done.
We don't actually have the users control it do we actually we do right here.
I mean users control is all we have that.
Ok cool.
So now if I go to admin users
OK we have a blank page.
We have to set that up.
All right.
Let's go to our admin.
Actually we can do this by hand guys.
I'll show you how easy it is let's just do it.
We're not going to copy and paste.
Let's just do it like this.
OK let's do it stands here.
And we're going to stand the layouts folder is going to be the admin file.
And then here we're going to your Say section.
It's going to be content and stop or you can put an section.
All right cool.
And here we're going to see users.
Let's go now and see what we have.
Whoops.
Make sure if you bring another tour guys make sure you save your documents.
There we go.
All right cool.
So now what I want to do is actually get something going here I want to see something happen.
So if one of these early users we got to actually bring the data.
All right.
First I want to create some type of table here.
Let's see if I can see right now if I type table and tab.
I don't get much right I just get an hour and a beginning and ending tag for table.
That's not good.
What I want to do is every time I type table I want a whole table layout.
So for that let's go online real quick and let's just say bootstrap table.
And I think these people here are W3 school has a nice table that we can just copy but we're not going
to just copy it we're going to make a Templi out of it.
So let's see this tape was fine.
All right.
OK.
So
all I can do here.
All right.
So let's go over with them here from the table.
Copy it.
Come back here.
We're going to paste it in here.
All right.
As a matter of fact let's go to a file BHB storing preferences or settings depending on what OS you
are using.
It's typing here live templates and we all go to user and listservs add another live template here I'm
going to pass all that coding here.
All right.
I'd like to have my tags a little bit more to the to the war.
There we go a little bit guys.
There we go.
And that is going to be table an array bootstrap table.
OK.
And the fine the amount and BHB.
All right cool.
Fine
no.
OK.
All right plie Let's check it out real quick table.
There we go.
Now we have a table.
Really cool stuff right.
So now we go back.
We should have a really cool table that we can always
see.
All right.
So this is what we're going to have our users display when have their ID their name whatever information
we have from the user right.
So let's go back to our controllers.
Let's go to in there real quick and Ryabkov.
Here we're going to say when I say everything on a variable and we're going to use model here use or
find or fail.
And as a matter of fact the way we're going to do this is like this we go can actually display that
off and I actually want to display all users actually.
And what I was going to do is we were going to only display the users I would log then but we're going
to do that for other roles out there for subscribers or other one of these play them.
All right but we're not going to deal with users when we are doing with when we are using another role
like Alter for for Polsce we're going to actually you know display the polls for the use of those logged
in for all their roles.
But for this admin here we're going to display all users.
So user.
And when you're going to say all OK and let's include that clouds on top make sure that you import it
with its name space.
And here we're going to use a little function I showed you about earlier a long time ago a lot of lectures
ago called Compact.
Now let's go back to indebt and we're going to start displaying this stuff here.
So
I'm going to use this as an ID.
This would be the name the email.
And what I also want to show that's about it for now.
All right.
I'm going to take all this out
.
I'm going to wrap.
I'm going to actually do a statement here just to make sure that we have users right.
So if users then I want to actually execute this code right here.
So let's just say and if we're to end the if statement.
OK.
And now we're going to do a for each year to loop through that and take the object out of there.
Let's end it for each right here.
Ok cool.
All right.
So now here this is the idea of the users are we going to use Belaid and we're going to say user ID
.
The next step is
a
user name
.
Right
User email.
And let's see how it looks.
Let's see if we get anything.
All right.
Answer.
And as you can see we got the idea of the user which is Coralee one the name and the e-mail address
.
All right cool.
You know what it would be nice to together created the soil.
So let's just do that here.
And I don't know why I get my indentation all messed up here.
Some reason create it and update it will do that too as well.
All right cool.
So you see that every time I do mind intention it's messing up a little bit.
I got to fix that.
I think I know why.
But anyway let's create it at
and let's do
it.
All right.
I've got to fix my shortcuts in this copy of sublime sublime BHB storm enter.
All right cool.
All right.
And this is just a an example guys lead on.
As a matter of fact let's do it right now.
We can use methods on the time stamps right with carbon carvings are including Lavell Mbai defaults
and I'll show you.
I showed you that already a lot of lectures ago where we were.
Time stamps are a can be can be used as instances of carbon where we actually use or met carbons methods
to do other things with it.
Right.
So for create it we can say we can use a method called Let's do this for humans.
Hopefully I'm spending it right.
I'm not though.
Whoops.
For humans to underscore this is correct here.
All right let's do this one too.
Now if I go back there and I refresh we can see that this was created 15 hours ago.
Cool right.
Instead of having that day there we just say how long has a has been created.
I think this is pretty cool.
All right.
So I think we are done with this plan they use her for now and we're going to continue with his lectures
in the next one with this subject.
Take care.