All right welcome back my students I hope you guys do not cheat.
All right.
Because I'm counting on you to actually do that from scratch you guys or I and you I hope you're not
laughing thinking.
You know the one the guy who's laughing is the one that cheated.
All right.
So anyway what am I talking about.
Well easily you could have gone to.
Use controller right because we already did this and you could have use copy and paste of this stuff
here basically.
All right.
Hopefully you did not do that.
I want you to learn OK.
All right.
But anyway so what we want to do we want to find a poll so we're going to say full post
if we can get it correctly here.
Find for fail.
Geez what's going on with me today.
And this lecture actually because I was fine.
All right.
So we find the polls.
Let's just give it a variable here.
We find it and we can delete it right away.
So let's actually do that real quick.
Let's see.
Let's just find it in the lead it.
All right.
So once we delete it from the database I don't think we need that.
We don't need this guy right here.
What's with the data from the database.
We have to link the image or delete it.
No I don't know why they gave it the name on the link.
All right.
We're going to use a function here called public path and we're going to concatenate that with the As
a matter of fact.
We do need that very well there.
This is the reason why we need it right now.
So we're going to say post photo file right and beautiful and we can redirect
to what womenfolks.
Cool.
I think we're good here guys if you want to do the flashing you can all rise up to you.
I'm going to live with the way it is.
I don't leave that to you.
All right.
All right cool.
So this is post number two.
Leslie one of these lists this guy this on categorize.
So this is both number.
Number two actually.
That's the same one.
All right.
Delete her doing.
Oh polls OK was able to the.
But we got a error there with property something there for some reason.
Let's see something here.
Let's go to public images.
We get a bunch of placeholders.
Let's look at this guy javascript this.
Click on delete and online one eighty.
Trying to get trying to get prompt in an object.
And let's get the numbers here again.
Post Oh I see what it is.
We were the lead in the polls before and then we can find the relationship of course because of polls
already deleted.
All right.
So once we all link it then we've got to delete it.
All right that's cool that's fine.
All right.
All we can do it in one line.
But of course if you think about it if you delete the polls how you're going to find a picture for it
right.
OK.
Let's go back in and try this again.
Are we running out of polls guys.
We are running out of polls.
Well I guess we'll know if he's the leader because we only got one left.
All right so he's working pretty cool.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much guys for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture