All right welcome back my student.
So on this lecture I'm going to talk to you a little bit about controllers or I maybe a lot.
But anyway I don't try to divide the lectures so they don't get to be too long.
But anyway so what our control is what we talked a little bit about the let me show you what they really
are.
All right.
So controllers are the middleman.
Where are they.
First of all they are located on their app HTP and then controllers on this for their right here.
Now you can have a subfolder for all the type of controllers or I know you can just put other controllers
in there.
Usually we have them on their controllers.
And there is a law robo calls with one controller as this version specifies here controller.
All right.
So if I double click it this will be a controller.
Now this control might be a little different from the rest but because this is the main controller.
But let me explain to you a little bit about maybe a key word that some of you have not seen before
.
Namespace and use.
All right.
So what is a namespace keyword versus what does this do.
Well namespace in those four functions in class is wide scope scope does for variables basically allows
us to use the same function names or class name in different parts of the same application that we have
without causing many problems.
All right.
So for example let's say I have a function called I don't know run this query.
And then I have another function Colver on the square in the same application imagine what would happen
if I call the same function name in the same application.
I would have a problem.
They speccing what we can do is we have a namespace like this right namespace and we get we get to say
OK I'm going to have this function.
The first one called.
Whether we say run this query we're going to have this function run this Querrey all right or we're
going to have this for the core functions functions one.
All right.
So we have a namespace for that.
And this is where we're going to be finding that Randy Square-D function for frankly under the directory
function functions one then the next function.
We can do it in the second directory functions to just see that.
So basically what you're going to do what we do is we organize those functions in different parts of
our application even though they have the same name.
We use a namespace to differentiate the functions.
All right even though they have the same name so we don't have a collision.
All right.
So space should be clear if not go and look it up on line or you're going to find a lot of information
use.
All right is to import that specific class or namespace to this scope right here to this file.
So if I want to use this everything that's here.
All right in this file I will use use or it will import that class or that namespace to our coring file
so we can use that functionality.
That's why I used us.
All right you going to see that a lot in Lero Bill.
All right.
But anyway let's get it over with the controller.
So now control is we can create a control it's super simple we can right click just like we create another
file new BHB file whatever and we can just say polls say and you got you got to follow this convention
of camel case.
All right polls controller and we just say and that say you create a post controller.
All right.
Now in Clarabell there is an easier way to do this to create a controller and it's using a terminal
right here ph bipartisan or the command line tool BHB artisan.
Let me just delete this.
I'm going to reichlich it and I'm going to delete it.
Right now if I use BHB artisan and this little tour right here this terminal in PH BE Stormy's is sending
us using the terminal itself.
All right.
We just have the convenience of using it right here inside BHP storing for those of you the happy HP
storm.
But I feel happy HP storm.
Get that your terminal and type in BHB partisan right make controller.
All right.
So as you can see undoing make Kallen controller all lowercase and this has to be done exactly like
this.
And then the name of your controller so Folse controller.
If I do it like this and I click enter it will create that controller.
Now if I go back to my door and I click it you can see that it is creating in fact double click it.
You can see that there already has a name Spey for me is importing the requests.
All right.
And I even have the class defined already.
So I just I just have to start writing my methods right here.
All right now I like to use it with the resource and the resource is something that I'm going to talk
to you a little bit about later but just know that the resource is everything.
It's like the crowd.
All right.
Create read of they deleting all that's good stuff.
That's what the resource are going to be.
Right.
So if I want to create a controller with all my methods let's say if I know if I have an application
that is going to to create read updating delete We already know that then I can do it in another way
.
Let me just delete this real quick and this time I'm going to use the BHB command to write a terminal
which is the same thing as a terminal here guys.
Right.
And for those of you who are using Windows the same thing as your command as you get a command prompt
right.
So I'm going to I'm going to do this.
BHB areason make Kallen controller and then I'm going to do this.
Hi and resource resource and then Pooles controller and 2.
All right.
Now if I click the sidebar here for those of you that have another editor you can just call it.
You can just refresh or application you should do it automatically though or I mind taking a little
bit to do some reason to refresh here and click synchronize.
No actually
let me do in your
resource center Oh he's already.
This is just not here in my application yet let me see if it is.
Now depending on your computer and your home.
OK there we go.
Now he's here if I double click it right click on this letter we're going to bring that down.
You can see that he created the resource for me created in index method that is going to display the
home page create method store method to save the information in a database to show the view to edit
and even of they and destroy.
So that's what we talk about what we mean we resource.
Right.
So this is a controller right.
And we can do a lot of things here this is how we control the information coming from the database and
go into the view and back and forth right on the next lecture I'm going I'm going to show you how to
use a controller.
OK.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture