All right welcome back I'm a student so on this section here we're going to create a many to many relationship
.
And it's if you remember all right if you remember from you know a couple years ago when we you know
we're learning about the many to many relationship we created three tables Well we had three tables
functioning right we had the roles we had they were all user and we had the users table right.
Those three tables need to be related.
Right that's what we did before and that's what we do right now.
But we are going to be creating the crawl to create Read day and delete.
All right so let's open our our editor.
We still have the whole project here.
No worries.
Let's just open it open the new one many to many click OK.
This window does suffusing BHB storm if not you know how to open it with your editor or ID.
All right cool.
So the first thing that I'm going to do is we've got to set up our database connection real quick.
We're first we need a database right.
Let's do that real quick.
All right.
So let's go to PH be my admin here.
BHB my admin and let's create a database.
Many to Many relationship I mean database.
There we go.
That was easy right.
All right cool.
So come back here.
Many too many beautiful.
User name is root password is blank right.
All right.
So we need a migration right when it's on migrations.
So let's go to database real quick migrations.
We already have the users we need the rolls and they're all user call.
So one of those migration is going to have a model and that's going to be the role.
Right.
All right.
So BHP areason migrate and actually let's just create the first one with a model on the migration together
the roles table.
So Mario rule and then I am cool if i click here we get that table there.
All right.
Beautiful.
Now let's create a roll user table.
All right.
And I hope I hope you remember the convention that we have to follow Al explained to you in a minute
if you forgot.
All right.
BHB artist and hoops make migration.
And this is going to be 3:08 rule.
Use your tea room.
Go.
And it's going to be roll user Antar beautiful.
All right let's.
Let me explain to you before I forget to tell you this.
Remember that we have to follow this convention with Claribel that way Laura Bell can guess or know
that this is going to be a pivot table.
Remember that a pivot pivot table pivot table whatever you want to call it PIII the old t.
Right a lookup table.
So once you follow this convention with making everything basic first of all putting everything alphabetical
order.
So are you know is before they you so we do that right.
And then you're separating two words roll on the score user like that.
And of course we make it singular.
All right now roll users roll user.
That's how he knows it's a pivot table.
That way we can use it like that in Larabee allowable knows the fields the columns and everything.
All right.
So cool.
So now because this is a pivot table we need to give it the IDs of the other tables to relate them.
All right because this is going to be a many to many relationship.
All right.
So integer
and ashes to ashes and the first one is user ID that's by default looking for that and it's not tables
table.
All right.
Another integer and this one by the fold is going to be looking for roll ID in all the tables when we
create a real relationship.
All right cool.
You can make this on sign guys.
So it's up to you.
Just like a safety net.
You can make of all so-so to you and you can make it in there.
So he looks up this thing.
So he's faster.
All right so we can copy all this stuff.
We want to play this.
All right now just for demonstration purposes only.
I'm not going to make a big application.
I don't need all this.
I can have the index.
That's OK.
As a matter of fact let's just leave it like that.
It really doesn't hurt me on signed and just making sure that this function is good.
All right cool.
They're all stable we need a column here for the rules table.
We need a name for our rolls.
It's going to be a string type.
So we had good rules for all user user ID rule by the cool name.
All right cool.
Now let's do some migration.
Beechfield isn't my great answer.
Beautiful.
Now verify that this has taken place in Europe.
Friedman says you don't want to be migrating to another table.
Right.
So many to many if you click on it you got all your migrations there.
Beautiful.
All right.
So the next lecture we're going to continue with this couple with this new section.
And I wish you the best and I hope you are learning and having a lot of fun guys.
It's my pleasure to teach you.
Thank you.
See you in the next lecture.
Take care.