All right welcome back to the students.
So you guys know me I'm mad when the S and on this lecture I'm going to actually describe to you what
Larabee is and why NBC really is.
Because I really don't know who's taking this course right you might be it might be your first time
taking this course and you're very new to NBC or are you very new to framework's So you really need
to get a foundation on why really we are actually teaching this course right.
So let's start with what is Claribel.
Well Lavell if you look it up on search engines out there you're going to find a very similar definition
to this Largo's a b b framework who uses the NBC architecture.
Now what is a framework.
Well a framework is the underlying system is the methods the classes or the files that makes up for
that install.
All right now what is NBC what we're going to get to that in a minute.
What is architecture.
Architecture is the design pattern that has specific framework Hass.
So in this case Lero those following the design of MVC.
Now let's go ahead and find out why NBC actually is.
Let's break it down is break down the M the M stands for model divvies stands for view and the C stands
for controller.
This class is the models are going to be classes their views are going to be methods and we are also
going to have some classes depending on what we're doing.
But mintage right so most of the stuff composed compulsive classes guys every time we talk every time
we talk about framework we were talking about the data classes for a lot of things.
Remember this is O.P. object oriented programming.
Right.
So the controller is actually our classes as well.
All right so now let's break it down a little more.
So what is a model.
All right a model deals with database.
It's a class right.
In this class let me just give you an example.
If we have users in our application we can have a users model right we can have a user model that deals
with everything that has to do with wearing that database for that specific table of users so that we
have a users model and we also have a users table.
Every time we have a model we always most of the time we always going to have a table for that specific
model.
So we have users we have a users model and we have our user stable if we have posts we have a post model
and we have polls table.
All right.
So what is the view.
The view deals with the e-mail.
So we got everything that you see on your application in the browser is going to be a view that is going
to be the representation right over our application the view controller they control is the middleman
that control it deals with the views and the model.
All right.
The controller talks to the model and says Listen Moto I need you to pull all the last names of the
users table give me the last names of the users.
And then once you give it to me I'm going to give it to the view.
That's why the controller does right in a very in a nutshell this is what Larabee is.
And this is why NBC stands for.
All right.
So there you have it.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
You're going to get this down a little more.
When you're going to be able to digest a little more and actually find out exactly how you know we call
Laro then why allowable really is once you start coding you won't find how and why NBC really is right
.
Anyway thank you so much.
Hopefully this.
It's pollination pronation here we make your your mind at ease We'll make everything more clear for
you OK.
Thank you.
And I'll see you in the next lectures.