All right welcome back my students on the last lecture will get a lot of stuff done right.
I mean we did it migrations we had a bunch of columns to it.
We created the model on this and this lecture right here we're going to start creating the relationship
.
And we play around with the routes.
All right.
So for the post we're going to say that impulse has a lot of comments right.
That's what we're going to say.
So let's do public function and comments.
OK.
Well you know return.
Whoops.
This has many posts.
Right.
Cool.
All right.
So and comments by.
We're going to say that and we we can actually start creating the fillable as well.
But here let's finish the relationship real quick.
We're going to say that this gentleman here has many replies
so return does
many replies.
Comment reply I believe that's the model that we created right here and we can say that.
OK that's fine for now.
Let's create a.
Let's start right here.
The Master Simon protection.
And I know for sure we have all the comments we have post ideas.
We have Oerter.
We have e-mail.
We have a body.
I believe we have is active and let's see what else we have.
Let's let's go back here.
Whoops that's not a
true e-mail body.
I think that.
Let me just take all these out real quick.
All right.
That's for comments.
Let's go to come in reply.
We are a similar fillable here.
This one's going to say comment Id here and in-common reply.
We can say public function comment we can say that this guy little guy belongs to a comment
belongs to a comment.
Whoops.
Just in case we need him.
All right.
All right cool.
So let's go and Bill the route.
Maybe later on we have to come back here.
But for now we're done with this.
Let's go to routes
and we already have their routes actually for it so we're good we're golden here for comment controller
.
What I would need the controllers.
All right let's create a quick
way.
We do have the controllers.
Let's create Let's just say BHP is an make controller and the first song is Paul's comment controller
but we're forgetting the resource
resource.
OK.
All right.
Let's create the rests.
This one is going to be called meant
replies.
Controller.
All right.
And that's it for these lecture.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next one.