All right welcome back my story.
So you start for us a story actually of dating this right using this.
So let's go to the comments replies controller and let's try this logic right here.
So we're going to say Come my reply find or fail and then we're going to do it right the requests.
Very simple stuff.
We're going to redirect back.
Make sure that we return that.
And let's check it real quick.
All right.
So it's working now.
All right cool.
Let's go back here.
So if we don't approve this we go back here we're not supposed to see it but we are seeing it.
All right.
So that logic is in control or admin.
Post controller and re-impose is where we have this logic right.
Well actually no we have this logic in the form.
That's how we are.
We're showing the replies in the form.
So we only want to show the forms if there are active for that we need to actually the replies.
We need to actually write that.
All right.
So let's go to resources and polls.
So we need to write a little bit more here a little more condition.
Would you say if your reply is
active
if it's actually equal to one then it's active.
One is short.
So
this is to comment
.
And if
it does that the fear this if this is the media yeah that's where we want to be.
All right
there we go.
So now if we approve it and come back here we can see that it works
.
That's looking pretty good guys really looking good.
Let's work with the delete method.
All right
let's come and reply.
Fine.
Fine or fail.
We'll delete the answers to your
return.
All right
Joe.
Redirect back.
Well let's set a
statement here for some reason those and find the
oh he's just going to say no replies
.
I
see that.
All right we've got to make sure that we are sending this to the right place.
Delete.
Let's go back to that show reply show replies in this show meant the page that's in Sayad men come comments
replies and show where I hear OK guys don't get lost on me I know that there is a lot of files out there
but.
All right.
So we're sending this Samit polls sending this woman to the wrong place.
That is Troy.
We've got to send it here.
There we go.
So now we try that.
We fresh.
There we go.
All right now let's check those few comments.
All right let's create a reply real quick.
What if we wanted to have a reply for this guy right here.
We don't have a button here for him right.
I think that Biden should be available outside.
It's disappearing.
All right so we need to put up an outside.
Let's go to polls again and.
Well we'll find a place for that by next lecture OK.
We're able to delete replies.
All right.
Approved them approve them and all that.
The next lecture will go ahead and it fits up.
And as a matter of fact take us a challenge.
Put this bun somewhere that is not here.
And when we you know when we don't have a reply that is available all the time.
So do that on the next lecture we'll compare cold.
Thanks