All right.
Welcome back my district.
So let's get going here.
We're going to pull out information from the database and populate this field here.
All right.
So first things first we got to make this a select.
We gather all idea right here and we know that we're going to have an array right here right whatever
that is.
So we could right now make it empty and we can say something like
choose options.
All right.
Let's go back here and see what we got.
There we go.
But now what we want to do is we're going to use a new method here.
We're going to concatenate another array coming from the database right here.
All right.
So let's actually well is we've got to convert that into an array.
I'll show you how do we do that.
Let's go to our controller actually right here.
I mean user's controller and he's going into being our creator right here.
OK.
So first of all let's pulao rolls by this rule.
All right.
Now instead of using all because all is going to bring that collection which we don't one there we want
an array.
We had to convert that into an array.
We're going to be pulling out just specific data from there.
All right first of all make sure that you include this on top this namespace so that where you can pour
that class and I do this and import it on top.
And we're going to be pulling out the title and the ID into a likely in a array.
Now if you want to actually find out exactly what you're pulling out how this works.
Make sure that you do a return or I or or die.
Dump this so that way you can check check it out.
All right but that's what we are doing here.
And then we'll take that in with ticketing as it rolls.
OK let's go back here and here what we're going to do is we're going to call Kartini and we can do this
here.
We're going to concatenate roles like this.
All right.
Let's go back let's check it out.
Enter and and column title.
OK.
That's because it's not title is actually names or name actually.
There we go
.
I think there's something here.
Oh I forgot the method to actually bring it down.
We've got to bring it out.
We're going to bring it down OK.
We could use all here because this is just getting an array but we have to bring it back right after
.
And still not working.
Constant rolls and he's on to find custom rules
.
The rule.
Let's go back to the users create real quick.
And the reason why because we don't have the dollar sign of course and are as you can see the arrow
is in create Antar.
There we go.
And now we have a minute trader author and subscriber.
So let's actually speak there real quick real quick just to make sure that we're getting the right value
so we see that we've got one for me initiated two for author and three for subscriber.
OK.
Make sure that you have this in the correct order because when you bring it down if you have this idea
first and your name the second it will not work the same.
So let's say for example here and here if we go back here you see that everything changes now is backwards
.
OK.
We don't want to do that.
All right cool.
Anyway so we are done with this on the next lecture we're going to continue and work more on the controller
area.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you then.
Take care.
It was fun right.
All right I thought so.