All right.
Welcome back my sister.
And so one thing that I want to address here before we jump into another section is having the image
here so that what we see right what right now we're able to edit the post when I get to see what kind
of image she has and unless we go to this section right here so it will be nice to do that.
Let's go to our posts
to this for us and
fuse and pose.
Let's go at it all we have to do is divide this form into well this page will have the picture here
and one side and then we'll have the form in another side.
Right.
Take that out there from there.
Actually let's leave that there and
put this inside.
Now you
have another flaid here
and then we'll close it right here
with the image right here and we'll give it a class actually of I Am G responsive
.
All right let's check it out real quick.
All right cool.
Should make this a little smaller right next to that.
Let's just make it three.
I guess this will be nine.
All right.
That's OK.
I think that's OK.
Right.
All right cool.
That's all we wanted to do in this lecture.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture