All right welcome back to The Last Lecture.
I was a little tired I didn't want to deal with this but this is active error that I got in the last
lectures because of my form.
I have this status all right and this should be active on both on three places actually on both places
here.
All right.
Sometimes I call this status if you're taking any milder courses.
You know that in a database I call this status but it's you supposed to Callie's active because that's
the name of the column right.
All right cool.
So now if we try this we go ahead and refresh this and try this in our image and we try this.
Well first of all we need to make sure that there's some type of data there.
All ID needs to be there us well we've got to put the past where again as you can see now it goes in
.
Now if you were able to submit it with a file you're going to see that this is going to produce an array
All right.
An empty array.
Let me just show you
now see that file in theory.
All right.
So let's go to the controller I mean use this controller here and let's just figure out well what are
we going to do.
All right.
We know we're going to have photos in the user right.
This is going to have for us so we need a photo table for that for now.
What I want to do is I want to show you and remind you real quick how to persist data.
All right to the database.
So now all we have to do here guys.
If you remember is called the user model or well use user model and used a method like this.
Requests.
Oh.
And that's it.
Right now the problem with this is that we're not going to get the pictures.
We're not going to get the files.
So let's redirect to out me users.
All right.
So
let's just get rid of that forever.
OK let's just put some type of name here use to get things going.
It's going to be a not status active
.
All right.
So we need that password for you for that.
But
I want to do
as I'm looking for some pictures here in my computer for for some other pictures would be useful for
us.
That's ok I guess we're going to use my picture.
OK.
Let's use it use my picture and whatever password and create and as you can see we get redirected.
We get Jose name e-mail has no role is not active.
OK.
So now let's go back here and we get to see that we did give it a roll but it's not actually taking
that role.
Or I would give it a roll of other let's just inspect her a little bit and find out what happened so
we can see that these roll ID right here.
It has.
He has an idea.
This is the select actually
right.
We could see that it has a value to for some reason.
It was not it's not doing that in the database.
So let's go and check the database for a quick page.
My admin called hacking users.
All right.
So we can see that their all idea was not set.
For some reason the password was not encrypted so we need to do that.
All right.
This is working.
Everything else is working with a real I.D. is not working let's find out why.
Let's go back here and we can see that we are actually taking the real I.D. there.
All right.
So let's go to our main uses controller.
Let's go back and check this again just to make sure.
So if I try to do this again I think you had to refresh there.
Well you can see that there were all these actually being sent.
But it's not being assigned.
And let me tell you why.
If you haven't figure it out yet.
Remember what we learned about mass assignment.
Oh there you go.
Now you remember right.
Mass assignment.
So let's go to app user and let's make sure that that roll I.D. is in this fillable Ari.
All right.
So overall I.D. and whatever other stuff you want in.
Right.
What else will we have.
We have a status right.
Or is active is active wasn't working either.
They just said zero.
I guess that was the default and what was the other one
though that one was real I.D. is active.
That's all that the only two that we have.
Right.
And the photo ID.
All right.
So Real I.D. is active.
Let's just put the real I.D. right here as well
as
photo I.D. right here.
All right.
So now if we go back to our I mean use controller we can try this out.
All right let's try it out again.
See what happens.
All right cool.
Easy to forget stuff when you when you're new and you have a lot of stuff a lot of information you know
thrown to you like I am throwing it to you.
So according Foxhall to come.
We're going to pull Maria in the team.
Maria is going to be a subscriber this time and she is now going to be active.
We don't want her to be active.
We don't have any files on this one.
And just create the user as you can see Marie has been created she's a subscriber she's that active
and she was created a second ago.
That's beautiful guys.
All right.
Let's refresh here and you can see that even the old lady was entered there is active this time which
you actually made it.
So he was active to see if it was working right.
So let's go ahead and create another user real quick.
Let's just create a Peter.
He's always in my courses.
I don't know if you guys can tell but Peter and Maria and pin and Jose they are always in my courses
.
There we go.
As you can see these these guys act if I just wanted you to see that it is working ok.
Beautiful.
So we got it working on the next lecture we got to see how we can you know do some file integration
into this stuff.
Some file features.
Thank you so much for watching guys and I'll see you internet lecture