All right welcome back my students so we got the installation ready up and running right.
So it's time for us to demonstrate was time for me to demonstrate how easy it is to create a log in
system in larva is going to be pretty cool.
Let me clear this out real quick.
All right.
Put it down to the way we can come back to it.
Let's go and open it up right here.
Open and he's the logons right up here.
All right.
Cool.
Or I remember We'll get to create a database right.
So we have to create that database connection.
That's the first thing.
And we have to do the migration.
OK.
So let's connect that to the database first.
So let's open up our BHB admin actually go Beechfield my admin and databases and I call this Claribel
on the score logon answer.
Cool let's go to the DMV.
The EMV file.
Let's go here.
Genesis to well on the score.
Logan bruit
empty.
We go now we can come back here and we can say BHP areason migrate.
That's all we got to do for this one OK.
BHP Adisa and migrate enter they migrated.
Beautiful.
So we got the connection going.
All right.
We migrate or our table here on the next election going to show you how to create the logon system under
one minute.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture is going to be pretty fun guys.
So stay tuned.