All right.
Welcome back my students on the last lecture we learn how to create sessions how to read them right
.
So we learn also that we have a function here a global function call session.
Now we can basically do the same thing we were doing with our requests.
We can do it in this function here.
So when we can say something like
I don't know it could be something else I should add this goes like that
Master.
Or it could be Ed when you're your teacher.
All right ladies.
So we do this we can return that data.
Let's actually return it.
Let's call it out in another session.
LOL with a key one here like this.
And let's just return it
doing two.
OK let's give it a different key answer.
As you can see your teacher.
All right.
So we can we are looking at is this using our global functions as well.
All right now so we learn how to create how to even update because we can what we do is when we are
updating we we said that information we grab the same same session and we overwrite it right.
But we also have mentors like let's learn this Actually let's
show everything real quick.
So that way you can see when we delete it that it really does need it.
All right so again a show or Sessions right here.
OK as you can see this is a new session that we have created.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to need this specific Session right here as we enter with a key number
two.
All right.
With a key one two.
So what I'm going to do is to say requests session
and then we're going to use a mentor call forget.
And we're going to give you the key name.
Right.
And now when you go back and does the end should be out of there.
You see that.
Now if you wanted to read everything and that's cool too.
We could
and we got it and just use the flush method.
All right.
I like this nut flush enough flash but flush would go
done.
You see the that's beautiful beautiful beautiful beautiful.
All right there are there are a couple other mentors that you can find into the committee and if you
want to dig really deep into sessions there but for the moment this is all we need.
We're not going to be using da da da many sessions here in our course but this should give you a pretty
good idea how to do it right.
And the documentation should fill you in on the rest.
But anyway thanks so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.