All right welcome back my dear student so in this couple of lectures we're going to do this pretty fast
and we already done some of this stuff already.
Right.
All right.
So we have some tax inserted into our table right or tax table.
Now it's time for us to do something else.
All right well let's do it manually and create.
All right.
We're going to create this new post at the same time we're going to sign the tag.
OK.
So we have the post model right here.
So let's go ahead and do this real quick and we're going to do this pretty quick.
And you know why we might even do a couple of them a couple lectures in this lecture a couple of relationships
already since we already done this before.
All right.
So grab the post.
And we used to create a static method and we'll create a new post.
OK we'll say my name
and it's going to be my first post.
All right.
Let's actually also create a video.
How about that let's just copy all this.
And my first video and it's just a video a movie or something like for movie player.
And we will change this to reflect the video model and to do that let's just import that on top.
Here we go.
All right.
Let's create those two real quick.
And you know why the same time let's add some some stuff to it.
Let's find the tag for
actually the tag another Porsche.
Let's find the tag.
And this is it.
Find tag number one when a signed tag number one to this post right here.
So we're going to see pools safe actually.
We're going to see tags and then save.
OK.
And we're going to save that tag on top there.
Then we got to go and create a video.
Is this the same at the same time.
And also sign attached to it.
And this this tag is going to be I'm going to put in tag number one here and tag number two.
So this is going to be like this.
Number two here.
All right.
And.
OK.
When you say I mean see VDU
video tags
save.
OK.
And we're going to say tag number two in here.
All right.
I think we're good to go here.
OK.
I hope you see what we are doing we just create into our we associate it with creating a post and then
we associate it in tag number one with it which is the tag would ID know of one.
And right here we're saving it right and then we were creating a video and then we associate in tag
number two would ID number two of course and we're saving it.
All right cool.
Let's see if this works.
Hopefully we get some temporary so that way makes this a little exciting right guys.
I don't want you to fall asleep here OK.
So I don't think this is a seam.
No that's do poorly morphic many are we already had are there many too many.
And then create no errors.
Geez.
First post first video.
Look at that.
Let's look at Tagalongs anti-Bible.
So we got the tag uble for polls so that means we have pulse with the of one.
We have the tag I.D. société with that.
And here we have the video number one with a tag ID number two associated with that.
That's beautiful right guys.
I mean we really really created something really amazing in a couple lines with Clarabelle right three
lines.
This would take a lot of lines in native BHB right.
But anyway I think this lecture was long enough I'll see you in the next lectures.
And good job if you follow me.
All right.
Take care.