Hi welcome back Maria students.
This is Edwin Diaz from courting faculty in dot com or for Edwin Diaz.
Come.
All right.
Anyway so we we have been having a lot of fun in this course and we created one of the cool feet coolest
feature in this course pretty you or else.
Right.
And I probably blew a lot of minds out there from a lot of my ex my students from the courses right
from PH before beginners or you know from my BHP Olby course or my call igniter corps or and so on and
so on.
Right.
It's you know it's been very hard for us to implement prove to you or else in those courses right.
We probably have never done it because it does complicate.
They are so complicated to do right.
These vans features all over the place.
You saw how easy it was for us to had pretty you or else to in Arabic right.
Well I'm going to blow your mind in this lecture because we are going to be adding pagination.
All right.
And in some of my courses and especially that piece before begin as we added pagination but it was actually
a little complicated.
All right.
I'm going to show you how easy it is with Clarabell right how easy it is to you know they already created
the code for us.
We just have to use it right.
All right cool.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go to our controller and actually they are now odd impulse
control are going to take that off.
So our admen post controller.
All right and we're going to go to our end that's right here we're going to work on that.
All right.
So how about open but what we've got to be paginate ing here is folks anes Georgia to paginate whatever
you want in your application are not going to go through you users to categories or media or anything
like that to paginate the rest of their application.
That's your job.
I'm going to show you how to do it and your job to apply to your own application.
All right so we're going to be paginate ing for every two results because we don't have a lot of data
but if we have a lot of data if we had a lot of data for example like 100 pools I would paginate it
probably every 25 results.
All right every 25 items or something like that every 25 pools.
So let's create another pause here and say another cool pulls by Edwin D.S. from coring faculty dot
com for doing the dot com.
All right.
We're going to do a little category there are going to put my bootstrap picture course there and we're
going to say I love this pause from my Sensei
from my Ph.D. sensate create Polsce great.
We have three books.
So now we can paginate it right so we only going to be able to see two results here and on the next
page we're going to see the next result.
All right cool.
So let's go to him that's right here on this method.
In that thing at me impuls controller and right here what we're going to do going to change this all
for another Mentha called paginate.
And if I can't spell it correctly I don't even know what I spell there.
Paginate.
There we go.
And we're going to paginate every two results.
That's it.
That's all you've got to do for there.
But now of course if I go here and refresh you can see now that we don't see the other last results
right.
Because we are kind of putting our restriction here saying only show the tuples and then the next balls
you're going to show would be in the second page right.
So now let's go to our control our views.
So let's actually minimize all this would you have this mass.
And we are going to add polls.
And that's.
And let's do it right below here.
Let's create a diff with a class or a row and inside there let's create another div where the class
of call and it would be s am sets another class of let's give it an offset and of said we'd be I say
5.
All right cool.
I think that's about right.
And here we're going to use Belaid and we're going to say we can use the whole array.
The whole collection right pools.
And we're going to use another global function your call render we're going to use render like this
.
And now we go back here.
Voila there we go.
I pagination guys look at this page number two baby food pagination right there guys.
Right.
I hope I just blew your mind.
If discours does does not serve a five star for this feature long right now guys I don't know what does
.
All right.
So if you have not given this corps a five star review go ahead and do it now.
Anyway that was just I'm just joking but really if you haven't given it you go ahead and do it right
.
But anyway this is the simplest thing ever right at this time so far.
All right.
Super powerful guys.
Anyway I'm going to see you in the next extra features for this course and I hope you have a lot of
fun.
Keep a keep coding.
Do it every day.
Practice practice practice because if you're new to this.
This is going to be very easy to forget if you don't call for a couple of weeks.
OK.
So actually this will now be easy to forget but some of the stuff that we have been learning will be
forgetful.
So I mean we'll be lost in memory anyway.
Thank you so much guys.
I'll see you in the next lecture