All right welcome back my students so now that we know how to create views right.
It's time for us to learn how to pass data interviews super simple guys I show you a way to do it but
I'm going to show you and show you what to do with routes this way is very similar.
All right.
So let's actually create what we're going to be doing here is going to do with it.
We're going to do a couple of things.
First we're going to create a custom method.
All right.
And then we're going to create a view as well.
So let's actually also create a custom route.
So a lot of customization here right.
So let's say for example I'm going to come in this hour of quick we want our users to go to our post
and we're going to say Id here Colma and then is going to be in the post controller Porsche's controller
.
Conan.
And then we're going to create a custom method called Show post.
All right even though we already have one in the resource show meant that we're going to create a custom
one called Show post.
So now that we have our routing place right let's go and go to a post controller here and create that
method.
It's a public function.
Show pulls out.
Right.
And we're going to return what we're eating we're going to return and return a view that we haven't
created yet but we are going to call it post.
So this function automatically was search for any files with this name inside the views folder.
Joe's the views for that.
Now the sub folders so you don't have to put a folder if you already have one there.
So I'm going to create this file going to call it post that belayed that BHB.
Now you might be thinking why in the world the teachers do.
Well we created these Dadley file very similar to the contact page.
Everything has to be done.
But I'm going to show you in a minute how we can use this.
Real quick.
So let's do a
post here.
All right.
So now I talked a little bit about the Bley engine right.
Did I say anything about the Bley engine.
I said that the Bley engine is a templating engine while the blade function is a templating engine that
Laura Bell uses to show BHB to execute BHP in a very very simple way instead of actually writing out
the BHB tax we can just put curly brackets around it and there are all the mentors that we can use.
But let's actually do this right here.
So if I wanted to echo something out here I would just do curly brackets and the name of that variable
.
All right.
But let's go back to our post controller here make sure that we are passing some data right.
So we're going to take in a ID here and this idea is going to come from routes from right here.
All right.
And now we're going to pass it into The View.
So there are a couple of ways of doing it.
There is a function that we can change this code chaining right here.
We can change this function or method with this one here.
So we're going to say with is going to take two parameters the name of the variable and the variable
itself.
All right.
So now this idea very well that's going to come from there you are well because this is a GET requests
and you Arel is going to be available in this post view.
Why.
Because a pulse controller right here is opening a file and is passing in that data.
That's why this view function is doing all right.
So now we got to display here because we don't have it here yet.
So we're going to use the Shift key impeach the store and we're going to type in twice the left bracket
curly bracket and that's going to create this second curly brackets right curly brackets and we're going
to type in the name of that variable which is ID.
All right.
So now if we want to see this thing actually we got to do is come back here and say whoops enter.
There we go.
Post one as you can see we're passing data beautiful for up enter.
Haha that is beautiful isn't it guys.
We're going to have a lot of fun with this anyway.
So now there is a better way of actually doing this that I use my cell phone.
You want to pass multiple parameters.
All right this gets very ugly when you want to pass multiple parameters so instead of doing this and
let me just come in this hour real quick.
Copy it and comment it out so I can use a new one.
And I take all these out there is of a native function called Compact.
All right dot grabs the upper arm as you can pass as many parameters as you want.
But if I pass a parameter that has the same name as a variable that I have up here it will convert this
into a variable.
It will convert it into this variable right here and then we can pass it into the view this way.
All right so now if I go back you say does the same thing again.
Even though I changed it.
All right.
Why use that.
Why use this function over the with function because with it with this compact function I can do this
name and password or something like that of course you're not going past the password through that you
are now.
But you can let's go to routes and here we can say for Slash and this name and the past four you never
want to do that.
Right guys never do that.
And password.
All right and now we go to our view and we can say name
best for all right.
Forward should be good.
Let's go to our application.
Let's just write whatever here let's just write whatever undefined constant.
OK we have a problem in our pose controller.
That's because we forgot oh we didn't we didn't pass it in here.
We forgot this little detail name and password.
All right.
Now we go back and we refresh
view became pools that believe we have a problem.
Let's try this out
.
So Id name password this looks about right maybe a misspelled there or something.
I think it probably misspelled it.
Let's go to Paul's blade and oh we forgot the little dollar sign symbols there.
We can't forget about that.
There we go.
See that are three parameters.
So doing password one two and three.
All right.
Beautiful.
So that's how you passed data.
Two views using Clarabell which is pretty cool guys.
Right.
And we are also using the blade templating engine the larva use is called Blade.
Thank you and I'll see you next lecture's keep having fun keep playing around.
Practice practice practice makes perfection the more you write this stuff the more it is engraved in
your head.
All right.
Take care.
Bye