All right.
Welcome back my student.
I hope you're really motivated.
We are learning a lot of good stuff.
We'll are we going to keep learning more.
All right cool.
So we are creator our mark migrations.
It's time for us to start setting up the relationship and doing the math assignments set up as well
.
So let's open up BHB storm.
And if I can make this a little bigger that would be nice.
There we go.
I don't know how he was I guess I had a small monitor attached to my computer anyway so let's go and
set up our relationship.
All right.
And let me see something real quick to our relationship.
It's
true.
All right.
Cool.
So now in the User we got to go back to the user.
OK.
And we have to say Pawlick function roles.
All right.
Beautiful.
So here what we got to do is say return this.
We launched too many.
OK.
Rules now rules roll.
There we go.
All righty.
So this is good.
We've got users all set up now.
Let's make sure we have Master Simon on our role here Mario.
So let's say protect the and let me see if I remember fillable.
And the only thing that we're going to be editing here is and name call is set up already.
All right.
Remember that if you want to do the opposite and get the user out of roles you set up that relationship
right here and you can do all the stuff there as well with without relationship.
We might touch on that later.
But anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.