All right.
Welcome back the students so let's test now to see if our routes are working.
Right let's go and find out how in admin comments are right.
First let's set up a link real quick in our layouts.
So let's go to outman layouts.
And here we go.
All posts categories media it would be nice to have her right below here somewhere
.
All right.
We can say
comments
or comments and we don't want to create comment comments.
As a matter of fact we only have one page and should not even be dropped down.
We don't need a drop down for this.
You know let's put it real close to polls actually.
All right so on polls if we go to the polls we can find out if we have any comments on that too as well
.
I think that's a good place for it.
And this would be outman comments I believe.
Let's check it out real quick
that
problem incumbents Let's go to the control test is out.
I mean post controller looks like I don't have my controller here yet
.
There we go.
Here.
OK.
So let's return to see if this works it works.
All right
.
Hello again.
Oh that's right with the migration.
So make sure that you have provide new information now.
You guys should know how to do this already.
We register the user and we have to set it.
You say this is not fine.
So we've got to work on that.
But let's go to the database real quick and let's set up a couple of things.
First rule like the one active one.
Let's get the rolls going
.
All right.
Let's go back here.
So it looks like admin comments is fine.
Yes.
It is not fine actually because his abdomen comments and it's so let's go back to that lay low and let's
fix that up.
There we go.
So now right here in polls we can check the comments polls comments controller does not exist
.
Polls comment all because his comment controller for some reason I call that comment and I'm going to
delete that actually because I want comments so it should be.
Let's see if we can find that common.
Here
we go.
Oh I don't even have to read synchronized at this time.
That's cool.
All right.
So it looks like he's working now.
So
so that's the row and we're supposed to be returning something from there.
But
that's right we have a new country we just deleted that so.
All right call this return this one.
I'm pretty sure it works now guys.
All right there we go.
So let's set up our Simply real quick and
in our route in view.
OK.
So resources views we should have that are available somewhere here so that we're looking at pretty
quick comments.
It's right here stance layouts.
Hope you guys having a good days of really good day to be courting guys.
Remember though why are you doing this or why.
Sometimes it seems that things can be can look like they're very difficult but they are actually very
simple.
And if you got to this point it's just simple stuff for you.
You are already probably thinking about your next project.
All right.
So let's go back to here and let's return to our view
and the view and many comments.
And it's I believe
it will go.
All right.
So this is where we're going to be displaying our comments.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture