All right welcome back.
I'm a student in this lecture here we're going to be jumping right to the cold and find out exactly
what it takes to upgrade to 5.3.
First of all I want to show you some of the major components that are actually breaking our application
right.
So let me see let me come here and let's open up our project.
I've got my project open in BHB storm.
All right.
So this is the old application.
This is the old one I'm going to open up another one a 5.3 installation so that where you can see the
difference.
All right.
I'm going to open up and
you have a one here.
All right one thing that I don't want you to take a look too much I don't want you to be paying attention
is where I have my code.
My my applications because I'm using a different computer so you know from the last time from the last
lectures to this one.
All right before this section I was using on a different computer and all my files were somewhere else
.
All right.
So if you see my application that is a little in my file structure well where I keep my files usually
in this folder here Colden that stuff.
This is from another computer or I remember that in the last section I was keeping everything in HD
dogs.
I'm using another a different computer and doing everything in it in a different environment.
Right.
But everything else you apply to it.
You know like the everything that we're doing the application the same thing.
Are we using the same application.
I just got it in a different directory in my computer.
That's all.
All right.
So let's go to the application real quick we know that our application is working.
All right so if we go to call hacking and then by the way I'm also using a different extension so don't
worry about that.
I know you're using the Wii.
That's why we were using before.
I'm using dot AP AP which is just the extension guys is the same thing right.
All right.
So our application is working.
This is 5.2.
We still 5.2.
So if we go this is the new version but if we go to our version the one we were using we were a terminal
and we type in ph priorities.
And I feel high inversion.
We can see that this is 5.2.
All right.
We know that.
So let me make this a little small here because I want to show you the difference that Major where our
application where our application is breaking.
All right.
And why is breaking I'll say.
Right we'll take this off.
We don't need it anymore.
All right.
So this is the new Lavell right here.
All right have you noticed something different in this one.
While going to tell you right now drought's folder.
Yes.
Now we have a route's folder here in these routes folder in the new Lavell version has three different
files API that BHP cancels that BHP and that BHP went up BHP is where we're going to be keeping our
routes from now on.
There's no more HTP routes BHP there's no more class that does that is only the controllers the middle
when the colonel here nothing else.
And as you'll notice also they Apfel this seems very small right.
Look at this apple right here we have what is a listener's policies a bunch of other things.
Jobs does classes here are only created when we need them so in the new version 5.3 if we need a policy
we wouldn't we would create we would create it would appear to be artist in command and that piece Pre-OT's
in command is going to also create a folder as we need it.
So none of this stuff that we're really not needing here and this is actually empty.
You see that.
So we don't have any of the stuff here.
Only less is needed in 5.3.
All right.
So the major thing that's breaking out application is this route folder here.
These are basically our routes.
All right.
So we're going to we're going to do that right now we're going to fix this.
So let's go to our application and I'm going to go into this area by error.
All right just like you doing it yourself or you don't know what you're doing but then you got me behind
your back showing you to make it basically teaching you how to make it work.
All right.
So I'm going to be you and you're going to have me behind you telling you what's going on.
All right let's do it.
So let's go to compel composer composer Jason and we can see that here we have the 5.2.
Right.
Well actually right here 5.2 Lex Cheniere to 5.3.
And let's encounter our first error.
So composer of date that's what you got to do.
Right.
Now this is going to take a little bit.
So my puzzle video and you're not going to notice it but I just wanted to let you know that if it takes
you a while for you is taking me a while for me as well.
All right.
It took it took probably like 10 15 seconds.
But anyway you see the first arrow that we got here.
All right we got this script PH BE already saying optimize whatever and it's event service provider
.
All right let's go to event service provider.
Let's go to app.
That's where it is right.
Let's check it out in app and provider.
All right.
So let's go there now app providers event service provider.
So the first problem that we got here is that we have parameters right here in the booth.
We need to take that off.
All right.
And this is actually in the in the guy from Laro News where he Eric the creator of Lavoe gives some
examples here on what to do from when we are upgrading.
All right.
To 5.3 he says take of the parameters that we're now using those anymore like that.
So we take them off.
All right.
Great.
So we just took him over let's see what happens and let's try again compose or update
us.
My post video again.
It took a couple seconds and now you see that we have another arrow here Rao's service provider.
The first error was event service provider.
So he also tells us to take the parameters of this file here as well.
We now need those.
So we're not actually using the router here.
We go we take them off take this off and because we are taking this off now we don't have this object
right here so we need to actually call this startingly.
All right.
Play this.
All right cool.
All right.
Now I can see a problem here already.
Let's go up a little bit and here.
All right.
Since we using this route here we need to include it.
So let's see if BHB storm is going to help me out.
It looks like he's helping me out telling me which one do you one we want included illuminates a poor
facade route.
All right cool.
So he's there.
Now we don't need this one.
Take that off.
All right cool.
I know that I see here is that we have this.
This right here so this app path is telling.
Hey listen I want you to map all the routes to this class here and that's this class doesn't exist so
we can't really map anything there.
All right.
So what do we do when we map it.
That's the question.
I told you that all the routes are going to be now in the new folder right coal route.
So that's where we need to map.
Well we don't have the For that we need to include that for them.
As a matter of fact go ahead and download the folder in this lecture or I'm going to give you a folder
with the three files.
Go ahead and download it even though you can actually create a new lovely installation and copy the
files from there if you want.
All right.
But I'm going to give you the folder for the 5.3.
It's going to be on this lecture so download it and then copy those files to your project right here
to the root of course.
Right because the router is going to be right on their app actually not on the road map.
Right.
If we look at this installation right here we can see that route's is right actually not inside app
is actually outside sound the route that was right the first time.
Right.
So we're going to copy that right now.
I'm going to do it.
But let's actually come here and crowds
and this is going to be web BHB.
All right.
So now I'm going to go and try to find this in my installation somewhere.
So we got.
OK.
This is the one that needs it.
This is the one that has it.
All right.
So I come here I'm going to grab routes and Angle and to put it into a project that I'm working on.
All right cool.
So we should be here in a moment.
All right.
Still something wrong here with my provider files on thing.
OK I'm messing this up here.
Fix that.
All right let me synchronize this.
And yours might synchronize automatically but mine doesn't do it sometimes.
Actually right here ready.
All right.
All right so we have this file here and let's see right now what we get.
So let's a composer update again.
And that's where a little bit.
Ooh we got a big one here.
This one says listen answers fill opening routes that way.
Which path.
Let's look at the path real quick.
We probably made a mistake here.
OK we made it we didn't make a mistake.
This is supposed to be base.
All right let's try it again.
Right.
There we go.
Looks like it worked.
Let's go to a composer there Jason.
And is there 5.3 is there.
All right.
So let's actually check the version right here.
Beechfield is some version 5.3.
All right.
So we were able to upgrade it on the next lecture we are going to take a look at our application to
see how it looks OK.
Right now I'm going to go to the front end real quick and see.
All right.
So it looks good from here.
All right fine or let's try to go to admin and it says of course that page is not available.
Logon that page is not available.
OK
let's try.
All right slogan something there let's go to our route.
Let's go to the Web here that feeds file.
And let's just do something here to see if it works.
Whatever and save it.
Well you don't have to save that year and BHB storm and refresh it.
OK it's working.
All right.
We just had to figure out why are admins now working.
Well we already know we don't have a router right.
We don't have routes for it.
Well the problem with the routes now is that I know for for a fact that I'm going to show you right
now ph isn't let's just do it on this lecture thing we've got time.
We're out less without making this lecture 20 minutes.
All right.
So we don't have the routes here that we can go to route stop BHP and.
Well we still have our route so we can play around with here.
Let's try to go to adenine real quick
right here.
Let's create this route.
Let's go back here.
All right.
So now if we try to go to admen.
Or are we getting errors here.
Well these are easily fixed and I'm going to show you how to do this in the next lecture I'm going to
show you how to set our route.
So in the next lecture we're going to be setting our routes and we're going to make this work ok.
I just wanted to do the most I can on this first lecture without boring you without making this lecture
30 minutes which some of you don't like.
Anyway thank you so much guys.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.