All right.
Welcome back my dear student.
All right so we are kind of done with this forum right here from this guy.
It's time for us to start playing around with the controller right.
So first of all I want to ask somebody they been do this right.
That would be cool.
And we already did therefore create.
So we would create.
All we got right here is an includes file.
So we're going to copy that.
We're going to take it to edit.
As a matter of fact we already have it included here we don't have to do that.
All we have to do is go to our Controller.
All right.
And on our update we need to use the user requests user's requests.
That's all we've got to do there.
All right.
We already have an included up here.
So once we do that we can decimate data now on less.
Everything is filled.
Let's just refresh refresh here.
And as you can see.
Well we need to find a place for this error.
They are a better place for it.
As you can see you can tell that was missing there.
OK.
All right.
So let's go back and try to fix that a little bit.
That's OK.
Let's go to are at it
let's see where is breaking.
Everything is like that.
It would be nice to have this in a different row.
So we're going to get a class or row.
Let's see if that fixes the problem.
You can do that as well if you want.
If you have in this type of issue.
Right.
OK.
You say this is a problem.
Well let's go back here and let's see what else can we do to it.
All right.
Don't mess with Edwin and telling you right now because
I hate when that happens guys.
I really don't.
No one's going to write it down.
Just stop trying to be lazy typing and stuff.
And so you get used to copy and paste and you don't want to type anymore
or use indenting a little bit there.
All right.
So let's see if that works.
I just added another role there.
Hopefully that will do something.
As you can see did it help though.
All right.
Of course you can make the arrow a little smaller than now you can change it.
There is a lot of bootstrap style swearers.
OK.
All right but anyway let's go and go and play around with our users controller.
And here we're going to go to the update.
OK.
So let's test this out first and let's make sure that we are receiving all these data.
And we go
right now and they've been checking for the ID.
We should.
But this use this play something here.
There we go.
All right so it's working.
All right.
So let's start.
So the first thing that we got to do what is it.
Well we got to find the user right.
So we find the user and which is eloquent and we say fine or fail whatever use or this is all right
.
And that's our least we've got the user now.
That's OK.
Now let's check for pictures.
Well first of all let's grab the input for that.
And
I don't know what's going on with me today guys.
I think I need more coffee.
I see there are no
requests file and the name was for the ID I believe.
Yes.
OK.
So we check checking for the file we already done this as a matter of fact you can copy and paste if
you like but I would prefer for you to type it in and that's why I'm typing here guys because I want
you guys to type as well.
Right.
And we're going to come cottony with the name.
All right.
Now we just got to move this Whoops to images and we give it a name.
Cool.
All right.
This is good.
All right so we got to leave it.
We're going to leave this live this lecture for the rest of this for the next lecture.
More right now we have completed enough.
All right.
I think you have a pretty good idea how we're going to complete this but you're welcome to finish this
off and then compare your call with me in the next lecture.
Right now I'm going to go and get some coffee.
All right guys.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lecture.