All right.
Welcome back.
Understood.
So in this lecture I want to actually modify this a little bit and make it better.
I mean Admin this controller and what we're gonna be doing here we're going to create conditions for
password field just in case is empty.
And we also are going to fix the update method here which is not really hashing a password so let's
actually do that right now.
And what I want to do is I want to do something like this and I say if and this can be abstracted to
a method guys.
So if you want to put it into a method go ahead and do that.
You should know how to do that by now.
Right.
All right so if the puzzle is empty We're going to grab the input and we only get to pass cerned feel
to it when I pass all the fields at set password.
And this is a matter that a lot of guys.
All right.
Just in case I'm not making this up and we don't have this we don't have a custom method.
This is something that is built into the framework.
OK so if it's empty we've got to pass everything except the password field and that's a very useful
method else mean something is there and we're going to pass everything to it.
OK.
One thing here would be very good to do is trim.
If now you might have a problem with whitespace
so we trim it and.
OK you take this guy as well because if not we're going to keep doing the same thing we're going to
keep hashing empty spaces.
And we put it right here.
Right.
So we have something we encrypt a password and we include the fossil fuel of course and they encrypted
.
All right what else.
Let's take it to the let's take this out a year let's take it to the update method.
Right.
Let's go to the old they meant a quick and
last place right here.
You should have a request or somewhere here in the method that I did not.
All right.
Just just because probably I removed it.
Maybe I was editing the lecture or something and forgot to put it there.
But you should have one of those there when you were updating it right.
But anyway so we take the same thing back to the Dave method and we are hashing that password as well
here so we don't have to put it right here anymore.
All right.
OK I think we're done.
Thank you so much for watching.
And if you have an issues let me know.
Take care.