All right welcome back a student so we got the right group here.
We got everything set up except that we need to set up our admin class of course are made aware and
we also have to set up our.
I was thinking about creating We could if we wanted to do all the logic here.
But you know I don't want to feel the same with a lot of logic.
A lot of stuff I like to also create.
I like to create a class here a method is admin method that will actually detected the users and a meaning
shared or not.
So that's what I'd like to do.
All right.
Let's actually create a here and then we'll take it over there.
OK.
So let's All right let's do a public function and let's just call this admin.
There are a couple ways of doing this.
You know you can pass in the role of the user and validated through here if you want to create a function
that could do that for the rest of the.
You can make something like this check roll and then pass the roll and do all your validation there
.
I'm going to try to keep it simple and just give you an idea.
So if you want to do it like that you can it's up to you.
I'm going to do it like this because like I said I'm creating discourse in a long way the heart in the
way that gives you space for you to think critically about how you want your application and how you
want your code to be.
All right.
I'm just giving you the guidance I'm guiding you through how he's done I'm teaching you.
But I'm also giving your space to be creative.
All right.
Hopefully that makes sense.
But anyway so we're going to say if this role and we are in use are right.
So yes.
So we have a
role right here.
We can use this as a property instead of using it like this right.
We can use it like this.
So if their own name is equal to Administrator guys if you having issues with all this O.P. That's because
you need a little bit more all the foundation of your into programming foundation I suggest for you
to take my older course on object oriented programming so you can get a foundation and then after you
take that then you can come here.
All right I just I just wanted to make sure that you're not having issues just in case if you are that's
why you need more foundation.
So if we find an administrator we're going to Eckl Well we're going to return true if we're going to
return false call.
You're right.
So let's go to out me real quick and here we're going to check to see if and when I do a couple of alleviations
here.
If the low end user that's what we've got to do because we don't want this user to be now logged in
.
Right.
So we're going to do this validation and we also going to include even though the value that I'll show
you right now what we doing.
So we're going to check if the user is logged in.
That's ok I already show you how to do that right.
And then we're going to do another validation we're going to say if they or the user
is going to use our function or method.
OK.
Make sure that you include this off glass top here.
It's facade.
And
we've got to say return the net requests.
So that means everything went through.
Go to the next request of the application array.
If for some reason
this user was not logged in or something
returned to I don't know somewhere where she is returning we can actually even give them 4 or 4 page
if we wanted to know or we can take them back to the intended place actually not intended redirect them
back to a four or four page.
As a matter of fact it's time for me to show you how to create a 4 or 4 page.
All right.
We could redirect them to actually the home page.
We wanted to.
Let me show you how to create a forum for Bache and this is why you can't miss any lectures.
I don't I stress this very much because as you can see right now I'm showing you a different technique
that I'm not going to create a whole lecture for it is super easy.
So I'm going to show you how to create a four four page real quick a custom 4:4 page.
Let's go to resources views errors in here you can see that we already have a file three page or we
have to do is create a four or four page Antar done.
That's it.
Now if for some reason costume for forbit you for some reason you have a page that is now found in your
application is going to go to this page right here.
All right.
So let's let's actually do it and show you.
So let's say you want to go to I don't know profile profiles.
Look at this.
All right.
So don't miss any lecture you don't.
You never know what you're going to learn in the next one.
All right cool.
All right so let's go back here.
All right.
So we're good to go here guys.
Let's actually try to log in.
We can see the Jose right now.
Let's see what title is he on.
Jose is a.
All right.
Let's make sure that we are implementing this correctly.
As a matter of fact we're going to leave it for the next lecture OK.
We're going to test this out in the next election.
Make sure it's working.
All right now we've got this far with this.
We are not tested at all on the next lecture.
OK.
And we're going to review how everything is working.
Basically I just said sent in twice but I show you how to do a 4 or 4 page.
All right.
Anyway thank you so much you guys and I'll see you in the next lecture