Bereit will come back and what you said and this is Edwin D.S. a game with another beautiful tutorial
for you guys.
All right so we got the database we've got the migration.
Now it's time to make this on the one minute so I want you to put your timer.
All right.
And I already will spend a couple of seconds talking.
So let's create.
All right.
Let's create the the system real quick and probably already 30 seconds talking so it probably on a lot
under 30 seconds.
This is a command BHB artisan make us enter while you're done that it's probably under 10 seconds right
.
Let's go back to this.
Let's refresh and let's say the registration system is done.
I promise you under one minute I should have promised under nine seconds if I didn't talk so much.
Probably was probably going to be under five seconds.
All right so that say you see how easy that was.
We created a database.
We migrated it and now we just did that small command PH BE make Auth. BHB already some make Auth. and
walla.
Does command has created their auth folder that has the log in file the register file has the password
has another follicle passwords and that has the emails in there and they reset the reset functionalities
.
As you can see right here we have layouts for a master page and I'll show you the method which is pretty
cool.
I'll show you all the files right now as a matter of fact.
So let's go to resources views and I've got to synchronize mine.
All right.
So I got it off for the here and you can see we got e-mails.
We got passwords for that.
We got a log in the registration registration.
We got the lay out which is a master label we have bootstrap already here available for us.
All right.
So we have to those include this masturbation in our other pages and we were good to go.
As you can see we're yielding content.
All right.
So we are basically in your way guys.
So in the next lecture we're going to register a user.
All right.
As a matter of fact the store right now.
Right.
Let's just register so you can see it.
So let's register.
I'm going to register myself as India's and to register as courting faculty that call my password which
is now my real password just in case.
And then I'm going to register it.
While not only is this going to register that user comput is going to logo's in.
So we are logged in that we can log out.
So I'm going to go right now to let me open a browser.
Actually I thought I have BHB my admin there but I do not.
Let's go to Lavell and Laro bill.
Logon to users and as you can see we have a user created not only that but they have that password has
been hashed.
So I hope you can see how powerful our view is.
Guys I mean it just gives me goosebumps right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching this and the next lecture.
We're going to inspect this a little bit more.
OK.
Take care and have a wonderful day.
Bye bye