All right welcome back my sister.
And so let's make sure that we are we've flushed down or sessions or right.
Nothing there or is empty because what we're going to be learning here in this lecture is how to flash
data now while we're flushing data eyes.
They're very similar to sessions.
The only difference is that flashy flashing data will only stay for one requests.
So when you flush data if you have any experience on other frameworks I usually is when you create let's
say some type of record in the database and you want to provide the user with some feedback on the form
right.
You want to display your post has been created.
That's when you use Flash data and show you how to use it right now.
So we're going to access their requests and that is the method.
And then we're going to change flash meant that here the first parameter is going to be why the key
would be in that session.
And the second is the message or whatever you want to type in for the value.
So I'm going to say polls has been created or something like that.
All right.
So remember this is only going to be available for one requests or a very short period of time.
I'm going to return session get message
ready.
So
let's do it one time.
Oops.
We're out there.
Let's look at it again.
There we go.
Post has been created.
All right.
So now I'm going to do is I'm going to comment this out.
And now if it was a session you would still have that when you try to display it.
But because this is a flash you can see that he's gone or I saw the second request you saw that he was
gone.
It's not there anymore.
That's what Flash data is.
All right.
So guys you're done.
We're done with sessions.
You know how did this play Flash data super easy to do.
You know how to play how to recreate sessions.
I mean you know now let me show you a couple of more things about flash the night before we leave.
OK.
So let's say for example you want to keep the data around a little bit more or you have to do is use
another method.
And they have this into the station guys.
All right.
So you can say reflash and this will actually keep your data a little longer.
We also have another Mentha that we can keep a specific type of data if you want to.
So you can say session and this one.
INSKEEP All right.
And if you wanted to keep that same message you keep the message right here.
All right.
And then delete everything else Ray.
So if you wanted to keep this flash data around just use the keep.
But anyway this is all into the communication guys.
If you wanna go back I'm going to give you the links but at the end of the sections like always but
always go back check with the community and practice play around with it and see what your specific
application needs and start you know applying it.
That's the only way to learn.
Thank you so much for watching guys.
Being a pleasure and I see you on the net lectures or section