All right welcome back my students.
So I decided to come back and give some more knowledge about you know retrieving models from from your
application using it when I decided to give some more knowledge because I think this is not just enough
but I want to give you a little bit more so you can defend yourself.
So let's just create another round real quick and let's just say get it and let's call this find more
right than function.
Whoops no go.
All right.
So let's say for example once a retiree something again and we just say let's use it.
Use this method find or fail this way.
And this is a method.
This is something that's already and application in the model right.
This final film met to try to find a record that you give it an ID right you give them the ID.
If you can't find the is going to give an exception.
So if I try to find record number one and I try to return this let's just return it.
Pause Well let's go to the browse and check it out real quick find Moyes to you or else that we have
to
write for more enter.
We get no phone reception no square resorts for model.
All right.
Of course we see this because we are in the development
area Ryad development stage of our application.
But if anything will we see something like this you know area like this.
Okay.
And we would throw out this 404 error that we can catch and we could show the user a 4 4 page or something
like that.
All right.
So just know that we are able to do that.
So now that we we we have the ability to do that.
There is also you can also come here and let's just leave it this way here and we could do this.
So you know this right of examples and we can use the model again.
I want you to get very used to doing this or I would guess a where
for example where users count all right and then you put it this function could take multiple Arap parameters
will say where users count is less than.
I don't know.
15.
OK.
So you could do that and then you can change it and take how the first out of it.
Or you could say first or fail.
Right.
So you can see how you can use eloquent to do a lot of things.
All right.
To leave this late this year if you want this file.
Let me know I will have it available for you.
That's why I'm creating everything in one file and I'm going to document it there.
But I want you to do the same thing I want you to write this stuff down with me ok.
Don't just get comfortable way for me to give you the file I might change my mind I'll give it to you
.
I want you to write stuff down and do it yourself.
OK.
So that's one thing that you could do.
All right.
And it's pretty cool.
Again there's a lot more methods you can find all these methods into the command station as well as
was clicking command.
All right command and clicking on it.
So if you go to your model right here you double click and you click command or control if you are in
a Windows and you pull your mouse over and BHB story is going to give you a whole bunch of classes.
But you click it while you pressing control command and you're able to go here and if you want to find
out some more information about some other methods you click it again and you try to see OK.
I want to go somewhere else.
You see that really cool stuff.
All right.
Keep it cool again.
Click it again.
You got all this.
Use me.
Go methods.
All these files all these classes.
But anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture I hope you learn a lot on this one and know that
eloquent super beautiful too.
And you know very descriptive with what you want to do right.
You get there where the way he uses counts is less than 50 and then you take out the first or fail if
you can't find it right.
Pretty cool.
Anyway thank you so much for watching.
We'll try.
I'll try to give you some more information.
But we'll continue with eloquence because I think it's very important for you to learn it and this is
why we are using our About the most.
See you in the next lecture guys.
I'm enjoying teaching it to you and I hope you're having fun and I'll see you then I see you in the
next one.
Take your