All right welcome back my students so it's time for us to start you know converting the other form.
We have that added for form.
OK.
So let's go to our edit form and that's what we got here.
So now if you want you can go ahead and bring this whole thing from over there here and pasted in there
and you can do the rest.
Just to get an idea right guys and it's here.
OK.
And you can do that if you want.
Now you don't need this anymore.
All right.
Because we can do that
up here.
All right.
So cool.
So now we have the title when we can take that off
and the submit button.
Let's go get the one from here.
Now I'm going to show you another way of actually not having to do this all the time guys this is a
simpler way by using templates from PH B-story if you already have BHB storm you can use a little command
on your keyboard and produce this whole thing right away.
So that way you know you don't have to do that.
I'll show you in a minute how to do that.
Let's go back here and take.
Get rid of this and
let me see what OK we have this.
All right.
So let's actually start it in this.
Let's do it manually or over here and whoops and let's do form
submit that's first parameter is this submit the name whatever name you want.
We can give it
up the post.
That's what it says on the bottom there of that post.
And the second parameter could be the class and we're going to name this class
and it's going to be a BT and VTM primary or in full.
OK.
Make sure that you have your little arrow here.
Ok cool.
So I think that's that's good enough for that.
All right.
And we can take this off but what happens every time I take that off I get this error.
For some reason
that's weird.
I mean you see remove extra closing tag.
We have another tag
.
OK let's use.
Oh I see we have this.
No we don't.
Let's go back here and get the form closing tag pasted in there and that way we can take that off.
Ok cool.
All right so we have the same form almost.
We have to edit it a little bit.
And this one here.
OK.
We've got to make this cold patch.
All right.
And the action is going to be instead a store is going to be of the OK same controller because that's
what we're using now.
We got to do something really nice in this lecture you're going to show you a bow form binding model
binding.
Right.
And I'll show you that in a minute how to do that let's go back to edit and see how that changed.
All right.
So I'm going to click here.
And all right we've got a mistake there and now I can't see where the mistake is.
I thought it was going to give me the form.
And so I was I was going to be able to show you what was wrong with it but I'm going to have to do it
anyway.
So what we're going to do here is I'll just do the model by name right away guys so that will you know
.
OK.
So for model binding one model is going to do is going to give us the ability to read populate the form
with the data from the database.
OK.
So if I do a model here and I'm going to pass post Colma because that's the object right.
So I passed that and I come here to this action.
I'm going to create another array here.
Now array and inside here I'm going to pass in the post ID.
Now you work here.
Antar.
Now you can see that the form works ok.
I thought it was going to let me show it to you without actually putting all that information but he
won't let me since I had to put some time since I changed the method.
OK.
All right cool.
So as you can see we were able to repopulate the form All right and if I do this update the form you
can see that it's updating nicely.
All right let's go back to the post.
All right so I hope you see what he's doing and we changed a function from open tomorrow.
All right.
And then we pass it as a first parameter object.
The second parameter was an array with another a sigh.
That way we can actually put the ID there.
So all this information this data is being sent basically very secure is now being sent in the you Arel
.
All right so when you edit stuff all right we click update post.
All right.
It's updating to patch.
OK.
Clarabell is actually preventing as I inject showing anything that you think could hurt or is from outside
right.
Anything allowable.
It's very secure.
We don't have to do any scaping anything at all.
Everything is being done for us.
All right so that where we can focus on building the applications set of you know worrying about if
somebody is going to hack our application or anything like that.
Cool.
So now let's let's do this all of us well we have the lead here for the lead.
We're going to do something very similar song going to copy this whole thing right here.
All right.
The only thing with the lead is that we don't need open we don't need to pass anything in here sucking
or Ray or anything like that so we're going to delete all of that.
And here we're just going to say destroy.
OK.
And for patch instead of patch we just going to say delete like this and we don't need this.
We need a cement bind so I'm going to copy this little guy right here.
We need a form by closing tags for form.
Copy that.
And this is just going to delete it.
And just for future reference we're going to change the class to danger.
Ok cool.
Let's go and check it out real quick.
Antar allergy Yes.
All right.
We forgot something as a matter of fact we do need to pass in the second array right here because we
need the I.D..
I almost forgot.
Ok folks.
All right cool.
So post ID.
All right.
All right let's check it out real quick answer.
There we go.
Yes gone example gone nuts.
Well so is everything's working working really good.
All right guys thank you so much for watching this as being a really good session for you to get your
hands dirty with forms.
And we're going to continue.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lectures.