All right welcome back my students.
So we have created our migration.
We need to set up our relationships so that way we can you know use it and either do the crush create
reading or are they in the league since we have to do the crowd.
Why not start with creating information first creating related creating related relationships right
.
It was kind of confusing there.
But anyway so we're going to say that the user has one address where we need to start creating an address
for the user.
So we're going to use a one to one relationship right.
So before we go into this I want you to notice something.
We are creating a relationship between the users say one addresses the right is not enough just to create
a model in this case because it's a one to one relationship we need to create a what Look at this table
.
Tell me what is missing.
That's right.
It's missing a user ID.
Right.
So we have two options either we king out of here and do a refresh or we King at the table.
Now I would add that table another table I'm sorry the column I would add the column.
If I had a lot of data I wouldn't want to redo or refresh you know.
But in this case we just refresh it because since we don't have data hopefully you don't have any data
.
But anyway this is an integer and his User ID my.
This is the column.
Let's make it on sign so that weighs all positive numbers on sign.
I believe that's the way you spell it.
Hopefully I'm correct if 9 is going to give us a problem.
We're going to make inaudible so that way we don't have to really have a value there.
We don't want to.
So if this address is by itself somewhere in our application we can associate it with the user.
You see what I mean.
So we can leave it along here.
So that's fine.
All right.
So let's do my refresh BHB artists and migrate refresh.
Now this is refresh.
Now is time for us to do the relationship.
All right.
So Whoops.
All right guys go back and to your user mark.
I'm going to go to the user model here.
I have so many monitors.
GUYS IT'S NOT EVEN FUNNY AND I DOn't NEED ALL OF THEM.
It's just that I just like monitors you know to have information all over the place so I have like five
monitors right now all around me.
And it's like when I switch to one screen thing I have a different resolution and another one because
they're recording resolution and the resolution I use to develop are different.
So that's why you see me sizing the screen sometimes.
But anyway so we are in the user mode.
This is a parent and the parent has to have a child and the child sees the address try dumbhead that
is going to go and ask for the user id by default in that in this table right here.
So we talked about that and we did it before public function
address and we're going to return the value out of the way we can use it right.
So we say return this was a relationship one to one right.
We don't have that remember.
Is has one there with you.
So the user is going to have one y address.
Beautiful really good job guys.
And you can set extra parameters here remember.
OK.
All right so cool we have this relationship where we fix star migration here.
What else.
Well on the next election we're going to continue with this and we're going to start inserting information
creating information creating addresses for this specific user which is going to be pretty cool.
Thank you so much for watching guys.
You're doing an awesome job and I see you on the next lecture