All right.
Welcome back my students.
So on this lecture here we are going to be finally uploading images.
Yeah that's right.
We've got to do it all right now I want you to grab any image that you have anywhere on your computer
and drop it in there and see what happens.
All right we're going to have our inspector Fleming open real quick and our Network tab right here.
All right.
Now I want you to look at that.
And going to drop some images real quick I'm going to drop my image.
And as you can see it gives me a 500 error there.
Does not find anything.
I mean it's this we get this internal error here is saying something is wrong.
What's going on.
All right.
So let's actually take care of that.
Let's go back to our HTP controllers.
And right here on store what we're going to create now we gonna come back here and we go and call the
store and make sure that you put the request here guys.
All right.
Cool.
Let's return let's actually go blow it right away.
All right let's just do it.
All right.
So from that form from that form automatically We're going to get a pause superglue or we'll call file
would a kill file.
OK.
Like this if it was native BHB will get something like that.
All right with the imagery information I.
I actually like.
I'm sorry.
All right files.
All right.
But in this case this is about.
So we're going to get our requests.
It's going to be type of file requests and it's going to be named file.
All right.
By default if you change if you want to change it you can go to the drop zone Web site and they have
they have the documentation there but then you can set a default with something you can set did the
form with some options.
All right let's give it some random time numbers here for our images like we do all the time.
And let's just move it as well to images
right.
And this created super easy stuff guys
path
actually is a path I believe this file has the same name as one comment on the form.
OK.
All right.
So let's see this bathing action.
All right let's.
Actually releasing images here.
Hopefully our application doesn't go all crazy because we're deleting images.
I'm going to delete are the images.
I know that's very.
As a matter of fact licious.
Let's just leave it there.
We're going to overlook some more images.
I don't want to leave my images.
No.
All right cool.
Let's click on this and let's use our blog.
All these images and I'm going to hit the open and when I do that let me see if I can.
Well now we're not going to be able to see it with my editor because I have to synchronize but if I
do this all these images should be here.
Let's synchronize it and let's wait for it.
There we go see that.
So now we get images now and not only that but we can see this thing in no obligation.
Real quick.
Let's go to our application and you can see all the images right here.
All right.
Beautiful.
That is just nice right.
It would be nice to be able to delete these images as well.
So we're going to do that in the next lecture.
Take care.
Have fun.
And I see you then.
Bye bye.