Welcome back to this tour.
So in the last couple lectures we have been creating forms and we have been also using packages to or
package this class right here to create this functionality.
Right now we have not discussed very much in valuation.
We have not touched that subject yet.
And I told you we will do it.
So let's go ahead and do that.
Let's find out how to validate.
Right now we go to create and we insert it we actually leave a blank and we do create pools.
It will create a blank record in our database we don't want that right.
So how do we value the way a lot of it.
Well there are a couple ways we can do this.
All right.
First we create it we use a method called validate or we can make a request class or I would which we
can do with BHB artisan.
All right.
Which is really cool.
So let's go ahead and do this let's go and do where we create this valley the method is in the controller
.
So let's go to controller and right here in the create.
Right.
Actually not in the create in the store because this is where the information goes inside the database
right.
This is where we define the little value the function.
All right.
So is part of this controller.
So we're going to say this valley the Mantid that's where we find this.
And of course with closing we pass a couple parameters.
All right.
So the first parameter is going to be the requests which is this guy there.
The second parameter is going to be an array.
All right.
And array of values keys and values so the key for this one here what we want to valy the right now
is a title.
All right.
So we want to make sure that I don't have something there.
So we're going to say that title and we're going to say I want you to required
this title.
All right.
If you want to pass another rule.
These are called rules by the way you put a pipe.
All right that's close to the backslash in your key word.
And then you pass something like Max colon and then the value let's say Max 60 characters or something
like that.
All right.
And you can find out more in the larger bail Web site.
And of course at the end of the section I will always give you a link if I don't make sure that you
look for it.
It's called validation rules.
All right.
Now where you can find more rules that you can set you can say unique and you can do a lot of things
with rules.
OK.
We're you going to do it for required.
We're going to do require just the title.
OK.
Well you can of course pass more keys and values and you can say content if you had a content in there
and you can go here and you can say required and then you can keep going OK as many as you like.
Now if you have a more complex form with a lot more fields I recommend using the requests.
And we're going to check that the leader in the course.
OK.
Actually probably after this lecture but let me show you how this works.
So all right let's go here to create.
And now let's try to do it.
And now you can see that it refreshes and it doesn't go anywhere.
All right.
Now when you do this automatically there is a variable that is available call errors.
It does very well is available.
While the whole application.
Any way you want to display any errors.
You will be able to access that very well in display.
All right.
Right now the variable has this error.
OK in the next lecture I'll show you how to display it but right now is displaying an arrow has a value
.
But we've got to display it.
All right.
So this is how you value the forms using Claribel.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
I hope you having a lot of fun guys.
Take care