All right welcome back my students.
Now that we are able to upload the images and place them in our database and you should be very find
out by the way in your database.
OK.
So go to your BHB my admin real quick and verify that those photos are being placed in there.
But anyway let's go and build the functionality where we delete them and later on in the course we might
build the functionality where we can select all the pictures and to lead them.
All right.
We're probably going to be adding javascript for that.
All right but for now we're just going to put up the lead button here somewhere and we're going to lead
each of these pictures.
OK.
We're going to keep adding more features to this application as we go into course.
Well let's go to our
media page is actually right here resources views media and then we'll go to and it's and this is where
we want it.
All right.
This just added it right here
form would create a whole forum for that.
And I want to I want you guys to get used to seeing this forum all over the place.
All right.
This story is just this right away
the men media's
right.
OK.
Looks good.
This is going to be the lead.
All right.
Let's take this out.
Let's change this to danger
and let's look at it.
Well actually that's it.
Let's put the lead here.
Let's look at this real quick.
We're now the find so we got to the final real quick though we did that already but no function.
So I mean that means medius controller and we're going to find the destroy.
Make sure you give it an ID and
that's it.
Let's just look at it.
A quick
action and this true action.
The media destroyed not define what we define Now
it is defined Neyens now sir.
All right let's spell this correctly actually.
There we go may some parameters.
Yes we're missing the I.D..
We know that what we're trying to we're trying to do without this.
All right.
You
can't catch a break.
Everything has to be so perfect guys.
There we go.
All right cool.
All right.
So let's go to the main medias and you guys know how to do this already Ray.
I mean super simple stuff.
I should let you do it
find
or fail Heidi.
All right.
Let's just give it a
and then here we want to do is on Lincoln.
We're going to give you the file name so
first we got to give it where the file is path and then the filename.
The
photo on file
and delete them redirect
moon
media.
You might want to put a flash here so well you know which pictures your eyes are leading right.
You might want to do that.
Let's leave this one here.
You can see I believe the yellow one because that way you can see which one we are deleting.
All right.
All right so you can see that it's working beautifully guys.
Now like I say you can add a message right after you deleted so you will you know has being successful
or laid on we can add a feature where we can leave more pictures once.
All right.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.