All right welcome back my sister and so we're going to start deleting some of these relationships right
now in my data right here my Ph.D. admin not in this one in this one.
Actually they are both the same sort about the guys in this here.
I've got a couple of tags and I have a couple of polls that are related to some of them.
Now your data my data may not be the same or right.
So we've got polls number one into here.
If I want to tag Jubal's you can see that I've got polls one in two and this one is related to two and
three.
All right so I got the two and three tags.
Two and Three.
I don't have a three here so I'm going to create a three right now.
All right.
There we go.
So we got polls for me.
Post Number One and Two.
All right have relationships right here.
All right.
So I'm going to delete this one in here.
Beautiful.
OK.
So it's just I want you to see what happens.
All right.
With this relationship when we delete it.
OK.
I don't know what's going on with my browser today.
It's acting up.
I'm going to have to do an update on my computer.
But anyway let's go ahead and create the delete route.
We've done this many times.
It's just and it's the same thing with this one guys with a polymorph and we need too many but a little
confusing since we have so many tables.
So what we've got to do is we find the post right.
Let's say we find pools number one right now we use a foreach each to loop through that collection because
we are linked to a collection.
Remember those tax.
That's what we're going to be looking through as tag.
Now this becomes the object.
Now I can say tag all right where ID equals.
We've got two and three right away ID goes to I wanted to delete it.
All right.
Cool let's try this out.
And let me make this a little big.
Here we go.
All righty.
This has been a very hard lecture to make because every time I'm creating this lecture either my my
the dog in the house barks somebody comes in the house or you know I mean in my office somebody comes
in the office every time I try to create It's like just something goes up.
But anyway hopefully I'll be able to finish it with you guys this time.
So delete.
Enter and refresh.
All right.
This is the
tag as you can see with the little tag number two.
Now that is less than the tag number three.
As you can see we're deleting the task tags through our relationship right refresh
.
We go here tagging walls and we got actually one polls and two polls and we got tagged two and three
OK.
And now in order for this to be the lead and we've got to find in order for this attack to be the leader
this is what gets confusing guys.
We have to actually find polls number one guys number two and we try to look for polls number one.
And look if we're talking number three.
All right.
So that's that's the problem.
That's why they're not the leader there.
So if we're going to find polls number two and the lead attack that he has because that's a relationship
that's it's tag.
Delete.
Oops.
The lead refresh now here guys.
Now here right here is gone.
All right.
And then this tag your eye here is related to nobody.
So let's relay this tag to
this pose.
So it's related to number one.
Now let's see.
Oops.
All right.
Almost there.
I tell you it is not your day is not your day.
As you can see there there's one time here.
This tag is supposed to be related to post number one.
And then for his own reasons still there.
All right.
That's because we generally tag number three oh geez.
Over guns.
Or I got this letter because it's funny right.
Refresh.
No tags.
All right so I think we're done with the leads.
And if you have if you guys have any questions feel free to ask.
Go in the discussion and have your laughter they also have some fun coding in them practicing and I'll
see you in the application section.
OK soon.
Take care.