All right welcome back my students.
I hope you're having a lot of fun and learning a lot with this lecture year that I'm doing in this election
.
All right cool.
So we have learned a couple of comments here and maybe we have now learned them we've just been you
know typing and trying to not get overwhelmed with all this information that's cool.
We can do this over again.
All right so let's go to our terminal and let's clear things out.
We know that we do ls high in L.A. actually L.A. we can see our hitting file.
So let's remove that get from there let's remove everything.
All right so we're going to remove everything.
Whoops.
Not good.
There we go and let's just remove that as well.
All right cool.
So now we got a clean slate.
Let's initialize.
Good.
All right.
Let's create a file in the mail.
So now we will guest star as we can see get the in the mail there.
All right.
So let's just do a commit real quick let's add it and let's do a commit commit
and add a file.
All right.
Basically showing you the work flow.
All right cool.
So we do get status.
We don't buy anything but if we do get log we can see the commit here add a file.
All right so now let's add something to the file page.
One feature one at it.
All right.
Save it.
Let's going out the file that do a comment or feature one.
All right.
Good luck.
I hope you see the workflow on this.
All right so now let's do.
Let's add another file another feature feature to save it.
Good ad good command feature to get log.
Now we've got three comments.
All right.
So now I want you to look at this.
So let's say I want to go back to my.
This is where out of the file this is where I added the first feature.
They say I want to go back to the first feature on a copy this and get reset hard paste.
Enter gate log.
This clearly is older but log as you can see we only see two commits here.
And this is done out of here.
You see that.
So that second that third committee is now there which is a second feature.
So let's add it again.
All right.
Save it.
There's added less committed.
All right.
Let's check the logs again we see three commits.
All right call.
Let's do a good reset and let's go back to that feature one again.
Are we going to do good research without doing the hard version of it.
All right so now as you can see has being on stage.
So now if we do get let's to clear
the gate log.
And as you can see that our committee is not there because we do this sauf we did a soft reset.
So now we do Gestaltists we can see that mortar fire fall right here has not been committed.
So basically our software we said we go back.
All right we go back to one step before.
So that one step before is out in this file.
Right.
So it could be committed.
All right.
Well committing this file that would be.
That would be the step.
But it has now been committed here.
So we need to commit it now.
And another thing that you need to know about the soft reset is that the change is still here.
All right.
We have not deleted this.
This only gets deleted when we do a hard reset.
All right so the change is still there is still the follow still mortified.
We just took off.
They commit when we do a soft reset.
All right.
So let's do the comment right now we can go back and say add a feature to whoops or the file as being
we got to add it.
There we go and do that.
And then to the command.
All right.
So now we do get log.
We can see the comments there.
OK.
I hope you see how useful this can be.
Because let's say you are you finish in your application for some reason.
You make a mistake at the end of finishing your application and now you're stuck and you saved the file
in a duplicate folder.
You have to go back there and try to find out.
I mean it's a mess unless you have something like virtual control it makes it very easy to go back and
forth.
All right.
So anyway I think we are good here showing you this steps.
And if I have anything else I will of course bring it up to this section here and show you we get.
But this is just a basic commands that you know you know are very useful for you to use on the next
lectures we get to see how we can push this to get help.
All right.
Which is a online repository and we'll explain that on the next lecture.