All right welcome back my students so now I have encountered an issue and one of the lectures and I
wanted to come back and let you guys know how I'm fixing this.
For some reason my Ph.D. artist and is now working so if I try to refresh refresh reset or refresh it's
now working even if I try to migrate or even roll back ok when that happens.
The best way to do it is not deleting it from here you need to go to the database in the lead or your
table is there.
OK.
So I will go to that database and I will select all of this and delete them all.
OK let's just drop it where is the drop here.
Yes I want to drop them all.
All right.
And now
you delete whatever you want to hear which is this one that I wanted really.
You don't have to follow me on this lecture.
I'm just showing you how we do something like this.
All right if I have a problem with BHB my artisan.
Now let's go back.
Art is an angry answer.
Now they all migrated.
So everything is fixed again.
OK.
So when you encounter issues like die and you use mph we already said and you making migrations and
doing this and doing that and you are in there he does it stops working go back in the lead.
Every time all the tables in there you can just generate them again.
Isn't that beautiful guys.
Right.
You don't have to go in and do this manually in the Petri maddening anymore.
You can just run the migration things done for you.
Beautiful.
Anyway I just wanted to record this video to help you guys with that.
And on the next lecture We'll continue with our relationships.
Thank you