All right welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to learn how to update using the polymorphic relationship.
All right cool.
Let's go and open our HP storm if you have one.
If you don't.
Don't worry about it.
We use a or other editor.
Let's get around for this.
Right this is going to be the update
.
All right.
So first we find staff ray machines find one or fail it.
Right.
OK cool.
And
let me see if we can do a little different here guys.
All right let me show you how to do it this way.
All right so let's do a staff photos.
All right.
So you know how to do this.
And let's just do a where.
I don't know ID equals one.
Bring me the first one.
OK.
And
I want to change it.
Let's change.
Let's grab it let's gravity in the variable.
Look at these watches for you.
All right.
So remember now I have this object now because first we change the subject.
They get returns a collection.
So let's do let's use a safe method here.
And this is safe.
Save it.
But we haven't even put in the properties yet.
So the only property that we can.
Well one of the problems that we can get is the path that's a column there and we're going to say updating
exemple the GBG.
All right let's see how this works.
OK let's see if it works for us.
All right.
All right cool.
Update
us.
And to whoops that looks like work Ray BHB my admin.
Let's go and order the polymorphic photos.
Act as you can see set of date example.
So it worked beautiful.
You saw how easy that was.
Michel you spell it correctly OK.
All right so you can do stuff like this when you updating.
Of course there are other ways of doing it.
But I wanted to show you to show it to you.
You can do it like this.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture