All right.
Welcome back.
My students so I welcome you with this big error that we had on The Last Lecture right.
We tried it again.
And while I can I find a logging controller.
All right cool.
So what is this all about.
Well we got a couple of controllers that we need to actually get.
So if I go back here to the documentation Mr. Eric here is telling us listen you need to grab a fresh
copy of each one Charlie from get help.
All right.
So these are the new controllers here.
And let's just copy this one see what what we can do with it.
All right let's copy the raw.
And let's just copy this and just create this controller manually or I get lazy.
All right.
Don't get lazy.
Trying to create this thing and another way let's just create it like this.
Forget about BHP adducing commands or anything like that.
This is old school.
All right.
So controller.
And because I'm creating a PSP file I don't need to pull the extension and Mr.
Some not so reliable Mr BHP story.
They are going to pay studying here.
And let's see what he says.
Now let's see if he's going to mess around with us again.
All right.
There we go.
That's what I'm talking about.
Beautiful.
All right.
So let's login and win at all.
You put your own password.
OK don't copy minds.
All right.
And your own username password right.
Let's do this.
And whoops.
What's going on.
Well we get into home and we don't have a home page.
Let's go to the index and we see that we are logged in.
So it's working.
All right cool.
A GO.
We can't log out.
That's not nice.
All right.
So now of course you can go back to the contagion and you can read a little bit about it and you can
say OK what's wrong why can't i log out.
Oops.
We can create our own logo.
Great.
Let's copy this guy.
And let's go back.
And what can we put this well in the routes.
Right.
Let's put it right up here somewhere right here.
All right guys.
And I recommend to actually kind of organize this a little bit and put whatever needs to be putting
admin putting out men and put some comments around you know try to make this look nice.
And I leave that to you.
All right that's your job is to.
My job is to teach you.
But you should already know this if you are this far.
All right.
Anyway let's go back and let's open our application software.
Let's go here.
All right.
So love me now.
We've got to change the redirection a minute.
But this go here and now we can see that we are actually locked down this logo.
And while we love that because we see this menu here.
All right let's go and change that in the loading controller and let's change that to home page.
I mean to the rude.
Let's go back here and let's try this again.
Come on Mac my computer sometimes she does this.
Don't mind her.
All right.
No that's not my password it's just password.
And let's try this one.
All right.
Good.
Let's try to logout and voila.
All right.
Logon system is actually almost ready.
Remember that we need to copy the rest of the
page be files right.
The rest of the routes.
All right.
So we have this control is right here we need to create this little guy right here and this is the forgot
controller page study.
There you go.
And no I don't want you to add them manually.
I mean to the good yet I'll add it myself later.
Let's go to the RAW file.
All right this is the I forgot Raul so copy this guy.
And let's just paste them here.
All right.
And we're going to do this for each of these.
And I think we've got two more.
That guy no more.
Make sure you got the name here.
Discreate is Guy you BHP file.
Go.
So
Cuppy This is the register
and we go I think we got one more right.
I was a long file.
Let's do one more.
This guy he said
All right.
So let's type this one.
I know I know it's risky because we can make a mistake and mess everything up.
So if you want to copy the name you're welcome to do that.
I'm just going to take a risk and do it myself.
We set passwords and whoops we haven't copied the role yet
.
There we go.
They sit in there we're done.
We're done with this.
All right.
And now remember that this file the this reroutes method here is actually giving us the routes for those
files.
Right for logging into and all that.
So let's look at our list real quick and you can see the lawyer right here actually.
All right.
Jim registration as well.
I think we're good here.
We got our logging and password routes and it's working.
The next thing is to actually and I think you know what we should be redirecting to add me right when
we log in.
It's up to you where you want to redirect.
I think gardening is a good choice.
All right so come here.
Let's see if that works.
All right.
OK.
But we have a lot of things to fix the young admin right.
So in the next election we're going to keep start fixing this and make this work.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.