All right welcome back my dear Mac users.
Now on this lecture here I want to recommend BHB storm as our editor as our ID is so little different
than some brackets and all those editors out there why ph be so different because this is NITV integrated
development environment this is a whole software packaged ready to use ph.
I mean this is an awesome really awesome editor.
And if you have some money I suggest you buy the product if you don't have any money.
You can download it and evaluate it for 30 days.
All right.
And David have discounts for students for teachers and for certain companies.
So if you click on buy real quick right now let me assure you you can pay for a yearly all right for
individual 89 bucks a first year 71 this second or $53.
This is worth it the guys so if you have the money and you can do it is worth it to you can also pay
monthly if you can pay every year.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff.
Now you can get also discounts for start ups companies for students and teacher education and training
.
They have a lot of different discounts they really try to help people out there get their software and
I mean this is one of the best ideas that I can find out there for Ph.D. and they also have ideas for
other full.
Dean for the mail I mean they have a whole bunch of different ideas out there but this is the cool the
best ID that I could find ph be out there right.
But anyway we can go ahead and try this for 30 days and that's what we're going to be doing anything
like it.
Then you can get a better price later.
You try one of these options All right.
So we can download it.
We click on download are you going to get redirected to this page.
Click on download right here.
That's going to download BHB storm.
Go ahead and double click it.
Once he finishes install it I already have installed in this computer.
So I'm not going to do that.
So once you have an install he's going to ask you if you want to try a software right so I'm going to
go right here go to my launchpad and look for it.
You can also place it in your dock here just drag it down in place it.
So because you're going to be using it a lot and then you're going to click on evaluate for 30 days
and click OK recept and you're good to go.
All right.
That's what we're going to be doing with this but I'm going to cancel this because I'm going to.
And you can go hunting aseptic later on we're going to create a new LaRocco project and we're going
to open it up.
But right now we're not going to open it up.
You can if you wanted to.
All right.
Once you have it installed you're set to go for this lecture.
And now again remember that you can use any editor you wonder differing editors if you have to blind
does good.
So blinds are really good too.
You can install some plug ins and make subline ID if you want.
All right is very Blaine's really good a lot of people use it for Clarabell but I like to use PSP storm
you can use any editor remember that you don't have to get BHB storm but I really do recommend it.
All right.
And you can tell on that as we recommended you to be storm Edwin.
Edwin Diaz from you to me.
All right.
If you want to get a discount something I think they might be able to do something with you.
But anyway thank you so much for watching these little guys and I'll see you in the next one.
Take care