All right welcome back to the soil.
Time for us to start jumping into the cold right.
Jumping into creating a a test trial and testing our application real quick.
Our small applications so let's go do that let's go two routes in.
Right here we're going to do it in the home page.
All right.
You could if you wanted to do it in another round like say e-mail Rao or even create a controller and
do this and the controller is on to you.
I'm going to do it here just to do it in a fast way.
All right.
So first of all we're going to create a data array here because what we want to do is have some data
right ready for the message.
All right.
So I'm going to have a title here.
It's going to be an associate of a re going to say hi my students.
I hope you like the course.
All right cool.
Let's go and create another one.
Content and this can be whatever you want.
OK.
Now I got to tell you right now this keys keeps going to turn into variables once he gets to that template
.
The view right now if you don't know what I mean don't worry.
And I explain to you in a minute
is love of course was created with a lot of love and dedication
for you.
All right.
That's true guys.
That is very true.
All right cool.
So if you want to send mail right.
We have to use the mail facade right or the mail class as the as I call it.
And there is a medical center.
There we go.
All right.
So now he's complaining here that his class is not included I guess less important on top.
So he doesn't complain.
All right.
So the first parameter here this is going to take a couple of Ramadan's the first one would be the view
because the way this works is that this would actually use a view instead of a roll masses.
Now there are many ways you can do it you can actually send a roll or hd a mail message by default.
This is sending NHT e-mail message OK.
But you can make this raw.
And I will go to the documentation right now and see it.
But let's just do this right now.
Let's try to set up this set this up.
Views are going to create here a folder called Mail array or e-mails and say here I'm going to say test
.
All right cool.
So let's go back to RAO here and we're going to say e-mails dot tests.
All right e-mails fill the folder into us just for the file.
This is how we do it just like we do views because this is a view.
So the segment that can take views like this.
All right.
Now the second parameter here would be the data that is going in.
And here you can put your array here if you wanted to but we're just doing it like this.
That way we can just pass it in in a cleaner way.
All right.
The third parameter is the closure function.
And now here what you can do.
This takes a variable and then you can call it whatever you want.
This very well turns into an object which you can use to call cement.
It's like the two method where is their email going to I.
Well let's say we're going to do in D.S. India.
Com for example.
That's what we saying is going all right.
And it's going to a guy named Edwin does.
All right and then we can change this to another method on the subject.
We go again say hello.
Student How are you.
Or something like that.
OK.
Now remember that you're going to what you're going to be doing is taking stuff from the form.
All right.
And inserting it right here.
I like form stuff.
This is hard coding everything right now.
But remember that this information will come from a form.
All right.
And then you can take it to your view.
So if we go to the view we take you there but we're going to do then and that's lecture OK.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the net lecture