All right welcome back.
This stood and so we getting arrows to errors in our application but that's fine right because what
are doing right now is upgrading.
All right.
Now for that we have to upgrade our application this way.
Right.
And it's not alarm bells for either guys.
Come on don't get upset at them.
All right let's fix this so we've got this raúl error here and this is because we need to find the name
of our routes right now.
All right.
Get out of here.
I should have just clicked.
Don't show me again but I forgot.
Anyway so what's going on here is that we are getting these routes we are Laro they always omitting
the first parameter here and we got the second parameter and we are defining this in our layouts.
Let's go to resources real quick.
So if we go to layouts real quick and we go in Admin we can see that we are saying admin post create
.
OK.
Yeah yeah.
So no yeah we can come here and do this and take it off.
But why do that.
We are actually calling this dynamically all right by the name so we can go to Web.
Let's actually find that up here on where we go web and we can actually start defining that need those
names right here.
All right customer names for applications.
How we do that well.
Let me show you.
So we having a problem with admin users and it's OK.
Good.
All right.
Let's actually create an array right here let's put a coma and let's give this array a key in this key
is going to be called names.
And now we just actually put another way inside this array and we bring it down.
And now we're going to say OK I mean users and it's I want you to go to and it's off.
Then that's off admin dot users in it.
That's it.
So basically here you find a way you want to go where you want it to go to what method basically and
your the name or your route.
So if we come here it's going to give us another error.
OK don't worry about that we're going to fix that in a minute.
As you can see now we have create error.
So it's missing all the methods here.
So we've got create and we do this all routes right now guys.
All right.
So if you want to go ahead and do that you can just do it for the routes that we've got down here.
I'm going to do it right now just because some of you like me to do this even though it's a lot of typing
.
All right so they create goes to I mean users create.
OK.
And then we go what are we got what is it.
That's one store
and this one actually you know what let's just copy this guy right here and copy him one more time.
So here I just going to change this for a store
and this one for edit.
All right.
Let's look at it now.
We're going to get another arrow going to get and that's error's for comments or something like that
folks.
All right.
So we've got polls that's and that's Raut right here.
So we'll do the same thing to this route.
All right.
And you can go ahead and forward the video and do it yourself if you want.
This is actually another array.
Yes that's fine.
We just need to call me right here.
All right.
And then just going to copy this guy right here because I don't want to type so much.
Let's take the last one.
We don't need it.
And this is going to be out in the polls polls
polls
polls that we go and let's do this one
names.
Whoops.
I went ahead of myself there for a minute
.
We forgot to call my Here again
and this is category's So we're going to go and see categories and we're getting better at it.
Right guys go nice and let's do this one.
Let's not forget this guy
.
It's fine
to the media.
Real quick
.
I don't know where my hand is slipping so much guys.
I guess the coffee by the way I'm not drinking coffee anymore.
For those of you that follow me for throughout the whole course I always talk about coffee.
I started being bad to my stomach for some reason.
We're going to click here he says I'm in polls and it is not fine.
All right.
That is strange oddment polls and it's
hmm
that's weird because we are finding it right there.
Right.
Let's go back and refresh
let's look at it real carefully.
So we've got this error here.
I mean polls and it's that we need to take care.
All right.
So
all that's right we are forgetting to put names on.
Here we go.
All right.
Not according guys a lot of courting whoops Where's my application
my prickish just disappear and I got this.
We go let's bring it back.
Sorry about that guys.
Like I said my computer sometimes does this stuff and I turn up to do it.
Well she still does it.
All right let's just open a window right here.
All right.
We've got comments we've got to work them comments.
A couple more here.
All right.
Don't get impatient.
I mean
this needs to be wrapped here.
All right let's do this one too and
we'll fix this if we are wrong and the next lecture guys.
I mean in the next lecture we're next following a lecture but we're just doing this balk at it in here
.
We should be good.
All right.
Anything we use We'll fix it.
Let's just copy this guy here so we don't have to type in so much.
So comments we can look at the comments
and replies.
I don't know if we have these routes for these replies but we'll find out.
All right.
All right so all the other names that are the key and all of that.
All right cool.
Let's check it out.
All right we got a error here and that I should be very noticeable.
And that arrow is on line at 97.
There we go.
What's going on here.
All right.
Check it out.
And we guy living OK.
111.
We've got an extra one there.
That's what we had.
Well I had.
I'm pretty sure you didn't.
So all right.
We got it to work.
Wow guys.
All right let's go to users.
All right.
We're getting something here.
All right so we got to go to this lecture here.
And if we go here we should get an error and we've got to fix that on the next lecture.
OK.
Let me take a break because I've been courting for like 12 hours and I need a little break.
All right if you've been calling for more than five you should take a break you're the student.
Take care guys.
I'll see you in the next lecture