All right welcome back my sister.
And so we are making a lot of progress here.
One thing that we have to start right now in this lecture is this Come in March.
I want to start on this.
I want to make this I want to use a package for this large of a collector package.
And I also want to only show this when the users logged in.
All right.
So let's go back to our code and let's take a look at that.
Let's make sure that we are there.
Let's see where this is at.
This is where they come in.
Is this the first comment and
this is a form actually.
All right.
So this is well we're going to be converting this form into one of our form.
All right so we're going to see form and we can actually take all these out.
Let's use our shortcut form open
loops.
I think it was open form on this lecture on this copy
form.
There we go.
All right.
So this is going to go to the
man comments controller right.
Everything else is the same except that this is going to be a tets area area.
This is going to be the body.
OK.
And this will be.
Submit
comment.
Let's look at it actually.
Let's also add a little bit of another attribute here.
Called Rose just two or three rows to it
because I think you already had three rows.
Let me check.
So select the has three rows.
OK let's refresh.
And we have the wrong controller
.
It's called pulls Commines controller.
I remember now we were gonna call it admin but we did not.
So its torment is now defined action pose Commines controller.
Now find Let's go out for a quick do we did that already.
Those comments controller is a resource
.
Misspelling it.
Misspelling it is.
Post.
We go mad.
The touch area
and getting so many bugs in this lecture is not even funny guys don't laugh meant that area
is not bugs it's just myself.
Without coffee I'm just some guy on the street.
All right so we got a converting to after so many bugs so many hiccups that we got to convert into the
form package here.
Ok cool.
So let's make sure that it works.
Let's go to our controller real quick.
Now the Post controller posts comments controller.
Geez.
All right requests.
And well there we go.
We got it submitting.
That's pretty cool stuff.
All right.
So how are we going to do this.
Well we're going to first do this comment and we're going to say create and we're going to create this
little bat boy right here
make sure that we do this
import that and also we have to redirect.
So things here if you go back let's go back to that to pause for a quick let's just have it here available
.
Take all these out of here.
Whatever we are now using is easy very easy today.
Clogged up with so many things here.
All right and just what we need.
All right.
That we need that we need that post.
So this is a thing we have a bunch of information that we need to send to our store Matt.
Right.
If you take a look we have the body but think about it like this.
Our table has other name right there has it all three has the email is active in all those fields how
are we going to send all this information.
And we don't even have the fields right.
We could create fields for it and I query.
You know but it would defeat the purpose of keeping this simple and keeping this only logging users
right.
So what we need to do is pull out the information from the logging user or in some form the requests
.
So let's go back here and start working on that.
All right.
So let's create a variable here and it's going to whole the user.
And now let's create an array real quick here
.
All right.
So what is this comment going to have.
Well we're going to have all the fields that we require in our table in our database right now plus
ID we can get that from the requests.
As a matter of fact we need to create some type of hitting input here so we can get that idea because
we don't have it in the store method.
So let's create this.
So we got to think about it like this.
We need to send the somehow.
Right.
So let's do that.
Let's get the input here and let's make it here.
All right.
The name let's make him false ID
and the value we can just make it to parse ID.
All right so we get that in the other side.
All right.
So we choose me.
So we got that cover.
Let's get the author and we can get this from the user object and e-mail.
We can also get that from the user.
Remember that only uses that would be logged into the application.
We'll be able to comment.
All right that's how we're setting this up
.
All right user and this will be the photo file and the body
and this we can get from the requests
.
So a lot of stuff.
All right.
And you can even actually create a little flashy.
Let's do that just in case you forgot to do this.
All right I'm going to remind you to do this.
All right.
And we can say something like a comment
flash or something like that.
Call my message.
Your you.
Your message has been
submitted and he's waiting moderation.
Cool.
And we can return to that right.
We return it to actually let's return it back
to the same page.
There we go.
All right this looks OK.
Let's make sure that we import off site and make sure that you have this in your your fellow was here
member that is active the court is going to be default.
Zero.
All right.
So let's do this here let's go and test this out real quick.
Let's get a page here a browser somewhere.
Let's go here.
I suppose one yeah we can go.
All right.
And let's also have ph be
this guy right here available.
All right my first
comment.
What happened.
All right.
They come in the night getting certain things trying to access a property that is not available.
So let's go back to those comments and here maybe the photo file doesn't have a photo.
And that could be an issue.
So it does have a form or the user does have a photo.
All right let's live 55.
All right.
Line 55 it is the photo.
Let's see what we got here.
We've got the file here.
And
oh ok.
The user.
Well we have that relationship song where we have to
go right here in the heart.
We do have that relationship.
Let's go back to it and let's try to submit everything we know the for Oh actually we don't need their
requests all here what we've got to do is request data.
We did this before we did the data array and that's why that happened.
Let's do that.
Let's see if we saw.
So they show it real quick.
Let's go back fresh and wow.
This comment.
It's great.
Actually this post
would be nice when we get some type of notification that to them before we do that before we submit
it.
Just we can see it.
So right below here I can add a check for a session.
So if he has a session what was the session.
He was a common
message I believe.
All right.
That is just
we want to this play.
I'm going to use the global recession
function.
All right.
So let's see that works.
Still trying to.
Still problem here.
I don't see it yet but let's go back to those comments and user for the file.
And of course we have the problem because this is enough for us supposed to be File.
All right let's go back here.
Actually no that's in comments.
The structure is the you know what
we never created that field.
So that's why we have a problem there let's actually create that real quick as BHP and make
migration and add forward all column to comments
table and if guys if you don't have a lot of data don't do this.
All right just migrate refresh and do it again.
You know like but if you have a lot of data you at the table like this.
All right let's just do it like I don't have a lot of data.
I don't mind doing this so I'm going to do this and I'm going to do my grid refresh on I'm going to
come back OK I'm going to pause a video guy so I went ahead and created this here on the on the replies
table and I did it on comments and then I did a migraine refresh and I went ahead and went to my database
.
Phil then the rules added the user.
I actually went to the application register the user once I migrated.
And then I came here in the end it does feel so that way we can log in.
All right.
So that's all I did and I also created a post.
All right so we have a pulse again.
All right cool.
So guys get used to this this work flow is what's going to happen to you when you are developing applications
and but a lot of them makes it really easy to see how we can just migrating create a table instead of
dropping the table or you know it's just you know a lot easier Clarabell.
But anyway let's go back to Paul Swann again.
And now that we have that let's go back and make sure they're both controller.
Is has the forward again field here.
All right.
And now let's try this again.
I think this will work even though I don't mind fixing bugs
.
No way.
We got the same line a.
All.
We got this photo file here.
Messing with us.
Oh that's because we could.
This is just messing with us.
Let's just leave it like this.
We'll fix it in the next lecture.
Let's go.
I can see right now guys I can't see it.
Submit this.
Let's go back here.
Good comments.
There we go.
All right.
It's messing with us.
Photo user photo file
.
I know this user has some type of photo software.
For a year the number one
actually
let's go back here real quick to our admin and let's see something real quick.
For users a forward it looks like our use of those in our photo.
So let's give our user a photo I'm going to give them.
I'm going to make myself like Rico.
There we go.
And now I'm going to try to do this again here and see if that was a problem because I don't like to
leave things on done and I enter whatever.
And it looks like you're mass's has been submitted and he's waiting moderation.
And it looks like it worked OK so the user does I have a picture Guice is not going to work.
Right.
So comments.
There we go.
All right we got it working please.
All right.
Thank you so much guys and sorry for the hiccups.
It happens and they'll get frustrated OK.
I love you.
I love all my students.
I'll see you.
Like you guys don't get freaked out when I say I love you right.
That's just a way of saying I love my students in general.
Thank you.
Bye bye