All right welcome back my students so it's time for us to start actually seeing something here in the
post page that means reading information and at the same time we have to go and show this information
for each individual post.
So let's go back here and say OK once you create this instead of redirect into pools that actually let's
make sure that there is some data there.
So there's got to end it's as you can see we're supposed to get something like this where I was supposed
to get this in it's content but we don't get that because this is now really really refreshing when
is redirecting is redirecting what is now refreshing the page at the same time.
So for that what we can do is we can say OK when you create a record or when you return this redirect
and we have a built in function for that Clarabelle and this one here you would just have to give it
where you want to redirect to polls.
OK let's try again let's create and different folks.
My second post answer and as you can see it says that page is now working for some reason.
All right of course we know that that's not true.
Right.
OK cool.
So why did that happen.
I don't know.
Let's try to create another one that see what the issue is.
Let's just say angular.
Yes.
Answer Scarlett on available to us this requests.
All right that's cool.
Let's let's check our
r r b list
.
It's BHB artisan actually
wrote this.
All right we're supposed to actually hit it in.
It's there but we're not hitting it for some reason but that's OK.
The reason why this might be a problem is because we've got this idea here.
All right let's just say take the video.
All right.
And let's come back and try now.
There we go is working now.
All right cool.
All right.
So instead of returning this we're going to return the view.
And the view is going to be posts in.
That's because they used the name route try that route name right here.
All right you see the column name on top.
That's what it is.
So now another way we turning that as you can see there is nothing there.
Let's just go back to that view real quick and put something in there OK.
Let's close this.
It makes it easy for us to file.
Now where we are close this aswell.
Let's go to views of those and it's so let's cancel this. All right.
So let's take some of this stuff from create and put it here.
And as a matter of fact let's take this one that's well and let's make all the area like that OK.
All right let's make everything
and I don't know why this is yielding this is not something that is
let's fix this real quick create.
It's not supposed to be yielding here anything.
We're supposed to be closing up this here and section.
So I'm going to correct that guys and that would be for all of them.
This is Section added.
Ok that's cool.
So I'm going to copy this.
I'm going to take it to where it is sitting there as well.
I'm going to take it all in.
That's that's fine.
That's it to show and take the form out.
Ok cool.
All right guys sorry about that little boy.
What was going kind of fast indeed now realize that I was copying the yield function.
All right.
But anyway.
So once we go to end that's what we want to do is actually display some of these data in here.
But we don't have any data coming to the view yet.
We have to go back to the controller and create these data and pass it through just like we did before
.
OK.
So we say post all that is was going to bring these data down.
OK let's assign it to a variable called Polsce OK.
And now here we're going to use a little function called Compact this little free the Find function
is going to take any name of variables any name that he finds in converted to a variable.
All right.
So he's going to add that little dollar sign to it.
OK.
So I think we are ready.
And let's go back to when it's let's go here.
And I'm going to create a tag here
and let's go and do this for each pose.
So that's a very well that's coming through I suppose and that is an object now.
And for each Well there is I believe that gets a collection.
Our guys if you want to find now remember that you can do the return here and return this whole thing
real quick.
And when you go back to polls Antar you can see this whole thing there.
All right.
But if you want to find out exactly what it is and you wrap it around the dye dump and you dump it out
.
OK.
And there we go.
You see the collection and we've got three of them.
One two and three.
OK.
Perfect.
So anyway let's do command Z control Z
and that.
All right.
So now we know that we have it available in the ANE That's file here.
Let's go and display some of these data.
Let's use blade.
And they say PPOs title.
There we go.
Let's look at it now.
Antar OK.
Let's go back to real quick.
We're still
returning the
let's go back here let's see what we return to we read we're making this return first That's why it
is now work.
All right.
Now let's do this.
And as you can see all the titles are here.
Pretty cool stuff right guys.
All right cool.
So now we've got three different Polsce titles this plane and we're really good to go for this lecture
OK.
I'll see you in the next one.
Take care guys.