All right welcome back.
My students are we are almost ready to send e-mail but there is one thing that we are missing that we
need to require.
We need to inquire a package Clarabell requires in order for us to send e-mail with mail gone awry.
So if I go to the doc's real quick here and you're going to say Clarabelle send email I'll show you
right now.
There is a package called Gause old HTP that we have to require.
OK.
So let's do that.
That's clear.
These are real quick and let's just require composer require his goals Gozal h t t p and then goes like
this.
All right.
Answer.
All right cool mine took like about 10 seconds there.
So now once we have this the next step is to set our view real quick.
Let's go to resources views and let's just push them actually mail here and bring some of the variables
.
Let's just say H-1 And here we're going to put the title.
Let's just say p.
And here are with I can't remember these variables are coming from the from these data array here.
This key right here are these keys.
OK.
All right so let's change this a little bit elysée.
Where are you coming back.
Let's just make sure we spell it correctly.
Why are you coming back.
I was in your neighborhood last time and I could not find my way back.
Hi.
What's up.
Has actually escaped.
There we go.
It's here and there.
All right cool.
So I think we are ready to send e-mail.
Let's go to our answer.
And we have this little problem right here OK.
All right.
So I think got an issue like this one time and I remembered the way we solve this.
And the way I solved it was going to and you can probably find a permanent solution for this.
For this Assos a difficult problem.
If you look at if you get higher and copy and paste it on google and try to find it.
I think I sold it like this.
Let me see if I will go to the vendor and we'll look for that specific specific package.
Let's make sure you synchronize that he's there for us to find it.
Gozal.
All right.
Then as it goes or this Gordis source code and here require a quick
configure the Fords here this is where we.
So let's turn this off to verification and let's make it false.
All right cool.
Nothing else that we get a check here real quick.
This is a little bit more avenges guys are not going to get into detail of all this but I'm just showing
you how to connect to an API and send e-mail.
There are many drivers out there that you can use with of L.K..
Let's make sure that this works now OK looks like it's working.
I'm going to go to my e-mail and find to see if I have something there.
All right looks like I got the message on I show it to you right here if you can see that.
You see that.
I just got it right now.
It's come in via mail gone.
We've got the title there and we've got the content.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff right.
So we are able to send e-mail with just this driver guys.
There are many other drivers.
You can also use BHB male function to do this a mandrill which is really cool.
And if you go back to your male gun statistics.
All right let's go back here and let's just check the logs.
You could see that we have some logs here that you can check.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff.
You can even build mailing lists.
And we are probably going to create a course on that to how people subscribe to our courses and to our
Web sites or applications and then send e-mails or automatic e-mails.
All right.
But on this course we're going to focus on build in our application which is not a meeting application
but but anyway routes tracking right here.
And you can see some information.
All right.
So anyway thank you so much for watching guys and I'll see you in the next lectures