All right welcome back my students are just like I promise I'm going to show you a couple of more things
about migration.
And one of the commands that I would like to do is I would like to reset everything right here because
you know I changed my mind and I don't want to have any tables anymore I want to.
Any migrations.
So if I wanted to delete all this all these tables I can.
All right.
So all I've got to do is just say let's just clear a command and say Ph.D. artists and migrate reset
Antar.
They will all roll back.
All right.
So now if you look at this Clarabell see a the only table we have is migration because what we're doing
is we're keeping track of the migrations right of the batch.
All right.
So anyway now let's migrate everything again.
So I'm going to say clear now BHP migrate.
We migrate to our tables again
and this year's refresh.
We see that we have more tables again you see how useful this is post users possible resets.
But now let me show you another one.
A really cool one is that let's say you make a change in a couple of different migrations right instead
of actually you rolling back manually and then migrating again.
Well you can do is run this command HP already send call in Refresh.
And what this is going to do is going to roll it back.
Right.
It's going to take off all the data at the tables and then is going to migrate it again for you which
is really cool.
This is what I use most of the time when I make difference when I'm testing things out.
All right.
When I edit a lot of that a lot of them instead of doing going back into an over rolling bag and then
migrating I just do a refresh.
All right.
Again you can learn more stuff if you run the BHB artists Anchorman.
And then you will have all that information right here.
Refresh you said roll back oh another cool thing is that you can also check the status so if you say
BHB artisan status
actually not now.
This one is actually migrates status sorry about that.
There we go.
You can see that.
Has this ran.
Yes.
It gives you a y for yes.
So if Fido migration reset and I do the roll a status is going to tell me has this run is going to give
me.
Didn't know.
All right.
Pretty cool stuff guys.
So anyway thank you so much for watching.
Hope you learn a bunch in this application.
I mean these lectures and we're going to be learning a lot more and when we build our application.
Right.
That's where the really juice of the course comes in.
So keep active keep motivated you're learning really cool stuff.
I don't want you sleeping if you tie your if you caught it too much.
Go take a rest.
Come back with a fresh mind and be ready to learn more.
Remember that you're doing this for you for your family you're doing it for whatever reason you're doing
and you're taking the cause and you need it.
So pay very close attention.
I don't want you to study anything else until you finish this course.
All right.
Take care and I'll see you in the next lectures