All right.
Welcome back my dear sir.
And so in this lecture you're just going to show you real quick or tell you real quick how to add a
custom domain to your application for mail gun.
Right.
So let's say for example one at the faculty or I are not going to do it because this is super simple
and we don't have a problem sending email in the last lecture.
But just in case you want your custom domain this is super simple.
Would we do this.
And then here.
All right.
Where is it.
OK.
So you've got to go to your DNS section of your domain register.
So if you're using Go Daddy you can go to domain's click on your domain manage your DNS and then there
you're going to go to our page which says domain details and then you can add a record.
So you click and record should be on the left side somewhere in Go Daddy ad wrecker and you're going
to add a techo record your horse name is going to be your wife's name and the value is going to be this
guy right here for the first têtes.
You're going to get two records.
So then you click Save or click.
I want to add another.
And then you other than that that's one you got another tetch Recker you got to put this as a host name
and then you're going to put this key this RSA key.
All right.
As a value.
And once you do that you're good to go.
OK you don't need anything else.
And now if you want the ad tracking you you add a name for it.
I mean these are auction of stuff if you want to do that.
OK.
I would add a C name if I were you.
I went to these values just to keep to track e-mails opened it clicks on subscriber fees and all of
that.
And now after that you click on continue to the main overview and there you can check to see when you
go to the next screen.
Not going to do that because this my coding faculty DNS is now hosted in GoDaddy sources somewhere else
because I have Amazon a W-S instance so I hosted with them.
So but anyway once you click here you're going to take it to a page where you can check your DNS to
see if he has propagated.
Now this thing can take from 24 to 48 hours.
I think all that it takes an hour or two more sometimes if it takes longer than two hours.
That's OK guys just give it a couple hours and then you should be good to go OK just keep checking on
that next page.
Let me see if I can go to the next page here.
All right.
So right now it says on varify and all you have to do is keep checking this and this will be agreeing
.
Believe me.
Please keep checking this every couple hours and when everything is good is going to give you the current
value on your DNS server right here.
Both of them are I should be the same as this and they should be green.
All right.
This should tell you.
But anyway thank you so much guys for watching this.
A couple of lectures is being a pleasure.
And I'll see you in the next lectures.
Take care.
Have fun cold practice.
Enjoy what you do.
Enjoy life.
Take care.