All right so after a couple hiccups in the last lecture we're way to get the comments working right
.
Pretty cool stuff though.
Laura is beautiful.
Very cool.
All right.
So I was playing around a little bit with it so we can see here that we have a comment here.
I think this will work even though I don't mind fixing bugs.
We got that one working.
Now it's time for us to start showing comments in our admin area right.
That way we can delete them all or update them or do whatever we need to do with him.
All right.
Cool.
So admin comments in this.
Let's go.
All right.
First we get a table.
At least we have something there.
All right cool.
Now that we have something there let's go to our controller real quick and try to pass something before
we try to show something right.
So let's pass as we go to controllers and post comments controller.
All right.
And that's right here.
That's Bhatt's past the comments
comments and
yeah that's fine.
Pass them right here
.
Hope you guys are having a good day.
It's really awesome to be calling today.
It's really nice weather.
Our size is like around 75 where I am pretty.
Really amazing.
I love the weather in Florida right now.
And I have an office here where I you know I used to come in and record some of these videos here so
it's pretty nice.
The weather is like around 75 to 80 85.
All right so let's go to college right now.
And now that we're passing the men we can start seeing them.
But here what I want to do is I want to say if count comments
is greater than zero we're going to show it.
And and if.
All right.
So we have some comments there.
What if we do it backwards and disappears.
So it's working.
All right.
That's just a little test there used to make sure that it's working.
That's one nail statement real quick here.
And let's just say else this poor H-1 with a class of tech center from Bootstrap and let's just say
no comments.
OK.
So let's turn this around again and see how that looks.
No comment.
He's right in the middle too.
We've got to get these comments thing out right here Friday right there.
Right.
OK.
And let's take this to rose out of here to Rose.
Let's do that for each right here.
There's two comments.
Comment
and for each one we want to see here do we care about the I-Team.
Well for us because we are in development.
Sure will.
We'll get the ID from the comment.
What else will we.
We want to see about it come and what we want to see who wrote that comment.
What else.
Their e-mail address will be nice
and calm.
Maybe a data comment.
But let's just do the common body here.
All right.
So in terms of bodies it can be really long so you guys can either create a show or view for that for
the for the comment just to see that individual comments so you can edit the whatever you want.
But I'm just going to show you here because oh let's change this thing here.
I'm going to show it here because this is mostly the supplication is moreover demonstration application
than actually something that that we are going to be.
Actually it is an application that you can take to the web and then we are going to do that at the end
of the course of course and then some of you are probably already doing that.
But some of the things that I do I do here in this course is to show you to reinforce the knowledge
that we got in the beginning of the course.
OK.
So some of that some sometimes I do things the hard way and the long wait for you guys to think and
do it a short way.
And the more creative way.
OK.
All right.
So we are actually showing really good information here.
Let's face the table headings here.
So let's turn the e-mails the next one and the body here
.
You know what it will be nice to see the post right.
That will be nice.
Let's put it right here somewhere.
Maybe we can convert this to the post so we can a comment.
Those ID actually.
Let's let's do this let's create a link here.
And this route
I think we gave them.
And the polls stay home.
The polls are out and then we just take the polls I.D. their common polls I.D. and we can say View polls
.
That's that's going to take us right to the polls.
Whoops.
If we can get it without syntax error that would be nice.
And oops what did I do here.
That looks terrible.
Really bad.
Trying to get a property in.
OK.
Let's go to comment and make sure that that comment has a post.
All right.
Public
Function.
Post
return.
This belongs to a pause.
Don't we already have this function somewhere.
Nobody nada.
OK.
There we go.
Your post goes straight to the post.
Pretty cool stuff right.
All right.
What else can we do there let's go back.
We can also count.
We can also see the replies there but we're going to do that later.
We can.
We're going to set up the replies later.
Right now we have it will be nice to wear like a little delete functionality to the lead and approve
the post.
Whoops.
So maybe a delete button right here an approved one.
So I will one click and we can pull the polls because right now these polls most of them are going to
be by default and they're all going to be on approve.
We have to come here and approve them.
So why don't we do that on the next lecture create like functionality where we are proof the post and
delete it.
All right.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.