Welcome welcome back my dear student.
So now we have created the many many to many relationship we have created this pivot table we can't
where we can relate two tables together right.
Really cool stuff.
Make sure that you understand each of them before jumping into another one right before jumping to the
next lectures.
All right.
So let's just come in all of this out.
And one thing that I wanted to point out.
All right.
Remember here we have in every med that we are also can have multiple parameters to customize the columns
.
All right.
Just in case you have different column names right.
So right here you can join two of the tables let's say for example and I do not join the table.
Right now you're saying in this many to many relationship let's say in this rules method here you want
to define the table name.
All right.
And you have let's say you have a different table name.
Let's say your team was now all user like we have in the migration right here you can find the name
of that table that you have customized.
So let's say for example your table is use or rolls.
OK this is where you find that.
All right the third parameter is going to be the key or the following key.
So we're going to say User ID.
OK.
And here you can see the roll ID.
All right I hope you see how useful this is.
All right.
So this is the foreign key are-I of the user user's table.
And this is the foreign key of the roles table.
Well here we find the name of that custom table that we can create.
Now we don't have we were following convention.
I told you the best the best way to follow.
The best way to do this is by doing roll user so that way we don't have to come here and create these
extra parameters right.
That's why we don't have to do this anymore.
All right.
And let's actually I'm going to comment this out.
So if you have any and you know what they are I'm going to come in this hour real quick here.
All right.
And a comment that out right here.
We don't have we don't need those extra parameters because we are following convention.
If not well we're using a different table and then migration different table name we would have to do
this.
All right.
So you can put a little comment here to customize
customize table names and columns.
Follow follow the format below.
All right.
You could do something like that.
All right I just wanted to give you that tip now.
Another tip that I want to also bring up is that we can also do the inverse of this relationship just
like we did before with a user right.
The user we have.
We came here with posts and we created this inverse relationship right.
So all I have to do is go to roll right here and I could create a user's method of public function users
like this.
All right there we go.
And now I just do this return.
This belongs to many and user that's all.
So if I want to return the owner of that specific role I just come here and create this relationship
right here.
You see how easy this is.
I live this the way it is right here.
But just know that is super easy to do the inverse on that.
Now another thing that I want you to learn here and this is just me maybe a a a tape lecture.
Now if you want to access the intermediate table.
All right.
Well you can do is you can go to let's say the routes Let's go to route real quick and I'll show you
right now.
This is what his lecture is mainly about.
But I took my eye to the freedom the liberty of giving you a couple of tips before.
OK.
So you could say this thing says in the intermediate table in the intermediate table here.
It's the pivot table.
OK.
So you can say pivot or some of you may have pronouns as private or look up table or something like
Does searcing and write beautiful spell check right.
So now if you want to add is that pivot table we first need to find the user right.
Or let's create a route.
Right.
Makes no sense if we don't create a route.
Well let's just say use or pivot like this.
OK.
And function
oops.
What am I doing here guys.
They're missing all this stuff.
We go.
What is is it.
What do they do.
We go to this right.
I turn myself into a mess there for a minute.
All right.
So now we we find the user.
This is what happens when you cold too many hours straight.
Right.
You start doing things in your head before you even do it in the code and you get mixed up.
So we find the user array will find user 1.
Then we get out for each loop here and we say user roles as role.
Watch this.
It's going to be pretty fun.
And you can say Go roll
it or pivot create it.
Whoops.
Here we go.
Let's find out.
They created for this intermediate.
Right.
Let's it's this is like this.
So
these are
PI that enter and created it and it's not available.
And the reason we created it might now be available is because we have to let it know to give it to
us.
Actually we misspelled misspelled or something let's just find out real quick user rules.
Because we don't have a created at all awry.
So
what's what's going on with my table roll user and
created.
We go and just do this one too.
Real quick way now.
And now we go back.
Let's see if we can find that browsers were
created a
user pivot it right.
It's making me look really bad guys.
User rules for all pivot created at home.
That's weird
.
Let's actually do this real quick return.
All right let's see if we can get something out of an answer.
There we go.
All right.
We only see the private pivot table but for some reason we don't get to create it.
But
we're supposed to get created.
Let's see if we can put a time somewhere.
Twelve five.
Let's see that works was
created at.
OK.
What about all the that's supposed to come out what is something there preventing us from seeing this
.
And I forgot.
Is has to be in the model somewhere where.
Actually hold on.
Let's go to the model real quick.
And this belongs to evil.
Let's use the pivot.
I think we have to let in all the columns that we want to pull out.
So we wanted to pull out the create it out and what was the other one.
Let's go to router real quick.
Yeah that's just for now.
I think that's all we got to do.
All right.
Let's go and enter.
No I think I mean spelling it right here.
Pivot.
Oh I'm doing the wrong place.
Guys I'm sorry.
All right let's go to user right here and there we go.
All right.
Let's see.
There we go.
We got to create it out.
Call them informational.
They are for the intermediate.
Right.
So that's pretty cool.
Make sure that you let the model know that you want to pull out that intermediate table from a column
.
All right with is met the right he almost forgot sometimes you know when I'm not used to writing with
the before Clarabelle versions you know like point lour before and other versions of four and then let
go of a 5.0 and five point one five point two and so on.
All right.
So time changes and make sure that you read the documentation make sure that you subscribe to the labo
news.
That way you can get up today with what's going on with different function idea every time they release
a new version.
Right.
So that's why it's always good to keep updated.
All right so I guess I got to read a little bit more.
And I don't Birley used as much.
So that's why I don't remember and I remember that the model itself has so many different functionalities
so many different methods and properties that you cannot even imagine to learn them all.
It's almost impossible right now to go through them all.
It is not impossible but to remember them all.
It is so if you don't use this much you're going to forget and that's why you need to do it one time
so that way you know that something is wrong and you can look it up.
All right.
But anyway thank you so much for watching.
And I hope this was very informative for you and I'll see you in the next lectures.
Bye bye.