All right welcome back my dear student.
So now that we have Lara Vale working in our work environment here in BHB environment we can make different
projects right.
All we have to do is access them by you know by their folder name and Pawlick directory.
So if we have something else like maybe blog we'll put local holes for Slash blog for slash public and
we can access our project through the browser right.
Well I think it's easier if we do something like this.
What do you think.
Blog dot tv right now that we know we know that if we visit blacked out the TV we can see our project
that we created last week right.
Instead of typing in local hosing blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Right.
Just a lot of writing to do and it's just not very professional.
Let's actually make a little change here make it so that way we can type it in just like a domain right
.
So where do we have to go.
Let's open terminal.
Right right here and let's just go to CD4 slash wherever you are in terminal to see the four slash.
Now if your command line looks a little different than mine that's because I edit my bash file.
I edit it.
So let me show you where it is.
See the little till they're close to the number one on the keyboard.
And for Slashdot bash profile.
Right.
Whoops we've got to do pseudo pseudo Nano.
And now you can see that where we created aliases we have I have this little piece of code here that
says export business one equals double cold's backslash capital W colon.
And that's why you see my command prompt like that.
All right.
I think I already told you how to do that.
Just refresh in your mind if not then you have the information now.
So control.
We're going to come out of that window because we didn't edit anything.
Ask for a date and give us a prompt.
Right.
All right.
So what we need to go from here.
We need to say sudo.
All right.
Because that's going to be the super user remember that.
And then Nanami's the editor that we are using we can use Venice well.
I like to use nano and we've got to go to far Flash applications then zap and the TC and I'm also typing
tab here all right because this autocomplete for me.
Right.
So now it's tab you see that.
And then each HTP the high and the four slash I mean tab and then enter we're going to edit this com
file.
This is the first one we're going to be editing.
Actually
let's edit the other ones.
First of all where you can have a better idea let's do control ads and let's go sudo.
All right.
I want you to get very used to the command line is very important right.
Suit on and on.
And I know that sounds strange to you but believe me the more you do with the easier it would get.
All right.
I want you to practice a lot with this.
So let's do applications again.
Let's do zap again and let's do zem files actually.
Well yes that's fine.
Zap files it.
See I'm doing good.
HTP the dot com Antar.
All right.
So in the line 400 something even though you don't see it here my editor is all the way almost in the
bottom line who's going to scroll all the way to the bottom there almost to the bottom.
And we're going to start seeing some hashes right here.
You see this he says include include include.
You're going to find a line that says virtual holes right here right below this.
Make sure this little link right here this line that they have this hash.
Make sure these are uncommented.
All right.
That's how it has to be.
Right so that way we can activate that file.
I actually TPD the holes right.
So command X and then is going to say do you want to modify.
Yes I do actually.
So why for yes and then answer.
All right so once you have that then we get to go pseudo Nano for a slash BTC and then hose like this
when a mess and then enter in here.
All right.
We're going to type in 1 2 7 0 8 0 1 which is the IP address of zem our local environment server.
Right.
And then we're going to type whatever address we want to type in the browser when we want to open our
application.
So in this case we already have CIMS right.
So let's use that lets do CMOS.
Even for development.
And you know while you can do whatever you want so if you want to put that app that's up to you.
Right.
Or whatever.
Even dot com which I don't recommend that you don't want to confuse your browser right.
But anyway the Evely There we go.
And then control X and then Y and then enter.
Beautiful.
All right so that's done.
The next thing is we want to go to.
Now let me show you a trick if you press the the key the the arrow keys the up arrow key on your keyboard
you can go in to the last command.
So you don't have to type everything again.
Right.
So we got to go to this one actually to the holes all right and then enter because we already type Dawan
and this grow all the way to the bottom here.
And we got some dummy têtes.
This is what we need to wear it to make this work.
This is where we're going to be placing our project on a different project.
So if I have a seam CIMS that that death we're going to pull one of those for the DAT def and then if
I have to do less outdoor to do less he another.
Another block of this four to do less than and so on and so on for every level.
Clarabelle project or big Claribel project would create one of these are-I we got an opening virtual
host tag and we'll have a close in one.
And then this cold in between now you don't have to type all everything inside there right.
But anyway let's go up and right here and between this line here I want you to type in something for
me right.
So what we're going to be tapping in super simple.
All right.
Let me know when you ready.
So you ready.
All right.
Let's go into it.
So we're going to say name all right name virtual holes.
Got it.
All right name.
And then virtual host you see camel case everything.
The first word.
All right make sure you spell it correctly.
OK.
And then the asterisk and then call in 80.
All right cool.
So now let's go to this one here first.
As a matter of fact I forgot something but I'm going to do it in a minute but that's OK let's just do
it like this first.
All right.
So we're going to let's see if we can edit this and make it work the way it is.
Sometimes I really need to modify it a lot but let's see if this time we can make it work.
So let's do the first ones here and then make this the localhost and we have to set the fourth one for
that.
So I'm going to do zem files H.T. talks.
All right I'm going to leave this like this.
Doesn't matter server name right is going to be local host.
We don't even need an alias for that but it's up to you if you want to do it
right.
Do local host
a.
And you don't have to have a narrow log for that either.
It's a matter of fact and take that off.
I'm going to do control I'm going to put my cursor right in the first line of the control K to take
up the whole line and you can see this instructions down here guys.
All right.
All right this is all control control why control the control cage you cut the tax.
So you have some instructions there you can go to the next page by control V at them etc..
All right so I'm going to go here and control.
OK.
All right I think that's OK for this.
And take that off too.
If you want to leave there a log that's good.
If you want that that's fine to use.
Put the name of your site you do replace this with a name where your sight array.
Very easy.
I'm going to take it off and you can leave it very simple like this.
All right.
So the second one I'm going to make it.
So it goes to my
see a mess.
All right.
So to do the docs CIMS Pawlick.
So it goes to our IT SEEMS Clarabelle project right.
And the server name very important guys.
Without this it will now work.
All right.
Let's do CMOS.
The eevee.
All right.
You can change this if you want if you want to put your email address whatever.
That's OK.
All right.
So this should work out of the box like this one not not at the bottom.
I mean we've made some modifications here right.
There's let's do control X and then yes Antar.
Now the next thing we got to do is do a restart.
And I hope we encounter some issues so that we I can help you with with the issues arising.
You don't have to go and google or anything like that.
If you have any problems you can always put posted in the discussion and we'll try our best to help
you out.
So I'm going to restart all right here.
I'm a way for this to start and then I'm going to try and that address on my browser.
And I want you to do the same thing.
OK.
All right let's wait for it
.
There we go.
So let's do CMOS daddy the answer.
And as you can see it's working.
Now let's real quick create a new project just to make sure that this works OK.
We don't want it to to be playing games with us.
There's a local holes real quick.
OK local's is working as well.
All right.
Let's do one more so let's go to terminal.
All right and let's go to see the let's go to our
HD docs right.
So Zahm remember with tab you can auto complete it.
So the docs see a mass actually right here and actually does that's what we want to be.
And then we're going to say composer create project Laro Vale which is a name and the name of the vendor
and the name of that package right.
Because you can download different applications with composer.
Now we want to name it something like I don't know to do app.
All right.
And then I use of are going to use 5.2 but you can use if you do the professor remember that I would
download the latest.
All right the latest Clarabell version.
All right 5.2.
That's where I'm going to do right here Antar.
Now we've got a way for that.
All right.
Beautiful.
So I hope you can see how easy this is I going to pause the video because this is going to take a little
bit of time and I'll come back in a couple of seconds for you is going to be like one second.
All right.
So hold on tight.
All right looks like he's done with mine.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go back.
All right let's go and press our up arrow key and we edit our V h the TPD the horse.
We also have to edit our host files so let's edit our host files first so sort of nano for was last
E.T. see and then we let me just clear it for a minute so you can see the commands
right there.
Let's press our error up arrow key.
Let's go to this one.
Let's put a password.
This is our computer password by the way.
I have a password so that's why I have to type it in all the time.
If it's a special file so I'm going to the one to seven.
OK.
And then whatever name I want.
So I wanted to use to do web dot dev.
All right.
Then control x and y for yes and enter.
So the next one is going to press the up arrow key again my keyboard.
And then I go to the videos file enter.
Now let's go all the way to the bottom.
I'm going to copy one of these guys.
OK and you can put comments on these guys so just in case you don't get confused I'm going to command
V it. so I'm going to basically paste it here.
You can do something like this.
All right so you don't get loss hash symbol and then you can put the name on your side whatever that
is.
So I'm going to say to do app.
All right and this one is a C See mess.
Def
So we're going to do for this Wongs changed this for a year to name to do to be named in this one here
.
Do
you also want to make sure that you have a folder with you.
All right.
Because many times I tell you that I have done this and I've been going crazy.
Next thing you know I never created a project for some reason he failed.
All right.
So go to the dogs and make sure you have that for them there.
Anyway let's do control it's an wife.
Yes.
And then for now we have to restart zap again.
All right.
So I'm going to restart it.
And then all we have to do after that is just try it out to see if it works ok.
It should work fine.
And other than that we've got to do some time to test that to make sure that it's working is that we
have to go inside the project with our editor and make some type of edit to our home page so that way
we know that it is working 100 percent because sometimes we redirect to Claribel 5 with every single
domain name and you would not know if he's working on unless you make a change or one of them.
All right so now it looks like he's working to do app that the enter and you see this.
Now it's now working and let me tell you why.
Because we're using the zap environment we have to give it permission.
Remember the watcher you don't remember.
Maybe you do.
Actually we did it on this Mac installation.
We gave it permission so we have to give to the owner of this server permission to write to the Zap
.
Right.
So let's do that.
So I'm going to go to my age detoxing and my command line that's where I am and I'm going to type in
this command.
If you remember them very simple let's do it.
So let's do c h m all D.
All right.
Then we're going to do this recursively so we put the flag are all plus W. which means right.
And then the application name which is to do app for Slash storage.
All right answer.
And now we go back to it.
There we go.
Now it works.
All right.
So beautiful.
All right before I go I just want to say that if for some reason you have a problem you have a internal
arrow 500 or four or four page or access Forbin.
Something's gone gone wrong in our patch is now recognizing your requests.
All right.
I'm going to recommend to do something right now so that what you have you don't have any problems with
permissions we most of these problems that you that you could have where your application is because
of Apache now recognizing the user not having permissions to write to the files right.
So your application does not have permission to write it to the files only certain people can do it
and certain users.
So that's why you might have a problem.
So for that I'm going to recommend this.
I want you to go to let me see if I have it right here.
Your applications and folders and files etc..
H.T. TPD dot com.
That's a file you're going to edit enter.
Make sure that you do Suro then OK to be an administrator a super user.
Let's go all the way down.
I'm going to scroll this file all the way down to where we can see the user right here you see right
here says user daemon.
All right that is the default user right.
That's zem ports there.
So that way this is a user that is allowed to do certain things in the server.
Right.
What are we going to change that.
I'm going to put a hash there because I want to keep it just in case for future reference but I'm going
to say I'm going to put it all in uppercase user and then the user that I'm using right now on this
computer on this desktop I'm using coding faculty right here for this.
This user's computer is called coding faculty.
This is the guy or me right.
There's going to be creating the application right.
But now we get to basically give you access to right to files right and reef files and all really cool
stuff in the server right.
So coding faculty is going to be my user command x and y for saving enter.
All right.
Now the next thing is starting Apache restarting it.
So I'm going to restart it right here.
And as a matter of fact stop or I'm going to restart or.
OK.
All right.
Once you do that let's go back real quick and let's just see if we don't have to give it permission
like we used to do like you know the problem that we had when we had to give a permission to that specific
for the let's create a new installation and check that out before we leave.
OK.
So let's go to zap.
Actually applications zap and HD docs and writing actually docs let's create a new level of approach
your real quick composer create
project Clarabelle Clarabelle and we can call this this new application we can call it a we have to
do that.
We have a CMOS let's make it a crazy app just to give an example hereright crazy app and we're going
to do use 5.2 steel here.
And when I do prefer distro distribution.
OK
.
Application just finished I just post a video real quick.
So now let's go to to see the file to see if it is working without doing the the holes.
All right.
So let's go Lokos Ray localhost and is call crazy.
So I have it right here enter in as you can see works and we don't have to give no more permissions
so since we already have that permission.
I'm good with it.
OK.
So if you do this this way if you give from the beginning you do this this way you're good to go I just
wanted to show you both ways of doing it.
All right.
So that way you can defend yourself when you have a problem in another scenario OK.
But anyway as you can see we're able to do it like this.
And you know we can delete that of course.
I'm going to go back in the lead that crazy app.
Let's just check it.
Let's just say.
Or am I friend or F..
And then crazy because I'm going to remove it.
All right so now you know how to do it the hard way and the easy way.
Anyway thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.