All right welcome back my students so let's finish this let's see if we can finish it without any hiccups
.
But if we have any hiccups don't worry about it let's just fix them right.
Let's we just fix them.
All right so we're going to grab here the use of spools.
All right.
We've got to use the method in this case because we are using another book chaining stuff right.
We're going to change another method you want to change the chain the create method and then return
the redirect.
Right.
And we're going to redirect back to admin folks.
All right let's check this a little bit here.
Just make sure that we are good.
Let's go to our requests.
All right category has to be there list shows for now let's just do this right because we don't have
category right now.
We have a like a static thing going static value here.
We just want to create a pulse to see if it works OK.
All right let's go try this and see if it works.
If not we'll fix it.
My second post and let's put an image here.
Let's just call this placeholder.
I don't know Clarabelle pictures are going to get a Larabee pictures for you guys.
All right.
So placeholder there.
I love this stuff man Loughran though.
This of the chain.
Something like that.
Cool.
There we go.
So we were able to create a post.
The owner is Edwin D.S.O. of pulling out the owner.
Now if you go back to that end it's let's use bring all these down real quick resources.
Let's go back to polls and it's Remember that we're pulling out the owner.
All right.
We're pulling out the owner right here.
OK.
All right.
Let's go to the database real quick let's refresh and see that we have the user ID.
I mean the idea of the force and then we have the user id right here.
So we were able to relate those to the polls and the users table by doing their relationship right here
.
Well by using that relationship because we already did the relationship.
All right cool.
So now what we got to work on next.
And we also have the photo I.D. guys.
All right.
And let's check on the photo real quick.
And looks like we do have a photo right here right here.
All right.
This image Let's double check our public images to synchronize.
It's a little bit but I think he's this one here.
Yep place holder.
All right.
So we're getting everything there.
Beautiful.
So now the next step for us is to work on the
work on the categories right.
We've got to work on the categories and so we can give each post a category that would be really cool
.
All right.
So less on the next video we're going to start working more on the posts to make sure that they have
a category to make sure that we display stuff in the correct order.
So you know let's do that after we create a category because right now we don't have category but we
do have a picture so we can work on that.
Also in the next lecture Lexie we have some time OK too so we don't make the video too long.
What if we don't we just split the videos right with the lectures.
Anyway thank you so much for watching guys.
It was a pleasure.
And I'll see you in the next lecture