All right my dear students let's go to the next one.
Categories.
All right.
Let's click on it.
They work in because we build some rules for it.
Let's just come back here and say javascript intermedia intermediate
level 1.
All right.
And it's put a category there.
While it's working.
All right.
We you have to do much here.
Level 2.
And these are actually my courses guys usually my courses is updated.
Nice.
We got categories working beautifully.
All right.
Now we might have create a couple other
name routes that we don't need for category so go ahead and delete those if you if we have any extra
ones.
All right.
But anyway so create categories Ooh create does not exist.
We made a mistake here somewhere.
Let's go and change it.
All right.
So let's go to Web and category's store.
And this is in the controller actually we have a problem and the control is meant to create does not
exist.
So
that's that's a new one of the main categories
and it's true.
I don't see the method create here.
Well let's try.
We don't have a mess to create.
All right.
It does not exist.
So when we click on Create here it's supposed to create it in the same page.
So this is supposed to probably a custom method or something that we have created in the last lecture
.
Let's go back and check it out.
So we have adenine categories here.
Nice.
Not cost them
.
Check out our out.
Real quick
.
I mean category's that's what I'm looking for
It's a post and it's going to cargo's controller store.
So
what's going on.
There we go.
This is where we this is where he's going supposedly.
All right.
So when I click here
is adding
and it's working fine now.
When I click Update
everything's working fine.
Oh OK.
OK OK.
Can we never created a gosh guys I forgot we have that link there for nothing we never created that
link.
So why don't we just take that off because he's going to confuse the whooshes out was right.
Let's take this off.
We never created this.
Now guys this is because I haven't been in the in this application for a little bit.
I have been busy so let's take that off.
We don't need it.
I don't know what I was thinking back then when I left out there.
So let's go to resources.
You probably were wondering what is he doing there.
We don't have that.
Shame on you.
You didn't tell me.
So let's do
this is actually in layouts an issue being admin right here.
Let's just take that off.
She's fresh.
There we go.
Let's say it was along.
All right.
So we're good to go here.
All right guys.
Now one thing that we need to make sure and you need to make sure is that all these fields are evaluated
.
All right so make sure that you have that intact right now don't worry the end of this fix up that we
do this upgrade.
We will make sure that our application is not submitting empty feels like this one here by creating
a validation point.
If it's if we have not created it if you already have created and we already have created it live with
the way it is but my application right now is not validating against empty fields.
All right.
Maybe yours is.
I'll see you in the next lecture.