Let's download and run the sample app so that you can see what to expect.
We'll build the Docker image with the app using the provided Docker file,
then run a container locally so you can see what it does before
you deploy it to your Kubernetes cluster.
The demo.zip file contains everything you'll need to create a
Docker image for the sample application.
This simplifies the Docker image setup as our main focus is
how to deploy to the Kubernetes cluster.
App.py is the flask app,
and the dockerfile and requirements files will be used
when we create the Docker image.
As you can see, this is a very simple REST service.
Version 1 of the application returns Hello from application and a counter.
This is purely for demo purposes to see how the requests are
handled by different instances of the application running on
different pods in Kubernetes.
Version 2 of the application says, Goodbye from application,
plus the same counter.
Let's start up the application so you can see what it does.
Navigate to the demo directory, then run the application.
The command is python app.py.
With the application running, we can check port 5000 on localhost.
Here is the message from the application.
If I refresh, you can see the counter incrementing.
Now that you see what the application does,
let's take a look at the Docker file.
This will simply use a python: 3.8 -slim-buster image as the base,
copy the requirements file so that flask can be installed,
copy the source, then start up the app.
Let's build an image using the Docker file.
Right now I have no images on my local machine.
I'll run a Docker build.
Now we can see the image that was just built.
Note the image id, as you'll need this later.
Let's run this Docker image in a container.
We'll map port 5000, then give the image id of what we just built.
The application is up.
I’m running this on a cloud machine so I'll hit the URL,
and here we can see the message from the application.
You can download the sample files, commands, and links to documentation under the Exercise Files section of this course.