Let's go to the AWS web console and check out a few things.
First, we'll take a look at the cluster and registry.
Next,
we'll check out the monitoring offered through
CloudWatch for your AWS resources.
Finally, we'll visit the billing section.
To access your cluster, search for EKS.
Here you can see your EKS clusters,
then drill into each one to find out additional information.
Note that the EKS managed node groups are not shown in the AWS console.
To access the container registry, search for ECR.
Here we can see our demo repository.
If we drill in, we can see the 1.0 and the 2.0 images that we've pushed.
To view your underlying instances, search for EC2,
select Running instances,
and here you can see the instances running in the cluster.
You can also see the Auto Scaling group that is managed by EKS.
Next let's go to CloudWatch.
CloudWatch will automatically gather metrics on your underlying AWS
infrastructure such as the elastic load balancers,
EC2 instances, disk and network.
There are several different options including third-party integrations.
We won't cover those in this course.
Next, let's check out the billing.
Here we can see the charges from the Elastic Kubernetes Service,
then our underlying EC2 nodes.
There are several options available for creating budgets and managing costs, but we won't get into those because this is a new account.