With all that out of the way right before we dive into the optional angle or refresher.
I already want to lay out the app will built.
Now I did show the app of course here still the theory behind it or here are building blocks on a slide.
We'll have a welcome part.
A welcome component which will create and will also create a training section.
This is the section where we'll be able to start new trainings and also of course then view to current
training and past trainings.
Finally we'll also have a off section where users are able to log in or sign up now to be precise for
the training part.
We'll need an exercise model which simply is like the day that definition what will work with will work
with exercises here.
And as I said will have a component for the active training and for creating a new training and a summary
component for the past training and I right components there because of course they use multiple components
all the angular material will all they have a training service to manage our data.
And for the off part build therefore have a user model to describe a user or off data model I could
say so which credentials do we need and then we'll have sign up and sign in components as well as an
off service.
Now we might add more for the course.
But that's the general structure.
So did you have an idea of how this is planned out.
Now after the next orbital module we'll dive right into it and we'll start learning Anglo material but
it will be learning on the job we'll already start building up there to.