We had a look at the angular Fornes at least a very brief one.
And number important concept of angular our services services our typescript classes which can be reached
from any component which to be precise can be injected into any component or actually also into Abner's
services.
Let's create a service to understand it.
I'll name it products service sort of fall as product start service start.
TS The name doesn't really matter but it's a convention to name it like this.
A service is then just a type of class like this one product's service.
Now a service holds some functionality which you typically want to share across multiple components.
This could be data what you want to use from other components.
It could be utility functions like logging something or sending HTP requests here.
I'll simply create my products array in the service and let's say it starts with just a book.
No actually set this to a private property and add two methods to the service and product where I expect
to get a product name which is a string and where it will simply reach out to disk products and push
the new product name onto it.
And get products where I want to return desire and it could just return this products though I will
actually return a new array and use the spread operator and next generation javascript feature which
will take the older eight this products and pull out all the elements to add them as new elements to
this new array.
This creates a new copy of that array because arrays and objects are referenced types.
If I returned this product like this.
So directly dicere we could edit it from outside.
Since the returned copy would just be a copy of the pointer pointing to the same place of memory.
With this approach we get a brand new array.
So if we edited from outside we won't change this array here.
Now we get that service and let's say we want to use this service for creating new products.
Now we need to inject it somewhere for an injection works like this.
Let's say in the products component where we add products there.
I want to use the service for this.
I will simply go to the constructor and add an argument products service.
Now I want this to be an instance of our service class.
For this we have to assign a type here products service and for typescript to find this we need to add
an import.
So at the top of the import statement re-import product service from dot slash product start service.
Now this will tell Engler which is the one creating a new instance of this component in the end that
we need this argument when this component is created and that that should be of this type.
So Engler will try to give me an instance of this type to be able to do so.
We need to tell it how to do so though and we do that by simply adding something in the app module.
Here in the provider's array we need to provide anything that we want to inject into any place of the
app.
So here I need to add my product service and I also need to add my import to it so that typescript can
find it.
Slash products service is the payoff.
With that angler is able to resolve this dependency and actually create a new instance of it and provided
here in this class in the component here.
Now we can use that has matured had an ad private in front of this or public it's up to you.
And this will now not only receive it as an argument but automatically bind it to a class property.
So it is a short way of not only getting that argument but also storing it in a class property.
And now we could use that service instead.
So instead of pushing to that local aere I could point us to this product service and product and then
push this form value product name or send this to that service.
Now of course I also want to use the products from that service and using it in the same file.
As we said it does not make the most sense because we could have managed it internally then but typically
used to move data across components but let's ignore that for a second and let's say that now I want
to also get my products from there.
So in the constructor of simply said This products equal to diss products service get products like
dis and all initially set this here to an empty array so that we can really see the difference.
Now it is safe to I go back you'll see that if I go deep it indeed will load my products from the service
after three seconds because it placed as in the time or as I just realized.
So let's move out of there just in the constructor body like this.
So now it's showing it there.
And then an even better place for this initialization is the energy on it hook a lifecycle hook which
we implement by implementing a special interface an interface is like a contract that forces us to have
a special method in this component we need to import on in it from an angular core and we simply add
a new method now which we now are required to get entry on and it's angular will execute this method
when it creates the component offered the constructor and it's a good practice to do anything but very
trivial initializations in this method here.
So now we will still get the same behavior as before if we load this page we will get our product from
the service if we add new products.
Now though we don't see it but we also don't get an error or the reason for this is that we only fetch
two products one time future updates are not reflected.
That is why we typically use a pattern here where we set up a subscription to get informed about changes.
For this we import something which is called a subject from our exchange as object is like an event
emitter.
And here I get an error message though this is the correct important text starting with our exchange
as worse than six.
If you're using an older wurden to correct one what we are ex-chief slash subject.
So here we're importing the subject.
And now with that we can create a new property in the service which is maybe products updated which
is a new subject like this.
We now want to emit and even food that subject whenever the products change.
So here an ad product all emit products updated by calling next year not emit just next and we can't
pass data with that if we wanted to.
So here I could simply pass this products but we can all just use this to trigger a new fetch So with
that create it we can go to our products component and an NGO in it or now actually fetch the products
but then I'll also reach out to the product service and reach out to products updated.
And here we can now call subscribe.
This will now keep us informed about changes.
We pass a function to subscribe where we get the value that was emitted.
In this case and on and then we to find a code that should be executed when ever this triggers.
And here is just the same code we had before where we wanted to fetch new products.
This code here will run an unlimited amount of times though when ever the products change.
Essentially Now when we set up a subscription like this it is a good practice to also unsubscribe.
If we don't need it anymore.
So we should import subscription from our exchanges and store it here in a property private property
maybe which has the products subscription which is a type subscription and we simply
WIPs that subscription here and the import too.
And we simply use that and store this subscription in it.
So the SUBSCRIBE method here returns a news subscription which is stored in a product subscription.
We now need to import one other interface which is called On destroy.
It's also imported from at angular clor and that requires us to now add another method DNG on the stroy
method and where engine that runs when the component is created.
This runs What does tear down.
And at this point of time we should actually unsubscribe.
So reach out to my subscription and call unsubscribe.
This clears up the resources and prevents memory leaks.
Now the cool thing is with this pattern.
Now if we add a new product it does show up because our subscription our triggers and we don't fetch
products again.
Now let's complete this by also using the service and the number of component in the product component
here.
We can also add the injection and directly bind it to a property products service.
His name is up to you.
But thereafter you need to find a type and at the airport at the top.
Never forget this statement here.
And with that and check that in the product component when we click a component instead of emitting
our event we can just reach up to the product service and call delete product method there and pass
this product name to define which kind of product to be deleted.
Now this method that doesn't exist yet.
So let's quickly create it in the product service here you will get the product name of the product
which should be deleted.
And then we can just call this products and set it equal to this products filter.
So the same logic we have before for products where the product name is not equal to the product name
we sent so that all our products are kept except for this one.
And thereafter we should again trigger our subscription with the next call to inform anyone who's interested
that our array of products changed with that.
If I now add a new product that works if I click on one it's still deleted.
But now all of that is handled through the service and does the services in a nutshell.
There is of course more to them.
We will use them for this course but this should give you a brief refresher about how they work and
how you work with subscriptions to also create live updating services.