So let's dive into angular material now.
What is angular material angular material is a third party package which you can use in angular projects.
It's developed by a team which is part of the official English team you could say.
And in its core it's one thing and angular components.
Now what does this mean.
It means it's a collection of three built and styled angular components components as you could belt
them on your own in your project.
You obviously build your entire angular app from components.
Well here you get a package of a lot of components you commonly need in angular abs or in any apps and
these components follow the material design spec which is the design spec created by Google a couple
of years ago which they use in their Android operating system and which is all really popular in the
web.
Now one important note using Engler material does not mean did you don't create any components on your
own anymore.
You will still build your application of your own components.
But if you need something like let's say a tap's component or a button that follows the material design
spec enhanced is ripple effect when you click it or something like this.
Then there is a component in the angular material package which you can't just import into your project
and use it if you don't have to trade on your own because some of these components like for example
tabs where you can switch between different content to be displayed.
Of course are a bit more complex behind the scenes angle material also is something else or actually
can be thought of as two packages.
You got one package which focuses on let's call it component building utilities and we get a second
package which Dan has a concrete component implementations using that material the signed spec.
The first feature set is bundled in a package called angler's CDK CDK stands for component development
kit.
Now this does not include any angular material styling.
This does not include the concrete component implementations.
This has a lot of utility and helper methods and classes for example for rendering overlays for positioning
elements and some raw.
Components like for example a data table which is a very complex component behind the scenes.
You will always use both when working with angular material though because the second package here which
has two concrete implementations is the one you import under angular material.
This is the package which gives you access to all these Angelyn material components which will have
a look at the second which are restyled and which behind the scenes build up on that CDK kit or on that
CDK package I should say.
Which is why you need that as a dependency.
Now let's take a closer look at what's in there or what the angle material package comprises.