It's time you built our first component.
But before we do that let me quickly also mention to good repository of the Anglo material project.
You can simply click on the Get Up Link on material dot angular dot.
I know this is word yangs material project or package Estival up.
You can check out the latest release by clicking on the releases link here.
There you can find bug fixes and breaking changes.
And you'll also find a list of all the English material components with notes a link to the documentation
as well as planned components.
So this might be interesting to you if you plan on using this in your next project and you don't know
if something is implemented or what's coming what's in the pipeline and what the latest change brought.
Now with data out of the way it's really time to get started and not just look at these components but
use them.