We want to control the layout of our singular applications.
And a great is actually not part of the angular material package.
There is another package though it's called angular flex layout.
If you google for angular flex dash layout you should find to get a page here.
Now there you will also find a couple of quick links like tear to the API documentation.
You click on that documentation is a bit confusing to be honest.
But we will go through it together.
The important part here is flex layout is a package that uses flex blocks C S S flex blocks behind the
scenes to allow you to position your components and elements of a couple of nice directives these directives
can be found under documentation.
You're on the right by clicking on static and responsive API.
Let's start with the static one.
There we get an overview over the core directives F X.
Lay out can be added to any container element to control how the child elements should be positioned.
They should be positioned in a row so next to each other or a column below each other.
You can also reverse that you can order to find the alignment.
So should it be centered or not.
And we get this strain main and cross access part here.
Now the reason for it is that as I said use flex blocks behind the scenes.
So we will all have a short look at flex box in a second before we do so.
Let me talk about the child components though because if X layout was for wrapping element the child
component gets eFax flex to simply take all available space and evenly distributed across all child
elements and you can also change this and for example give one a higher percentage and Yabrud and so
on.
But we'll do this in a second.
Let's talk about flex box first.
To do this I will quickly add a new code here and use Section 2 hour sign up page and there.
I will just add a couple of diffs So here this def will receive an ID of Child 1.
The next one simply a duplicate gets Child 2 and the third one gets child free and the second year will
get the ID container.
This is only some temporary addition to showcase whole flex box works.
And of course it will be a short introduction if you want to learn more.
You can find useful links at the end of this module.
So this is our container.
These are our charts.
Let's go to these CSSA fall of this component and add some styling for the container.
So for the element of the container ID the section here.
And for the different Charles lets start with the container there we can turn this to use flex blocks
by adding display flex if we do this we won't see much though because I need to give these tiles some
styling so quickly all add a class to each of them and somebody named this child.
Now NDC is as follows.
I'll add the child class here and set the width of 200 pixels and a height of 200 pixels and a background
color of red.
If we go back to our running application everything's red.
Now to see a difference.
I will actually not assign a background color here but use my individual child IDs to give a child one
a background color.
Of red child to a background color of green
child reep a background color of blue like this
now we can see a difference.
And one thing we can see is that if I increase the width of this it will only increase to a certain
point until each box has its 200 pixels of width if I decrease the window all shrink equally.
So they don't stick to their 200 pixels with date decrease and size.
And that's one part of what flex box does.
If I give the container a whiff of let's say 100 percent and I remove the with on a child and instead
give each child a special property flex where I just said one is a value you'll see that now they all
increase in width infinitely because flex 1 basically tells them to take all available space and distribute
it equally.
If I gave for one child let's say Child 1 a flex value of two.
It will take twice as much space as the average ones.
You can see this.
It's doubled the size of the average flex elements and just ratio stays constant even as I increase
and decrease the with notices.
Flex box here.
We can also go back to the container and add flex dash direction a special property we can use if we
added display flex and set this to column.
The default was wrote Cullom now changed the way DS elements in a container are positioned now they're
position beneath each other instead of next to each other.
So now we get the same behavior as before.
But the direction changed.
And now this is important for the cross and the main axis because we can also now define how it should
be positioned.
If I remove these flex elements here for now and I reintroduce my with we can see that now they're all
stuck on the left because they get the width of 200 pixels and the direction is color.
So from top to bottom this is the so-called main axis the main axis always follows the direction we
defined here.
So either from top to bottom of the column case or from left to right in the row case or actually from
bottom to top in the column or the worst case and the same for rope.
But let's stick to row and column.
So here the main axis goes from top to bottom if we now add a number property to the container not to
the child but to the container which is called justified content.
We can set this to center.
Now if you have a look at this.
Nothing changed because this defines how d elements are positioned along the main axis so from top to
bottom they're centered.
But since our height here automatically takes the height of all summed up elements.
We don't see that effect.
We can see it.
If we assign a height that's greater than the height of the recombined elements.
So for example 700 pixels to see the wrapping container.
I can also get this a border if one picks a solid and black.
Now with that set up we see the container this black border part and we see that the elements are centered
in it because of justify content's Center which Center them along the main axis which goes from top
to bottom.
That's why they're right in the middle of it.
You also want to send them here horizontally since our flex directions Cullom we have to center them
on the so-called cross axis to cross axis as always.
Well the opposite of the main axis the main axis is defined by the flex direction the crust Texas in
this case for flex direction Cullom would be from left to right and you can use a line item sphere to
define how to position them along the cross axis.
For example flex and what pushed him all the way to the end.
So you're right.
In this case and of course you can also use Center to position them there.
If you now switch back to flex direction row you will see that they are now positioned from left to
right and they're still centered but now actually main and cross axis switched the main axis now goes
from left to right.
The cross exits from top to bottom.
The main axis is positioned with justified content to cross axis with a line items.
So let's go to the main axis and change this to flex start.
And before we change flex direction this would have pushed them all the way up.
But now since we go from left to right it pushes them to the right.
And this is how you have to think about flex blocks that can be confusing at first but it actually really
makes sense you turn a container into a flex container with this plate flex you to find a direction
with flex direction and you can position elements along a main axis and the cross axis and for each
child you can find a width and height or give it flex 1 to take all the way of space or even change
to ratio here.
Now there's more to flex box but for introduction this is all you need.
If you want to learn more check out the last lecture in this module you will find some useful links
there.
Now with that let's get rid of all this CSSA code here and let's start working on this and the next
component and see how this angular flex layout package helps us.