We added the date picker.
Let's now add a number map for field for the last control I want to add to does sign up for.
And that should be a checkbox which ensures that the user confirmed the terms and agreements of our
page.
Let's say a pretty common use case.
Now for that we got a separate component which we can use.
The mad dash checkbox component.
Now we of course need to add an import to material module for that.
So from an angle or material I'm going to import the matte checkbox module here.
Wrap that and add it to both imports and exports of course so that it's a way label everywhere.
Now with that added We can use it in the sign up component and Matt checkbox takes the label that should
be displayed next to it between the opening and closing tag.
So maybe agreed to terms and conditions and of course you could put some link in there which actually
links to your terms and conditions page.
Now by default the label here is positioned offered a checkbox or put in other words the checkbox is
positioned in front of the label.
You can change this behavior though.
But before we do that that's safe doesn't go back to your app and you will see that we get an error
because the checkbox actually is not trapped by a foreign field because it's no input.
And if you remember the documentation of math form field you probably will recall that it only listed
inputs and text areas as developed children as well as other components like mad Aromat hint they picker
which interact with the form feuilleton checkbooks however works stand standalone.
So if you save it like this now it works and you see the checkbox here you now all see that the checkbox
is centered because we had our eFax lay out a line set to center here for all the inputs.
For me that's fine.
We can't absolutely centredness here.
Now back to that label thing though if you go back you can add something to that checkbox.
You can at the label position property binding and set this to before you save this.
Now the label is actually in front of the checkbox.
So this is the alternative you have.
I'm going to switch back but I want to bring this to your attention.
You can change the positioning of the label now and back to the default where it comes after checkbox.
Now even though it's not wrap by Matt form field checkbooks is still compatible with Angey little forms.
So we can and we of course should still gift is Angi model and a name like agree maybe and we can also
add the required validator to make sure that this is actually required and the whole form is only deemed
valid if we did add it.
By the way we should also add and model to the date picker input here.
So there at the end I'll add and you model and the name of birthdate.
I will also add required here.
Would that be added validation to all our fields.
Now we got our whole for belly data and controlled if I had to submit everything is invalid here.
As you can see still or automatically it gets some styling.
And if we have a look at the submitted form here on the value we can see a birth date email and password.
All of course MTV I do check is an assessment again.
Then on the newly submitted form we would see that it reset to truth.
So this works.
One important note I also want to share.
You can also change the theme of the checkbox so not just the position of the label but you can also
set a color property and set this to primary for example the default was excellent year so that the
checkbox wasn't is pink color.
Now it's actually in the primary purple color.
This is how we can set this all up.
Now let's finish up the form by improving the positioning of the submit button so that there's a little
bit more space and also making sure we can only click it if the entire form is valid.