So within just the work on our toolbar and site that thus far at least Now one thing I want to prove
is that all the logic for toolbar and site navigation lefse and the app component.
I don't want to have that all in the app component.
A better approach in general and angular is to split your app into multiple smaller components so that
each component on its own doesn't contain that much code that makes it's easier to maintain and to understand.
So for the app component we got the science half year and we got the toolbar.
Now I will actually leave the site in here.
So the math side of the container but the magnae of list that can be outsourced into its own component.
And for the tool bar we can outsource the entire toolbar into its own component.
So quit Engy Servier and with MGG all generate a new component and place it in the navigation folder.
So the component I create is navigation slash and then I'll name it header and to add it to the right
module I'll add dash dash module app dot module.
With that it will create this new component in that folder.
Now create a second component in the same folder.
And this one will be named side nav list.
So these are two new components now created in the navigation folder.
With that I can restart as you serve.
And now the goal is simple get the content from the app component into the respective newly created
components.
The difficult part will be to ensure that we still can click that toggle button in the tool bar and
trigger something in the side nav which will now be in a different component.
But step by step.
Let's take the madness of list here from the app component and cut it and let's add it to the side nav
list h him out file like this.
So now we gather here and we already get an error.
The side nav isn't found because remember this is referring to the local reference side Neph which we
have in the app component.
The thing about local references is that they are well local so we can only access it in the app component
and not an average components.
And that's the issue here and we'll solve this later.
For now let's leave it as it is.
And one thing we have to do though is in this site NAF list we need some styles.
So from the components siestas file we certainly want to take the links and the caption with us and
it to the site nav lists as file so that the things are still styled.
All right.
Now already drapped the link stylings here.
And also add them to the hetero component and yes you could also outsource them in some global style
file but you're able to find it differently because it also it wouldn't be that strange to use different
styles in the different parts so different style and deciding immigration than the tool bar here it's
the same but still is duplicate code in this part the hetero component HMO part of course all those
should be populated and it will be populated with the entire match toolbar component and whatever it
wraps from my app component.
So let's cut that and add it to the team I'll follow the hetero component like this.
Here we also have the issue of not reaching science.
So is the issue we want to work on.
We now get cleaned up see as as components.
Yes s and h mail file we now can add app header here above our router outlet to use our newly created
header component which has this app headers selector and of course you use the site nav list inside
of our app component.
Matt side nav select are here like this.
Now we need to make Does chain work again so that we can click a button to header and toggle this side.
And the same for Decide Neph list where we click a link and then we want to close the site.
Now to do that let's start with the header there on a click we call the toggle method on the site nav
reference which we can't access anymore.
Well I'll simply call a method then on toggle side NAV or whatever you want you can give this any name
you like.
And we need to create this method and the hetero component now.
So down there in the typescript file all asdis as a method.
And my goal now is to emit a custom event in the head or a component to which I can listen from my app
component here on my head or selector which I can use to call toggle on the side Neph reference.
No this is a common pattern and one that should work really well.
For this ultra a new property in the head a component types could file and I'll name it site nav toggle
the name is solely up to you.
The important part is that it's a new event emitter object.
So you should import event emitter from an angle core and we can also already import output to make
this a listener event which you can listen to from outside.
So first of all I'm going to initialize this event dimeter create a new object based on it.
Now even if it is a generic type but actually can set the type too wide because I don't plan on emitting
any payload.
Any object with the event and it will decorate CNF toggle with an output.
Don't forget the parentheses to make this list inable from outside.
And now the only thing is that we need to emit event here in on target side neph.
I'll reach out to side of toggle and simply call emit.
Now we admit any event whenever we click the menu button.
All we have to do now is listen to seitan after.
So back in the app component H.T. mail file.
I'll add this as a custom Ubuntu app hatter and there I will now simply reach out to side nav and call
toggle that's all.
Now we won't be able to close it up and clicking links but it should open.
Let's go back to the running happened.
Open the side menu and this works.
Now to the links that does work again because right now the app crashes it crashes because when clicking
a link we try to call close on site nav which is undefined though because this is not a local reference.
A way lable in the sign up list component.
Now the solution is to simply follow the same approach as the header component.
Here I will add on close Mefford.
The name is also up to you here and then in the typescript file of that component.
All import event emitter and output and then create my own custom event.
I'll simply name it close sign half year which is a new event emitter type Woit because I also won't
pass any payload here and decorated with an output and then I'll add the on Close method which I call
from the template and cold this close side nav emit just like that.
Know if this set up the ultimate event whenever we click a link and now we can go to the app component
HVM m file edit listen to our acustom event which we named close site.
And here I can then use the local reference because we can access it in the app component and call close
just like that.
With these changes someplace if we go back and we open this page.
Now if I never get around the site Nev. opens closes just as before but this time we're taking advantage
of having multiple components and therefore having a leaner app component.
Now one important word of caution you could of course also have the idea of putting demand side nav
into its own component and not just the content.
There are solutions to make this work for sure but in general you can quickly end up in a situation
where you fail to open the Met site.
Because at least right now it looks like Matt's site Neph always needs to be a direct child of Matt's
side and Neph container and you break that chain.
If you add another component in between your own component does this why I don't recommend putting this
into a component but instead putting this into a component death just one word of caution.
Chances are it is fixed or a different behavior when you're trying this.
But right now this does not work as expected.
Now with that we finished the site there and the toolbar.
Now one thing we can't check is if we increase the width.
Here we see the stylings a bit of 40 toolbar icons or items I should say.
So let's go to the site Neph list component s s file and here where we have our navigation items that
of course is wrong in this site Neph list component that should go inti should go into the header component
here.
So this is where we add this.
And now with that this looks good.
And if we decrease the size deciles looks good.
So this is now working.
Now next I want to work on you wall come screen and of course on the training screens.
So let's continue with that.