With our cart finished let's replace select type of training with a drop down where we can select which
kind of training we want to do.
For this let's have a look at the official documentation again and we can find a dropdown under form
controls this select component.
It does this how it will look like.
And this is exactly what I want to use now here again we got a lot of documentation about how you may
styli it and find a unit to your needs to make it fit perfectly into your form and do exactly what you
want to do.
For example you can also add multi-select for drop downs you are not limited to drop downs where you
can only select one.
You can add groups as you can see here.
And so on.
There are a lot of things you can do.
We will use a relatively simple window but later we will populated dynamically.
So this a basic select and at its most basic form as you can see it just uses a map form field.
Then Matz is select which is interesting because it's never an input nor a text area.
But behind the scenes there's also a valid form element which is accepted by metaphor and field and
then we just have options in there.
And this looks a lot like a normal HVM select element with the options inside of it just with the matte
prefix in the end.
So this is what we want to at last.
Copied over into our cart and walk through it.
We got the math form field to be able to show errors or hints and get a floating label and to register
this correctly the angular forms then we get the math select and demand option component.
Both are unknown right now because we haven't added the appropriate module to our material module on
the so that we can specify the placeholder which will be a label that floats up when we start selecting
and mad option here and this example is actually already populated dynamically with the energy for loop.
We will do this later too.
But for now let's simply start by well hard coding this all in there.
So the first option I want to use is let's say crunches.
So here I'll assign a value of crunches for now.
This is the first exercise I want to support.
Then next option I want to add are touch toes also update the value.
And thereafter I want to add side lungis.
And of course feel free to add your favorites torturing mechanisms here.
The last one I'll add is a bird piece.
Certainly the worst of all of them.
So let's add them here.
And again this is something we will populate dynamically later.
We have one problem to fix though unlocking the select component.
And you know how this works.
We go to material module in there we add a new import at the very top of Mat select module.
You don't need to import the options module or a component separately because it's part of the Select
module which makes sense I guess because the option belongs to the select and the other way around.
So we'll add to imports and exports.
Once that's done we can save it and look at our result.
So let's go back to our application.
We can already see this drop down where we can select different exercises.
Now in my opinion the card doesn't look that great though there's certainly there are certainly things
you can do.
I think it would make sense to center everything centered tidal center the button centered dropdown
and we can easily Centra everything with flex lay out of course.
Now we can simply add ethics lay out a line to match car title and set the center.
You can also add F X layout here first but actually you don't need to do that.
It will then automatically Turdus to a row orientated layout.
With that we see the title is centered.
Now we can clearly copy that and do the same for the Matt card content and the Matt card actions.
Now everything is centered in our card and looks much better.
One thing that's not looking good is on smaller screens.
The card is too white.
So what we should actually do is we should give this card a width of 400 pixels only on big screens
or put a number words on small or very small screens to be precise.
I want to set this to 100 percent and not to 400 pixels by doing it like this.
The card spends the full width on small screens as you can see but only has 400 pixels on bigger screens.
And with that this card is now finished.
You can of course colored this button if you want.
You can choose different actions.
The only thing I want to adjust is I want to give this new training section here some styling in my
C Ss class for C-s is filed for new training.
I want to add some padding of 30 pixels from top and bottom so that this actually looks more like a
card.
And now we really got a nice look here where we got our card where we hit start and where we will soon
see our ongoing training.
Let's implement these ongoing training in the next lecture.