We have the basic Spener but a lot of functionality is still missing.
First of all let's ensure that it doesn't go above 100.
If it does then we want to cancel it to be able to cancel the entire Well we need to store it first.
So at a time or property which is a number and then I can set at this time are equal to set intraweb
does shows an error here but actually will work said entrail returns us a number an ID which we can
use together with to clear in the world method which is provided by Javascript.
So inside of the method we execute every second.
I want to check if this progress is greater or equal than 100 which is our exit condition.
We certainly want to stop when this is reached.
In this case we want to call clear into Will and again this is not a method provided by Engler or by
angular material.
It's a default javascript method and we pass this timer as an argument.
Now this will stop it whenever we reach 100.
And to ensure that we see this a bit quicker I'll actually increment by 24 now so that we only take
5 seconds.
So now you see it grows and grows and grows and the number stops.
So this is now working.
That's decrease this to 5 again.
But let's now also ensure that we can click that stop button and pause and ultimately cancel this training.
Now to Stop all.
First of all at a click listener and execute on stop your or any method name you want of course.
Let's add the on stop method and then let's run clear interval.
This timer This should immediately stop the timer.
So if we start to training here and I had stop doesn't continue.
Now what I want to do is I want to show a dialog to the user where I ask him whether he really wants
to quit.
And if the user cancels then we should receive the timer.
If the user confirms then we should continue and go back to the previous page.
So for that let's have a look at the official documentation and let's have a look at pop ups and modals
and their dialogue.
Sounds about right.
The dialog allows us to enter something here for example and click that and that is the actual dialogue.
And you can populate this with whatever you want and you don't need to enter a name or anything like
that.
First of course you're really flexible about how this dialogue should look like.
The interesting part here in the example code is that we don't see anything that would have been in
that dialogue because dialogue is created all in code daises word dialogue is created with dialog open
after injecting mat dialogue.
This is super important.
The dialogue is a special material component.
It's not added to the template as we did it with all abro components we used thus far.
Instead it's invoked programmatically.
Let's take a closer look.