Let's say want to get some data into our dialogue we open it with the open method but let's say in the
dialogue component we want to output some dynamic value.
For example here we could add a number special component in there.
Matt dialogue content.
And then simply output
some paragraph where we say you already got and then your progress percentages.
Now how would we do this how would we get that data into our dialogue.
It starts in the compound where we opened the dialogue there.
Additionally tudy Capote and which should get opened in the dialogue we can pass an object with some
additional configuration.
Now all the details can be found in the official docs but one super important piece of documentation
is data which we want to pass to the receiving or opening dialog.
We do that by setting a date up property here which in turn can be a javascript object where we don't
for example have to progress key which is equal to this progress.
So to the progress we currently store encourage training and now we're passing this on the data property
to our to be opened dialogue now in that dialogue we're opening we have to receive it and use it.
And for this we use a mechanism that looks complicated but actually isn't.
We have to inject something into our stop training component.
So we'll add a constructor.
And now here we don't use the normal Dependency Injection mechanism which you might know this mechanism
where you basically assign some value to some property by defining the type of what you want to inject
works in most cases.
But here we're not injecting a class or something like that we're injecting an object an object managed
internally by angular material we do inject that by adding the inject decorator which you might not
have used that often it's imported from any angle or core and it has to be added in front of some argument.
You can still use to have it cut to meet the binded argument to a property like here.
All quickly adds my private data object or past data to make it really clear that this Knabe doesn't
have to be named data.
And this is of type.
Any You could also precisely to find the type you're passing here.
So object for properties property that's a number.
Would be the alternative.
So we get that but we need to pass an argument to the object decorator and debt argument is something
we import from ET angular material.
So let's import that something from at angular material and that something here is constant.
It's called Matt dialog data.
This is simply a constant storing some random number or ID which allows us to access to data which angle
material internally stores when we call the open method.
You can kind of think of that as our apps where we might use a service to store some data we want to
pass between components angular material dastards internally for the data we pass here and it gives
that an ID or it uses an ID to store them.
So to say.
And that idea some number which we all could use but since it's easier to remember text it mosques this
idea with this text Matt dialogue data a so-called token we now pasters to inject to basically tell
it.
Yeah.
In your reference of data where are you somehow stored the data off to currently open dialog.
Please give me the data.
This is what we're telling.
Angular material with this syntax.
And please give it to me and store it in the past.
Data property.
With that we can use the past data property anywhere in this component like here in the template of
course and X-ists thought progress because that is something we'll have a way lable and this should
be public here.
So with that we got our past data and we now should be able to open that dialogue.
And see the current percentage in there because we're successfully passing it into the dialogue with
this complicated.
But in the end not so complicated approach and it's always dead approach.
So in the end you just have to remember this pattern.
Now that's nice but we're clicking.
True or false and we're passing a yes or no and we're passing true or false back to the opening component.
How do we consume this value.
How do we take this into account.
So for this I'll actually store this dialogue at a constant named dialogue ref because this dialogue
open will return a reference to the open dialogue and then on dialogue.
RATH I'll add or execute the oft reclosed method which gives me an observable that's fired whenever
this is closed.
So I can simply subscribe to that observable you know and or uses a lot of observables.
So it does here and it will get the result.
And now we can do with the result whatever we want.
For example decide whether we want to continue or not.
So you're able to simply console log result for now.
So with that if we again start this exercise stop this and hit no we return false as you can see the
click yes we return true and that's exactly what we bound here.
True true yes and false to know.
Now we get that information and now we can use it to continue with the training or stop it.
Now to do that let's implement some logic in the next lecture.