With basic authentication and self-education even committer added let's make sure we redirect the user
whenever he the dictates or locks out and that we protect route's which should only be accessible to
authenticated users.
Regarding the redirection we can actually do that in the off service we can inject services into services
and what to inject the angular router into the off service to be able to inject the service into a service
we need to decorate this of service with the injectable decorator which you have to import from angular
CT.
So you should import injectable from at a singular slash chord like that.
Now we can add a constructor to this of service and received the router you could simply use the type
router and router is imported from the angular package too.
So you add a second import where you import the router for on at angular router.
With that we got access to the router which allows us to route or navigate around programmatically.
So here when we were just a user we can call this router navigate and there we actually have to pass
an array of Route segments.
I only got one segment though training.
Now I will copy that code and run the same after log in and for log out I want to go to the logon page
instead.
Now we get duplicate code and register user and log in so we can actually add method to your private
method.
I'll name it off successfully or whatever you want to do.
Here I will copy the code where we emit our off Change event with true as a payload and where we go
to the training route or at this code here and now and log in I simply called this off successfully
and do the same here in Rochester user.
With that change we should be redirected whenever we log in.
Let's try this out.
Let's go to the log in page and enter a value here.
And we're on the exercise page.
Awesome.
You also see the side nav adjusted.
Now that's one thing I also want to redirect.
If we log out and for today we need to hook up to the log out button.
So for us we're going to go to the hatter component.
And on this lock out button here I'll add a click listener.
And to make sure we all get this hand I can all add a quick inline style where to set the cursor to
pointer.
Of course you could also use to see us fall for that.
So you're all execute on log out and all I'm going to do the same in deciding that later for now any
header component let's add is on log out Methot may be here before on the stroy to have all logical
order I guess from on in it over our efforts to destroy.
And then on log out let's call the off service and there the log out method without arguments.
Now implement the same in the side nav list here.
There are all the add on log out and execute this off service log out log in log out and in the template
off that component.
I'm going to need to add a click listener whenever we well do click this button.
The problem just is this button already has a click listener on clothes.
Maybe we should call on log out here instead.
And back in the typescript file I will actually also call this on close here.
We'll actually do this first with this and all files saved.
If we go back and reload the app.
And I hope the side menu and I log in and redirect it if I click log out I redirect it back to the sign
in page.
This is working the route protection is missing.
Let's add this in the next lecture.