We added the data table in the last lecture.
Now let's add sorting faltering and Page anation to it.
Let's start with sorting so that we can conveniently sort by calories duration whatever we want to do
to add sorting we need to work both on D.H. female code of our data table as well as the types code.
Let's start with H.T. mail.
First of all we have to add the math sword directive to the math table.
This makes it sortable so to say we don't have to define by which letters we can sort because by default
no header no column is sortable and that's a good thing.
Some columns don't make for good sorting columns so which columns do we want to sort by maybe the date.
Well then we add a special directive to the mat hetero's cell component and that directives the mat
Saward header.
Actually this is not a directive but a component selector to be precise.
So we added two matched headers cell.
You add this header dis selector to all columns.
I want you want to sort so my case I also want to sort by name by calories and by duration and also
by state.
So for me it is all columns but this is not a must.
You can also just use some of the columns.
So with that we added this sorting logic here.
Now we just need to do something in our typescript file for the past training component dare we need
to attach some special property of data source to our math or direct.
If we added in the component so to this directive you're now behind the scenes.
A lot of things are happening.
It's basically finding out which headers should be sortable and we'll connect everything and we do set
up this connection by getting a reference to our.
Matt Saward directive for this we can use view child which as you know gives you a way of getting access
to elements to find in your template in your types of file.
So here I will add at viewer child and I want to get access to Matt sort.
You need to import this from angular material.
This is referring to the math or directive which we added to the table here now by accessing it with
the future we don't get access to the entire table.
This directive is sitting on.
But really just the underlying sorting set up angular material in forwards for us due to this combination
of math or the math or whatever so of store days underlying configuration to put it like this are stored
in a sort property the name is totally up to you though which will be of type mapped sort.
So to type we're selecting here with you child.
Now we need to assign this to data source so that we can't do this NGO on it though because we're fetching
this from the template and the template is not done rendering at this point of time.
So I'll use a different lifecycle look after the you init.
This needs to be imported from an angle or a coworker.
So let's quickly add the import here off to review and Annette and this forces us to at end offer ofter
view in the method here which executes once that is done rendering and initializing.
So here I will then set this data source sort.
A property that data source object has equal to this sort.
So to this configuration we fetch from the template so to say and that is all.
Now if we go back to the running application and again quickly log in and simply stop a couple of exercises
so that we have something to view we do that then we see we get to exercises and no sorting mechanism.
We also have no error what's going wrong.
This is something you can easily mess up or simply not not know the max table component which include
it by adding the math table module in the material module does not include sorting page anation and
filtering.
We simply have to add these imports separately and it's very deceiving.
We don't even get a warning if we don't do that.
So here we have to add the math source module.
And as with all the other modules we have to add it to imports.
And of course all due to exports to make it available to Iran.
Now with that we can go back and do this thing again quickly log in with some dummy data and get an
error here.
The reason you know the reason is Matt sored header is incorrectly added to energy container here should
be to the Mad Hatter's sell a component in all cases of course.
So that was a weak error here.
Make sure to not make this error but now you see well there's this one thing that can go wrong.
But now with that fixed if we log in again now we should be able to run a bunch of crunches.
Stop this.
You don't need to wait for that.
Start with a piece and also stop that.
And now under past exercises we can actually sort by Callard a duration excuse me by calories by state
which is the same your name.
And of course the date and here to date looks the same but 10 minutes and so on are also saved.
That is why we can sort by that.
So DNA is sorting which works out the box with a few adjustments and additions in the next lecture.
We'll have a look at filtering.