What I can do the next module.
So in the last modules we spend a lot of time working with angular material and I hope that it's clearer
how you work with it and how it works and how you can add the components you need in your app to your
app.
Now let's move on with our app here and from a styling perspective I'm pretty happy right now.
We miss a back end though we're only working with dummy data which we manage in the regular app through
services.
We're not storing anything on a server.
We're not fetching anything from a server.
So it's time to change this.
And for this I'll use firebase as a back end and angular fired too which is a third party package as
a connector to that Bakhit.
Now before we dive into aler fire to let's have a look at firebase what is firebase.