So what is firebase firebase is an easy to use back and if this is our regular application set up where
we have a client so the browser and the server and we sent back and forth requests and the server returns
H-G e-mail pages or in the case of a singular only one single page at a time then firebase is relevant
for the service site.
It can be used as a hosting provider to host the regular app but more than that it can be used as a
back end to which we connect to store data fetch data run all kinds of calculations or also very important
authenticate users.
Indeed tell'd firebase has a couple of different services and has services connected to real time databases
no real time simply means that the databases you can use can actually be used in a way that uses WEP
sockets behind the scenes so that you can get live updates into your page into your angular app without
the need to send subsequent rest API requests.
But more on that later.
So they offer database solutions using no sequel databases to be precise.
These databases are used to store in-sync data.
You can reach them while you rest.
AP I already official firebase SDK or with angle or fire as you will learn in this module and you don't
need to write any service code they work out the box.
You don't need to create rest endpoints.
You don't need to write any code to validate data.
You can almost directly communicate with the database.
So to you it looks like you do in-between.
There is of course some layer which although it acts as a cure to you there but you can easily access
the database.
That's the key take away of these services.
The site's databases firebase has an off indication service with this service you can easily add user
sign up and log in.
You can reach it.
Also why arrest API or do you firebase STK you here you don't have to write any server side code.
And if you use the SDK then even on the front end you get a lot of utility functions things like storing
the token and so on firebase also offers storage services.
So files storage services which help to a file upload download also all down the wired firebase STK
end here too.
No server side code is required.
Additionally firebase has analytics services where you can integrate analytics into your apps firebase
that's important to mention at this point alls is a popular back and for mobile apps.
So for Android or Iowa as apps there you can integrate even a bit more analytics services for web apps.
And finally a relatively new service are cloud functions cloud functions as a service where you can
write your own code and execute on the Mont. by attaching it to certain event sources.
Now the cool thing about firebase in all these services is not just the service offerings but that here
all the resources are managed for you all the servers are managed for you you don't need to provision
spin up manage and secure servers.
So that's all done for you.
You just used the services and you're charged on a pay what you use basis.
So if you're not using data a lot it's essentially free to you.
They have a generous free tier and if your usage becomes bigger and bigger because more people start
using your web app while then you're hopefully earning money and then this will also cost you money
but it will still be very cost efficient.
So these are all the fire based services in this module.
I'll only focus on the real time databases and authentication though don't we all use angular fire to
use these services in the angular app and you will see how easy that is.
Now one important note this is no firebase course firebase is way more than what we use in display app.
But this of course is an app focused course and it's about angular in its core.
Therefore I will indeed tell show you how we use the services we do use if you want to learn more about
firebase.
Please reach out to their official page.
You can find useful links in a lecture at the end of this module.
Now with that let's have a look at the services we are going to use and how we use them.