I'm all the firebase page now.
And as I said it's a service provider that of course charge money.
You can check the pricing page to find out what you will pay and they have a very generous free tier
plan here.
So the things we're going to use here in this module should absolutely be free.
If you use them in the same amount I used them here in this course if you ever exceed these limits you're
not going to be broke in a couple of hours.
You will actually get a warning and you don't even need a credit card to get started.
So you're absolutely safe.
So that's pricing.
What about the services we will use.
If you click on products that the services we will use are actually the cloud firers store here which
is their latest data based solution we can use and which is highly scalable and fast and use authentication.
So these two services here now you can always dive into the docks here to learn more about services
if there are some cases which are not covered as course as discours.
As I mentioned of course is no firebase deep dive court.
Now to get started what you will need to do is you have to head to your console the fire based console
and for that you will need a Google account and then you need to create a new project here.
So I will quickly do that and I will name it.
Energy fitness tracker you can choose any name you want now choose your region which doesn't affect
the pricing by the way.
And then click Create project.
Now this will set up a firebase project for you where you can access all these services.
I was mentioning.
Now again we will only use the database in authentication but you will see these are their core services
which is also indicated by the fact that they're the top two services we see here.
So that's the firebase console and feel free to browse through it and explore their service offerings
in our application.
I want to start by adding a database to fetch the exercises we offer not from our service where we currently
hard code them.
You have a look at our training service that we have all our exercises hardcoded instead of want to
get them from firebase and I will use a singular fire.
Now what is a singular fired.