OK so it's time for a little bit of theory.
We're going to use angular fire in this module and angular fire will use observables.
That's its core asset if you want.
Therefore we need to understand what observables of service and subscriptions really are and how that
all works.
So we get an observable and an observer.
These are terms you often hear.
The two are connected with a subscription.
And if you use angular you use this construct a lot actually an hour course project we already use a
subject which is a special kind of absorbable you could say we could use that subject to emit values
by calling the next method we could subscribe to it to subscribe method.
Now in contrast to a check and absorbable would be something where you can call next where you can just
subscribe and absorbable which emit events based on some other source which it wraps.
For example you could wrap that say button event with an observable and receive a new event emitted
which you get delivered to your subscription whenever a button is clicked in its core.
All observables have free methods that can be triggered either by the source they're wrapping or in
the case of the subject.
Maybe by you programmatically and next Meffert an error or method and a complete method because observables
can emit a new value can fail or can complete and emit no further values in all these cases.
These methods are simply triggered or invoked.
You could say now as I said NASA will simply wraps something for example I gave the example of the button
here.
Number one it could wrap the call back off an H2B request that could succeed and therefore execute next
and give you the response and also execute complete because once the HTP request A-stan no further values
are to be expected for different events sources like for example the baton which you wrap.
This might be different because dairy you could absolutely get more events in the future.
You don't know how off the button is getting clicked.
Of course if you go back to the HTP request example that could also fail in which case it would also
call the Aero method.
And this will actually all to complete or to be precise.
Cancel the observable.
So there if an error occurs you all won't get any further responses or events to be precise.
So this is an observable.
We can think of these observables as streams of data.
So an observable raps such a stream of data.
It's all about asynchronous jobs.
In the end though theoretically you can also use synchronous data streams.
So here's the concrete example we got a value that submitted.
Let's go back to the HTP example.
We sent the request and a response arrived.
This could be of value or we're wrapping a button event listener.
Now the button was clicked.
We get a new value.
The object with Event data.
Now the observer has a couple of methods which can be triggered.
And for de-value we get this.
Let's say it's a successful value a successful event.
No error.
Therefore the next method is triggered.
Now we can get more values for some observables Abourezk might only be able to emit one like the HTP
request and let's say all these values are successful no errors.
So next is executed a couple of times in the Observer.
Now sometimes tonsorial might be completed.
So the complete method is triggered.
Now another absorbable might have a different stream of data.
Although some successful values but then may be an error which executes the error method.
The end is never reached.
In this case.
So these are observables and this is of course highly abstract and theoretical.
We'll see it in action in a second.
No worries.
And if you want to learn even more with a lot of practical examples I get a whole serious on my YouTube
channel which you can also find a link at the end of this module.
So here is another thing that's really cool about Horrible's.
We get the observable and the observer and the observer by the way remember is simply connect the to
the observable through a subscription so gets informed about all these values.
Errors or completions.
However the best thing about observables is that you can use operators.
Operators are simply some methods you put between the event emission in your stream of data and your
observer.
So where are you.
Then do something with the data.
An operator could be the map operator.
The are ex-chief as library which actually ISDE Library giving us this whole absorbable functionality
has tons and tons and tons of operators and we will see some of them in this module.
Again for more operators check out dead YouTube serious.
I was mentioning.
So we got to operators what do operators do though they're running before we actually received the value.
Our observer.
But after the value was emitted.
So all values go into an operator and then depending on the operator.
Something happens to them.
The map operator for example allows us to specify a function that is executed on every value which we
can use to transform the value.
Like the map method on the javascript frameworks so we get transformed values in that case.
And DS transformed the values to dedi reached the observer.
The cool thing is that we can chain operators and therefore you can rebuild complex chains of value
handling operations where you may be first transform data.
Then you even throttle the collection of them so that you only receive one value every two seconds and
this example your and stuff like that does what you can do with operators and this is one of the coolest
parts about observables.
The many operators that you can use to transform the data manipulate the data and so on.
Still I could imagine that this is highly theoretical So why don't we just dive in and doubt it.
You've got at least a basic understanding of that observable thing matters and what it's about.
Let's use angular fire which embraces this whole concept but which also makes it easier to understand
that since there begat actual examples.