So in the last lectures we look at how we implement authentication and protect our Bakan everything
works fine as long as we are logged in.
We can then send our requests.
And of course fetch all available extra sizes if we log out.
Everything all kind of works.
But then we get an error that we're not authentic hated and that's true.
The problem is we get this error because our fire store subscriptions and the training service still
are active.
Even if we alog out so here and the training service we got subscriptions for all kinds of stuff for
example for fatting available exercises.
And this is of course a life subscription.
It doesn't finish just because we locked out so we can do a couple of things to fix this issue or work
with it.
One thing we can do which we should do anyways is besides this first method we passed to exercise this
first function where we handle the data.
We can't pass a second function where we handle errors.
So for now let me simply output that error here and now if we go back and we lock bag in and log out
it changed.
We still get the error printed here but now it's actually handled by us so to say that is why we don't
see that red error message.
This one is coming for our second subscription.
The first one is simply locked here.
If we comment this out and do nothing with our in I tried to say again
now we only get the Dobry error message and don't see anything about dead error.
So if he copied that pattern and go to our second subscription which is down here and we add the same
pattern here.
Now if we log in an hour we shouldn't see any errors anymore.
Now clearly you could say that is a bad solution because the errors happen we just hide them.
But it might actually be OK if you say whenever it erro Chris here I don't want to do anything.
Well this is an approach to Hightstown.
Of course you have one problem here though if you got some Obert error which you want to show to the
user Well you just hide it away.
Right.
So here we can't handle this.
So an alternative approach would be to cancel our subscriptions let's remove our air handlers which
you still can remember if you want to implement your own error handlers.
And let's now store the subscriptions we have here.
So all in word subscription from our ex-chief.
Yes and create a new private property which all name FHB SERPS for firebase subscriptions which will
be an array of subscriptions.
Actually initially it's an empty array.
But then here I will reach out to my firebase substrate and Porsche.
This first subscription onto it so I'll just add it it still will subscribe.
I will just add that subscription to firebase Suppes subscription rate and I'll do the same down there
for fetching completed or canceled exercises or reach out to FBA precepts and will push this subscription
onto the now or we'll add a new method which would call cancel subscriptions doesn't take any arguments
but will simply take Bayat subscriptions.
And with four each I can execute some code on every subscription in that irrate and for every subscription
I simply want to call unsubscribe now I just have to call cancel subscriptions from within the off service
so I'll go to my off service.
It already has.
Add injectable.
So now I can inject my average service here private training service like this and when ever we log
out here I want to call this training service cancel subscriptions.
Now you save this and remember I did remove the error handlers.
We still shouldn't get error messages because when logging out we now do unsubscribe and therefore we
do that before we try to make an request to make a request to the back backend which wouldn't go through.
So this is also a valid strategy here.
Now there's one other thing we can now do to do some cleanup work and that is changed the way we emit
does you are affected event which we read now do in log out and off successfully.
Let me show you how you can take advantage of an observable based off status listener provided by angle
of fire in the next lecture.