In this module we did a lot of cool things.
We added firebase and the angle of fire store to be precise.
We hooked it up to our angular gap through angle of fire.
You learn about the various ways of using angular fire to set up different types of subscriptions.
Referring to the angular fires Stallworth to work with data to manipulate data to add data and get data
of course and you learned how to implement authentication with Angel of fire and fire base and how to
protect your service resources using data authentication approach.
Now we get a cool realtime application that's fed from different running app instances so where we're
sharing data in real time without reloading the page and I'd say this is a really cool state for this
app to be in.