This far in course we already achieved a lot.
And our application is already looking good and working great.
Still there are things we can polish we can optimize both from our optical as well as from a technical
perspective from an optical perspective.
We could for example add better error handling especially during authentication and maybe also show
some spinners some loading indicator.
Whilst we are affiliating and from a technical perspective we could split our app module into further
modules so that it's less crowded and implement lazy loading forward of training part.
These are the things I'll tackle in this module.
So let's dive right in.