We can also improve the error handling in the training components in new training or specifically in
the training service where we fetch all available exercises.
We're not handling arrows right now.
Now it would make sense to handle errors though.
And what do we want to do if this specific method fails.
So if we can't fetch the actions the exercises the user wants to do well we could for example show a
snack bar where we at least inform the user.
So here after the first function we passed to subscribe we can pass a second function which will be
triggered for all arrows we get.
And here in that function I want to use the you Ice Service which we're already injecting into detraining
service and I want to call shows a snack bar with a message where I could say fetching exercises failed.
Please try again later.
Where I don't have an action and wait all the show for three seconds.
Now we have that error handler in place now to also see it in action.
What I will do is I will simply temporarily not return my untransformed array here but instead simply
fro a new error here in my map function.
Now this should lead to the error method being triggered.
So if we do log in now
we get this error at the bottom after a short duration.
So I'll now reword this.
And now we will always see that spinner but we get to snack bar.
Now let's also remove to spinner though so let's reach out to you guys service loading States changed
and call next false because actually year I also want to remove the splinter.
But now we'll have the problem that we will have a select dropdown with no well to select from.
Now we could do that but maybe we instead want to show a button which allows us to trigger does fetch
available exercise method again.
Now how could we implement this.
Now the good thing is we got this exercise has changed event emitter which we're using when we successfully
fetch exercises I could also emitted event when we fail and it will simply emit null here so no exercises.
Now we can go to new training where we subscribe to deceive and dimeter here.
And what happens here now is if we fail we still get an event but the exercises we get will be null.
So this exercise will be null and that allows me to handle this in my component in the component.
We can now show a button which allows us to fetch again whenever exercises are null.
So in here we have our math form field with the dropdown and we got that spinner and I only want to
show these if we are loading or not loading.
And if we get null exercises so here I want to show that for field.
If we're not loading and if exercises and we could also add a condition to the spinner.
But here I'm actually fine with always showing this when we're loading.
What I would change though is I'll add a second button and the action area the first button is always
shown right now.
Now right now we hide this complete block whilst we're loading and that is always fine.
But then after we're done I only want to show the start button here.
If we got exercises.
So if exercise is this true.
Otherwise if we got no exercises which is my condition for the second button I want to show this second
button where I say fetch again and this will actually be not a submit button but a normal button.
So type button and I don't want to disable it it'll always be enabled but I will at a click Lisner where
I want to trigger this fetch method again.
And if we have a look at the new training component there we fetch our away label exercises right from
within Engy on it.
Now I will create a new method which I'll simply call fetch exercises and I'll move that code from you
on it where we start fetching them into dead Meffert and instead call that method from inside and on
it.
Now we get this extra method now fecche exercises we can execute this method whenever we click this
button this fetch again button.
So we should execute this fetch exercise this method in this case.
Now with that set up we can go back to our application and ensure that we get an error by going back
to the training service and again temporarily commenting this out and throwing a new error in the map
function of the fetch available exercise this method.
And let's now have a look.
Does LOTES we see a spinner and we see the error message at the bottom and fetch again button.
And if I click as we start fetching again but of course we always fail.
Now on the other hand if I reword this in a comment the normal return killed in then we will also see
a spinner but we will successfully fetch it and we will not see that fetch again button.
Instead we can start our exercise now and this is improved error handling which I believe makes this
application better.
It allows us to provide a better user experience handle errors and tell the user what's going on.