So we did a lot with all these modules and now the app Marchal is really really lean.
We could also create a core module to put all the features of the app module into that but I'll leave
it in the app module instead.
What I wanted to do though is create a shared module because if we have a look at the training module
then we see that we import common Marchal and forms module there as well as material and flex layout.
And we do import the same things in our off module.
So a shared marshal for these things certainly makes sense.
So in a shared folder all create a shared module Dud's TS file and I'll name it shared module decorated
with at Ngee module of course and import Engy module from an angle or Clor.
So let's add this import ngi module from at angular core like this.
And now indeed shared module here which is just a normal module which we'll use for sharing though.
All I could define clear declarations of components which we share across Martial's but we got nodes
such components but I can import some things and export them again so that I can use them in other modules
because as I said by default a module keeps its imports and declarations to itself.
But if you add exports it actually shares it with any Alber modules that import this module does the
same pattern we already use on a material module by the way they are we just import and export a bunch
of stuff.
So this essentially already is a shared module.
Now we're taking this a step further and create an additional one for more than just material components.
So in the shared module here what do we share.
Well as we just identified the common module in the forms module material and flex layout D reac the
forms module is only used in the off module.
So I will leave it here but I will cut the comment at the form's module and add them to the imports
array of my shared module as well as tree exports array so that we can use them in our modules too.
And the same for material and flex layout angle of fire off is going to stay off Marchal because that
of course is only used here.
So let's move these two things we just picked all the into the shared module both imports and exports.
Now obviously we need to add the import Puff's to import statements for these things.
So in the off margin that would be the flex layout module and that would be the common module.
And of course also the forms module.
So all copy these remove flex layout and Carmen from the off module remove forms module from the at
Angola forms import and put these imports I just copied into my shared module here however I don't need
the reactive forums module.
Now what import is missing and that is the material module which I'll also remove from the module and
which will also now add to my shared module.
The payoff is the same as before since the old folder level is the same.
So now I get my share shared module prepared and I can import this shared module into my off module
so here and imports array.
I'll add my shared module and of course you also need to add an import statement at the top where you
point to the shared folder and they are to the shared module file.
And we don't need exports are really off module because we're not exporting anything.
So that's the shared module.
Now we also have our training module there.
We can also get rid off the common and the forms module the material and the flex layout module and
simply add the shared module instead.
And just as in the module you need to add an import statement for this year to import the shared module
from the shared folder and from the shared module file.
So with that we are using a shared module.
Let's take a closer look at the app and see if everything still works if we reload the page if we now
log in.
That's looking good.
That's also looking good.
Let's start some side lunges here.
So does this now all working great.
So now we're using a shared module.