The Last Lecture.
We created our off routing module.
Now I want to load my training routes in their own module.
However for training I want to do this laser early which means only when we really need it.
Do you off routes should be available right away.
Because even though we check for your syndications state at startup and redirect the user if he is authenticated
the first page we actually load is a log in page because it's very likely that we need it.
The training component the training pages are not as likely to be needed because if the user is not
locked in we don't need to load this in advance so therefore we can take this route and also put it
into a training route module.
However one that will be loaded lousily First of all that's at the model.
I'll name it training routing that module though.
Yes that's the full name.
And there will export a class training routing module.
And this is a normal angular module which is decorated with Engy modules that we need to import from
a single or court.
So import ngi module from at angular coord.
Now we set up our route so I create this routes constant which is of type routes which we import from
the angular router package.
And here I add this signaler route.
I just cut now in DNG module I'll add my imports aere and point to my router module here.
This all needs to be imported from the router package.
So Afterall it's all implored router module and here we all call for child and pass our routes or our
single route.
In this case I'll also export this.
So export router module.
Doesn't change.
Now I also need to import the training component here because we use it in this fall.
So training component from and then it's this training component here.
And we're using a service here.
So I need to import data to import off guard from off guard.
Now we could also add to provider 40 off guard to dis training routing module.
I'm talking about this provider.
However we can also change our setup.
First of all let me remove the training component in the app routing module.
I will now leave off guard here in the app routing module because I will soon change this so that we
needed a disk file and that providing it here makes more sense than providing it in the training module.
And since we provided them at low level it will be a singleton.
So in a training module it will also be available in a training routing module I mean.
So with that we are loading our trading routes eagerly at the moment to get them we just have to make
sure that in the training module we import the training routing module so that we added to the imports
array and add an import statement pointing to the training routing module file.
With that it's loaded eagerly and we can go back to the application.
And as you see log in and see our training routes.
Now let's implement lazy loading to do that.
I will actually change something in my app module.
I will no longer add training module to imports.
I will remove it from the imports array and it will remove the import of that file appear instead I
will use a number pattern supported by the build workflow we're using here or in the end by angular
where in the app routing module I will register a second route where tipoff is training as we had it
before but where I don't assign a component but instead said load children this is the key word for
lazy loading.
And here we pass a string because if we would pass a type and add an import we would already include
it in the bundle at this point.
So it has to be a string so that it can be analyzed at runtime.
Here we now have to point to the file to the module we plan on importing.
When we reached that route and that will be in the training module excuse me in the training folder
the training module docked TS here and in there we want to access the training module clause which we
indicate by adding a hash tag and then training module.
This is required because theoretically your class name could differ from the file name.
So now we're telling angler if we're targeting slash training you should actually load the training
module related code and analyze whatever is in there and in there we get the training routing module
with for child.
So we will still reach this route however important here we now have to remove training and have an
empty path because this will be appended to this training path we have in the app routing module anyways.
So with that we got our lazy loading set up and this will actually lazy load not just US routes file
but any training component related things.
So anything we import here in the training module with that if we reload.
Yep we get this error here that the training service is missing the angle of firestorm.
This makes sense and the training service we are injecting angle of fire story here and angle of fire
firestorm is provided in the training module.
The problem just is the training module is only loaded when you visit slash training.
We provide the training service and the air marshal though.
So at an earlier point of time that is why its missing the angle of Firestorm Marshall.
Now we could provide the training service and the training module but will face an issue there.
We have a look at our office service.
We do inject the training service there.
We do inject to training service because we call cancel subscriptions so the service depends on the
training service which depends on the angle of fire storm service or module and the service has to be
provided in the launch tool because we need the tools to service gives us right at the point of time
the app starts.
So the solution is to re-aired angular Firestar module to our app module so added to the imports array
of app module and make sure to also add an import statement at the top of the file where you import
angle of Firestar module from angle of fire to slash firestorm.
With that we can go to the training module and removed the angle of Firestar module from the imports
erate there and remove the import statement here.
Now with that if we save this the arrow we saw a second ago should be gone.
Now we get a new era though this era is that it confines this module training module.
The reason for this should be that in the app routing module you emit omit here.
This does fall ending the ship without dots.
TS this path you're in the app routing module.
If we fix that leaded recompile and reload the application we should be able to successfully log in
and go to our training components.
If you inspect the network tab you will see that if we log out and reload and we now log in
a bunch of new things are loaded.
Amongst them the training module chunk.
And this is the lazy loading in action.
So with that we're loading this lazily which means only when we really need it.
Which of course decreases the size of our initial bundle.
So what we download up front this is how we implement lazy loading and how we improve the performance
of our application.
Now I want to fine tune this by now also changing the way we use our off guard.