Here's a quick addition in this module there is a bug in our code.
A tiny back but there is a box which I want to fix if you will have a look at the training service due
to me copy and pasting code in the complete and cancel exercise.
We always say to set the state to complete it and we can see this if we log in and we have a look at
our past exercises.
We see that there are a lot of canceled ones which clearly didn't complete where we actually like this
one here and say completed.
So that is of course incorrect on the cancell exercise year.
I should set this to cancelled and not to complete it.
So this is just one fix one logical error that's in the app which I quickly want to get rid of the rest
absolutely works fine.