All right we'll come back with a student on this lecture here.
We're going to start working with the files.
All right.
I got some files that I want you to download.
So go ahead and download it from this lecture is going to be called the Student hyphen files that zip
downloaded unzip it and then on your age the docs I want you to create a folder called logon and then
inside this folder we are going to be placing whatever I'm giving you on this lecture whatever follows
on giving you right here.
All right so we're gonna get pasted in there.
And now we have this content.
Now if you go to your local host.
All right.
I'm going to show you right now.
But if you go to your local host slash logon you should have something like this right now.
Basically what I did here is super simple.
All right.
I gave you a bunch of templates that we are going to be using for the course.
We are also using Bootstrap which is for those of you that don't know and you should know by now but
if you don't know bootstrap is a framework for the amount CSSA has a whole bunch of predefined classes
or big files with a lot of styles that we can use we can use those classes to make our application a
lot better like like you are seeing right now this is all bootstrap.
All right this is I have not caught any CSSA here.
So if you minimize it you should have some functionality like this.
This is javascript but this is booster up doing this for us.
Right.
So let me give you an introduction to those files real quick.
So right now we have a whole bunch of templates that I created for our course and then we have the CSSA
for that we have our bootstrap and some empty stylesheet.
But this is the main file that is creating all this down there.
And we have asked for that with some Bushrod Yes also some javascript double shrive uses to make some
really cool functionalities.
And of course we download Jake wari because we're going to be using that framework as well for javascript
for writing javascript in an easier way.
And we got some empty scripts Yes.
All right.
So that's it.
We shouldn't be dealing.
You shouldn't be dealing with NEHTA Melchior says because this is a course for Logan and registration
right.
We don't want to deal with any of that.
So make sure that you have these files working in your local host and your server basically in your
local environment and on the next lecture.
We are going to work some more with his files so that where we can get to the fun part.
All right.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.