All right we'll come back and buy the student.
So on the last couple lectures we set up our files and downloadable resources and I mean we are ready
to go to start working with the database.
But now let's actually create a database we don't even have one.
Right.
So let's get started doing that real quick.
And you know for those of you that know me from the courses you know that I wasn't feeling 100 percent
on the last lectures is because I you know I have my coffee Well now I do so I'm good to go.
So let's go to local host right for us last BHB adamant my admin.
Of course right there.
And then here we're going to create a database.
All right.
So let's call this database law again on the score.
I think I already have one.
I don't have one.
Create beautiful.
All right.
So now inside here we got to create some tables.
First is going to be the users table.
This just create the user stable for now.
As a matter of fact I think that's the only one we've got to create because this is a logging application.
All right.
But anyway we need another table in the future.
We'll add it that will add our table if I extend the course let's just click go.
Let's add an ID with an index or primary click OK on that make sure you select these a underscore I
which is autoincrement.
So that way the idea keeps getting incremented every time we add a new record.
All right.
What else do we need to know from the user.
How about first name.
How about last name.
That's good to know when you do have a registration number or username and we add more.
But let's actually said DiSalvo right now 11 var car 255.
I like to do to 55 make our car user name 255 just to make it easy for everybody right all right I'm
going to add we need a password and some more columns.
So let's just add three more I believe.
So you got username and password.
How about active.
Actually let's do confirm
let's do validation Valley validation on this core code and let's do active here.
All right.
Hopefully enough forgetting anything else.
All right so last word we're going to make this a Tatz validation code could be tells us well that's
fine and active will make this tiny int which is data type which is like it only takes two values 1
and 0.
I'm going to set it up to be defined as 0.
All right we're going to use it to detect if the user is active.
All right.
So I think we're good Let's talk with checked is real quick to do the password.
We don't need to put anything there because X has all the characters we can put in there.
It would take any characters any amount validation code.
OK.
All right good.
Let's just save it.
Perfect.
So now let's check our connection to the database.
Real quick.
Why NDB.
Let's actually create a variable called Call on and let's do my Eskew like connect.
Let's just say loopholes because that is the default name for the host.
When you first install the Zam map or ramp whatever local environment software you are using the user
name is root by default password is empty.
And our database name which I believe was logging on the score D-B.
All right perfect.
So we have our connection what else.
Let's go to our Internet and let's see if it works let's do it right here.
I say if Conn is available which is variable right here will bring a positive or negative or actual
force Canek response.
So right now we're testing if that means if it's true.
If Con is true or false We're going to tackle something right right now if it's true we can say yes
is connected.
Yay.
All right.
So let's go to it local who's Logan.
Yes he's connected so we are good to go.
Our database is connected is created.
Our table was created.
And if we do anything else will actually make it happen on the next lecture.
But we're good to go right now.
Take care and I'll see you in the next few lectures.