Hi welcome back my students.
This is Eric from the future.
And I just come back some time just to make sure that everything is OK.
All right.
So in the next lecture we're going to be you know dealing with e-mails I want to make sure that you
already have a column for e-mail if you don't have one.
I want you to go to your users table and create a column for e-mail right below the username.
All right.
So once you have that I want you to go in.
Insert any type of data that you want.
All right.
So I'm going to just go insert here and on the next lecture I'm probably going to have different information
because I made them from the future but just you know for you to know they're OK.
So anyway just type in whatever username you want and whatever e-mail around is going to use these e-mail
here and whatever passible you want of course.
All right.
You don't need a confirmation code.
If you don't have that column Don't worry about it.
I will help you make that later on but you should already have that and active.
We're going to leave everything else the same.
I just want you to have this e-mail column which is very important we're going to be dealing with that
in the next election.
OK.
So I have that in there have some data.
All right and I'll see you.
Well you'll see my Edun from the pass my my other editing in an intellectual.
OK.
It was a pleasure like always.
And I'll see you around.
Take care.