Welcome back my students.
So this is either from the future or I just want to give you a heads up on the following lectures the
following lectures are going to contain the mail functionality the email by sending email them the native
BHB mail function.
Now that works for many people but it doesn't work for a few people.
So if you have any type of issues with that mail function know that I added section to deal with that
problem for those of you that cannot get this to work.
I had a I had a section 12 that deals with this.
Not only do we fix these through the application but basically we improve our application by adding
a third party library called BHP Mader.
And that is you know use in a lot of BHB projects because we use s m t p.
Basically we get configurations from our.
Let's say if we're using Gmail G.M. first as a.p services for free.
So you got your username the patent number and all that.
Plug it into that class so that BHP melee class and then you can send e-mails and they get to get to
their users in about ninety nine point nine percent of the time with a malfunction.
Some of you are going to have issues and it's not going to work.
But don't worry I got your cover if you have issues.
Go to Section 12 blog inter-party library which you're going to learn a bunch.
You're going to have a lot of fun with that and that's it.
OK.
For those of you that do have a problem as you can continue learning about the malfunction it doesn't
hurt.
For those of you that don't have any problems continue learning and learn about a third party library
as well.
In Section 12.
So thank you so much for watching guys.
I hope you know everything is going well with you.
If you have any issues or any questions posted into the discussions and we'll be happy to answer them
for you.
See you later.