All right welcome back my student.
So now we have come very far with this register score user function here and we are doing a lot of things
here.
So now it's time for us to send the activation link to the user right.
Because right now this is registering from the user but we haven't sent the activation link yet.
Now we could if we wanted to come here and use the mail function and do that.
Now what I want to do is I want to make this malfunction a little bit more generic.
And we're going to do the same thing we were doing with the help of functions right here.
All right.
And just in case in the future we have some type of plugging or something for it we can use this generic
function this helper function here to change it here and then we would change through our whole application.
All right so I hope you understand that concept.
So we're going to say send mail send send e-mail when they send an e-mail like this.
All right so we have a plug in we'll put the plug in coding here and we can use this to change everything
through our whole application every time we send e-mails right.
So the first parameter would be the e-mail.
Then the second would be the subject right after we'd be the message Hemmers G.
And we could just say message there right now right.
Yes let's just say I'm and G.
And the last one would be the headers.
All right.
And all we got to do here is just return the mail function with all these parameters like the.
Now we could if we wanted to return already with some type of message right.
So that way we don't have to write any code.
And the other side we could say hey if because these malfunctioning if it fails it's going to return
some type of false or negative value.
And if we return successful we will actually submit the form and return a success a true back to the
two where we is calling this function right.
So we can say if mail then we can echo something and say let's just you know what you said we're right
away some type of message
let me see maybe we can you know what is actually returned the mail I guess and then we can handle this
session somewhere else because
that would be too much.
We want this function to be the most generic as possible and and putting all these echoes inside this
function doesn't make it very generic which is going to make the functioning echo something I would
let's just return this and then we can handle that outside.
Right.
So let's go to the registration here and.
All right so here if the registration goes good then we can send the mail right or right here before
we echo the true so that we don't have that much coding here.
We've got to think about this one minute where we already have a link here.
All right let's use user right here.
Send e-mail.
Now let's go down here.
We'll move on.
We need to later on.
But that's fine.
Let's just send it here because we're going to write a lot of code here.
I don't want to clog the space right here with so many things.
All right.
If we change our minds later on we'll change.
But right now I think this is the best way here because we are escaping all these values here already.
All right.
Any way e-mail we only scaping e-mail by the way.
Well then we'll actually let's go up here and get the
oh these parameters
right.
And there we go and let's see what we want to send.
So we've got a subject there and the subject is is going to be called activation active AA account.
All right.
Then we have a message
this message will write something like this.
We're going to say please click the link below to actively open your account and then we'll put the
link below.
This link is going to say HTP in this case is going to be local hoze boy will change out later.
All right.
And as a matter of fact I'm going to.
Yeah that's fine.
You can leave it like this for now.
Logan and activity that BHP is going to go to this page activity that BHB and then they're actually
yeah that's the that's a page that we want to send it to.
We're going to send the e-mail and we will send another parameter here and we'll put an ampersand there
email and then the validation code.
So then it's a code equals validation code there we go.
So once they click on this link and this is going to be our Web site here later on we're going to put
our Web site there.
But once they click on this link this is going to send the e-mail of the user in a validation called
hash and encrypt it.
All right.
And then we can actually create a function to read to activate the user later on.
But that's what we're going to do right now.
All right.
Let's make this a little smaller like this and here I want to create the headers and I say from of course
no reply.
At my Web site right to your Web site.
All right.
Does
Ray
perfect.
We'll test this in the live server later on.
But right now we're just going to leave it that way it is if we have in the next lecture We'll test
it out in our local environment just to see if they the users being register and just we're going to
check.
What can we get when we put these values in there you are L..
All right.
So I think we're done with the registration right now.
What else can we do here.
Al's right.
Yeah we're good for now.
Register user.
And if we are unable to you say use it for some reason.
We're going to return false.
All right.
Perfect.
All right I think we're good for now.
The next lecture will test it make sure that he's working and I see you the next one.
Take care.
Have fun and enjoy.
Bye bye.