All right welcome back my students on The Last Lecture.
We created these checks here just to verify that whatever information we're getting is coming from that
form or that person is on this form.
Perfect.
We don't need to do a lot of validation here because we're going to be able to.
Well we going to do is we're going to send a link to that person.
Right.
We're going to send a link to that e-mail address that's come from the form and they have to they have
to go into that e-mail and click it.
All right.
So we need to verify that you know existing our database and we already have a function for that so
we can say something like If e-mail exists and we bring in that post to pro-global which is post and
we can clean this up a little bit.
Let's just clean it up before we put it in here.
So it's very clear that we're doing that.
They should put in a variable.
Let's just keep it up as we go and let's just go do this post email.
All right.
And this is coming from this input right here e-mail.
So once we clean it up a little bit actually we are scaping you there.
And that just reminded me make sure that this data that you got up here.
All right.
We are actually scaping.
So we're good.
And we just make sure any data they use.
You're skipping just in case I missed something make sure that you did it right.
But anyway.
Beautiful.
All right.
If e-mail it says
Just make sure that we have or checks in place or curly brackets post
talking's talking Cherrix.
All right.
And then e-mail check.
So they e-mailed zest Dan we want to go ahead and send an e-mail to that person.
So same email right.
And we're going to you know let me see is this what we want to do so we're going to send them an e-mail.
They're going to click on the e-mail or you know what we can actually from here we can actually verify
instead of sending an e-mail and take him to the code page which is did this page right here.
I think that's a better option called BHP hopes is that it we have an arrow there and 584 I think we
stop writing this function right here.
All right.
Call that BHB.
You see that so we can verify that use and send them to this page.
We can send them a code as well and then send them to this page.
You don't want to send them a cold let's send an e-mail let's keep it like that so that way we can send
a covert e-mail and they can do that.
They do that with e-mail that's that's fine.
It's more secure.
So we're going to send an e-mail or let's make sure that this is the e-mail right here.
So we're going to send an e-mail.
And that's going to have the e-mail address by and subject object the message and head on.
All right.
So let's work on the subject.
The subject is going to say Please reset your password and we're going to verify this later.
All right.
But
the message is going to be
like this.
And we can use the delimiter and function at a function I guess show you before if you want to do that.
That's up to you.
All right.
So you can put your the limiter into this.
It's up to you.
And I like this for now but please click the link below to reset your password.
Actually you know what.
Let's actually.
Here is your reset your password reset password.
We said code and we're going to have to give them a code.
So we're going to have to create is called right here.
All right.
So let's do it.
Let's create this validation code.
All right.
And the five and we can use the e-mail for that and we can add some Microdyne to it used to make it
a little bit stronger.
So that would be the validation code right here.
Right.
It's a dollar sign there is your validation code
click click here
to reset your password.
And then we got to put the address here HTP localhost
code that Ph be.
All right.
And we're going to send some parameters right.
We can send the e-mail the user use to make sure that we have the right user and the validation code
ampersand and code.
All right.
Beautiful.
And ahead of course
in code and headers
from.
And we could actually make this permanent in that sendmail function made that is permanent but like
a default we don't have to do that no reply.
And this will be your Web site.
Coming from all right.
This looks good.
We send the e-mail and that's beautiful.
All right.
In the next lecture we are going to also make sure that this page is only available for a certain amount
of time.
But by setting a cookie with an expiration because we don't want anybody to come here if the cookies
expire and if we send the link to the person are ready to do any of this called here we don't want the
speech to be available.
You know a year from now because anybody can come here and keep trying and trying and trying to hack
it and they maybe it will be successful.
Right.
So we want to make sure that this expires and if it does expire we're going to kick the person out of
here and send them somewhere else and let them know listen you cookies expire.
You need to go and you know go to the recovery that BHP page again and try again.
So anyway thank you so much for watching this lecture.
We are done with this functionality for now.
But we are going to again set some cookies here.
And so messages.
All right thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.