All right welcome back my student.
Very good.
We are here again.
Let's check it out.
Let's check to see if we are able to get the revalidation going so that way we can get redirected to
the reset that BHP page or else we get some errors.
Let's see if we can make this happen.
All right.
So let's go to that call that BHB paging I think is going to redirect us now.
All right because our cookie was expired.
Let's go and get some new session going for this guy right here.
The line which is a pretty cool guy.
Right.
Don't you think he's always letting us use his e-mail right.
So.
All right.
So now we have to type the raw the right validation for this to happen.
So we need to replace this validation code here that we having our text editor.
Hopefully you are following me with the new one here.
So we got one right here.
And I would go
and we go our new one let's see if now we try to go to that called page with all the credentials where
all the stuff.
And it will redirect us.
Right.
Well it's not going to redirect as we got to typing that that code in the box is.
It will only allow us to go into that what is redirecting us because for some reason is
telling us that something is wrong.
Is hitting one of these guys here.
If he's not set get e-mail or get code he's going to redirect us let's check it out again.
OK this is wrong right here.
It is supposed to be e-mail and cool to one G.M. and now the validation could get by let's do it again
real quick.
Well now we've got the right one let's just correct this Ted.
Add it to real quick here to e-mail.
All right there we go.
Let's do it again.
One e-mail I think I had it in 15 minutes but I when I took it down to one minute again for my cookie
expiration date.
All right.
Let's go back to the to the database real quick let's refresh double click here.
Come back here and let's test it before expires again.
Here we go.
Now we should get it right after.
Now we were able to enter that code.
So now if we enter the code that we have which is this called right here pasted in there and continue
is going to take us to the reset page.
All right so it's working perfectly.
Very good.
Maybe in the future we'll make this code a little bit shorter.
You can see that ball right now is working really good guys.
So if you're ready to learn some more really cool stuff.
Stay tuned and we'll get it going all right.
You're doing very good if up to this point.
So I want you to feel very proud of yourself.
If you want to go ahead and toast to this location go ahead and get some drinks going where your friends
and your family and celebrate because you're learning something super cool right here.
See you in the next lecture.
Take care.