All right welcome back my student.
So let's actually try to get some data from the last one Shneidman that we created which was a password
reset function.
Right.
But first we need to come from this here.
All right.
So we need to have those parameters.
They are in place for this to work.
So we need to go back to our.
Now this one here or a string.
Hopefully this deal works and is now expiring Fielitz That's why we need to do it again.
And third OK still works and I'm going to grab this little guy right here copier right here and continue.
All right Roland validation code.
See there.
Oh that's beautiful.
Let's go back here and refresh.
And now this.
You have the right validation code.
Next we continue reset page.
We should put some type of message here right.
All right.
So now what we need to do is make sure that we are echoing something here we find these values right.
So now remember that we are also setting some time five minutes here for our time access.
So we need to also check on that when we do our pass will reset function right here.
But right now we just want to see that it works.
So let's go past where we sat.
Let's go to the reset page and right here.
We go and paste that in there and let's check it out.
Well my mouse here and enter and he says he works.
All right now when I get into something that I get when I mean we cover these placeholder there.
So what I'm going to do and I copy this
when I get this whole thing here
let me see if I get something a little better than that.
All right here
take that off.
Take this off and paste that in there.
Well I think this looks a little better.
There we go.
It works is misspelled but it's getting there.
And it's also check for the time axis.
And I think we already have one here.
Let's just use this one.
So that would be the first check right.
All right.
So we still good here.
Alice
we got and I said a message and we're going to tell that user to something like.
Sorry
and I see we got some type of
message somewhere here that we go right here
get that and we're going to say danger here.
See how easy it is get.
I we're going to say something like.
Sorry.
Please sorry your time
has expired or something like that.
And we're going to take him back
to recover.
Or to call that ph be taken back to recover then well later on we'll will see if we can take him back
to call that BHB so they can submit their their their information again but recovered that BHP should
be good for now.
Right so we take him back to we covered that with that they have to do that over again.
We have to get the whole cold again and try again.
All right.
And make sure that we have that display message there.
That's good.
All right.
So once we find out this is good we also need to check for body nation code.
So if we check here I think one of these functions is doing that code so we can get that see that that's
a lot of check right there.
So
if you are talking ampoules talking are the same.
Then we check all this.
That's another bone is right there
all right we're going to make sure that we have our or curly brackets.
Good that they all match.
OK.
So this one matches that statement.
This one matches that.
This is for that cookie it's creation.
So I'm going to take these or else out of here.
And let's check it real quick if that time at CES.
We got one two and three and four with a function so we're good with them right here.
But this one here needs to be with the L statement right there.
Beautiful.
So now we go back we should be telling us to go back.
You see that.
So your time has expired.
All right.
Perfect.
Make sure yours is good as well.
All right so now that we have all this information then we can start allowing them to reset their password.
We're going to start working on that on the next lecture.
Beautiful.
So organize your call to make sure that you have the right curly brackets here on the right place and
we're good.
All right.
Perfect.
You're doing very good if you're following me if you're not following me.
You're going to get lost and explaining.
And now hold them by the hand too much in this last lectures because what you already are up for a professional
and BHB.
See you in the next lecture.
Very good.