All right welcome back my student.
So it's tough for us to start checking to see if we get some type of response from here right because
we're doing a lot of checks right now and we're checking for that separation.
We're checking for the talking inside the form just to make sure that he can't die whatever data we're
getting comes from that form and we are also checking for that you are able get for the GET request
e-mail and call.
Right.
I'm going to make a little bit of modification here what I'm going to do is I'm going to we want to
check for this one before we check further talking because this was going to be available before.
Right.
So that's how I'm going to do it now.
And then if we get to talking then we can process the form.
All right but here we also got to make sure that they know that this is not going to be available to
us unless we submit the form.
All right.
So keep that in mind.
All right so in order for us not to get an error we need to do it on the set here and then make sure
that we compare it.
All right but let's do this first let's go to our recover and get some new validation cause the way
we can test this out.
All right so let's go and say warren g mail dot com.
All right.
So we got that.
Let's go to our table and let's just quickly refresh you again.
This new validation this double click it and get it.
Let's come back to our tax file and that's good.
We don't you know this stuff here let's just replace this one here real quick.
Need a you code.
Right you see how easy this is.
Now I come back here and paste in the browser and are now looking into our code right.
So now we can go and do this.
We can also trend this just in case they make a mistake in typing space or something when they pasting
it.
We can do it as well.
Right guys you know that let's just click continue and you see we get these undefined talking heads
because we are trying to use it when he's not actually we're set yet.
So all we can do with that is we can create a new set for that specific
person right here where that person functionality person I'm calling this guy a person already and I'm
calling him a guy.
Him Oh stop geez.
I'm already getting too too too friendly with the Coldiron guys.
Don't do that.
Please don't get too friendly.
So anyway would check to see if this is set.
And we also check checking to see if the talking is set and then were saying and both talking is equal
to session talking.
All right.
So we could divide this a little bit.
And compare it so we can do this like this.
We can do this so that way it can be a little clearer to you.
And then if it's set
we can do it like this.
Well like the
right.
And of course we need this one here.
Make sure that you have your 1 2 3 4 5 down here.
So one two three four and five.
One two three four five.
We got this still here we got those we got this one there.
And this is the
access code right here.
So we're good we are good.
And then we can go.
It works.
All right this is when we set to break something on that form let's look at it real quick and we don't
get no errors.
It works.
Look at that.
All right.
Beautiful.
So now we get right to our.
We sit here.
All right.
So we can say if we're not in we can't select We can update users.
Right.
And we can set the password
equal to and let's escape that real quick
we've got to pass we're coming from the fourth from the set so we can do this.
So this is available that means the form was submitted.
All right.
So that's OK.
And password.
All right.
So we can all day the password.
But we got to do another check before we got to make sure that these two fields match OK.
Let's do this query first.
Where.
He calls or e-mail.
Check this out real quick.
All right.
So before we do that let's compare the fields here.
But we also got to do something else I forgot this password needs to be what you might call it.
We need to verify this password but this is an encrypted password right.
So that's another thing that we've got to do but let's just do this two things.
First if this is this password field is equal to that confirm
right here.
All right.
And as a matter of fact we need to take it out we haven't converted this into variables yet so we need
to use a post super global to do this password.
And I should put this as a placeholder there.
All this is equal to this guy right here.
There's going to be right here.
Then we can do this.
Let's test this real quick.
All right.
This is going to be very secure.
Guys crazy secure
passwords match.
All right let's check it out if hopefully our cookies night spired.
Let's make these cookies expire a little bit later.
Guys seriously.
So let's go to functions and mine is set to five minutes.
Let's send this to 15 minutes.
This is in the valley they code.
All right.
Perfect.
So let's
go to one e-mail right.
And let's come back here and refresh validation code.
Right.
Are based on this jacket then with page that he in the euro and are the same routine that we've been
doing.
Paste this here continue.
We are good to go here.
And now let's just say one two three one two and three.
Enter passwords match.
All right.
So we are good to this point here right.
We're got to cut the video here and we're going to finish on the next lecture OK.
I think we would.
We have been doing very good.
We need to encrypt the password so if you want to go ahead and do that encrypted password compare it.
And if everything is good then we can go heading all day to user right.
Well we got to actually we do have to compare it from the database to be honest with you because what
we're doing is creating a new password so all we got to do is encrypt a new password and then update
whatever we have inside that table.
So if you want to go ahead and do that go ahead and do that.
You're doing very good if you follow me to this to this point.
See you in the next lecture.