All right welcome back my students.
So it's time for us to you know to not feature a couple of bugs but to improve our application a little
bit.
Now in the Forgot Password page right here in the we cover that BHB we're not doing anything with this.
Cancel button here right.
It's not taking us to somewhere else.
It's actually refreshing that page and we don't want to do that.
So we've got to fix that functionality and see that we don't want that to happen.
All right.
We want to go somewhere and we are also going to.
Let me go back to it.
We also won this logo that BHB to be able to to not be here unless we are logged in.
All right.
So let's fix that right now.
When you have a problem like this and you try to refresh back you're trying to go back and forth and
you have that confirmed refresh confirm reload page error that we got on the last one I show you right
now.
We're right here confirm resubmission that's the browser.
All right this is a functionality of some browsers especially chrome that will try to confirm with you
if you want to resubmit the form.
Right.
If they find out that this is not something that you they're just trying to verify if you really want
to resubmit the form.
So this is a function of the browser for that not to happen what you want to do is you want to refresh
the same page.
You want to do a redirect to the same page.
So that way you don't get the error.
But anyway let's go in and get this functionality going.
So that is in recovery that BHB.
Let's go
now recovered and recover underscore password that's where the function ID is so if we get a post requests
we got to do inside just post requests.
So I think we can do it right here.
So if it's said and I believe that Paul Superguy overvalue is canso meant counsel on this course of
May.
Let's go and look at it real quick but I'm almost sure that that's what it is.
So let's go to recover that BHP and cancel the summit.
All right we've got to change it to underscore I like underscores why this only IDs and classes I leave
with a hyphen.
All right.
So let's make sure that we audit correctly and paste that in there.
So if they click on that let's just take them back to index that BHP.
All right.
Or actually logging up BHP that's where they came from.
If they click on this log and up BHB Let's see let's see this thing actually refresh.
Click on it and now takes us back to Logan at BHB.
So that's one thing.
Now the next thing that we need to do is log out.
All right.
That's really easy to fix.
I mean not fit but to add functionality it's got to naff now right here.
Now if we are only going to show this if and our logo functionality is present if we are logged in.
So let's do this.
Right.
And as a matter of fact let's use this shorthand syntax and can show you if you don't know about it
I'd like to show my students new stuff you probably already know that.
But from my All the courses right.
And then and it is like this.
And now we can put the HMO right in the middle.
It's a shorthand syntax for IF statements we can use this for loops as well.
So if we are logged in
then we can show this.
So let's go back here and less refresh.
You can see that it's not there.
So let's log in.
And I believe the new password was my name Edwin Logan.
And now you can see the URL is showing right now and we can log out now.
It's now showing.
All right.
Very easy to add.
Very easy.
All right.
What else do we need.
If we had something else let's go to register to see if that's good there.
All right.
We don't have these contacts.
We want to be able to go to our home page admen if we are logged in.
That's another thing.
All right.
So let's show also admin here.
Add me that BHP.
Let's go and show it up here.
All right.
We're not loading and winter now we're showing admin.
So we go to Home Page and these links are now working so let's fix that real quick.
Let's go to him on this one.
XP and
so we click on it and you see adman's still exist.
And the project name you go to this one as well.
We don't have this contact's pages there.
All right.
Beautiful.
All right we still logged in.
I know that we don't want to see the log in that BHB we are logged in right somebody logged in here
and we don't want to see this page if we are logged in right so we can also check on that real quick.
So let's go to Logan up HP and we can do something up here.
So we're going to say
hey we are logged in.
We don't want to go here we want to go to redirect to admen up here.
All right.
So enter.
And now you can see that we are redirector so we can visit our page even if we wanted to.
All right.
Ogowe it takes us back to home.
And this is where we can logon.
All right.
Remember me.
That will keep keep us logged in for a day I believe that was the last time we said it.
And I think we're done with the functionality I can the next thing for us to do will be to upload this
to the live server and then test to there.
OK.
So and the live server we're going to see this really in good action.
Thank you so much for watching this lecture.
And if you were if you are really happy with this course please don't forget to give me a review and
send me a message and Sundt and tell me that he really helped you out.
That really brings me up a motivated me to keep going and making more courses for you guys.
Thank you so much.
And I'll see you in the next lectures.