Hi welcome back many students so I'm super excited because now is the time to find out if things are
working with that email now.
Remember that the mail function in BHB is not very very good.
It's not 100 percent.
So some email providers might put this in any email coming from the mail function into the spam folder
because a lot of hackers use it to spam people like spammers.
So anyway now we can test the functionality.
Remember me if you want to do that you're welcome to do that.
I'm pretty sure it worked 100 percent but you never know.
Right.
So let's let's just test this out real quick and low again.
All right well Ted we are there let's shut everything down.
All right.
I think I don't have to log in to Go Daddy again.
That's a pain.
That's OK.
You can wait for me right.
All right.
So let's do this and let them call college Logan and you can see takes us to admen because we are still
logged in so that that's working.
Now what we need to also verify that is working is the Forgot Password.
So let's do something here we won here let's say won and you know what we've got to do.
We've got to register my the actual like really the right address because if we register the wrong address
they get our application is going to send e-mail to that address and if it doesn't exist we can really
click on the link right.
So let's go let's register.
I'm going to raise them myself and then I put my writing e-mail information and then I work Whoops I
typed in the wrong stuff here.
I got another application there so I'm logging app registered IP HP.
All right.
So I'm going to put my silver in there and I'm going to call myself.
Just anyone that's going to be my user name email address is going to be
support at coring faculty.
That's my Web site for courses.
Faculty dot com.
All right.
And I'm going to put some password that you don't know.
All right so you're welcome to put whatever password you want.
I'm just going to put a very short password here.
All right.
And then I registered.
And he says please check your email and I'm going to do that right now so wait a minute.
And then I see if it went to my e-mail address so I can show it to you.
OK.
And it looks like I got it.
I've got a whole bunch of other e-mails that I want to show you.
All right.
So anyway I'm going to show you why not.
I got a whole bunch of stuff here coming from postal service e-bay and Buddha or whatever.
So you can see that it came from Rico 20:30 awry active account of this subject.
And now we've got this link right here.
Pretty exciting right.
We can modify these and make it better.
But I already got this very like if I minimizer you can see it better now.
All right.
So we fight.
Now this is the wrong place of course because he says local So we need to modify that and make it to
go to our website.
All right but I'm going to take this link here.
I'm going to write Colligan going to copy that address and I'm going to modify that address.
All right.
So I'm going to go to my text file here.
We'll correct that in a minute.
But we know he's working.
So I'm going to say I'm going to put my website address in that link right here and like that.
So he's going to be ups.
All right Edwin called College dot com for Slash blowing app and he's going to be activated.
There we go.
And that's going to be that late.
Let's see if that works out.
All right.
And we can activate like the pasted in here.
Enter your account has been activated.
Oh how beautiful that is working really good.
Ryan so happy guys I'm so happy.
Beautiful.
So now here we got a little game right.
So let me see if I remember the e-mail that support and my password and remember me please look again.
We are logged in.
So it's working beautifully.
All right.
Perfect.
So now that it's working really good.
All right.
So now let's say I forgot my password right.
As a matter of fact we got a live this like this on the next leg you were going to check on.
Actually the Forgotten Password why I'm right.
Because we've been doing really good right now and I don't want to really make this like 20 minutes
and then something is wrong and then I will have to go in the next lecture and do it right.
So we did good and this lecture is working.
The only thing that I recommend is for you to go back and change this link on your on the application
and make sure that it is localhost here says your Web site.
All right.
So go back to that function to activate user and change that.
For their age race or user I believe that's where we put it.
But anyway go change that.
Any way you see locals to your Web site if you're doing this on the Web site.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Take care.