All right so in this lecture we are going to be correcting the address where we send the e-mails right.
So I just want to do that make sure that you have it done already in your site.
I'm going to go to functions and then I'm going to edit the function I want to correct it right in front
of you so that where you know exactly where it is.
But you should know this.
I just want to make sure that you do it right.
So I'm going to do a control and command effort just to find this function right here where we are sending
this.
You see this all right.
So I'm going to pace whatever I had.
My you are well and that's going to send this Sree.
He's going to give me the link that I'm looking for.
Save changes.
That's it.
I'm good there.
All right we can close that.
All right.
So now the next thing that I want to check on this here is the Forgot Password.
Now we also need to make sure that this recover sends the right e-mail address as well.
So actually we need to go back to there.
Let's see if we can go to this again and this should be recovered.
SY So let's do my F and let's look let's look for localhost.
All right.
As you can see we have it right here.
So I'm going to this is for recovery password.
So there we go.
Co-host and this one was not set correctly before based on the same code in there and it's going to
go to my
write address save it.
All right so now we should be good.
Let's refresh your errors refresh here.
Good.
All right.
So now I want to replay I want to actually modify walk out.
Let's say I lost my password right or wrong and it's happening here and I got to type in the past where
there probably doesn't exist.
Let's see what we get here.
This e-mail does not exist.
OK.
I just like to see some errors you guys recording faculty can send this.
And please check your spam folder for that.
And sure enough we got it right here.
Please reset your password.
Click on it.
And we got this link right here.
We can modify this.
This is the code here.
Here's your password reset code.
All right.
And we also have it on the euro.
Let's right click and we see we are able to get in this and we can get this cold right here and we can
push a strong extremal tagline here just to make this bold.
All right.
And let's play.
Paste the code writing here and click continue.
Now we are able to reset our password and I'm going to make this something else.
All right.
So my new password is going to be Edwyn 1 2 and 3 and window 1 2 and 3 and 4.
That came back here and it was wrong.
So my password didn't match.
But we didn't get that arrow there.
Let's just do it again.
One two three four.
Actually the one to and Edwin and then one two and three and then at one point two and three we sat
down went through so we have to work and I already change the color in there.
So if you haven't changed it change it to green.
So we have to work on that very very fixation to make sure that that's actually being echoed.
All right.
Print it.
But anyway the good thing is that it works.
And now we can go ahead and say support faculty and we can type in some crazy password.
And those credentials are not good.
And if we come here and we type in the right password and when I want to pray log in.
While the registration system is complete.
All right.
Beautiful.
We can log in again and we can keep logged in anytime we want.
Pretty cool stuff right.
So if you're happy please read discours.
Thank you so much for being my student.
And if I have anything else to add I will keep adding lecture lectures.
You know that I'm always adding lectures if you're taking although my other course is that I have you
know that are always at lectures just to make my course is better.
And you always keep learning with me if I learn something new I'll show it to you and some of you when
you learn something new you of course posted in the discussion board which is pretty cool.
Thank you so much for watching and I'll see you maybe in the next.
Extra lectures.
Oh I see you.
I see you in the next course.
Take care.