All right welcome back my students so I decided to add another lecture here and now we are at functions
at BHB in Amin password.
Underscore we set.
So we saw that when I was showing you in the life server about you know we said when we were resetting
the password I typed in their own password the second field and the password confirm in a confirmed
password field input.
And you know it didn't give us any arrows any timing or or anything like that.
So it would be nice if we get some type of error.
So we're going to add that right now.
So make sure that whatever I show you in the local environment you update it in your life server and
whatever show you life server you are updating your local environment.
All right just in case you do do both.
But if you do only one or your code is going to be here anyway so the password don't match.
We're going to do an else.
We're going to echo some
validation errors.
All right.
Simple as that.
All validation errors and we're just going to echo something like passwords password
fields don't match.
Just in case and we're not going to test that because I'm pretty sure they worked.
But why you want to do is you want to add this to your life server.
All right.
So make sure that you let you add that to your live environment.
Functions right here.
All right.
And that's going to go in the past will reset right all the way down.
You see this right here right right here is make sure this is desk next tag after we direct it is and
we're just going to paste that in there like this and save it.
All right.
And that should work 100 percent there.
I just wanted to for you to be sure that you add that the way you get some verification there are they
don't match or anything like something like that.
Perfect.
So anyway thank you so much for watching my lectures.
And if I have something to add or you have some type of some some function I you would see you want
to see added to the course please post it in the discussion board and I'll see you soon.
Take care.