Hi welcome back my student.
This is Edwin from the future.
We are creating this new section here to fix bugs in the application.
You know not every application is perfect and one of the best part.
In my case my opinion is debugging your application and making it better right.
So in this lecture here we're going to be facing a little bug.
Well a little.
Type all that I have on some of the functions.
So let me show you what it is.
So it is going to find and any editor you can have a Find function on the right are going to find the
splost symbol but in reality let's look for M.D five right.
Let's look for another M.D five and you can see right here any five takes I string parameter all right
to make your pass where you know to hash a password right here.
What the problem is is that we're using a plus symbol to concatenate this.
And if you want to if we really wanted to concatenate is we use a dot notation right.
It still works you know.
But he adds basically the string to the micro time function.
So the correct way of doing it is with the dot notation right.
Let's go to the next one.
And M.D five years good here we have another one.
And this is in the recover PP-ASEL function let's go again.
And it looks like that's it.
All right so in the register use a function and then we cover function is the problem right recoverer
password.
Make sure you have those down notations they are right.
Anyway thank you so much for watching.
And you know some of you already gave me reviews.
I really appreciate that very much that you took the time to express how you feel about this course.
You know for those of you that gave me really good reviews.
Thank you so much.
Without you I wouldn't be here.
I wouldn't have motivation to wake up in the morning or a night time.
I've made these courses here as better as best as I can.
You know I try my best to do these courses.
So.
Well you guys can benefit.
Anyway thank you so much again and I'll see you in the next lectures.
Take care.