Welcome back my students.
So let's go ahead and start this right away.
So what I'm going to do is go to the beach and see a simple on how this is done right.
So we're going to first require the class to instantiate and we're going to use of properties and methods
whatever he has here.
Really call it very simple.
We're going to be doing this using composer of course we create a composer Jason way place that value
in there and run the program.
If you don't have composer remember that you can go ahead and learn how to install it including faculty
that come if you look for the free courses there.
OK.
So we can use this command the composer in our command in our terminal.
If you go to terminal in your project you can see you have to go to your Where are your projects located
in my cases locating application mamber actually docs and them the name of my folder.
This way you're going to be running your composer commands.
Now remember that when you run composer if you install it if your own composer you're supposed to tapping
composer.
And if you get one of these retro that's your thing.
It's installed globally.
If it's not installed globally you're going to have to type composite out ph A R.
OK.
And but anyway go ahead and learn and install compose it should be very very straightforward.
OK then we also want to be using this fake e-mail fake as A.P. testing server OK.
And so go ahead and sign up for that is free.
By the way and I'll show you in a bit other the configurations that we have to set a set up there.
Basically the way we're going to be setting it up is that we're going to be really sending e-mails but
to a different server not to our e-mail provider but we can of course just replace configurations and
that's it for those of you that have windows.
Make sure that if you want it you want a really nice terminal.
Very similar to what I'm doing which is Linux based download get.
And then you're going to have an icon on your desktop and you can just double click it there and open
your command prompt.
I'm using web storm.
I mean BHP storm and I have my terminal down here.
Just a little bit more comfortable but this is basically the same thing as having the terminal open
in the terminal from a different place.
OK.
Dissenting is just wraps around that.
So anyway.
So how can we stop this.
Well first of all we need composer and going to be using a command called require.
So we type in the name of the program composer require.
And then BHB mailer for us last BHB mailer so the author and the package and the name.
So once I do that I was going to download it automatically you're going to see that that command is
going to create a composite adjacent file.
We don't have to create it manually.
We could if we wanted to and then write the Jason data in this well you the penances will be located
like this and then you have another one and another one that separated by coma.
Right.
So it creates a lock files.
Well this is for version documentation here.
And if we go here you can see that it create another full vendor in this way or your packages will be
downloaded to when you use composer.
So composer of course you got that one BHB mailer that's the one we got now.
So if you want to use this package you have to go.
Usually you have to go to this folder to this folder and then you have to require this to load a case
file and once you require that that's going to be allow you to use that program sewing functions we
would go ahead and require that if you wanted to use it OK.
Right.
What I want to do right now is I want to require using composer because if we use a composer We require
a file that composer has here is code overload.
We can actually define that.
Every time we're going to use any of these classes in the vendor directory.
OK we don't have to require this or are is going to require all those classes automatically for us.
OK.
So let's go and use that.
Autoload from composer instead are using requiring every class manually.
So this is actually require
and that dot because I noise in the vendor
Odo Oda that BHP.
So this is in functions.
Actually my ideas is telling me that it's actually there.
Let's go back here.
Let's go to line 1.
In my case I want 44.
And let's go and go to our home page and look at the simple they got there just simple stuff they got
and of course make sure that you instantiate the object class with BHP Meilleur like this can do that
if you're not passing parameters.
And you can leave this here but I'm going to delete it.
It's very clear to us to know what it's doing right.
Well you can leave it there.
It's up to you.
And what else do we need Well we need to check
these lines here
and base that in there real quick.
So here you were typing your hostname and in my case in our case this is going to be as him as MCP dot
male track because that is a program that we are going to be using the server our testing server and
the port is going to be 25 25 and then we need a user name.
And when he or password.
OK so we're going to leave it like that shouldn't be a problem with this.
So what I want to do instead of echoing here I'm going to return
true if this works
and of course
falls
well we can just return to arrow if we wanted to.
But I King I'm going to comment that out.
So you have it
and I'm just going I have no matches.
Message sent.
We're going to return false later.
But that's fine.
OK.
We just want to get this working real quick.
Let's see I got to is missing a return statement so anyway that's my ID telling me that it is.
Let's just you know what
it's doing like this for now.
So let's go to a male trap on the next lecture and get our Sebti our username and password.
OK.
Thank you so much and I'll see you in the next lecture.