Welcome back my students.
So let's face a couple of things.
Well it's not so much a fit scene but Addie So let's go to our same malfunction year and when I want
to add.
You saw that in my e-mail trapping the development server there for the e-mail we saw that we got a
link but that's not going to always be the case sometimes you have to be specific and you have to tell
which remailer to actually send the e-mail.
So make sure that you use this method here and said this true true but the argument.
And another thing is I know some of you are from different countries and you might use defraying and
what you might call it might use different characters in your language and you're going to have things
that we don't have in English.
So when you want to send things like that characters that are not English you want to set this property
chart set and you're going to set this to you T F.
OK.
Basically this UTF and coding basically is going to it's going to have a whole bunch of characters set.
Well is this card that says we're going to have a whole bunch of characters.
They're very common.
OK in many different languages so use that and that you should be good to go.