Operations Backlog and Tickets.
In this section,
we will discuss how we transform a ticket into a fully-formed backlog item.
Let's define in general what an operations backlog means.
It's a prioritized list containing short descriptions
and other information about the issue, functionality or requirements,
desired in the product or system.
For each backlog item, that is ticket,
you want to capture key attributes that'll help you make good decisions.
This is very important.
I'll have a few attributes for you to get you started,
but is very important to choose attributes wisely.
They will help you save loads of time and money.
So before we talk about those key attributes,
let's review the assessment process, a little more detail.
Here is an approach, a process to performing normal ticket assessment.
Assess Backlog Item.
So you or someone else or a small team will review each item.
The assessor owns the backlog item.
Never have a ticket unowned.
So until it is assigned or reassigned to someone else,
it is owned by the person doing the assessment of the ticket.
Next, provide feedback to the ticket creator or the initiator of the ticket,
for example, by sending a confirmation email,
or a Slack message, for example,
or the ticketing system itself will have a feedback loop to the requester,
I'm sure.
You want to inform the requester that the ticket is under review,
and please reply within a reasonable timeframe.
People don't like to wait.
"Gee, I wonder what happened to my ticket.
"Are they looking at it?
" You want good, quick customer service.
Next, you will analyze the request.
Ask the requester questions, get clarifications,
or ask other Subject-Matter Experts for inputs.
Spend only about an hour or two at most per item or ticket.
Do not solve, only assess.
You don't want to spend all day doing solution solving.
You have lots to do with assessing and keeping the
tickets moving forward into the backlog.
Maybe some tickets are literally, five minutes,
five seconds, but never more than one or two hours,
or if it's more than that,
then you add to the ticket that the assessment will take an additional,
say, four hours or eight hours to do the proper analysis.
Next, update attributes of the backlog item or the ticket item.
Now each item will have attributes or information of value
which we will go into detail in the next slide.
Ticket is now ready for grooming, that is it's in your backlog,
it's ready to be looked at and groomed,
and we're going to talk about grooming more in the next section as well.
But now let's talk about those attributes or fields of information that are
very important to be attached to the backlog item or ticket.
The purpose of collecting information is to help you and your
team make good decisions regarding your demand.
You can't make good decisions without good data.
So you need to decide what are the minimum fields you need
filled out to be able to make good decisions.
Timeliness in analyzing the request is important.
If you take too long, you are likely not to meet the customer's needs.
Also, who is responsible for doing it, doing the analysis?
You need someone to be relatively savvy about the business and
the systems in order to perform the data fulfillment activity
and prepare the ticket for grooming.
The person doing the initial assessment may not be the person doing the
analysis and gathering the important data element.
It certainly could be, but doesn't have to, and lastly, urgency.
Most tickets may be changes to an existing system,
like I need a new ID, add a new field to the report,
or things that I have been calling normal tickets,
but at times that normal ticket might be extremely important,
or even politically important, that needs immediate disposition,
maybe not a production issue, but needs to be handled very quickly.
Once I worked in a ticketing system that had a checkbox for VIP,
very important person, and the name of that person,
and if you check VIP, it went to the top of the queue,
quite interesting.
All right.
So let's go over the list of attributes that I think are important.
So what do you think they should be?
Here is an example list of attributes that might work for you as a starter list.
Ultimately the list of attributes is what you and your team
needs to do the job and it's up to you.
Now I have two columns here: the attribute and an example.
The first, item number or ID, and it should be unique.
It's just an easy way to do a reference, certainly.
Next, a short description of the item.
Ensure it's easy-to-read and easy to understand its intent,
in this case, modify the home page to reflect the five new products.
Category, such as maybe operations, could be an activity,
a project, just some sort of way to categorize this particular demand item.
You may want to filter later, like,
well show me all the items that have to do with operations,
or show me all the items that has to do something else.
So a category bucket is quite handy.
Next, system reference, maybe there is a system or application name or a tag,
maybe it's the corporate website or something like that,
then level of effort or LOE.
It could be something chunky like just use small,
medium, large, similar to the scrum style,
or it could be number of hours like 40 hours.
Maybe the small medium large might be something
like less than 25 hours is small, 25 to 50,
medium, 50 to 100, large, anything over 100 is really large.
Maybe just have some sort of yardstick like that that
helps your team quickly go small, medium,
large.
Next, due date.
There's always going to be a due date.
When do they want it?
Many times, it might just be right now.
Next, blocker.
What items are blocking or impeding this item?
Here's a quick definition.
A blocker is something that is blocking or impeding your work.
It's in the way of moving forward.
In other words, there's no way you could do this ticket,
that is this backlog item, unless the blocker is removed.
For example,
you need to meet with Joe who's a subject-matter expert and he's out of town,
so we have to wait.
Next, risk.
What risks might there be, such as we may lose revenue if we don't do this.
Again,
a risk is defined as something that might happen in
the future to affect the item.
So you need to consider risk as well.
Next is sponsor.
Now a sponsor could be the actual ticket requester,
but what I really mean by this is is this requester,
underneath a particular senior manager or vice president,
for example.
I want to know where in the organization this ticket is coming from.
This could be very, very important.
Maybe the company right now has issues with manufacturing,
and therefore, any ticket that comes through,
maybe the VP of Manufacturing,
I might want to move up higher on the list to get done because I
know the business is really having trouble now manufacturing
certain items and getting them out the door.
All right, the next is urgency or impact.
Urgency values may be things like high, medium,
or low, and the impact is maybe the broadness of the issue.
It might be very urgent, but affect two people.
It may not be that urgent, but affects 2, 000 people.
So something less urgent, but affecting more people may drive a higher priority.
Next, business domain.
For example, is it manufacturing, engineering,
sales, things like that,
and may want to know where in the business does this fit.
Of course, technical domain.
Is this a.
NET thing, a Java thing, e-commerce, maybe SAP, Oracle, or other platforms.
It may be great to just know what that technology is because
it may help you make the particular assignments or assign
the right resources later on.
Lastly in my example is priority.
I like to assign numbers, like one, or two, or three, and they are unique.
I never use the same number twice.
I don't have five number ones because that's just plain impossible and silly.
So priority is a category that identifies the relative importance of this
particular issue or problem or change and the priority all of times is
going to be based on the impact and urgency,
in particular, maybe even some of the other attributes I mentioned.
So I do use impact and urgency to help me assign the particular priority.
Now notice the attributes are all about collecting information to
provide you data you need to prioritize and assign resources and to
decide if or when to start the particular work.
None of the attributes have to do with the actually working the ticket item.
That'll come later after it's been approved and is being worked.
When it's being worked,
then additional attributes could be filled out in terms of its progress.
Okay, now let's move on to grooming and con-bon for operations in the next section.