Now let's recap right work versus work right.
Demand management is all about determining and selecting the right work to do.
And work management is all about literally doing the work in the right way.
That is following the best practices, standards,
and tools that your company or organization adopts
in order to carry out your work.
Our key work management types are operations... Again,
that's on-going work, short verse of activity,
made right projects, and you have to have a lot of business domain.
Next is project.
Remember, projects have a beginning and an end.
They're may be in the long term, and they're very focused activities.
And initiatives are long-term strategies that drive large
projects and require large resource commitments.
And they are very important to the success of a company.
Now, they each have their own process for demand management,
though similar,
and they each have their own processes for getting
the work done in the right way.
We focused on demand first in this course,
so you can see the distinction between demand and work,
and that demand is the process of selecting the right work.
Then we discuss the work management processes for operations,
projects, and initiatives.
In actuality,
demand and work should be one integrated and continuous overall
process with subprocesses for each work type.
Yet I also want you to know that at a macro level,
demand and work are one big process and should be tightly integrated.
IT has a pretty challenging balancing act, in my opinion.
74% of senior IT leaders say it is challenging to balance business initiatives,
innovation, products, services, very disruptive,
with operations.
Therefore,
you need a really good structuring process to manage
demand and work management for operations,
projects, and initiatives like you've seen in this course. Now let's move on to recapping demand management.