Now let's recap tickets, backlog, and grooming.
For this course,
a ticket is a representation of an instance of potential work to perform.
A ticket starts like as a demand item.
For each ticket,
you must capture key attributes that will help you make good
decisions about how to disposition the ticket to either get
right on it since it is a hot issue,
prioritize it and keep it in the backlog and revisit later,
or possibly it shouldn't belong to you in the first place.
And you reroute the ticket.
Sometimes, the term "ticket" is also called an issue,
card, or requirement, or even some other term.
Demand is a term representing all of your unstructured potential work,
where a backlog is a prioritized list of known work containing
information about the desired requirement in a product,
service, or system.
Backlogs are the same in the conceptual sense for each of the
three work types that we have defined: operations,
projects, and initiatives.
Grooming is the process of reviewing items in the backlog to
ensure the backlog contains the appropriate items,
that they are prioritized,
and that the items at the top of the backlog are ready to be worked.
The grooming activity could be done daily or weekly,
or whatever period makes the best sense for you and your team.
Now, grooming for projects and initiatives tend to be longer cycle, such as quarterly or even longer.