Now let's recap operations work management.
Here are the key concepts for operations management.
The role of operations: make it as easy as possible for your
customers to maximize their productivity.
You exist to service your customers.
Operations work management process.
In my opinion,
you must have a ticketing process as the core way to manage your work.
Design it, build it, get buy in from your team and customers,
and use it and improve the process overtime.
Why Kanban?
Because it's just great.
It is an easy technique, highly visible,
simple to comprehend, yield in great results.
We also talked about Sprint versus Kanban.
Now, in a nutshell with Sprint,
the deliverables are determined by a sprint or a set periods of time.
And with Kanban, work is delivered continuously in an as needed basis.
The importance of quality triage.
With quality triaging,
your developers and QA teams will appreciate complete bug tickets that has
all the information that is there and then they correct it.
And the product will have a deeper understanding
about the health of their system.
Organizing operations.
So which is the best way to organize your team?
There is no one right answer,
but I wanted you to be aware of the numerous approaches of
structuring your app support organization.
And lastly, organizational dynamics.
Be vigilant and look for opportunities.
New hires may drive possibilities.
Also rotate people through different roles and make
customer service an absolute.
Now let's review Kanban.
Here is a Kanban board.
We have three columns in this case.
We have the To Do column on the left.
Middle column Doing, that's the work in progress.
And the last column is the Done column.
The To Do column of course is our backlog, those are things we need to do.
We will review those items on the left column,
approve them to be work, then we would move the card into the Doing column.
After we complete the work, we would move the card into the Done column.
And as I've mentioned,
you can add as many columns as you want to simulate
any kind of workflow you have. Very easy, very powerful tool to use, highly recommended.