Hello, I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the overview module in the course Demand
and Work Management: A Practical Guide.
Let's get started.
Have you ever asked yourself: Do I need more people?
Seems like I have too much to do.
Am I working on the right stuff?
Everything seems important.
Am I getting the right guidance from my customers, managers, and stakeholders?
Do I need to hire more with new skill sets,
maybe more leadership-type people as well?
How am I going to get this done?
What is the best way to do the work that I have?
What's the priority?
Everyone is saying do mine first.
Is there visibility to what I'm doing?
Can others see my list of work to do and see my
progress on the work that I'm doing?
Or conversely, have you ever been asked these questions by others?
And if you have, did you struggle with the answers?
Well, you are not alone.
Most people do struggle.
And a major client of mine, the senior vice president told one of his directors,
"You will get the resources you need.
"Just give me the business case "or show me some data or something.
" Since the director had no written list or backlog of work
and no way to status and track his work,
he was unable to get resources.
Yes, he did need them,
but any reasonably qualified senior manager must act on good solid data,
not just, "Gee, I'm really, really busy; can I hire?
" Sorry, that doesn't work for me either. Now, let's find out just why you are here watching my course.