Key Roles in Demand Management.
In this section,
I thought I would share with you the key roles that are essential for supporting
demand management for each of the demand types: operations,
projects, and initiatives.
Here are a few key demand management roles that would be
required to run demand management for operations.
Manager or Leader.
This person is the process owner of the operations demand management.
They would lead, coach, and mentor the team,
and can do any of the roles, if needed.
Next should be the Queue Monitor, someone or team,
monitoring, reviewing the queue,
performing the triage and keeping the tickets moving forward.
Analyst.
You will need one or more analysts to perform the analysis for each ticket.
This role will perform more in-depth review and research if needed,
and the Groomer role, facilitate the daily grooming,
review items in the queue, ensure attributes are in place,
adjust priorities.
Remember, people may have one or more roles.
When I use the term role,
it does not necessarily represent a single person only doing that job.
Now, in a very large organization, that might be very likely,
of course, and if I was the leader of this team,
I would have everyone cross-trained to be able to do any role.
Now let's take a look at project roles.
Here are a few key demand management roles that would be required
to run demand management for projects: PMO,
Manager or Leader.
Here,
PMO stands for the Project Management Office and either the PMO or
manager would be the process owner of the project demand
management activities and they would lead,
coach and mentor the team, that is the manager could do any of those roles,
if needed.
Project Manager, Project Leader, and Project Coordinator,
all roles responsible for the actual running of the projects.
Even though this role was more on the work-management side of the house,
I have placed them here since they'll be working on the processes within
the PMO and how to execute and deliver the projects.
Queue Monitor,
someone or team monitoring and reviewing the queue of new projects,
performing the triage, and keeping the projects moving forward.
Business Analysts and Groomer.
You will need one or more analysts to perform the analysis for each project.
This role will perform more in-depth review and research,
if needed, of course, and the groomer, facilitate the grooming,
reviewing projects in the queue, ensure the attributes are in place,
adjust priorities,
and of course review the status and outcomes of projects in work and make
any resource or priority changes as needed as well.
As before, remember, people may have one or more roles.
So when I use the term role,
it does not necessarily represent a single person only doing that job.
If I was again the leader of this team,
I would have everyone as cross-trained as possible to be able to do any role.
Okay, now let's look at the initiative roles next.
Here are the initiative demand management roles: our steering group,
comprised of senior executive and SMEs, Subject-Matter Experts,
which will be the governance of the demand initiative process.
Senior business architects and analysts that really know the business.
These people will help with the business cases,
perform return on investment, do high-level planning and business architecture,
and of course, portfolio program and project managers and support teams.
These will be the leaders to actually run the portfolio management office,
the program management office, maybe offices,
and the project management offices as well. Now let's summarize this module in the next section.