Operations Work Management Process.
In the previous section,
we talked about just what the operational role is and its activities.
Now we want to talk about how we want to execute and manage
that work through a work management process.
Let's recap our demand sources for operations.
Pretty much, everything is going to come through from verbal,
phone, email, forms, and tickets themselves,
of course.
And what do we do with those requests for services?
Let's check it out in the next slide.
In the operations world,
everything is a ticket or certainly should be in my humble opinion.
Trust me, this makes life so, so much easier.
You may think, "Ah, what a pain.
"I need to open a ticket or add to a ticket.
" But it is an essential tool for all operations work.
The operations world can be crazy busy.
If you don't track your tickets, you can't measure.
If you don't measure, you cannot improve.
So go find a tool and use it.
I will talk a bit about tools in the summary module.
Now on to the operations ticket process.
Here is the operations ticket process at a very high level.
We have done our triage and backlog grooming like we
discussed in the previous module.
Now we have all of our approved tickets,
some of which may be hot production fixes,
and we're going to have to get on those ASAP,
and others will be what I call normal work.
Either way, the tickets are basically all treated the same.
Now, this is a very high level.
Now, the next slide,
I want to go through a detailed timeline of events in the life of a ticket.
Here's a timeline of ticket events.
The first event is approval.
Demand management approves and releases the ticket after triage.
Next, it is assigned.
Resources are assigned and allocated and the ticket is updated.
Resources meaning one or more people may be assigned,
and the ticket then collects additional information about who was assigned.
Next, well, the work is in progress.
Work is being performed, and the ticket can be periodically updated with status.
Next, it's ready for QA, the work is done.
So the resources prepare for customer testing and buy off,
and the ticket again is updated.
Next, customer approval.
The customer tests and approves or rejects a ticket,
and then a ticket is updated as well.
Now, if the ticket is rejected, it flows back to work in progress,
and it'll be ready for QA again and ready for customer approval.
But if the customer approves the ticket,
then it's scheduled for production,
and the resources hand off to devops or maybe installs themselves,
and the ticket information is updated again.
And lastly, ticket closure.
To me, it can only be closed by the ticket creator.
And then the ticket information is updated again.
Now, this is just a general process, and you may have your own,
but be sure you document it and communicate it to all users of the process.
Tracking your work is, to me, an absolute priority and benefit to you,
your customers, and your management.
Here's a tip.
Have a process for managing the workflow of your ticket events.
And here's a way to maybe do that.
To design it with your team, just don't force it on them.
Get together as a team and come up with your own design.
Build it, though, using an automated tool.
There are so many out there.
And again, the summary module will talk about some of the tools.
And get buy in, not only from a team,
but key users as well because they'll be main participants.
Then use it and improve it over time.
Now, my previous slide was a very simplified workflow process.
Many automated tools have workflow templates that
you can use and customize as well.
I suggest you start with one of those and then tweak it to meet your needs. Now let's go check out kanban.