In this section we will define just what a project is or
what our project should be so we are on the same page as
we work through this module.
Here is a basic definition of a project.
A project is a temporary group activity designed to produce a unique product,
service or result.
Now, notice these keywords.
Temporary implies a start and an end.
Group implies more than one person, usually a team.
And unique,
a project is something special and not normal for
the current business Operations.
Now, here is another way of looking at the definition of a project.
Because activities can have a significant impact on the business,
the construct of a project was created.
So it is important to have a disciplined approach to
certain kinds of work in order to provide focus and
visibility to the success of the business.
That is why I have separated out Operations to focus on that type of activity
and in this module we are focusing on the project activity.
And lastly, in the next module, we will focus on initiative activities.
Now let's check out the attributes of a project.
So why are certain activities labeled projects?
Well, they have certain attributes or characteristics and let's discuss a few.
Criticality.
When work is critical to the business,
it is recommended that you make it a project.
Focus.
When work has a project, the business can provide better focus to that activity.
When work is critical and there is focus, you also need visibility.
Visibility is when the project's outcomes are being reported to
managers and leaders of the organization.
A project is unique in that it is not normally a routine operation.
In fact, the activity may not have been done before at all,
so a project is a specific set of activities designed to
accomplish a singular unique goal.
But that's not all.
Now, let's talk about a few more attributes.
Here are a few more attributes or characteristics of a project.
A project has a defined scope.
Project scope is the part of project planning that involves determining
and documenting a list of specific project goals,
deliverables, features, functions, tasks,
deadlines and ultimately cost.
In a nutshell scope's what needs to be achieved and the work
that must be done to deliver its outcome.
Yes, I know, the scope keeps changing, known as scope creep.
But there is still scope and hopefully a change management process to
manage the changes in scope and to set expectations.
That is why project managers are so critical to the success of projects
and we will discuss their role in the next section.
Projects have a specific start date and when completed, there's an end date.
Projects are not Operations.
They start and they end.
Resources, a project has resources provided by management such as people,
money, equipment, etc.
to sustain the project.
And lastly, closure.
This is very important.
This term represents the end of the project.
Some closure activities are to secure client acceptance,
transition results from the project to Operations,
capture lessons learned, close out any contractual and business matters,
and hopefully, celebrate your success.
Now let me give you some examples of projects.
I am sure you are all familiar with projects but here are some examples.
Implementing a ticketing system to streamline our Helpdesk workload.
The migration of a company's applications to the cloud.
Maybe you are migrating from an old,
internal on-premise system to a cloud-based system.
Adding a new module component to your existing web application.
Maybe it is to enhance the sales order web-based system
with a mobile order status module.
Upgrade to a new CAD that is a new computer-aided design system.
This may require new hardware, network, software licenses,
configuration, customer integration, training,
and a myriad of other actions.
Remember, projects, to be successful,
must be formally managed to deliver on time and on budget results.
Now think of your own environment.
Are you on any projects?
Which ones?
Do they have a defined scope, start date, end date?
Assigned resources?
A list of tasks to accomplish?
If not, it is either Operations' work or a very poorly defined project.
Now, the PMO, the Project Management Office,
is a critical element to the overall success of your projects and in the next
section we will see that the rubber meets the road with the project manager and their essential role in project execution.