Here are the course modules.
First, we're going to explore the fundamentals of demand management.
Then, construct your demand and management process.
Next, building your operations management process.
Next, building your project management process.
And next, building your initiative management process.
And lastly will be the course summary and a recap of your understanding.
Now here is an interesting quote.
"All things are in a state of flux" by the Greek philosopher Heraclitus.
Can you imagine he was way out ahead of his time and he
was way out ahead of agile methodology, like,
by 2500 years?
Because we know that change is constant,
all of our processes, by which we manage any sort of systems development,
must be able to adapt to change.
Don't fight change, embrace it.
We talk about following the agile process to write software.
Well, let's follow the agile, AKA, adaptive process,
to manage our demand or work intake, and also the work itself.
Lastly,
Heraclitus was famous for his insistence on ever present changes
being the fundamental essence of the universe.
And so, it is.
Change is all around us. Okay, now let's see what demand is all about in the next module.