Traditional Project Management.
In this section,
I will walk you through the traditional project management steps that have
been widely used in industry and quite successfully,
I might add, for many years.
So what does the phrase project management mean to you?
Here's a basic definition.
Project management is the discipline of initiating,
planning, executing, controlling,
and closing the work of a team to achieve specific goals
and meet specific success criteria.
The primary challenge of the discipline of project management is to
achieve all the project goals within the given constraints.
Let's review the five phases of traditional project
management on the next several slides.
Over the next few slides,
we will cover the five phases of traditional project management.
Sometimes these are referred to as process groups versus phases.
It'll be a broad brush of these phases.
Whole courses exist on these topics, if you're so inclined.
The first, concept and initiation phase.
That is, how do the projects get started?
Planning, how do you know what to do, when and by whom?
Execution, how things get done.
Performance and monitoring, that is how are we doing?
How is the project progressing?
And lastly, closure.
It's when the project is done and what makes it complete?
Okay,
now we're going to go into each one in a little more detail so
you'll have a really good understanding of each.
First, a note on the slide structure for the next five slides.
On the left will be the phase name and the title
will be the English translation, if you will.
Okay, how do projects get started?
We did discuss this in the Demand Management modules and I am repeating it
here for completeness since inception initiation is one of the five
industry-recognized phases of project management.
Okay, the drivers for new projects come from management directives,
of course, project request systems, potentially,
tickets from Operations, projects from initiatives.
These were the four drivers of new projects that we discussed earlier.
Now,
all of these drivers will feed into the PMO or business analysts who will
begin documenting the project definition in more detail.
It will have things like scope, budget, high-level requirements,
cost savings or business value and things like that.
Remember, we call these the project backlog attributes in the Demand modules.
We need this information for project grooming and selection,
so we review the project definition information to help us determine
the project priorities and which to select next.
Project launch,
lastly a project is selected to work and we are ready to launch it.
Now what?
Well, the output of this phase is a solid,
written project definition document and the approval to work the project.
Now, let's move on to planning.
How do we know what to do next?
We begin detailed planning, input, project definition.
In order to start this phase,
you need to receive the project definition from the previous phase.
I have seen a million ways companies do this from verbal
descriptions to a one-pager to a document six inches thick.
I just recommend you have a documented process and that you
have collected the important and critical information you
need to do most of your planning.
Input into the planning phase.
You want to validate the project definition.
You want to do this with the team,
validate the contents of the project definition since there may have
been some time between project approval and you being assigned the
actual planning portion of this project.
So you may need to just double check the document and its contents.
Build your list of tasks.
Sometimes we call this a WBS, a Work Breakdown Structure.
Understand all of the work that needs to be done and itemize it.
Next, itemize the acceptance criteria.
Obviously,
the WBS will list all of your activities but sometimes the real desired
outcome of the project can't get lost in the details of the WBS.
The acceptance criteria can be phased, as well.
So put together a list of major milestones by date And what will be
delivered in terms of the customer and not in technical terms.
Apply resources.
Resources are usually people and tools but may include other items.
For each WBS or each task listed,
identify who will work this task and when they are
needed to start working on the task, the project.
In addition you may need other resource details such as role
description like maybe senior developer,
required skills like.
Net or SQL server,
training needs like Angular or React and skill experience
level like maybe 10 years' experience in software development
in the healthcare business domain.
Also put together your estimates.
So for each task,
make an estimate of hours based on the resource that
you have assigned and as a result, in a high-level budget.
Develop your schedule.
A project schedule will have start and end dates for each
task and ultimately the entire project.
Remember,
all projects have an overall start and end date and
it'll be determined by this schedule.
So the output of this phase is a solid written project plan.
Now, let's move on to execution.
So how do things get done?
Now, the input for this phase is the project plan.
The plan you're going to use to execute the project.
The project manager will be coordinating the people
and resources to implement the plan.
So basically, execution is execute the plan.
Also,
there are a couple of other very important things you will
need to support the execution of the project.
It's leadership.
It is the action of leading a group of people or an
organization to a common set of goals.
Also,
leadership is the ability to guide others in a direction or decision that
leaves them still feeling empowered and accomplished.
For those who know me, you know I'm crazy about snow skiing.
Well, leadership is like skiing.
You can't just learn it by reading about it.
You just have to do it.
So if you're thinking of leading a group or a team or
a department or an organization, jump in and do it.
You need that experience.
And lastly, you need effective communication.
A big part of a PM's job in executing projects is communications.
Project managers need to be great communicators.
To me,
it's hard to imagine a successful PM and a successful project
that does not have a good communicator.
The end of this phase is really a completed project
but before we move on to closure,
let's talk about reporting and monitoring as we are executing a project.
While the previous three steps or phases are underway,
you will need to report and communicate to others that is,
how well are we doing?
For example, are we on budget?
Do you think we will meet the schedule?
Are we meeting the customer's expectations?
Do we have any known issues or risks?
Project controls are all the things you use to monitor
and measure the progress of a project, also known as project performance.
Here are the key activities for this phase.
Communications management.
Communicating project information to your stakeholders,
customers, users and team members.
This would include things like status reports,
executive briefings, budget reviews and steering committee meetings,
to name a few.
Change management.
That's reviewing, approving,
prioritizing and implementing changes also known as change control.
Configuration management.
Controlling the versions and content of the project deliverables.
Requirements management.
Ensuring all business requirements are identified,
tracked and managed Risk and issue management.
Identifying, monitoring and responding to risks and issues.
And vendor management.
Managing your suppliers and vendors supporting the project.
All of these activities are in progress throughout the project.
Now, let's move on to see how to close a project.
When is the project done?
Well,
the goal of this phase is to bring closure to your
project for all parties involved.
So here's the checklist.
For closure to happen,
you want to make sure you've met all the project's success
criteria and met the customer's expectations.
You want to transfer responsibility of the project deliverables to the
operational support part of the house or the organization.
You want to thank and acknowledge all participants.
This is important.
Everyone has likely worked very hard and we all like to be thanked.
A retrospective and improvements.
That is get the team together and have a retrospective or
another term would be a lessons learned.
Talk about what worked and talk about what didn't work,
and make changes to your processes and make
recommendations to the Project Management Office,
as well.
In my experience, I have found that companies have a hard time doing this right.
For example,
project team members continue to support the operational aspects of the
outcome of the project when they shouldn't or they don't thank the team
for their hard work and may feel unappreciated.
Not only thank them but maybe make it an event with awards or
dinner or another form of appreciation.
Alright!
Now, would you like to learn more about project management?
You may want to consider checking out another one of my courses,
Project Management for Software Engineers here on Pluralsight.
In this course, you can quickly learn common sense,
experience-based tips and pointers on how to improve
your project management skills.
You will learn the practical elements of working with customers,
people, technology,
processes and connecting them successfully to be more
effective as a project manager.
Next, some words of wisdom.
Here's a tip for those who are project managers or leaders.
Plan for the worst, expect the best.
It goes against human nature to always expect the worst.
But with IT projects, pessimism, otherwise known as contingency planning,
is a good way to keep small issues from becoming full-blown business disasters.
So when you finish making that project plan,
well, plan, plan and then plan some more.
Alright,
now let's move on to an Agile approach to project management in the next section.