Identifying sources of demand.
So, how and where does all this demand, requests for your products and services,
come from?
Let's find out.
Let's look at the sources of demand for the demand type operations.
So, where is all your work coming from?
Verbal, people might just stop you in the hall,
go to your desk, or your manager just says,
go do this.
Could be the phone.
People might just call you and say, this is what I want or need from you.
Email, or maybe a messaging service will ask for your help.
At least with email or a messaging service,
say, like Slack, you have something in writing,
much better to act on.
Next, maybe a form.
That is someone used a paper form, or electronic form,
or system to capture and log the request,
certainly even better than email.
And, lastly, maybe it's a ticket,
that is you are using a real issue management system that has tickets,
that is issues a request, they're captured,
and they're tracked.
I think this is even better.
Now, all of these make up your work intake,
that is your operations demand of things people are asking or telling you to do.
So, this is the point at which the operations demand management process begins.
Now, let's check out the demand sources for projects.
Let's look at the sources of demand for the demand type projects.
So, where is all your project work coming from?
Well, it could be a management directive,
someone up high on the organization chart,
or your boss, assigns you, your team,
or your department a project or even multiple projects.
It could also be a project request system.
Many organizations have a process to collect project requests.
So, someone fills out a few electronic forms and they get routed,
say, to you, and then they get worked.
Could be tickets.
There could be some tickets that are in fact not really quick fixes,
but actually, upon further review by you,
much more complex.
And, hence, you might decide they weren't being categorized as a project,
and not just another operational task.
Lastly, projects come from initiatives.
Remember, initiatives are very large,
very strategic activities that in fact are a main
source of driving new projects.
Now, all of these make up your work intake,
that is your project demand of things people are asking or telling you to do.
So, this is the point at which the project demand management process begins.
Now, let's check out the demand sources for initiatives.
Let's look at the sources of demand for the demand type initiatives.
So, where is all your work coming from for initiatives?
It could be from the board of directors.
You don't get much more senior than the board of directors of a corporation,
large or small for that matter.
Typically, a board is looking at very high level and broad strategies.
Steering groups.
Many times these are comprised of senior company
individuals across multiple business domains,
such as manufacturing and engineering, within a company.
Senior executives.
They may band together to tackle problems and
comprise their own list of initiatives.
Business leaders.
Maybe this group is not only leaders in a company,
but may also comprise of business leaders in the community,
or their supply chain, as two examples, all working together.
And, lastly, PMO,
which is the portfolio management office that I'll
further define in the next slide.
Now, all of these make up your work intake for initiatives.
That is, your initiative demand of things people are asking or telling you to do.
So, this is the point at which the initiative demand management process begins.
The next module is dedicated to elaborating on the demand
management processes for each of the three demand types.
But, before we end this module, it is important to define the term, PMO, a little further.