So, what does PMO stand for?
Well, when you find out, let me know.
Okay, I'm kidding, but this abbreviation seems to be misinterpreted by many.
I will give you a quick definition of the PMO,
but we'll go into much more detail in the remaining modules.
At a high level, the PMO is an organizational structure.
Sometimes, PMO refers to the project management office,
so, in a nutshell, responsible for the management of projects,
and the processes by which they follow to manage those projects.
Next, program management office, which is responsible,
you guessed it, for the management of programs.
Now, think of programs as a container for multiple projects.
And, lastly, like I mentioned in the previous slide,
portfolio management office,
and that's responsible for the management of portfolios,
which is typically a container for one or more initiatives
further containing programs and projects.
These organizational structures are very important to the success
of demand and work management best practices,
very important.
As I stated, we will go into much more detail in the remaining modules. Okay, now let's summarize this module.