Hello and welcome to the final episode of this module the episode we will get to see the final result.
Not only are we going to see the training of our DC fans but also we're going to see what it's capable
of in terms of art.
We're going to see the generated images of our DC guns in this fall their result here that so far is
empty.
As you can see as far is empty it's going to be populated with all the fake images of our Zygons.
We're going to check if it looks like something.
So if you're ready we'll start by printing some interesting information that we would like to see during
the training.
And that is for example the Epoque how many epochs out of 25.
And also the step that would be nice to see the steps reached because there are actually a lot of steps
in the day loading many batches so let's print of this and mostly what we need to do also is to save
the images in this result's folder.
And then after all this will be good to start the show.
So let's do this let's quickly do those print.
So I'm going to put in quotes.
Well first the box into brackets so I'm going to add a percent D out of percent D because you know this
first percent will correspond to the epoch.
The second percent will correspond to 25.
So you know we'll see like the epical reached out of 25.
Then we're going to do something similar for the steps.
So I'm adding another pair of square brackets.
Percent D out of percent D.
So this time percent here will correspond to the step I and percentage will correspond to the number
of elements and they lower that is Lendale or lower.
All right.
And then after this that is for each step of each epoch we will print the last of the discriminator
which will be here since it's a float.
We're going to add some percent that for f to have a float with four decimals then we're going to add
the same for the loss of the generator.
So I just need to replace the here by less Gee there we go almost over.
Now we need to get out of the quotes at some percent and then in some parenthesis we put the names of
the variables that correspond to these values here the percentages and the percent point for refs.
All right.
So the first value to response to this First percent D is Epoque.
So here we have two input first Epoque then the second percent here corresponds to 25.
So when 25 then the third percent here corresponds to the step.
I see that exactly.
I then the fourth percent here corresponds to the number of mini batches that is Lenn they are lower.
So here I'm adding Lenn data low.
And then finally we have to input the variable names for our two losses corresponding to point for f
and point for f..
So the first one is the last of the discriminator and the variable for that is.
So I'm adding a comma and the variable for that is of course the R R D.
But then to get the value itself we need to take the data attribute and then in some brackets we add
zero.
That will get us exactly what we want that is the value of the error of the discriminator.
Perfect almost done.
We need to do the same for the generator.
So come out the same and we replace our Ardi by R.G..
Perfect.
I think our print is ready.
Great.
Now as you can see I would like to save the real images and the generated images of the mini batch every
100 steps.
So now we're going to do is to make an IF condition that will save the images every 100 steps.
And the trick to do that is to an IF condition and then I present 100 equal equal zero.
That's the rest of the division of I buy 100.
So if the rest of the division of I by One hundred is zero that means that I's divided by 100.
And so this way we get this step every 100 steps are right every 100 steps.
What do we do.
Well first we're going to save the real images.
So to do this I'm going to take you tiles which is the shortcut name we gave to torch vision that you
that allowed to save some images with torch vision.
An advanced library of torch for computer vision.
So you teals and then we're going to use to save underscore image function to save the different images
that is the real images on which our model was trained.
And then the fake images.
So we're going to start with the real images and therefore what we have to put here is our batch of
real images that we called real.
That's the first argument and then for the second argument we need to specify in quotes the name of
the path leading to the location where we want to save the real images.
And this path is going to be P.C. S which is a train that will refer to the route then slash results
because the results folder here is a subfolder of our replow the root folder.
So prison S then slash and then after that we need to give the name to the PNAC founders who contend
these images.
And we're going to call them real and this core samples that PNH.
All right and then some percent and in some double quotes we need to specify the string attached to
this percent S and that is that slash results because the name of the folder where we want to save the
images is our results folder and this that here corresponds to the roots that is this working directory
folder.
All right.
And then we can add a third argument which is just to normalize.
And this argument is normalize and we have to set it equal to true.
Perfect.
So we saved our batch of real images contained in real here and now we're going to do the same for the
fake images.
So we're going to get these fake images by calling our next G network again to which we feed the noise
random vector.
So we're just doing it again to get the fake images.
And now we can save them so I'm just going to copy this line pasted right below.
And now I just need to replace a few things first.
This time we're not setting the real image but fake that data that's what contains the fake images.
Then here we keep present.
As for the name of the path leading to the folder where we save our images but then we're not going
to call them this time.
Real samples but fake underscores samples underscore airpark underscore.
And here I'm going to put the number of the epoch when the fake images are saved.
And to do this I'm going to specify here a double with three integers so present.
Oh 3D.
And then that PNH.
All right.
And then since I added a new variable here with the percent of 3D then besides the path of the results
in double quotes I need to add the variable corresponding to 0 3 and according to you what is it.
Well that's of course the epoch.
So that's where you will get the fake images and we'll know from which book they are coming.
All right.
We will know in which epoch they were produced by the generator.
Perfect.
And then I'm keeping normalize equal.
All right.
And now we're ready to watch the final result.
And so if you're ready now it's time for the show.
And there we go.
I just executed.
I selected all the code and pressed command or control plus enter.
And there we go.
We have started the training.
So as you can see this is the first epoch and the first steps with 0 1 2 3 4.
And for each of the step in each book we get Indeed the last of the discriminator and the last of the
generator.
So now it's going to take a while it's actually going to take several hours on my computer.
I'm going to let my computer do all this work for me.
We're not going to watch the whole training.
And at the end of the training I'll see you back and we will see the fake images generated by our decisions
and we'll see if it looks like something.
So let's let this run and I'll see you at the end of the training.
All right the training is over.
It actually took more time than I thought.
When I woke up after a long night of sleep well it was still not over.
So I guess it took more than eight hours in my computer.
Indeed I don't sleep any more three hours per day.
I noticed it was bad for life expectancy and I still want to be able to make some courses for your children
and grandchildren.
But as long as we have the final results that's all good.
So I'm going to show them to you now and we'll see if we can call our deep convolutional dance.
A great artist.
All right.
So before I show you the first samples I would like to show you the real samples just to see on which
images real images are a computer vision model learned to generate some fake images.
So these are the images.
All good.
Now let's see what it was capable of creating.
All right so let's start with the first samples.
Nothing special here.
We cannot call it art at all.
But then what about the second one.
The second one is already better the second one looks more like something but still it still looks like
some kind of smoke except for this one maybe that looks like a mountain but I think we'll get better
than that.
Then some pools.
Number two.
So the numbers here correspond to the box that was given at about 0 1 2 3 until about 24 25.
Back in Seoul.
And this one this one is actually pretty good.
We start to see something here.
We still need a bit of imagination to figure out what's inside the image here.
I see him for example to see some kind of a duck on a on the sea or the ocean.
I don't know if you see the same thing.
Well maybe my imagination is playing some tricks but I can start to see something here.
Let's look at the third fake samples.
So the fake images of the third book are right definitely better here.
Here we can see a human.
I guess it's a human here.
I think I see a squirrel.
I don't know if you agree.
OK.
Much better.
Let's look at the other ones much better here as well.
All right.
Let's look at number six.
Much better here.
We can see it better and better each time.
I don't know if you agree but to me the fake images really start to look like some real images even
if it's not perfectly net.
It's still a little bit blurry.
But still we can see some objects here.
All right.
Let's look at number 10 for example to see if it's already much better.
Yes it looks pretty good.
Let's have a look at number 15.
Still very good so perhaps you didn't need that many a book perhaps you could try to do the training
with five or up to 10 bucks.
But definitely after a certain number of book we see some great results.
And here it's even more visible than before even more clear.
And these are pretty cool images.
We can see some nice colors now.
So I would.
They're calling this model an artist maybe not Picasso but definitely a better artist than me.
So that's pretty cool.
And that's actually the end of this Mudgal congratulations for having implemented the deep convolutional
Ganns.
That was definitely not good stuff.
You coded almost 150 lines of code so well done.
Awesome job.
You not only implemented the deep convolutional Ganns But also you smashed the three modules of this
course.
Well keep in mind you implemented some cutting edge models.
I remind that SSD is the state of the art moral and object detection.
It beats the faster our CNN and you know.
So at the time I'm speaking and I hope this course will last but at the time I'm speaking you did implement
a state of the art model in computer vision and deep learning.
So really really really you can be proud of yourself.
Keep up that great work and great passion for the coming courses and some more modules.
This adventure is definitely not over.
We will learn so much more.
We are dedicated instructors really happy to share our knowledge so there will be more.
And until then enjoy machine learning.
Enjoy the journey enjoy.
I mostly enjoy computer vision.