Hello and welcome to this new tutorial today we're going to start with the big first step of the implementation
of our deep convolutional Ganns that consists of defining the generator.
That's the big first step.
And the second big step will be to define the discriminator then we'll have our brains and then we will
train these brains to generate fake images.
But today we're going to start with this big first step.
Defining the generator and we'll do it in two steps steps first we will make the class that will define
the architecture of the neural network of the generator.
So we will put in a sequence to different modules that is the different layers of the neural network
then we'll make the forward function to propagate the signal inside and will that work.
And then once this class is done we'll be able to create the generator itself that is the neural network
of the generator by simply creating an object of the class an instance of the class.
So let's do this let's make this class.
So to define a class in Python We start with class and then we give the name of the class which is going
to be G for regenerator and then we'll call the class for the discriminator D.
And now we're going to use a trick an object oriented programming language which is inheritance.
We are going to inherit from in that module which contains all the tools that allow us to build a neural
network and it's called an end or modules because the modules are the different applications and connections
you can make inside a neural network.
For example one module can be a convolution.
Another module can be a full connection.
Therefore the name and to apply the inheritance there is nothing more simple we just need to put as
argument of this class G.
The module we want to inherit from which is and that module.
There we go this one.
And in that module so that introduces a new class.
And now inside this new class we have to define the whole architecture.
And besides we'll include the forward function to be able to afford propagate a signal.
That's the advantage of making a class A class is an advance structure inside of which you can include
some properties of the future instances of the class that will be created.
That is the future object.
And also some different functions that will be like some tools of your object.
Quick and the best example for those of you who are seeing your class for the first time.
Well we could define a self-driving car with a class in one class we could include all the properties
of the Sandrine car and then different functions for example to move forward function to turn the function
to turn right function the stop function.
All these functions that would allow to control the self-driving car.
Well here that's exactly the same we're making in class to not only define the architecture of the neural
network of the generator but also we'll add the forward function which is like a tool that we can apply
on the neural network.
And this tool will be used to propagate the signal inside the neural network.
So let's do this let's first start by defining the architecture of the neural network.
And as for every neural network that we make with a class we do this inside that in its function the
innate function is the function you always start with a class.
It is the function that defines the properties of the future objects that will be created from your
class.
And speaking of this object that's exactly the argument that we have to employ right now.
And this is called self self has been a mystery for a lot of people but there is absolutely no mystery
about it.
It just refers to the future object that will be created.
It's just a common way to specify that when we create a variable we use the self to specify that this
variable belongs to the object.
So each time I put self.
That means I am referring to the object.
That means I'm taking the object and setting some properties to it.
So self.
And now we are arguing to activate the inheritance because we import the n and module to inherit from
it.
But now we have to activate this inheritance and to do this we use the super function inside of which
we input our Class G which is inheriting from the end in that module right here.
And then the second argument is self because we will use the tools of that module on our object because
our object is nothing else than the new one that work at the generator and the neural network and the
generator will be composed of the different modules.
And in that module the conclusions the full connections and more.
All right and then that's not over we just need to add a that and underscore underscore in it double
underscore again and parenthesis.
All right.
Nothing more important to know about this.
That's just what we have to type here to activate the inheritance of the end and that much our next
step.
Now the next step is to make a meta module what is a metal module.
That's a huge module that will be composed of several modules.
I remind that by module I mean the different layers the different connections inside the neural network.
So now we'll create a big metal module which will be a sequence of several modules some convolutions
full connections inversed convolutions and more integrate this metal module.
Well we're going to take our object because this metal module is going to be a property of the object
and therefore I'm taking my object and this metal module of the object will be called Maine.
Main will be the metal module that will contain all the different modules in a sequence of layers.
And speaking of sequence of layers.
That's exactly what we'll introduce right now with the N-N that sequence show class inside of which
will create the different modules.
All right.
So you probably recognize that sequential is actually a class so self that main is actually a new object
of the sequential class but of course this object represents this method module composed of the different
modules.
All right so now we're starting to define the architecture of the neural network and let's start with
the first module.
According to you according to the intuition lectures you saw with curial what is going to be this first
module.
Well of course that's going to be a non-first convolution not a convolution.
And in verse 1 that is exactly the inverse of a convolution.
And why do we have to start with an inverse convolution.
Well that's because the role of the generator is to generate some fake images.
And therefore since CNN takes as input some images and returns as output a vector.
Well and then CNN will do exactly the opposite.
It will take as inputs a vector we will create that vector we'll call it noise later on in the training
that will be the input of this inverse CNN and it will return a fake image.
So you're going to see that the input of this inverse CNN that we're about to make will be a random
vector of size 100.
And to get the inverse of a convolution in PI torch we're going to use the can transpose to the class
that is that this inverse convolution module that we're going to create will be an object of the current
transpose to the class.
So let's do it.
We take our end in that module because this can transpose to the class is taken from the end module
so end then dot com capitals C transpose to the.
Here is this one.
That's the inverse convolution.
The first module of our big Maira module that is the first module of our neural network can be transposed
to D.
And now we need to input several arguments.
Get ready for them as you can see.
There are many of them.
All right.
So the first argument is 100.
That's the size of the input 100 meaning that the inputs are inverse CNN will be a vector of size 100.
Then the second argument is 512.
And that's the number of feature maps of the output.
Then the third argument is four.
And that's the size of the kernel which means that the kernels will be squares of size four by four
then the next argument is one.
And that's the stride and the last argument is zero and that's the padding.
By the way the architecture that I'm about to define right now I didn't invent it.
It is coming from a lot of experimenting that was done by researchers and the machine learning and AI
contributors.
So I did not invent it.
I just took an architecture that is open source and that turns out to work very well for adversarial
networks.
So don't worry about the choice of the numbers.
They just come from experimentation.
All right and then we have one last argument and I'm specifying it because it is actually about the
bias which by default is equal to true.
But I'm going to set it equal to false because we don't want any bias.
It works better this way.
And therefore I'm saying the bias here to false.
So one hundred for the size of the input 512 feature maps and the output meaning the output of the inverse
convolution not the final output.
Then a kernel of size for four by four is stride of 1 a batting of zero and no buyers.
That's the first Mudgal of our neural network.
Congratulations.
You just applied an inversed convolution all right and now we are going to normalize all the features
along the dimension of the Bachche the diamonds and of the batch is 512.
We have 512 feature maps and we're going to Bachan on each of these 512 feature maps and to do this
we take again our and then Mudgal and then we apply the batch we should find in here.
Here we go Bachan on 2D and as arguments we need to input the number of feature maps we want to bet
on.
And since the 512 feature maps Well we are going to bet on 512 feature maps.
All right.
So playing batched normalization is pretty simple.
Then we are going to apply Ereli to rectification for the non-linearity of the neural network that is
to break the linearity and to do this.
Nothing more simple things to our end and module we take are in a module that and we apply the review
rectifier activation function and as arguments we just need to input just like that.
That applies really to rectification then we are going to apply another inverse convolution.
So I'm simply going to take my end and can transpose to the module.
Pasting it here.
And then here we go with the series of arguments.
So this time we don't have 100 for the size of input because the input is now the output of the previous
module which was an inverse convolution but in the output we got 512 feature maps and these feature
maps become the new input of our new inversed conclusion.
So this time we don't input 100 year when put 512.
That's the number of inputs of this new inverse convolution.
Then we need to choose a new number feature maps in the output of this new inverse convolution.
And this time we're not going to pick five phonons well.
We're going to pick two hundred and fifty six.
Again that's a choice motivated by experimentation.
That's really not his job to figure out such an architecture.
All right then we're going to choose a kernel size of four four by four then as I tried to this time
and padding of one and then same we don't want any buyers and therefore adding Byars equals false perfect.
That's our next module.
We now have two inversed convolution.
Our generator is getting into shape.
So now we're going to do the same we're going to batched norm each of the new 256 feature maps.
So I'm just going to take this and that batch Enorme 2D it here but then replace 512 by 256 because
we're batch norming each of the new 256 feature maps and then we apply another rectification which is
going to be the loop again.
So here let's just copy this and paste it here.
All right then guess what we're going to do again.
We're going to apply another inverse convolution.
So I am taking this.
And then that can transpose to D.
I am pasting it here.
And then the input is actually the output of the previous operation that is the inverse convolution.
So that's 256 the 256 outputs feature maps become the input of our new inversed convolution.
So 256.
And now guess what we want in the outputs.
Well you probably understood the logic we wanted divided by two.
So we're going to take one hundred and twenty eight output future maps.
In this new inverse convolution and then the good news is that we're keeping a size four by four for
the kernels.
Let's try to add a padding of one and then no bias.
Congratulations.
You just applied your third inverse convolution.
And so then that's the same we're going to apply a batch known to the two batched norm.
Each of the new 128 feature maps.
So here I am replacing tournament 56 by 128 and we are going to apply reglue rectification to make sure
we break the linearity for the non-linearity of the neural network.
All right.
And then guess what we're going to do again.
We are going to apply an inversed convolution again.
So I'm taking this again I'm taking the cones transpose to 2D and I'm pasting in here and this time
we have as input of this new inverse convolution.
One hundred and twenty eight feature maps because that was the output of the previous inverse convolution.
And this time guess what we want for the number of the output feature maps of this new inverse convolution.
Well of course we want 64 new feature maps and then good news again we're keeping a size of four by
four for the Colonel's a stride of two and a betting of one.
And then nobody has a right.
We're getting close to the end.
We need again to apply a batch norm.
So let's copy this again.
We are going to batched norm each of the new 64 feature maps that are the output of our new inverse
convolution.
And then we are going to apply a really rectification to again break the linearity.
Right there we go almost over.
Don't get crazy too fast.
We have one final inverse convolution to make.
So that's exactly what we're going to do.
We are going to apply our last module the inverse convolution and I'm just copying the name of the module
because this time we are going to input different arguments.
So the first argument is the number of inputs which is the output of the previous inverse convolution.
So that's 64 again.
And then for the output That's important since we're making the generator that is supposed to generate
some fake images.
And since these fake images are going to be with three channels while the output of the generator is
exactly going to be the three channels of the fake images and therefore the number of dimensions for
the output is going to be three corresponding to the three channels.
All right.
And then actually that's the same.
We're going to use kernels of size four by four a stride of two the padding of one.
And again no bias.
So I can just copy this and paste it here and there we go.
We have applied all our inversed convolution that's almost over.
We just need to end this up with a hyperbolic tangent rectification to not only break the law in the
area again but also to make sure we are between minus 1 and plus 1.
Have a look at the age function you'll see that the values are between minus 1 and plus 1.
And also it is centered around 0.
And why do we want to output values to fall between minus 1 and plus 1 and being centered around 0.
That's because we want the same standards as the images of the data set.
And because the created images of the generator will become the input of the discriminator that will
come after that.
All right so now we just need to and this architecture with our n module again and then that we apply
the term age to hyperbolic tangent rectification for the non-linearity of the neural network and to
be between minus 1 and plus 1 centered around zero.
Whew.
Congratulations.
You made a neural network.
That was definitely not a piece of cake.
So I guess now it would be nice to have a break in the next story will make the food function that will
propagate the signal that is the input of the generator through all the different layers of this new
will that work.
So have a good break and I'll see you in the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy the revision.