Hello and welcome to the practical applications of this course I'm super excited to start with you and
I'm going to start with some good news right now and this Statoil we are going to install everything
so that at no time you have any installation issue.
We will install all the packages all the libraries anything that we will use to execute the codes and
execute the models.
So basically this is just the installation tutorial.
And then it will only be about coding and executing.
So this is a new feature we're very excited and proud to give to you.
I'm talking about the virtual platform this virtual platform is the combination of a platform that will
be hosted on the yes Web site.
It is right now in development and a virtual environment that will contain all these packages.
You will need to execute the codes in the models.
So right now and this Statoil what we're going to do is we are going to install an icon that because
we will connect this virtual platform environment to Anaconda.
And then in a flash light we will be ready to start and execute the models.
So let's do this let's start by downloading Anaconda and then we will install the virtual platform and
then we'll be good to go.
So right now I'm on Google and the first thing I want to do is to go to the Anaconda Web site.
There we go.
And I can digest that and I can then Google you go to the first link and I can get loud and then you
go to download and I can there right here.
We go.
And then you choose your system.
So when those macros are Linux I'm on Mac OS so I'm going to download Python 3.6 version.
You must absolutely download Python 3.6 because it will not work on Python 2.7.
So that's important.
And then once you're ready you click on this download button and the download will just start.
Right now it's just starting.
And one minute left.
Perfect.
We will have the ANAC on that platform in one minute.
So that's for a teacher to get a teacher.
But you can click on those things that's very important.
We won't be needing this.
So so far what can I tell you.
Well and I can There is a platform that contains several ideas.
We will be using one of these ideas which will be spider because it's like a studio you have a viable
window where you get to see all the variables you create your file explorer.
It contains some interactive and dynamic eye bison console so very efficient to execute the code.
This is definitely the one we want.
Everything will work like a wonder.
So here we go download is done.
So what I'm going to do now I'm going to go to my download folder where I can find a neck on the package
folder that I just downloaded.
So let's double click on it then we will get the installation steps so it can continue continue continue
agree and still for me only That's fine.
Continue and install arise and right now it's installing it will just take a couple of seconds and it
should be ready very soon.
All right.
Almost done writing package receipts is perfect.
It's just installing and I can there with all the pages are going to do that.
But we will be installing more packages.
Thanks to the virtual platform.
Here we go.
That's done.
Now we're going to click on close and you can choose to keep it.
That's fine.
Just to keep the download file.
OK.
So now Anaconda is installed but we're not going to open it yet because we'll be installing the virtual
platform.
So now stay with me and let's do this.
It's going to be very efficient.
We will just executes one line of code in the terminal.
Or for those of you who are on Windows in the second prompt.
So first of all let's go to the computer vision is that folder that you downloaded in the previous To
toil and let's go inside and let's go inside the installations subfolder this installation subfolder
contains three way e-mail found one for Linux one for Mac and one for Windows.
You don't have to do anything with those.
Why not file you can open them if you want but please don't nullify anything.
These are just why a mail file that contains all the dependencies packages libraries that are going
to be needed for the morals that will be executed in the course but you don't have to open them.
What's We're going to do now is open a terminal or the Anaconda prompt.
So for those of you who are on Mac or Linux you just need to open a terminal.
I am on Mac so I just type command space and then terminal here.
Answer.
That's the terminal I suppose know how to open a terminal on Linux you can find it very easily at the
left of your screen.
And now for those of you who are on Windows what you need to do is to go to the lower left corner of
your screen click on the windows button then find in the list of programs Anaconda's 3.
You go inside and then you will find an icon that prompt you open the prompt and then you will get a
black rectangle like this a black screen.
And now we are on the same page.
We just need to type something that will install everything and then we'll be good to go.
OK so now you guys on Mac and Linux have your terminal opened and you guys on Windows have your and
can that prompt open.
And then we're going to type a command line to install everything.
But first we need to be in the folder that contains the Y MFL.
So we have two choices now.
Either you find this folder which is the installation folder through the terminal you know by typing
CD then desktop because the computer vision it is that folder is on my desktop and then computer vision
it is that then instillations that we go and then you press enter but maybe that's not the best way.
If your computer vision is full there is somewhere hidden in your system.
So in that case what you can do also is just take the way a male that corresponds to your system.
So for example my way email is Mac so I'm copying this I'm putting it in my main folder which is an
law here I can paste that here.
All right.
And now since my terminal is in the right folder along which contains my way e-mail Well I'm ready to
type the command to execute the code.
So as you want it's whether you are comfortable not with navigating inside your system that's the two
possibilities.
The only thing that matters right now is that your terminal or Anaconda prompt is connected to a folder.
And the way a mail file corresponding to your system must be in that folder.
So if that's the case what you only need to do is type Konda
create then minus f then virtual platform.
And then if you are a Mac you type Mac.
If you are on Windows you type windows and if you are on Linux you type Linux.
I am on Mac so I have Mac and then don't forget the dot.
Why.
Well that's all you press enter and this will install everything.
And at no time will you ever have to install anything else.
So let's press enter and let's see the magic.
There we go using an icon that API fetching package.
Metzer that's out and it's going to install everything now and this shouldn't take a while.
This should take like one minute to two.
Let's see something back package specifications and there we go.
Isn't it beautiful.
Everything is being installed.
And we won't have to bother about this after that.
So that's pre-reg saying that's a new feature.
That's the virtual platform behind the scene.
You know we're installing a virtual environment.
But of course then you will have the virtual platform the graphic virtual platform on the LDS web site
which is still in development.
So beautiful it's going to take maybe one more minute.
So let's see.
So as you can see it's installing some packages like f f MPEG because we'll be working on some videos.
It's installing pipe and 3.5 3.6 because by then 3.6 have some issues with by.
It's installing by George of course because it is the most powerful to implement neural networks.
It's installing open C.V it's installing side by it's installing.
Well everything we need and even some more stuff that like you know very useful bits that we won't be
using it but it's because of the dependencies.
You know when you and someone package you have to install some different packages.
So but anything you'll have everything you need.
OK.
So I think that was the last one to install.
And now you just need to wait a few more seconds and we will be ready to start very soon.
I'm so excited and so excited because then I will show you right now the folder that contains all the
models and we will test the virtual platform to make sure that it works we will test it with the first
model.
So let's see let's see what's going to happen.
All right.
Yet that looks like it's the end.
It's going to be the end in a matter of seconds.
And there we go.
Yes.
Perfect.
So no error.
Everything is fine.
It tells you some stuff like to activate this environment use source activate virtual platform.
Don't worry about that you won't have anything to do about that.
I will show you what to do right now.
It's so easy.
So let's do this.
You can close your terminal or Anaconda prompt now.
And now what we're going to do is open Anaconda.
So for those of you who are on Windows you can find it by clicking on the windows button at the lower
left corner and then find an icon that 3 but you have to find an eye can the Navigator.
And here on Mac I'm going to type Anaconda navigator like this.
It's in my apps.
And there we go.
And I can that is about open initialising.
And here is Anaconda and now the only thing that we have to do to connect to the virtual platform.
There is nothing more easy.
You get two applications on then you click on this little arrow.
And here we go.
Here is the virtual platform you click on the virtual platform.
It's loading.
And now we are connected to the virtual platform inside Anaconda.
That's beautiful.
So now the only thing that you have to do left is just click on launch you know that's the idea we're
using spider.
You click on knowledge and you'll be inside of a beautiful studio which will use to execute the models.
There we go.
So I'm going to quickly present Spider.
This is the area where you have your code.
This is the bison console.
Make sure that you have the item console and not the button console.
Here you have three windows Falak 4 or you have all your files your folders.
So we will find the computer vision areas that folder will explore where you have all the variables
you create and help if you need some help sometimes you will get the help to get some informations of
the object's classes we're going to use.
But the first thing we're going to do is we're going to go to explore and find the computer vision it
is that folder.
So as you saw it is in my desktop there it is computer vision is that.
And now we're going to test the virtual platform to make sure that it works.
So I'm going to click on computer vision it is.
Let's test for example module one face recognition.
So in each of the folder modules you will have to code the commented version of the code and the code
without comment.
So the command version of the code is the name of the module face recognition and this quirk invented
and the no commented version of the code is face recognition and is going to comment.
You can find the same for the other module to object detection object detection commented object detection
of Cummins and for Gannes DC again come into DC again no comment.
This again means deep convolutional again.
And then you have some other foules which are some other bytes and files or XML files or some folders
that contain some tools that are required for the models.
So for example here for face recognition the tools are two Cascades one cascade for the eye and one
cascade for the face.
These are ex-MIL files and theres just to be able to detect the eyes and the face with open city but
the code the heart of the code is one of these vowels.
So you have to come into the version of the code and we together are going to retype the code line by
line so that you can understand what's going on.
But for example I did a double clicking on face recognition commented and we're going to test it out
right now.
So as you can see each line of code is commented that's the same for the other code and to test it we
simply need to select the whole code by pressing command or control a and then to execute.
We simply press command or control enter and there we go.
Is it working.
Yes it is I'm going to show that to you right now.
Here it is.
That's the result of Module 1.
So hi guys welcome.
Welcome to my place.
This is actually where I'm recording all the tutorials.
So this is face recognition as you can see we detect very well my face in blue and my eyes in green.
So that's one of the models we implement and of course that's a very classic example.
But don't worry the more you will progress and of course the more you will get some very very powerful
models especially the one for object detection and the one from module 3.
And also this virtual platform will be updated through time we'll add some new stuff some new models.
So make sure to keep in touch with it.
All right so I'm going to press on cute to exit this.
There we go so that works very well.
We don't have to test it for the others.
I actually tested it 10 times to make sure that it works.
I tested it on Linux Windows and Mac.
So you should not have any problem.
All right.
So I hope it's clear.
I hope you manage to get to where I am right now.
Is it getting this code if it's not the case.
You can ask some questions in the Q&amp;A.
We will assist you.
There is a great support team that will be very happy to help you.
All right so I can't wait to start coding all this.
And until then enjoy computer vision.