Hello and welcome to this new editorial in the British this editorials we described the challenge that
we have.
We have to detect a funny dog on a two seconds video and we will do it through a computer vision based
on deep learning neural networks.
So we already found the right folder now.
This quick to toile I'm going to explain the libraries that we're going to use.
They're already all installed I already prepared the code that will import them.
So there is nothing to do but I think it's important that you understand what we will be using them
for.
So let's start with the first one as you can see the first library when port is torche that's of course
the torch library that contains PI torch which is definitely by far our best weapon to build a new one
that work and do some computer vision and that's for a specific reason it's because by torch content
the dynamic graphs things to which we are able to compute very efficiently the gradients of composition
functions in backward propagation.
You know when we have to update day to wait through stochastic gradient descent Well we have to compute
the gradient of some composition functions because we have several layers.
You know it's a deep neural network so we have several layers.
And therefore it's like one has some functions of the PRI's layer which has some functions of the previous
previous layer so that generates some composition functions.
We have to compute the gradient of these composition functions to have data weights according to how
much they are responsible for the error between the target and the predictions.
So that's where it plays.
And the dynamic graphs is a highly advanced graph structure that allows to have some very fast and efficient
computation of the gradients.
So that's why torture is our first choice then from torche undergrad which is the module responsible
for graden descent.
We are importing the variable class which will be used to convert the tensors into some torche variables
that will contain both the tensor and a gradient.
And then the storage variable containing the tensor in the gradients will be one element of the graph.
Then of course we import CB2 and that even if we're not going to implement a model based on open Hargus
gate we're just importing CB2 because we will be drawing some rectangles around the deck.
But the detection of the dog will not be based on open city Harker's Cate's.
They will be based on as is the neural network that is single shot multa box detection so opens we just
to draw the rectangles then hear from Data Import base transform the classes as label map data is just
a folder that contains the classes based transform and classes then base transform is a class that will
do the required transformations so that the image the input images will be compatible with the neural
network.
You know when we feed the neural network with the input images they have to have a certain format and
base transform will be used to transform the images in this format so that they can be accepted into
the network.
And then what Les's.
Well look Les's is just a dictionary that will do the encoding of the classes.
So for example planes will be encoded as one Dug's will be included as to is just an example it's not
exactly just mapping but that's the idea.
We'll do a mapping because of course we want to work with numbers and not text.
So that's just a very simple dictionary doing the mapping between the text fields of the classes and
some integers.
All right then from the import build SSD.
So first SSD is the library of the single shot multi-book action model and then build as that we import
from the SSD library will be the constructor of the SSD neural network.
And so if you want to have a look you can have a look in this as is digitized and fell to see how it
works.
But it is just a constructor that will build the architecture of this single shot not box detection
model.
And finally image I know is just the library that we'll use to process the images of the video and applying
the detect function that will implement on the images.
So at first we wanted to import pill P L which is another library but image I O actually turns out to
be a much better choice in terms of lines of code.
You'll see we will only have to type two or three lines of code to be able to process the images of
the video.
That is funny Doug and before and apply to detect function that will implement to detect the dog and
the humans on the video.
All right.
So I hope you have now a clear understanding of the libraries that will be used.
It's important to know how they work.
And now with you're going to do is define the detect function that will do the detections.
So let's take a fresh start in the next tutorial.
And so until then enjoy computer vision.