Hey guys, welcome to the obligatory
course overview lecture.
Let's talk real briefly about what
we're going to cover in this course.
All right, in section one, we're going to
go way back in time to finally
understand the thing you've been trying
so hard to ignore - your computer.
We'll learn about machine code,
why The Matrix predicted
everything we experience today,
why your mom can't figure out
how to use Windows, let alone that
penguin thing, Red Hat Linux,
and how two thieves with oversized glasses
changed computers forever.
In section two, we're going to cover
how the internet works,
why Al Gore invented it, and how is it that
browsers and websites actually work.
Section three, we're off to understand how
tech stacks resemble sandwiches,
what front-end and back-end programming
entails, and lastly,
what are the most common languages
people learn, besides French.
Section four, I'm going to ever so gently
hold your hand and
start to dip our toes into the
basic concepts of programming.
Section five, we're going to explain
the ever-increasingly important
concept of the API, and then we're going to
tackle the great trio of confusion:
frameworks, libraries, and integrated
development environments.
Section six, we're going to tackle
content management systems,
how WordPress is the lord of the internet,
and the reason why
Shopify, SquareSpace, and Weebly
are why we can't have nice things.
Section seven, we're going to cover
advanced concepts worth knowing,
like object oriented programming,
model view controller paradigms,
continuous integration, GIT commits,
and a whole bunch of other
things that will make you feel really smart
...or really stupid.
Section eight, we're going to talk
about all the tech trends
and what's happening nowadays with
the cool kids: responsive design,
platform as a service technology like
PARS, full stack JavaScript,
hybrid apps, SWIFT, and drugs.
Section nine, we're going to wrap up
by going to talk about,
for those of you who want to learn how to program,
how do you pick what to learn,
where do you go to start.
And for those of you who do not
want to learn how to program
and instead want to hire programmers,
we'll also cover where you can
go to spam the people we were just
previously talking about.
All right, guys, I hope that gets you excited,
and if it doesn't, well...
this is awkward, because we're moving
on to the next lecture.
See you then!