Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
This lecture, we're going to talk about one of the bigger trends
that will last 2-3 years, which is called full stack JavaScript.
Now, you remember what we said about JavaScript before,
JavaScript, up until this point, has been pretty squarely
a technology that works on your browser, and not on your server.
Remember, JavaScript, interaction.
Button clicking, form submitting, motions, animations, those kind of things
are what we always think of when we think of JavaScript.
Now, that all changed recently with the advent of what's called Node.js.
Now, Node.js is not a library, it's not even a framework, it's a system
that allows you to create an environment on your browser and then test your JavaScript.
For some reason, and I'm not technical enough to give you this answer,
and I don't even think you need to know this, but
that innovation has allowed people to use JavaScript both on the front-end,
on the browser, to deal with elements on the page,
and also on the back-end, to do the traditional
job you'd see back-end languages doing,
like querying databases, or making calculations, or pulling information from APIs.
The reason why Node has been able to be
created is because Google recently came out
with what they called the V8 JavaScript engine,
and it at first ran exclusively on Google Chrome,
so at first, you could only do this on Google
Chrome, and now it's on the other browsers.
Now, you might not be technical enough to appreciate this,
but this is a very big change in programming, and if it's a trend that sticks,
it's going to turn everything pretty much upside down.
The reason why I say that is, well,
so many people have spent so long learning back-end languages,
learning how to do everything using traditional
languages, like Python, and PHP, and Ruby,
and if it's such the case that company start using full stack JavaScript,
just using JavaScript on the front and the back,
well, then, essentially, a lot of people are going to have obsolete skills.
Now, the obvious advantage to using full stack JavaScript
is that you only have to know one language,
so if you're someone who learned the front-end,
you don't have to learn a new language
to now learn how to do basic back-end functions, and have a full control of your app.
Now, something that's worth knowing is that
this new type of JavaScript is called asynchronous JavaScript.
What that means is that when a browser reads that index file,
the first page it sees on a website, or a web app,
it reads it from top to bottom, it executes the code at the top,
then it goes to the middle, then it goes all the way to the bottom.
With JavaScript, you originally could insert actions and interactions that could run,
check something, and then change the code further down the page,
so it can actually interact with you as you're using
it without having to refresh the page.
Asynchronous JavaScript is kind of a step even past that,
and it's through a thing called multi-threading, which basically means that
when the browser tries to run that code, the JavaScript actually will be running
several things simultaneously as it goes through,
so you could be pulling information from the back-end,
checking basic validation on the front-end,
and kind of completing the whole package all in one page.
Now, from a practical standpoint, what do you need to know about full stack JavaScript?
Now, I obviously take it from the web development business angle,
which is that if you're trying to work in a web development firm,
or you're someone who's making a decision about should we use traditional methods
of application development, or this new thing called full stack JavaScript,
I tend to focus on the efficiency.
Full stack JavaScript has a lot of potential, but as it currently stands,
it's actually still underdeveloped, it's made leaps and bounds,
but, for instance, full stack JavaScript doesn't work very well with databases.
If you use information that you need to save
and pull all the time, it's actually really inefficient.
Also, in general, my experience with it is that it will take someone longer
to do something in full stack JavaScript than if they just did it
in regular JavaScript plus an actual back-end language.
The great things about this new JavaScript abilities is that you can see
cooler and cooler things, especially with full stack JavaScript.
What ends up happening is now we can make pages reload significantly faster.
It almost kind of has the feeling as if it's instant.
So that's really what you need to know.
It can make some really cool effects on your page, it could potentially up-end
a lot of people who know traditional programming,
but at the same time it's still not efficient enough,
and because of that reason, it hasn't yet become the mainstream,
but don't hold your breath, it could actually change everything.
And that's what we mean when we say that JavaScript is eating everything.
All right guys, see you in the next lecture!