Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, so let's get into a subject
that everybody thinks they know,
but in reality very few people actually know.
What subject is that, you ask?
Well, it's how does the internet actually work?
And no, "Open Google Chrome" is not how the internet works.
But before we actually jump into that, one quick note.
Why do you need to know this
as a developer or as someone who
plans to interact with developers?
Well, it's actually quite simple.
The internet is not perfect, and it breaks.
And when something goes wrong,
are you going to know how to fix it?
When your website goes down, say,
because the DNS is not done propagating,
what are you going to do if you
don't even know what the DNS is?
Also, worth noting is that understanding
the basics of how the internet works
is actually very helpful for understanding
online industries in general and
understanding the broader trends
that affect our lives every single day.
You don't know what net neutrality is?
Well, yeah, you kind of have to understand
the basics of how the internet works first.
Anyways, let's start with a little history lesson.
Do you know who invented the internet?
No, it wasn't Al Gore and I don't even
know how that rumor got started.
The most official and credible sources of
information point to a research project
created by the group called DARPA, D-A-R-P-A,
which stands for Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency.
Creepy and vague, they are responsible
for a lot of things you hear about today
that make you go "What? Really".
Yes, besides making mind controlled limbs
- I can actually thank them for that one
- robot exoskeletons, submarines that can fly,
and creepy robots that can walk
and kind of balance like humans, they also
made the first version of the internet.
Needless to say, interesting group of people.
Sometime in the 1960s, DARPA created
a well-known project called ARPANET,
which, I know, is not very original and also
really hard to pronounce, ARPANET.
The idea was to connect one computer
to another through vast distances of space.
So in 1969 they managed to do this
by setting up the first computer in UCLA,
and the second one in Stanford.
With these two attached, they sent
the world's first computer message,
and I'm not actually making this up,
the first message was just two letters: L - O.
Was that some mystery code sent by a secret agent?
No, actually it was just a clueless Stanford
student who didn't know what they were doing,
and accidentally crashed the machine
while trying to type "LOGIN".
#inspiration
Over the next decades and with the coming of
smaller, non-room sized computers,
DARPA needed to create a more efficient way
for computers to communicate with each other.
This system, and it's something you're undoubtedly
going to see mentioned somewhere,
was the Transfer Control Protocol and the
Internet Protocol, abbreviated as TCP/IP.
Ok, you really don't need to know
the specifics of this unless you get into
actual hardware and IT, but just know that TCP/IP
is the protocol that computers use
to transfer information to and
from servers and other computers.
TCP is just a system for breaking up
data into "packets", which are basically
small batched chunks of information optimized for transfer,
and IP is a series of numbers that tells
that information where are you going.
You smarties out there might notice that
IP sounds a whole lot like IP address,
which we'll talk about in second.
Up until the 1980s, it's worth knowing that
the Internet was really only used for
transferring research between research institutions.
Now, this might blow your mind,
or you might not just care at all,
but the World Wide Web, which stands for WWW,
is actually not the same thing as the internet.
You know that WWW you put before
every website you want to go to?
That stands for World Wide Web.
Let me explain.
So let's just step back just a second.
The word "internet" that we've been talking
about is actually just a variation
of the original word, which is intranet.
An intranet is just a connection of machines that are all "local"
and connected either directly to each other
or directly to a hub and then to each other.
If you've ever heard of the term LAN, spelled L-A-N,
that's exactly what LAN is - it stands for Local Access Network.
If you ever played video games
you might have heard someone say
"Me and my super cool friends are going to
drink Mountain Dew and have a LAN party".
I can make fun of it because that was
actually me for several years of my life.
So if a LAN is connected to another LAN
- that's to say one group of connected devices
is then connected to another group of connected devices,
through an intermediary linking them - well, that
right there is technically called an internet.
Why exactly is that different?
I don't know and I suggest you
don't think about it too hard.
It has mostly to do with distances and
connecting hubs of computers to each other.
Ok, that's a roundabout explanation to get back to
why World Wide Web is something entirely different.
Well, see, the thing with the internet is that
in order for computers to transfer information
from each other to each other, they need
to have the same hardware and software.
Just like how I can't send a WhatsApp message
through Facebook Messenger,
you back in the day couldn't send your
LO message to another computer
if it wasn't built or capable of receiving
that specific type of information.
The World Wide Web, on the other hand, was
something developed to skip over that problem.
It created a unified system whereby all
computers, regardless of technology,
could access and transfer the same information.
The Internet, as you might have heard
me joke, is just a series of tubes.
* It's a series of tubes *
Well, not literally, but it is a series of
dumb boxes and wires connecting them.
The World Wide Web, or what you would just call the "web"
is built on top of that and acts as a standardization
system for sending and processing information.
One of the ways that it does this is through HTTP protocol,
which essentially acts as a language for coding information
in that every computer on the planet can understand.
Ok, so when you go to Domino's to
order a pizza, you type in what?
http://www.dominospizza.com
By typing in that HTTP, we are just telling
the computer how to communicate.
Nowadays it's kind of redundant,
we don't even know why we do it.
HTTP specifies the protocol with which
to transfer this specific information,
and WWW tells your computer where to start looking.
Guess what? We are halfway through the browser bar,
so celebrate with your new found knowledge
and I'll see you in the next lecture.