All right guys, welcome back to the course.
Let's tackle the next language on our list
and get the run down on what it is,
what's different, and what do we need to know about it.
This one is called PHP.
PHP is one of the oldies but still one of the goodies.
PHP stands for, and stay with me on this one,
it's PHP Hypertext Preprocessor.
Yes, the acronym PHP includes its own acronym in its acronym.
This is, and I'm not even making this up, an inside joke
amongst the original people that developed the language.
I can imagine that after the 15th Red Bull and the 14th hour
of staring at a screen of code, that was a pretty funny joke.
Also, pro tip, if you want to impress
your developer, use the word "recursive,"
which actually describes the way something is self-referential,
like a name encapsulating its own name within itself.
You're welcome for that one.
PHP is one of the most well-known back-end languages for the web
and it has had a sizeable community for
significantly longer than other languages.
PHP, for the most part, is considered easy
to learn, but because of its age,
it's inherited a handful of inefficiencies
that can make it rather tedious.
Remember, in the last lecture, when I showed you the example of
Python code versus a mysterious other code?
Well, it wasn't really mysterious, because I told you what it was.
Remember, that was PHP. It's got curly
brackets, and tons of goofy rules.
So, what do we need to know about this language?
Well, there are, I'd say, something like three things
you'd have to know about this language
if you had a meeting with your CTO in the
next 15 minutes on building a new product.
Number one is that PHP is for the most part open source.
Remember, open source means free and available for anyone.
That means that this is not a commercialized language,
rather it's supported and developed by a group
of enthusiasts that prefer to not monetize it.
Anyone can use it and anyone can get set up with it very quickly.
That means that, generally speaking, using this language is cheaper,
because it's rare that you'll find a tool for it that costs money.
It's hard to make a tool and charge for it in PHP,
because it kind of goes against the open source ethos.
As a result of being open, and free, and all that good stuff,
it also means that the community using it is enormous.
This then leads me to point number two that you should know.
Number two, it has the largest community, and is therefore
the easiest to find and recruit developers for.
More supply, lower price.
Good for companies, bad for developers.
The last thing I'd say that's worth understanding, number three,
is that because it's free, and the community that uses it is enormous,
there's a strong vibe against the developer community
that PHP is some form of an inferior language.
It's pretty similar to hipsters who love something
until too many other people love it,
then they disown it and pretend like they never liked it.
PHP does have some drawbacks, but for the most part it is flexible,
it's well supported, and it's easy to use.
The next time someone makes a disparaging comment about PHP,
you can just say one thing that will
shut them up, and that's "Facebook".
Yes, Facebook, that massive ground-breaking
platform is built entirely in PHP.
Remember The Social Network, where Mark
Zuckerberg, played by Jesse Eisenberg,
is throwing those coding parties, and trying
to make their website as fast as possible?
* What's going on? *
* They have ten minutes to get root access to a Python web server, *
* expose its SSL encryption, and then intercept
all traffic over its secure port. *
In that very accurate documentary, that was PHP they were using.
Facebook and all of its glory is built on the back of PHP.
And if saying Facebook doesn't work
for you, you can also say "WordPress,"
which they may or may not get, but we'll cover that later
when we get to the content management systems.
I'll tell you a secret though, WordPress is
responsible for 22% of the entire internet.
And guess what? WordPress is 100% PHP.
All right guys, see you in the next lecture!