Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Ok, so in the last lecture we learned what frameworks roughly are.
They're pre-made code that you can use for your programming project
to save you time and make that whole process easier and more effective.
But there's an important distinction to keep
in mind when thinking about frameworks.
There are essentially two different separate types of frameworks
that are not really that similar.
We have front-end frameworks and we have back-end frameworks.
Ok, so there exists on your browser a set of three different languages
we've already covered in this course: HTML, CSS, and can you guess the third one?
JavaScript.
Those three determine the look, the feel, and the interactivity of the website,
and then behind the scenes we have a different set of languages
that are doing all of the heavy lifting, and all of the applications' bidding.
Now, those two sets of languages do
different things and are inherently very different,
and that's why we have two distinctive frameworks aimed at helping each side,
the browser side and the server side.
In this lecture and the next couple of lectures
we're going to take a peek at the first kind - front-end frameworks.
If you really think about it, you could probably
deduce what a front-end framework does.
Since we're concerning ourselves with looks,
and positioning, and visual organization,
what do you think a front-end framework is probably going to do?
Remember, it's something that helps you speed up efficiency
by giving you a lot of the basic stuff that you would have to
create from scratch if you were starting from scratch.
Well, if you haven't guessed it already,
it's going to give the developer a pre-made system.
It's essentially going to give them a template website
that's set up in the most convenient way possible.
In most cases, it will give them a CSS sheet
that gives the developer a pre-made "grid system".
In front-end development, a grid system just means making a style sheet
that allows you to easily put images, buttons, and text,
and anything else you want on the site
into easy to use and see vertical columns.
So if you had, let's say, a three-column grid, that means I could put
one thing on the left third of the screen, in that column,
one in the middle, in the middle column,
and one on the right, in the right column.
And since that grid came from a framework, the framework would automatically
place all of the objects within those columns for me,
and keep them in the right place as I use this on different screens.
Now, this is obviously an oversimplification,
but trust me, it saves developers a lot of time,
because it takes a lot of time to just sit there and make a grid from scratch,
saying it needs to be this height, and this width, and everything that
has this name goes over here, it's just an unnecessary process.
Another thing a front-end framework might do is
give what's called a "UI pack" or a "UI kit."
UI stands for User Interface, which is a really fancy way of saying
"what you see on the screen," like buttons, and like text.
In this case, a UI pack or a UI kit would give them a pre-made set of
button designs, fonts, sliders, headers, really any common component
you would see on almost all websites.
It could even give you, say, graphic design for more specific things,
like profile pictures, frames for images, charts, a lot of more specific detail things.
Past that, we'll typically see a front-end framework maybe give a set of
pre-used JavaScript commands for things that, again, are routine and very common.
Things like submitting forms, things like popups, sliders,
search boxes, error messages, that kind of thing.
Of course, not all of them are the same but for the most part
we'll see these three common things.
We'll see grids, we'll see UI kits, and we'll see what are called interaction snippets,
also known as just little chunks of JavaScript.
Now, in simple plain English terms, I would call this:
one, grids we would call probably layouts,
number two, as opposed to saying UI kits I'd just say buttons and other objects,
and three, I'd call interaction snippets just pieces of action code,
little bits of JavaScript for pulling information and communicating with the server,
and doing those basic tasks.
Ok, in the next lecture, let's actually jump in and look at
one of the most popular front-end frameworks out there: Bootstrap.
All right, see you then!