Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Hey, so I want to take a quick bit to explain to you very quickly
how it is that in the next lectures we're going to preview
the code that we're going to talk about.
So when you program, you are going to use, and this is a concept
that we'll learn later in the course, but it's going to be
something called a text editor, or let's call it an
IDE - integrated development environment.
So, in this case, we're going to stick with text editor, because
that's usually what people write their programs in.
Some people out there are hardcore and don't
use text editors, they just use text documents.
Those people are crazy, we're not going to do that.
So, the easiest way of getting to a point where you can kind of
follow along and play with it is just go to sublimetext.com.
Very popular text editor, it's free as we currently speak,
I don't know in the future if they're going to start charging.
I know for a fact that the version you can download right now,
they will constantly bug you about paying, but you don't actually have to pay,
you can just keep clicking out of the thing.
So you go to sublimetext.com, this is what it looks like.
It's just a big black window, and it allows you to type in, and what it'll do is
it'll color code, it'll help you organize your programming thoughts, basically,
it'll allow you to preview what you're making, it'll even allow you to
write in the same document in two separate areas at the same time.
These are all things you don't have to concern yourself with, but
it's helpful to understand why people use these.
So just go down and say download for whatever.
If you guys are on Windows, they have a version as well,
so what you're seeing right now should say "Download for Windows."
Once you download it, then you can just open it up,
and it typically just looks like this,
and you can pretty much play with it from there.
So when I type in here, it's basically going to treat this like code.
Down here, I can tell it what type of code I am writing in,
so, you know, let's say I wanted to make something HTML,
you would just say, so HTML is separated into three different sections,
you have a head, a body, and a footer.
It doesn't even matter, you don't need to know this,
but I could just say, like, "Hello world," I can exit out of it,
remember those tags that we learned when we talked about HTML.
So right there, what it's going to say is, "I want this text,
"Hello world," to display in header 1,"
which is a really old way of saying moderately
large text, I mean it's like size 28 or something.
And then what you can do is go up here and say File - Save As.
I suggest you just save it to your desktop, that's the easiest way of finding this,
and then acting on it, so save it as Index.html.
Remember, we learned about this, this is the first file that any time
you access a website, your browser is going to initially just go to.
I've already created it, so we have it right there. Great.
Now that it knows its HTML, and you can
change it over here, it actually color codes for me.
So, if I wanted to say like, this was in the head section,
see how it automatically will tell me, it will finish the text for me,
so I don't have to type that out.
So, and then, we save it, Command + S, you guys are Control + S.
Oh, would you like to purchase?
No, I would not. Ok, great.
Now what that has done for me is it's saved it on the desktop right here,
and what I want to do if I want to view it is I can just open it in Chrome.
Right, there you go. Hello world, right?
So that's how we create a little quick feedback loop.
So I can write here, and then every single time I want to update it,
I can just go back to my browser, and then... So if I save that,
go back to my browser and literally just refresh the page.
There you go, ok? That's how I change it.
It gets a little bit more complicated than that, but don't worry.
If you want to follow along, go and download
Sublime, and we can do it together,
otherwise you can just watch me, doesn't really matter.
All right guys, see you in the next lecture!