Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Ok, last lecture we got into what CMS's do
and why they were created to begin with.
Now, recap.
Every site that publishes anything to the world has a whole lot of functions
it needs to get that most basic task done - the task of publishing something.
Formatting, sizing, image processing, site navigation, commenting, abilities
to take user submitted information, the ability to update and manage itself, etc.
Doing that yourself is pretty crazy unless you're a big company
that can spend the resources and the time.
For the rest of us normal people, we use a content management system.
Ok, so what are the popular ones?
Well, let me first introduce you to the mother ship,
the granddaddy of all content management systems - WordPress.
Rock your subconscious mind, I guarantee
you've heard this term somewhere before.
Your friend's blog about her Southeast Asia backpacking trip
was probably made on WordPress and it probably said WordPress
somewhere on the site because she didn't really customize it very well.
WordPress is the world's largest and the
most popular content management system.
Want to know a mind blowing fact?
22% of the entire internet is built on WordPress.
Whaaat?
Yeah, I know.
No, really, if you go to any website online there is a
better than 1 in 5 chance that it's built on WordPress.
"But it looks just like a normal website" you might say.
Yeah, exactly.
WordPress is so large and so well established that it has a veritable tomb of
templates, plugins, and extensions to make it whatever you want.
To go with that tomb, it has an army of people who for a living
just customize WordPress installations.
WordPress can handle everything we mentioned and then some.
It can handle payments, it can handle
email lists, it can handle post scheduling.
The only thing it can't do is probably save your marriage,
and ironically, it probably has ended a couple.
It's really hard to use.
So when I say a site could be built on WordPress
and you wouldn't even know about it, I mean it.
Let's look at some sites that are built on
WordPress, you might recognize a couple of these.
Let's look at BestBuy, built on WordPress.
Time Magazine, built on WordPress.
Fortune Magazine / .com (do they still have a magazine?), built on WordPress.
New York Times, yes, built on WordPress.
Harvard Business Review, AMC, it just goes on and on.
True story: WordPress was created by one man, Matt Mullenweg,
who in order to create WordPress spent two years programming almost non-stop
and sleeping in what's called polyphasic sleep,
and that means that you sleep for 40 minutes six times a day.
So you sleep 40 minutes, then you stay awake and program for 2.5 hours,
then you sleep for another 40 minutes,
and then you repeat that pattern for two years.
I'm just tired even thinking about it, if I don't sleep my 14 hours, I get cranky.
Ok, so if you had to know one CMS, it would be WordPress.
Impress your friend at the bar with this amazing piece of knowledge,
and if any of them at the bar know virtually anything about the internet
they will already know this and think you're quite lame.
Whatever.
What are the other popular ones and what should we know about those?
Well, the next up is worth mentioning, it's called Drupal.
Drupal is the veganism or atheism of CMS.
If you know someone who uses it, they cannot wait to tell you about it,
because, oh my God, Drupal does everything.
What's there to rave about?
Well, like WordPress, it has an innumerable number of modules, and plugins,
and extensions you can add to it and make it fit for whatever you want to make.
Forum? Sure.
Membership site? Sure, there's a module for that.
Online courses? Yeah, there's actually a module for that one too.
What's worth knowing about Drupal is that from 10,000 feet
and without actually diving into the system itself,
it's actually virtually indistinguishable
from WordPress on all aspects except a couple.
Number one is Drupal is less mainstream and less popular than WordPress.
They only have about 2.2% of the internet on their platform,
which still is an enormous amount of websites.
Number two, it has a more enthusiastic
but smaller core of developers supporting it.
These people give each other barbwire tattoos of the Drupal logo
because they are hardcore, never die Drupal.
And it shows.
Drupal has more modules, and extensions, and
updates per developer than any other CMS in the world.
Worth noting, both Drupal and WordPress are built out of PHP
and are generally considered multi-purpose, as in
no matter what you are trying to make or do,
one of these will probably work for you.
I like to think of them as the onesies of content management systems.
One size fits all.
All right, now the last CMS we're going to
talk about in this lecture is called Magento.
Have you heard of Magento?
Probably not.
If you already know what this is, then, well, why are you taking this course?
Maybe you're a mystery shopper from Udemy.
I just want you to know that I see you.
Magento is similar yet unique to the other ones that we've talked about.
Like the other ones, it's also built in PHP, and like the others,
it's enormous, and started around the same time as the others.
But Magento targets an entirely different use case.
If you haven't noticed, most of the examples
I gave you before for WordPress or Drupal
are heavy on the whole blog and written content angle.
Newspapers, blogs, forums - these are things that just
naturally fit within the WordPress and Drupal system.
But one thing they can handle but are at somewhat of a disadvantage
because they didn't really focus on it is e-commerce.
E-commerce as in buying stuff online.
People who run stores have different needs
and focus on different things than people who write blogs.
They care about inventory management, things called SKUs, product imagery,
and in general they're less concerned with
how many likes their social media posts get.
The opening was there, and Magento was one of the first to go for it.
So, like the other two, it's huge, it's popular,
and you have to install it on a web server, just like the others.
But unlike the others, it's made specifically for selling stuff.
Whatever stuff you want.
If you were going online and buy a Samsung Galaxy Note 7 from Samsung.com
and it came to you without exploding, you'd use Magento to buy it.
Samsung is built in Magento.
I don't know if it's too soon for Samsung exploding phone jokes, but anyway.
If you bought a laptop from Lenovo or a
sweet "looks original but is actually a copycat"
pair of headphones from Sony.com, you used Magento.
Ok, those are the three biggies you need to know about.
All three are built in PHP, all three are for the most part free and easy to set up.
WordPress is the biggest and the most popular,
although it is known to be frustrating at times,
Drupal has similar characteristics but is best known for the cult that follows it,
and Magento was going to go WordPress, but they took a turn
and decided to go Magento and just focus on selling things online.,
something that when WordPress and Drupal were coming out
was not nearly as big of a thing as it is now.
Remember, this is a time before Amazon Prime,
a time I really don't like to think about.
Next lecture, we're going to cover the new guard of CMS,
how it's changed, and what the F is WYSIWYG.
Don't even try to spell it, much less pronounce it.
All right, see you then!