Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Hey, in this lecture we're just going to cover real fast
how exactly do back-end frameworks work.
All right, so you remember from previously, we kind of explained frameworks are
broken down into two different categories: front-end and back-end.
Front-end frameworks primarily are going to deal with how the website looks,
where to put the images, what is the grid system going to be,
assuming they use a grid system.
With a back-end framework, it's a little bit different.
Now, we remember back-end languages like PHP, like Python,
like Ruby, like Java, and those are the languages that run
in the background and do the website's bidding.
Every time I submit a form, that information gets
ferried to a database by a back-end language.
Every time you make an internal calculation on a website, you will see that.
Every time you pull information from another site to your site,
that's going to be handled by a back-end language.
Let's say you logged in through Twitter to your Product Hunt page,
great example of back-end at work.
Ok, so what exactly would a framework do for a back-end language?
Well, it does a lot of things, and it's pretty similar, I would say, to a front-end.
First of all, every single time you make a
website and you set up the server side files,
you're going to set them up in a pretty standard way.
There are ways that the general community accepts as being positive and correct,
and then there are ways that are just flat out wrong.
The first thing you'll see a framework do
is help you set up this file and folder structure.
You'll notice this the more and more websites you look at,
you'll always have a folder for your CSS,
you always have a folder for your images,
and then you'll always have a folder for certain special things like APIs,
like models, like templates or themes, yatta yatta.
The second thing a framework is going to do is it's going to give you
a lot of pre-made code for functions that you're probably going to use.
In a lot of cases, frameworks will give you tons
and tons of pre-made functions and code,
you're not going to use all of it, but they're going to give you a lot of
the common ones that you're going to use in the vast majority of websites.
Some examples might be, every single time you pull from a database,
you have to write a query to pull that information,
that itself, if you had to make it from scratch,
it would be pretty tedious, a lot of frameworks
will give you templates for handling that.
Let's say you wanted to install a search box on your website,
so that you could search all of the pages in your site.
One thing you might see a framework do is give you the code for doing that,
it will help you index all of the files, and then give you the system
whereby you can actually search through all of them.
It might also help you with downloading files,
it might help you with optimizing images, saving, and recalling them,
it might even help you with setting up, which
we're going to talk about later, called APIs,
for pulling information from other websites, let's say Facebook or Twitter.
It might, in a lot of cases, even help you
do things like setting up a payment terminal,
because every time you set up a payment terminal, whether it's PayPal,
or Stripe, or Braintree, you're going to do it in a very similar way,
a lot of that stuff is just redundant, so a
framework will help you get through that.
Now, two things I think you should keep in mind
and are worth knowing about back-end frameworks.
A lot of times back-end frameworks will give you structure, and what that means
in certain cases is that it will force you to program your application
in a specific way that fits with the structure they've given you.
Later on, we'll talk about things like MVC and OOP,
but a lot of times you'll find frameworks that will force you into
what's called a certain paradigm of programming.
A good example of this is Code Igniter, which is a framework for PHP,
when you make a website using that framework,
you will make it in the Code Igniter way.
Now, that's great if you're using Code Igniter, because it can save you a lot of time,
it's a problem if someone who's working on
your team doesn't know how to use that framework,
or you need to transition to a different framework, it could require a large overhaul.
The second thing that's worth knowing is that you have full frameworks,
and then you have smaller frameworks.
Often times, the smaller frameworks are called micro-frameworks.
The basic gist is this: full frameworks
will give you tons, and tons, and tons of
pre-made functions, support, file structure for a wide variety of use cases,
so much so that sometimes when you install a full framework,
you have issues with maintaining all of that information,
and just keeping track of where everything is,
what you need to use, and what you don't need to use.
It can be really complicated to learn a framework,
and that's why some frameworks out there are actually smaller,
they focus on more core functions, functions that are more important
and less on the extra things that you might possibly need.
The two main benefits, obviously, of that, is
that it's easier to learn, and manage, and maintain,
but then also it actually will help your website
perform, or your application perform better,
because browsers don't have to load as much code.
Ok, so that's the basic gist of it.
The next couple of lectures, we're actually going to dive in
and look at a couple of back-end frameworks.
We're going to look as best we can,
keeping in mind that a lot of the stuff is non-visual,
so we're going to try to get a little familiarity, we'll see what happens.
All right, see you then!