Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
So, the next tech trend we're going to cover is what's called a hybrid app.
Now, in general, when you hear me say app, I'm probably talking about mobile apps,
it's just kind of a short form, and if I say application,
I'm probably talking about something on the web.
Now, if you remember from before, we covered very briefly
what the three types of mobile apps are.
The first one is native, and native basically means that the app was written
in the code that the mobile operating system essentially recognizes and accepts,
so if you're making a native app for iOS, it's going to be in Objective C,
if you're doing it for Android, you have to write it in Java.
The second type is what's just called a web app, which is essentially
just a website shrunk down, and partially redesigned to fit and work on a smaller screen,
and then often times that will be then taken
and put into a package that can be used like an app.
A lot of people don't even notice this, but there are web apps on your phone,
and when you press the button to open the app, it just takes you to a web page.
The third type of app out there is what's called a hybrid app
and it's something that kind of straddles the fence.
Now, the basic idea behind hybrid apps is that most people and companies
are probably going to want to make a mobile app
for as many operating systems as they can,
and that often means that they end up spending a lot of time,
and building out, and hiring different resources for different operating systems.
So the basic thinking behind the hybrid apps is
"Why make three apps, Windows Phone, iOS,
and Android, if you could just make one?"
And that is what a hybrid app is.
A hybrid app is an app that you write in basic web code,
that then goes into a system such as Phone Gap,
which basically acts as a compiler that takes that code, compiles it,
and then interprets it in a way that every single
mobile operating system can actually understand.
Now that seems like a great deal, right?
Why would I spend all the time and resources to make
all these different apps when I can just make one?
Well, it's because there's actual downsides to it.
There's two main downsides to hybrid apps.
The first downside is interactivity.
Because you're writing essentially in web code, and then you're compiling it,
it's harder to control the finished product that comes out,
and also the systems right now are kind of underdeveloped.
And when I say interactivity, what do I mean?
I mean actual movements, popups, motions, those kind of things,
the things that have become really popular in the last 4-5 years.
I don't know if you ever noticed this, but go to Facebook.
Go to your Facebook app right now, open it.
What you'll notice is when you press buttons,
often times it just looks more seamless,
when you press a button, it might depress,
and then you might see a smooth motion come up, and pop open.
If you ever opened the Twitter app, it shows the icon Twitter,
and then it just zooms out, and then you see your homepage.
Those two are examples of native applications.
Now go and look at something like Netflix.
Netflix is actually a hybrid app, and you can kind of tell
by just navigating through it and pressing buttons.
It just doesn't feel the same, and it doesn't respond
the same way to the other apps you're used to.
The second downside to hybrid apps is with hybrid apps
it's harder to control basic core functions of the phone itself.
So it's harder to do things like dial a phone number, send a text,
or save and retrieve images on the hard drive of the phone.
The only reason why that is is just because systems like Phone Gap
are relatively undeveloped, and every year they're getting a lot better,
so next year I wouldn't be surprised if that's not even a problem anymore.
So that's really it.
Hybrid apps are apps that are written in one language,
stuck through a program that then translates it for every single platform.
It saves you a lot of time and money,
but you end up giving up full control over the app,
and in general, it doesn't perform the same way, so the user experience often suffers.
Also worth noting that there are hybrid apps that work on desktops.
What do I mean by that?
I mean web apps, like your Gmail, or going to, say, Slack, that work in your browser,
but also then work on your desktop, not accessed through a browser.
A great example is actually Slack.
If you look at Slack, they did not make their app
in the native language for either Windows or OS X.
What they did was use a hybrid app system,
not worth getting into the specifics, but I'll post it in the resources.
That whole process was kind of kicked off by a thing called Adobe Air,
which essentially was kind of the first system that would take web apps,
compile them, and interpret them for your desktop, same way like a Phone Gap works.
All right guys, that's basically what you need to understand about hybrid apps.
Upside, cheap and fast, downside, you lose some on the user experience,
and also, hey, we have hybrid apps all over, you just need to get used to spotting them.
All right, see you in the next lecture!