Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
Ok, so the next concept we need to take a peek at is the concept of "printing".
Now, I know what you're thinking, roughly.
No, it's not a system for queuing up a printer, and in fact
I really don't know why they decided to call it "printing" at all.
If you know, you can post in the Q&A, because I honestly don't know,
I'm sure there is some very strange story as to why that is.
Ok, so the basic idea of printing is that it's a common command
you can put into your code and what it's going to do for you is that
it's going to take all of the work you have done so far and
output that onto a screen whenever you run the code.
This is actually something that tripped me up quite a bit
when I originally learned this stuff too.
What do you mean put it on a screen? It's already on the screen for me.
To get over that hump, you just have to
remember programs are just text documents.
They don't actually do anything until a browser opens them,
at which point the browser knows how to
read the instructions and responds accordingly.
So if I gave that burrito recipe to the browser,
it would just go "Hm, interesting, these are some values
and you did this calculation. Great. Good to know."
And, looking at this calculation, then what would it do?
It would just know that these are the values,
but then it wouldn't do anything past that point.
So how would you tell the world that you know how to
calculate the price of burrito, chips, and guac?
If I wanted the browser to display on the screen
so the customer knew what the actual price was during the calculation,
let's say we're at the cart stage,
and they need to know how much dough they're about to lose,
well, I'd actually have to "print" this screen,
and that process, that function tells the browser,
"Hey, everything I just did, or what I'm specifically telling you to do,
take that and print it onto the browser, so that person can see it."
Remember how we talked about back-end languages, how they do
a lot of the unsung work behind the scenes?
Well, the vast majority of what happens behind your browser,
in the back-end, you just don't see.
It's going to make a lot of calculations, it's going to store information,
it's going to save it, it's going to move it around,
you never see that stuff happening.
It's only when it prints that it shows up
on the screen and you see something change.
I save something and I need to see an update message pop up,
it's not until somewhere in the code it
says "Print this message" that I actually see it.
So, in this situation, in Python, what you would do is,
it's actually just called "print," and specifically with Python,
you have to put parentheses after "print,"
so I would just say "print equals the total."
So that is actually it. Now the browser knows
how to get the burrito price onto the screen.
If I wanted to do the same thing, but let's say,
in a different language, say, Ruby,
well, how would I do that? I would
actually just have to drop the parentheses.
And it's going to flip out because it's expecting
Python, but that is how you do it in Ruby.
So how do you think I would have to do this in PHP to the exact same function?
You can probably guess from the last lecture, because why?
Because variables have to have a dollar sign in front of them.
That's it. That is how you'd print in PHP,
without it is how you do it in Ruby,
and with parentheses is how you do it in Python.
The more you know.
Ok, so printing is basically just how
you ferry things from the browser's memory
to the browser's output, which is basically what the user actually sees.
This is a concept in back-end languages, as you'll notice,
in here, I didn't tell it to print this, and it showed up.
That's because when your browser sees an HTML file,
everything it's going to do it's going to display on the front.
If it needs to make a calculation, and then display the result of that calculation,
it's going to have to use a back-end language, which, again, is behind the scenes.
So, if I wanted to ferry that information from the back-end,
the Python file, to the HTML, I would need to print it.
Ok, hopefully that makes enough sense.
So now, when you hear the word "printing," really that just means show it,
put the code on the screen, because naturally,
code just does not automatically output itself,
you have to tell it to output.
On to the next concept we're going to cover, it's called commenting.
All right, see you then!