Hey guys, welcome back.
All right. So, have you ever heard someone say the phrase
"How well documented is the code"?
This is actually a big concern for developers,
especially when they're working on an application
that someone else has contributed to or someone else built.
Let's say you get hired to a new company,
and you're coming in, and you have to start writing code
to modify a site that's already been around for a while,
it's been made, it's been up, and it's been edited for years.
If I were to just open up their codebase, just pop open
everything they've built and just look at it,
well, there is a very good chance that I would get lost trying to figure out
what everything in the page is trying to do, what it's referring to,
when it's going to get used, what gets displayed, what doesn't,
what part of the application is using this calculation.
That is why we have a concept called commenting.
So comments are literally just the way that the developer adds in
verbal, non-restricted, text that doesn't follow
any programming syntax to explain what they're doing.
You might think, why didn't I just type in instructions for future generations
right there next to everything else?
Like, "Hey, I just took the total and put it on the screen."
Why don't I just do it like that?
Well, because, if you kind of remember
from before, machines just follow instructions,
they're not that smart, they're just very fast at following set instructions.
So if I decided to go save this and run it, it would probably explode
when it got to this point, because it will think this is code,
it will think this is going to be in Python,
and it has no idea what this is, it's just going to output a bunch of errors,
and then depending on the language you're using, it may just
break everything else, stop there and exit, and give you an error message,
or it might just create an issue and then move on.
Again, your browser doesn't know if it's code.
So if it doesn't taste like code, it will flip out
and the document will have a problem.
So to avoid that happening, we have to what's called "comment it out,"
that's the phrase, commenting something out.
We have to use a specific symbol that when the browser reads it,
the browser just knows inherently that if I see this symbol,
everything after it, or within some basic parameters,
I need to ignore it, because this is not code,
this is that weird human speech.
So in Python, the way you would do this is pretty simple.
I would just take that thing I just wrote, and that's it.
And notice how in Sublime it recognizes that I'm commenting,
and so what does it do? It just kind of greys it out, so visually,
if I'm looking at it, and I'm trying to program, this just doesn't get in the way.
So then I could do really whatever I wanted.
I could say "That's a really expensive burrito,"
or subtotal, and then I could give explanations for how this works.
"Everybody wants chips with their burrito."
And when I run this, the computer is not going to think
"Everybody wants chips with their burrito" is code,
and it's not going to try to do anything with it.
Now, in Ruby, the way you would do that is actually
the exact same, that's actually kind of nice.
So how exactly would I do this in, let's say, PHP?
Now, remember, PHP has been around longer,
so it has a lot of legacy issues,
it has a lot of things that look like lower level programming languages,
so that's why a lot of people think that it's unideal to use.
At the end of the day, it's not really a big deal.
The way you do it in PHP is a little bit more complicated,
you would say, do a slash, then a star, I can say whatever I want here,
and then I have to tell it again, now I'm ending my commenting.
So then I do that, and just reverse it around.
That's how it does it, so it knows to look for this, and then
it's not going to comment it out until it sees that,
the opposite version of that code.
Now, in a sense, this is actually more efficient, because I can be more specific
about what to ignore, such as everything
essentially in between these goal posts.
Now, in the other languages that are more open-ended and more loose,
you might actually tell the browser to skip over some real code instructions
because you accidentally got it too close to a comment.
So I might, for instance, if I accidentally do like that or something,
it might actually read it incorrectly, or there is times where
it'll just skip over it, because you were not specific enough.
Comments are a simple concept, but they're really, really important,
especially if you're someone who works with developers or manages them.
When you hire developers, what do you
want them to do to make the ideal codebase?
Well, generally speaking, you want them to comment on whatever they make
so that the future hires who work with them can understand it,
or if you have to get rid of that developer for whatever reason,
the next person taking over their seat has
less of a learning curve to figure it out,
they don't have to stare at it for days to try to piece it together in their head,
they can take these little cookie crumb clues.
Ok, so that is commenting, it's a way to keep track of what you're doing,
because when you have actual applications,
these are just pages, and pages, and thousands of lines long,
it can get confusing, unless you have someone pointing you in the right direction.
That is what commenting is for.
All right guys, see you in the next lecture!