All right, and we're on to the next one.
All right, so we know roughly what HTML is, right?
Every site will start with text and images.
How do you format those text and images?
Well, you format them with HTML.
You add tags to each individual thing that
you want to display on the browser,
and that way you can change the way
it actually displays. That's pretty much it.
Now, if you lived in a world where
all you could do to your website was
put photos and text, and then
tell it what color and size to be,
you would find that the experience is a bit lacking.
If you agree with that statement, then you agree
with pretty much everyone in the world back in 1994.
Remember how we talked about why there
are different languages to begin with?
Well, one of the reasons was that often times languages
are created for what we need to do right now,
and then later, when we need to do more,
well... crap, I guess we need a new language.
That oh-uh story is pretty much the genesis of CSS,
which is otherwise known as Cascading Style Sheets.
HTML was made to modify and format text originally.
That was it, and it worked great for text.
So naturally, in 1991, when the World Wide Web first came available,
and people could put webpages up onto
the internet for other people to see,
naturally people went with the language that
was actually available to them at the time to use.
And no surprise, pages back in 1991 were just text.
Basically it was like your school paper, but displayed online.
Now, it wasn't actually until 1994 that HTML was upgraded to allow
inclusion of things like images and, oh boy,
let me tell you, stuff just got crazy after that.
At the time, that is legitimately how people felt.
I'm obviously joking though, because nothing compares
to what's been happening in the last four years.
Now, maybe you at home can put together
why what I just said is a problem.
Anyone? Ok.
If HTML is made to edit text documents and
then all of a sudden we can make web pages
where text can be anywhere on the screen and look like anything,
how exactly would HTML handle that?
Going from, remember, just documents, to now
having this free range screen that it has to handle.
Let's say you're designing a site like the one we're in right now.
On the right hand side, when you click on the,
I think it's the Q&A button, you'll see a bunch of text.
Now, look at the text at the top. You see it? Ok?
How in HTML would you put that there?
Remember, you only have 142 tags,
and none of those HTML tags say
"Put text here next to this."
Remember? It just said, like, the size,
and the color, and that was it,
it didn't help with positioning, and that was one of
the many problems that CSS was set out to solve.
What CSS allowed you to do was
have more control over the page.
After all, HTML was never meant for page
description, it was meant for text description.
So with CSS, you create a variety of new attributes and then
you can apply them to HTML elements on the page.
The way you did that was by using what's called a "class,"
which, let's be honest, is really the same
thing as a tag, just with a different name.
Remember how in HTML if you wanted
to apply, let's say, underline to text,
you would wrap it in code with little alligator brackets and "u,"
and then end it with alligator brackets with a "u" and a slash in front of it?
Well, CSS actually operates in a very similar way.
Let's say you wanted to make that underlined text display
on the top right corner at exactly that one specific spot.
Well, what you would do, let's say, is create a class, name it,
and then give it some detail, give it some attributes.
This class, let's say, we'll call Class1, and has the properties of being
50 pixels to the right and 600 pixels to the left
from the center of the screen, just as an example.
Then, much like a tag, you would wrap that
text in its new class, and there you go,
now that text gets the attributes of location,
and it's displayed on your screen where you want to see it.
Any attribute you give to that class will be then
given to whatever you wrap in that class tag.
To keep things simple, you would create these class rules either
one, in the document, the same document
as your text, but separated at the top.
or two, what virtually everyone now does and
you should do, when and if you learn how to program,
is that you create a separate page, and you
change the end of the name of the document to .css,
and then you have the original document
with your text just refer to it,
that nifty skill that, remember, we talked about with HTML.
The advantages to this second way of doing it are pretty obvious.
One, you get to keep your text documents clean and easy to read,
and two, multiple documents can share the same CSS document
and then use its rules and different class attributes.
If you wanted to, say, change the font
on all the text in the entire website
and not just the one page you're talking about, then you'd only
have to go to one CSS sheet document and change it once.
Out of curiosity, why is it called Cascading Style Sheets?
Well, first off, it's a sheet that describes
the style of the elements on a page.
So that part was pretty obvious.
Now, what does cascading mean?
Cascading refers to the fact that classes can be combined
and then displayed in essentially what's a "cascading" style.
You know how, when someone comments on
a blog post, it displays their comments normally,
but if someone then comments on that
specific comment, it indents their comment
so that visually you can organize it, and
actually understand who they're talking to.
That concept we just talked about
is called nesting, and the more you do it,
the more it creates that indented staircase look,
and that's where we get the word cascading and CSS.
CSS, when you, say, make a class inside of a class, as in, like,
a comment on top of a comment, or directed at a comment,
what ends up happening is you have two separate classes,
one is a subclass, and one is the master, mother class.
The subclass only applies to what you apply it to, but it also inherits
the attributes that are associated with the class that it's attached to.
You don't need to obviously understand
that in depth until you actually get into it,
but just understand, by doing this over and over,
it starts to look kind of like a staircase.
Sure, that helps you understand why it's called that,
but it's also why some people find CSS extremely frustrating.
I would imagine front-end developers think purgatory is a life of
endlessly editing CSS style sheets, and trying to figure out
what class applies to what, and what
class is canceling out the other class,
and what class is inheriting the class that got cancelled.
All right, that pretty much wraps up what
you need to know on the topic of CSS.
Currently, we are on CSS3, and, as you can imagine,
the language is getting more and more important.
Designers and front-end developers
spend a large portion of their time
learning how to master this language,
so they can display their sites correctly
as they originally intended.
CSS is one of those languages that every web developer has to have
a basic understanding of, at a bare minimum
they have to know how to edit it.
All right, next lecture we're moving on.
We got text and formatting with HTML,
we got page positioning and style with CSS,
next up we're hitting JavaScript,
which makes your site interactive.
Stay tuned!