Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, so in this lecture, we're going to address the obvious question.
This is a lot of different information and different systems,
how do I choose one or the other?
And it's an important question, obviously,
especially if you're going to build an app,
launch a blog, create a forum, or pretty much
anything else you could possibly do on the interwebs.
Well, the first distinction is easy.
Are you going to sell things online?
If you're primarily going to be working on an e-commerce store,
then spend your time working with a Magento, or Shopify,
or any of the other like a hundred e-commerce focused CMS systems.
These are made for you, and made for
all the problems you will run into selling things.
And yes, there are a lot of problems you haven't thought of
that other non e-commerce systems don't really bother to address,
such as "What happens when I accept a payment in a different currency?",
"How can I detect user fraud or pick up on a bad credit card?",
or even "How can I routinely offer sales on certain items to boost sales?"
Someone creating a blog could not care less about these questions.
Now, one thing you need to ask yourself upfront is
"Is the purpose of this site primarily to sell things?"
or "Is selling things just one of the many things my site does?"
Keep in mind, online shops also have blogs.
Amazon has a blog, although I'm not sure anyone has actually ever read it.
Going with an e-commerce focused system can still facilitate this.
Shopify is going to be harder to attach a blog to because
they control too much and they're all about the money.
Magento, on the other hand, can make this a little bit easier for you.
What most people do, believe it or not, is they either choose a platform
that focuses on e-commerce and handles blogging sufficiently
or they use two separate CMS systems.
I know - mind blown - one for selling and one for blogging.
Now, does this create unique challenges? Yes.
Is it hard to do? No, not really.
Now, if you're more focused on creating other types of content
and selling things is but one of the things you do, then typically you're going to pick
one of the onesie CMS systems we talked about before.
Why? Well, because they handle all types of content
really well and they can handle e-commerce fine.
Since you're not going to be running intense cohort and regression analysis
on your year to year sales totals, using an e-commerce platform might be overkill.
All you have to do with WordPress, for example, is just install plugins for what you need,
plugins for listing products, plugins for accepting payment.
Is that easy to do?
Well, it's not the hardest thing in the world, let's just say that.
Ok, so that's your first fork in the road.
To money or not to money? That is the question.
The second question is "How particular are you about details?"
Do you need to make this site 100% unique and tailor every part to what you want?
If that's the case, then you need one of the older, more traditional CMS systems,
because with those, really the sky is the limit.
Keep in mind, obviously, that you're inviting way
more work onto yourself by going this route.
If you're not as particular about the details, and don't care about having
an exclusive design, then try using a Weebly, or a SquareSpace, or a Wix.
They, after all, do look pretty slick, because that's what they focus on.
Now, what if you can't tell if you care or not about these details?
Although, I mean, this is a bit weird, try this.
Go to SquareSpace.com and look at one of their templates.
Now, when you're looking at it, how many things can you point out
that you think are wrong with the website?
If you're response is along the lines of "Ooo, pretty"
then, trust me, you're probably fine with non-customizable newer CMS systems.
Another question worth asking, "What are you planning to make?"
If your answer is a blog, a forum, a store, a news outlet, a membership site,
or a site that just has information on it, then, well, you're well within the bounds
of using a more restrictive but easier to use CMS.
If your answer is along the lines of "It's a site that needs to do this and that,
but not this, and look like this but not that," well then, you need more customization.
What if I want to build an online service or tool that is 100% unique?
Well, I'm sorry to say this, but you're not going to be using a CMS.
You might use one to run smaller parts of your website that are non-unique,
like your blog, or like large portions of the site that frequently have updated text,
but the rest of it, well, that's probably going to have to be made from scratch.
Well, unless you're using a PaaS system, which right now,
I know, means absolutely nothing to you, but we'll talk about it very soon.
Ok, here's what you want to ask yourself.
Store or no store?
If your main focus is selling, use a Magento or Shopify.
If you're not, then don't use those.
If you care a lot about details, uniqueness, and creative control,
then you're going to want to lean on the spectrum towards customization
and more work for you - WordPress and the like.
If you're not picky about details and what you're making
does not have a large unique technical aspect to it,
then using a SquareSpace or a Weebly is probably going to be your ticket.
And lastly, if you're creating a custom application, then, well,
you're not going to use a CMS, I'm sorry.
All right guys, see you in the next section!