Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, let's get ready to tackle yet another technology concept, the API.
Have you ever heard someone say "The Facebook API crashed,"
or "Twilio has such a great API," or "Slack's API won't let you do anything"?
If not, well, you probably don't hang out with a lot of programmers.
Well, never fear, APIs are actually not that complicated of a concept,
and I think we can tackle them relatively easily.
The term API stands for Application Programming Interface,
which is kind of gibberish, but we can take that, I think, and break it down.
Let's say you're building this sweet app where you can write down
all the tasks you need to do in a really pretty and snazzy to do list app.
First of all, there are seriously hundreds
of these out there yet they still keep coming.
Let's say you think it'd be really cool that when the user types in a name,
the app could fill out the to do item with
information about that person from their Facebook.
Now, no doubt you've seen this happen, because it happens everywhere.
One app borrows information from another,
or similarly, one app tells another to do something.
I can post a message on Facebook, and with the click of a button,
that same message can auto post on Twitter.
Thank you, Buffer.
How do they do that exactly?
Well, it's through this concept called APIs.
Now, let's imagine we're in that to do list scenario,
you're the founder, you just created this app.
Chances are this is the situation you're looking at.
You probably think that you have a whole lot of valuable code files
and a whole lot of user data information
within your app, and within your app's community.
At the same exact time, Facebook has the same thing,
and they think all the features they've built,
and all the users they've collected are also pretty valuable.
This is all common sense.
Now, if I wanted to ask Facebook for that information,
they couldn't just manually give it to me,
because, number one, that would take way too long,
and number two, they can't open up the code base to me,
because that would put them in a really vulnerable situation,
because I could steal something, or, more likely,
I could just break something in their application.
So the solution to this conundrum was what we're talking about, which is an API,
also referred to as an API layer, because APIs exist almost
outside of the main code base of your application.
An API is basically like a mini application that
runs on top of the larger application you're building,
and it's used to facilitate the transfer of
information to external apps that ask for them.
The API can do a number of things.
Since it's a program, it can automatically handle
the transfer and fulfilling of information requests.
That saves everyone involved time.
It can also, say, limit what the other apps can ask for,
it simply won't respond if they ask for the wrong thing,
or if they ask for too much of something, they can give them denial responses.
The last thing it can do is give out detailed information on
the best way to access the information you have such that
it doesn't make a mess or slow down the system of the host.
In one of my courses, I think it was the Product Management course,
we made an analogy of an API to a waiter,
and I think it's actually a pretty good way of thinking about it.
If I was at a restaurant, I would sit down, then I would look at a menu,
and when I figured out what it is that I wanted,
I would ask the waiter to go get that for me.
The waiter would then go to the kitchen, get what I want,
and bring it back to me. I might pay him.
Now in the programming world, if I had that to do list app,
and let's say I wanted information on Jessica Smith,
I would ask the API for information on her, it would then leave,
go dig up that information, and then bring it back to me.
Piping hot. The food, not the person.
If I was making a website, little known fact, I could actually list out
all of my Udemy courses through requesting the Udemy API.
That way, I can save time displaying it manually on my site,
and I can access information they have that I might not.
So that's the basics of an API.
Some alternative systems that you might see that are actually based off of APIs
are things like the Facebook, LinkedIn, and Twitter login buttons.
You know those buttons that let you login to the account of the website
by providing them with your Facebook information?
But essentially what's happening there is you click Facebook login,
the system then goes to the Facebook API and asks "Hey, is this person real?"
and Facebook login says "Yes, they are real.
Here is some information you can use about them",
then the app comes back and it lets you login,
now that you are verified as a real bona fide human being.
That's probably more than you ever wanted to know about APIs,
but they are incredibly helpful to know and understand.
Now, there are two big changes you need to observe
with your newfound understanding of technology.
Number one, when people build apps they're doing
less and less of the actual building themselves,
and more and more of asking other apps' APIs to do the work
and to give them the information they need.
In fact, there are companies that exist out there
where their sole customer storefront is just an API.
If I wanted to add in, let's say, text messaging features into that to do list app,
where it needs to remind you, so it sends you a text message,
I wouldn't actually create my own system for sending text messages,
I'd simply connect to the API of a service called Twilio
and then let them do it in exchange for a small fee.
Twilio brings me to the second point
and the second trend you need to be aware of.
We're now seeing businesses being created where the API is not an afterthought,
it's the actual business model.
You can effectively create a commonly used and useful chunk of an application,
let people connect to it, and then charge them for using it.
Crunchbase is an example of an API that was built
to give people information about startups.
If you wanted to use them, well, they have a
freemium model, where it's a limited free version,
or you can pay a ton of money to get full access to their sweet database of information
that's maintained and improved all the time.
So it's a whole lot less of "let's build all of this," and a whole lot more of
"let's build a little bit and borrow the rest from other APIs."
Ya dig?
Ok, moving on.