Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
All right, we are on to the next concept to dip our toes into.
The concept we're going to talk about this lecture are called strings.
So, remember the last lecture, we learned about commenting,
we know what printing is, we know what variables are.
Variables are a way you store information
so that you can use it later in the application,
or even in the other pages, it saves you a lot of time.
Printing is how you tell an application,
"Hey, this needs to display on the screen."
Commenting is how people leave notes to the people that follow them,
to tell them how does this work, what does
this do, what should I be doing right now.
The next concept just relates to text.
So, remember when we talked about commenting,
and how commenting, the reason why we have a special code for it,
like in Python and in Ruby, it's that compound sign,
is because the computer, if you didn't have that compound sign,
it would look at the sentence and think that that was code,
and then return an error, and screw everything up.
So the computer is dumb, it doesn't know what is
you talking to someone else reading the document,
and what is actual code it should execute.
Strings are kind of in a similar vein.
So, in this example up here, we were just saving stuff as numbers.
Well, what if I wanted to save a variable as text,
so, if you want to write something on the screen that's going to be text?
You inherently are going to run into a problem, where
text often will get confused as code, especially in things like Python,
where text is how you do things, so me verbally saying something in text
could very easily be confused as commands.
So the way that you would do strings and they typically,
thankfully look very similar in most languages,
is you first of all have to store it in a variable,
otherwise the computer won't know what to do with it,
and it's not something you can use later.
So what we would do is we define a variable, so we would,
let's call it a variable "string", why not?
And then, by saying equals, we can say that this is,
whatever comes after this is going to be what "string" stands for.
And then, in order to tell the computer that "Hey, this is text coming up,"
what I would have to do is just put single quotations,
and then I could say, "I can type whatever I want here."
Now, in Python, it's single quotations,
in PHP it's going to be double quotations,
in Python actually I think you can use double quotations,
it just has slightly different rules associated with it,
same thing with PHP. If you have double quotes,
it changes some detail down the road,
but for the most part, this is just how you do it.
So, now that we have that stored, if I wanted to put this on the screen,
I could say "print equals string", and then I could post it on the screen,
and it would say "I can type whatever I want here."
Now, what would happen if I wanted to give a quotation in my string?
Say I had a quote about Gandhi on my homepage, I wanted to display that,
how would I do that? Because if I do a quotation it's going to look like,
"Here's the quote from Gandhi."
You see how even the color coding here just got destroyed?
What this actually thinks now is, because these double quotation marks
are only surrounding the "I" and the "from Gandhi",
it actually mistakes those as the strings, and this is not a string.
There's a lot of different ways that languages can handle this,
but it's through a concept known as an escape command.
Now the best way of thinking about escape commands is
we have written something right here, and
because it's wrapped in those quotation marks,
the computer knows that "Hey, this is text,
I shouldn't try to do anything fancy with it,"
it is essentially enclosed. But how exactly would I escape out of that
and change the rules, essentially say
"Yes, I know that you think this is a string,
but here is a super-secret command to let you
know that no, actually we need to change this."
So with an escape variable, I can essentially tell the computer that
"Hey, this is a string, but this one thing I'm typing to you is actually code
and you should run that." So, an example would be,
let's say I wanted to write a sentence, but I wanted to put it on two different lines.
I couldn't do it like this, because this would actually confuse the computer.
"Here is a quote," I can say it like that, and then like that.
So that confuses it, because the computer reads one line at a time,
it would see this string, and it doesn't see the ending point,
so it has no idea what this is, and then it would run into an error.
What I could do instead is I could give it this super-secret code,
which in Python is back N, and then I can just say the rest of it.
"This quote." And what'll end up happening is, it'll read this,
and it's just preconditioned to know that backspace N is an escape command
for how to skip lines. There's a lot of examples of that.
Anytime that you type something that is relatively complicated
or it looks like code, you're going to run into this problem.
So how would I describe where I saved something on my C: drive
on a Windows computer, especially because the C: drive would look like
C:/bunch of words/bunch of words,
it's going to get very confused by the slashes,
so you have to memorize the set of escape variables so that
you can make a string without essentially screwing it up.
One thing worth noting, another thing.
How exactly, for instance, would I make a string,
but also insert a variable?
So, these are the variables, so it's burrito, but if I said burrito in this string,
"I want a burrito," would it come up as 9?
Or, I guess it'd be "What is the food price?" and then I'd put burrito.
Would burrito come up as 9?
No, because it has these quotation marks, so it's going to think that
burrito is just plain text, like humans talking to humans.
If I wanted to do that, well, there's multiple ways of doing this,
and again, every language has a different way of handling it,
just know that there are ways that we handle this.
In Python, for instance, you could do it several ways.
One would be actually to just do it like this,
so string equals this plus, so that you concatenate, which means
attach two things together, and then I just say "burrito."
So what would happen there is, it would save string as what is the food price, nine.
Because I essentially put this outside of the string,
it now knows this is programmatic, oh wait, this is what it means,
I already know what burrito means.
Alternatively, you can do it like this,
where you'd use an escape variable, which is this,
and then you can put any letter you want, so I put like B,
notice how it even lit it up differently.
So then what I'd have to do is, then I'd put it outside of the string,
B followed by what the value of B is, so I could say this variable is 9,
or I can even say this variable is burrito.
So it's a little bit redundant, but that's kind of how you have to do it,
because if I wanted to type in burrito, I just couldn't do it,
so I'd have to use this special escape command to do that,
and then the computer just knows how to then read the next variable.
Ok, so that's the basics of strings.
A string is human text, it's text that
you want to tell the computer not to read.
Anytime you print something on the screen, anytime you
go to a website that shows text, headline on a newspaper article,
or an online newspaper article, it's going to be from a string.
It's somewhere in that code, if you pull it, you look at it, and say print headline,
or something like that, and that headline would
be parentheses whatever the actual headline is.
If we didn't have those, then the computer would get confused,
think it's code, and just return an error.
Ok, so that is strings, next lecture we're moving on to the next concept.