Hey guys, welcome back to the course.
So, in an effort of being balanced,
let's now take a second to look at
the anatomy of mobile sites and mobile apps.
I know a lot of you guys out there
are interested in the mobile space
specifically, so let's take a little turn
and talk specifically about mobile.
Ok, so here's the test of how well you've been paying attention.
Let's say I'm on my phone and I open up my browser
and I go to the same site we were talking about in the last lecture.
Now, what do you think is actually happening
behind the scenes when I do that?
If you're someone who is incredibly smart
or you're just cheating, well, guess what?
You probably know the answer, which is it's the exact same thing
as when you access it through your computer.
Your phone, after all, is just a (remember?),
it's just a small computer.
It's like your computer, but with a smaller screen.
It uses different technology to access
the same information, but it's roughly the same thing.
So how is it exactly that the same set of
instructions for the way my computer views
the website is the same as the instructions
for my phone to view the website?
This is obviously a conundrum, right?
Because my phone is definitely smaller.
Well, the answer to that is that today,
nowadays, mobile phones are so prolific that
virtually all websites you go to are going to have,
in that original index file that we talked about,
that index file with the set of original
instructions, it's going to include
information on how to display that same
exact information, but on a smaller screen.
This concept relates to what we call responsive web design,
which is a concept and a buzz word
that we'll cover later on in the course,
especially when we get to the tech trends section.
Now, there is a difference between displaying
correctly on multiple devices and being responsive,
if you don't know the difference, stay tuned, we'll get to it.
Ok, so mobile sites, when accessed
through the browser, operate very much
like the browser on your computer,
it's the same interpreter viewing the same files.
But now, what is then the difference between
mobile apps and mobile websites?
Two words that people constantly, even to this day, get flip-flopped.
Well, I'm glad you asked that question, even though I asked it,
and this is a very important distinction for you to know.
You will look like an idiot if you keeping referring
to a mobile website as a mobile app.
Maybe not immediately, but
eventually people will get sick of it,
because there's a very distinct difference.
To explain the difference, let's think about how we,
the everyday non-technical bumpkin, use both of these.
Say you wanted to look up some
information about a local store on your phone.
You would most likely what?
You open up your browser, you go to
something like Safari if you're using an iPhone,
and you type in the name of the store,
and you navigate to that site,
you probably just go through Google.
That operates the exact same way
we discussed before, same process.
But what if you wanted to, say, use Uber to call a ride?
Well, in that case, you couldn't just go
search for it and use their website to do it,
you would actually have to go to the app on your phone, open it,
and then use the features in the app to call a ride.
If you don't have the app, well, guess what?
You'll have to download it.
In this case, you aren't pinging a web server
to load a bunch of text files, it's a bit different.
In this case specifically, when using an app and not a website,
you actually have a lot of those files we talked
about before already stored on your phone.
So, remember that generic setup of
web servers that we talked about?
You have the index file, the backend file, a big
box of images, and potentially like a .css file.
Well, in this case, and again, this is oversimplified,
but to get the point, the index page,
the folder of files, and the equivalent of style instructions,
well, they're already stored locally onto your phone,
and that is actually what happens when you download an app.
You download the Uber app, they're
just going to send you the images,
and the rules, and the ways that
their app should display on the front.
Right now, on your phone, you basically have a bunch of
half-filled website folders, packaged together as apps.
So in this case, because the files aren't being interpreted - accessed
and displayed is what I mean by interpreted - through a browser,
the files have to be written in a different way for your phone
and its operating system to understand and then correctly display.
Different systems are going to require different languages.
You are essentially skipping the whole browser process entirely,
and taking what the browser does, and replacing it with
what a package of information called an app does.
Now, the biggest difference in the app scenario is you don't have
the equivalent of that backend file
we described before on your phone.
That folder is still actually out there
on the server, most likely at some side service
that Uber specifically operates,
in the Uber example, and that is used
essentially automatically to link up with the app whenever you open it.
So in the package, which is the actual
lingo for a group of files you download
when you download an app, are going
to be instructions for where to go
to find that missing piece, that missing backend functionality,
and then plus what to do with it once you find it.
Now why is this behind the scenes
functionality stored somewhere else?
Well, because the processes it's going
to run could be really complicated
and burdensome on whatever machine is required to run them.
Remember, that's why there is an advantage to
putting your server files on a server to begin with,
and that's also why the concept of RAM
in the previous section is so important.
Computers generally have a lot more RAM, they can handle this
in a much better position than, say,
your phone, which has limited specs.
So if that had to run on a tiny little phone,
it could potentially make it
run really slow, and thus ruin the experience of using the app.
Again, this is very much an over simplification,
but it's the best way
of conceptualizing how it works
when you are essentially non-technical.
Once you start learning more and more technical details,
you'll find out that it operates quite a bit
differently, but it's the same general idea.
Ok, so again, how do mobile sites and mobile apps work?
Try to explain this to yourself and then repeat it back to me.
Well, it depends on which one you're talking about.
Mobile websites are the same thing as pretty much any old website.
It's going to use a browser to interpret and display a set of files,
and the only difference is that that site
that it's going to display, it might have
different instructions for how the site should look when
accessed on your phone, versus a tablet, versus a web browser.
Now, on the app version, however,
we already have those files on our phone.
We're simply telling the phone to, "Hey, open these files,
find the main set of instructions, and then run that way."
Behind the scenes functionality gets handled
on an external server, much like any other web server.
So in this case, the files included in your app are made especially
for your screen and only your screen, and that's why in general
apps are going to look better than a mobile site.
Later on in the course, we're going to get
into the differences between apps.
We're going to talk about native apps, hybrid apps,
and then even what is a web app specifically.
I'm sure you've heard those three before,
but you probably didn't know that
there's a pretty distinct difference between the three,
and that difference is pretty important lest you, again, want to look
like an idiot in front of your developer team,
which is not what we want.
All right guys, moving on to the next lecture. See you then!