Hey hey hey, welcome back.
Ok, first off, I want you to know
that this lecture is entirely optional.
We're just going to geek out a little bit
about the history of browsers and
why we care about this little old browser called Netscape.
If you really don't care, then just skip the lecture,
see you in the next section, doesn't hurt my feelings.
You don't need to know this stuff to be
effective at what you do, but who knows?
There might be a trivia night where you get a Netscape question
and you win some chicken poppers for the team.
So what is Netscape and why should we care about it?
Ok, so back in the old, old days, when people used to hear
this noise when they connected to the internet,
back then, browsers were a
very new concept, as was the internet.
The internet in its infancy was just a loose gathering of websites
that were not connected to each other,
basic in function, and impossible to find.
Remember, this is pre-Google. A lot of people,
still back then, thought that the internet
was just a novelty, and Newsweek magazine
famously proclaimed that "The Internet is Dead".
Newsweek never again made that mistake.
Except for the other, like, ten times.
Netscape was, for all intents and purposes,
the first commercially available browser.
They were the first browser to have
a monetization scheme and thus actually
had money to invest in making their system,
and by association, make the internet better.
The first browser ever was actually
called Mosaic, but it was very prototypical,
and much like the model we see
with a lot of obscure browsers today.
It was an open source system that many
people contributed to, but there was
no centralized source of effort iterating on it
and investing money and effort towards it.
Netscape did three things that changed the internet forever.
One, they invented a new language
called LiveScript, that allowed websites
to have a much richer functionality. Prior to
this point, websites were very, very basic.
LiveScript later became... anyone?
JavaScript.
And as we know now and will explain later,
JavaScript may or may not be eating the entire world.
The second thing they did invent, which
is a game changer, was what's called SSL.
Remember how we talked about the main way
that computers transfer internet related data?
Remember? It was called the TCP/IP.
As it turns out, that unnecessarily long
acronym was really easy to hack
and it had essentially no way of
preventing information passing through it
without being intercepted and understood by Russian hackers.
So, enter SSL, which stood for Secure Sockets Layer.
What it did, quite simply, was that it encrypted the traffic
that was being passed through that TCP/IP protocol.
It would then un-encrypt it on the client machine,
assuming that's where the information was meant to go.
SSL opened up a whole new world, if you haven't yet
made the connection to why it's so important.
All of a sudden, the internet, which up
until this point was about as complicated
as the modern day Craigslist, it got a whole lot more useful.
With Netscape, you could buy things online
without worrying about people stealing your information.
The last thing that Netscape did,
and arguably the most important thing it did,
was that it launched what we call the browser wars.
As we all know, when companies fight
over customers, we the customers usually win.
Unless it's Comcast, because they
will always find a way to screw you over.
Netscape turned a young Bill Gates internet crazy, and, as a result,
Microsoft launched the browser that
today everyone hates, Internet Explorer.
That's it. Without Netscape, who knows
where the internet would be today?
They figured out a way to make
websites significantly more interactive
at a time where most people thought the
internet didn't really have much potential,
and they invented the first way to
securely operate online, which enabled
the first e-commerce websites, and then
last of all, it poked the eye of the reigning
tech giant Microsoft into creating a competing
project that advanced the internet even further.
So what happened to Netscape and this
very eccentric founder, known as Marc Andreessen?
Well, Netscape, they got destroyed and eventually folded.
Turns out, back in the 90s, everyone used a PC,
and that meant that everyone used Windows,
which meant that all Microsoft really had to do was
include their own browser in their operating system.
Netscape really couldn't compete with that and they folded.
Microsoft then went on to get sued for what was pretty obviously
an illegal use of monopolistic behavior, and the rest is history.
Eventually, a bunch of nerds at Google
wanted to create a browser-based email,
but they weren't really happy
with the current options of browsers,
and thus Google Chrome was born.
Hurray for history!
Ok, I'll see you guys in the next lecture.