All right, welcome back.
Let's lurch further into time and get
closer to things that are interesting.
So how is it that a black command screen
got to where we are today?
Well, there's a really long answer, and then
there's the answer I'm going to give you.
And the answer is: because Steve Jobs.
As is so often the answer to questions
in Silicon Valley, "because Steve Jobs"
is actually an easy and not too
oversimplified way of explaining this.
All right, so in the 1980s, we had two dueling stars,
we had Sir Bill Gates and Sir Steven Jobs.
They weren't fighting over the iPod versus the Zune,
or the iPad versus
whatever the Microsoft tablet was called,
they were fighting over something entirely different.
They were fighting over how to make MS-DOS,
that black screen operating system
we just talked about, and other similar operating systems better.
Well, the idea came to Steve Jobs
one day while staring out the window,
and after hours of number crunching on a whiteboard.
I'm actually entirely kidding.
The idea just came when he stole it
from a company named Xerox.
You see, back in the day, Xerox
- remember the X-E-R-O-X
- they didn't just make printers
that lied about being low on toner.
They made all sorts of computers and operating systems,
and they did actually a lot of stuff.
Their biggest innovation was something
called the GUI, or which is pronounced,
I'm not even joking, "gooey". Yes, "gooey."
GUI stood for Graphic User Interface.
Keep in mind, up until this point, operating
systems were text based user interfaces.
GUIs were Graphic User Interfaces.
Xerox decided, "Hey, why not make a visual
representation of the file system on a computer,
and then create a clicking little plastic piece
that you could use to navigate everything."
Believe it or not, this is actually a radical way of thinking.
If you lived in a world of just text commands,
and I said, "Hey, let's do text commands,
but instead of text let's only use images,"
you would probably look at me
similar to the way an Amish person looks at a cell phone.
In one of the biggest business strategy
face palms of all time, Xerox, for some reason,
invited Steve Jobs to come see this brand new experimental GUI.
Steve said "Thanks, this is interesting,
and I'm not at all going to copy it"
and then proceeded promptly to copy it,
but add the one thing we all agree
that was great about Steve Jobs
- he knew how to package things in a way
that regular consumers would appreciate,
and more importantly, buy.
Using his product design orientation
and his absolute disgust with things
that were over complicated, he came out
with the first graphic user interface,
with what he called Macintosh.
The GUI in this case could translate images
and mouse clicks, it could translate
motion on the screen, and opening things
down to lower level machine code.
As an interpreter, operating systems
were getting considerably better.
We went from just text to actual image manipulation.
Really, the rest is history.
Bill Gates then decided to steal that same idea from Steve Jobs,
spawning the movie "Pirates of Silicon Valley."
Graphics got more complicated,
processes got somewhat simplified,
and a new breed of software bloomed under GUIs.
Software could use images, and buttons,
and form fields, and pretty much
everything we today think of with operating systems.
Now, today there are three main operating
systems that you need to be aware of.
There's Windows, there's Macintosh OS, for operating system,
and there's that penguin thing called Linux.
Now, Windows is the brain child of Microsoft and
the first graphic user interface to really catch fire in the 90s.
Back in the 90s, very few people actually used Macintoshes.
Yes, hipsters sat in coffee shops using ]N*gasp* Windows operated laptops.
Well, I mean, it's kind of an exaggeration, because
they didn't have laptops, but they didn't use Macs.
The point here, believe it or not, is that
once upon a time, Windows was cool.
Now, Windows' basic mission statement
was to make an operating system
that appealed to everyone.
People who were not technical
could learn how to use Windows
relatively easily, which is still true.
Those that were technical, or who wanted
to really learn how to use their computer
were offered pretty much unlimited tools and
options for digging in and customizing it.
In the 90s, as computers were still a novelty,
sales relied heavily
on that second type of user, what we
who wear the suits call power users.
Computers, remember, used to be just for hobbyists,
because they were so hard to use.
With more accessible software though,
more people used it, but it wasn't really
until the 2000s that operating systems were being accessed
by the full spectrum of the human population.
In the 90s, you could pretty much get away
without owning a computer.
If you don't own a computer now, well,
yeah, you're probably Amish,
or one of those people that wear
the top hats and the curls.
I'm also assuming there's no Amish watching,
I'm sure it's a safe assumption.
So with this demographic shift,
Steve Jobs and his characteristic impatience
with complicated things came to the forefront yet again.
By restricting his operating system, known as Mac OS,
and making it dead simple to use,
the legions of non-technical people finally felt a little bit
more comfortable using a personal computer.
I'm talking about people like my mom.
You see, in the Steve Jobs operating system,
there is no start button.
There are no such things as drivers that you have to install.
You want to uninstall something?
There's no uninstall script, you just drag it into the trash.
Want to protect yourself from viruses?
Well, then spend hours studying which antivirus software is best.
I'm actually kidding, Macintosh OS
automatically protects you from viruses.
Mac OS was everything Steve Jobs loved.
One, it was simple.
Two, it was aesthetically pleasing,
and three, it locked you into a pretty
but overpriced clam shell device.
This combination, with the addition and
popularity of the iPod and the iPhone,
pushed Mac usage in market share
close to around the same as Windows.
Today the two are still by far the most
popular ways to get your computing done.
It's a bit like the Capulets and the Montagues.
Everyone who cares about computers
in any way has a strong opinion
about which operating system they prefer and why,
but it's important to understand why
they came about and what they changed.
Now, while this horse jockeying between
Windows and Mac OS was happening,
there was a third option that was being built on the side.
That was called Linux.
Linux was the "third way", the Gary Johnson, so to speak,
and it was built by and relied on
by a small group of dedicated enthusiasts.
Now the idea behind the Linux operating system
was that it was going to be
completely free and completely un-restricted.
There was no large company with shareholders
that they had to satisfy behind this system
and anyone using it could modify virtually anything they wanted.
Linux was the original mainstream example of
the concept that we'll talk about more and later, of "open source."
Nowadays, Linux is used primarily
by people with strong technical backgrounds
that either subscribe heavily to
that open source kind of ideology
or simply want to have a much larger amount
of control over the system they use.
When you meet someone who uses Linux,
it's kind of like meeting
a third party candidate voter
in the U.S. during an election year.
"You voted for who?" I might ask, except with technology.
Now, Linux has come a long way,
obviously, since it first started out.
Nowadays we have all sorts of different versions of Linux,
each with somewhat of a different angle.
Red Hat Linux is a good example,
the first Linux to actually have
a for profit company behind its development.
A couple of other ones worth knowing,
like Ubuntu and Fedora
were the first I know to start emulating Windows in more of an
attempt to get average users to come on board using it.
Worth noting, and this is something
we'll get to later in the course,
Linux is the dominating operating system for server technology.
If you ever installed a server
for serving websites (probably not),
there's a good chance that it uses Linux.
We'll cover that, why and how that happened later.
All right, let's recap it.
Today, we, for the most part, have three main
operating systems for personal computers:
Windows, Macintosh OS, and Linux.
Windows was the champion in the 90s
and tried to be the one-size-fits-all for all customers.
It's not hard to use and if you want to customize it,
you have a decent set of options.
Now, Mac OS, on the other hand, in the last ten years or so,
has evolved as a response to
the Windows popularity of the 90s.
Mac OS is a much simpler and more restricted version of an operating system
that followed the basic idea of
"Why give someone ten buttons
when they realistically only use three?"
It also was a mirror image of its larger than life founder
who liked things pretty, simple, and closed off.
Great for a computer, terrible for an OkCupid profile.
The last one is Linux, which is kind of the rebel third party
that focused on being free and completely unrestricted.
You can do really almost anything
you want with Linux, except figure out
how to open a basic application, or find that file you just saved.
That second part is why it never really caught on
with the majority of the earth human populations.
All right guys, that's enough about operating systems.
See you in the next lecture!