Hello and welcome to this art tutorial in the British Statoil we imported our mall dataset and we prepared
our data correctly by taking the two columns we are interested in the annual income and spending score
.
So we created this variable x that contains these two columns and now things are going to get much more
interesting because in this tutorial we are going to build our DNA program and we will use it to find
the optimal number of clusters exactly like we did in the Cayman section where as you remember in step
two we use the elbow method chart to find the optimal number of clusters.
Well here in hierarchical clustering Step two we will also look for this optimal number of clusters
.
Only this time we're not going to use the other method.
We are going to use the then program.
So let's do that right now.
The very cool thing about it is that we only need one line of code to build this program.
So let's write it let's write this line of code.
We start by creating a variable then program then equals and then we're going to use a class H class
.
So let's type each class here and then let's press F 1.
And here we have all the info of this age class class.
So let's look at the arguments here we only need the first two arguments.
The first argument is a dissimilarity structure as produced by this and in our case this parameter is
going to be the distance matrix of our dataset X which is a matrix that tells for each pair of customers
the Euclidean distance between the two.
So that means that for each pair of customers we take the two coordinates annual income and spending
score and we compute the Euclidean distance between the two.
Based on these coordinates.
OK so that was just to explain the first parameter of the H class class.
And so let's put it in our code.
We input d'Este and in parenthesis X come up and then method equals Euclidean so that specifies that
we want to compute the unity and distance matrix for our data X..
OK so that's the first parameter.
This distance matrix and now the second parameter is the method.
So this method is simply the method used to find the clusters and like in Python we're going to choose
the most common method which is the word method.
Here it's called word dot D and it's actually a method that is trying to minimize the variance within
each cluster.
Kind of like would we didn't k when we were trying to minimize the willing cluster sum of squares.
Well here it's based on the same idea but instead of trying to minimize the within close the sum of
squares we are trying to minimize the within cluster variance to find our clusters.
So here we write method equals word darty.
So that is the end of the line to build this dense program.
And now we just need to plot it.
So just below we are going to write plot then in parenthesis then program then let's give it a title
by typing main equals paste parenthesis then program in quotes.
Then let's give a name to the x axis by adding x love equals customers.
Because in the dead program all our customers are going to be on the x axis and then finally let's give
a name to our White Label.
We're going to call it Euclidean distances and that's because in the dental gram The vertical lines
that we're going to see are actually the Euclidean distances of the closer's that is between the centroid
of the clusters.
OK so we're good to go with our A-plot.
So and our dental gram actually.
So let's select all this code section here executes.
And here is our den program.
So let's have a look at it.
I'm clicking on zoom here to make it bigger.
OK.
And now let's try to find the optimal number of clusters.
Thanks to this tent program.
So as Cuil explains in the intuition section to find this optimal number of clusters we need to find
the largest vertical distance that we can make without crossing any other horizontal line.
And then we just need to count the number of vertical lines at this level.
OK.
So let's start by finding the largest vertical distance.
So it's not here obviously then maybe this one it's quite a large distance that would actually give
us three clusters because as you can see here I'm crossing three vertical lines.
Definitely not this one.
And here we have another large distance you see from this point to this point is quite a large distance
and then below obviously we don't have any large distance.
So now the question is what is the largest distance between this distance and this distance.
Well if you have a better look at it we can see that the largest distance is actually this distance
.
And how many vertical lines do we have at this level.
Let's see one two three four and five.
So that means the optimal number of clusters is five clusters and that's of course a relief because
that's what we obtained with the Kamins algorithm using the elbow method.
So everything is fine everything is perfectly coherent.
So we welcome our second step and now we are ready to move on to the next step which is to fit our hierarchical
clustering algorithm to our data X. And that's what we will be doing in the next tutorial.