Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So in the previous tutorial we imported the dataset and today in this tutorial we're going to implement
the UCB upper conference bound algorithm.
So I'm not sure if it's bad news or good news but there is actually no package that we can use easily
to implement this UCB algorithm.
So that's the bad news.
But the good news is that we are going to implement the UCB from scratch and that's good news because
that will give you the opportunity to really improve your skills in our.
So be ready.
It's not going to take three or four lines like we used to have before we are going to implement the
whole algorithm from scratch without using any package.
And we are going to do it step by step.
And speaking of steps let's now actually jump to the slide of the upper confidence found algorithm.
So this algorithm takes three steps.
The first step is at each round and we consider two numbers for each add.
That is for each version of the add these two numbers are and I the number of times the ad I was selected
up to round and the sum of rewards of the adversion I have two round.
OK.
So the first thing that we need to do here is to declare these two variables because we will need them
afterwards.
OK.
So the first one the number of times that I was selected to round and let's actually call this variable
numbers of selections.
All right.
So we need to consider this number for each.
So what we're going to do is create a vector that will contain each of those numbers of selections of
each add.
So we will set this variable equal to a vector of size D and we will initialize all the components of
this vector to zero.
And so how can we do that in our.
Well we simply need to type integer and in parenthesis D.
And this will create a vector of size D containing only zeroes and we're doing this because of course
at the first round each version of the ad hasn't been selected yet.
So the number of times each version of the album selected is of course zero.
OK so done for the first number.
All right.
And the second number is the sum of rewards of the add up to round and.
OK so let's call this variable sons of rewards this way and same you know we need to take the sums of
rewards of each version of the ad at a trial.
And so we're going to set it as a vector of the components as well exactly like we did for numbers of
selections and same we will initialize it to zero.
Because of course at the first round the sons of rewards are each version of the ad is of course zero.
So we will just copy this copy and paste it here.
All right.
So basically step one done.
Now let's move on to Step Two.
Step two is from these two numbers.
We compute first the average reward of an eye up to around and.
And second the confidence interval that's round.
And so basically we need to compute these two numbers at each round.
And so let's implement this step two since we need to compute these two numbers at each round.
And of course what we need to do is to make a for loop.
All right so that's what we're going to do.
We're going to go through all the rounds from 0 to the 10000 round.
So for each round.
And so we're calling the rounds.
And then now we need to input the lower bound which is one.
So that's the first round.
And then the upper bound which is.
And so and is the total number of rounds that is 10000 rounds so in case you have a problem with more
rounds or more users we will you know declare this variable here and equals while here for our problem
it's ten thousand.
All right 10000.
So right now we're in the loop.
And so what do we need to do.
We need to compute for each version of the at the average you are.
And the confidence interval.
So that's exactly what we're going to do.
And since we're doing it for each version of the ad I will what we need to do now is again another for
loop and this time we're going to loop over all the 10 different versions of the ad.
So the ads are indexed by i.
So for I here in one and then again we're going to input here D.
In case you have more versions of your ADD or more arms for your specific problem.
So we are going to declare a new variable here which is D.
And since it's the number of ads we will set it equal to 10.
All right and now we're entering into the second loop so right now at this level we are at a specific
round and dealing with a specific version of the ad and now we can compute our two numbers.
The average word of the eye and the confidence interval.
So let's start with the first number the first number is the average word.
So let's call it average reward and equals.
All right.
So what does it say it says that it's the sum of rewards of the adversion I up to around and divided
by the number of times this adversion I was selected at around.
And so simply let's write this formula.
We already have these two variables where we have to vectors but of course we will take the ice element
of these two vectors because they correspond to our version.
I have the add.
So let's do it sums of rewards and we take the element of this vector divided by numbers.
Selections and same we're taking the element of this vector.
Great.
So we have our first number computed the average word.
Now let's take care of the second number.
The confidence interval Well we will not build the whole confidence interval which we will compute right
now is the upper bounds of the confidence interval because that's what we need for Step 3.
As you can see Step three is we select the app that has the maximum upper confidence bounds so we just
need the upper confidence bounds of this confidence interval.
And so what is this upper confidence bound.
Well it's the average reward plus delta I and and Delta and it's given by this formula it's the square
root of 1.5 LUGG and divided by an N which is the number of times the adversion I was selected to round
in.
So let's compute this delta first and then we'll compute the upper confidence bound.
So Delta will cut its actually delta on this core.
And so its equal to square root which I call s q r t.
Parenthesis here.
OK so what do we have first.
We have this three divided by two 10 times and then we take the log.
So log here and in that we divide by the numbers of selections of the adversion plie that is number
of times the adversion I was selected up to round and.
OK so great for Delta Delta is ready and therefore now we are ready to compute the upper confidence
bounds which is of the essence of this UCB algorithm.
So let's do it let's compute the UCD and let's call it upper bound this way upper bounds equals average
reward
plus delta.
Exactly like in the slide.
OK so great.
We just computed the average reward and the upper bounds and therefore we are done with step 2.
So now let's move on to Step Three.
Step three is to select the add the adversion I that has the maximum upper bound.
So now things get a little more complicated because we need to actually create a vector a huge vector
like a huge list that will contain the different versions of the ADD that were selected at each round.
So let's do this.
We're going to declare here a new variable that we're going to call an underscore selected and this
variable is going to be the huge vector that will give us the list of all the different versions of
the ad that are selected at each front.
That is you know at the end of the algorithm when we run it the ADD selected will be a vector of 10000
elements and each of these elements will be the ad that was selected at each round.
So we will clearly see the results of the strategy used by the algorithm.
OK.
So as usual we need to initialize this and we are simply going to initialize it as NMT vector because
what we'll do next is to append the different AD's one by one up to the last round round 10000.
OK so now the question is how are we going to append the different versions of the add in this at selected
vector.
Well let's go back to the slide.
Step three is we select the ADD either has the maximum upper confidence bounds.
So we already computed the preconditions bound.
And now we need to create another variable that will be the highest upper confidence bounds because
right now this upper bound variable here is just the upper bound for each of the diversions of the ADD
at round end.
And so that's why we need to create another variable that will take the maximum of these upper bounds
here of the 10 adds at round.
And so let's create this new variable and we're going to call it Max upper bound.
So since this smacks of preven variable is going to be different at each round.
Well we need to initialize it at each new round.
So therefore this voidable Max upper bound will be initialized right here.
So we will initialize this Max upper bound variable here to zero.
And then what happens is that we will compute the difference upper bounds of each of the 10 adds and
then we will compare these upper bound to this Max upper bound.
And each time the upper bound of the ad I hear will be higher than max upper bound.
Then we will set max upper bound equals two upper bound.
So that's the idea.
So let's do that right now.
So basically what we have to do here is in this for loop we need to add a new IF condition and this
condition will be if upper bound larger than max upper bound.
And then what happens if upper bound is larger than the max upper bound.
Then we need to set max upper bound equal to upper bound.
This way you know what will happen is that we will compute the different upper bounds of each of the
10 adds that's round.
And at first this smacks of revelant is equal to zero.
Then we compute the first upper bound.
And of course it will be larger than max of rebound because it's equal to zero.
So the next upper bound will be equal to upper bound.
So that's for the first add and then we will compute the other upper bounds of the other ads.
And each time we find an upper bound that is larger the next upper bound than max or pre-ban will be
equal to this new upper bound.
All right.
So this way we will get the maximum of the different upper bounds of the 10 x at the specific round.
And all right and now we need to do one more thing you know we need to select the ADD that has the highest
upper bound and therefore each time we find this upper bound to be larger than the max upper.
Not only we need to do this to keep the max rebound but also we need to keep track of the index that
has the max rebound and to keep track of this index.
What we need to do here is to create a new variable here which we'll call add and we will make it equal
to I.
Because right now we are dealing with a specific ad because we are at a specific eye of this for I loop
here.
And so I hear has a specific value that corresponds to a specific ad and so we need to keep track of
this specific add each time we find another band that is larger than the max or we're bound to become
this new max of rebound.
All right.
So that's great.
But you know when we use a new variable here it's always important to initialize it.
So that's what we'll do right now.
We will initialize this as variable.
We will initialize it to zero.
OK.
So we're getting close.
Now what we need to do is deal with the initial conditions because this is what happens that round.
And you know this is the strategy that happens at round and but this is actually not what happens at
the beginning because at the beginning you know during the 10 first rounds we don't have much information
yet.
We don't have much information about their reward whether they earned reward equals one or reward equals
zero.
When we selected them because simply we haven't selected them yet.
So that's why we need to deal with the initial conditions that is choose which as we will select during
the 10 first rounds.
And so according to you what will be the strategy to select the asterisk to 10 rounds given the fact
that we don't have any information.
Well there is actually no strategy.
We will simply select the 10 first ads without using the strategy here.
We will use this strategy as soon as we have some informations of the reward of each of the 10 ads.
So basically what we will do during the first 10 rounds is to simply select the 10 first ads that is
run one will select Add one round to will select to run three We'll select at 3 up to around 10.
We'll select at 10 and then that will give us some information about you know the number of selections
of each of the 10 as well.
That's round 11 the number of selections will be one for each of the 10 at and we'll also get some information
about the sums of rewards that some of your words will contain either zeroes corresponding to the go
to zero reward when they were selected during the first round or ones corresponding to the ads that
go to one reward when they were selected during the first 10 rounds.
So let's do it now let's simply select one two three up to 10 during the first ten rounds and then let's
use the strategy so to do this we will add that if condition here which will be if numbers of selections
by is larger than zero.
So that means if the version I was selected at least once then we will use this strategy and actually
we need to align this.
And so now thanks to this condition here the strategy will be applied after the 10 first rounds.
OK.
And now we just need to add a little something to make sure that the algorithm selects one or two at
three to 10 during the ten first round.
And to do this the trick is to add an else here else and then we will set the upper bound to a very
large value like 10.
And the power of 400.
So to get this we can use one three four hundred and that's 10 to the power of 400.
So now I'd like to give you a little enigma.
I would like you to figure out why we're using this very large and you turn the power of 400 for the
upper bound here in the else condition try to figure out why trying to figure out how it will be useful
for what we want.
And now you get the answer and the explanation in the next to Torro.
Until then enjoy machine learning