I other friends.
I ready to build that convolutional neural network.
We have a long but yet very exciting journey ahead of us.
Let's do this.
Let's kick this off.
All right.
So we're going to start with the very essential step, empowering the libraries, which will only consist
of importing sense of flow and actually the preprocessing module by the Keris library.
So let's do this for us quickly and efficiently in a new Kotel.
So actually, you know how to import Tenzer flow.
We start with the import command and we specify the name of the library Tensor Flow.
And we add this shortcut.
T.F. Just like before with the Eynon.
Then I would like to import something else which will allow us to do the image preprocessing in part
one in which is the image.
Module of the preprocessing module of the Keris library.
And therefore here we're going to start from.
Well, the Keris library from which we're gonna get access to the pre prah siccing module from which
we're going to import the image sub submodular.
And the reason why we want to import this is because we want to import a specific class, which is the
image data generator.
And I will explain very quickly what this is about.
But this is absolutely compulsory.
In part one, data processing, you know, when preprocessing your images.
So that's important.
Here we just need to add import and then image data generator.
OK, good.
I will explain very soon what this is about and how we will use it.
All right.
And then, you know, this other thing that I like doing just to show you that indeed we are working
with Tenderfoot 2.0.
I just want to print the version of tensor flow we're using right now.
And remember, to do this, we need to call center flow first and then after a dot, a double underscore
and then version and double on the core again.
And this will, you know, print in the output, the version of tend to flow.
We're using this is just to make sure we're working with 10th floor 2.0.
However, you know, depending on when you're on this code, you know, after a record is tutorial,
you might have a different version, but you will definitely get a sense of flow to version.
OK.
All right.
So here I just executed the first cell in boring tend to flow end image repressing Modulate Kiraz.
And now let's run this to indeed reassure ourselves that we are working with of Flow 2.0, which is
so much better than tons of low one.
All right, good.
So now we can move on to part one data repressing, which will be done in two steps.
First, repricing the training set and second, preprocessing the test set.
So let's start with the training set and let's create a new coattail.
And now let me explain how we're gonna do this.
All right.
So how are we going to pre-process our images?
Well, we're actually going to do multiple things.
The first thing we'll do is we will apply some transformations on all the images of the training set.
The images of the training set only we want apply these same transformations on the test.
The reason why we want to apply some transformations on the images of the training set is for only one
purpose.
It is to avoid overfilling.
Indeed, if we don't apply these transformations well when training our CNN on the training set, we
will get a huge difference between the accuracy on the training set and the one on the test set.
On the evaluation set, actually, we will get very high accuracy on the training set, you know, close
to 98 percent and much lower accuracy on the test.
And that is Scott Overfitting.
And that's something we absolutely need to avoid.
Anyway, you know, whether you're working on a classic data set or working for a computer vision and
for computer vision.
Well, the way to avoid overfilling is, as I said, to apply transformations.
So that was the way.
And now let me explain the what you know, what are these transformations?
And then I will proceed in the end to the how how we're gonna implement that.
So the what what are these transformations is.
Well, some simple geometrical transformations or some zooms or some rotations on your images.
So basically, we're gonna apply some geometrical transformations like transaction's to shift some of
the pixels.
Then we're gonna rotate a bit.
The images, we're gonna do some horizontal flips.
We're gonna do some zoom in and zoom out.
Well, you know, we're going to play a series of transformation so as to modify the images and get
them, as we say, augmented.
In fact, the technical term of what we're gonna do now, you know, with all these transformations
is called image augmentation, which consists basically of transforming your images of the training
set so that your CNN model doesn't overlearned, you know, is not overtrained on the existing images,
because by applying these transformations, we will get new images, which is the reason.
Why we call this image augmentation.
We basically augment the variety.
You know, the diversity of the training set images.
All right.
So that is the what?
And now we're going to proceed to the how to proceed to the how.
I'm gonna take you to the Keris API because you have to see it.
You know, just like what we did with Cycad Learn.
I'm going to show you and guide you through the Curse API to find the exact tool we're gonna use for
this.
So let's open a new tab here.
There we go.
And in the search bar, let's enter just keris crassly that lets press enter and let's just get the
first link.
There is only one cares.
And that's, of course, a deep learning library in Python developed by France specially.
By the way, a very talented French data scientist.
All right.
So let's go now to API docs and now, my friends.
Welcome to the Keris API.
This is probably my favorite deep learning library.
It's absolutely fantastic.
And now where we want to go is, of course, to data preprocessing, which includes, of course, three
things.
Actually, you have to know it image the repricing, which is what we're about to use right now.
But then also time series data pricing and also text data pricing.
You can also do some deep and help, you know, an LP with deploying with carers.
But now, of course, we're looking for something in image data repressing.
And let me show you exactly what that something is.
We just need to scroll down.
Well, actually, you already know what this is, because we already import the class.
But there it is.
I'm talking, of course, about the image data generator class, which will indeed generate batches
of tensor image data with real time data augmentation, which is exactly what I've just explained.
And I haven't mentioned the batches yet.
Well, that's because, you know, we will create different batches of actually 32 images.
And these images will either be the original ones or, you know, the augmented ones, the transformed
ones after we apply the transformations.
And speaking of applying these transformations, well, we're going to do that exactly with this image
data generator, Class four, which will find all the arguments here.
And, you know, most of them correspond to different transformations.
I can already tell you that we will use the zoom range, which consists of zooming in or zooming out
on the images.
But also we'll use the horizontal flip, which consists of flipping the images horizontally.
And then we will also use this one to shear range, which is some kind of transaction.
You can check it online.
But no need to understand this.
And all the details just know that it's a geometrical transformation.
And if you want to go further than it's actually some kind of transaction.
But there we go.
These are the three transformations we'll use the sheer range, the zoom range and the horizontal flip.
And now I'm sure some of you are asking, why do we use these transformations?
Well, I'll be honest with you.
The reason I'm using them is because I simply took, you know, the code snippet example from Keris,
which is right below exactly here.
This is the code snippet example using image data generator class.
And as you can see, we use sharing transformation, a zoom transformation in a horizontal flip transformation.
And we're just gonna do the same.
But, of course, feel free to try some other transformations.
Who knows, maybe you'll get better accuracy Indians.
Okay, but let's just trust this.
And actually, I chose this because, of course, I tried it on our future CNN, which we're about to
build.
And you're going to see that the results in the end will be absolutely amazing.
Okay, so let's just take this let's just take this code snippet to, you know, actually get a tool
that will apply these transformations.
Then, of course, we'll have to connect a tool to our training set.
So back into our implementation.
Well, let's base that right here.
And this, as you can see, it creates an object which we call trend data gen up the image data generator
class.
A trained data gen is an instance of that image data generator class in which represents, of course,
the tool that will apply all the transformations on the images of the training set.
And there is one I haven't mentioned.
You know, I mentioned and explained these three ones, which are the transformations.
But we also notice this one rescale equals one divided by 255.
Can you guess what this is about?
You know, we already saw this many times on our classic data set.
Well, this is, of course, about feature scaling.
This will apply feature scaling to each and every single one of your pixels by dividing their value
by 255.
Because remember that each pixel takes a value between zero and 255.
So by dividing all of them by 255, we indeed get all the pixel values between zero and one, which
is just like a normalization.
And once again, features going is absolutely compulsory for neural networks.
You know, when training neural networks.
All right.
So basically, this is feature scaling and.
These are the transformations that will perform image augmentation on the images of the training set.
And this I remain is in order to prevent overfilling.
In the end, you can try actually, you know, the future training will have without these and you will
see what I mean by overfitting.
All right, good.
So that's not it.
That's not it.
You know, the training set repricing.
We need to, of course, now connect that train data gen object to our training set, you know, to
our training set images so far.
This is just the object.
And so the way we're going to do this is we will, of course, go back to our Keris API, because indeed,
the way to do this is just to take this next code here that will actually import the training set by
accessing it from, you know, our directory and at the same time creating these batches and resizing
the images.
Now, in case we need to resize them in order to reduce the computations of the machine, you know,
to make it less compute intensive, which is what we all do, because we will see that with a lower
size will still get amazing results in the end.
So let's get this.
And once again, I will explain all this code.
And mostly we will have to change it the right way so that we can adapt it indeed to our situation.
So let's take it step by step.
This is actually the name you want to give to your training set, which you are importing in the notebook.
And let's just give the usual names.
We're going to call that training underscore set just like before.
Then we take indeed our trained data agent object.
That instance of the image data generated class.
And from this object, we're going to call a method of this class.
Right.
Because this class is every class contains methods.
And one of them is this flow from directory, which will just simply, you know, connect this image
augmentation tool to the images of your training set.
All right, then let's have a look at the different parameters.
So the first one here is actually the path leading to your training set.
And so, of course, we have to change this because we have a different path to our data set.
So this is a whole folder which I've shared with you at the beginning of this section.
And this is also the root folder.
You know, this is the base of the folder.
You know, the beginning of the path.
And so now, in order to access the training set, well, we first need to specify that we want to go
into this data set folder and then into this training set folder.
And that's exactly the past leading to the training set.
And therefore, here, you know, in this parameter of the flow from directory function, well, we
simply need to replace data here by data set and then train here by training set.
All right.
This is a simple path leading to the train folder.
Starting from the root of our directory folder.
OK.
Good.
Now, next argument, target size.
That's indeed the final size of your images.
One day, you know, will be fed into the convolutional neural network.
And actually, I tried with 150 by 150.
And that actually made the training very, very long.
So I actually wanted to reduce that to, you know, 64 by.
64.
And that Stolley fine.
This will make the training much faster.
And still we will have amazing results.
You'll see that again.
Then the batch sizes, you know, the size of the batches, meaning how many images we want to have
in each batch.
And the 32 is a classic default value.
And we're going to keep that.
It will be totally fine.
And finally, we have to specify the class mode, which is either binary or categorical.
And of course, since now we have a binary outcome, you know, cat or dog.
Well, we have to choose, of course, class mode equals binary.
Okay, perfect.
And that closes the preprocessing of the training set.
We're done with this first step of decompressing.
And so now we're gonna move on to the next step.
Preprocessing detests it.
And of course, in the spirit of always, be as much efficient as we can.
Well, we're going to go back to our Keris API and we're just gonna take this time.
This line of code to get that same image data generator object to, you know, apply to transformation's
to the test images.
But be careful, we're not going to apply the same transformation's here, such as a sheering the zoom
in the horizontal flip, because, of course, we don't want to touch the test images because they're
are like new images.
Like when deploying our model in production.
And therefore, of course, we have to keep them intact like the original ones.
However, what we have to do to them is indeed to rescale their pixels.
And that's the same as before, you know.
Remember when we were applying feature scaling to our training set and test set?
Well, we used the fit transfer method on the training set, but only the trend for method on the test
set.
And that was, of course, to avoid information leakage from the test set.
And while here, that's exactly the same, we have to keep the images of the test intact by not applying
any transformation.
However, we have to feature scale them because once again, the future predict method of CNN will have
to be applied to the same scaling as the one that was applied on the training set.
So you see, this is exactly the same as before, is just that we are using some different classes,
but which are, after all, the same tools.
All right.
So let's get this and let's put that back into our implementation in a new coattail.
So we're going to paste that.
We're going to keep the same name for the object.
That's solely fun.
And then.
Well, same.
We're gonna go back to this and we're going to get exactly this, which will actually import the test,
set images into our notebook.
All right.
So let's face that.
And now let's do the required change.
Actually, please press pause in the video and do the changes yourself.
I'm sure you're going to do this successfully because this is exactly the same as before.
All right.
So now let's do it together.
The first thing I would like to do is just change its name, which is exactly the name of the variable
that will contain the test set.
And just to be consistent with before.
Well, let's just go the test set.
All right.
So test set.
Then.
This is correct.
We call our test data.
Here, which will only apply if it is going to the pixels of the test images.
Then we call that same function flow from directory to access the test set from our directory.
And here once again, we need to replace data here by data set and then validation by, you know, remember.
Now we want to get the path that leads to the test set and therefore that first dataset and then test
set.
All right.
So here we just need to replace validation by test set.
Good.
Then, of course, we need to have the same target size because basically the brick method has to be
called on the exact same format as the one that was used for the images of the training.
So here we need to get the same size as in the training set.
Therefore, 64 by 64.
And the same batch size.
Basically, our will be evaluated on batches of 32 images.
And of course, the same class mode.
Binary.
Good.
Well, there you go.
We're done with data processing.
It was very different.
It was actually brand new.
But we recognize some of the same process steps as what we did before.
And so now I'm very excited because we can move onto the exciting part, which is about building the
CNN.
Yes, we are ready for part two now, which we're going to tackle on several steps.
And so make sure to get good energy for this.
And as soon as there is a case, join me in a next story or to smash design.
Part two building to CNN.
And until then, enjoy machine learning.