Hello and welcome to this art it's toil.
So this story was not going to be like the usual ones because basically what we're going to do is just
make a template in order to build our future classification models more efficiently because indeed we
already built our first classification model which is the logistic regression model and then the future
sections we're going to build a new classification morals like that as VM support vector machine kernel
SVM Navy base decision tree classification as well as Ranum first classification.
And so you know we will build these models in the same data set the social network as data set.
And so we will make one templates for all our future classification models.
So right now let's make our classification template.
And maybe you already noticed that we we're going to make this template very easily because the only
part of the code where we cut something specific to logistic regression is only in this part because
we use the GNN function to create our logistic regression classifier.
But then in the other sections everything is purely generalized.
You know we use our classify variable here which is indeed an Disko the logistic regression transpired
within the next sections.
This classifiers is going to be something else and same in this section here we don't code anything
specifically related to logistic regression.
Same in this section here about the visualization of the training that results.
The only variable that we use is classifier.
So nothing directly related to logistic regression and same for this section here.
And so if we give another definition to classify here then this code here will be perfectly adaptable
to this new class I will be making in the future sections.
So that's why it's so simple and therefore it's worth doing that for the next models will be creating
.
So I'm going to take everything from here to the bottom.
Copy and paste it here in my future classification templates and now our classification template is
almost ready.
We just need to remove this section here because this is directly related to logistic regression because
here we are using the GNN function that is only used to build a logistic regression model.
But you know in the next sections for the next classifiers we'll be making.
Well we'll have this classified variable here that will be the classifier of our future classification
models.
And then here you know we'll use the right function needed to build this classification model and then
all the rest will be ready.
We will have our new classifier defined here then since we have Caspari here and predict function well
we won't have anything to change here and simpler here and simpler here as well because the only variable
that we use is classifier.
And that will be defined as the classifier of a new classification model.
So let's remember that and let's you know to remind us of what we need to do.
I'll just add a come here to say that it's the section where we create our classifier here.
All right.
So that's the section where you create your classifier.
And by the way you can totally use the same place on your data sets and your business problems you will
just need to change the name of the data set and pick your columns of interest and then just change
the name of the depan variable here and here as well.
But then what you will only need to do is to create your classifier here so you will pick the classify
you want and then everything will be ready.
You will be able to predict that as a result you will be careful of the index here and make the condition
matrix and visualize your training set and test results so you can totally use this template as well
for your data sets.
And definitely this template is ready to build the future classification morals we will build in this
part.
So here we go.
Template ready.
Well we can still generalize it even more by replacing logistic regression here by classifier.
And also we can replace logistic regression here by classifier and here as well.
And now the template is fully ready and fully generalized.
So you will see how it will be so efficient at building the future classification models.
I look forward to creating these models with you.
And until then enjoy machine learning