Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So now let's proceed to the next step of the cleaning process which is about removing all the numbers
from the reviews.
So we will just copy this line and pasted below because you'll see that now doing the next steps of
the kitchen process is going to be very easy because we will always use the same line here to update
the corpus.
And as each new step we are going to apply the right transformation that we want to do for the particular
step of thinking process to the whole corpus thanks to the T.M. map function.
So basically what we just need to do is replace this content transform transformer with two resin put
by remove numbers and that's all we apply.
Just remove numbers functions the reviews and the corpus threw the team up function and that will remove
all the numbers of all the 1000 reviews in the corpus.
So let's check it out to check that out.
We cannot do it with this first review because this first review doesn't contain any number so nothing
will be removed here.
But I had a look at the data sets and there is the review 841 that contains a number.
Let's have a look at this review.
To do this we will use the same line as we used to look at the first review.
So I'm pressing the Abara here to take this line of code that gives us access to the reviews and in
putting the index one here will put the 841 index.
And now let's press enter to have a look at the review and the review is for 40 bucks ahead.
I really expect better food.
So that's a negative review and what should be highlighted in this review is this 40 number here which
we want to see if it's going to be removed once we apply this remove numbers function to the reviews
of the corpus.
So that's all the numbers in the reviews can be removed thanks to the team map function.
So let's check it out.
We will select this line and execute done.
And now let's have a look at this 841 review.
So I'm pressing the up arrow twice to get back to this line of code giving us the original review.
It's now the corpus is updated.
Let's see if the number 40 disappeared and it did 4 bucks ahead.
I really expect better food.
Forty does appear and that's exactly what we wanted.
So great.
Basically all the numbers are now removed from the reviews in the corpus nextstep done and we are ready
to move on to the next step which will be about removing any kind of punctuation in the reviews because
of course in our sparse metrics in the end we don't want to get a call in for a comma or another calling
for a colon or another call for a dot or for a semicolon or any kind of punctuation.
Of course we only want to create some columns for relevant works that will help the machine learning
classification algorithm to see the correlations between the presence of the words and the outcome whether
the review is positive or negative.
All right so let's do that in the next tutorial.
And until then in Germany learning