And finally interpreting coefficients in front of us here we've got the four models that we built in
our backward elimination method.
And as we agreed multiple three is the best one is the best fitted model.
And if we were to deliver a model on our project it would be this one.
So let's go ahead and start in Chippering coefficient by looking at this model.
Here we've got two variables.
R&D spend and marketing spend.
So it's basically how much companies are spending on their research and development and on their marketing
.
And we will also get the constant And we were predicting profit.
So these coefficients here these B 1 and B 2.
What they're telling us is that.
So how how to interpret them.
First of all you look at the sign if the sign is positive that means your variable is correlated with
your independent variable is collated with your dependent variable.
Meaning that if you change the value of your independent variable then the value then you can see that
the dependent variable will be changing in the same direction.
So basically if you'll be increasing spend on R&D then you're profitable be increasing If increasing
spend or marking then your profit is also increasing which makes sense right.
So if you spending more in research and development making a party better than probably your profits
should increase eventually as well.
Same thing with marketing.
The more you spend marketing the more you sell and therefore the profit should also go up.
And that's the sign if the sign is negative if the sign were negative then it's the opposite effect
.
So basically increase your depende variable and you depend variable decreases.
And now let's look at the magnitude.
So here you can see right away that magnitude is higher foreign disband and the magnitude is law for
marking spent magnitude is always tricky were regressions.
Be careful of magnitude sign is kind of you know pretty obvious.
It's either it's one way or the other magnitude can really trip you up.
And I can give you an example here so you might think that OK right away.
Magnitude is greater so this this coefficient for R&D spend is bigger than the market spend coefficient
So definitely R&D spend has a bigger impact.
Well what if I tell you that I could easily fall changing anything in the regression.
I could easily make this coefficient bigger by a law by a thousand times bigger than R&D spend.
Well it's easy to do.
All I have to do is say marketing spend instead of looking at it in dollars.
How about I look at it in a fraction of a cent so every market is all of this could incense so marketing
spend instead of counting an adult is counted and cents right away because our variable has gone down
a hundred times.
All catfish and will proportionally increase so it'll go up a hundred times and if I change my data
and replace everywhere marketing spend half cents and everything else I will leave the same then run
this model I guarantee you that the coefficient here will actually become 2.9 9.
It'll just increase a 100 times.
Everything else will stay the same.
And that way right away you'll see oh wow.
The market is Benke of sions greater so than market has been has a bigger impact on your dependent Berbel
profit and that's a mistake that a lot of beginners make you should not fall into this trap Magot it
is a tricky thing and the way to think about it is always say magnitude in terms of units of the independent
variable.
So the correct way to analyze this is even if not knowing what they're measured and maybe this was measured
in thousands of dollars and this was measured in dollars.
I don't know for instance although I do I do know of course I've seen the data but if say I don't know
the you can still make a conclusion you just have to say this is R&D spend has a greater impact on profit
per unit of R&D spend then marketing then marketing spend has per unit of marketing spend and that's
all.
So basically even if they're measured in different things by saying per unit of the underlying variable
you are protecting yourself from that error that you know they are they are measured in different things
.
And moreover Imagine if they're measured $100 are the ones measured in kilometers or something that
you can compare dollars in kilometers.
Right.
But you can always say per unit.
And this leads us to the actual interpretation of these variables or these coefficients What does it
mean.
So this means 0.7 9 means that for every unit if you keep all other variables constant so you only have
on a verbal So if you keep everything else constant but you are able to adjust R&D spend for in this
model or for it for a hypothetical company for every dollar for every unit of R&D spend that you increase
your profit will increase according to his model your profit will increase by 79 cents.
Thats exactly what this coefficient is saying.
And so for every unit that you decrease in your R&D spend your profit will decrease by seventy point
seventy nine over unit of profit.
And because R&D spend is mission dollars and profit is also $2 that means so for every unit increase
in for every dollar increase in R&D spend your profit will increase in by 79 cents.
So let let me just repeat that again that you are looking at units increase in R&D spend they translate
through this coefficient into units increase in profit.
So if your profit was measured in apples then a 1 dollar increase of 1 unit increase is always going
to be true one unit increase in R&D spend will drive point seventy nine unit increase in profit and
off of course of the profit units.
So lets turn and turn that into dollars and apples a one dollar increase in R&D spend will drive a point
79 or 80 percent of an apple increase in profits.
So here you are talking about units of R&D spend and profit you are talking about units of profit and
this coefficient.
It links them together.
So as long as you say per unit you're fine.
Once you already know what these variables are measured and then you can start comparing them if they're
on the same scale and in this case they are on the same scale because they measured everything is measured
in dollars here and you can say that a dollar increase in R&D spend drives 79 cents dull 79 cents increase
in profit and mark a dollar increase in marketing spend drives only 3 cents increase in profits so basically
if you're the venture capitalist which companies are going to invest in well from this model you're
going to decide that you should invest into companies that are spending more on their R&D.
There may be lots of reasons behind this and this is not just around the fact this could be true in
reality because profit is revenue minus expenses maybe marketing does drive a lot of revenue to a company
but at the same time maybe for these specific companies that were looking at their expense the cost
of marketing so the prices that they pay for mortgages so high that the increase in profit the net increase
in profit is actually marginal.
So the marketing is eating up a lot of the revenue is creating whereas R&D is you know is creating a
lot of revenue and a lot of it is actually staying in profit something like that but were not worried
about that right now thats more financials.
What we're doing is we're delivering a model.
So that's how you interpret coefficients for linear regression.
Very simple.
Just remember about that per unit trick or tip I guess because if you forget about that you can you
know make the wrong conclusions.
Otherwise it's all pretty simple.
The last thing that I wanted to mention here is that you can see that every time we run a model the
coefficients change.
So what that is telling us is that confession's actually only talk about the additional effect of every
single variable given that the other variables are already in place so for instance in this example
you confession of marketing which is to 0.39 is means that given that R&D spend is already in your model
and it's fixed then marketing spend adds additional you know contributes to the additional effect of
0.0 to 9 9.
Meaning that if you were to ring around a different model and take out R&D spend then the coefficient
would be completely different.
And that's what we see here that when we take our marketing the coefficient for R&D spend is Tichenor
.
So that's another thing you should remember about that coefficients merely portray the additional effect
that every single variable brings into the model.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I look for see you next time.
Until then happy analyzing