Hello and welcome to this art to Tauriel.
So so far we've been doing a great deal of simplification for Corpus and therefore for future sparse
matrix features.
But we can still do better and doing better is what we'll do in this tutorial and it's a new step of
thinking process that is called Stenning.
So what is timing.
Well Stenning is about getting the root of each word.
For example if you look at the first review we have this love word here and the root of this word would
be love.
So what is the purpose of getting the root of the word.
Well it's of course still related to our goal to reduce the total number of words that will be in our
future sparse matrix of features and we can do this by taking the route of the words because whether
we have loved or love or will love or loving.
Well this actually means the same thing for algorithm.
And not only it means the same thing but also it gives the same hint whether the review is positive
or negative.
So we don't really need to have some different tenths of one same verb.
And we don't really need to have evaded words.
We just need the root of the words.
And that will be perfectly enough for machine classification model to train on the future sparse matrix
of features that therefore will contain only the roots of the words and you can imagine how we will
considerably reduce the final total number of words.
That is the final total number of columns in the sparse matrix of features because of course by only
keeping the roots of the different versions of the same word.
Well of course that simplifies it very well and therefore it considerably reduces the final total number
of words.
So that's the I mean that's also a very important step in natural language processing.
You will most of the time apply stemming to your text whether you are working with reviews or articles
or books or HMO pages.
Well for any kind of text it really helped your machine learning algorithm to do an even better job
for your classification problem.
So let's do it for our reviews and it is still going to be very simple.
We will do another copy paste here.
So I will actually copy this line because we only needed two parameterless the corpus and a function
that will perform this timing.
So based here and I will replace remove punctuation by the appropriate function to proceed to systemin
which is this term capital D document.
Here it is.
That's the function we use to perform stemming on all the reviews of our corpus.
So let's check it out.
Let's select this line right now.
Our first review is well loved place and you'll see that after stymieing love becomes love.
All right so let's execute now press command and control us and to to execute.
Here we go.
New corpus.
Updated.
And now let's have a look at the first review of this new corpus.
So I'm pressing the bar here to get this line of code and now pressing enter.
And here we go.
Wow.
Love and place so loved was replaced by love because the root of luffed is love.
All right.
So and that's the center all the reviews in all the other reviews.
The words were replaced by their roots.
So that's done for this new step.
And actually we are almost done with the cleaning process.
We have one final step and we will do this final step in the next tutorial until then.
And so machine learning