Hello my friends.
Welcome back.
Now let's learn together how to import a dataset as a reminder we're going to learn how to import the
following data set data that CSB which is a very simple data set of let's say a retail company that
is doing some analysis on which clients purchased one of their products.
So the rows in this dataset correspond to different customers of this employee and for each of these
customers we have the country they live in their age their salary and whether or not they purchased
the product.
Okay so we're going to learn how to import that CSB on Python using of course to Bender's library.
Here we go.
So let's first create a new code cell and now let's import this dataset.
So the first thing we have to do is to create a new variable and these variable will contain exactly
the dataset.
So I always like to choose simple names for my variables representing Well what we're creating.
And therefore since now we're importing the dataset and we want to integrate the data set in a variable
I'm gonna call this variable dataset.
Okay as simple as that.
So this horrible what will it be equal to.
Well it will be equal to the output of a certain function by US and the certain function will exactly
read all the values of this dataset and it will create what we call a data frame.
It's a certain format of data whether it is in Python or even R.
So it will create a data frame and it will contain exactly the same rows and columns and values as what
you see here and this data frame will be exactly this dataset variable.
All right.
So there we go in order to create this data frame we're gonna call a certain function by the bender's
library which is called read on the score CSP.
And in this function we will only have to input the name of the dataset with the extension.
So since we're about to call a function of Bender's while the first thing we have to do is call the
library and therefore remember since we gave it the shortcut named PDC in order to call it we need to
add here PD and then to call a function from a library we need to add a dot it's always done like that
and that's where you can call the function you want to use.
And as we said this function is named read underscore CSB and then you add some parenthesis to enter
the argument.
So there we go.
Let's do this.
This will only what you will have to do when using this read on this course as we function you have
to input in quotes the name of the dataset.
As a reminder the name of the dataset is data with the capital did not see as V.
So there we go data that see as.
Okay.
And this will create the data frame you know all the values inside this data set.
And this data frame will be exactly this data set variable.
Okay.
So that's the first step but that's not enough to import data set you know as a first step of data processing.
The next thing that you have to do is create two new entities.
The first one is the matrix of features.
And the second one is the dependent variable vector.
So let me show you exactly what they mean and where they are in the data set right here.
Okay.
So I'm gonna give you now a very first important principle in machine learning in any dataset with which
you're going to train a machinery model.
You have the same entities which are the features and the dependent variable vector.
Can you guess here.
What are the features and what is the dependent variable.
Well very simply the features are the columns with which you're going to predict the dependent variable
and the dependent variable of course is the last column because you know this company would like to
predict if some future customers are going to purchase a certain product based on these informations.
So very simply the features or also called the Independent bobbles are the variables containing some
information with which you can predict what you want to predict which is called the dependent variable.
All right so remember this very important principle in any machinery model that you're going to build
you're going to have separately.
The features usually in the first columns of your data set and the dependent variable usually in the
last column of your dataset you will see that all the data sets will use in this course and most of
the data is that you'll use in your machinery and career will have the same format with first the features
you know in the first columns and the dependent variable vector in the last column.
Okay.
And so right now what we want to create are the two entities we want to create our first the matrix
of features containing separately these three columns here in a country H salary and separately we want
to create the dependent variable vector containing only this last column because that's the column we
want to predict and that's exactly what we always have to do in this first day to be pressing face.
Let's do this.
Let's create these two entities and we are gonna call them X for the matrix of features and y for the
dependent variable vector.
All right let's do this starting with X..
So how are we going to create X.
Basically that simple we have our data set you know containing exactly all this all these columns.
And in order to create X Well we simply have to take the three first columns of this data set because
you know X will be exactly all these values here.
You know with the three first columns.
And so what we're simply going to do is play with the indexes to collect indeed the indexes of these
three first columns basically of the columns of all the columns of the data set except the last one.
So let's do this.
Let me show you how to do this.
First what you're going to do is take your data set that exact same variable which you created in this
first line of code here.
OK.
Data set then from this data set and I'm adding a dot here because we're about to use a function you
know one of the attribute functions of a Bender's data frame and that function is I look and what will
it allow us to do.
Well as you can see I look here stands for locate indexes and therefore what this function will do is
it will take the indexes of the columns we want to extract from the dataset not only the indexes of
the columns but also the indexes of the rows.
And actually we have to start here with the rows.
We can specify the rows that we want to get and put into x.
And of course these are all the rows you know we want to get all the rows into x.
We only want to take the first columns what we want to keep all the rows.
And the trick to take all the rows whatever data set you have with whatever number of rows is to add
here a column.
Why is that.
Because a colon in Python means a range.
And when we specify a range without the lower bound and neither the upper bound that means in Python
that we're taking everything in the range.
Therefore here all the rows.
So that's the trick to take all the rows and you will always have to take all the rows.
So here you won't have anything to change then.
Now we have to specify which columns want to select with the indexes and to separate the rows that we
just took from the columns we need here to add a comma.
And now we can take care of columns.
All right.
So now I'm going to show you a trick in order to take all the columns except the last one because indeed
as I told you most of the data sets you will use to train new machinery models will have first the features
you know in the first columns and last.
The dependent variable vector in the last column.
So now we're going to use a trick so that we can take automatically you know regardless of the number
of columns in your dataset all the columns except the last one because all the columns except the last
one are exactly the matrix of features.
And the trick to do that is to add a new range here which this time will be colon minus one.
So what does it mean.
Well as we said the colon here means the range.
We know we're taking a range here on the left.
We have nothing that means that we're taking the first index in the index 0 because index is in both
and started zero and then you know we're going up to minus one.
So what does this minus one mean.
Well minus one means here.
The last column minus one in Python means the index of the last column however and that's a very important
principle in Python which you must absolutely know a range in Python includes the lower bound therefore
including here the lower bound 0 0 but excludes the upper bound.
And therefore here we're excluding this index minus one meaning the index of the last column and therefore
what this will do is it will take all the columns excluding the last one and that's exactly what we
want for our matrix of features X..
So voila.
There you go.
Now you just collected the right indexes to create a matrix of Features X and the beauty of this is
that you won't have anything to change when creating the future matrices of features X of your future
datasets but make sure that your future data sets indeed have the features in the first columns and
the dependent viable vector in the last column.
Okay perfect.
So in order to finish this line of code which is not adhere dot values and this just means that we're
taking indeed all the values in all the rows of this data set and in all the columns except the last
one of this dataset.
Perfect.
So now you're learning a lot.
Don't worry if this feels a bit overwhelming at the beginning I promise you that we will use this trick
many many times.
So you will just soon be so familiar with it and master it like a pro.
All right.
And now let's do the same for are dependent variable Victor and you know this will be exactly the same
we'll just have to change one little thing so I'm going to copy this and paste it right here.
And now according to you based on what I've just explained.
What do we have to change here in order to get the dependent variable vector which is most of the time
in our data set indeed the last column.
Okay.
So let's see first.
We have to take our dataset because we want to extract this tax column from our dataset.
Then we have to use I look to collect the indexes of the rows and columns we want then we indeed want
to take all the rows of the data set because we want to take all the purchase decisions of these customers
whether or not they decided to purchase yes or no the product.
So okay we want all the rows but then which comes that we want to get here.
Well we only want to get the last column.
So according to you what is index we need input here in order to get only the last column.
Well this time since we only want to get one column we definitely don't want to get a range and therefore
I'm going to remove the range here.
And then what are we left here.
We're left here with minus 1.
And as I've told you minus 1 is exactly the index of the last column.
So there we go.
That's exactly what we need to create this dependent variable vector.
And thus this line of code is done.
Congratulations.
Now you know how to import dataset create a matrix of features and create a dependent variable vector
and the cherry on the cake is that any time you want to create these for your data sets you won't have
anything to change because this will automatically take all the first columns for The Matrix of features.
And the last column for the dependent viral vector.
All right.
Now I'm going to show you indeed that X and Y will be well created and in order to do this we're going
to add a new code cell here inside which we're just going to print.
So that's the famous print function which allows you to print anything whether it is a text or you know
an array like X or a vector like Y.
So we're going to first print x and then I'm going to add a new code so here where we're going to print
y and this is just to show you that indeed X and Y will well be created with this code.
Okay.
So let's do this now time for the fun part.
We're going to execute all these cells here because you know so far we've just written the implementations
but we have to run the cells in order to build all this.
So let us first run this code cell.
Empowering the libraries.
All right.
So important as you can see if I click here.
Yes.
This one here means it is executed.
Now time to run the second one.
But before running this we have to do something very important.
It is to upload this data set here and see as we format inside our Google Code that notebook.
And to do this you just need to click false here.
You know this little folder then upload.
Then you're going to go to this whole machine learning a zip folder containing all the codes and data
set and which was provided to you in the first section.
And I will give it to you again in every sections that you make sure not to miss it.
And inside this folder you're going to go now to part 1 data processing in order to get indeed that
data.
See as we file containing the data set we are importing right now so open and now the data set will
be indeed in Google collab your notebook.
And so now we can run this cell to import it.
And there we go.
It is already important.
You know it is executed.
So now we're going to execute this cell in order to print the matrix of features X just to check that
indeed we get all the first columns inside this matrix and indeed.
Well let's check the dataset once again.
Remember the first columns meaning the feature as we wanted to get into this matrix X are first countries
second age and third the salary.
These are the three columns and indeed inside X we have first the country column with all the countries
of these customers their age.
And in the third column their salary or their estimated salary.
So that's perfect.
We get indeed the matrix of features X containing all the features or also called the Independent vote.
All right.
And now let's run this cell to print.
Why the dependent variable vector.
And indeed it gets the dependent variable vector containing all the decisions whether or not the customers
purchased the product.
Right.
We can check.
No Yes No no no.
Yes.
No no.
Okay.
That's in the same order.
That's perfect.
We now have our data set.
Our matrix of features x and our dependent variable vector Y.
And lastly let me remind why we had to create these two entities.
That's because the way we're going to build our future machinery models expect exactly these two entities
in their inputs.
You know we will use some classes to build these models and these classes don't expect the dataset as
a whole but these two separate entities.
And that's the only reason why we had to create these two separate entities.
So now you know and therefore congratulations not only you improve your knowledge of machine learning
but also you now know how important data set and create a matrix of future an independent viable vector.
So now we're going to proceed to the next step which is a new tool which I'm going to teach you and
that is taking care of missing data.
Indeed as you can see the data that contains some missing data right here you can see this is an empty
cell.
So I will teach you exactly how to handle that case which happens most of the time in data sets.
So let's do this in a next material.
And until then enjoy machine learning.