Hello and welcome back to the course of machine learning.
Today we're going to cover off some additional comments about the Navy base class fire.
All right so let's have a look.
Droguet What three things.
Number one is the question of why is it called Neive.
Number two is the appeal of X and how we can potentially drop it sometimes al-Shehri a quick shortcut
.
And number three is what happens when there's more than two features involved in your dataset.
All right.
So let's get started.
Question Why is this algorithm called the native base algorithm.
Well the answer is pretty simple.
The answer is because the Bayes theorem requires some independent assumptions and the base theorem is
the foundation of the Navy base machine learning algorithm and therefore the data base machine learning
algorithm also relies on these assumptions which are often times not correct and therefore it's kind
of naive to assume that they're going to be correct.
That's the reason why it's cold.
Let's go back to our example and see what what that means.
So here we've got age and salary.
Right.
And based on those we're using the Neve base algorithm to classify our datapoints into people who drive
to work or people who walk to work.
Well the Bayes theorem the way we apply it actually requires that age and salary have to be independent
of the variables that we're working with.
In this case is your salary have to be independent and that is like a fundamental assumption of the
base theorem and then you can only apply it and then you can't get those probabilities and so on.
But in our case if you just think about it fundamentally it is probably not the case.
Probably there is some sort of correlation between age and salary because as a person gets older their
experience grows their their number of years that they've spent and the workforce grows and therefore
their salary grows so it's natural for the salary to grow if age.
It might not be a super strong correlation for it not for everybody but overall there is some sort of
correlation.
So they're not absolutely independent variables and also you can even see that from the chart you can
just by looking at our child see that there's some sort of correlation between the two variables.
And therefore given that they are not independent you can't really apply the Bayes Theorem and therefore
you can apply the base algorithm to machine learning and that's why it's called Neive a base algorithm
because oftentimes it's applied even though the variables or the features are not independent or not
completely independent and it's still applied and it still gives good results.
And that's why it's called naive because it's a naive assumption.
All right.
Number two P.O. Box.
So let's have a look at what we performed.
So kind of like rewind and analyze what we did in our steps in the proof.
So in step 2 what we did is we took over.
So when we were calculating X we drew a circle around our new point.
We were moved the data point just so it's not in the way.
And then we shaded the area.
And so what is P.O. Box will peel back is the likelihood that a randomly selected point from this dataset
will exhibit the features similar to the datapoint that we are about to add.
And as we agreed anything in that circle is deemed to be similar to our data point.
Another way to think about it is what happens if I throw in a random variable or random data point into
this data set right now.
What is the likelihood that it will fall into the circle what is the likelihood that it will exhibit
features similar to the features of the point that I'm about to add into the data set.
So basically it falls into that circle and so pay of X is the number of similar observations or similar
observations means observations similar to the points that we're about to add.
Divided by the total number of observations which is true in our case.
So it's four four we can see that there's four points in this circle right now divided by three.
And the interesting thing here is that this result is the same both times.
So this is in step two in step one where we were calculating for the people who walk to work.
So the ability for people who walk to her.
It was the same so basically X doesn't change with you calculating it in in the instep one where we're
calculating the probability that the person with these features is a person who walks to work or if
you calculate in the Step 2 scenario where you are calculating if that person with these features is
a person who drives to work and therefore it's the same time.
So what does that mean.
Well let's have a look at formalists so you can see that the formula in step 1 it was p off.
The problem of person who exhibits features X that he walks he or she works walks to work and there's
a formula in Concepcion X is at the bottom and for a step two it was a possibility of a person who exhibits
features X being a person who drives to work.
And as you can see proof of X is at the bottom here.
So what did we do in step 3.
Right.
So let's move on to Step Three from here.
Step three we compared the two.
So now if we take these two formulas these right sides of the formulas and put them into the comparison
like that.
You will see that at the bottom the denominator is the same.
Now though we know that the demon nominator is not zero and it's actually greater than zero probabilities
is never less than zero and we know it's not zero.
So we can just get rid of it.
Right.
We can multiply both sides by X and therefore the sign won't change.
And also we'll get rid of the denominator.
And that way we won't actually have to perform that calculation.
So that's one less calculation to perform.
So you can just compare the top part of these calculations and so that is what is done a lot of the
time.
So if you've done other courses on machine learning or if you've read some maybe articles on machine
learning you will find that this is oftentimes the case and also sometimes it is not mentioned that
this is happening so sometimes it's assumed that or it can be assumed that you know what's going on
.
So just be careful that look out for that.
And it's an Izabella approach.
As we discussed it's totally valid to do it that way but that is only if you're comparing the two.
Right if you're only comparing the two then you can do that if you actually wanted to calculate the
value.
So we said 75 percent 25 percent.
You want to calculate the value can't do that because it will be two different realities because you're
supposed to divide by a certain value.
It's not the actual value.
And moreover if you want to like it comparing is OK but calculating the actual value and maybe some
perform some operations or you know you calculate the value from this.
You want to compare the value from this scenario to a value from another problem right.
Like a value from a different kind of a scenario where p of X will be different right.
Not from this particular example that you're working with.
You want to compare the probability of the person being a person who walks to work.
In this example to the possibility of that person being a person who walks to work from a different
example right where it will be different if you want to compare across like that.
That will also not work because you know X is different so be careful of that.
It's always the safer and safer way is always just to perform the full calculation.
But if you're doing an orphan or if you just want to save some time or if you just maybe we're reading
other literature then it's it's also good to know about this approach where the denominator can be dropped
when just comparing between the two.
All right.
So that was another point or like kind of a there or maybe one shortcut.
And so the last point for day.
What happens when we have more than two classes.
So remember in this scenario I only had two classes the red the green or the people who walk to work
and the people drive to work what happens when you have more Klaas's.
How is the challenge different.
Well when do we have only two classes we compared as we remember we compared the people the probability
that a person who exhibits features X walks to work so basically that new data point that we added.
What is the probability that it's a person who walks to work versus what's the probability that that
new data point is a person who drives to work.
And it turned out that we were comparing 75 percent versus 25 percent and 75 percent was greater than
25 percent and therefore probability of the person of that person be a person who walks to work was
greater than that person being a person who drives to work.
And therefore we decided to classify them as a person who walks to work.
And it's very straightforward.
And moreover you'll find that every time when you just have two classes it'll always add up to one.
So we didn't even have to calculate the second one.
We could have just stopped at this one because if this is 75 percent this one is automatically 25 percent
.
So always going to be like that if you have two classes the way changes if you have three classes it
is it gets more interesting right.
So you've Calford one and there is.
Then there are still two more left.
So if you're working with one of just two classes since you calculate one you're done you can decide
right away if it's greater than 50 percent then you assign that class if it's less than 50 percent yes
another class if it's equal to 50 percent then you've got like a tie whereas if you have two or three
or more classes then just counting the one won't be enough because then you have two other ones and
you would still have to calculate and at least another one so just means that it's more of an interesting
selection problem when you have more classes that's pretty much the main thing that changes when you
have more classes.
And there we go.
That's all for today I hope you enjoy these extra tips on the naive base class fire.
And I look forward See you next them.
Until then in Germany in learning