Hello my friends.
All right so let's implement quickly and efficiently.
The linear regression model on the whole dataset.
First a quick reminder on what is the linear regression mode that we're about to build.
We're simply about to build this one right because we have only one feature which is the position levels
and that have been invaluable which is of course the salary to predict.
All right.
So that's what we'll do first and then we'll of course implement the polynomial regression model with.
I will tell you how many powers of that same position level feature.
Okay so let's do this.
Starting by creating a new code cell.
All right.
So I hope you did it yourself first to make sure you refresh your skills.
And so if that's the case of course you started from the psychic learn library because that's the library
that contains this linear regression class which allows us to build a linear regression model so cycle
learn from which we gonna get access to the linear model which contains this class.
And from this linear model we're going to import that linear regression class as Google Gulab guesses
perfectly perfect.
That's the first step.
Then we're going to create an object of this class so I know we used to call it regressive.
But this time since we're gonna have to regress regresses you know we're going to have the linear regression
regressive and the polynomial regression regress.
Therefore this time I'm going to call it Lin rake for linear regression.
Okay.
So Lin rec will be created as an object of this linear regression class so I'm copying and pasting that
here and adding some parenthesis.
And remember we don't have to input anything in these parentheses because there is not much to tune
in the linear regression model.
Good.
And finally now we have you know the linear regression model but it is not smart yet it is not trained
yet on this data set you know to understand and learn the correlations between the position levels and
the salaries.
So that's what we're gonna do right now by using this fit method which is exactly a training method
that will train the model on these data.
All right.
So to do this we're gonna call our object first Lynn rag from which we're gonna call the fit method
which remember has to take as input the couple of matrix of features and dependent variable vector of
the training set right.
That's what we did before but remember here that we didn't split the data set into a training set in
a test because we want to leverage the maximum data in order to train our model and therefore this time
we're going to take the whole matrix of Features X and the whole dependent variable vector Y.
All right so here we just input x and y and there we go.
We built the linear regression model in a flashlight so we're going to execute this.
Here we go.
And now we have not only our model but also a trained model on this dataset.
Okay great.
Now we're going to close this and we're going to focus on the heart of the matter which is the polynomial
regression model.
I'm going to teach you now how to build the polynomial regression model.
All right.
So we're going to create a new code cell and now we're gonna go back to this slide to explain exactly
what we're going to do.
All right.
So as you understand what we've just built so far is this model.
We only have one feature the position levels and the unavoidable vector to predict which are the salaries.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to create a multiple in our regression model but instead of
having different features in x1 x2 and x end well these features will be X1 X1 squared and X1 at the
power.
And we'll actually tune this parameter and a bit to try several powers so not to confuse the polynomial
linear regression is not a linear model because you will see that it can learn some nonlinear correlations
but we call it polynomial linear regression because indeed there is this linear combination of the squared
and you know power features x1 X1 squared and X1 and the power.
All right.
And so the process of building this model on Python will be first to create a matrix of the power features
you know a matrix of features but not containing different features like x1 x to an extent but a matrix
of features containing X1 as a first feature then X1 squared as a second feature and then X1 and about
and as an end feature.
So that will be our matrix of features and we will call it X poly and then we will create a linear regress
or object you know from the linear regression class to integrate these bound features of this matrix
of features in this new linear aggressor you see the idea.
So it's a building process in two steps.
We're going to first create the matrix of features containing these features at different powers and
then we'll integrate that into a linear regression model because indeed this is a linear nation of these
powered futures.
All right.
Perfect.
So let's do this first step.
The first step is to actually import this tool that will allow us to create this matrix of powered features
x1 X1 square next one at a power.
And this class is called polynomial feature.
So we're going to import it first which we can get from once again of course the psychic learn library.
There we go.
But this time we're gonna get access to the pre processing module which contains that polynomial features
class.
This is a class because indeed we're kind of pre processing our X1 feature because we want to create
out of X1 well X1 X1 squared and X1 at the power.
And so we're kind of doing pre processing of the features.
All right.
So from this pre pressing module we're going to import well that class po li no meal features.
Perfect.
I really like Google color so pulling on more features and then of course.
Well you know any time we import a class.
Next step is to of course create an object of this class and this object will be exactly the tool that
will allow us to create this matrix of the features x1 X1 squared X1 at the power.
And I will precise what n which was then we will choose several of them.
But there you go.
That's what we build with this polynomial features class and so well we're going to call this object
of this class purely underscore rec as polynomial regressive but it's not exactly the aggressor itself
because you know the final polynomial regressive will be the combination of this matrix of power features
and the linear aggressor and that's why we will call it actually Lin rect too you will see so poorly
rag will be created as an instance or an object of this polynomial features class so we're going to
paste that here adding some parentheses and that is where we're going to choose the n you know that.
And here is exactly chosen in this new class.
So first we're gonna start with two.
Okay we're gonna build a polynomial regression model resulting from the equation y equals B zero plus
b 1 X1 plus b 2 X1 squared where X1 is of course the position levels and y is the salaries.
All right.
So let's create this let's precise degree which is the name of the parameter for that N equals two and
then we'll try three and four.
Okay then next step.
Well the next step is now to proceed to this transformation of this simple matrix of features containing
only x1.
Meaning exactly this columns.
So far this is our matrix of features of only one feature.
And now we're going to transform this matrix of a single feature into this new matrix of features containing
X1 as a first feature X1 squared is the second feature and then that's it.
Because so far we start with an equal to but if we chose for example an equal three well the matrix
of features would be X1 X1 squared and X1 and the power of three.
All right.
So that's what we're gonna do and do this.
Well we're going to take of course are fully rag object again from which we're gonna call the method
fit.
Transform again you're starting to know this method that you know the method that usually proceed to
a transformation and here the transformation is to turn this matrix of a single feature into this new
matrix of features composed of X1 as the first feature and X1 squared.
The second feature all right fit transform then some parenthesis and then according to you now what
do we have to input here.
Well that's pretty obvious.
That's exactly the matrix of features we want to transform into this matrix of squared features let's
say right.
So X X of course that's what we want to transform X so far is only composed of this column.
Okay so fit transform X and now we have our new matrix of features.
However this exactly returns this new matrix of features and now we're going to create a new variable
which will be this new matrix of features itself.
And we're going to call it X underscore poli equals what is returned by this fit transform method applied
to X grades great.
And now we have exactly the matrix of features composed of the position levels and the squares of the
position levels good.
So now according to you what are we going to do.
Well as I said at the beginning it's like now we have a new matrix of features you know composed of
these two variables here and Well very simply we just have to build a linear regression model that will
integrate these features into this equation y equals bizarro plus B1 X1 plus B2 X1 squared right you
see the idea that's where the linear comes from and therefore well you know what to do.
You know how to create such a linear regressive but we have to create a new one which is of course different
than this one because this one is already trained on this matrix of single feature X and therefore having
already learned coefficient.
So now we need to create a new one which we're going to call of course Lynn rag and I'm adding underscore
to which therefore will be a new object of this linear regression class and in some parenthesis.
And well this object will be now trained on this new matrix of features composed of the position levels
at different powers.
And of course then the salary because indeed we need the dependent viable vector to train the linear
regression model and an imaginary model.
All right.
So the next step and final step is to of course call this new linear regress or object that we've just
created from which we're gonna call the fit method which will take as input.
Of course this new matrix of features containing the position levels are different powers.
And of course the same dependent variable vector which are the salaries.
All right let's do this.
Let's input first X Foley and then Y.
And there you go.
You have your polynomial regression model.
Congratulations.
Now you know how to build a nonlinear regression model and that's what we're gonna see clearly with
the next steps when visualizing the linear regression results first and the polynomial regression results.
Now you know how to build such a model and you have them in the toolkit.
So you're getting more power in machine learning more knowledge more skills.
Congratulations.
That's amazing.
And now I can't wait to move on to the next material to show you indeed the different results we get
with linear regression and polynomial regression.
So I'll see you in the next material.
Let's quickly run this cell in order to get the model itself.
And now whenever you're ready let's proceed to the next story or for the visualizations.
And until then enjoy machine learning.