Hello and welcome to our tutorial we are finally getting to the final round of our classification adventure
in our machine learning journey because today we're making the very last classifier the random forest
classifier.
So this classifiers basically the daddy of the previous class for you the decision tree classifier because
very simply a random forest classifier is a team of decision trees.
So you will see that we will pick a number of trees to compose our Random forest and then when it is
time to make a prediction then each of the trees of the random forest will each one make a prediction
whether or not they think that the user will buy yes or no the SUV and then the random forest will look
at each of the votes of its trees and then we'll count the number of votes for each class that has the
number of votes for Yes to use about the SUV and the number of votes for no they use or didn't buy the
SUV and simply based on a majority vote run them for us classify you will choose a class that received
the majority vote that has the most votes from its trees to make it as its ultimate prediction.
So that's the idea about run for us.
And therefore if you understood correctly decision trees then you would have no problem to understand
running for us.
OK.
So let's make our very last chance for you right now and let's find out about the results.
So let's start with the basics We'll get to our machinery as you folder to set the rightful the rest
working directory so this rifle there is and boy 3 classification.
And here it is section when you're running for classification.
That's the right folder.
And as I was telling you we are reaching the end of part three classification because the next section
will be dedicated to evaluating classification models performance in order to improve the models.
And therefore this is our last gasifier.
So let's go to this folder.
That's the folder we want to set as a working directory make sure that you have the social network ads
as you file.
And if that's the case click on this more button here and then set as a working directory.
All good here and now let's go to our classification templates to build around them for us classifier
with the best efficiency.
So we'll just take everything from here to the bottom copy and then will paste it here.
All right so I'll just give a quick reminder about what this template is doing.
So the first step is to import the data set.
We are putting the social network ads as we file that contains some data about users of a social network
and their information like their age and their estimated salary.
So this car company has just launched its brand new SUV at a ridiculous price puts ads on the social
network and the last column of this social network ads as he felt tells.
If yes or no.
Some users of the social network bought the SUV.
So zero if no one if yes then we encode here the target features factor because we sometimes need to
do it for the class Faiers that we build.
We are just doing this to specify to declassify that our last call them purchased is a categorical variable
with factor levels 0 and 1.
So we don't need to do it for all the classifiers but we do need to do it for sun like the Navy base
class very as we saw.
So it's good to keep this code section in the template then we split the data set into the training
set and the test set.
So as a reminder the training set is where our machine learning model that is are running for US disfiguration
model will learn the correlations between the age and the estimated salary.
And the question whether the user will buy yes or no the SUV and then based on these informations the
machine learning model learns how to make some future predictions.
And so we build this test set here to test the performance of our model in terms of predictions.
And then in the last section of the pre-processing phase we apply fut. getting to the data and we are
only doing this because at the end of this template we make this very cool graph for both the trends
that result in the test results that will plot the prediction regions and the prediction boundary.
OK so right now we need to change a few things in this template but some very few things.
First let's not forget to change the title of the plot here will replace classify it by random forest
classification.
We'll copy this because we'll do the same in the test results.
Here it is.
Perfect.
OK.
And now what we only need to do is to create our classifier here and then we'll be ready.
So I'll just paste the same thing here.
Run them for us gasification to the trainset.
And now let's create our classifier.
All right let's do this.
So it's very simple.
We're going to use a library that is called random forest.
So let's do this let's first install the package with the command install that package.
So that's for those of you who are using this package for the first time then you won't have it installed
on your back just is here.
As you can see mine should be already here because I used it several times.
There it is running forest.
So if it's not the case for you then you need to install the package here.
And so in this install the packages function you just need to input the name of the library in quotes
.
So it's random Forest be careful with the capital F here and not capital are here.
All right so that's what you need to impart Anyway that will install the package.
I won't do it because I already have mine installed with what you just need to do is to select this
and press command and control plus enter to execute.
And this will install the package without any issues.
All right so here I'll just press command per shift Plessey to make it as a comment.
But then what I need to do is to add the command here library and then input the name of the Ranum for
us library because as you can see here it's not selected.
So I need to add this library around and for us command to select it automatically especially if I want
to make some automated scripts in the future.
So that's the thing to do that's very practical.
And now we're all good let's create our classifier.
OK so as usual we'll start by creating the Voivode classifier that will be around them for us class
for itself.
And now we will use the random forest function to build our classifier.
So here I'll just take the function random forest and now let's see what arguments we need to input
.
So we'll just go here and press one to get some info about these functions or here we need to click
here and here are some info about the random forest library and function.
So let's look at the arguments which are what we're interested in.
OK.
So the first argument is data we will need it as you can see it's a national data frame.
So it's not an argument that we need to build around him for his classifier.
Same for subset.
And they do action we actually don't need the three first parameters to build around for us.
However we of course need the x and y arguments here which as you can guess will be the matrix of features
and the dependent variable vector.
Indeed as you can see X is a data frame or a matrix of predictors.
So that's pretty clear.
X is our matrix of features a matrix of predictors which are our independent variables age an estimated
salary.
And then why is that to be a response vector.
So of course why is the dependent variable vector that is the purchased column.
Okay perfect.
And then the last argument that will need to build around for us classifier is of course the number
of trees we want to have in the forest and this number of trees is given by this entry argument here
which as you can see is the number of trees to grow.
So to grow is a nice way of telling that the trees will learn from dataset how to make the predictions
.
And basically this argument is the number of trees.
So remember in the pattern to toile we chose sentry's.
Well let's do the same here.
Let's pick.
Entry equals 10.
And that is actually everything we need to build around him for us classify you only X the matrix of
featurism matrix of independent variables y.
The response vector of the dependent variable vector and entry the number of troops.
OK so let's do this let's end with the arguments.
Let's go back to our.
And here we are.
OK.
So let's end with the arguments as you remember the first argument was the matrix A features the matrix
of independent variables.
And that is trainset excluding the last column which has indexed 3 because as you remember in the training
set we have the first two columns which are independent variables age an estimated salary with therefore
indexes 1 and 2.
And we have the third column indexed by three which is are dependent variable vector purchased.
So here minus three.
Then what was the next argument the next argument was why the dependent variable vector.
And then here will take trainset and let's pick it this way to specify the name of the in the bin invariable
$2 here and purchased.
Purchased is the name of our dependent variable column.
All right so we almost have everything we need.
The last thing we need now is of course the number of trees and that is entry equals 10.
You can play around with the entry arguments you can choose many more trees in the forests you'll observe
some interesting results.
That's interesting to see what different teams of trees can do to predict the response of your users
in the social network whether they buy yes or no the SUV.
But if you do this make sure to pay attention to overfitting which you want to avoid.
You don't want to overfit run them for his class.
Very true the training said.
Because if you do this then it might make some poor predictions on a new set.
You can actually check it out with the test but he will choose 10 trees and we'll see what happens.
All right.
So actually we're done with the templates.
We changed everything we had to change and now we can just you know select everything and execute to
make everything ready.
You can actually take some coffee or tea and you can just select everything and execute to watch the
results.
But let's rather do it step by step we'll just do the first preprocessing step all in once here so I
just selected the preprocessing phase and now I'll press command control press enter to execute all
right all good we have our data set our training set and our test set.
So everything looks fine we have 400 observations in total 300 observations that went into the trainset
and 100 observations I went into the test set as you can see the training set and the test set are scaled
because in the end we were plotting some graphic results with a resolution of open 0 1.
So in order for our code to execute faster and not actually break our code we need to apply features
just getting our training set and our test set.
Otherwise we wouldn't need to do that because the running for US classification is not based on Euclidean
distances but it's based on you know conditions on the independent variables.
But because of this code here that is compute intensive we need to apply feature scaling so that everything
is well executed.
All right so let's do this let's watch the results.
We just need to create our classifier here by executing the section.
So I'll just do this all right.
Again now let's predict the test results then we have the confusion matrix which will tell us in a flashlight
how many incorrect predictions we have.
So let's actually do it directly.
It will be faster to see how our Ranum for us classify it well on the predictions.
So let's execute this.
And now let's enter CME here in the council press enter.
And here we have our confusion matrix.
OK we have seven plus 10 equals 17 incorrect predictions.
Well that's not too bad.
Just for fun let's let's just pick another number of trees like for example let's pick 500 trees 500
trees is a lot.
That's a really big army of trees to make some predictions.
And now just for fun let's take this.
I don't need to do this because my library was already selected from the previous execution of this
code section here.
So let's rebuild a new classifier with 500 trees.
Now let's look at the confusion matrix.
But before let's build our vector of prediction because right now the Y protector of prediction is the
one given by the run and for us with 10 trees.
So let's really execute this.
Right now we have y spread as the vector of predictions predicted by the Ranum for us with 500 trees
.
And now let's look at the matrix of predictions.
Remember with Gentry's we had 17 incorrect predictions.
And now let's see.
Select executes C and enter.
And now we have 15 incorrect predictions.
Great.
We invested 490 more trees to win to correct predictions.
So definitely that means that there are a lot of useful trees in the team.
OK so as you want let's maybe go back to centuries here because obviously 500 trees is not very useful
.
All right so I'll just take that again.
That as well.
And that as well.
All right.
And now let's look at the training search results.
So everything is fine here we changed the title here with random first classification.
So it's all good.
We are ready to look at the graphic result.
And by the way you can puzzle the video now and try to guess what you about to see.
Try to guess the shape of the prediction Regence and of the prediction boundary.
If you understood correctly the decision trees and you would have no problem guessing what's about to
happen.
All right so I'm going to execute right now.
Commander control presented to execute and Showtime.
All right.
Wow that's quite something here.
OK.
So first of all give a very short and quick reminder of what this is about.
So the points here are the real observation points.
There is the real users of the social network the red points are the users who didn't buy the SUV and
the green points other users who bought the SUV.
And then we have the regions here the red region and the green region which are the prediction regions
.
So the red region is the region where I run them for us classify predicts that the U.S doesn't buy the
SUV and the green region where around for us Kaspar predicts that the user buys the SUV.
OK so in short the points are the truth and the regions are the predictions.
And now let's see.
OK.
So the Ranum for us classifiers definitely catches most of the users that didn't buy the SUV in the
right category.
That is the red region.
So that means that it classified.
Well most of the users who didn't buy the SUV and same for the green users who are other users.
But yes we in reality because as we can see most of them are in the right green region and it's desperately
trying to catch some outliers.
We can call them this way.
For example this guy here is a user that didn't buy the SUV in reality because this is a red point and
it is way into the green region here and we can see but the random first class fare managed to make
this little rectangle part of the region in red to catch this.
Use it I didn't buy the SUV and classify it well.
But is it the smart way of doing it.
Because what will tell you that for some new observations we'll have you know some users who didn't
buy the SUV in this red rectangle here.
So that looks like overfilling because it made this red rectangle here because we had this user indeed
who didn't buy the SUV but nothing tells us that for some new observations we will have some users who
didn't buy the SUV in this red rectangle here.
So we should be careful with that.
And same for this user here as you can see at this user isn't some sort of irregular red region here
but fortunately around for us classify was not too obsessed at making all the predictions correct.
Because as we can see this red user here is in the green region.
So that means that it's still paid attention to or fitting but not too much.
And we should be careful with that.
So speaking of overfishing Let's check that right now let's look at the test results right now to see
how this region here because you know the regions won't change.
These are the regions built by our model.
So when we look at the test results we will have the same red region here with this rectangle here and
green region here.
But what will change will be the test set observation point that is all the red points and the green
points.
This will change and we will see if we have some red points here in this rectangle here and actually
probably not because this looks like overfitting that occurred because our class was fitted too much
to the trainset So let's find out about that right now.
Let's select this section dedicated to visualize the test results.
So I'll just select everything and press command control press enter to execute.
All right.
So what is the first thing you see here.
Well yes indeed this red rectangle here is totally useful for some observations.
So that was clearly a red rectangle region to catch some uses of the trainset because our class was
too much fitted to the trainset and this red rectangle actually doesn't make any sense here because
indeed we don't have any red user in this rectangle region here.
Well it's it's not that it doesn't make any sense but it's totally unuseful here.
And besides you know we have this green point here and this green point could have been in this region
here and it would make an incorrect prediction.
We were lucky on this one that this could have happened because these are new observations and they
are random for us classification machine learning model didn't learn anything from this new observation
point.
So this guy could totally have ended up here so lucky on this one.
And by the way same for this region here we don't have any red user.
That is some user who didn't buy the SUV in this red region.
So this red region is totally useful as well.
OK so that's the idea but most of all it did a pretty good job because of course got most of the red
users here with a low age and the low estimate salary and therefore users who didn't buy it yesterday
.
And most of the green users who are quite all that with a higher estimated salary who bought this awesome
cheap luxury as you.
And now what is the conclusion of all this.
Because we reached the end of our classification adventure.
We built all our classifiers So according to you what is the best gasifier for this particular business
problem.
What is the best one.
It should be a classified that classified correctly.
The users who didn't buy the SUV and the users who bought the SUV and at the same time prevented overfilling
in the training set to be able to make some good new predictions of some new observations.
So in my opinion the best class would be the kernel as VM in terms of the balance between the percentage
of incorrect predictions and the fact that we want to prevent overfitting.
Well if we look at them again in my opinion the kernel as being classified would be the best one.
All right so that's the end of this tutorial.
And now I have to say congratulations because you built a great deal of classifiers from simple classifiers
was logistic regression to more sophisticated and more complex classifiers like kernel SVM or Ranum
forest classifiers.
But that's not the end of the journey in the next section we will be talking about how to evaluate the
performance of our models and how we can improve them.
And then eventually we will have a homework on a real life data set where we will combine what we learned
here about how to build some classifiers and all the next concept that we will learn to evaluate the
model of performance in order to find the best model for this real life business problem data set that
you will be given and we will do the job as a data scientist or a machine or any scientists would do
in reality.
So congratulations again.
I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
And until then enjoy machine learning.