Hello my friends all right.
Let us begin this uproar conference bound implementation.
All right so we're gonna start efficiently thanks to our data repricing template because indeed as you
see the first steps are just to import the libraries and import data set.
So let's do this.
Let's go to our data pricing template.
Let's get our libraries which we will indeed use you know in this UCB implementation and same for Thompson
sampling and here.
Let's create a new hotel and let's place that right here.
Indeed we will use map luckily because you know at the end will plot the histogram and we will use of
course pandas to input the deficit.
And speaking of important data set.
Well that's our next step here.
So let's actually only take that line of code because of course for reinforcement learning we don't
have to create a matrix of features or a dependent variable.
So let's create a new code cell and let's base that right here.
And that of course replace the name of the data set by the real one which is remember add city R optimization.
OK so let's do this add underscore s.t. are on this core optimization.
OK.
Because we are optimizing the click through rate of the ad.
We're trying to maximize the clicks of users to a specific ad and we will identify what is that specific
ad having the highest clicks for rate.
OK.
Good.
So that's it.
Now we're going to run these two sales.
But first we need of course to upload the data set.
So I clicked on this photo here.
Right now the notebook is connecting to a runtime to enable file browsing and also to run the sales
here and in a second.
There we go.
We should see the upload button.
So let's click it and then please find the machine learning is that coding data sets for though wherever
you put it on your machine.
I put it onto my desktop.
So let's go inside then let's go to part six we're past halfway now.
Congratulations Part 6.
Reinforcement learning then uproot confidence bound.
And there we go python and we select this dataset.
Make sure also to have this slide open on your machine especially for the next tutorials where we will
you know implement each of the implementation steps first you and then us together.
Okay.
So let us like this.
And there we go.
Let's kick open.
Let's press okay.
And we will have the data set.
Okay.
Good.
Let's double click it to make sure we have it correctly.
All right.
So we have the 10 add and we have you know well you know you will have a lot of page because you have
actually 10000 users.
So remember each of the rows here corresponds to different users connecting successively to the web
page or wherever we show the ad and then for each user we have a one if the user clicks on the ad or
a zero.
If the user doesn't click on the ad and I remind that this is a simulation we're not supposed to know
all these but the only way we can stimulate the execution at the UCB model and the Thompson sampling
model is to have indeed this dataset with the real truth.
Okay.
And I remind the important thing is that each ad has a different click through rate and the goal of
our UCB or Thompson something algorithm will be to identify as fast as possible the ad that has the
highest click through rate.
Okay.
Good.
So let's close this.
And now well let's just run the sales starting with this one important libraries and then this one importing
the data set.
And now my friends we are ready to implement the UCB algorithm.
And of course we'll start fresh in the next tutorial.
Until then please have a look at the slide you know to get familiar with the steps and make sure you
understand them.
And whenever you're ready let's implement this together.
Until then enjoy machine learning.