I I'm a friend.
I hope you had no trouble at all to train that came his model on the data set in order to identify that
optimal five number of clusters which we figured out thanks to the Elbow Method because indeed in order
to do this you just had to do exactly the same as what we did here inside this loop by just replacing
that eye.
Number of classes here which is the iterated variable by 5 because now we know that we want to build
a train and run the Caymans algorithm to identify five clusters.
And therefore here we're simply going to take these two lines of code and we're going to paste that
right below in a new code cell to indeed train or came into model to identify five clusters.
All right.
And we don't have to import the Caymans class again because this was important here.
You know right here.
And this cell was already executed.
So no problem at all here we can just call this class directly and input here of course not.
I clusters but five clusters to identify and same deal we use the Caymans plus plus in method to avoid
the random initialization trap and we keep a random state of 42 in order for us to have the same result
displayed on our notebook.
And now this line of code actually indeed trains to came in tomorrow on the data set to identify five
clusters.
But as I told you in the previous tutorial we also want to do something else which is to build that
dependent variable finally of which the values are you know exactly these clusters from one to 5.
So actually you know the values of this dependent variable will be one two three four five one will
be you know let's say cluster one two will be cluster two three will be cluster three four will be cluster
four and five will be close to five and each of these clusters will actually be a certain group of customers
because remember that our dataset is composed of customers which will actually be grouped or segmented
into these clusters these five clusters.
And so there you go that dependent variable which we're about to create will split through its values.
Well all these customers into different groups.
All right so that's what I meant by we are creating indeed a dependent variable.
And so there you go.
That's our next step here.
How are we going to create that dependent variable.
Well I'm going to show you a little trick.
If you look at the API cycle learned four K means you know the Caymans class well you will notice that
there is actually a fit on this core predict method and that fit pretty method not only trains your
Caymans model on the data set but also it returns exactly that dependent variable which we're about
to create you know with the five different values taken by that variable.
You know one two three four five which of course correspond to these five different clusters containing
different groups of customers and in each group.
Well the customers are grouped by similarities you know they contain similar information in each group
and in the next step you know when visualizing the clusters you will perfectly understand what will
be exactly these information but I don't want to reveal them now.
So we're just going to create that dependent variable for now.
And since as I've just told you while this fit predict method returns that they've been invaluable Well
we're going to create a new variable here which we're going to call y underscore k means you can call
it y key means or you can call it y pred if you want.
You know that's also the name we usually choose for our dependent variables.
But since it results from the Caymans algorithm I prefer to call it wiki means plus we won't have to
compare it with a White House variable.
So that's why I want to make it a bit different.
But there you go here with this line of code you know calling the FID break method we create indeed
this dependent variable resulting from training or a K Means algorithm with five clusters to identify
five clusters.
Okay.
So let's see if this works.
Let's run this cell to train came its algorithm to identify five clusters and all good it was run properly
and now I'm just going to show you what we just created you know why k means so I'm going to input here
why on underscore score k means inside this print There you go.
Let's run it and let's see what we created.
And well there you go you can see now all the different clusters to which belongs each customer.
So here you have to read it this way the first customer belongs to cluster three so that's actually
customer I.D. number one customer right.
Number one belongs to cluster three and actually belongs to class and number four because this is only
the index of the cluster.
And remember that index is in bytes and start from zero.
So here actually the numbers of the classes are 0 1 2 3 and 4.
So let's be careful what we say with them.
So let's do it again.
Customer idea number one belongs to the fourth cluster.
Then a customer idea on the two belongs to the first cluster customer idea number three belongs to the
fourth cluster and etc. And the last customer I.D. belongs to.
Well I have to go to the second page here.
There you go the customer I.D. number 200 belongs to the third cluster or cluster of index 2.
All right so there you go.
That's the dependent variable that is created through the training of the Caymans algorithm.
And so now let's proceed to our last tip.
We're going to visualize two clusters on a 2D plot where you're gonna have on the x axis.
Well you know the annual income.
That's our first feature.
And on the y axis the spending score and we will see how our different customers and different customers
of the more were grouped into these clusters.
And we're going to clearly see the different clusters and their centroid from one to five on this truly
plot.
Okay.
So I actually can't wait to show you this because it's going to be a very clear graph.
And once again that's the reason I only want to keep two features here to be able to visualize this
clearly and well that's exactly what we're going to do in the next tutorial.
So as soon as you're ready join me I want to ask you to implement this on your own.
We will do it together and we will enjoy the results together.
And until then enjoy machine learning.