Hello welcome to the next section.
This is just a quick video inserted before the actual content because I want to make it very clear that
this section is optional.
Yes I said it seven times here.
I just want to be very very clear you do not have to do this section.
It's all on HTP how we work with the Internet within Python how we can request data from an API.
I added it in now because it is a fun topic for people who are interested in it.
It's something that I think can break up the monotony of learning a new concept after new concept and
just doing a bunch of the smaller exercises you'll learn in this video or in this section how to do
some more substantial things like send an HTP request to an API get data back parse it as Jason and
then do something with it.
For some people I think that is exciting.
I know from my previous experience it is an exciting thing but for other people this may seem like something
that's unnecessary if you don't care about the web.
If you're only passionate about data or you want to get through this course so that you can start working
on your own project and it doesn't have to do with HTP requests then skip this.
So I don't want to hold you hostage and make you sit through the section because it is longer.
It's not necessarily harder but I have to cover some background information about the Web.
So I just want to be very very upfront.
Also if you're interested in the web scraping section later in the course you'll definitely want to
at least run through this section quickly because we have to make requests in the web scraping section.
So we use what we cover and this section anyway.
I will shut up.
But just remember optional if it bores you if you don't care if you start that section and then you
feel like it's not for you.
No shame in skipping.
I mean there's no shame in skipping in general but I'm officially saying it's OK.
Yeah I'll shut up now and we'll get on with the content.