Hey welcome back.
So this section is all about a little drum roll lists which you probably could see Anyways on the slide
list or something that I've mentioned a couple of times maybe five or six times in the course already
basically in this way.
I've said all right there's this thing called a list and you can loop through them but we haven't talked
about this yet so we'll get there eventually and then we'll talk about looping or and the data types
video are talked about.
There's numbers there's billions and strings there's this thing called Bliss.
We'll come back to that later.
Well this is where we come back to it.
So let's start with the simplest question.
What is a list.
So it's really just a collection or grouping of items and those items can be anything.
In Python it could be a string it could be floats.
Integers boolean values.
It could be other lists.
When you talk about dictionaries that's also an option.
So it's a way of combining data into one variable one structure.
So this is the first of the data structures will be working with and the data structure is sort of just
like the next level a higher level up of a data type where it will actually store other data types inside
of it in a structured way.
So we'll come back to all of that.
But let's start by actually walking through a hypothetical situation.
Let's say I wanted to make an app that had a shopping cart or a shopping list feature.
So a user could add items to a shopping cart and we would keep track of those items.
Very basic thing but fundamental to any Web site any e-commerce platform where you're buying things.
So there's going to be a list behind the scenes used to store what your data is what you're actually
buying in other languages by the way.
These are called arrays often in Python they're called lists.
But the idea is the same.
It's a grouping of information of items together with an order.
So without lists with what we know right now we could store information like let's say we're doing a
shopping cart we could do.
Item one equals.
I don't know bananas.
And then another variable item 2 equals and we could have a Lego set or something and we could keep
going.
But our code would only work as long as we had defined item 1 2 item.
However many variables the user was allowed to fill up so we could have a while loop and ask them to
input something and then we'd stored in item 1 and then the next time through we'd store there and put
an item to the next time through an item 3.
But that's clearly limited.
One thing is that our data is all over the place.
It's not associated at all.
These have nothing to do with one another.
And imagine if we had 100 items in our cart that would be a nightmare as far as the code.
And it also just it's not a good solution.
So what we could also do is store everything in a string potentially if we were working with strings
so we can have something like let's say the first item added to our list here was printer paper.
OK.
And then the next item that's added in is a microwave.
So we could come up with some weird way maybe like three slashes to denote a different piece of data.
And then after microwave we're buying I don't know a towel or something like this.
Then this is a way of storing data in a list or it's not technically unless it's a way of storing data
in a string multiple pieces.
But then there's problems with this because if we want to print them out separately or if we want to
do something we have to split them up based off of the slashes.
What if we want to reorder them.
Maybe it's some sort of wish list for my birthday or a holiday I want to have a priority.
You know with the items this is the thing I want the most at the top.
So if I want to reorder this using code it would be really really difficult.
So all of this is to say that a list answers it helps with all of these problems a list allows us to
have as many pieces of data as we want.
In one structure we can reorder them.
We can split it we can add new items delete items.
It's basically like a little mini database stored inside of a single Python variable.
So here's a simple example of something you could do with a list so it's a simple while loop it as well.
It says Welcome to shopping cart.
Would you like to add something to the cart.
Let's say I want to add in printer paper and it keeps asking me let's say this time I'm going to add
applesauce.
And after that let's do a house plant and protein powder and a zebra print Grug a photo zebra print
rug you know on a real zebra.
And that's good enough for us.
So I can type q which is how this program is set up where it will quit and then all it does is it print
out to me your final grocery list.
But notice the order is actually changed and it's sorted things alphabetically.
So we get applesauce then-House plant printer paper them protein powder and then zebra print Roeg so
very very simple example.
Obviously this is not a web site.
It's a real e-commerce platform.
Nobody adds items to your cart like this in the terminal.
But the idea is the same I'm adding these items in in one order and they are coming out in a different
order.
But behind the scenes are all stored in the exact same list.
So I could easily reverse the order with a single command.
Or I could put it in half.
I could remove the two and say printer paper and protein powder I could remove those soups easily I
could merge it with another list or so many things we can do.
So the last thing for this video I'll discuss our objectives.
We have a lot to cover with lists.
First we want to be able to describe create an access list data structure.
So we've talked about what they are but we haven't seen the syntax.
We haven't seen how to access them or to create them.
So that's next then we're going to use a lot of built in methods to modify and copy lists.
So we've seen things like print or random rant.
Well lists have a ton of their own built in methods that we can use to do all sorts of things sort add
new items delete items cut cut lists and have all sorts of things.
Then we're going to learn to iterate over lists using loops and something called list comprehensions.
So I'll leave that one at that for now.
And then finally we'll work with nested lists to build more complex data structures.
So I mentioned a list can store anything.
Another It can store strings or booleans ints floats whatever.
It can also store other lists.
And that's where we start to get to more complex data structures.
So from here on out a quick little roadmap we're going to start basically going in this order will start
by talking about creating lists and accessing items.
We'll have a couple of quizzes and exercises interspersed.
But then following this section will be another section that consists solely of exercises.
So coding exercises in the browser.
We have a bunch of tests written where you'll get feedback and be able to tell if you did something
right or wrong.
So that's coming up hopefully something to look forward to if you like those.
All right let's get started with lists.