All right.
So as the side says this is the Mac installation instructions.
So if you have a Mac watch this video if you don't have a Mac but you're curious you could watch this
video too.
But ideally find the video that suited to your platform whether you're on a PC or using Cloud 9 or Mac.
So it's really simple actually.
Unlike a lot of the things that I've had to teach people to install before Python is pretty straightforward.
If you visit GWW Python dot org slash downloads or just google Python or Python download the first link
that comes up will take you to Python dot org and just click on the downloads tab.
So here is python dot org.
Click on download it will detect that you're on a Mac and then you want to make sure zoomin you want
to make sure you're using Python 3 point something not the Python 2 version.
And these numbers will likely have changed by the time you're watching this but there will still be
a Python 2 x 3 x we want the three.
So click on this.
It will take a moment to download and then we're going to run that package once it's done downloading.
All right so we just go through the steps continue continue.
Make sure you read this entire agreement continue again.
Yes I read it.
I agree to all those terms and then install.
OK.
So now you need to enter your password or thumbprint or whatever sort of an occasion you have on your
computer and it will take a little bit a fast forward through this and we should get something like
this installation was successful.
Nice green checkmark very satisfying.
We click close and we can move the installer to the trash and that's it super easy.
So then the question becomes how do we know that it worked.
The first thing I should say is that you'll need to open a new terminal window to notice any changes.
So open a new window or quit your terminal restart it and you should now be able to type python 3 like
this and hit enter and not get an error message.
Now that three is important.
So I'm going to first of all I guess I can explain what this says very briefly.
This is the interactive python shell REPL basically stands for read evaluate print loop.
Essentially it's a place to type code in Python.
You hit enter and you get a result.
It's mainly used for debugging purposes.
It's not where we actually write most of our code because as soon as we close this window it disappears.
So we get out of here.
We can do control D.
But what I want to show you is that if we just type python on its own it actually opens up the same
thing.
But on my computer I have Python 2.7.
I believe that most Macs come with Python.
I want to say all of them do but I'm not positive if that's been the case throughout all of history
but this Mac came with a version of Python already installed.
So if you just type python it's referring to this python 2.7.
So we want to make sure we're using Python 3 eggs again with control D.
So we want Python 3 and you can also do dash dash version and you want to make sure that you have three
point something.
OK.
So that's pretty much it.
On a Mac.
Super straightforward to install.