Hey welcome back.
So this is the first of our project sections.
We have a bunch of these in the course where we kind of take a break from just lecturing and learning
new things with the slides and the exercises slides exercises.
And instead we focus on building something a bit more substantial.
So this project is going to be the simplest because we only have a couple of tools in our toolbox.
We've got variables conditionals.
We can get input and we can print things and that's pretty much it.
But that's all we need to build a simple rock paper scissors game.
But eventually these projects sections will pick up some steam.
We're going to learn a lot more in the course and we'll end up doing things like connecting to API is
it connecting.
Talking to servers through python or downloading H.T. mail scraping the web and parsing information.
There's a whole bunch of fun things we'll do.
We'll make some more complex games but this is our first one.
And the way that this will work is that you can either do this on your own.
So I'll give you in just that in just a moment I'll give you the instructions and you can attempt to
on your own.
And then there's a solution video will actually create it or you can just go ahead and walk through
the video with me and create it together depending on how you feel what your comfort level is with things
like conditional statements.
So before I show you the instructions I just want to point out I spent a lot of time putting these emoji
here and for some reason whenever I go to full screen they just disappear.
What is this.
It's ridiculous.
Anyway so the way that this works there are two versions.
So there is the basic version that we're going to start with and the basic version is well it's pretty
basic in that we have two human players.
So we basically you know rock paper scissors is printed out you don't have to do that.
Maybe a welcome message and then player one enters a choice.
Rock paper scissors.
And then they hit enter and then Player 2 enters a choice.
And then we can perhaps shoot or something.
And then the result is printed.
So this obviously is is pretty basic and also kind of unplayable because player two can see what player
one has done.
So in my solution.
Actually over here if I run Python 3 let's say player one play scissors.
I added a bunch of these lines that say no cheating no cheating no cheating so that you can't see.
Player 2 can't see you player one entered and now.
Player 2 enters rock and Player 2 wins but they were unaware that player 1 played scissors.
So this is the first most basic version and that's what we're going to start by building.
And then once we have that logic we're going to build upon it in the more advanced version that includes
a simple computer.
I don't even want to call it an AI just a computer player that plays random moves rock paper scissors.
So we'll get to that but we're going to start with this basic version.
So try this on your own if you feel comfortable with it.
Just make a new file.
Hopefully you can see kind of where you need to use conditional logic where you need to get user input
that sort of thing.
And if not then just build it along with me in the next video.
And then after that we'll have the intermediate version.
All right let's get started.