Hey welcome to this new section on the command line for PC users.
So I'm going to keep this very short and try and get us on to Python as soon as possible.
But first I want to talk about why I even have the section in the course.
Why bother with knowing any command line.
And by the way if you do know some command line commands you're comfortable making files navigating
changing directories that sort of thing.
Then skip this entirely and move on to installation.
OK.
With that said our goals in this section are to define what the command line is and talk about why you
should care.
Learn some basic command line navigation and the basics of how the file structure works and then we'll
learn to manipulate files and folders using the command line.
OK.
So let's talk about what the command line is and why you should care.
The command line is basically just an interface to your computer.
Growing up I was used to using my mouse and a Gooley a graphical user interface if I needed to find
a file I would click double click.
Here's a file.
I found it gay then double click to open it or you know it's another example I would go in here and
to move a file I could click this and then move it into that directory and that would be one example
of using a graphical user interface.
Whether it's on a Mac or a PC the command line however is a text based interface.
So it's definitely uglier.
It's not as pretty but it's also way faster and also more powerful.
It's a lot of things you can do using the command line that you can't do otherwise.
So there are special keywords we type in.
I mean you've probably seen this before if you're new to IF you're completely new to the command line
you still have probably seen it in movies where hackers are typing and typing code really fast and the
text scrolling by and all the stuff is happening.
That's usually supposed to be a command line interface that you see in those films.
So here's an example of something that you couldn't do without the command line.
If I copy this command and move over to my shell This is the command line and I'll talk about how we
get this how we open it up what Power Shell is in just a moment.
But we're going to show you if I paste that command in and I hit enter it goes through every process
on my computer.
Hundreds of them and finds everything that's currently running and printed out so we can see there's
things like let's see web account manager storage service.
I mean I don't know what 95 percent of these are actually doing but this is happening behind the scenes.
And our command line provides a interface a window into that world that we wouldn't be able to see otherwise.
But that's not really why you should care about it for this course.
It is cool.
It's powerful.
But for this course it really comes down to one thing and one thing only to run Python.
We need to have a command line where I can type the python command.
So if you tried this on your command line right now if you haven't installed Python if you're on Windows
this won't work.
You'll have to wait until we get to the installation section.
If you're on a Mac or a Linux based machine then usually comes with Python pre-installed.
So I'm getting ahead of myself.
But the point is we need to be able to use the command line to run Python and we need to be able to
navigate using the command line.
For example if there's a folder on my desktop I'm going to show commands that we haven't seen yet.
We're going to learn them in this section.
I could find that file and then execute it with Python.
And this is where we're going we have to be able to find a file with the command line so I can run python
on the file.
This file contained to my code and it's a very silly app.
All it does is print Hello 10 times.
But the point is we need to be able to do this.
We're going to write our code somewhere and then save it on your desktop you probably will have a bunch
of folders.
We have a bunch of files in this course we need to be able to save them and then find them in the command
line which again it's just another interface.
I already showed you this file actually using the gooey with the double clicking on the folder.
I did the same thing through the command line and then I executed it.
And I couldn't do that without the command line.
So in the next video I'll have you know start writing code will dive into power shell talk about the
differences between PCs and Macs and then start running command.
As soon as possible.
So that's pretty much all I wanted to cover.
Just know that the command line if you've never used it it's not as intimidating as it seems.
It could be if you had to get into some very serious intense system level stuff.
But for what we're going to use it for just finding files and folders making new files and folders and
most importantly executing files with Python.
It's not that bad.
It might be a little slower than what you're used to up front because most people who are new to it
are comfortable with the mouse but it's worth it in the end.
And it's also what you'll see me using in the course.
So if you do want to follow along with exactly what I'm doing then the command line is what you'll need
to use.
All right.