Welcome back.
In this video I just want to address something that I think is a common question which is what do underscores
actually do.
What's the significance of underscores in names.
So there's a couple of options we have something like this.
We have another thing we have to underscore is in front of something and then finally we have these
Dunder method names that have 200 scores on either side of a name.
So what's the difference between any of these What's the significance.
So really quickly let's start with this first one.
Let's say we have a class I'm going to define a class for all of these that we use just called person
and instead of person we have our net which is one of those donder methods.
So maybe that's a good place to start these Dundrum methods we could define our own.
I could define a method called Hello.
There's nothing wrong with that technically and Python but conventionally this is a bad idea.
The whole goal is that we only define these when we're actually referencing or overwriting something
that exists in Python a special Dondre method like init.
So you don't go around to defining your own method willy nilly that are done for methods.
These are special things that Python looks for for example.
It always looks for the Dunder init method in a class when it tries to instantiate a new instance of
that class.
So you don't want to go defining those.
That's the simplest one.
Those are just magic methods.
We talk a lot more about them later in the course but just don't venture out and make your own Dunder
methods.
All right.
So we have this.
And let's say just set a property called a single underscore.
I don't know.
Secret equals high.
Self-taught underscore secret equals high.
And then another property that doesn't have that underscore self-taught name equals Tony.
And then I initialized a person P equals a person like this and then I just print P dot name print P
dot underscore.
Secrets do we expect anything different to happen based off of what we've talked about so far.
If we run this you can see both of them are printed out just fine.
This single underscore is simply a convention.
It's a way of telling developers please.
This is supposed to be a private variable or private property or method.
There's no such thing as a private attribute or a private method in Python.
That's just how python is.
It's how it's how it was created.
Other languages support private methods private properties or attributes where you could not access
them from outside of the class.
Usually though it's not based off of the name.
Usually you would define something like private self-doubt secret equals high.
And then if I tried to access this from outside I would not be able to.
And then this would be public by default.
Python does not have it.
So this is the way that we specify something is not intended to be used outside of the class.
The secret is only supposed to be used.
Maybe we have a method here called doorman and Dohrmann asked the secret.
Let's say like a speakeasy where you have to have you have to know the secret.
So we could just say if gas equals that underscore secret then let them in.
Or something like that where we're using underscores secret internally but it's not intended to be used
outside like it is here.
But again there's nothing preventing someone from doing that.
It's just about respecting conventions.
You don't get in trouble if you access something that starts with an underscore.
It's just a way of developers saying this is intended for internal use vs no name you can access freely
or change at will.
And the final example where we have two underscores before the name of an attribute or method and nothing
afterward.
Just to before this is actually not purely conventional.
This actually does something behind the scenes and to illustrate that let's get the comments out this
code that won't work.
Let's make something in here called self-doubt.
Two underscores.
I don't know message because I like turtles like this.
OK and if I try and print that double underscore message we actually won't be able to let's try it.
I mean get attribute error.
Person has no object or person object has no attribute.
Double underscore message.
What's happening here is something known as name mangling.
So when you put two underscores before the name of a method or an attribute Python will behind the scenes
mangle the name change the name of that attribute and to see what it actually looks like.
Let's just do d r of P and we'll print that and run it.
OK.
So you can see what we have going on here.
We have name we have underscore secret but there's no double underscore message all the way up here
though we have underscore person double underscore message.
It's always in this pattern where it's single underscore the class name and then the double underscore
whatever we call it message or get name or whatever the attribute or method was called.
So if we did one more here.
Self-taught Hellawell equals ha ha ha ha ha.
And I rerun the code you'll see we now have to underscore person double underscore ELO well underscore
person double underscore MSDE so we can access them if we wanted to we could just do print peacoat underscore
person double underscore and S-G or the same thing.
But for EHLO well and if I do those we get.
I like turtles.
Ha ha ha.
Along with those first two examples.
So when we say name mangling you might think that that means like totally changing and obfuscating the
name making it impossible to know the kind of you know making it secure or something.
But that's not at all what it does.
Its sole purpose is to make this method or this attribute particular to this person class so that once
we talk about inheritance we might have another class called sales person or teacher that inherits from
person and they have their own double underscore message and we don't want them to conflict.
We want them to be unique.
Well if we use double underscore message then Python mangles the name and basically put the class name
in there so that you know self-direct person message is different than self-taught teacher.
Double underscore message.
Anyway that's not really for this video.
It will make more sense when we talk about inheritance and overwriting and name conflicts and all that.
I just wanted to run through all three examples.
This first example single underscore is to signify that something is supposed to be for internal use
in a class.
Pure convention.
This second example what we just saw two underscores at the beginning.
Python will actually do something and see only one where Python does something based off of the name
and it's not a convention thing.
What it actually does is that it changes the name it's called name mangling and it puts the class name
first but it's not hiding it or anything it's predictable and how it behaves.
And then finally Dondre methods to underscores on either side.
It's a convention that you should respect.
You can define your own but you shouldn't.
They're used for Python specific methods like init that we will then define on our own and we'll see
a bunch more things like Len.
What else are DPR there.
They're all over the place and will define our own.
Spend a lot of time later in the course talking about them.
So don't go to finding your own methods with two underscores before and after.
In most you know what you're doing and it's a particular thing in Python that you're trying to override.
I'll get done with underscores.