All right welcome back.
So this video is about moving and renaming files and directories and you might be wondering why they're
together in one video.
And it's because they actually share the exact same command.
That command is move or M V.
So M.V. again can be used to move files.
It's a little more obvious but it can also be used to rename files.
So the way that it works is that there are two arguments you give it a source file.
The one that you're targeting and then a destination where you want to move it to or how you want to
rename it.
So if the destination is in a different folder the file would be moved to that folder.
If the destination is a new name in the same folder it will rename it and if it's both if it's a different
name and it's in a different folder it will rename the the target file and then move it.
So let's take a look at an example where in the directory cat pics as signified this little arrow inside
of cat pics there was a file called faves.
T.
Ok so if we write M.V. faves that takes t space goat greatest of all time t XTi.
But this will do is act to rename faves that t XTi to go to next to you without moving it anywhere.
It's in the same destination folder but you've just changed the name so you can see by the diagram the
name has been changed.
If we type LS now from inside cat pics there is no longer a favor x.
It's just gote that text.
Ok so then the second use case is something like this.
M.V. greatest of all time t s t.
And then rather than providing a new name or providing a different directory.
In this case the parent directory signified by two dots as we've seen before with the CD dot dot.
So this will just move the graceful time that takes the file back into the stuff directory.
As this arrow shows slides and if you type LS now it's gone.
There's nothing in cat pics.
And if we back out one level with C.D dot dot and type LS again.
Now we can see instead of stuff we have the cat picks directory and now the go text file that has been
moved there.
So that's really all there is to move.
I'd say the trickiest thing about it is just remembering what comes first the target file or directory
that you're trying to move or rename comes first and then the second argument is the destination or
the new name or both.
So let's give it a shot.
I mean my terminal again.
I'm on the desktop this time.
And let's go into my cat photos directory.
I must say I want to rename one of these so I have a file called Kiddie.
One got jpeg and I want to rename it to be something a little bit more expressive rather than Kitty
one.
Let's take a look at what that file is.
So that's my new kitty still unnamed at this point.
Just call her Kitty.
Let's rename this file.
Sleepy Kitty.
So M.V..
And then the file We're targeting Kitty one that JPEG space and then what I want to rename it to.
So let's do sleepy kitty.
Jay peg.
OK let's type LS now and you can see there's no longer Kitty one.
J peg.
We just have sleepy kitty J peg.
All right so that's the first use case and the second one is to move files around.
Let's back out.
I'm going to go to dog photos this time and I have inside of.
Let's look at CD Rustie pics or ls resti pics and tell us why it picks OK.
Nothing is in white X so let's move the puppy photo which is inside of rusty pics and put it inside
of Wyatt pics.
Ok so the way that we're going to do that is M.V. and because we're inside of dog photos right now.
So let me make this a little clearer.
We're in this directory and I want to target this puppydog jpg file.
So that needs to be rusty pick's slash puppydog JPEG use tab autocomplete to help you out.
And then where are we moving it to.
You want to move it to y it picks just like that.
So let's type us OK let's look inside rusty pics.
It's not there anymore.
What about in white.
There we go.
So we moved that file.
OK let's move it back just to show you and rename it to be rusty puppy.
So to do that from where I am right now I'm still on set of dog photos we're going to do the Wyatt picks
slash puppydog a peg and we're moving it to Rusty picks but we're going to add in a new filename and
this time we'll do resti puppy.
Jay.
So previously we just specified the directory and it moved the file and kept the name as puppydog J
peg this time and doing both.
And now let's look at Rusty pics and you can see it's called Rusty puppydog Jay peg.
And if we look at why it picks there's no photos there.
OK.
So again wrap this up with Move it can move files it can rename files and it can do both and it can
do that to directories as well which I didn't show but I won't make you watch me do that.