Hey welcome back.
So this video is all about dictionary methods.
Just like with lists as we saw in the previous section there are a bunch of built and methods we get
for free that we can use on any dictionary.
Fortunately there are fewer that we need to know about.
There was kind of a lot in the last section but I still decided to split this up into two videos just
to keep it more manageable and shorter.
And I should just warn you there's no logical grouping to which methods made it into this video in which
he has made it into the next video.
Unlike with lists where we saw you know three ways of adding to a list or three ways of deleting from
less I just decided to split them in half.
So let's get started with the first four.
Oh I forgot about this note.
Working with dictionaries is very common.
There are quite a few things we can do.
Thank you very good to add to that.
So the first one I see is clear and clear is pretty straightforward.
It will just empty out a dictionary leaving you with a hollow shell of what was there before.
So we can have a dictionary.
We create it using the dict syntax and we run clear which is what we save the dictionary into and it
just empties it and there's nothing left.
So over here I think I have instructors Still if I did.
Instructor not clear.
And we look at instructor again empty.
All that hard work gone.
OK.
That's that.
Next up his copy so copy will make a copy of a dictionary.
So here is that same simple dictionary or we have a because one B is 2 and C is three.
We save it to a variable called D and if we run out copy and we save it to another variable you'll see
it makes a copy a clone that looks exactly the same it contains the same data.
But just like with lists when we were copying lists they look the same and double equals.
That's true.
But if we use is they are unique objects in memory they're not stored in the same place.
So let's do this example here just to show that.
So here we have D.
And I could do C I'll just call it clone instead of C equals D.
Copy.
And if we look at clone and we look at d they look identical.
And if I do clone equals equals D That's true.
But then if I do a clone is d that's false.
If you don't remember when I covered double equals versus Is there is a video all about it.
Pretty early on in the course.
I don't remember exactly where I think it was in the section about strings.
Essentially the difference is this test for equality of values and this test for equality in memory.
If there actually references to the exact same place in memory which these are not.
Next up is from Keys which let me just warn you it's kind of odd.
It works a little bit different than the other methods that we've seen and that we usually call it just
on an empty dictionary or on d i c t n dict and why we do that will make sense once we talk about actually
creating our own methods and classes and objects.
So for now just take it as fact that we'll call it on an empty dictionary and we call that from Keys.
What we do is we pass in take a look at this second example First we pass in an iterable collection.
So here's a list with a string email and then a value.
And in this example the value is unknown a string and it will go through this iterable collection and
assign each one of these each item to a key with the value unknown.
So you end up with email unknown in a new dictionary.
Same thing here if you just have the string a as a first thing we pass in and then it lists one two
three four or five.
It will make a new dictionary with a set to one two three four or five.
So a logical question is why would I ever want to do this.
That seems really like more syntax to generate this compared to just writing this myself.
But if we have a bunch of keys that were trying to set to a default value for example let's say I want
to make a new user variable.
So any time and I don't know an empty user or we could have a player object in a game or a player dictionary
in a game or something.
And I don't want to go through and set every property to none or to zero or to whatever we want to set
it to.
I could use dict which I can also type act like this dot from keys and I'll pass in a list.
I haven't are too early man.
Let me go back to our personal list and let's just do things like name do score let's do e-mail and
have a profile bio.
Or something like that.
OK.
And then we can set them all to something like we could do not initially but I'll send it to a string
just called unknown and I can hit enter.
And if we look at new user now you'll see that we have name unknown score unknown email unknown profile
unknown.
So it's a way to programmatically create it.
Usually it's used to create default dictionaries to assign values initial starting values to properties
and just to show you if I did have an existing dictionary which will I have new user if I wanted to
do new user dots from Keys and do the same thing let's add a single value of phone.
And then also set that to an unknown and then need to close totally messed that up.
Here we go.
Close that there.
OK if I do this you'll see that all we get is this new dictionary new user is unchanged.
It doesn't contain phone anywhere.
And what was generated was just a new dictionary.
So you can use it works if you try and use it on an existing dictionary.
It just does the exact same thing as if you use it on dict or an empty dictionary.
OK.
That's all I'll say about keys for now.
It's usually used to generate default values.
Actually that's a complete lie.
What I just said there's one more thing that I'll mention.
If you don't pass in a list or some of the other iterable collections we'll see for example if I do
the same thing here.
But instead of a phone and a list I do phone like this it's going to try and iterate over the string
and it's a string as an iterable collection and it will do earn iterable object.
I get p h o and E.
So just worth knowing that if you are trying to do a single value even though this won't throw an error
it's best to put this in a list.
We could do the same thing also.
I mean just print this out with a range.
Let's go from 1 to 10 just like that.
And now I get all the key is from 1 up until 9.
So strings lists ranges as well as some of the other iterable collections you'll see in the next section
are all valid here.
OK enough of from Keys.
Next we have get now out of all of these I think personally I think get the most useful.
What it will do is if a key is in a dictionary like in this case a is we run Didcot get a.
It will give us the value which is one.
But if it's not in there Machir don't get no key which doesn't exist.
It gives us none.
Rather than throwing an error.
So this is what I was alluding to in the last video when I said you could use in to test for the existence
of a value or for a key but get is a nice method that is easier more simple to use.
So let me show you a quick demo.
We still have instructor over here.
I emptied it out.
OK well I just pasted it in and now I have an instructor and I could do something like instr. don't
get and then pass in a value like name and it will give me the name code but if I try and do something
that doesn't exist like e-mail it gives me none which we can actually see here.
But if I try and run the same thing and save the results into a variable called result and I look at
result nothing changes but I can do.
Result is none.
And that is true and that's it for this video at least.
So we saw for your review here clear to delete the entire thing.
Copy to make a clone from Keys which is commonly used to create default values and get.
Which is probably the most common that you said of all of these.
It takes a given key and returns the corresponding value or if it doesn't exist it gives you none.
Instead of throwing an error.
OK.
Next up.
Just a couple more dictionary methods.