Get now onto this thing that I've been hinting at and which is we don't actually have to use the re
comprehend or the list comprehension brackets.
Let me just prove that I'll do the same thing.
Let's go back to my name's if I get rid of them.
And I had better.
It still works.
It tells me false because not all names begin with C and people if I just tried to copy this on its
own and run it.
We haven't seen this yet but this is called a generator expression.
We have a section on generators later so I'm not going to go into detail right now.
So this is like a lighter weight version of a list.
So it isn't a list.
It doesn't.
We can do things like dots.
I don't know a pen or something.
None of those lists methods exist but if we're using this as an intermediate we don't actually want
a list at the end of what we're doing.
For example right here with all or if we go back to this one I don't want a list back.
I'm getting true or false.
I'm never saving it to a variable.
There's no reason to generate a list.
And in fact these generator expressions are much lighter weight.
So it's a lot of new concepts and weird stuff going on.
You can read about it online but it boils down to this to save space.
Space meaning memory and to make things less intensive you don't have to add those list comprehension
brackets unless you want a list and you need a list at the end of it.
But if you're just passing it in to something like any or all or some of the other things that we'll
see you don't have to add those.
There's a good stack overflow post on this generator expressions versus list comprehension all included
as a resource.
This person is asking you know why would you use this versus this same exact code except list brackets
versus Prendes.
And there's a lot of good answers.
Some of it gets into very nitty gritty details.
Some of it even goes into like particular parts of the Python specification things that you can read
that explain exactly how it works.
But I like this guy's response basically use a generator expression.
If all you're doing is iterating once if you want to store and use the generated results you're probably
better off with less comprehension.
Well in our case we're just passing it into another function.
We're not storing it we're never seeing it again.
So there's no reason to add those to the list brackets even if we can.
It just takes up more space.
OK last thing I made a little demo here to illustrate and to prove that a list comprehension and a generator
expression take up very different amounts of memory of bytes in system memory.
So I have the same exact expression X times 10 for x in range 1000.
So basically between 0 and 1000 we're going to multiply each number by 10 and stick it in a list.
In this case and done here I'm using a generator expression.
So in this example like we're not using either these ever again we're just passing them into cist don't
get size of and this will just prove to you that using list comprehension takes up a lot more space
to make that list compared to a generator expression.
Remember if you want to save it to a variable or do something with it other than just passing along
or iterate over it then you definitely want a list comprehension.
But if you're passing into a function like all or any or you're just iterating over it you could use
a generator expression.
But honestly the end of the day.
There's a reason very few people really talk about this.
Most courses don't go into this at all.
It's kind of a niche topic.
So it's not a big deal because the memory difference even though it is an order of magnitude difference
in this example it's still on any computer not going to make a difference at all.
As far as what we can perceive but on with the main event here let's take a look.
So I'm using something called since I'm importing it this module has a set size of method that will
just take you know an argument and will actually tell me the size in bytes in memory that it takes up
a number and then I'm just printing the two out.
So let's see what happens.
Here we go.
Drum roll.
And when you look at that list comprehension to do the same thing nine thousand twenty four bytes generator
expression is only 88 bytes.
Pretty incredible difference.
So just kind of a fun little fact here.
It's not a deal breaker.
You can use a list comprehension with all or any.
But if you're just passing it directly into any or all.
I wouldn't bother.
Don't add those brackets.
Just use a generator expression.
And if none of that makes sense and you're totally lost let's just ignore this video.
Move on to the next one because in all likelihood you might not need to use any or all all that much.