All right welcome back.
So now that we've scraped all of our data we get it in a list at the very end.
All we have to do is inserted and we have a couple of options.
I mean we have to connect to the database do all that stuff create that table but then we can either
do a bulk insert and conveniently we have it as tuples which is what we want inside of a list.
So that's nice and easy.
Or we can iterate over the list and insert one at a time.
But I think it's better and it's actually faster and sequel prefers it if you feel let me say that if
you do some research it's generally faster to do an insert with 10 items instead of 10 in search of
one item.
So I head over here and we already have our import for Sequel 3 so I'm going to make a new method called
I don't know save data or save books and it's going to take a list of all of our books as an argument
and the first thing that will do is just initialize the sequel side of things.
So we need to make our connection equals sequel light three connect.
We don't have a database I've created yet so I'm going just make a database called bookstand DB and
then I need to do our cursor connection cursor and then from there we have a couple of queries.
First we want to create our table so seacock execute and the query is create table books and then we
have a couple of pieces.
And this is going to be a long one so I'm going to do it on three lines on three lines.
I mean on multiple lines using three quotes.
So create table books and then I think from there I'm just going to spot this up so this will go on
the next line indented.
And the things that we want are a title which is text.
We want a rating which is an integer and then we want a price.
And actually if we look at the order and building the tuple and right now it's title price rating which
is totally fine.
We just it's best it will make our lives easier if we put them in the same order.
But it really doesn't matter.
So we'll do.
Sure.
Rating.
And then.
Well I think price is slightly more important than rating maybe.
So let's just go this way.
So we have title then price and then rating so price is going to be real which is basically a float
and rating is an integer.
So we have title text price real rating integer and that should create the table for us.
That's all we need.
See that execute that.
Then afterwards we want to go and insert all of our books which we'll assume are in this all books list.
So if we have all of this data like this we have access to it all that we need to do is do a bulk insert
multiple insert of this data and it would look something like this.
The actual query is just insert into books and then values.
We're going to have those three placeholder question marks and then we just would pass in after that
our list of tuples of books which are coming from here again would be called all books.
So then the method that we need is not up execute It's actually secret executes many.
And that will allow us to insert them all at once.
We don't have to write the loop ourself.
So this is a big test.
We're going to create that table and insert all those books in.
Now we're not calling Save books yet so we would need to call that here.
So let's do that now.
At the end so after our loop we have this or this list of all books that contains all of our data we're
just going to call save books with all books like that.
All right.
So start scraping books from that euro.
Re-initialize everything and then we go and find all articles that would create this list.
And for each article that came back recalling a book we're compiling three pieces of data as a pull
we're spending that into our list all books passing that list into saved books which should then go
insert at all.
So it connects the database creates a new cursor.
It creates a table so we'll comment this line out after the first time.
If you're running this over and over you probably would want a separate method or Honestly you only
create a table once.
So I would just do that without Python.
Just go into the sequel and do that and then insert it into books.
We'll see if this is correct.
Always room for error when you're dealing with sequel and python.
Oh and we need to make sure we do our connection commit and then connection close and now oh fingers
crossed let's see if it works on three books scraper.
OK that's a good sign that we don't see anything.
So we should now have a file books D-B sequel.
Three books D.B and first we have a Books table.
Now is there anything in it.
Yes there is.
All of our data is in there.
So now I have access.
Imagine that you're scraping this like let's say we were scraping a famous bookseller that starts with
an A and you were running this like all the time and getting all new books has her added or I don't
know daily you are scraping all fantasy books or whatever genre.
And we had like hundreds of thousands or maybe more.
And you want to then be able to figure out what are the actual highest rated books or what.
I mean we could scrape a lot more information reviews if we could take those reviews and run them through
certain API so it would tell us how positive or negative the language actually was or which ones are
fake versus real.
And then we could store that in our database and then we could go through and do all sorts of queries.
So like this is this is silly but let's just select all books let's say like book titles from books
where rating is greater than 4 or greater than equal to four.
And this gives us the highest rated books Sapiens A short history of nearly everything that went pretty
good for that.
And then I haven't read the others.
And also they're all just randomly generated ratings on that Web site.
They have a disclaimer that says they're not real they don't reflect the quality of the books anyway.
So now we have data here.
It's sort of a trivial example but we went through the steps of scraping and then saving it to a database.
And you could apply that to scraping any other web site and then saving into your database usually with
some reason in mind you're not just going to save it for no reason.
But if you're trying to figure something out with sequel and you totally could do that.
All right.
So that wraps up sequel.