Hey welcome back.
So this video is on external modules which is a topic that I always love to teach because by the end
of this video we'll be doing some fun things.
We're going to get some colors printed out in our terminal using Python.
We're going to print ASCII art Star Wars style scrolling text things that right now we're not really
capable of.
But we're going to talk about external modules that will help us accomplish that.
So a quick review we've seen built in modules that come with Python.
We include them using import.
We've seen how to define custom modules we know make code in a file and then we import it using the
import statement.
Now we're talking about external modules.
And these are modules that exist online on a server basically Python developers all around the world
develop modules packages and they can push them up online so that anyone else like us can go download
them and use them in our code.
So here I'm on a Web site called pi.
Pi is probably how it's pronounced IPY.
Python dot org.
If you just search for Python packages it's called the Python package index and on here you can see
that there's currently over 120 4000 different packages that Python developers have contributed.
And they range from really commonly use things down to really need.
Weird sometimes funny packages.
And we can actually go to browse over here and they will be broken down into categories.
So there's things like what do we have.
Natural Language Processing.
Mac specific what else.
Desktop development packages Internet packages graphics and audio packages so you know here's sound
synthesis.
There are packages that will help us generate.
I don't know squarewave or make make noise make musical applications or under speech.
There's probably some packages that will actually help you know that you could convert text to speech
or something using Python.
Let's see if we scroll through some of these.
This is under the sound and audio speech category.
We have things like what do we have here.
Python's simple text a speech module a robot that receives voice commands to play albums from an MP
3 collection called Music Butler.
So like I said some very specific uses but then there are packages that do much more common things like
help you develop web applications or what we're going to focus on the first package you'll see is just
a way to add color to our print statements.
Right now all of our print statements are just default terminal colors.
So for me black and white but we'll see a way to say I want this to be green and this to be purple.
So I've showed you all these packages on Monday exist.
How do we install them and use them.
And the secret is you need to use something called Pipp P IP.
It doesn't really stand for something officially on Wikipedia.
It says it stands for Pip installs packages which is a recursive definition which maybe that's the original
but it people to say Pip it's a way of installing these packages.
And it used to be a separate thing.
But now as of three point four Python three point four it comes installed when you install Python.
So we don't have to install anything we don't have to do anything in order to use Pipp.
All we do is we run Python 3 dash em.
Pip.
Install.
So this is always the same.
And then the name of a package.
So the first package that we're going to work with is called term color.
Here's the page the documentation page for it.
And it just lets us print color text.
So very simple and straightforward we can do things like print hello world as read and you can get fancy
and make it blink in the terminal or reverse and there's different things you can do.
But the first thing we have to do is actually install term color.
So using this syntax Python 3 dash em Pip install.
Open your command button and run it with term color or if you have another package you're trying to
install replace the name with.
Replace term color with the name of the package.
I already have it installed and so it tells me that term color requirement already satisfied.
But if you don't have it installed it might take a moment.
It's going to actually download it and now we have access to it in our python files.
So I'm going to make a new file.
I'm just going to call it colors.
Why.
And the first thing we need to do is import term color OK and back in the docs.
The documentation is not that amazing on here.
It tells us things like the colors that we can use.
Unfortunately no purple.
It shows some examples but there are two builtin methods or two built in functions that we can use to
help us out.
And the first one is called Dear D R and what it will do is tell us the list of names that a certain
package or module comes with or any object they will be clear if I show an example.
So in here I'll run print Diyar term color and if I execute this now it just tells us the attributes
that are in those two colors highlights and then there's a function called colored.
Another one called see print.
So this isn't that useful.
Also we can see some other things in there but this is on its own.
Doesn't help that much but there's a second built in function called help and help will show us documentation
for whatever objects we pass in.
So let's do help term colored and now look up we get noticed we don't have to print it.
By the way my terminal is taken over and we get a little overview of the functions.
So there's one called colored and take a look at this.
We've taken the text that we want.
Are we pass in a text that we want to be colored.
We specify a color.
We can also specify on color which is the background and then we can see available text colors red green
yellow blue magenta cyan whites text highlights attributes.
We can do blank or reverse concealed.
OK so back in my file.
Let's undo that or delete the help and let's try running this colored function so we'll just start simple
pasand some text like.
Hi there and then a color which we could just pass in as read or something.
But let's do keyword argument and do Suyin like that and there's going to be a problem right away.
Can you spot it.
Colored is not going to exist.
It's going to be a name error and that's because we either need to do term color dot colored or what
I prefer From term color.
Import color or colored just like this.
Now I should be able to access it.
But the thing is if I run this Python 3 colors nothing happens and that's because by default this doesn't
actually print anything.
So let's save it to a variable.
Just called text.
Now we can print text.
I could also just put the print to this directly but the it just returns like a string that's ready
that has the color information encoded in it and then we need to print it when we want to and that that
blue text or cyan.
Let's also let's play around and do magenta
cool and remember if you want to see a list of the colors you can always type help again.
You could also just go into Python 3 and the terminal like this.
And if you just try and do help turn color you're going to get an error but you need to import term
color and then do help turn color.
And we can see OK so we've got red green blue yellow blue.
So things like orange purple Those aren't there available textiles.
So let's do on magenta and make R-TX yellow.
Let's try that.
See what happens.
So that's going to be color is yellow and then on color equals and we have to do on magenta.
It's not magenta it's on magenta.
Let's see.
Oh I get a quilt out of here first.
Try it very ugly but it works.
That's magenta.
Let's switch that around.
Anyway we need to be about aesthetics so much but let's do it on yellow instead.
Oof that yellow is just terrible.
Q How about Green
find enough.
The other thing that I'll mention is that I won't open up help again but there's another thing another
parameter argument we can pass in called adder's and it's actually a list and if we pass and blink and
I only know this because I looked at help but I just don't want to make you watch me open that up multiple
times so Blinkx
Oh it's really hard to see at the end.
I mean get rid of the green let's do on Suyin and make the color magenta OK.
Now you can see it's blinking.
Ok cool.
So hopefully you can see how this is exciting.
Yeah.
It's just colors but that's something we don't know how to do.
Frankly I don't know how to do it.
I don't think it's that hard.
You have to learn to like these weird.
They're called the see color code or something.
A NSI something like that and maybe two eyes.
So it's not impossible by any stretch.
It's just something I don't know about.
But why not just use a nice little package called term color that does it for me so I can just specify
colored.
There's a little interface they say the color I want the background color to be blinking.
It's nice and it's pretty easy.
And we use pipit to install it.
So in the next video we're going to continue to use this but we're going to try building something with
it.