Hey.
Welcome back.
OK.
So in this video we're going to talk about generators and in particular I'm going to show you how to
make an infinite generator which maybe isn't that common but I want to show it to you because it's something
that we can only really do with iterators.
So for example I kind of thought for a long time about an example that would that would potentially
make sense.
Let's say that I'm making a music application like I'm a deejay and I want some sort of software written
in Python that helps me create.
I don't know if sound and play sound on certain beats.
And for example we're going to work in four four time which you're not a musician basically just four
beats to a measure.
It's a classic rock n roll counting you know one two three four one two three four.
Anyway what we're going to do is create a function and let's say I want a function called Current beat
and it always gives me the current beat either one two three or four and then it starts at 1 and 2 and
3 then for the next time it goes back to 1 and it just helps me figure out where I am in the music what
beat in a measure.
And if none of that makes sense let's just say I want a function that just returns 1 2 3 4 and then
cycles back to 1 2 3 4.
But I don't want them all at once.
I want the current beat each time I want one.
I want to.
For example I can have a function called Play kick drum.
Let's say I'm trying to mimic Queen's We Will Rock You and it's a classic drum pattern where the kick
drum plays on the first and second piece and then not on the third and fourth.
So then we get one two three four and I only want that sound to play.
I don't know if current beat is equal to 1 calling current beat.
Then we'll play sound or something.
Of course this code won't work we don't have any audio set up but if this is what we had current beat
needs to reliably return one to three or four and then repeat OK all of us just set up.
I'm trying to show you.
If we defined a function call the current beat How could we have it return a single number.
But every time return a different number and then start repeating we don't have a way of doing that.
We can return one thing from a function.
So of course we could create a class we could instantiate this class like we saw earlier when we created
a counter class make it an iterator.
But the point is with just a regular function we can't what we could do is I don't know returned a list
that we could generate and that's less than ideal of course because it's way less than ideal.
I want one thing at a time but we could have a list or a tuple of numbers that say one two three four
we'd have an index set to zero.
We could do something like set a max equal to 1 equal to 100 while.
And we need one more thing result list or a tuple whatever.
Wow length of result is less than max.
Inside of there well we're going to do is they could take Gnome's of eye starting at zero will add one
to I plus two equals one and we'll append that to result result that append number I I post equals one
but we will run into a problem when I get past the length of the list.
So I need to add and if so if it's greater than or equal to the length of numbers so that in this case
as soon as it gets to the length 0 1 2 3 then we reset it to zero.
So then I go back to zero.
And then finally we can return results.
All of this is a long way to show you something that I don't want.
And the limitation of function in print and current beat and try running it.
There we go one two three four one two three for over and over and over repeating a cycle.
But that is not what I want.
I want one thing at a time and let's say that I had ten thousand measures or a million measures of music
going for this to even begin to work.
I guess I could generate this first and then I could loop through it one item at a time.
But for that to begin to work my list would have to hold what four million to one million measures and
there's four beats in the measure.
That means four million things that it's holding at once.
Before we even begin.
And that's bad because lists as they grow take up a lot of memory and I only need one thing at a time.
OK.
So all of this is to show you.
Instead let's go this route with a generator current beat
and we'll have the same thing.
Nom's Wow that was I really butchered it there.
One two three four.
Well haven't I set to zero.
And then we'll just wild true show forever.
We're going to we could start by just yielding numbers of I.
And so that should give us zero.
And then adding one to I plus equals 1 just like before.
But we solved that problem where if we get to the end so we'll just do.
If I is greater than or equal to length of numbers I equals zero.
Reset it back to zero.
And this will keep going.
Every time we call next on that and just proof.
And also double check for any errors here looks good.
So if I just make this thing called an counter equals current beat and I do next on counter you get
one and two three four.
One two three and it keeps going forever.
So anytime my code whatever it is needs next beat it can call next on counter and it will keep going
forever.
But it still only gives one beat at a time.
So I don't have this giant list.
If I had a million measures it doesn't matter how many measures I have because all that I'm really dealing
with is one number at a time.
I think I just added a letter here as to how I am dealing with one number at a time rather than four
million stored in the list.
So hopefully that distinction is clear.
This is not really something you have to do all that often.
It's not just the music part but any sort of infinite generator.
But it is really cool to know that you can do this and this I think it shows a big difference compared
to a typical function.
OK so next one I'm going to show you is how we can actually see the difference in memory usage between
a generator and using a function with a list or something.
When we start working with like millions of results.