Hey welcome back.
So in this video I'm just going to walk through the test that I wrote to test the deck in card classes.
They're actually the same tests that I wrote in the exercise when I don't know if you did this but if
you did enter your code into they you to me coding challenge interactive python Ed. trademark copyright.
All that craziness I wrote these tests to go in there to test your code.
Now I'm just going to walk through what they actually look like.
So if we go over to Test I can start with the card tests.
So I import both things up top and then I have my card test class.
There's no you know you don't have to do separate a separate class to test cards an index card and deck
but it's better to separate things.
We could do all of this.
I mean you could technically write all of your tests in a single function or single method.
It would just be kind of a nightmare to understand what was going wrong.
So it's better to break things up.
So with card the first thing I have is setup.
I'm using the same card for all these tests where I just have you know initialized new card with hearts
or shoot is hearts and value is a for Ace.
Then to test it I'm just using this self-direct card and checking that self-talk card that suit has
been assigned to Hearts and that self-edit card value has been assigned to AA.
So to assert equals and then our docstring to test the representation what's supposed to happen is that
it returned to string a of hearts.
If we're using self-direct card so I'm doing that.
So we just use self that assert equal representation.
Self-caused So this is the better way of testing it.
You could also do self-direct card dot our EPR and direct the call the method where we can use this
function that will then call DOT Dunder our EPR.
Behind the scenes anyway.
So we're testing that it's equal to this.
So both of those work then we move on to the deck tests.
The book of the logic and I have the same thing where I make a new deck self-taught deck equals deck.
You don't pass anything in.
So before every one of these this code runs first I'm testing init and I'm checking that assert true
that self-taught deck of cards is a list instance list should return true.
And on top of that we're checking that it has 52 things in it.
I didn't actually check to see if the items were exactly cards.
I just checked those 52 things in there and that it's a list.
But then later on I'm checking you know certain things have to be cards anyway.
Then we have test our EPR is the same same idea representation except I'm expecting it to say deck of
52 cards or a deck of cards.
But when you make a new deck which is what happens it should be 52 did test count.
I'm first asserting equal that at the beginning count is 52.
So if the deck got count of a brand new deck from here should have 52 cards then I am popping one off
self-doubt decked out cards up pop and then I'm checking that the Count has now gone down to 1 or gone
down by 1.
And that works as well.
I should stop saying that all of these work I've already run them.
You've seen me run them.
There are three tests for deal this method here not deal hand or deal card but just underscore deal
the method be used internally in those other methods.
And there's three things I'm testing for.
What happens if you ask for a reasonable amount of cards that you ask for two cards and there's 50 in
the deck.
That's fine.
But if you ask for fifty five cards and there's only 52 what happens.
And also if you ask for two cards when there's two cards left does it still work.
So back in the tests the first one is just to check if there are enough cards left it should deal appropriately.
So we have a brand new deck with 52 cards.
Then I'm calling.
Deal underscore deal with 10 and that should be me with 42 cards.
And what I do is check that when we call self-direct decked out under a square deal 10 I save the list
to a variable called cards and then check that there are 10 things in that list and I'm checking the
count of self-doubt deck has gone down by 10.
So two things at once if I was only checking to see if Count went by went down by 10 then it might be
missing the fact that those cards are returned and there could be a problem where those cards weren't
returned they were removed and then never returned.
Which case this would not have full test coverage of this method.
Then I'm doing the same thing but trying to deal 100 cards and that should never work because there's
only 52 cards maximum.
Same thing.
So I call self-taught decked out underscored deal 100 save the result to cards.
And I should check that the length of cards is all the cards possible 52.
And that self-direct count is empty.
And then lastly this is a trick here one deal should throw a value error.
If the deck is empty and you try and deal from there and if I try that self-doubt decked out under square
deal and I try to use the self-taught DECT count which will then deal everything in the deck.
This will empty it drain it completely right here.
Then I'm going to try and deal one more but assert that it raises a value error which it indeed does
right there.
OK.
So that's the syntax as we saw it a couple of videos ago to test for errors.
We use a with statement.
Next up we have a card in deal hand.
I'm checking that when I call deal card Cingular it gives me the last card.
And one way to do that is to start a brand new deck which is from our set up all the way up here.
And then I call self-doubt decked up cards negative 1.
So I'm not removing it.
I'm just saving a variable called Card equal to the last card in that list.
But I'm leaving it in the list then I make another variable called Delta card and that's equal to the
result of deal card on self-taught deck.
So that gives me the card and they're supposed to equal one another.
I was starting right checking with the last card twice.
And then I asked for the last card and they should be the same thing.
So then I can do a self-taught assert equal card and Delta card they should be the same.
And at the same time I assert equal that self-direct count went down by 1.
And it's now 51 cards with Deal hand.
I am dealing 20 cards at once and saving it to a variable called cards and then I'm checking that the
length of the cards is 20 and then I'm also checking the decks.
Count the method.
That's the number that returned has gone down by 20 leaving me with 32 cards almost there then we get
to shuffle.
As I mentioned in the intro shuffle is harder to test when you have random stuff going on.
You can't predict what it should equal Exactly.
So the approach that I took is a bit different.
I made a variable called cards and set it equal to self-doubt decked out cards the slice with just a
single colon and that's just going to give us everything that makes a copy.
So I cloned it into a variable called cards and I'm going to use that to compare after a shuffle.
So I have the initial state and the reason I have to do this I couldn't just say cards equals self-doubt
deck of cards because it would be pointing to the exact same thing.
And once they changed you know self a deck of cards cards would change as well.
I need a copy of it.
That's one way of doing it.
So I'm keeping the original state and then I shuffle self-direct cards and then I'm checking that the
two things are different now.
Self-taught assert not equal cards is not equal to self-direct cards.
The initial state is different than the current state.
And that's kind of all I could do if I wanted.
You definitely could be a lot more intense about how you check for the shuffle.
But what I'm doing is just checking that they're different.
So the before and after state are different.
But that length is the same as before.
Otherwise you know if I had tried to shuffle we could have just deleted everything from the deck and
if I didn't have this line this test all of this would pass because we're just checking if the two things
are different before and after and an empty deck is different than a full deck.
But by doing this I'm ensuring that it's still full at the end but also different.
And then we have shuffle on a non-full deck an empty deck or a partially empty deck.
The goal is to only be able to shuffle a full deck.
So we just deal one card right off the bat and then we call self-taught decked out shuffle and we assert
that that race is evaluated.
And it does indeed.
So that concludes the little walkthrough here.
Let's just run those tests without the dash B 12 tests run.
Everything's good with the dash B.
We get all this information and everything is working.
All right.
So whether you actually wrote all the tests and went along with this or you wrote a couple of them and
then gave up or you rolled her eyes at me and just didn't do any of the tests and maybe you watched
the solution video hopefully right now at the end of the section you can see that testing is potentially
useful.
It also is potentially time consuming and they can be a lot of work.
My goal with this section was not to try and convert you to a testing maniac or to a preacher about
the benefits of TDD nonstop.
I really just wanted to expose you to testing so that if you do keep working with python there will
be a time and at some point where you either have to write tests for your own project for an open source
project or you have to make sure tests are running correctly before you can submit a poll request or
you're working on a dev team somewhere freelance or full time doesn't matter.
They'll probably have to write tests or at the very least run tests to make sure you didn't break anything
by adding changes in.
So it's a good skill to have.
Keep it in your tool belt however you feel about it.
Anyway moving on to more fun stuff.