Oh right almost done with lists.
It's been a long ride.
We're talking about nested bursts in this video.
So nested lists are just lists inside of other lists.
So we've we can also call them multi-dimensional.
This is another way you'll hear them.
But remember any list can contain any sort of elements whether it's strings or numbers of booleans or
other lists.
So it might look a bit weird but it's totally normal.
We have a list that has three elements.
If we ran the length of this list it would give us three but each of those elements is its own list.
So that's where we get the multi dimensional part.
You might be wondering right about now when would you ever use something like this.
And the answer is actually probably more frequently than you would expect unless you are expecting frequently
in which case you're right.
So here's a couple of examples.
If you're building any sort of game like a board game like tic tac toe or you need to lay things out
in a maze you'll commonly used nested list if you're interested in learning about web development.
You'll find yourself working with data that contains list of lists all the time.
Like imagine you've got some data back from Spotify or iTunes and it contained five most recent play
this for a user each one of those playlists would have a list of songs associated with the playlists.
So you have a list of lists each play list itself a list and you might even go further than that because
the information for a song instead of a playlist could be another list or it would most likely be a
dictionary which you haven't talked about yet but we get these nested structures also if we're talking
about any sort of tabular data and the information we would plot in a chart or turn into some sort of
visualization that's almost always nested data as well.
So you know working with things and the mathematical data structures like matrices you'll find them
nested as well.
Basically anything in data science with Python your data is almost guaranteed to be nested.
Oftentimes more than one layer deep.
So just good to know.
This is a real thing it's not just one of those things I'm showing you to be like hey look you can do
this in python you never will.
This is one of those things where it's like hey look you can do this in Python and you probably will
do it all the time.
And it's not as scary as it seems if you are feeling intimidated.
There's lots of real world use cases.
So let's let's see just how to access simple data.
So here we have a nested list three items and each item is another list of numbers 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
So if I wanted to access this number here I first have to access the outer list.
So this is the zero with element of the main list.
So I accessed nested those brackets zero.
And then I add bracket 1 which will give me 0 1.
Here's another example.
We have just nested list of one.
So that's going to be this list.
0 1 2.
So we want one and then we use negative 1 to get the last item.
So it's copy this over to my terminal and let's say I wanted to access 8.
How would I do that.
OK.
So nested list and I first need to target this last list which is 0 1 2.
Or I could do negative 1 as well.
What did I do wrong.
Nested that stereo and negative 1 Give me the last item.
So I could do negative 1 and then to access 8.
I could do 0 1 or I could do negative one negative two if I wanted to and I could also instead of negative
1 at the beginning I could do two because it's 0 1 2.
And so the way I would do it typically would be this.
I don't like using negative numbers most of the time.
I would just do to one.
So we just chain them together.
So what about printing values or iterating through nested lists.
So you have to use two loops which we have seen nested loops before.
Briefly I let you know they are a thing and this is a really common use case for them.
If you have nested data structures you can loop through one layer at a time.
So in this first example this first loop is going to go through every item in the top level list.
So three times it's going to loop through and this variable right here one is going to be equal to this
less the first time through.
So then we're going to loop through that list on its own and have its own list have its own loop for
vowel in this list.
Print Vout.
So our first loop is going to go start here on this list and it's going to run in the second loop.
One two three times.
And then the first loop starts over and moves here and it runs one to three times.
Print them out and then it starts over again and does these three.
So this is a very common practice.
If you have nested loops or nested lists you need to use nested loops to print them out.
So here I have a file with a nested list structure representing latitude and longitude coordinates.
So each one of these could be a location.
Maybe this is the I don't know maybe we have a clone of Airbnb.
And these are the locations of properties that are owned by a user or something.
So if we want to just loop through them in the simplest way I could just say for I don't know property
or do location.
Hello C in chords.
And if we just print out lock Alosi don't forget parentheses and we run this.
This is going to be Python 3 we get our three lists and then instead of that we could do for chord in
location print record which is just going to reference each individual coordinate in my colon if we
try it now end up with what you see here.
So using nested loops is definitely a thing with nested list.
However that also brings us to nested list comprehension.
So here's an example.
Here we have the same nest list three items that are each sub lists and they go 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
So just to print the value for each one of these.
All we have to do.
So instead of array brackets we have our exact same syntax but start here.
So for one is an L I think it's an L.
Yeah that's what it does for list and nested lists.
I mean that looks exactly like the one and the L S are the same.
I wouldn't name a variable once it must be an l.
So for lists in nested list for each one of these we then have this nested thing.
Print the value for Vout in L..
Then another example here of using a nested list comprehension is.
In this case to generate a nested list that could represent a game board or something.
And we're using range twice so we could start in either place.
We start here.
So are making.
This is going to be the individual lists inside the lists.
We're going to generate a range from 1 to 3.
It's not inclusive.
So one to three and for each number in there we're going to make a list so we end up with one of these.
So if we just ran this which we've done before we just get a single list.
One two three.
OK.
But we're doing that multiple times.
You can see for each value in the range one to three.
That means doing it three times.
We're going to generate this this and this.
So it's identical.
One two three one two three one two three.
And let's look at it now.
There we go.
And then here's another example this time using some lovely nested list comprehension plus conditional
logic.
OK.
I tried it.
I recorded a couple of versions of me explaining this last thing.
Let me try this again.
So this version is very similar to this except we have some additional conditional logic.
So rather than just generating the numbers 1 to 3 we're actually taking those numbers and we're deciding
if there even or odd are going to spit out an X or an 0 instead of 1 to 3.
So let's start with the simple part right here.
We're repeating this list generator this list comprehension that's nested three times.
So whatever we do we'll have three of them which is what we end up with.
And so what are we actually doing inside that list.
Well we're doing something three times again.
Range.
One two three.
And each time through we're going to call that number numb.
So numb starts at 1.
So then recheck is numb mode to not equal to zero.
So that means is it not even meaning is it odd.
And one is so we do an x next time through in the range we go from one up to two.
So two is too mad to not equal to zero.
That's false because it is even.
So we do.
Else 0 or so and so we get an 0 and then range goes up to three.
And that's the last time through.
And three is odds we put an X and then we repeat this whole thing for the next time through this range.
So this range started at 1.
Now we're at 2.
Then we go to three.
And that results in this.
So let's take a look at this and there we go.
X x x x x x.
So this would be like a tic tac toe game or three by three but let's say we wanted to generate the initial
state of a game board where let's in our game our board could start out as like star star star or slashes
and then as the game progresses we fill it in with X or so.
So if we just wanted to generate a three by three grid a multi dimensional array of soly asterisks all
we would have to do we start by repeating something three times.
So we'll just do star string for vowel in range one comma for or we could shift that.
Where'd that go.
No i lost it.
OK one more time I messed that up Arab star
for and we'll just call it I in range 1 comma 4 so we end up with three.
And what I'm trying to say before I lost it was that we could also do something like you know five to
nine.
And it doesn't matter.
Well actually that does matter.
It needs to be five to eight.
OK.
But we can shift this number up now to make it multi-dimensional instead of just doing a star.
We're going to repeat the same thing.
So in here if we just did this by the way we end up with just a single list with star but to add three
stars in they're going to do star four.
We could call it X it doesn't matter in range one comma for or we could do 4 x in 1 to 3 as a list does
not matter how we structure this.
But I think the simplest way is just to use a range.
Same thing here.
Range one comma for.
And there we go.
Oh gosh.
OK.
That was a lot.
So congratulations if you made it through here and made it through this.
If you just skipped to the end.
Well you found a good spot to skip to because it's the end.
We made it through.
OK.
So next up we have a couple of exercises.
There's one tiny topic I want to cover that will take a minute and then we're done with lists of these.