Welcome back.
In this video I just want to show how you could use the art module and some of the method chief seen
already to build some simple functions.
So we're going to do two things we're going to build one called contains phone and then another one
that's called Just say is valid phone.
Sometimes you know you might want to extract or actually instead of contention let's go with extract
phone.
So extract phone is going to take a big string and extract a single phone number or we can make it extract
all phone numbers that are found is valid phone is going to check if the entire string not if it contains
a phone number.
But if the entire string is a phone number then it will return true.
Otherwise return false.
First things first let's import Arri.
I have a new file called phoned up Hawai and extract phone will take in an input string let's just call
it input and then in here we're going to create our pattern.
So I'll call it phone rejects equals and then we need to do our compile our raw string and we'll just
do the exact same thing so four or three of these and then four digits.
No.
3 again dash.
Now we have four digits.
OK.
So just a basic one we can come back and add in the optional parens for the area code and a little bit.
So we have that and then we're just going to use input and we'll just go with a match equals and then
it's going to be phone rejects dot search input which is whatever string.
So we would call extract phone and then pass in you know my number is and then a number like this and
we want it to return this number and then all we really would need to do is just return match dot group
and if we test this out do it twice.
So let's print extract from a number and let's do another one.
But where there isn't a valid phone number.
Add an extra couple of digits.
And let's run our code which I called it phoned up Hawai and you'll see that it actually grabbed two
phone numbers because it matched the pattern twice.
And that's really a matter of my phone rejects not being a good good enough rejects because this is
a phone number right here.
But it also contained these two numbers.
So what we could do instead is say that before and after on either side there should be a word boundary
character.
If you don't remember what that means it's either going to be a space or the beginning or end of a line.
So if we test it now OK.
So it works on the first one.
The second one we get the error and this is what I was expecting to get attribute error none type object
has no attribute group.
So we can't just return Match.com group because in the case and there is no match we can't just call
non-DOD group that's what match would be.
Instead we need to first test what we have a couple options we could do a try block and catch an error.
What was the error catch attribute error.
I'm just going to do.
If a match like this then return matched group else what would we want in return.
It's up to us.
But I think Nona's fine return on so tested.
Now there we go.
We can also return empty strings that great could return false.
It's up to us to decide you know how we want to use extract phone.
But for now returning none is fine.
So this is extracting phone numbers let's just verify it works.
If the phone number is at the beginning or that the phone number is the only thing in there.
So let's add in a couple other things afterwards.
Here is a phone number.
The only thing in there it should extract perfect.
So it's working just great.
So that's extract phone.
And you know we could use this for any rechecks not just a phone number.
Extracting data from a string only extracts one.
So we could easily alter this to extract the multiple.
Just call this extract all phone or phones and keep this the same button match it's not going to be
fun rejects out the search it's going to be find all input if match return match group return None.
OK so I have these.
I'm going to just comment them out for now let's just copy one of them and call extract all phones.
My number is 4:03 tune up or call me at 3 4 5 6 6 6 dash 7.
OK.
There we go and let's see if it works we're printing it out.
Clear.
Nope not quite list.
Oh right that's my bad.
It returns a list.
It doesn't do all this match.
Remember from the last video if you saw it when we use find all it just returns a list right away.
So let's just return this
and let's test it.
There we go.
We get a list let's just verify what happens if there isn't a match in there like this.
It returns an empty list and that's fine.
I'm happy with that.
OK.
Moving on to the next example I mean just reformat this a bit.
Copy that.
OK.
Next up it's going to be is valid phone.
And a lot of time this is what I'm doing a lot of the time with projects is testing validating input.
We ask a user for input like you know enter a phone number using input or we have a Web site maybe where
it is a form suit and people need to enter a phone number.
We want to make sure it's a valid phone number not just some random digits or two digits or the string.
No thank you.
We're going to make sure it matches a pattern.
And of course it's not just e-mail or not just phone numbers e-mails credit card numbers addresses zip
codes all sorts of different things.
Def is valid phone.
Let's have a take and then put in the way that it should work is that if I call is valid phone ups and
I pass in let's just copy one of these a string that is a valid phone number it should return true and
make some space.
But if there's other stuff in there that should be false or if you know there isn't a phone number in
there at all.
That would still be false.
So it's not a matter of if it contains a phone number at all it's that it's only a phone number because
if a user you know we ask a user to enter a phone number and they enter in some other stuff along with
it it's not useful if a user enters in their email as you know call at blah dot com.
And then a bunch of other stuff afterwards we can send an e-mail to that.
We need to make sure that it's a valid e-mail.
So let's fix that.
Let's get this working.
We're going to use our same phone rejects paste that in.
The only difference is that instead of using FIND ALL or search we could still use search.
By the way what we could do.
Let's actually do that now.
Let me copy the search here and copy all this logic but what you'll need to do is change our regular
expression.
Remember this year where we add a carrot at the beginning where you care.
There it is.
So instead of a boundary character we want carrot which means it has to start with these three digits
and then a dollar sign which means it has to end with these four digits.
So nothing comes after it.
Nothing comes before just a slight alteration to the pattern.
But now if we test it let's see what happens I'm not printing any of these.
I me just quickly add in a print.
OK.
Let's see if it works.
So we should get.
True False False.
If it works and oh well we don't get true and false but it's working.
We just need to return the correct values now.
So instead of if match return match that group we could just to return true otherwise return false.
And we get true false false which is perfect.
That's how it should work.
It validates if this is a phone number.
There is another option which is to do this Aldus to find them twice.
We have a phone project so we could use the same rejects from before.
But instead of doing phone rejects that search we can do full match and full match is going to take
this rejects and only return a match if the entire input string is a match.
We don't have to add these characters in.
We could reuse the same rejects from before not have to edit it in any way and instead use full match.
And if I come in this version out we should get the same result.
And we do.
So I'm going to go with the second option for now I'm going to leave both of them here but comment this
one out.
One thing that you might be wondering about is I'm compiling them all separately.
This is being duplicated.
This line across all of my functions and it would make sense to not do that if we wanted all of these
functions to use the same regular expression in our application.
But I'm going to leave them in here rather than defining it up top is something that we could access
and all the functions.
I mean just define them in each individual function just so that if students happened to copy and paste
one part of this their code will still work.
They don't have to have the entire file.
Ok so this was nothing groundbreaking we just used some of the methods we saw in the last video but
hopefully you see now how you can use you know army and regular expressions and patterns inside of python
and some potentially useful ways or extracting phone numbers or a single phone number all phone numbers
and then retesting if a given string is exactly a phone number and nothing else nothing less.
It has to match this pattern.
Exactly.
OK.
We have a couple more things to talk about.
Coming up next.