All right.
So we've seen how to define instance attributes and instance methods.
Now we're going to talk about class attributes and then following this class methods.
So if an instance attribute is defined on each individual instance of a class on each user object a
class attribute is defined once and it lives on the class itself.
So directly on the class and they are shared.
So whatever class attributes we define are shared by all instances they kind of all point to the same
class attribute.
So let me show you what I mean.
So I'm back in the same user file where I have my class User net and then a couple of instance methods.
I'll start off by saying that class attributes and methods are used far less often than instance attributes
and instance methods.
But with that said this is a video on class attributes so I better come up with an example.
And the first one I'm going to show you has to do with keeping track of how many users we've created.
So let's say that this is modeling a chat room now.
And I went to the Facebook Messenger and I want to know when to keep track of how many users are active
at any given moment.
So I could say something like five users online for users online.
So what I'm going to do is define my class variable and the syntax for that is we just put it up here
and we don't write self.
So if I just define a method or a variable in here or in here if I said something like I don't know.
Count equals zero.
This is a variable scoped to full name.
But if I wanted to be part of the class or defined as a class attribute I'll come up here or anywhere.
That's not in one of those methods.
But traditionally you do it up top let's call this one.
Active users and set it equal to zero.
OK.
So what we've done now is define a class attribute called active users and it exists one time on the
User class itself not on the individual instances of user.
And the way we actually refer to it if I wanted to print active users I could come down here or comment
everything out and just do print.
And I refer to the class name user that active users.
So I don't refer to the instances anymore just use you're not active users.
It started it starts at zero.
But see if we're right and we get zero OK.
So let's say Now any time a new users initialized we're going to add one to active users.
So we don't write self.
It's going to be user active users plus equals 1.
So any time a new user is created and it runs automatically This code is all for the instance self.
So the individual instance last name age first name this is referring to the class attribute or a class
variable.
Active Users who we're adding one to it.
OK.
So let's test this out.
We're going to print it out and then let's create or to use or so I'm going to copy this.
Put it afterwards.
And then let's print active users again.
So we should see zero and then to after we create these two users let's test it cool zero and then two.
All right.
So we could also do something like define a method called log out and all that log out does is let's
make it an instance method because it's going to print something like I don't know Jane logged out.
Jane left the chat room.
So we'll make that an F string that will return.
And it should say self-taught first has logged out.
But before that we're going to decrement user data active users.
OK.
So when log out as called on an individual instance of user We're going to refer to the class variable
active users and subtract one from it.
Remember there's only one copy of this at any given time.
We could have a thousand different users.
There's only one user that active users they're all referring to it when we write user active users.
And then I'm going to return self-doubt first as logged out.
Let's test this out.
So I'll do.
Print user 2 dot log out.
And then let's print active users again.
So we should see zero active users add to.
So then we should T-2 and then we should see a log out method and then we should go down to one active
user and moment of truth there we go 0 users.
Then we created to then block a logged out.
So we're left with one.