Hey welcome back.
And this video to show you a tool called auto PEP 8 and it's a package that you need to download if
you're going to use it and it will automatically format your Python code to conform to the PEP 8 style
guide.
So this is a guide that we talked about earlier in the course but it just explains some conventions
you should follow.
You know when you're using comments for example don't use an extra indentation or for scroll down.
What else do we have.
You know tabs vs spaces.
Maximum length of lines when you should wrap it over on the next line.
There's a lot of stuff that is kind of well it's pretty specific compared to some other style guide
to languages.
And you don't have to do this yourself.
You can use Otto PEP 8 back on the documentation.
All we need to do is start by installing.
I already have it but it's Python 3 dash em Pip install auto PEP 8 number 8 and tells me requirement
already satisfied.
Ok so I already have it and I have a file that we're going to use it on.
So this file is messy and it has a bunch of problems in it.
For example this is a long comment.
It should be wrapped to fit within 72 characters according to the PEP 8 style guide.
I'm not going to count 72 characters personally here.
I have no extra space in this tuple.
What else is going on you know a long string.
There's a couple of other things you know.
Some very long dictionary.
You get it.
We're going to just work on inventing things properly and formatting it nicely and you'll see what a
difference auto 8 makes.
The syntax can be quite complex.
If you want to use all the options.
I'll just point out some of the more important ones.
So when we run it we're going to call auto PEP 8 from the command line and I usually run an in place
so you can tell it to run in place which Where do they explain that.
Here we go using dash I or dash dash in place make changes to the file and place.
I usually have no reason to keep the first version that's all ugly.
I just want the nice pretty fried version.
So that's one option to pass in.
You also can Pessin an option called aggressive or dash A has a flag and what this will do.
Most of the changes that auto pep it makes relate to whitespace adding lines in string to getting too
long or your dictionaries are getting too long.
Figuring out how to format things nicely removing trailing spaces all that stuff.
But there are certain things that if you tell it to be more aggressive it will change.
For example in the style guide it tells you if you're checking if a variable is true or false.
You don't use is and you're not supposed to use double equals either.
Instead you should just say if greeting or if not greeting or something like that instead of using is
or double equals and if you have this in your code and you use auto 8 without aggressive it won't change
this it will just fix whitespace problems like we've already talked about.
But if you do tell it to be aggressive it will fix this and it will change it to this anyway.
So as far as usage we're going to start with autopap 8 dash dash in place and then the file name.
So in my terminal I'll paste that in the file name.
Oh I already forgot I called it ugly code.
P Y.
And you just run this on whatever file you want.
Make sure you're in the same directory.
Takes a moment.
Doesn't look like anything happened.
But if I go back to my file hopefully saw that change.
No code has been changed other than whitespace being added or removed.
Most of it was being added.
In our case to make it a lot nicer to look at you know very clear what's happening now and I'm going
to add a little bit of extra code here just to show something of a value like cat.
Let's say is cat owner is true.
And then I want to add a statement like if is cat owner and I'll start with saying double equals let's
say true if that's the case then I'm going to print out OK.
So see what it looks like before and if I go back and run it.
But this time I add in.
Well if I just run it on its own again you'll see it didn't change that because it's only doing white
space changes.
But if I run it now with Dash a I don't want to type Dasch aggressive dash a tells it to be aggressive.
And I think that only did one level of aggressiveness.
I think we have to do two separate Dasch ways to tell it to be doubly aggressive which as we go you
can see it now changed.
If is cat owner print me out.
So I just wanted to show you that there are different levels.
I'm not entirely clear at what happens at each particular level but if you just want for mounting of
the white space you don't need to use dash or dash aggressive at all.
If you do want it to take care of things like this then you can use to dash.
In this example but the big point I want to make here is that external modules like this external packages
can really help us out.
Nobody wants to sit here and do this on their own and memorize all these rules even.
Because if you're switching between programming languages it differs and there's a lot to keep track
of just as far as the syntax itself let alone the style guides and conventions.
So it's much easier in my opinion at least to use something like auto Peppi and as a final note there
is a sublime text package if you are using sublime that you can install that will do this for you in
sublime.
So you don't even have to you know run it from the command line.
It is just a command you run in sublime that will do it.
I'm not going to go through the installation process because in one of my other courses I did show something
similar in a sublime package.
It wasn't for Python and I don't think I've ever had more problems or more questions about something.
It just works very differently on everybody's machine between Macs and PCs and different versions of
software.
You know OS whatever versus Sierra.
Anyway it was just a nightmare.
So I'm not going to go through and cement it in my video and never be able to change it.
I highly recommend it.
If you do use sublime all the time go to the get hub repo and you can follow the instructions.
Anyway that's auto pep 8.