All right this video we're going to see a built in function.
This one is called sorted.
It's different than sort which we saw earlier.
It's a list method sorted.
Is it built in function that will work with other other iterable collections other than lists.
For example we could pass in a tuple and the syntax is a bit different as well.
It looks like this sorted and then we pass in.
So instead of doing list sort which actually will list a particular list.
In this case we pass in you know a list or a tuple and I'll show you an example but here's the first
one more numbers.
It's just 6 1 8 into a list.
If we pass it into sorted in the most basic way without any other additional parameters or arguments
that I'll show you it will sorted like this but it does not change more numbers so it returns a copy
that is sorted.
But notice that more numbers it's unsorted still down here.
So that's different than the way that sort works.
So it could have Nom's and just do some random numbers and 5 5 and 3 something like this.
Right.
And if I did numskulls sort remember it actually sorts Nom's in place in the names list.
But if I redefined Nomes and now I do sorted numbs it returns a sorted version and Gnome's is unchanged
OK.
So the next thing I'll show you we can change the direction that we're sorting things.
Setting reverse to true.
And now if we look at it it goes in descending order from 55 down to 1 and still Nom's is unchanged.
Oh and before I forget.
Let me just show you.
You can also do it on a tuple could do.
Sorted and I'll just pass in a tuple and here like to come one come a 45 and 23 in 99 like that.
And it still returns a list.
But it's important to know that it can accept a tuple unlike dot sort which is a list specific method.
OK.
So I showed reverse that this is where it gets more powerful when we're about to show you sorting numbers
is easy enough.
But what if we have data that looks like this.
So here's our user data from our Twitter social media clone and let's say I want to sort them by user
name.
It's not as easy as just saying sorted users because users of the list.
And if I just try and sort it like this it does not like that I passed in this list of dictionaries
and less than is non-supported between instances of dict and dict.
It can't compare.
You know which one comes before the other and there's no way for it to quantify it.
So we get an error message.
So we need to specify what we actually want it to sort on what is the special piece of data that it
should use to sort.
So the parameter will use is called key.
This is how we specify what should be sorted or how it should be sorted.
But then the trickier thing is how we actually tell it to sort.
Well we could do the most basic one let me just show you the simplest one.
I just do Len and it will run length line on every single dictionary.
Dictionaries do you have a length.
I think right now this all have basically the same length.
It counts the number of keys I believe.
So these all have user name and tweets.
But if I edited them just to add in some random keys like a is equal to color is purple and down here
I'll say no is 10.
And one more random key.
This one also has a color set to teal.
OK so this dictionary here has one key two key three four keys.
So it should be the longest.
And then this one has one two three keys and all the rest only have two.
OK so if we try sorting that way I'm going to paste the new users data in and if I do sorted users comma
key equals Len it's going to try and use the length of each dictionary to sort and you can see it does
it in ascending order.
So we get things sorted by the length.
The last two items in here.
This is the longest dictionary.
And then this is the second longest the one with purple.
So that's probably not how we actually want to sort them.
We want to sort them by user name alphabetically so instead of key equals Len.
Well we're going to need to use our friend the lambda and let's see what should our parameter be called.
Let's go with the user colon and then we just want to sort of based off of user user name.
OK so this is basically telling the key to sort of is the user user name for each user in there.
I know it's kind of bizarre.
You think the lambda syntax but let's see if we're right.
What happens so now we start off at Bob and then doggo lover guitar gal Jeff and then finally Samuel.
So we're now starting using the username but we can also do things like sort based off of who has the
most tweets who's most active and to do that instead of duplicate this we have a record of that set
of user user username.
What a mouthful.
Well sort of based off of the tweets but we don't want to just sort by use or tweets.
We want to sort by the length of user tweets.
OK so now it's going to run.
Figure out the length.
So this user has three tweets this one has one this from zero.
So copy this over tested out.
And so we get zero tweets zero tweets all the way up to Samuel at the end who has three tweets and it's
working.
And if you want to reverse it we do reverse equals true.
And now we'll get a list of our users sorted from most active to least active.
I have one more example.
If we had a list of songs like we do here each song has a title and it also has a play count how would
I sort by play count.
So I want to you know have a list of my most most commonly played songs.
Well it would look something like this sordid and then songs and what's the key.
If I can type piki.
There you go.
It's going to be either Lamda and let's just call each one of.
And we want to sort by play count.
And that should be it.
Let's paste it in.
Here's our songs.
Song is like that.
There we go.
Now let's sort them by play count and so we have.
Happy birthday on this one play all the way up to YMCA has 99.
So of course we could also do reverse equals.
True and now we get most popular most played songs down to our least played songs.
OK so that is sorted.
The key differences between sort is that sort Z-list method only works on lists.
It actually sorts in place so it doesn't return a copy.
It alters your original sorted we'll accept other iterable collections like tuples not only lists and
also we can pass in things like a lambda to specify exactly the key that it should be sorted based off
of.
So this is commonly used if we have objects like this in a list and we want to sort based off of a property
in those objects call.