All right welcome back.
So we have one small topic to talk about around importing our own custom modules and it has to do with
this special underscore or Dondre double underscore name variable.
So double underscore name double underscore.
So remember that those are sort of special properties that you're not supposed to do anything with.
It's supposed to touch them but they exist.
And the way that name works every file every module has its own name variable.
So Python gives it the name variable and by default the value of double underscore name in the main
file that is being run is equal to double underscore main double underscore main.
So let me just show you to make this a bit clearer.
It's a very weird thing to talk about with slides only so sublime I have two different files one is
called Say hi.
And one is called say stop like if you've never heard that before it's a slang term for what's up.
I don't know if people still say it but say hi and say sup and all I'm going to do is to find a single
function called Say hi no parameters and it's just going to print high and then afterwards my name is
and I'll send it to my double underscore name is and then all interpolates and F string double underscore
name OK.
And then let's execute say hi once at the bottom just like this.
So now when I run this Python 3 say hi we get Hi my name is Main.
So I'm going to copy this and twitch it to say sup S U P.
And the only difference I'll have here is my name is and I'll keep that the same but I'll just have
it say sup and then we'll call say sup very silly I know but if I execute this and I call a supped up
I get the same thing.
Sup.
My name is Main.
So all of this shows us is that this name variable is set equal to Main in the main file when we execute
the file.
So I'm directly executing say sup.
So in that case.
Inside of that file name is set to main.
But now let's require one inside the other.
So at the top of say Hi I'm now going to import and I'll do from sets up import the say sub function.
So from this file import this function just like this.
And then after say hi let's call say sup.
Right.
So it's going to run.
Say hi first and we should see.
Hi my name is and whatever name is inside of say hi.
And then we'll run say up and we should see what name is instead of say sup.
So let's see what happens.
Clear this out and I run say hi that's the file hit enter and when you look at that it's kind of weird
right.
We have three things showing up.
So even though we only executed two functions three things are showing up and not only that but the
very first thing to run is Suppe.
My name is say sup then.
Hi my name is Maine.
And then Suppe.
My name is say South.
Ok I'm tired of saying stuff but what's happening here.
Well explain it in detail in just a moment.
But the file itself that we're running is called Say hi.
That's the main file.
So the value of name instead of say high will be main If it's the main file we're running.
Say Suppe is not the main file we're running.
It's being imported.
And so the value of it is the name of that file which in this case is say sup.
So name is just a variable that refers to the name of the module unless it is the main file that you're
executing.
But then why are we seeing such.
My name is say sup first.
Why is that happening.
And to understand that we go back to the slides just to recap in every file if it's the main file being
executed the value of name is mine.
Otherwise if it's being imported It's the value of name is the file name.
OK so here's what happens when we actually import something.
Python tries to find the module.
So it's looking for a file called say subtype p y.
If it doesn't find it throws an error but if it does find it which is what happened in our example it
runs the code inside of the module that's being imported.
So inside of say sup remember I'm calling say sup.
So even though I'm only calling it once in this file which is this is the only file I'm trying to run
because it's running in this file or because I am calling it in this file the first thing that happens
is Python says OK I'm looking for say sup.
Oh I found it.
I get to execute it.
So it runs that file and then it sees 0.
He also wants me to do say hi and now say sup again.
So to prevent code from being run if it's not in the main file which are execute there's a little trick
we can do.
It's pretty simple.
We're just going to check if name is equal to men then we'll run that code and that way it will only
run if it's in the main file that's being executed.
So we could fix our problem where say is is being executed before say hi or just coming over here to
say sup and AB adding an if statement that says if double underscore name is equal to Main then we'll
run say sup.
So this will only run if I'm actually executing say Septem why.
Otherwise it's just going to be imported and it won't be executed.
So let's test it.
If I run say hi again.
Now we only get high and then Suppe which is what's supposed to happen and if ii executes say sup directly.
Now I get something.
My name is man because I'm directly executing this file.
So name is equal to mine.
So it's kind of a weird concept but really the main takeaway.
Every module has a name variable double underscore name double underscore.
If you are directly running that file by calling it Python 3 whatever Python 3 file Doppie why that
file the code in that module will have names set to mean like this.
Otherwise it will be set to the name of the file which is what we see here where name is say stuff.
So hopefully that explanation made sense.
I know its kind of weird but this is the work around.
You'll see it pretty commonly.
It's how we can ignore code when we import a module.