You'll get next up to more built in functions this time a pair max and min.
So they work very similarly except they do the opposite thing.
So Max will tell you there's a couple ways of using it.
You can pass it two or more individual arguments and it will tell you the max you know and Max numeric
value or the max alphanumeric value if it's string characters.
So I can show an example of that we could do something like max of three sixty seven and ninety nine
and it tells us Max is 99.
OK.
So that's the simplest way to use it.
Or we could do you know individual strings like C D.
And how about a.
And it tells us d is the max.
And that's because of the way that strings are weighted.
Right.
It goes from A to Z.
We can also pass in and iterable like a list or a string or a dictionary or a tuple and it will it will
tell us the maximum item and that iterable.
And this still seems maybe not that useful but we could have a list of numbers and these numbers can
be totally random right like this.
And then I could just ask for the max of.
And while I'm here you know I'll show you mine does the same thing except opposite.
So it tells me that the minimum number there is five.
OK.
We could also just to show you to Max Peston a string like hello world like this.
And it tells me the max is w.
If I did man instead the men I think is going to be e.
Oh no.
The space comes to 40 anyway.
So this is an iterable thing remember to string.
So this counts.
I can also do max on a tuple.
That's the last thing I'll show before a show a more exciting example I have a tuple here that gives
me 65 is the max.
OK.
So that's OK enough but let's say we have this list of names.
So I'll just paste it in.
OK.
Aryeh Sampson Dora.
Tim and all of.
And I want to know the minimum or the maximum length.
So if I just did man of names it's going to give me Aryeh because alphabetically I think is how it's
doing it.
Or is it based off of the index.
I don't know by default.
No it's doing it alphabetically which is not what we want.
Suppose I want to know the shortest name in here who has the shortest name or the longest would be the
same logic.
OK so there's a couple of options.
The first thing we could do if I just wanted to know the length itself of the shortest number I could
do men and then length Lenn for name for name and names.
So this is just like what we did with all.
And with any this is a generator expression too we don't have to do.
Well first of all it tells me the shortest length is three.
So if we just copy this remember.
If you watch that video I get a generator object generator expression.
And we don't have to actually put in those lists brackets.
But if I did put in the list brackets to do I would get the likes 4 6 4 3 10 and then I find the men
on that.
But because I'm not using this list for anything I don't need those brackets.
If you didn't watch the video on any and all that goes into more detail than that.
But the problem here this is just giving us the shortest the actual length itself.
What if I want the name Tim or if I did Max instead I would want it to give me all Cavender instead
of whatever this is eight or nine characters.
Maybe it's more anyway to do that.
It's a little bit more complex.
You need to use a lambda first and he's going to copy this over here so we have a record of it.
If you're looking at this.
OK.
So let's do Max this time.
I want to find the longest name so the longest in names comma and just like with sort I can pass in
a key in key.
Going I set to a lambda again and I'll call the perimeter.
And so this is how we specify the way things should be sorted to figure out the men or the max.
So what's the property.
And we want length of and that makes sense.
So Lamda if you totally awesome lambastes don't stress it too much but go back and watch solemnised
video.
But what we have here is this little anonymous thing a function essentially where we have a parameter
and inch for each one of these.
We're going to call this take the end and do length and.
And that's the expression that's returned so that will be a number like two or three or five or seven.
And then we're going to use that to judge the max and that's how Max works.
If you pass in key.
So let's see what we get.
All of it.
And if we did the same thing but change it to men we get Tim.
So what we saw here was giving us the actual shortest length itself.
Here is using that length to find the shortest name and give us the name.
One more example are same songs list we've been using.
Let's say I want to find the minimum let's say I want the song that has the least number of place.
So that would be men and then I'll use a again.
So first I need to tell it to sort songs or to use songs.
And then the key is going to be Lamda and we'll go with the song.
I like to keep this short just.
S stands for song though.
And what's the property play count.
Like that and mutts.
Well first we need to tell Python over here about songs and now I'll paste this one in but if we get
there we go.
Happy birthday has the least number of place and if I did Max
I guess YMCA and would say I only wanted the title right.
I want to find the title of the song is played the most.
I could just tack on title and they get YMCA because this is returning to me a dictionary.
And then if I just add title there that will give me the title of the most played song.
OK.
So copy that over as well so you can see a pattern here.
A lot of these built in functions I'm showing you on.
They work on one level.
They're simple but then you can specify kind of an additional argument or parameter where you pass in
the lambda that makes it a more flexible syntactically more confusing.
But if you're able to wrap your head around lambdas and what's actually happening here this is a really
nice way if you need to do something like minimax although it's not that hard to do it yourself.
If we wanted to recreate this right here we would just loop through for song in songs we'd have a variable
called Max right and we could set it equal to the first song or something song.
Zero doesn't matter equal to zero.
And then all we do is we loop through here and we check ok if song play count is greater than max then
we'll just set max equals.
Song play count and it's going to loop through each time.
And if it finds a new max it updates the max variable and then at the end we could print Max but this
is easier.
All right.
So I'll comment this up and then this will be in the resources if you want to download it.