All right.
So next in our string of string videos very funny I know we are talking about something called concatenation.
So a quick video.
Basically this boils down to adding two strings together.
What happens when you have a string in a plus sign and another string.
And the answer is probably what you'd expect.
It just shows the strings together.
So here's an example.
I have two strings one called string one is equal to your and string two is equal to face.
Now if I make a new variable called string three or I could just print the result out and I make it
equal to string one plus a space plus string two.
Well I get your space face kind of right.
If we didn't have the space here then it would just Chevon together as your phrase one word.
But we had that space in because we want that space so it says your face anyway.
That's really it.
To the basics of concatenation.
But I'm going to add on a little tangent in just a moment but let me hop over now to our terminal and
I'll just quickly demonstrate a common example.
Let's say your ASCII user username equals and this is me asking a user what's your user name and they
type in the answer and we're simulating that.
So maybe they say blew the cat that's my cat's name.
Then we might want to add a little greeting that says Hello there and welcome to the game.
And then comma and then I want to add in username.
So that's all I need to do.
And that plus sign but I need to pay attention to that space because if it's not there I don't get a
space it's not catastrophic if there's a comma but it could you know make things really hard to read.
So we had that space.
All right.
So that's the basics of concatenation.
You can do it multiple times you could do a plus b plus Z and we get ABC.
Now this brings us to an important point which is what if I tried to do eight plus.
Hello.
What do you think will happen.
And there we go.
We get unsupported operand types.
So Python basically goes through this it's having a great time.
Like OK 8 we're dealing with integers and plus.
OK that's an operator for an integer ridable I had two numbers.
So we're working with numbers great.
I'm expecting a number expecting a number.
Oh no what the heck is going on.
This is a string.
It doesn't know what to do.
So it doesn't do anything it gives up.
I mean what would you expect it to do.
I guess theoretically it could turn 8 into this string eight and give us eight.
A low but it doesn't do that obviously.
So you have to be aware of the context and with concatenation at least you need to be working with strings.
So if we tried to do something like you know a common example we'll see in a little bit we'll make a
guessing game.
We ask the user what's your guess and they might say My guess is nine and then we want to print something
out that says your guess of let me add quotes in here your guess of 9 or whatever they guessed.
UPS Plus guess plus is wrong if we want to do this.
We're going to encounter that problem because guess is a number and it's going to try and add number
to string to string and either quotation mark or parentheses excuse me.
But either way it doesn't work because we're working with strings and and we can't add them together.
OK so just be conscientious that there's a solution we'll see in the next video.
The only other thing I'll point out there's an operator that we haven't seen called plus equals.
It's just a nice little shortcut when you're reassigning variables.
So here's an example.
We have string one is equal to ice and I am updating it by adding in Creem spaced cream using plus equals
that makes a new value of string 1.
Ice space cream.
So rather than having to say string one equals string one plus ice plus cream I'm able to just say plus
equals.
So I could do name equals colds and then rather than if I wanted to add my last name onto this rather
than doing name equals name plus Steele like this whenever you see name equals name plus or variable
equals the same variable name plus you can replace it with plus equals.
Just like that name plus equals still.
Now if I look at name it's called Steel.
So this is concatenation in action but it's not limited to strings.
I could do people because ninety nine and then say people plus equals one.
And now I look at people and it's 100 and with numbers we also have access to things like minus equals
So let's go down by 10.
Look at people now.
So it's taking the value of people and subtracting 10 and re-assigning that two people could even do
multiply or star equals.
Now we look at people and it's 900 and now at this point the word people just looks weird and looks
like it's spelled wrong to me.
And staring at it too long.
But really this is about concatenation adding two strings together.
And then this thing at the end about plus equals it's just a nice thing that you'll see me use just
to save some time.
But you do not have to know about or don't have to use.