OK next I'm just going to do a quick demonstration of where a generator excels.
So a classic example is working with Fibonacci numbers.
If you're not familiar with the Fibonacci sequence you can write out the first few.
What do we have here 2 3 5 8 13.
OK.
So know it always starts with one and one I believe.
And you basically to get the next number in the sequence you add together the previous two.
So one and one gives us 2 to 1 gives us 3 3 and 2 5 5 and 3 8 in 5 13.
Keep going these numbers grow pretty quickly and to keep calculating them.
We could use a regular old function.
Let's say I want to generate the first one million with the example or actually what I have down here.
What does this count right here.
Yeah this is a million.
I want to get the first one million without using a generator or any iterator.
It doesn't have to be a generator.
But without using anything just using a regular function I would need to put them in a list here or
I have a list called Nom's.
I have two variables a zero B is one.
And then I guess the first number is zero in the sequence.
Oh well.
And then while the length of that list is less than the max.
So while there are less than 1 million numbers in in the list we're going to append B.
It will start by adding 1 and then we're going to swap the numbers so a is now equal to be.
So is now 1 and then B is equal to A plus B which is a plus 1 which is 1.
But next time around it now you know ads and B together to get to and then keeps going and keeps going.
So hopefully you can see how this works.
If not it's not necessarily the focus of this video anyway but just to show you that it does work.
We could do something like print fib list of 10 and this will give us 10 numbers.
So it's not up to 10 like you know the highest Fibonacci number below 10.
It is a 10 number in the sequence and if we run it.
OK.
So there we go.
We're getting the data back.
It's in a list.
We don't really have any other option if we're using a regular old function because we have to keep
track of what came before and to get to the millionth Fibonacci number.
We have to have every number before that one.
So the list starts to grow really really long.
And if I were to do something like $1 million we don't even have to print it let's just say I want to
generate it.
How many zeros again.
All right here's one million.
So this will give me the first one million Fibonacci numbers.
I'm going to run it and then I'm going to cut over to my computer's activity monitor on my Mac and we'll
take a look at how much memory is being used.
OK you started it.
Now I did a search for Python over here and my activity monitor.
If we open it up we can see what it's saying.
Real memory size 503 megabytes.
OK.
And I think I'm going to stop this process because my computer is not very happy when I'm recording
a video and running a script like this.
So I'm going to stop it.
But 490 megabytes a big number.
You can see.
And that's just the real memory size.
But let's just focus on that.
OK.
Now down here I have a generator that does the same thing and that it generates the Fibonacci sequence.
But all that it does.
So we have X and Y and sort of a and b started 0 and 1 and then I have a count instead of using the
length of the list.
There is no list with the generator.
So it's just a counter.
Starts at zero while the counter is less than the max.
While it's less than a million each time we add one to count and then all we do is the exact same thing
where we have X and Y and we assign the value of Y to X and then we update Y to be exposed Y and then
we yield x.
And so if we did something simple like 4 and 5 Jan for 10 if we print and we get 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
first 10 Fibonacci numbers.
OK.
So the difference of course just like our last video.
They're not in the list.
We're just getting one at a time and it's not storing however many analysts at the same time from trying
to get the millionth Fibonacci number.
It's not storing all nine hundred ninety nine thousand nine hundred ninety nine numbers before before
it.
And we're just getting the current one.
So if I do this instead.
See I think I need another zero.
There we go.
1 million using the Fibonacci generator instead of the list.
I run it cut to my activity monitor.
Take a look 6.7 megabytes.
Serious very drastic difference 6.7 compared to how many hundred megabytes it was for the last version.
And I'm actually printing it here as well.
So in the other example I wasn't although that shouldn't have a massive difference on memory should
more be about time.
But anyway that's kind of a cool example.
This looks cool but I'm worried about having a seizure.
Hopefully my point here is clear.
So I'm not.
The point is not that lists are slower because oftentimes using a generator actually will be slower
than the alternative but instead a generator is easier on memory especially if you're dealing with really
large sequences are things that if you stored in a list the list would grow massive.
And when I say big I'm not talking about a thousand or a couple thousand results I'm talking hundreds
or thousands or millions of data points.
Things grow really really large when you use bursts.
But if you instead use a generator the difference can be significant.
Again not in time necessarily but in memory.
That wraps this up.
The last thing about generators will show you is called generator expressions.
Quick and easy.
See you then.