Hey I'm back and it's time for a quick little code along where usually what I do with these catalogs
is try and just synthesize the things that we've learned individually on the slides and build something
slightly more substantial putting the pieces together.
But I'm also going to introduce something we haven't seen which are nested conditionals.
So in a two second preview it's just a if instead of an F..
OK.
So what we're going to do is build a very silly bouncer program that just ask for users age and in the
US at least you can often get into concerts if you are older or if you're over 18 but you can't drink
until you're over 21.
So sometimes you have to wear like a special wristband if you're 18 or 19 or 20.
And then if you're below 18 you can't get in at all.
So build a super simple little program that spits out text depending on an input age.
But then we're also going to handle errors and very rough handling of errors.
For example if a user doesn't type in an age at all it will break our code.
But we're going to add in a little conditional check to prevent that.
OK.
So I have a file I called it bouncer.
P Why.
Call it whatever you want and I'll start by just laying out the rules or the pseudo code.
So we asked for age and then our ages are between 18 and 21.
You wear wristbands wristband if you're 21 plus you can drink normal entry.
And finally Otherwise you're too young.
OK.
So let's start by asking for age.
So we'll just right.
Age equals input.
How old are you.
And all out of space here.
Just so we don't end up with that weird kind of text running into each other on the command line.
And then let's just start right off with our if so will change us around as we go through this but we'll
start it just an if and let's just check for users between the ages between 18 and 21.
So we're going to do if age is greater than or equal to 18.
And age is less than 21.
We don't want less than or equal to 21 because if you are 21 in the US you can drink.
So if that's the case we'll print out.
You can enter but need a wristband.
Now here's the thing.
This isn't going to work right off the bat.
Can you tell why.
And the answer is that it has to do with data types.
Remember that this comes in as a string.
The value returned from input in age is a string.
And here we're comparing strings to numbers and that won't work if you try it here.
Let's say somebody entered that they are 19.
So as a string is 19 greater than or equal to 18.
The answer is no because type error greater than or equal to not supported between string.
And so that's our problem.
So we need to solve that.
And the simplest way of fixing that that we've seen is to cast things as it is.
So it's fine for us to assume that ages are going to be whole numbers so we could do it.
Age and age just like this.
And if we run this code now it is Python 3 bouncer.
How old are you.
Nineteen.
You can enter but need a wristband.
And just to make sure I entered too.
We get nothing.
OK.
So that's good.
Next up attended the case where your older than 21.
So that's an L if int age is greater than or equal to 21.
If that's the case we will Prince you are good to enter and can drink.
OK the last thing we need is our colon here at the end.
And if we try running this now Python 3 pouncer.
How old are you.
If you're 18 you can interpret need to respond.
If we are 25 you're good to enter and you can drink.
Perfect.
So let's add in or else which will just be print.
You can't come in little on and let's add a sad face.
So let's test it.
And this time will enter 9.
Can't come in.
But everything else still works right.
We have 18.
You can enter it but you need to expand.
And if we are 67 you're good to enter and can drink.
So this seems good.
There are a couple problems.
Well there's one main problem which is if an end user just hit enter empty string doesn't work when
you're running it on age and you have an empty string and just kind of freak out and give us this invalid
literal for into base 10.
Basically doesn't know how to turn that into an integer.
So what we're going to do is add a simple IF statement to check if it's an empty string or not.
And so what we want to do what we could do is say if age is equal to or is not equal to empty string
we could do this and then indent everything inside of that if the other option then we can actually
start with that.
So let me just rearrange my comments a bit.
Remember indentation Well it doesn't matter for the comments except to make it clear what's happening.
But it does matter when we're dealing nested if statements so we have if age is not equal to the empty
string.
All of this is going to be indented because we only want to check the ages and then turn it into an
integer.
If it's not an empty string and if it is so wide add an ELSE We'll just print please enter an age.
OK so let's see what happens now.
Oh OK so we're missing our colon.
There we go.
Try that again.
How old are you.
If I hit enter it says Please enter an age.
But if I enter 12 says you can't come in little one.
Now this check I should be clear is only working for empty strings.
We still have the problem of someone entering a or this as their age.
We're not going to solve that in this video.
There's not a super easy way we will learn a way of handling errors and trying Well we'll get there.
But for now we're just focusing on the case of an empty string for use or just hit enter so we could
do it this way.
The other option is to do it with a kind of shorter shortcut.
Taking advantage of the fact that an empty string is falsie.
So all we can do is say if age do this otherwise.
Print please enter page.
So remember if there's anything in age a 1 to whatever the number or text in there it's truthy.
But if it's empty it's falsie meaning this will be triggered.
So this is an easier way of doing it.
If there's an age do this math.
The other change I would support.
First let's just make sure it works.
Oh my gosh I keep forgetting my colons.
Try that again.
We enter age.
It works.
If I just hit enter though it says please and turn age.
Now what we could do is refactor this into.
Age and age were casting age to an end multiple times and the fact is we're not using age anywhere except
as an integer so it would be better just to do.
Age equals int age and then get rid of all of these instances where casting it just like that.
So this is more of just a stylistic thing there's no reason to continually turn it into an integer.
Just do it once inside this statement because if we did this up top did it here we would encounter that
problem if they didn't end turn age with an empty string.
It would break our program so we're going to leave it like this.
OK and let's make sure this works now
we are 19 you can enter we're 21 you can enter and drink and we are eight.
You can't come in.
And if we hit an empty string please and turn age OK.
So this this all works good.
I just want to hit home a couple of things.
The indentation really matters like it has with our single statements.
It also matters if we want these to be nested inside of this if so for this code to run this has to
be true.
But for this code to run this has to be true and this has to be true.
So that's that's important.
And we could keep nesting these further and further and further.
The other thing I could point out you don't have to do nested statements like this.
We could rewrite the whole thing by saying if age and a and I'll just copy this right here.
So we could rewrite this first bit at least by just putting it all in one giant if statement if age
exists and age is greater than equal to 18 and ages less and 21.
Then we'll print.
You can enter but need a wristband and then we can also say elif.
Age and age is greater than or equal to 21 and we don't need the parentheses on this one.
Then we could print.
You are good to enter and can drink.
Hopefully you can see what I'm doing here where basically we just put this part in front of each of
these and it's the same idea.
But this is much nicer and shorter and cleaner and you can see how things are related.
So that because we're using it and remember if this was false the whole thing is false.
Well if this is false all of this is false.
Never never event runs.
All right.
The only other change I would suggest is we're not really doing this the most efficient way we could
do a check where we don't actually need an end at all.
We could start by checking.
So I will just duplicate this down here.
The comment that all out we could start by checking first if age is greater than or equal to 21 that's
the first thing and we'll say you can come and drink.
So I'll get rid of some of these comments.
You're good to enter and can drink and then the next thing that will do if they're not greater than
or equal to 21 that means they are already less than 21.
So all we have to do is check OK are you greater than or equal to 18 in which case you can enter but
need to respond else.
You're too young.
So just to walk through what we did.
Remember the only way to get to this is for this to not be true.
So we don't have to do this.
And between 18 and 21 if the first thing we're doing is checking if they're over 21 we're going to print
you're going to enter and you can drink.
But if they're not over 21 or equal to 21 that means they are less than 21.
So this already inherently means there are less than 21 but greater than or equal to 18.
So that's a way of saying between 18 and 21 and then if that's not true it means they're definitely
somewhere lower than 18.
So we get this else hopefully that refactor makes sense.
It's kind of cleaner and easier to understand what's happening versus appear we had to use that.
And but I am going to keep this file with both of them.
Just so you can see you know if you look back at the solution code you can see how I did it once again.
My colon this time I caught it.
Let's just make sure this works are refactored version.
How old are you.
I'm 10.
You can't come in.
How old are you now.
I'm 98.
I'm going to enter and can drink and now I am 20.
And finally empty string please enter an age.
All right.
So hopefully that made sense.
Well hopefully the video makes sense in everything in the course makes sense as always.
That's my hope.
But really here what I wanted to make clear was the fact that we can do nested statements and then also
the problem with the input and having to convert things.
But really the main point I'd like to make here.
Aside from just hitting home how if an elephant elf's work is that we can nest them together and remember
indentation matters in Python.
All right.
So we have a quiz after this.
And then next we're actually going to build a simple little game of rock paper scissors.