All right.
So we've seen how to define functions with one or more parameters.
But there's still a couple of finer points around parameters we have yet to discuss.
And in this video we're going to talk about one of them which is setting up default parameters giving
parameters a default value.
So let me just illustrate what I'm referring to.
Right now we have this square function from a couple of videos back where we just you know there's a
single parameter numb and we return numb times numb.
Well let's suppose I want to change this up to rather than squaring every time I'm going to change it
to be called exponent and it will have two parameters a numb and a power.
And it's going to return numb raised to the power.
So as an example if we had print exponents two to the third that should return to us two times two times
two which would give us eight.
Same thing if we did let's say three to the second power it should return to us nine three times three.
And right now it actually it should do that we should get eight and nine if we execute this let's verify
that Python 3 my files called exponent Y and we get 8 and 9.
Cool but now let's say I want a default behavior of the most common operation or the most common exponential
operation is usually to square something.
So let's say if I don't pass in a power it should default to 2.
So that we should square thinks this should still return 9.
And this should still return 8.
And let's add one more and if I just passed in seven it should be forty nine.
So these will have a default value for power.
And if we specify a value it should override the default.
But if we try this right now there's a problem and the problem is after the first one runs when we don't
provide a power This error is triggered.
Missing one required positional argument power power is required.
So how do we fix this.
And the answer is we just need a little bit of magical syntax inside the function definition.
Right after the parameter we can get an equal sign and then a default value.
So this right here power equals to basically says if no power is specified by default it should be set
to 2.
And now our code doesn't break anymore.
Let's test it out.
And now we get eight nine and forty nine.
It's working.
This is also the exact same idea powering things like pop.
So we've seen pop before Here's a list of countries and I'm able to do country pop and specify an index
like zero in which case it takes an index and removes the first.
It removes the item at that index.
So countries is now shorter but I can also do countries and not specify an index and by default the
index will be the last index in the list.
Oh well I think that's kind of failed.
I need to actually call pop just two countries parentheses now for two countries that pop without specifying
an index.
It defaults to removing the last item.
We've done the same thing here.
If you don't pass in a power it defaults to to back to the slides.
Here's a couple of examples here we have an add function with two default parameter values.
So if you don't pass in either a or b then we just get 10 plus 20 A defaults 10 B defaults to 20 if
you've left one off like if we passed in just five then a would be equal to 5 and B would be equal to
20.
Or we override them both by passing in our own values.
Here's another more complex example.
It's called show information and there's two parameters.
First name and is instructor first name defaults to Colt is instr. defaults to false and all that it
does is it checks if the first name is called and is instructor is true we print Welcome back.
Cold If first name is Colt and is instructor is is false because that's the only other option.
Will print or we return.
I really thought you were an instructor.
And lastly we just return Hello whatever the first name is.
It's been passed in.
So let's talk about why these default harams are so useful.
If we take an example like pop we used it all the time.
It works in two different well that's the same thing but in two different ways.
Right.
It will either by default remove the last item or we pass an index and it removes that index.
We use it in both situations and there's no reason to have two separate functions to do that.
You know just have a remove last or remove by index.
Instead we put them together in pop.
So in a way it makes our code more flexible but also without default parameters we often can have errors
when we tried to run xponent without passing in a required power.
It actually just broke.
There was an error and it got mad at us.
Python said you know I expected exactly two arguments and I only got one what's going on.
So we can avoid those sorts of errors by actually using default harams.
Lastly let's talk about the values that default parameters can be so they can actually be anything.
Lisp dictionary strings Bullen's.
And what I want to highlight here.
They can actually be other functions.
So here's an example and this one if you haven't seen if you haven't worked with them.
The programming language for this one might mess with your head a little bit.
But if we look at what we have first up there's a function called add no default values or default parameters
just it takes two numbers and adds them together.
Same thing with subtract we have subtract it which just takes 2 numbers and subtracts a minus B.
But then we have this one called math and math takes two numbers a and b and something called F N which
is going to be a function and it defaults to add and what happens here instead of math.
It just takes whatever the function is that's passed in and it executes it with a and b.
So in this first example math to come to a is to B is 2 and No f n was provided so it defaults to add.
So add 2 comma 2 which then calls add a peer which returns 2 plus 2 which is 4.
So we have a default value default parameter which is a function.
In this case add referring to this or we could do math to comma two and then pass and subtract.
And in this case is to be asked to F N is subtract.
So then it calls return subtract 2 common to which then run subtract and we return to minus 2 which
is zero.
So I apologize if this confuses you more but I just wanted to show you that a default parameter is not
limited to a string or an integer.
It could be a list dictionary or even another function like we have here.
OK.
So here I have the exact same code in a sublime text file.
But let's instead of putting our default parameter at the end.
Let's put it at the beginning.
There's going to be a problem I mean first off right off the bat.
This function called down here is going to have function B to A is 2 and then B is subtract which is
going to mess everything up.
But even ignoring that here's the problem.
If I just want to add four and five.
I know that function f and by default is ADD.
So I don't pass that in and I just do four and five and I'm trying to do a is for and B is 5.
It's not going to work because these parameters are assigned in order.
So four is assigned to F and 5 is assigned to a.
And then there's nothing assigned to B.
It has no default parameter so it just throws an error so we have to make sure that our default parameters
either go at the end or that every single parameter has a default value but we can't have one go at
the beginning and then be followed by something that doesn't have a default because then Python gets
confused.
It just assigns things in order and then we end up one parameter short so hopefully that made sense.
I think this video is getting a little bit long so I'm going to end it here.