OK.
So we've been working with decorators for a little while now.
The next step to take is to create decorators that actually take an argument.
So everything we've done so far has been you know speed test.
It's always speed tests.
It does the same thing every time.
But what if we want to do something like this.
So I don't have to decorator written just yet but I want to insure first arc is and I pass in burrito
and that will enforce on fave foods that the first argument needs to be burrito in order for the code
to run.
Otherwise you'll get an error or a return an early return that will break out of the function or something.
Same thing done here.
And sure first arg is if I pass in the Number 10 I want to make sure that add to 10 whenever its executed
number one is always 10.
So this should work.
This should not work.
Lets start by implementing ensure first arg is and theres an extra step.
We actually have to take to make this work.
So I have a little fragment here.
This isnt exactly working code but its more just an illustration of something when we write this pattern
at decorator and then define a function afterwards.
We're really doing this right.
Phunk re-assigning phunk and then be the result of running decorator when we pass in func and whatever
is returned from that function is assigned to func.
However if we then want to also add an argument when we call the decorator there's an extra step we
have to take because we now need to call something like this decorator with args and then we pass in
the ARG first and then that should actually make the decorator function return decorator function that
we pass phunk in to be decorated with.
So essentially we need an extra layer of function because the argument that we're trying to pass in
or in this case burrito.
You then need to return a function that is going to ensure that first Argosy burrito.
But first we have to make that function if that makes any sense.
It's kind of a multilayer process.
So let me just demo it first before we get too sidetracked.
First things first we need to define sure first arg is.
That takes a function in and instead of calling this F and because it's not going to be a function that
we're passing in it's a value or an ARG.
Our biggest problem with this idea let's go with Val.
So this represents burrito or 10.
Then inside of here we're going to define another function we can call it inner.
It really doesn't matter.
And inside of that we're going to define our wrapper function.
So there's a lot.
So enter is what will actually take the function and we can add in our ADD wraps.
Fehn right there.
Then we have the wrapper function and don't treat these colons.
When you close this when that open up and wrapper should just have ARGs in or just regular decorator
function that we've seen and didn't hear will do an if statement and we want to check first of all if
there are any args and then check if args 0 is not equal to thou.
So burrito or something.
If we just did this.
If R.G. are not equal Divell we'd run into an error if there were no args.
So instead we'll check to arge exist and is the first one not equal to Val.
If that's the case we can start by just returning.
You know first arg needs to be let's make an F string needs to be vowel.
Otherwise we're going to return F and start args quires
and then we return the wrapper.
And then finally we're going to return inner.
There's an extra intermediate layer now the whole idea is that when we pass in burrito we are then constructing
a decorator using that value.
So this is the decorator that's being returned.
Inner right here inner is what actually accepts the function arguments.
And we just check if the argument the first one matches whatever value is and blah blah blah.
You know we return this little error message.
Otherwise we return the result of calling function and so on.
It does get a little bit messy but hopefully you can step through how this is actually working.
Now let's test it out and miss any colons and everything.
OK here let's see what happens.
So I'm printing the result if we execute it.
It looks good.
So first of all it worked when we called this first one in reinsured first argues Greedo we got it worked.
We didn't get an error.
Then when we tried it again and we passed an ice cream first we got first our needs to be a burrito.
After that we had inchers ensure first August 10 and we call it with 10 first and then with one first
and we get the successful one and then we get the return value.
First our needs to be 10.
OK.
So there's a lot here.
I will upload both these files.
I think this illustration here can help you understand what's happening why we need that extra layer
of a function because there is now two things that are actually being passed in.
It just looks like one because the decorator magic behind the scenes in the same way that this looks
like a function is not necessarily being called what it actually is behind the scenes it's just the
nice syntactic sugar.
All right so now we've seen how to create a decorator that accepts an argument.