Hey welcome back.
And this video I'm going to introduce a more intermediate topic with lists called a slice or slicing.
It's basically a tool that's built in that allows us to make copies of entire lists.
But more commonly just portions of just individual slices.
So we could say give me the part of this list from indexed to 10 or give me the part of all of us from
index 5 all the way to the end and the syntax for slicing is a bit different than what we've seen so
far.
It's not a method that we call on a list with a dot and then the name of a method like append and parentheses.
We actually use the square brackets that we use you know to access an individual item out some list
bracket zero gives us an individual element at the first index.
But for a slice we use the same brackets but there are three pieces of information we can provide.
And we don't have to have all of them but we see some examples.
And the first example is where we want the slice to begin where we should start cutting.
Make our first cut to the list.
The second is where to stop and then the third is the step or the interval.
Are we including every index every you know skipping every other one.
Just like with range.
If you watch the range video or we created to start stop and a step we could do odd numbers from 1 to
20.
The biggest difference is that we're using colons to separate them and square brackets.
OK so let's take a closer look at the first parameter which is the start point the index where we should
start slicing.
So here's an example.
We have one two three four stored in a list as first list and the first thing I'll point out is that
we have to add this colon afterwards.
Because if I just did first list of one it's going to give me the item at index 1 which is 2.
So in order to tell Python where slicing we have to include at least one colon.
So even if we're only using the start and we're not including and step you need at least have a colon
and the same goes later once we learn we can do.
We don't have to include a start.
And we can just do an end.
We have to include a call in before.
OK so here's our first example.
If we slice from index of 1 to the end we get to three and four.
So it starts right here so 0 1 starts at 2 and it slices to the end.
And here's another example we started index 3 0 1 2 3 which is for Item 4 and we got to the end which
there's nothing afterwards.
So we end up with a list of just four if we tried to slice from index 20.
So you know 20 Colan we would get an empty list.
Python will look for it.
It doesn't find anything at that index but it still gives us a list.
What's cool about slicing is that we can also slice from the end using a negative number.
So if you slice from negative 1 we just get the last element in a list or in this example we slice from
negative 3 to the end.
So that's going to be negative one negative to negative three forward.
So two three four.
So if we pass a negative number you get back a new list with that many number of elements from the end.
If that makes sense and as a quick aside we can also just pass in a colon and that will give us the
entire list.
It's the same as passing in zero colon.
Let's go to my terminal and I'll make a list of colors.
OK.
So we have red orange yellow green blue indigo violet Roy G Biv.
And if we want to do a slice let's do something from yellow to the end so that index of 0 1 2.
And if we just do index of two of course it gives us yellow.
But if we add that colon then it goes to the end.
Yellow green blue indigo violet.
So the note that I added at the end there is that if we do zero colon that will just make a copy of
the list.
And it's actually important to notice or to know that this is a copy of the list.
It's not giving us the same list and we could prove that.
So if we have colors and then I make colors two equal two colors.
Zero colon which we could actually just do colon as well that's the short cut so I'll show you that
now.
And I look at colors too.
It looks the same as colors.
And remember the way we could test we can do colors equals equals colors too.
And that's going to tell us if the values are the same and they are.
But if we do colors is colors too.
That's going to tell us if they actually referenced the same thing in memory and they don't.
We've made a unique copy and it has its own address in memory.
So when we use is it comes back as false.
OK the last thing I'll show negative numbers.
You know if we go back to colors and we slice from negative into negative to Colin what do you expect
to get if this is colors I'll hit enter and we get indigo and violet.
So it goes from the negative to index.
So that's going to be negative one negative two and it slices to the end.
So indigo and violet Let's now examine the second parameter of slice which is the end point the end
index.
So the first parameter is where to start the slice.
What index to begin the first cut and the second parameter is where to end it.
And it's important to note it is Xclusive.
So it does not include the last index that we provide.
It's just like ranges in that way but it's not like Rand and very confusing in my opinion.
So here's an example.
Same first list.
One two three four.
And if we slice with colon too.
So we don't even provide a start point.
It's going to assume to begin at the beginning that the zero index and it slices until index of two.
But it doesn't include index of two because index of 2 is 0 1 2.
That gives us three.
So it slices up until here giving us one common to.
Same thing here.
If we slice with Colon for starts the beginning and goes to index 4 which is 0 1 2 3 and index 4 doesn't
exist.
It's after the list ends.
So it gives us everything in the list and then here's our first example of passing and a start and an
end.
In this case we're slicing from index one to index three.
So index of one is included.
So 0 1.
So it includes two and it goes up to three.
And then this is index of 3 0 1 2 3.
So it includes indexes 1 and 2 Give has 2 and 3 so many numbers to talk about.
It's easier with colors but treat this as a reference.
And if we pass in a negative number as the end value into our slice it will end the slice at that many
elements from the end of the list.
So if we wanted the first two elements in the list we could slice from the beginning until three from
the end and we could pass in negative two as a second option.
So here's an example.
In this case if we do colon negative one it's going to go from the beginning which is index zero.
Up until the last item negative 1 which is 4 and it doesn't include it.
So it gives us 1 2 3 or this example goes from index of 1 up to index negative for one non-inclusive.
So that gives us index of 1 0 1.
So we get to 3 and we stop because this is negative 1 here and it's Xclusive.
So let's go back to colors.
And this time I make a bit more space if we look at colors.
Let's do a slice from red to blue including blue.
So basically leaving out indigo and violet and to do that with the colors and we could do zero colon
test to make it clear we're starting at the beginning or just two colon and then the index of indigo
so that 0 1 2 3 4 5 just like this.
And that gives us red orange yellow green blue doesn't include Indigo.
Now if I just wanted a slice from yellow to green.
Well what we would do is start off with the first index that's going to be 0 1 2 and it includes two
so two and we want it to stop.
They get red yellow and green.
So we want to just stop it blue because it doesn't include blue.
So that's going to be 0 1 2 3 4.
And if we look at this we get yellow and green.
Finally let's move on to the third parameter which is the step.
So it's basically the number to count at a time the interval how many to skip.
It works the same way as the step works in ranges.
Or we could generate even or odd numbers or multiples of five that sort of thing.
So for example if we had a step up to count every other number 1 3 5 and so on.
So here's an example.
We have our first list but this time it includes one up to six.
One two three four five six.
And notice that we have two colons in a row.
So this signifies we have a start.
There's no end.
And then we have our third parameter.
So if you see this two Kolins it means there's no middle there's no end parameter.
So our start is from index of 1.
So that's going to be 0 1 and we're going to the end.
But we're counting by twos so we get index up to her.
Excuse me.
Index of one index of three and an index of five giving us two for six.
So this example I'm actually just looking at it and it's wrong.
I'll have to update the slide because if we have first list Colin Colin too this means start at the
beginning and go to the end.
I believe the reason I think I was using the old version of first list which only went up to four but
this one goes up to six.
But if we're counting by twos for the entire list so start at the beginning go to the end come by twos.
It should give us index of zero index of two and then index of four.
So it should be 1 3 5 not 1 3.
So I'll update that.
OK.
It is updated now.
Steps are useful for getting a certain pattern and a slice but things get really interesting when we
add negative step values.
So for example let's take a look at this first one.
So we have our first list.
One two three four five six and we're going from the beginning or from index of 1.
So that's two.
And we're going to the end.
However we're stepping back.
So we go two down to one to the end.
So we reversed the direction rather than going forward.
We're going backwards.
So we end up with two come a one in a bust Here's another example it works a little different because
we're not passing in a start point we're passing in.
And so our end is index of one which is to remember that end is not exclusive so it wouldn't include
too but because we have negative one.
We're actually going for the end of the array so 6 5 4 3 and then we stop because we hit this index.
So the result is six five four three.
And then finally and this last example we're stepping backwards and we're starting at index 2.
So that's going to be 0 1 2 here and there's no endpoint.
So we're moving backwards from 3 to 2 to 1 with that negative 1 slices are definitely a bit tricky to
wrap your head around especially when you add the negative numbers.
But keep practicing Also it's not a deal breaker for Python.
You'll see them use a lot but if you have questions about them you can pretty easily get them answered
or figured out with just kind of sitting down and thinking through it.
So now that we've practiced with slices Let's see some cool things we can do.
So what we saw from earlier going from the beginning to the end stepping back by 1 0 reverse a list
or a string.
Way.
So instead of using the reverse method we could simply do it this way.
So here's an example with a string.
So I mentioned at the beginning that all of this works with strings so we could do zero zero negative
1 or just call and call negative 1.
And it just reverses the entire string.
Another thing we can do is modify specific portions of a list.
So here's an example we have numbers 1 2 three four 5 is a list and we can actually set a slice.
So we have numbers 1 2 3.
So that's going to be index 0 1.
So from 2 up to here 0 1 2 3.
So these two are actually going to update it to be ABC.
So it adds that data here and we end up with one A B C for 5.
All right.
So lastly for just two or three seconds.
Well that's not that's a lie.
For like 20 seconds let's just do colors and let's do one of those tricks using Well let's use steps
first of all so let's do colon colon too.
What do we expect from that.
Well it starts at the beginning red and it skips and it goes to yellow to blue to Violet.
And let's play around with the negative one which will reverse it.
It's another way of reversing the list.
And finally let me show you something a bit different but still colors zero which is going to give us
red.
Actually that's two longer color that's two colors five which is indigo.
That's a string.
And I actually can change this on it's a bit of a bonus.
And what does this do again to a list or a string.
It will reverse it.
So if I chain them together it accesses Indigo first and then slices it by reversing it using negative
one at this step and we get our get our Gidney Gidney it's a quick little bonus thing there.
We can do the exact same thing.
So if I did hello like this and then I access the zero character we get H.
But if you Colon four I get opes unintentional there.
Please don't come at me please.
And you know we could do the same thing that we've seen let's do colon colon three.
It goes from H and then it skips this this and it goes to that L skips to go so that L skips two and
gives us the last oh ok that's enough.
This video has been so long I'm sorry.
There's a lot to cover with slices.
So we're going to get some practice.
If you're feeling lost.
Hang in there.