OK.
Welcome back.
So this section is all about the Internet.
We're not going to be making websites or doing any web development necessarily but we're going to write
Python code that talks to Web sites that gets data from API eyes and build simple applications using
API data.
And the way that it will work is that we'll use a package that allows us to make HTP requests.
So pretty exciting stuff.
You know we're continuing on with the theme of taking Python and using an external package to do something
more interesting whether it's printing ASCII art or changing the color of our terminal or getting data
from a Web site.
So the way this section will be structured is this video is going to be a crash course on HGP and how
the Internet works.
So if you've never done web development or you're unfamiliar with how the Internet works and what a
request and a response is what an IP address is what a get versus post request is if you have any questions
about those things he just said watch this video.
But if you've worked with you know in javascript or a node or in C or some other language and you're
familiar with making requests and receiving responses you can move on to the next video where I'll actually
show you how to make a request using Python.
So two paths.
Pick the one that's best for you.
All right.
So let's begin this crash course on HTP Hypertext Transfer Protocol.
So where do we begin.
Well there's a lot to talk about our objectives here are to describe what happens when you type a you
are l into a U R L bar.
You hit enter a lot of stuff happens behind the scenes before we actually get our result.
So if I you know I go to Google dot com or let's say I search for Idaho salmon there's a lot of stuff
behind the scenes happening for me to see this page here.
So we'll discuss that.
We want to describe the request response cycle.
Explain what a request or response header is and give some examples.
Explain the different categories of response codes and compare get and post requests.
So I should preface all of this by saying you are not going to leave this video being an expert but
you should know enough to understand what's happening when we write Python code that communicates with
API and Web sites.
But if this stuff interests you I highly recommend you check out Web development with Python or just
web development in general.
All right let's begin.
So the Internet stupid meme.
You see the Internet.
It's like this series of tubes.
Very very funny.
When you hear you know the Internet a series of tubes.
It's definitely kind of a joke at this point.
But the sentiment behind it is true.
It's just a bunch of computers.
The Internet is just a bunch of computers that are connected.
I can talk to one another.
So I think people overplay this.
You know Internet is a series of tubes joke but it is true at its core the sentiment behind it.
The internet is a bunch of computers that are all in a network connected by tubes whether it's you know
a fiber optic cable or other wires or cables connecting the computers or there's some wireless Internet
in between.
Eventually everything comes down to tubes or cables or wires or whatever you want to call them.
And data being transferred.
So speaking of data being transferred when I go to you know open up chrome and I type google.com and
I hit enter Let's walk through what happens.
The very first thing that happens is called DNS lookup.
And the next slide will go over that in more detail but Google the outcome is not.
It's not a real thing.
Well it is a thing but as far as my computer is concerned it needs to send a request to a particular
IP address.
So the first step is called DNS look up.
It takes google.com and it actually finds the correct address to send a request to then my computer
makes a request an AGP request to a server saying hello server at Google.com called is looking for the
home page of google.com.
Can you give it to me.
Then the server receives that request and says oh OK this person is looking for Google dot com.
Did they search for something.
No they just want the regular home page.
All right.
Send them the homepage.
And then the server does just that.
It compiles the home page for me and sends it back.
So the last three things here is called the request response cycle.
The computer sends a request to a server whether it's your Facebook your Twitter.
I don't know Google any Web site read it.
Most the time for me to send a request.
And then the server sends something back to us.
And what's important is you know when I searched for Sam in here the exact same process happened I the
DNS lookup happened it figured out how it you know googled outcome's IP address and then the server
received my request.
But this time my computer or my request said hey please give me the page with Sam and results.
And so the server had to process that request go find all of the salmon result in the giant Google database
and build me a different web page than if I had just looked for the home page but notice you know it's
the same place I'm sending it to Google dot com is the same first base you Arel same domain.
It's just that there's all this extra stuff afterwards and that translates to a different HGP request.
So we'll see more about that.
But let's start with the DNS lookup.
So it's like a phone book for the Internet phone book you know takes people's names.
It's been a long time since I've seen one but takes people's names and connects them to phone numbers.
This takes domain names you or else like google.com and turns it into an IP address.
This is what we actually send a request to at the end of the day.
This is just a little human friendly layer.
Facebook's com after we try an ad for a hit enter.
I go to Facebook dot com a hit enter before requests can be sent off.
We have to know where to send it.
So this might be Facebook's IP address.
Same thing with Amazon.
There are these unique IP addresses.
So let's let's hone in on this request response cycle.
So my computer which is often called the client or anyone's computer who is initiating a request I send
a request and there are different types of request.
This is called a get request.
We will have a site on that too.
But let's just focus on the IP address.
So this is me sending requests to that IP address and that server process is the request and it does
something maybe it talks to a database.
If I'm going to Facebook.
Facebook needs to go to database and it needs to you know pull out all my photos and friends and assemble
my news feed and then send it back to me.
One thing we haven't talked about is how it sends it back what the format is anytime we view a web page
it's an HMO but also talk about that when we talk about API eyes.
OK.
So we we send a get request we'll talk to what we get means and then the server assuming everything
is fine.
Sends me the page I'm looking for but you've probably seen web pages you know you try and access a page
and you get a 404 error.
It says Page Not Found.
Or maybe you could get an error that says Page is moved or you know you don't have permission for bidin.
There's these different status codes.
So 200.
You probably don't see often because you get a web page and 200 means.
OK so there's no reason to display a message to say OK.
Unlike you know if you get a 404.
Usually there's a four or four page to tell you something went wrong.
But anyway the server respond to the response respond to the response it sends back an HD Pierpont containing
information.
You know a web page but always a status code to explain how the request was received if it was OK or
if you asked for page you don't have permission to view or if that page doesn't exist.
So the last step the server sends something back in that response which is called the response body.
And this is HMO.
So we're not going to talk about him out other than the fact that it is what is sent back to your client
and rendered in your browser.
So if I hit enter again I'm searching for Sam and I'm going to go to View developer view source this
as soon as it loads.
This is the time all this massive thing that is sent back from Google server.
So this is what is sent across the tubes in between my computer and Google server.
This is part of the response and all of it comes to my browser and the job of my browser is to turn
it into this.
So every little word you see here every time it says Sam and every photo is all enclosed or contained
in this aged him somewhere and it looks like a mess because it is a mess and this is not made for humans
to really read.
It's made for computers to read this is made for humans to read as a side note by open command option
J in Chrome.
There is a network tab and this shows me HTP requests that come and go.
And if I make a new request by just hitting enter here or let me just go to Google dot com the main
homepage watch down here.
A lot of stuff happens if I scroll up and I click on this one here Google dot com.
You'll actually will see a status for 200.
It was a get request sent to Google dot com and then we could see that we got a response back.
And this is our response.
This is the page we're seeing right now.
So this is just a little developer tool to help people like us who are trying to understand what happened.
What's interesting is actually the very first time I sent it I got a three to one moved permanently.
And then I was redirected to three or seven Internet redirect to this URL and that's because I just
went to Google dot com not www.youtube.com.
And so that happens behind the scenes I'm automatically redirected to WDW to Google about COM.
But I do remember a time when I was a kid where you had to type that GWW anyways getting side tracked.
All I want to show.
We sent a request we get back a response it technically looks like this.
Our browser makes it look like this.
Next topic.
Those requests and responses contain HDP headers so headers are sort of like meta data about the request
and they're sent with both requests and responses and they just provide additional information about
the requester response.
So the most important thing when I send a request to Google is the I'm and I'm asking for am I asking
for Google that com the home page or I'm asking for Google or com slash you know salmon or whatever
it is am I looking for Google dot com slash news cetera.
And that's important.
But there's also other information that I'm sending along like accept and accept is is my computer's
way of saying these are the types of responses that we will accept back.
So there are different formats of data.
Tim Ellis the one we see in our browser but there are other formats.
We'll talk about briefly including Jason and XM.
So for now I'll just leave it at this but this is a way of saying I will accept X formats back.
There's this other thing called Cash control.
Just another example of a header.
It specifies how the caching should behave.
There's something called User-Agent which contains information about the software used to make the request.
So if we actually look at this request here someone I sent to Google dot com.
Here are the headers.
These are all different headers so there's the request.
You know there's the request method and then in the response there are also other type of headers you
might get and I'm not going to go into detail here.
I just want to put these here to show you that there is information metadata sent in a request.
And then also sent back in a response.
But the most important part of a response that we've already talked about are the status codes.
So every request we send gets a response and those responses if they start with it too.
So there are these three digit numbers if they started that two it means it was a success if it started
with the three.
It means it was a redirect which we already saw.
We got to 3 007 redirect when I tried to go to Google dot com with the W W and if it starts the four
it means it's a problem on our end but we could try and generate one by going to google.com slash Hello
slash called slash cat and there we go.
We see the HTL page that says 404.
But if I look at the request and then I go to the response well not the response body for the headers.
There we go.
You can see status code is 404.
So 4:4 is the most common for error meaning not found.
There's also five hundred satis code which means something went wrong on the server side meaning that
it's not your fault.
Something happened on the back end somewhere on Google's end which pretty pretty much would never see
from Google these days because that would be disastrous.
OK.
So this video is getting long.
I'm going to end it here.
This is part one of that crash course on HTP requests.
The next thing we have to talk about is get and post request and the differences between them and then
also what the heck an API is.
So we'll talk about that.
So to quickly summarize I go to you are a hit enter first thing that happens that you are well it's
turned into an IP address using DNA in the DNS look up process.
Then my computer the client makes a request to that IP address with additional information.
So it's not just the you are all that I'm looking for if I'm looking for Slash samen or slash.
I don't know Toona but it's also who is sending the request what type of data.
All except back and a bunch of other things.
Then the server processes it and says oh he's looking for the and Page.
Let's build him the second page.
He wants him out OK I'll give it to him NHT M-L sends it back to me.
Gives me a status code along with it that says everything is good or the page you looked for doesn't
exist.
Something like that.
And then my page my chrome window or whatever browser I have it might be my phone could be my laptop
will display the resulting HMO.
He gets back from the response.
OK.