Welcome back in the last video we talked about how we're using sequel like three as our database is
lightweight.
It's easy to use and learn and it comes pre-installed on many machines.
So let's let's go through the process of checking if you have it installed.
And if you don't let's follow the steps to actually install it.
Now I will preface this by saying that the people who will have to install it most likely are some Windows
users and my windows machine right now I only have one at home.
It's completely broken.
I just got it out to see if I could record the installation video with it.
I can't get it to turn on.
So if you are using a PC and you do need to install it I'm going to link you to another video just because
I want to get this content out and I don't know how long it's going to take for me to actually get my
PC working or buy a new one.
So with that warning out of the way here's how you can check if you have it installed in your shell
if you type sequel 3.
You should get something like this and you're prompted change to say sequel lite if it doesn't if you
know for example if I take this type sequel light instead of sequel 3 it doesn't know what I'm talking
about.
So that's all you need to do to test it.
Sequel 3 and then now you're in the prompt.
You'll notice things change and to get out of there you can do control d or quit quit quit.
Yes.
OK so that's what you need to do your test if you have it.
If you don't have it then what you need to do is install it.
So if you go to sequel.
ORG it's not the most beautiful Web site ever.
You can go to download and it's honestly not very clear.
The steps you need to go to actually install everything.
They just give you the file to download.
But to get it set up so that you can actually type sequel like in your comment.
Well geez.
Sequel three prompt others a little more work.
So I looked around to see if there's any good text tutorials I couldn't find anything very good and
nothing very recent but this video is well done and it walks you through basically all that you need
to do to install it.
So I'm going to link this tells you if you're on Windows which version to download where to extract
the files how to name things so that at the very end of the video you can type Seacole light and it
will load.
Oh and also I should mention that for some of you the prompt will be sequel light on certain PCs and
on on Macs it's usually sequel 3.
So make sure you try both of those before you go through the steps of installing.
OK.
So go ahead give it a shot.
Installing it if you need to.
I know it's going to be annoying but remember it is the least painful of the databases to install.
And then once you have that working in the next video we'll go over the basics of the syntax and if
you do not if you aren't able to get it to work I still recommend that you watch the videos on connecting
to a sequel database because it will apply to other databases.
So if you do have post-arrest installed from a different course for example you could take what I teach
you and sort of you can't copy and paste it and get it to work with postscripts but you could tweak
it and just have to alter a couple of lines in order to get it to work.
So I wouldn't give up entirely if you do run into trouble but we'll keep an eye on the Q&amp;A and see if
those installation instructions are problematic or not.
OK.