Hey there.
Welcome back.
And this video I'm just going to introduce Sublime Text which is the text editor that I'm going to use.
You definitely do not have to use this but it's a free option that is really really popular amongst
developers.
Python javascript you name it.
It works with any sort of language.
It's not particular to one and it's really flexible.
It's FREE.
So it makes a really good option for students who are just testing something out.
There are other editors out there that some courses will have you know sign up for a 30 day trial and
then after that it's 100 200 dollars.
So this is a nice alternative and it's just as powerful.
So it downloaded.
All you have to do is go to Sublime Text dot com.
The link is also included as a resource with this lecture.
Then go to download or on the home page it detects that you're using a PC click download for Windows.
Then you should see this Sublime Text 3 set up wizard.
Complete the process and once it finishes you should be able to come down here into what it is called
Taskbar type Sublime Text and it should open up for you and it will look something like this on your
computer.
So it's just a basic text editor.
Oh it's not basic but it's compared to something like Microsoft Word.
You know just as text for not working with images in here we're not working with clip art or whatever
else it has.
We're just adding in our code.
But it has some really nice features like syntax highlighting we can change color schemes autocomplete.
So even though we haven't learned Python yet I'm just going to show you some of those features.
Now in this sublime video sort of make a new file which you'll be doing a lot.
You can do file new file or control and I'll do that now control and.
And then let's give it a name so we can you know go to File Save just like any other app or control
as I will save this on my desktop inside of Culp's code and I'm going to give it a file name.
Let's go with demo.
And I could do Dot T x t if I wanted to for a text file what we'll be doing pretty much exclusively
is dot p y.
Actually later we'll will do C S V files and a couple other things.
But why is all we need for Python demo.
P Why that tells sublime that it should be a python file which will then trigger syntax highlighting
and some autocomplete for Python but also it's important to put Python code in a python file so we can
run it.
OK so save and now I can type python code if I type one plus one.
You can see that the ones are purple and the plus sign is red whereas I just make a new file do command
or control and I do one close one.
Python doesn't know what type of file this is.
So you won't see those colors.
A common question I get asked Why is that happening.
Just make sure you save your file as p y.
Anytime you make a new file you have to save it first.
Other than that you can go up to preferences color scheme if you want to change.
You can also download some other ones but I think these are the ones that come by default.
That's not bad to go with that one.
Put your code in here save.
Make new files.
The only other thing you can open a folder which is common for working with multiple files at once.
I would go and open this entire directory for example and make this full screen.
I now have access to all my files here.
Later on we'll work on projects that have two or three python files that work together plus maybe a
data file that would need to import.
We don't want to have to open them all individually so you can use that feature file open folder.
I believe you can also use the graphical user interface and drag a file down to the icon down here of
Sublime Text and that will open it up just the same way so that's all I want to talk about with sublime
in this video.
It's FREE.
It's nice easy to use very strong developer community and if you happen to be interested in customizing
your editor the possibilities are pretty much endless.
You can find custom scripts custom color schemes you can download all sorts of tools awesome utilities
online but I'm not going to go into that because we better get on with Python.
So that's coming up next.