A Welcome Back in this video we're going to introduce one of the most powerful and unique features in
Python list comprehension.
The idea of comprehension actually applies to many other data structures that we'll learn about later.
Things like dictionaries and set tuples and generators all of which we'll see later on in the course.
So understanding them.
You could say comprehending them and the syntax the idea is going to be really important.
So basically it just cool shorthand syntax that allows us to generate new lists to make new lists that
are direct copies of other lists or more often than not are tweaked versions where we could take one
list and then generate a new one that has every number squared or every string reversed and they can
get a lot more complex than that.
So I'll just let the examples speak for themselves.
But before we get there we need to start with the syntax.
So I'm going to show you the syntax.
It's going to look bizarre and looks like it does nothing because it's basically a bunch of blanks.
At least in this example.
So we start with the brackets just like we did with slice slices and there are three components.
So we have this first variable name for and that word is always there for and then a second variable
and that is the same as the first one and you just bear with me for a moment in and then the name of
another list or of a range something that we could iterate through.
So this part is kind of like for something in a list it's a for loop but then we have this first thing
that's a bit different.
And you know this is just impossible to talk about without looking at an example.
So let's do that first.
OK.
Here I have a list called numbs.
Very simple.
And let's do a list comprehension of I'm going to do X times X or we could just actually let's just
do X times 10 for x in Gnome's.
So what this will do is for every x in NUMP So one two three are going to multiply it by 10 and put
it in a new list.
So we end up with 10 20 30.
So I think this makes it a bit clearer.
We have blank four blank blank.
So we have a list placeholder variable for each item in that list and then some way of manipulating
each item in the list.
So X times 10 we could do.
I don't know X divided by two and we get 0.5 1.0 and 1.5.
But the rough idea is we take an existing list and output another list with different values based upon
the first list.
And this seems like something we could do with a loop.
And that's because it is.
So here's an example of doing something with a for loop.
So if we wanted to make a new list where we take a numbers list and this new list has every number from
the numbers list but doubled.
We could loop through numbers and for each number there are going to double it and then append it to
the double numbered list or doubled numbers list.
So one at a time we multiply by two and added into this list multiply two by two we add four to the
list three by two.
We had six the list and we end up with this.
But using a list comprehension we can do it in a single line.
So we have our numbers list and then all we have to do is write array brackets or choose me list brackets.
Numb times to four numbers in numbers.
And Python takes care of the rest.
It generates a new list with 2 4 6 8 and 10.
So we can do the same thing.
It's just a lot more concise and definitely preferable preferable just better than this example.
So it's really helpful stuff.
Let's look at a couple of more examples.
So here we have a string.
And what we're doing.
Remember we can do a for loop over a string for each character and for each character in name we're
going to take that character like C and uppercase it.
So upper is a string method.
We saw it briefly I think in rock paper scissors.
If you watched it we also saw lowered but all it does it takes a string and converts it to uppercase.
In this case and we end up with a list where each character is an uppercase letter from the string c
o l t all uppercase in the second example we have a list of friends and we're taking each string in
uppercase saying the first letter and getting back a new list of friends with their names capitalized.
So we have friends.
Ashley Matt and Michael we are looping through.
So for each friend in friends take that friend take the first character and uppercase and so then we
end up with Ashlee capital a matt capital am Michael capital M and so we end up with a list always so
even though if we're working with a string in this case we're looping through the string.
This is a list comprehension.
The end result that's returned is is a list same thing down here.
This stuff can be a bit tricky.
So we have a couple more examples.
Feel free to pause this at any point try things out on your own.
It does take a little bit of getting used to but it's used pretty much everywhere in Python and in a
lot of the big codebase is that you'll see out there open source projects.
You definitely need to be comfortable with these if you want to use Python in a data science or game
development web development.
All that stuff you previously saw that we can use this comprehension to iterate over a string.
We can do that with ranges as well.
So here's taking a range one common six generates numbers between 1 and 5.
And we just multiply them by 10 and we get a list with 10 20 30 40 50.
Pretty neat neat.
Yep.
And this next example we're using miscomprehension in a little different way.
We're turning values into their boolean representation using the bool function which we haven't really
seen but we've seen as TR for string to convert to a string we've seen it to convert to an int.
Same thing.
So it takes in a number it doesn't take in a number it takes in a value whatever it is and it will return
if it's truth or falsity.
So remember that things like any anything like an empty string is inherently false.
So if I convert that to a bool we get false but if I add a space and there are some letters it becomes
truthy or an any number is going to be truthy except zero.
So all we're doing here is taking this list.
Zero.
An empty empty list and an empty string.
Converting them all to bools when we get false false and false.
Not something you probably do but it's just fun to see that you can work at all sorts of data in the
Solus comprehensions.
And in this last example we're taking a list of numbers and converting it to a list of strings.
So you definitely will find yourself needing to convert one data type to another in Python.
And if you need to convert a list from one type to another list comprehension is a great way doing that
because you don't have to loop through manually and run the string convert or string function as TR
every single time to cast a number to a string you can have Python take care of it for you with a list
comprehension just like this.
So we have our events and for each name in this numbers list we're going to turn into a string.
And our end result is the string version.
One two three four five.
Cool.
So let's try a couple of these.
I think I have colors here still.
So we could do something like array brackets and let's do color dot upper for color in colors and we
end up with all caps or we have names still.
So we could do something like as tr of Nom's numb for an Nomes.
So remember this is totally up to us.
Call this whatever we want.
And now we end up with the string version of things and we could even do something like this as tr of
Nahm Plus the string hello for name and names and we end up with one hello to hello hello.
OK.
So hopefully you can see how flexible these are.
I'm going to stop here but I'm actually going to continue talking about this comprehension in the next
video where we'll see how to use miscomprehension with conditional logic built in.