All right.
Welcome back.
Now we're going to talk about writing to CXXVI files.
And there's actually two different ways of doing it.
We can write using lists or write using dictionaries.
And in this video we're going to quickly show how to use lists.
So the function we want our writer.
So this will actually create the writer just like we saw reader.
This is sort of the corresponding version reader and writer.
And then we have a dict reader which we've already seen and adicts writer which you'll see in the next
video.
OK.
So writer and then the method that we'll use most the time is called right Roe.
So here's an example.
We open a file we have to import writer from CSFB we open a file that is important because we are writing.
And then we call writer pass and the file save that to a variable call it whatever you want a writer
writer or something something I don't know then we just call Dattner right Roe.
And we passed it almost.
So each time we passed the list it had arow to a file for us and that's pretty much it.
So if I actually just copy this version over and I do a quick demo pasted in we can open fighters dustiest
V.
Well let's actually just do some random file like testing that yes let's do cats.
How about that cat s t w.
And then I can leave this the same.
It's important to note that to get the headers just another row.
So we pass that in let's do something like name come up.
I don't know age.
It'll be my cats.
And then we can write a row that is blue comma and we need two strings.
You're either way back down here blue.
And she is.
I don't even know she for three.
And then we'll do one more line which will be my unnamed kitty who is less than one.
We'll leave it at that.
OK.
So let's run this now.
There isn't a file catch up yet but it still should work.
If I run the file.
OK let's see what we get.
Is there a new file called Cats.
Let's open it.
So do several cats.
That's three.
And here's our data.
We've successfully written data using writer.
OK.
So one more example I'm going to show I'll make another new file.
And what we're going to do is actually read in from one file and then change some data.
We'll just uppercase everything in our example and then write it to a new file.
So we'll read in from this file fighters that cxxviii then we'll capitalize everything and then print
it out.
So to do that let's make a new file let's call it scream.
Why and we just want to start by from C we.
Just going to use reader and writer.
So we'll just import reader and writer and then we'll do our with open and to our file that we're going
to read from is fighters dot CXXVI as.
And we'll just call it file then we'll do CACP reader equals reader file and we can just double check
everything is working.
Right doing I don't know for row in CAC reader as we've already seen print to row with purines of course.
And let's make sure it works OK.
We're getting the data.
So now what we're going to do is take this data and uppercase all of it and write it into a new file
that we'll call scream touchiest free.
OK so if we did we could just do a separate and open what we do need to do a separate open for the file
that we're going to write to which we could call.
I don't know scream ing fighters at CSB.
We need that W because we're writing to it as.
And we'll just call it file again and then we'll do cxxviii writer equals writer file.
And now the trick is basically what we want to do is take this data that's coming back which is a list
of lists.
While it's not quite a list of lists it's an iterator that's returning a bunch of lists.
But if we convert it to a list it will be a list of lists.
And the simplest way to go through and just capitalize everything in there not necessarily the most
efficient but the simplest for now is just going to be to use a list comprehension a nested one.
So let's just make a variable called fighters and it can be a list comprehension where we use CSP reader
and will do something like it's going to need to be nested because we're turning it into a list and
each row is Sonesta is a list itself.
So we might have let's go with s dot upper for s in row like this and then we'll put our nested brackets
for row in CAC reader.
All right so for each one of these We're going to go through each row and for each row we'll call each
item s and we're going to uppercase it.
Let's see if that works.
So we'll even comment the writing part out and now will do for row in fighters print row.
If we executed OK everything's in all caps looks good.
Now all we have to do is take this fighter's data and write it to the file.
So down here we'll just do four fighter in fighters we want to be writer dots right row fighter.
And this includes the headers because the letters are inside of this.
Even those called fighters.
It includes the first row of headers as well.
We uppercase everything.
Like I said this is not necessarily the best way of doing this.
It's just a simple way of doing it.
Or we're just upper casing everything inside those nested lists.
Then we don't need to print.
And now this should work.
Let's test it out and just a new file called Screaming out.
Screaming fighters up see here we go.
So we took this file and turned it into this using both reading and then writing it back.
But before we wrote it we uppercase everything.
OK.
So very last thing we can talk about if we wanted to we don't necessarily have to do it this way we
could nest things together.
So instead of doing this fighter's line we could do this right here and then to all of that this and
instead of here I can access for fighter in CAC reader.
But the thing is that each one of these has a list.
So we want to write what we want right row.
And then here we want to do something like as Dot hopper for s in fighter and let's see what happens
if we do it now.
And with his screaming fighters works perfectly.
But it's important to note that if I were to do it this way and I didn't want to nest these things I
want to go like this I remember that this code closes the file.
This file here fighters at CACP after the width is done.
After all that code runs.
So if I do it this way we have a problem because it's telling me on line 8 IO operation on closed file.
What's happening on line 8.
I'm accessing cac reader and it's not a problem that you know I made some random variable in here that
equals one.
I could access number right here.
So it's not a scope issue.
As you can see here we get one printed out.
It's a problem that arises because cac reader is connected.
It depends on this file being open.
And so if I ask to sit down here that files not open so we have a problem.
So the solution which I just showed in just a couple of seconds ago was indenting these inside one another
because we're only really writing data while we're working with data from one file.
So as far as efficiency it's not a good idea overall just to keep a bunch of these files open all the
time.
But if what we're doing is just transferring data from one to another and slightly altering it.
I think this approach works fine.
Otherwise we would need to make a new variable and save it equal to the list like we did in the last
example I have it here still like this.
So I will put both of these as potential examples and you can choose which one works best for you or
I'll add some comments just a second.
OK.
So there's the comment two different methods two approaches that work.
One involves taking the data from CACP reader iterating over it turning into a list saving it to a variable
that we can access later.
And the other one involves using nested with statements and keeping that file open so that we can access
directly from cac reader without transforming the data first.
OK.
Moving on.
To show you one other way of writing data to see SFE file.