Hello welcome back in this video will dive into the details of why testing matters why you should test
or why you should at least consider testing.
It's not necessarily something you need to do all the time.
But we'll talk about when and why you should do it.
And we'll also go into one philosophy around testing called TDD test driven development.
OK first off why test my wife with this in the slide to be honest.
Thank you.
I think I thought it was funny at the time.
I make almost like that ahead of time and then I come back and record.
I regret that I apologize.
OK.
So really why test.
So the whole idea of tests is that we're going to write code to monitor our own code to test our code
so we write these tests to ensure that you know there aren't bugs or at least to reduce the bugs and
errors in our existing code.
We write these tests that basically say OK this class should behave this way when I call this function
Let's say I add a called the add function with one and three I should get four back.
Very simple test.
But now imagine that you're testing a huge production application that has I don't know what 100 files
of code maybe ten thousand plus lines of Python code.
There's a lot of places where things could go wrong.
A lot of bugs that pop up.
So what you do is you write these tests and depending on what you're working on you could have a ton
of tests and you could have 10000 lines of tests or more just for 10000 lines of code.
So you run these tests on your own code and they'll tell you everything past or everything passed except
this one thing failed and then you hone in on OK what failed.
Why did it fail.
And it highlights problems in your code but it's not just existing bugs or problems.
Testing can also ensure that your bugs stay fixed.
Imagine a scenario where you're a developer at a company a big production app and we have I don't know
50 developers and everybody's working on their own features kind of on their own little pockets of code.
And what you do is you push your code up when you think that it's done and someone reviews it typically
or maybe two people review it and then it's merged into the codebase.
But maybe you change a line here or there that you don't think it's important to anyone else and it's
just a change that you need to make for your code or you're adding in you could inadvertently introduce
a new bug and you wouldn't be able to catch that or you might catch it later.
But having tests in there would help you catch that that bug earlier when you have a lot of people writing
code.
Anytime you're ready to deploy changes to your site or your app or whatever.
You run your tests and you'll see a bunch of green things or you'll see some red errors that tell you
hey this used to work doesn't work anymore and then that allows you to hone in on the problems.
So that ties into ensuring that new features don't break old ones.
For me that's one of the most important parts of testing especially in a big complicated app things
that you know you make something work once and then you forget about it six months later you're adding
to the code base and you inadvertently change something.
You change the data structure that you didn't think there was something else depended on.
You have a variable naming issue or whatever it is you overwrite a function accidentally tests.
Well Lerche you to that definitely faster than you as a human just finding them.
It also ensures that refactoring and cleaning things up doesn't introduce new bugs or break existing
functionality.
And some people think it makes development more fun.
I believe it makes it more satisfying especially when your tests do pass.
But we can.
This is as good a time as any to talk about why some people don't like it and it just comes down to
speed writing tests can slow you down a lot.
Sometimes your test files can be massive.
It's a lot of code to write and it really depends on the project.
The end product that you're working on.
If this is something for your own personal use it to one person dev team.
Yeah maybe you don't need a ton of tests but if this is on a large scale you have multiple developers.
Or this is something that people depend on.
It's not a hobby project but you have clients or customers or whatever shareholders you do not want
your code to break in.
You know what you never want your code to break.
But in those situations especially tests are absolutely worth it.
In my opinion so I'm not trying to proselytize and say that you need to write tests for every line of
code you ever write but at the same time it's never a bad idea if.
If you want to do it.
Some people think it's fun.
Crazy's.
OK so now that brings us to test driven development.
So testing is a separate idea.
Testing is the idea of writing tests writing code that tests your other code and you can write those
tests at any point you can write them after you introduce a new function.
You can write a test and guarantee that that function works.
You could write your entire application and then afterwards write a bunch of tests and see if those
work.
Or you could go with test driven development.
The idea behind TDD again is that you write your test first.
Once your tests are written you write the code to make them pass and then once those tests pass your
feature the thing that you're working on is considered complete.
So this is a philosophy that not developer shop not every company abides by the ones that I have experience
with or that I've had my students go on to I'd say that the minority but it's still very popular ideology
that might be too strong for word.
It is sort of like a cult.
Some of these people who get really into it because they feel that people feel very strongly about it.
Put it that way people who diligently follow TDD tend to be very devoted because it is kind of a radical
way of changing your development process.
Most people's approach is just to start writing code that don't want to step away from their code and
then maybe write some tests at the end.
But I've had some very good experiences with it.
So I'm not trying to say it's a bad idea.
I just want to throw it out there it's not something you have to do by any means.
I don't want to be seen as somebody who is trying to push it on all my students.
It's sort of like religion.
I'm not going to tell you to think one thing or another.
You get to make your own decision.
You're all adults.
OK.
The last thing I'll talk about is something called red green refactor.
This is like the mantra of test driven development.
It refers to you know the colors of your test passing and failing and it's sort of a workflow that you
practice with TDD.
So you start with the read.
You write a test that fails.
I make a brand new application the very first thing I would do if I was following TDD is write tests
that fail I know they're are going to fail.
So I say you know the log in function when somebody tries to log in with the incorrect username and
password they should see this message when somebody tries to log in with the correct password and email.
They should be redirected to this page.
Nothing is going to work.
So I get to fails then I write the minimal amount of code necessary to make the test pass.
So that's important.
It's not just about making the tests pass.
You don't just keep writing and writing and writing.
You write.
The very least amount of code possible so that your tests are covering.
So you have as much parity between the tests and the code and then as soon as they start passing you
can also focus on refactoring.
A lot of times what happens with TDD is that you write tests and they all fail and then you do bare
minimum to make them pass.
Then you write some more tests and they fail and then you update your functions in your application
to that those new tests pass.
But then by writing the bare minimum to make those tests pass you may have foregone some nicer cleaner
ways of writing things.
So you then you go back and clean up your code.
You refactor things if you have duplication if you can move things into one function or extract things
out into another function.
Then you've refactor.
So I actually show an example later in the section of the TDD process of red green.
Refactor.
So it's just a little mantra like I said that that people follow when they are doing test driven development.
Anyway I feel like shit like this it's like the birds and bees conversation it's uncomfortable no matter
how you feel about TDD.
Testing is a good idea.
It can really really save you a lot of time in the end.
You know to catch even just one bug if you write 100 Tests and they all pass and you never have to worry
about them again.
But one of them catches a bug that you wouldn't have known about otherwise or that you would have found
out about a month later when a user reported it it's worth it.
TDD on the other hand is totally up to you if you want to write your test first and then write your
code and then keep that cycle going.
Fine by me I like I said I think that it's a good idea but I also don't think that it's the right tool
for every situation.
OK so that's a high level overview of testing and TDD and all that fun stuff.
Now after this video at least we're going to dive into writing some code see how we can write tests.