Welcome back.
We are pushing on with the built in functions only a couple left and this video contains three that
are very short simple to talk about.
And there are all kinds of mathy they have to do with numbers and the first of the three We'll talk
about is called Abz stands for absolute value.
If you're not familiar with absolute value I'm going to do a terrible job of explaining it.
I don't remember the official mathematical definition but the absolute value of a positive number is
itself the absolute value of a negative number is the positive number.
So it's a way of just taking the numeric value without the negative sign.
So negative 5 turns into five five stays as 5.
So we just pass a number.
Abs abs negative 5 gives us 5 abs 5 gives just 5.
Quick example do abs of negative 23 give us 23.
It also does work with floats.
So I could do absolute value of three point 4 4 4 4 4 and it gives me 3 point 4 4 4 4 4.
And I do the negative.
It gives me the exact same result.
And that's kind of it.
You know it only works numbers and integers and floats.
So if I tried to do a string it's not going to try and convert it to an int or float first.
It just immediately tries it as it is does not like that.
So you know for getting user input into String we could do a float of 20 or something like that.
And then that will then convert it to a float from a string and then do absolute value as a side note.
There is another method called Fab's which you have to import with math.
Important Math.
And we could run Mathcad Fab's which I think it just stands for float absolute value and it will do
the exact same thing but it treats everything as a float first.
So if you pass an int it converts converts it to a float.
And so we get 4.00 instead of 4.
Next up we have some.
So also mathy all that it does is it will take an iterable a list a tuple whatever and it will take
an optional start and it will just add all the elements together so the sum of everything in that iterable
Plus the start.
So I'll show you what the start means.
But what's important.
It goes from left to right.
So it starts at the left side and keeps adding until it gets to the right side.
Start by default is zero.
So let me show you what I mean.
Let's just try adding a simple list.
We could do some of.
One two three.
Right.
So that should give us 6.
It goes from left to right.
So the optional start that we can provide has to be a number.
If you did something like 10 it will start at 10.
And then add all of these numbers to 10.
So it's a starting point and this should give us 16 as you can see or if we did negative 6 we'd get
zero.
So it starts there.
Add 1 adds to adds 3.
Other than that see can do two balls if we wanted to we could do floats in there.
So let's do two and three point seven.
And it returns a float even though one of them wasn't it.
You can also do a set containing numbers like that one.
Somewhat interesting thing if we try and some strings like a list of strings like high and there I just
do it on its own.
Well I need the quote.
We're going to get an error.
We're going to get an error no matter what.
But the first one is it's going to try and start at zero.
The integers zero and add it to a string and it gives us an error on two prototype plus int and string.
It can't doesn't know what to do between the into the string.
So if you actually provide your own start and instead I tell it to start with I don't know ELO Well
you would think it could just add a well plus high plus there and give ELO Alhaj.
There is one string.
But instead it gives us this customary here that's in the source code.
Some can't.
Some strings use join sequence instead.
We've already seen how to do that.
Empty string join.
Know so we can do the exact same thing where we just take this empty string join passing the list and
we get high there.
But I just think it's interesting that there's actually a note a custom thing in the source that tells
you not to use some.
And on the documentation you can see they actually have a note here too for some use cases they're a
good alternative to something that fast fast.
The preferred fast way to can catch a sequence of strings is by calling empty string but join to add
floating point values with extended precision.
So for a more precise way there's math in the math module a method called F sum just like we saw with
Fab's f abs the value float absolute value.
Anyway that's all there is to sum.
Finally we have round so round we'll take a number and it will return a rounded version and we specify
the number of digits.
How how precise precisely what the round to be.
How many decimal points should round two and by default it will return the nearest integer.
If we don't specify the number of digits.
So for example round ten point two.
It just assumes to round to the nearest integer.
So that doesn't mean it will floor it like integer division or something.
It will round it appropriately.
But if we specify two digits then it will give us one point to 1 in this example.
So we can do round of 3.5.
One two three four and let's round if we don't specify anything.
It gives us four it rounds up.
In this case to the nearest integer.
But if I did two three digits I get three point five one two to this decimal place.
What else.
That's pretty much it with round you.
If he manually specified none.
It will also round to an integer.
So by default if you don't specify or you actually pass the value on then it will round to the nearest
integer.
And that's kind of it I guess you should be aware of the fact that you know floats are only precise
so far so if we had a massive float like 9 9 9 9 9 9 9 and you kept going.
That's got to be past the largest float we can store and we try and round it to I don't know 15 decimal
points it just runs half to 10.
So at some point the precision slips just worth knowing about.
But if you need something precise you're probably doing something crazy.
I mean I don't even know what you would need to be that precise honestly.
But if you were then you would also probably know a way around it.
Or you have a supercomputer to help you or something.
OK.
So those are three built in functions that are I just lump them together as mathy.
So we had absolute value abs some.
And then round we have one more in the next video.
And then we've covered pretty much all of the built in functions.