We'll get we're back.
We're talking about dictionaries still.
All right.
So in the list comprehension videos I mentioned we're seeing how to do this with lists but there are
similar things we can do with other data structures that we'll see later.
Well one of those is dictionaries.
So in this video we're talking about dictionary comprehension as the slide says.
So the syntax is similar but it's also different.
First thing right off the bat instead of using the list brackets we're using dictionary brackets so
that part probably makes sense.
We still have the four blank in blank but then up front rather than a single plank.
We have blank Colan blank and I'm saying a lot of it doesn't make sense and I'm just talking about it
like this.
So it will iterate over keys by default and we can use dot items if you want to iterate over keys and
values.
But let's just took Take a look at our first example.
So here we have a dictionary called numbers.
And if we look at numbers it just has first is one second to third is.
And they're all you know the integer 1 2 3.
Here is our dictionary comprehension.
We are iterating through numbers not items.
So right here this is a standard for what we've seen before for key value in number items.
We're going to take the key and just keep it the same.
So each of the keys in this new dictionary starts with first the second and third.
Just like before but value.
We're going to square multiply by itself.
So we end up with 1 times 100 is 1 2 times.
Times 2 which is 4 and 3 times 3 which is 9.
So just one more time to iterate iterate.
Reiterate are you using key value because we're using dead items.
So we're looping through and for each one we're basically adding a key value pair.
Just like with a list comprehension Oh we only need one value here which represents what to add to each
list to each part of the list.
In this case we need two pieces.
The key and the value.
OK let's try this again.
Here's another example which does this one do.
So this iterable collection now this is different.
We're not using existing dictionary.
We're making a dictionary but we're starting with a list and we're going through it for each number
in them.
We're going to set the value to the square of number but the actual key is going to be known to try
and pretty visualize this before I run it.
What do you expect.
And we get one call and one to call in four and so on.
So we have the initial number known as the key and then the corresponding value is that same number
squared.
So here's another example.
This time we have two strings.
And what we're basically doing is looping through the strings and we're taking the first of string one
the first character which is a making that the key and the value is 1 B to C 3 are basically course.
I don't know what we would call this.
We're like interleaving them.
And to do that we need to just write a loop to loop through one of the strings.
So we're just using a range for I in range 0 to the length of the string and we're taking that number.
And the reason we need to do that rather than doing for character in string One is we would need the
index to access the corresponding character string to.
So it's better to use a range.
So I is going to be a numbers starting from zero.
And then we're just making the key string one of I.
So that would be the first time through and the corresponding value string two of I which is 1.
Hopefully you can see how that makes sense.
We're basically just generating a number over here and plugging it in first string and then that string
and setting them as corresponding key value pairs.
OK so a quick example here.
I have a simple or instr. dictionary says name called City San Francisco color purple.
And if I wanted to do sort of a joke version but I'll call it yelling instructor and I'll have every
key and every value upper cased.
So it would look something like this I could call it you know yelling instructor equals we need a dictionary
here.
Dictionary comprehension and we'll just start with key.
I'll do K.
Dot upper colon value.
Upper space for k comma V an instructor dot items.
So right now it looks like a lot this little bit of syntax is kind of gross with the parentheses in
the colon but we're just iterating through instr. that items giving instead of key and value and using
K and V just to keep it shorter.
And then we're setting the key to be the uppercase version of the existing key and the value to be the
uppercase version of the existing value.
And if I look at young instructor now I have name called City San Francisco.
Well name called City San Francisco color purple.
Anyway it's just a silly little example but let's look at conditional logic now.
So here's another example.
We have a list of numbers 1 2 3 4 and we're just going to iterate through that list and create a dictionary
that specifies one is odd to is even threes and fours even and so on.
And just create a nice little dictionary that has you know values maps too if there even or odd.
So we loop through for name and number list.
We have our dictionary brackets.
And then this is the syntax we set.
Numb colon.
So our values are a key.
It's just going to be the number we could do something else here.
Oh just leave it at Colon and then even if Number two is equal to zero else odd.
So we're going to set the value of corresponding values even if it's even no remainder when we divide
by 2.
Otherwise set it to be odd.
So let's check it out.
And if I pasted in there we go I get one odd to even and actually could even do this instead of for
number in numberless letters to range from 1 to 100.
And we get a massive list or massive dictionary that has no corresponding key value pairs for each number
and it's corresponding.
What is this property called.
Even this oddness.
There's got to be a name for both of them.
I'll look it up and put a pillow.
And we're not limited to just doing our conditional logic on the value side of things on the right side
of the colon.
We go back to my instructor dictionary when we doing the upper casing.
Let me just bring that back here.
Here we go.
Yelling instructor I could do something like this let's say it is going to be silly but I only wanted
to uppercase color and leave name and city lowercase but still uppercase every value so I could do something
like this K Dot upper if K I'll do is color.
Else ups will just do K and if we look at yoga instructor now name and city or lowercase What color
is upper case.
So you can see we have conditional logic as part of the key and then the value is the same.
So appear we had conditional logic is part of the value.
All right so that just about wraps it up for dictionary comprehension as well as dictionaries.
We have some exercises that sort of fun thing but we're done with new content with dictionaries.