Get super quick video I can probably do it in one breath.
Let's try.
OK.
So what we're talking about here is swapping values.
So if we have a list with two items James and Michelle we can swap the values around by using this comma
syntax so name zero common names one.
We're going to change them to be names one common names so whatevers and names you out we're going to
put names one there whatevers and names one.
We're gonna put names here or there.
And the effect is swapping them and we get Michelle comma japes and that's pretty much it does so often.
So when do you need to swap.
I'm losing my breath.
OK I can do it.
When do you need to swap.
When you're shuffling things.
So if you had imagined a list of I mean a list of cards which you could model with strings you know
we could have like a 8 C would be eight of clubs eight D would be eight of diamonds.
Eventually we'll talk about objects and classes but you could shuffle a list full of of cards.
Sorting is another really important example if we're trying to sort a list in place to find our own
custom sort.
And we have a list of people or numbers or whatever it is and we're trying to do it in place meaning
that we're not making a new list.
Well then we just need to swap things because that's the that's pretty much all we can do because we're
not making a new list.
We need to move things around if we try and move one thing we have to move something else.
So we need to swap and just a lot of algorithms in general that we'll be discussing later on.
So swapping is just a little shortcut that we get where you use the comma instead of a variable assignment.