Hey welcome back.
In this video I'm going to introduce something called compilation flags.
These are little preferences that we can set when we're compiling a regular expression that impact how
it works.
And there's a couple of them.
The docs if you scroll down to the compilation flags section you can read more about them.
They let you modify some aspects of how regular expressions work.
They all have different names and the ones that I'm going to show you there are two in particular.
I'm going to focus on the Ignore case and verbose.
So these are two flags you can add in that will change how things work.
Ignore case I think is most self-explanatory.
It will tell a regular expression to ignore the case of letters.
So instead of having to say match upper case a to uppercase Z and the lower case a lower case the we
can just specify it is the ignore case.
Often if we're working with user input we don't really care about capitalisation so that's pretty commonly
used.
And the second one is called verbose.
And let me just start by illustrating how that works.
I have a regular expression here that this is for emails.
It's slightly different from the one we've seen.
I found this online.
Somebody suggested that this is slightly better or more accurate so we can work through it really quickly
as to start with.
It is the spirit of mine.
So a digit a letter underscore a slash a dot and a dash more than one of them as a plus sign.
That's the first capture group then a single sign and then ANY digit.
I'm sure why this one is done that way.
I think it could also just do zero to nine.
It's easier for me to read that 8 as the dash plus So more than one of those or one or more and then
a period dot.
And then this is the top like camarade org from 2 to 6 letters and it has to end with that.
OK so that's not too bad.
Hopefully we've seen similar things.
The parents are in here just for capturer groups.
We don't really need them.
But what I want to focus on first of all is that this is kind of a long line and it can be intimidating
or difficult to understand what's happening especially if you didn't write this.
If you're working in a code base and there some large regular expressions.
This is actually pretty short.
You know there are some very large ones that I've seen in different applications and if you're not the
person who wrote it or worked on it it can be very intimidating.
What we can do to help out a bit is use the verbose flag which allows us to put this on multiple lines
and add comments so it doesn't impact how it actually works how it matches things.
It's exactly the same but it allows us to expand things onto different lines.
And if we look at the documentation I think there's an example here we go.
So this is using for Boese the verbose flag you pass it in at the end and it allows us to break our
code or reject pattern up and comment on it and it will ignore the comments.
C's explain a little bit whitespace within the regular expression string is ignored except from the
White space in a character class or preceded by an undiscovered backslash so it will ignore whitespace.
But if you if you need a space or you need that whitespace as part of the pattern you can use a backslash.
OK so I'm going to convert this one and I'll just leave it up here and do it.
Another duplicate.
I'll call this one pattern equals precompile and I'm going to start off we need our raw string but we're
going to do a triple double quote so we can do it on multiple lines comma.
We need to pass in the flag.
Verbose.
If I don't have that on there it's not going to work.
So you can think of it as you know it's one line but we're just breaking it up and then in here we add
in the different components.
So what I like to just break it up.
So take the first little bit and add a comment.
But let's just put all the pieces in first.
Actually then we have the at sign.
It's kind of up to you how you want to break it up but I'll do it this way.
Each little piece and then we end up with this.
OK so same thing just copy and pasted.
But now you can go in and add a little comment here that says what do you call that at the beginning
of an email like the kitty at gmail dot com the user name the name.
I don't know what to call that.
I'm just going to write.
First part of email.
Then we have a single sign.
Then after that what do we have here.
This is the domain or the email provider.
Then a single dot and then finally we have com or net.
I'll just put that for the top level domain so we're just adding little comments that explain what is
what and when to comment this out.
Get rid of this one.
Let's make sure it works.
So I'm here to do a pattern that lets you search and pass in Thomas.
One two three at yahoo dot com.
Pattern of search of safe that is just call it and match.
Then let's do a print matched up groups.
And let's also do group singular.
Let's see if it works.
Who are you.
It's the same thing I had this problem in the last video I'm sorry.
Hopefully you saw that before me.
I didn't import Ari.
OK.
So it's working it's matching this entire e-mail and then we have three groups which we maybe don't
need to separate Yahoo and come out maybe we just want this first thing but it doesn't really matter.
We're not doing anything with it.
This is more about the flags.
So if we don't have her boss in there and I just do this there's a problem.
It doesn't work.
It's not actually matching anymore because it's as part of the pattern expecting a new line character
and white space and newline characters and it just doesn't work.
But if we add for bosomed there which is our e for most it works also we can do instead of read out
for Bowse where said the letter X instead r e.
X it's kind of annoying that it's not R E V but X stands for extended I think.
So we can do X and it should still work.
And it does.
Okay.
So lastly let's talk about Ignore case ignore case.
It's nice and useful right now with what we have.
If I did Thomas with capital T and capital S or Yahoo with capital Y and I tried running it.
It doesn't work.
It doesn't match anything anymore because we're only specifying a lower case here.
So I could go in in all these cases and do upper case a to lowercase to uppercase Z or I could tell
it to ignore case and unfortunately I can't just do comma.
Ari does it ignore case which is the name of the flag.
It only wants one argument with the flags.
And so you might think oh we could put them in a tuple together or something it doesn't like that.
If you go to the docs it explains here.
We have to do multiple files can be specified by bitwise OR ing them like this are e.
I type the or symbol R M.
It's kind of bizarre in my opinion but if you come in here let's go back to verbose.
Just to be more verbose and clearer are not verbose or already done ignore case it's not saying one
or the other it's just saying use both these flags.
And that's the syntax we have to use.
Now if we run our exact same code it matches even though we didn't specify uppercase A's and Z is we
only have lower case.
It still works and we can further shorten this by going to R E dot X which is again for extended r e.
I makes more sense for Ignore case.
Tested again.
It still works.
Cool.
So that's pretty much it to flags.
There are other flags but those are the ones that I use that most people use all the time.
You can explore some of the other ones that docs go into detail but ignore case and verbose are the
two most popular.