Welcome to the last video and this section on functions it's been a whirlwind.
Learned a lot hopefully did a couple of exercises.
If not we have a ton coming up the next section is all exercises bunch of practice hopefully.
But the last thing we're going to talk about here before we do a recap is how we document our functions
and Python comes the very special way of adding documentation of adding little messages to each function
that explain what they do.
And it looks like this.
We use triple double quotes so three double quotes and then a message and then three double quotes and
it's always the first line of function and you don't have to do it for every single function ever.
You know we won't do it for most things but if we do any complex projects well when we do complex projects
it will be nice to be able to document what each function does.
So first line of the function triple double quotes.
This one we say a simple function that returns a string hello and this is not just a little comment
feature but you can actually access it by referring to the function and then using the dot double underscore
doc double underscore and that will it's a property generated automatically by this.
That will then retrieve whatever we put inside those triple double quotes.
So for example print we've been using print all the time.
If we do print out double underscore doc double underscore we get a little message that says print the
values to a stream.
There's a bunch of stuff here.
You know add to add a new line at the end that sort of thing.
Or let's look at random dot Rand int which you have to import.
So let's import random.
And if we do dot doc return random and integer in range including both end points.
And lastly let's just make a list dot pop dot Doc and it says removes and return items and index defaults
to last raises index error.
If a list is empty or index is out of range so this all just goes to show that all the built in functions
have this.
And we can define our own when we define the function.
So in our xponent function triple double quotes just like this first line of the function.
So we could just say something like this.
Exponent power raises no to specified power power defaults to.
Just like a little note that explains how this works.
And by default nothing will happen but maybe at the end we'll do a print xponent dot double underscore
and we want doc double underscore.
And now if I try running Python 3 xponent we get the same values but then at the end it just prints
to me that docstring.
OK.
So that's all there is to that.
It doesn't have any other functionality that's it.
So lastly let's recap all the ground we've covered.
There's a lot we've learned so we've seen that functions are just procedures for executing code to a
couple of lines or more maybe 100 more lines although that's not a good idea to have them that long
but once you code with a name sometimes to take inputs and often they have outputs they spit something
out at the end using the return keyword to create inputs.
We make parameters which can have default values we call those default parameters we assign those with
an equal sign.
Variables defined inside of functions are scoped to that function.
So remember that scope is a thing that is kind of a painful video probably but we talked about how when
you have a function if you define a variable inside it it exists only inside that function and not afterwards
not beforehand.
Only in that function when invoking a function we can pass in keyword arguments in any order where we
use the equal sign.
It's different than default parameters because it's inside of the function invocation set of thing in
vocation.
When we execute the function we'll see this a lot more later when we talked about dictionaries and unpacking
them.
Finally be careful not to return too early in your conditional logic and refactor when you can to remove
unnecessary conditional logic.
Make sure you don't return in a loop as well.
So remember in that video I showed two common mistakes that were made when using return statements.
Oh boy.
Yeah there's a lot we learned a lot in this section and hopefully you enjoyed some of the smaller exercises
I sprinkled in throughout the last section but after this immediately following this video is a section
of 10 or more maybe more like 15 exercises.
All in the browser with a bunch of tests written that all will challenge your skills at writing functions
and they should be arranged in difficulty from easiest to hardest but that is slightly subjective.
So I'd start at the beginning.
You don't have to do all of them you don't have to do any of them but I recommend you attempt to do
them because it's good practice and it took a long time to make them.
So enjoy that hopefully.
And then afterwards we're going to talk more about functions.
Some of the more advanced topics around them see and a bit.