Hey there.
Welcome back.
In this video I'm just going to talk about one important feature of strings so let's say we have a string
like ELO Well three characters.
This string is indexed meaning that each character has a number that corresponds to it.
So I can access individual pieces of the string using that number and the first thing you should know
is that those numbers start at zero.
So the first character is the zero with character.
Then this character is the first character and then the second owl is the second character.
And if he wanted to access those pieces of data we use square brackets.
This is a silly example to do something like this but I put that number in there.
EHLO Well bracket is zero.
He's going to give me el more commonly he would have it in a variable like name equals.
Chuck and then if I do name bracket zero it gives me see if I do named bracket 1 h.
I won't go all the way through if I wanted to get the last letter I need to do 0 1 2 3 4.
If I try to access 5 however we get an error string index out of range we will talk a lot more about
indices and indexes indexed items.
Let's just call them that including lists later on.
But I just wanted to expose you to this this feature this ability of strings one simple use case of
this that I can show you.
Imagine we have an app where we ask the user if they want to play again.
It's a game at the end we ask do you want to keep playing and they can either type yes or yeah or Y
or Glaspell this way or you like this.
We want all of those options.
And for no they could say no or nah or 9 or some other no sounding negative that starts with an end.
What we can do is just check the first character so we can have a variable called the answer.
And let's say answers equal to ya like this.
I would just access.
Answer zero and that's why and then that way if this was instead.
Yes sir I do answer zero.
And it gives me why again.
One other point that I should make is that we can access them using negative numbers as well.
So I have.
Yes sir.
In the answer very well if I pass in negative one it starts from the end and gave and gives me are negative
2.
It's going to give me I can keep going.
So if I wanted to get y for some reason I wanted to start here I would go negative one two three four
five six negative six gives me y.
Or you could just do zero.
Much easier anyway.
This may not seem that useful right now but later on when we get to things like lists we'll be using
this syntax all the time indices in Python.
Always start at zero.
So it's important to understand that as well.
And that's pretty much it.