Hey welcome back.
The last big topic around projects that we'll talk about has to do with substitutions or finding and
replacing things in text based off of a regular expression pattern.
Another very common use case.
Before we dive into the specifics I just want to highlight at the bottom of the documentation on the
Python docs.
There's a nice little overview of some common problems with regular expressions.
And one of the big points that it makes is that you may not always need to use a regular expression.
So if you're trying to match a fixed string or a single character and you know you're not using things
like ignore case then regular expressions might be overpowered.
Strings have some of those methods already in place to help you find things or substitute things.
So you know you could use the replace method for example if I click on this you just give it a what
you trying to replace.
And then what you want to replace it with and it will do that.
So if I'm trying to replace the curse word the F word exactly the F word and nothing else.
And I want to replace it with stars or something.
It would probably be best to use the string method replace But if instead I'm trying to replace something
that's like phone numbers I'm trying to replace phone numbers in the string and block them out with
the Stars so that people can't you know see the number I'm releasing some document I don't want the
numbers in there it would be better or really only doable using a regular expression or you could do
it yourself manually and like iterate through the string at each index and check it would be a nightmare.
So string don't replace wouldn't work.
Just keep that in mind.
Sometimes there are things you can do without a regular expression.
OK.
But we are in a reject section after all.
And we're going to talk about the sub method very useful.
What it will do you compile a pattern first then use that pattern we call sub with it and we specify
what we want to replace that pattern with.
This is the replacement.
The first argument and the second argument is the string that we're going to replace things in.
So let me show you an example.
Let's say that I have a classified document here very short classified document.
Last night Mrs. Dezi and Mr. White murdered Mr. Chao and I want to remove the names to protect their
privacy.
So what I need to do is basically select anything that starts with the pattern misses period or Mr.
Period or.
Well we don't have a Ms.
Let's do that.
Now we do I want to select that followed by a name that comes afterwards.
So how are we going to do this.
Well let's define our pattern first.
So are e compile save it to a variable called pattern.
Are you compile our rostering.
And we'll start with select Mr. or Mrs. or Ms.
And we put parens around that because we only want one of these or works.
And then there is a letter.
Let's just do a to z rather than upper case and you have to worry about that and then we'll do our IID
dot ignore case are you dumb.
I saw more than one and that should work for us.
That should match it.
So Mr.
MRS.
Mr Mrs or Ms.
Followed by A to Z.
And let's just make sure that it's matching.
So if we just start if we use a let's do pattern find all and then we'll find all of the text.
That's the name of our string.
Let's print the result.
Remember this returns instead of a match object it just returns a list.
I have it spelled correctly.
OK.
And if I run the file you'll see that it looks like it's not working.
It looks like it's only it's only matching Ms.
Geez.
Mrs Mr and Ms.
That's because the way I find all works if instead of find.
We did search and let's do say variable let's just do actually print patterned out search text dot group
like that.
You'll see that it matches the first thing it returns because that's what search does.
It only gives the first match.
It does give us Mrs. Daisy.
It was not just matching the misses.
It's just that when we use find doll it uses that first group here rather than the entire match.
It's kind of annoying anyway.
What we want to do is use sub which is pattern.
So what do we want to replace it with.
Just write read redacted or something like that.
And what are we replacing in the string text.
So we're using this pattern and we're ignoring case this will match this right here.
This right here and this right here and then we're going to replace it all with redacted each instance
and then let's do print let's just print the result of that.
Let's save it to a variable and then print results.
Here we go.
There we go.
Last night redacted and redacted murdered redacted.
OK.
So that's good but maybe it would be better if we changed it a bit.
What if we could do something like last night Mrs..
And then D and Mr. W so that we still can keep track of who is who.
Rather than redacted.
I mean imagine there's you know a whole police report with like 20 sentences plus if it just said redacted
over and over and over it would be very difficult.
So if we do this instead it should be easier.
But this is harder because I mean how do we do that right now replacing them all with the exact same
thing redacted and it's replacing everything or just replacing the misses and the space in between.
And the name what would you want to do is actually just replace this part and this part and that part.
So it's kind of hard.
Well it seems hard.
What we can do is take advantage of capture groups.
We already have a capture group here and we can work with that.
There's a special syntax.
It's kind of bizarre that allows us to reference capture groups and see if we can find it here.
Looks like this backslash G for group.
And then in brackets angle brackets a number and that's of course that will correspond to running group
1.
Also if we give Remember this from earlier for we can add a name to catch capture group you can refer
to it in there just like you would use a number you can use the name.
I'll just use the number though.
So this is group 1.
So if I wanted to just do Mr. redacted Mrs. redacted MS redacted get rid of the last name I already
have.
Mr. Mrs. and MS in a group.
So I'm going to reference backslash G.
One which is going to give us whatever the result was the first capture group and out of space.
And if we look at the result now we get last night Mrs. redacted and Mr. redacted murdered MS redacted.
If I didn't have the space in there or if I changed the order like this I'm swapping them you get last
night redacted misses and redacted Mr. murdered redacted Ms.
OK so hopefully you can see how that all works.
It's kind of a weird syntax to use this but this is how it works.
It's matching whatever the first group was.
So if I wanted to continue on and include the first letter we have to get a little fancier.
We need to differentiate.
Right now we're just getting all of the letters.
Like it's just Mr. Mrs. and Miss.
And then any letters afterwards until you hit a space or at least we first want to capture the first
letter.
So it's just going to be a.
I'm not going to specify it has to be capitalized because maybe there's you know Mr. White like that
and I'm going to capture that in the group and then afterwards any number of letters following that.
So what that will now allow us to do is also reference backslash g to and I can get rid of the redacted
part.
So it's going to capture this.
It's going to capture a single letter and then any other letters afterwards are not being captured in
the group right now.
But it's still matching them.
And then I can just take first group space group too and that should give us Mrs. D.
Mr. W let's see if it works.
It does.
Mrs. D.
And Mr. W murdered Mrs. or Ms.
C..
Awesome.
So that's the basics of using sub.
You can just directly substitute for a string that you hard code in or you can reference parts capture
groups that you went and added in using parentheses in the regular expression itself.
This is pretty powerful stuff if you're trying to do this on your own.
It would be a lot more work if you weren't using regular expressions.