All right welcome back.
So we're going to build something again.
It's tiny.
It's not going to amaze you but we're at least using the things we've learned so far.
So variables alongside data types and having to convert data types using format strings that sort of
thing.
So what we're going to build is a converter which apparently misspelled both within a year and an hour
anyway.
What's it's going to do is take kilometers and convert them to Miles.
Or you could easily make it work the other way around.
Totally up to you.
But the somewhat new part the novel bit is that it's going to ask a user in the command line how many
kilometers do you want to convert to Miles.
And then the user will type in I dunno 50 or something like that.
So here's kind of how.
Here's how it will work.
Let me clear up my terminal and I have a file a solution file I'll just run that now Python 3 converter
duppy Why how many kilometers did you run today.
Let's say I do a long race.
I did a 50 K my 50 Clomid run was 31 point 0 7 miles.
So notice how it asked me for input you know same thing here.
Let's say I only ran do nine kilometers which is 5.5 nine miles.
So that's what we're going to build.
And the first thing we need to talk about is how we actually get user input.
So let's make a new file.
I'm going to call it mileage.
Why call it whatever you want if you're using Cloud 9.
You know open the file up with the card 9 editor you Sublime Text.
If you're on a Mac or PC and you have it installed or just any text editor but I have the SBL command
I'm going to open it up and the first thing I'm going to show you is this little bit of magic called
input and it's actually no more magic than any other bit of Python code.
It's a function just like the other ones you've seen like print or Ent. to convert something to an integer
or as TR for string.
We haven't talked really about functions but that's all we're going to say for now.
And input will ask the user to enter something.
It doesn't really ask the user.
It just changes the prompt in the command line and it waits for the user to type something and hit the
return key hit the enter key.
And the important thing is that we need to store the value in a variable.
So I'm going to just call it KAMC.
So we're going from kilometers to Miles and my version.
But feel free to do it the other way around.
You just need to change the coefficient that we divide or multiply by.
So KMC equals input.
And let's start by just printing a line up here that I don't know.
Let's go with how many kilometers Did you or do you want to convert.
Did you cycle today.
Why not.
It's a little less crazy to do 50 kilometers.
Cycling versus running and all we'll do after this is just print.
OK you said and let's make this an F string or actually that's just too concatenations so.
OK you said plus Cambs.
So it seemed to just parrot it back to the user.
So let's go to the command line now.
OK.
So here we are.
And the file is called mileage dot p y.
So Python 3 mileage and it says how many kilometers did you cycle today.
Let's say I did 57.
OK.
You said 57.
Very useful program.
Thank you.
It's working just fine.
So input again gets input from the user and saves the value in a variable.
Now what data type is it.
This is important.
You can actually infer it already based off of the fact that this worked.
Remember if it was a number it wouldn't.
If it is an integer or float it would not concatenate with a string.
So we can deduce that it is a string but that's going to be a problem because we need to do math with
it.
So right now it's a string 50 ups like this.
And if we try and divide it and I think I'll look it up but it's 1.6 something to go from kilometers
to Miles.
Let me do that now.
There you go on Google.
One mile is 1.6 0 9 3 4.
Ok so I'm going to copy that and it's going to paste that here for now.
So of course this won't work.
First of all it won't print anything out or save it to variable but also it's a string divided by a
float.
That's a problem.
So what we want to do is turn K.M. is that the user entered into a float so we could do it just like
this.
If you're comfortable with doing sort of two layers here of taking a float of the input and that works
fine.
We could also do this.
So float.
And the reason I'm doing float by the way is for more precise division because let's say the user entered
fifty point five kilometers.
If we turn that into an int it would turn it into 50 and then divide by 1.6 versus if they entered fifty
point five.
And we cast it as a float.
It will stay fifty point five.
OK.
So let's save this to a variable and we'll call it miles equals float kilometers which is the user input
divided by 1.6 0 9 3 4.
Let's see if that works now and maybe just maybe we'll have an error.
Let's see what happens.
Let's say we did eight kilometers and we didn't even get the error I expected.
We did something really silly or I did.
I'm not using miles.
I'm just pointing out the initial input.
So we did this math and it just goes to waste.
All right let's try that again.
So we did eight and we get an error.
OK so this is the one I was expecting.
Notice we get a type error must be string not float.
So what's happening is this concatenation is upset because this is a float that the result of the division
is a float regardless of the fact that this is a float.
Remember that any regular division where there's a single division sign single slash is going to be
a float.
If we did a double one it would be integer division.
OK.
So a float we can just add that to a string.
So we're going to use handy dandy strings.
So rather than just saying OK you said Let's say that is equal to and in here we'll put our Miles variable
and then afterwards just type the word miles.
So we should get that is equal to seven miles or six point two miles or whatever we want.
Now let's try running it again.
I ran 8 or cycled 8 kilometers that's equal to four point nine seven owner and 8 blah blah blah blah
blah miles.
So it's working.
The math is working the problem or it's not necessarily a problem but it's kind of annoying as how many
decimal points we get here.
We don't really want that.
So let's round it which is new.
We don't we don't know how to do that yet.
Fortunately it's very simple.
There's another little function called Round round is a bit different than something like input in that
we actually provide two different items two pieces of data to it.
The first is the thing around and the second is how many decimal points to round it to.
So I'm going to comment that out for now command slash on subcontext or just Octa Thorpe hash sign.
And we have a couple of choices.
We could just round it right here.
So round miles and let's go to two decimal points.
So this works.
Remember that instead these curly braces it sort of I mean it's regular Python where we can do math
we could call something like round it depends on you know how long your code is you don't want this
to be excessively long in the middle of your string but it's not a problem as far as the code goes.
So now let's try it let's do eight again.
There we go 4.9 seven miles.
So we could do it this way or we could come up here and do the round and do this whole thing.
Comet too.
But I actually think it's better to do it on a separate line because that line gets a little bit long.
So let's do miles equals around miles to down here we just display miles.
So all we're doing is repeating this.
It is another line but it's a little nicer to read.
So we're doing the math first and then we could even call this rounded miles if we want but we're going
to call it Miles and update it to be rounded of the current value of miles to two decimal places.
And let's just double check that it still works.
Let's say we ran.
Let's go with 30 kilometers that's equal to eighteen point six four miles.
Right.
That seems to be working just fine.
The last change we could make is just tell the user kilometers first and then Miles so instead of saying
that is equal to you could say your curly braces K ambs
kilometer ride is.
And then let's do.
Am I.
So we're just working with abbreviations.
So this should say something like your 10 kilometer ride is what it is 10 kilometers whatever the math
is.
And Miles let's try that again 10 kilometers your 10K ride is 6.2 1 miles.
Great.
We could do was instead but otherwise that's it.
So kind of the way we went about this.
I was trying to showcase a couple of things kind of forced us to encounter that type error was and it
was a big one where input gives us a string but we're trying to do math with it.
So we need to turn into a float.
But then to printed out we can't concatenate because it's a float now.
So we need to use an F string and that's really the key thing here.
Round was a nice little bonus on top but it's not something we covered in this section.
We will come back to functions like around.
We'll come to that later but for now this is all that we need.
It's a nice simple little converter.
Probably will never use it ever.
But it's still given the small amount of pieces that we have in our toolbox.
It's something at least it's better than just you know printing a single variable out.
OK.
Next up we're moving onto boolean logic.