Hey welcome back.
And this video we're going to use sub with a substitution method to find it in place but rather than
replacing with some new text we're going to swap items within a given string.
So here I have a list of book titles.
Imagine that I had this on my computer and rather than what is this nine books in this series it's this
series called The Tales of the city.
One two three four five six yeah.
Okay.
Rather than just these imagine that I had an entire library of ten thousand books or movies or songs
any type of media with a file name.
And they all followed the format where there was the name of the file and then a space and then a date
for numbers a date in parentheses.
And this is great but let's say that like in a series like this there's a particular order to them and
I need to.
I'm starting out.
I want to know what order to read if I try and sort them right now.
I mean this is kind of silly because I can just manually it's not that hard to look at the dates here
but if there was 10000 of them here I wanted to know what order they're in.
If I try and sort them right now or do titles does sorts and then print titles.
You know what to expect.
It will sort alphabetically based off the first character and I end up with baby cakes first and then
all the way down to the days of a madrigal.
That's not the correct order.
So let's say that I want to swap things around and change the format so that we get let's say 1978 space
tales of the city like that.
This is it with the new order I want I don't want the per end either.
I want just the date.
How about a dash.
Let's do that like that.
That's what I'm looking for for all of these books.
OK.
So what we're going to do is start off by defining our pattern.
We need to match two different pieces.
The title here.
And then the date.
So let's start by defining our pattern.
And before I forget import are we not making that mistake.
The third time.
And then down here we'll do pattern equals precompile do rostering and we'll say it needs to start off.
So we'll use the carrot and start off with a word character any number of word characters and that will
work but it will only get us to here.
We want it to keep going and include all everything until we get to the data at least.
So I'll just add the spacing.
OK.
So that will get us all of this and I'm going to add an extra space here and I'll explain why in a moment.
But let's come back to it and focus on the date.
So to match the Prendes we need to do backslash parentheses.
So that would give us the open that would give us a close.
And then in before in between we want four numbers.
So I'm just going to do digit 4.
OK.
So that should match opening parentheses for numbers closing parentheses.
UPS which gives us this whole thing here.
Now the reason I added the space if I didn't add a space here this regular expression that's first part
would match all of this including that space and that's OK.
That's correct.
Because I'm telling it to match all weird characters and spaces until we hit this parentheses.
So that's what it's going to do.
But then when I swap the two I will end up with a space at the end of my file name.
Because if I just select this and I leave that space there I move this to the front.
Even if I add a space here or a dash I still have that space at the end.
So instead when I group these things I'm going to do that now.
My first grouping is going to include any number of word characters and spaces except the last one.
So any number of word characters and spaces until we get to this one that comes right before the parentheses
and the date.
So it's just a way of getting around that.
And then I could put parens around the entire date like this.
And I can start with that but you'll see the problem it's going to select the parentheses and I'm trying
to change the format to just be the date dash.
So I don't want the prince but substitute things to so that's going to be patterned.
Sub save it to a variable just called results patterned out sub.
And I'll just put a string in there for now and pass in.
Let's just do it on a single title.
Titles 0 to start this first one.
And what do we want to solve.
This is where we need to use our backslash G for group and then a number.
The group that comes second this one here group two is what I want first now and then I want a dash
and then backslash G group 1 which is going to be all of this.
Let's see what it looks like.
There we go.
1984.
You can ignore this part that's coming from here.
Get rid of that 1984 dash baby cakes.
But I do have those parents around that date to get rid of those.
I just won't add them into the group.
I'll change this so that the parents are only around the four digits.
So it's kind of crazy.
It's very compact and gross to look at but we're selecting we're looking for parents.
This is the actual print the see character opening and closing and in between those four digits I'm
putting in a captured group which will be Group Two.
So now when I run this there we go 1984 dash baby cakes.
So now I'm just going to run through every title and run this code.
So it's going to be for book titles.
We make a new list.
I'll just call this fixed books or fixed titles.
It's an empty list and then I saw it again OK.
Then I'm going to come down here and for book and titles I'm going to just make a very I'll just call
it result still instead of title zero though I'm going to use book for each book and titles or place
and then all appendant to fixed titles.
I could do it on one line but it would be pretty long and then I'm going to sort.
Fixed titles at the end because now all the dates will be first and then let's print fixed titles.
OK let's see if it works.
Awesome.
So we get from 1978 1980 1982 all the way up to 2014.
So it's working.
We've successfully swapped not just directly swap to the data we also you know ignored this space at
the end we ignored the parentheses but we took the date itself put it at the beginning add a dash and
then kept the title pretty cool and difficult to do without projects like pretty much anything in the
section that I showed.
So hopefully you can see some utility in something like this whether you know this is kind of a contrived
example like a lot of the things they have to show you but still imagine this on a much larger scale
an entire collection of files or an entire directory of you know something you downloaded that has a
million not a million 100 or 200 or 300 files.
It's it can be useful to use a regular expression to do something like this to swap your data around.
So just to wrap up if you're still uncomfortable with this syntax I know it's kind of weird but this
just references groups.
We could also give these a name instead.
So I can do question mark P and giving it a name like what's this title.
And then here do the same thing.
I covered this earlier on in the section if you skipped through that this might be kind of odd to date.
And then here I can replace this.
I'll keep both lines.
Comment that one out.
But I will replace it with G date.
Dash title.
And instead of using the group numbers 1 and 2 I'm using the names that I gave them.
And does it still work.
Yes there we go.
So if you prefer that it's a little longer but it's also easier down here to refer to things based off
of what they are.
The name is rather than a random number.
Well it's not random but rather than a number.
OK.
So we covered a ton of regular expressions outside of Python as well as a lot of the module methods
we don't cover everything but we covered the most important things.
Searching matching working with groups.
And now the last couple of videos using the sub method to replace things or swap things around a lot
of useful stuff.