Welcome back to the final build function video.
It's been a bit of a marathon but hopefully somewhat interesting because they're kind of all over the
place.
They do very different things.
And the last one is called Ziph and it might be the weirdest one of all of them.
If I read the explanation it's not going to make a lot of sense and makes an iterator that aggregates
elements from each of the provided iterable is returns an iterator of tuples Were I a tuple contains
the fifth element for each argument sequences or intervals the iterator stops in the shortest input.
OK that's enough.
What it does really is imagine that we have two lists of numbers and there are the exact same length.
It's going to make a new list where it pairs up the first two numbers from the list and then the second
two numbers and the third two it zips them together.
Imagine you know an a list on the left and left list on the right.
Take the first one from each.
Put them together and then you move down and you take the second one from each and put them together.
So here's an example.
If we Zipp one to three the list and four five six the list we end up with a list of tuples like this
one come a 4 2 5 3 6 and that's if we convert it to a list by default it returns an iterator of tuples
and we have to convert it to a dictionary if we want a dictionary or list if we want a list.
So let me show an example.
I'll do number one.
And we can go one two three four five two equals six seven eight nine 10.
Like this I can spell.
And now if we zipped them together this we get this iterator of tuples and what we actually need to
do is we can turn it into a list.
So I'm going to save this to a variable and I'll just call it Z and A list of Z.
You can see it's a list of tuples 1 in 6 2 and 7.
I could also do a dict of the same thing and get one is the key and 6 is the value.
So what it's doing.
Hopefully you can see where the name Zipp comes from.
It's pairing up this and this and this this and this.
If we have an even length.
Well actually even before that we just show it does go from left to right.
So if we switch the order and we do number two common number one and now list of Z we get 6 then 1 rather
than 1 then 6.
So the order matters and the items don't have to be exactly the same length.
Although I'll show you what happens.
It's redefine that's redefined number two and have a go to 11 and 12.
Now if I read Zipp them I'll go number two first if I print it you'll see it stops as soon as the shortest
interval is exhausted as soon as we reach the end of whatever the shortest thing is.
So we don't see 11 and 12 anywhere because we were limited by numbers 1.
Another thing to mention we're not limited to you know two items at once.
I could also have something called words and I'll just put in pi and ELO well.
So it's not really a word.
Ha ha.
And how about a smile emoji.
So we have four of them.
Now if I do list of zip and well let's start with words.
And then comes one and then comes to what we get.
We get a list of tuples each containing three elements now.
And also remember this is the shortest one.
So it limits how far the others go.
We stop when we hit the end of words.
So I have a more complex example of when we would use this.
But I want to start by just showing you one more thing which is that we can also use the star operator
to unpack a list in this example and what will happen.
Here's a list of tuples.
0 1 1 2 2 3 and so on.
If we pass in Star 5 by 2 which is the name of the list it's going to take all these tuples out of the
list and pass them and individually.
So it would be the same thing as running zip with this element this tuple comma this up this tuple combo
this tuple and what it will do is then go through and pair up.
All these things here pairs is the wrong term actually.
It's going to take the first item from all five and put them in one tuple and then take the second item
from all five and put them in another tuple.
So we can use that start to unpack things and it's pretty common when we work with more complex data
structures.