Hello.
Testing Testing 1 and 2.
Very funny right.
Testing.
I do I come up with this.
OK.
So try and keep it light because testing is.
Yeah.
It's not the most exciting thing we got to learn.
Great introduction and this video we're going to talk about a statement in Python called the assert
statement.
It allows us to assert that certain expressions must be true.
And if they are not it will throw an assert error.
So it accepts an expression like let's say we had a function called the ADD keep coming back to this
basic function and it takes in two numbers.
Number one and number two we could write an assert to make sure that no one is an IT or that no one
is positive or whatever we want some expression.
And if it's false it will throw an assert error.
It returns None.
If the expression is truth the show does nothing and it raised an assertion error.
If the expression is falsie I think it a cert error earlier assertion error.
And finally we can specify a second argument an optional error message before I even dive into the code.
Before I show you any examples let me just start by saying that assert is useful and has its uses but
it is not the end all be all to writing tests at least not nowadays.
I do believe that a used to be a lot more commonly used.
It was sort of the granddaddy thing has been grandfathered in from languages like C but there's a big
shortcoming which is that we can ignore all the assert statements in an application with a single line
of code when we run the python file.
We can ignore everything in there and that could cause a lot of problems with our tests.
My opinion is that you shouldn't use assert to test all of your code.
I can point out a couple of situations where you might want to use it but I'm just going to show it
to you because it's an option at your disposal.
But there are better options now including things like unit test which will take a look at in two videos
from now.
So on to assert the syntax just looks like this.
I have a function called the add positive numbers and the whole idea is that we want to test to make
sure that the numbers that are passed in x and y are both positive first thing I'll mention is that
a search is not a function.
I've been very careful to say assert statement and this kind of I don't know if I'm missing something
it's kind of annoying to me.
Back in Python to print for example was a statement and so was raise and they've now been changed to
functions.
Print is a function we need parents assert was a statement but it still is a statement.
I'm not sure why I haven't dug into it so I don't know why.
But you don't need parens.
It's not a function it's a statement.
OK so we call a cert and then an expression.
So if this is true with nothing happens we just move on to this.
If this is false however whatever it is after the comma is a little error message that's optional.
So whether that's there or not.
If this is false it raises an assertion error which is what you see here.
Assertion error.
And if we specify a little message you can see it says both numbers must be positive.
Which is the message we specified.
OK.
And that's kind of it to assert you type assert and then an expression and then an optional error message.
OK I've made a file just pasted the code in and this file is called assertion stop P Y and as I said
if we run this right now you should see just do a print on the first one just like this.
If we call 1 and 1 we should get 2.
I call 1 negative 1.
We won't get 0.
We'll get an assertion error.
So if I run the file Python 3 assertions up why the first one works and then we get this assertion error.
Both numbers must be positive.
So you can think of assert as basically if some expression is.
Well let's just say if not some expression.
This is not going to be a valid code.
But if not some valid expression then raise which assertion error like that.
Essentially that's what it is.
Except for the fact that it can be overridden all the assertions all these search statements will not
run if we run our code in something called optimized mode.
I'll show you later in this video.
So there's that slight difference.
If I ran you know assert four equals four that's true.
We don't get anything.
But if I run four equals two it raises a certain error.
So if this is false it raises an assertion error and I add a comma and then no four should not equal
to assertion error.
For sure not equal to back here in the same file.
I will come at this out.
Let's say I'm going to define a function called Eat junk and eat junk.
Takes a single string argument called food and the whole idea is that it's really silly.
But we're going to just make sure that food is a junk food.
So it's either candy or ice cream or pizza or something like that.
And at the end we'll just return an app string that says like I'm numb.
I am eating.
And then food.
But like I said we want to verify that it is.
Let's say it's either pizza or ice cream candy or fried butter.
This is a real thing.
OK.
So to rate the assert statement it's assert food in this is our expression this is true or false.
Food is either in there or it's not in have a space.
Now I do.
And then we can provide an optional message.
But this is going to be a pretty long line.
So I think I would prefer to break this up do our strings like this EVERY go totally optional.
Food is in this list and then will say the error messages.
Food must be a junk food like that.
OK.
Then down here.
Let's just ask the user for input.
Enter a food please and then we'll just call it junk and pass and food and let's print the whole thing.
So we have the super simple function with an assert.
And then we're asking for input and then passing it in printing the result.
Now when I run it it asks me for food if I enter pizza good or good to go.
If I enter that school with kale we get a certain error.
Food must be a junk food and that's working great how it should work.
That brings us to our next slide assertions warning.
So if a python file is run with the dash o capital O not zero it stands for optimizer optimization mode
up to something mode.
What it will do is that there's a couple of other things but one of the things it does is ignore all
assertions which is not good.
So let me show that to you.
Now if I do Python 3 dash capital O the same code please enter food and if I do Cail again I get no
I'm numb numb.
I'm eating kale so totally ignored that assertion.
And if I had code where I was using search statements exclusively to test my code and it was a real
app and not just a junk food function I could be a problem to demonstrate why this could be bad.
I have a bit of a fantastical scenario down here.
I've written pseudo code but imagine that we have some real code and an application to check if there's
a search statement to check if a user is an admin and the user is an admin.
They can destroy a bunch of things they can remove posts.
They can do whatever they want.
They can delete our database that's encapsulated by destroy a bunch of stuff but I haven't a certain
here so I should be good to go right.
I'm checking his user as being passed in.
Is the is admin attribute true and if it is then good if it's not then we should raise that assertion
error right.
Well if you ran your code with Dasch capital O or somebody else did that would not run it off.
It just ignores this line so anybody could destroy a bunch of stuff.
It's a simplified example here but the underlying idea holds true no matter how large or small the code
base is.
If you depend on assert statements Well you can't depend on them because they may not run.
So that's the moral of it.
Asserts can be nice and that can be useful but you cannot count on them to run.
They're not guaranteed to run because there's a loophole deliberately designed in there.
I'm not sure why to be honest.
Because as far as I've read optimized mode it's not actually all that optimized anyways.
People complain about it all the time.
But anyway I am getting a bit off track here.
I hope we will see a better alternative.
Ok I will end on the video here.