All right you've seen the basics of inheritance.
Now let's dive a bit deeper.
So we have our Animal class in our cat class that inherits from animal.
But right now they don't really do anything.
Well cat has zero functionality has nothing different than animal.
So let's let's make things let's switch it up a bit.
Here's what I'd like to do.
So we have animal and we have a cat.
Each animal has.
I don't know a species and a name.
So Tony the Tiger or Jim the Sloth a cat also has a species which is cat.
It has a name like blue and maybe it has a breed as well.
And a favorite toy or something like that.
So let's start by setting up animal correctly.
So I'm going to get rid of this class variable or class attribute for now and let's just do a it self
and every animal has a species.
Let's go with name first and then species and then we'll just set self-taught name equals name self
that species equals species.
OK.
And otherwise we'll leave animal alone.
Now when we define cat we need to add our net of course and it needs to start with self and every cat
is going to have a name and a species of breed.
And let's just call it toy.
And I could just manually define them self-taught name equals name self but species equals species.
Self-taught breed equals breed self-taught toy equals toy.
I could do that.
And that works just fine.
When I make a new cat I just need to specify this is blue the cat and she is a cat.
She's a she Scottish Fold and a favorite toy is string OK.
And I need to comment this invalid code out and why don't we just define a nice def art EPR represent
method.
I honestly don't know how people pronounce that.
And let's just return a simple string that just has the name.
So this self-taught name is a self-taught species.
And actually we could just put this up in animal
here because every animal has a name and a species.
OK so if we do this right now and I just print blue get blue is it cat blue.
The cat is inheriting this method from animal and it's able to call it what print is calling it we're
not explicitly calling it.
But anyway let's now focus on this here.
This is duplication and this is kind of the whole point of inheritance is to avoid this sort of scenario
where you know the idea is that an animal contains all the base functionality that every animal has
and a cat will only have the additional things like breed and toy.
So what we can do is say when a new cat is created we're actually going to use the niche in animal first
and set up a name and a species and then afterwards we'll set up breed and toy in the first way we can
do that then the uncommon way you probably won't see is to manually call animal dot underscore in it
like this.
And then we actually have to pass in self referring to the cat instance.
And then after that we'll do name and species which is this name and this species so we can do this.
And if we actually test this out it should work just fine.
Hopefully there we go.
We still get blue is a cat and we can still print.
Let's do Plude that species and then let's also do blue dot breed and toy so you can see some attributes
are being defined appear in animal and some are defined down here in cat and all of them print out correctly.
So this works totally fine to do class name dot net and then pass in self as the first argument.
But Python has a little bit of a shorter way of doing it using something called super.
So if you type superbe with parentheses it's going to refer to the base class or the parent class of
whatever the current class is.
So it changes given or just depending on context.
So super instead of the class cat refers to animal and then I can call DOT net.
And the nice thing about super is I actually don't have to specify self anymore.
It will automatically be passed in so I can change this to just be name Comus species like this.
And let's verify that it works.
There we go.
So I can replace animal that init self with super which will return animal and run animal data in it
and pass in self as the first argument.
The other small change you could make here is species for a cat is always going to be a cat.
So I might just do this.
Species equals cat.
Remove that from the net and a cat.
We don't have to specify when we're making a new cat that it is a cat and now we'll just have breed
and toy just like that.
And just to show you let's define a method on here called play and it should just let's have it print
instead of turn which is kind of uncommon but it makes it easier to demo.
Let's just have a print self-taught name plays with self-taught toy.
OK.
And then I should be able to call blue dot play which is an instance method on cat and we get blue place
with string.
And that pretty much wraps up this simple example.
So just to recap we have two classes animal and Cat.
Cat inherits from animal because of this little line here.
And we don't have to involve super.
We don't have to involve the init method from the parent class.
We don't want to we still would have access to things like make sound or any other instance methods
or class variables across attributes class methods defined on animal but to reduce duplication we didn't
want to redefine self-taught name itself that species down here in the cat in it.
So instead we can just call Animal Planet and the shortcut is super and super refers to animal and it
looks for the init method an animal.
And that's pretty much it.
So that's the basics of inheritance at least the simplest form of inheritance.
I'm going to show one more example in the next video with users and moderators and we'll see how it
works with class attributes.
You can watch that if you want another example or move on and learn about multiple inheritance which
is where Super really becomes super useful.
It really does become more useful though.
So see you in a bit.