Lou.
Welcome back.
This video is a bit of a surprise.
It was unplanned.
So I didn't reference it in the last video but I think that it could be necessary.
What is the video.
Well it's a quick crash course on the aged him out and see assess for people who have never worked with
them.
If you have a working knowledge of age to mounseer says you don't even need to be able to write it just
if you understand what they are and how they work together.
Then you can move on go to the next video and we'll start scraping.
But if you don't if you've never seen H.M.S. just as you don't understand what it is then watch this
video and then Web scraping will make more sense because the whole point of scraping is that we are
getting data extracting it out of each team mouth so it helps to understand what it taught him.
It's OK.
So Timo stands for HyperText Markup Language And let's focus on that last part markup language the whole
idea is that I have some text some data some information that I'm going to send from one computer to
another.
Let's say I have a recipe or a research paper or a study.
Let's go with the recipe though.
I have my recipe for S.F. sourdough low for something like this.
That's the title.
And then I could add a little thing that says you know written by Cold Steel and then I want to have
some bullet points for ingredients we have ingredients and then I somehow want to have bullet points.
So I want the first one to be I don't know flour and I'm not going to put in measurements It's just
say flour and water and yeast and I guess for sourdough you need the starter sourdough starter.
I'm actually learning how to make sourdough right now so I'm not an expert.
It's very bizarre.
I have a colony growing in a jar in my kitchen right now.
They have to feed every day that one day I'll make sourdough from Anyway this is enough here.
So I have this information.
This is all that there is to a recipe.
It's just data points you know ingredients.
And then the actual steps.
So the whole point of HMO is to be able to send information like this but also encode additional information
about it in code structure because when I send a message it might just all end up like this.
And this is sort of an exaggeration but imagine that this is what sent on an index card.
It's not how it works Of course it's not sent written on anything it sent as ones and zeroes across
a cable.
But imagine that we have an index card and I'm sending it to someone across the world.
And I want to be able to tell them Oh this right here.
This should be bold.
This is the title and it should be 32 pixels font.
And this is the title I mean.
And then this written by Colt that should be on the next line below it and it should be italicized in
a smaller font.
And then we have ingredients and then should be bolded but not as big as a set of sourdough loaf and
then flour water yeast and sourdough starter should all be bullet points.
If I wanted to actually add that structure how could I do it.
I mean there's so many ways that I could do it I could do something like big colon and then maybe put
all of this in parentheses and then I could say italics colon.
And this is not aged him by the way but this is my version of encoding structure.
This would work and Tim L maybe could have been written this way.
But instead the syntax I was chosen uses tags like this.
You've probably seen these before.
So we have these angle brackets less than greater than brackets around a word like body and then often
there is a closing tag of these to correspond these to.
Here we go.
Or these two correspond or head and head correspond.
And there's a slash that shows the closing tag that designates the closing tag.
OK.
So there's a bunch of tag names.
We're not going to go into all of them this is again a crash course in not showing how to actually write
a bunch of Timo and I was going to show you what it looks like.
Let me get rid of this.
And let's say that I wanted to actually show you some edged him out here.
What I'm going to do when I take all this and move it up here.
What I have here this is known as h tim old boilerplate.
If I get rid of this I have an H him l file crash course that h him out.
If I type him on hit tab and sublime text clips it gives me this out of the box.
It's so commonly used every time I'll Dokument when we make we'll have this at a bare minimum.
This is just the starter and there are certain things we can fill in like a title.
So in here we'll put.
I don't know recipe let's just put bread recipe like this and save.
So I remember how I said data is sent from one computer to another and we want to encode the structure.
The other side of the equation once we actually write each Tim L your browser is going to receive the
edged him out and then render it and display it according to the rules.
So if it sees a title bread recipe as our title what it does with the title it's sort of counterintuitive
if you haven't worked with him.
It puts it at the top of the window or at the top of the tab in your browser.
It doesn't actually show on the page.
If I open this file crash course that aged him all should open my web browser and we'll see him in full
screen.
But you can see right here bread recipe is my title.
So it's done that for me automatically and that's really all that's a relationship between him and your
browser shemale contains instructions whether they're written by us when we're developing our own site
or from Facebook when we get a response from Facebook when we load the page or I click log in it sends
T-Mo and my browser displays it.
OK so now let's just run through a couple of tags and paste all this in.
I accidentally delete that.
So if I want to make this the largest text on the page I can wrap it in an each one tag.
Age stance or header.
One is the largest.
There's one down through 6 1 8 1 2 8 6.
So if I just do this all of this text is going to be on the page but only this text is going to be extra
large if I refresh.
There we go.
Make that a bit bigger.
This is extra large and this is just regular text next phone and make this italicised.
I have a couple of options.
There's the old way is using an eye.
Now you're supposed to use E-M for emphasis.
And if I do this and it go back to my browser and refresh I don't know if you can tell but this is now
a tablet I italicised it looks like I missed my last name so let's add that in.
OK.
Next thing we have ingredients so ingredients we will make an H three and then our water used to sourdough
starter.
All of those We're going to be bullet points the way we do that is by creating an unordered list.
And then inside we make a bunch of lift list items.
And what I'm doing by the way typing ally and hitting tab and it auto completes it for me.
OK.
So we have our flower in one and we have water.
And let's just do yeast for now.
So all the same data same information here I'm just adding extra stuff around it.
And then the browser is going to take care of it.
Here we go.
And look at that.
We have some structure.
So if we actually look at the page source this is all that is sent to my browser.
Right now it's coming from my own computer.
But if this was coming from a Web site we get to my back and then the browser displays it correctly.
Now there are a ton of other elements different tags that we can write in HMO besides italics and large
text and bullet points.
You can do things like add images and hyperlinks all sorts of things.
Videos many many things that I can't even think of.
There's like 100 something tags I believe.
So we're not going to go into them.
All I want you to understand is that information is inside of tags.
If I'm on this web page here and I wanted to scrape what I need to do but say I want every title this
is a blog I want all the title titles of the blog posts I could right click and click inspect and this
will show me the underlying Timo.
These are the Google Chrome developer tools and what we can see if I click this little button I can
highlight over things.
So this whole thing right here is an article and then inside that article we have an H for called section
heading where is the section heading further down there is this is the section heading inside of that
we have something called a tag says a hyperlink and then the text right there.
New Year's resolution Developer Edition.
That is the data I would want so we identify the information we want it's enraged him.
This is a data I want to grab with Python or something.
Then I have to be able to tell Python how to get here.
I need to know the you know the path that we took.
It's like Hansel and Gretel little breadcrumbs.
It's in an article.
And then there's nature for and then there's an anchor tag and then take the text in the middle of an
anchor tag.
In the next video is when will actually start doing the scraping.
But what else should I talk about with him.
So there's tags like I said information inside of them.
Most web sites are much much more complicated than this but there's nothing really extra.
It's just a lot of time.
A lot of tags all the information is contained in tags but there might be 10000 tags on like a Facebook
home page or something.
Lastly let me intro see SS very very quickly.
SS stands for cascading style sheets.
All we'll focus on is the style part of that.
So C Ss allows us to add style.
Right now this web page is hideous from the look today it's black and white.
Most web pages aren't they have fancy fonts and colors and backgrounds and animations and all sorts
of things and we can specify that with C Ss so I'm going to show you here is not necessarily best practice
but because this is a short video.
I mean just so the quickest easiest way to add style we can type a style tag.
What you're usually supposed to do is put your C S S code in a separate file and then link to it here
so that you have an HMO file and then a separate CSSA file.
But I'm going to do it in line meaning in the same file.
So here's the syntax if I want to make H-1 purple.
Who wouldn't.
Such a great color then I do this right here.
H-1 then these brackets inside of them key value pairs.
Sort of like a dictionary.
Color Purple.
I could also do something like background.
This can be so ugly.
Background yellow.
And then I need the semi-colons afterwards.
Unlike some Unlike Python for example we need this to specify the end of a line.
If I now refresh my page look at that beautiful purple text with a yellow background and it's worth
noting that applies to all h ones on the page.
There just happens to only be one next.
Let's say I want to alter the style of all lies.
So we just select ally and then our brackets.
And inside I'm not showing you you know there's so many properties just like each time all tags there's
at least 100 if not 200 properties.
We can change besides color and background but say I want all allies to be red and the colors I'm using
are just built in ugly colors.
You can make your own custom colors but I'm not going to get into that here.
So color is red and font size is going to be 20 pixels so we're making it larger.
So this applies to all allies.
I refresh my page.
I'm using command are.
Hopefully you can see they grew a little bit and they're all red.
Now that's the very basics of C S S.
The last thing I'll show you is commonly things are styled using classes and IDs.
So as I showed you here typing ally and giving styles is going to make every list item on the page the
exact same all of them are going to be read and 20 pixels.
If I wanted to single this one out and make flour I don't know blue.
Instead what I could do is give this ally an ID ID equals first or something.
It's just an arbitrary name that I've made up and it needs to go in the tag itself not inside not in
between.
And then over here I can select based off of first like this.
I use the Octa Thorpe and then the name of the ID and then same brackets.
And if I say color is blue it's going to find the item whatever it is.
It could be an ally could be an H-1 whatever has idea first is now going to be blue.
So I'll save refresh.
You can see it change to be blue.
And if I move that ID which by the way an idea is supposed to be used once on a page so it's to single
one item out.
Let's move it to the emphasis tag and refresh.
This is now blue.
OK.
So an idea is used to call one thing out.
There's also something called class and this allows us to create a grouping or a class of items that
are styled similarly and we can impact more than one thing at a time.
Unlike an ID so to say my idea is an idea except we can apply it to multiple items.
So let's say I have let me add a couple more Elyas here and I want the last two these two to have a
class.
So I'm going to just type class equals instead of ID and then give them a name and let's just call them
green.
Now I can select based off of the class which is slightly different.
We don't use the octave Thorpe.
We use a dot and then I can type a dot and the name of the class which green and then what I want to
happen to agree things let's do color teal.
Great color.
And now if I go back refresh There we go.
So we have all of these lies.
And before we restyling them all together but then I singled out this one with an idea and made it blue
and singled out these two with a class and made them teal.
So an ID is for one item classes for as many as you want.
And the reason that this matters is that in the scraping videos as we progress through this section
we can actually use these classes to identify information that we want to extract because a lot of times
Web sites will use classes and let's say we're looking at Craigslist for example they might have a tag
called a paragraph tag and there may be thousands on a page but all of the ones that have apartment
details as a class are the ones that we want.
So we don't want all paragraphs.
We only want ones with class apartment details.
Well now that we understand what a class is and we know that we use a dot to access it we see assess
when we actually see how to select things with beautiful soup which is the module I'm going to show
you in the next video.
It will help to understand classes and ideas as well as Team attacks.
So this has been very unstructured.
If you are actually curious learning aged him out there are great courses out there free and paid.
I have one.
I think I'm allowed to say that if not I hope I'm not in trouble.
But there are good courses out there.
I highly recommend you learn H.T. mounseer says.
It's a great very easy skill to pick up compared to something like Python because as you can see here
I mean you're not really typing any logic at all.
It's pure.
Do this for me and make it green make it blue.
Put this here as a bolt point and make it purple.
And that's pretty much it.
OK.
That wraps up this crash course next.
Now that we understand what Tim is just a data format to send data back and forth to encode information
about it what should be big what should be small what's italicised what's a photo and so on.
And then we shall see assess which is a way to control how things look.
We saw them together.
Now we're going to see how to actually extract information out of HCM from any web site using something
called beautiful soup.
That's next.
He made.