Already we've seen a lot of the common errors and exceptions.
Next I'm going to show you how to raise your own.
So this isn't about handling errors or preventing them.
This is about when you're writing code.
Let's say that someone else might use your code down the line.
This is how you could give them custom error messages or you don't have to customize them but how you
could throw your own type error or value error or something like that and it's super simple.
All you do is use this keyword res and then an error and then an optional argument string that can explain
something about it.
So just by calling this actually if I just copy this as is I go over to Python you can see I get that
error value error which is what I called invalid value.
I can also call it just as raise value error like that and it just gives me the new error.
I could do.
I don't know Ray's name error and blah blah blah in here doesn't matter.
I get name error.
Colon block.
Now of course you want to be helpful with these.
And you also want to throw these errors throw.
By the way is not officially a python.
That's actually the way that you cause error messages in other languages.
So I mean to say raise not throw.
Anyway we can raise errors willy nilly all over the place but we want to be deliberate in how we use
them and we want to make sure that we're using a name error when something is a name error.
Technically there's no rule that says it's up to us to raise things when we want.
So I could raise a divide by zero error whenever I wanted in some random function that has nothing to
do with division.
It's just that that isn't very friendly to anyone else who's going to use that code.
So let me share an example of a silly example but an example on the Nonetheless that shows a potential
good use of race.
OK I made a new file called raised up why.
Let's suppose that I'm creating a module here that allows people to actually colorize text.
We'll see this when we actually get to the modules section.
There are existing packages that do this so that I could print something to the command line instead
of just doing print.
Hi I instead can do something like colorize.
Hi.
And it will then printed as read or something like this.
If I passed and read and there are packages that do that and say that I was a developer of one of those
and I want to make this usable and friendly for other developers people who are going to use my module.
So we're going to start really simple.
Let's just say there's a function called colorize and all that it does is it takes.
I don't know some text and then a color and someone would call it like this.
Colorize text would be hello and then a color would be something like red.
But imagine that we all have a set list of colors which is true.
Let's say we have the colors of the rainbow.
If someone tries to pass in a color that doesn't exist or something like chicken which isn't a color
we could raise an error.
In that case we could raise a value error and if they tried to pass in something that isn't a string
in the first place for either of these we could raise a type error and say hey you are supposed to pass
strings and so let's actually do that now.
So the ideal usage should be something like this.
Hello read and we're not actually going to get the text to print out in a color that's significantly
more complicated.
Let's just say the end result of ours is printed text in color just like that so it should say printed
hello in red.
That's the end result of what we want to do is check if we should raise any errors.
So the first thing we could do.
Let's work on the type.
So if text is not a string or if color is not a string it could do this if and let's start with Hello.
Which is text.
So will say if type of text is not string just like that.
Then we can raise what kind of error do we want.
We could raise anything.
Like I said the divide by zero is fair game just doesn't make sense.
It's up to us to be responsible.
What makes sense in this case would be a type error.
And then let's just do something like text.
Must much text must be a string or instance of string or something like that to be more official sounding.
OK so now if I try and call this where text is not a string.
Well let's let's call it twice one where it is in another time where it's a number.
And if I execute it now can see we get the first time it worked.
We get printed hello and read.
Then afterward I get type error text must be instance of string.
So we have successfully raised our own error in a context that actually makes sense.
So if a developer was using this if someone was using this function colorize they would now know that
they made a mistake and it explains how they should use it.
And next up let's worry about the colors.
So let's define a list of colors that are valid and make a tuple or not using it for anything.
It just just needs to hold values.
So I'll fast forward through this.
OK let's say this is the tuple of valid colors that we can print to the command line.
Cyan yellow blue green and magenta so that they know purple and what we want to do is just check if
they're trying to call colorize with a color that is not in colors and will throw a value error.
So we'll just do if and will just check color not in colors.
Raise and then we want to be explicit about the problem so we could just raise an exception just a generic
exception like this.
Well I guess I'm not causing the problem yet.
Let's do.
Hello.
Well read will cause it actually because read is not in colors.
So let's try that now.
We just raised this generic exception that's not a very good idea.
Like I said we can do whatever we want but we want to be explicit.
So this should be a value error and we'll just say color is invalid color which is kind of clunky and
how it's worded but it's short and simple for now.
So if I call it now we get color is invalid color.
So that's basically it to raise.
You know we call race and then an error and then we can absolutely pass in some information about it.
One thing I would mention though is a good practice.
This is a matter of opinion but let's say right now we're not checking if red or if color is a string
because we are just directly checking if it's in here.
But if I did want to check is color a string and I wanted to raise a type error.
It would be better to have individual type errors if that makes sense or we have one for this copy this
type.
Color is not string to something like this.
Rather than combining them into one.
So if type of text is not string or type colors not string raise an error that just says must be end
of string because it's unclear what the culprit was what's the problem text was the problem color.
So this way we get it's clearer what's going on.
But anyway we're kind of already taking care of it down here.
And so now if I try and run this with Hello 10 we get color must be instance of string.
And if I tried to run it with list comma 10 we get color must be instance of string.
And of course we only get one of these errors at a time.
So then if we fix that make this I don't know let's go to scien.
Now we get text must be instance of string.
OK.
So hopefully this example even though it doesn't actually do anything it marks just prints you know
a little string at the end.
But imagine that this was an actual thing that we made to share with other developers.
These errors would be very helpful.
The only thing that would be more helpful is to have good documentation to help prevent developers from
trying to you know pass in red or a number.
If we had documentation that explained text must be a string color must be a string and color can only
be cyan yellow blue and so on.
That way a developer wouldn't you know have to just guess and check.
OK.
So that's raise.