And welcome back.
In this video we're going to define a custom for loop.
And like I said in the last video it's going to be a slightly dumbed down version.
Definitely not something you would use to replace an actual for loop but it's going to help us understand
how things work.
All right.
So as we already mentioned if we did something like for Nahm in one two three or four chart in hi there
what's happening behind the scenes is that this right here or here whatever the iterable is will return
an iterator because inside the for loop it is being called on this stream or this list and then that
returns the iterator which then the for loop keeps calling next on over and over and over until it has
the end.
And then once it hits the end we don't actually see the error rate.
It intercepts it using a try except block and it just stops.
So let's take a look.
Let's define a function we'll just call it def my for something like that.
And the first argument will be iterable.
So that would be the thing we're trying to loop over and let's just leave it at this for now.
The way that my form should work right now is that it just prints out every item in.
If we did Hello it should printout each character individually.
So it's just going to print to start then we'll work on adding a custom function so we could pass in
print or something else.
So my four iterable what we want to do is very first thing call it or on iterable and we'll save that
to variable just called iterator.
OK so this is like what we did in the last video editor of a string gives us a string iterator.
Then we just want to continuously call next on iterator.
So if we just did it once and I'll need to comment this out.
I just did this once.
Print next an iterator.
I call my for on hello what do we expect to get.
Let's run it.
We get the letter H.
All right.
So then if we called that one more time now we get H E and so on.
OK.
So instead of calling it twice what we actually want to do is do it forever.
While true we want to call print next iterator and if we do this of course it will work.
Intel it doesn't we see here it works.
Then we get to the end and it calls next again.
And here's that stop iteration error.
So this happens in a normal for loop except we don't see the error because it never gets to us.
So what we want to do instead is ADD and try and then except if I could spell.
OK so we're going to try to do this.
And rather than just plain except it's better to do stop iteration or stop iteration There we go like
that.
And if that's the case we'll simply break from the loop and we could start with a print like and of
iterator like that and then break from the loop.
If we try this.
Now there we go we get h l o.
End of iterator and no error.
So we're basically there just a couple of things that we could change.
The first is that we can get rid of this of course.
Next let's test it on a list.
One two three four.
OK.
Still works because we're calling it her on the list gives us a list iterator and then we can just call
next on that.
The next change will make instead of just automatically printing.
It would be more accurate or closer to a for loop.
If we could pass in.
OK I want to print each one.
Or instead of print I want to sum each one or whatever.
A function is.
And to do that let's just say we pass in a funk here.
OK.
And then rather than printing we'll just try next iterator and let's save that to a variable.
The result of it.
Let's just call it.
I ECOs next iterator or item or thing it goes next.
Iterator and then we'll just add in or else and we'll just call Phunk with thing.
OK.
So hopefully this is making some sense walk through at once if we go with let's do this again with a
string ELO Well OK so ELO Well iterable phunk is print.
Iterator is going to be the string iterator for ELO well.
So we call next on it the first time.
That gives us l and that works a thing is equal to L so the it doesn't run.
And instead we call phunk which is print and we pass an L So print L next time through we call next.
Again this time we get 0.
So then we call print oh so Prince o.
One more time L next time through.
However in the try next.
Does not work out we get this error stop iteration so we hit this and we break out and that's it.
That's the end of it.
All right.
So we could do things like instead of printing.
Well let's just test that it works by the way and it does.
We could define a function called Square for example.
And it just takes a number in and let's just have it print x times x.
And now if I call Elwha with print and then we'll do a list with one two three four five square.
It's going to call square on each one of these items.
That ELO well and then 1 4 9 16 25.
So we have successfully written our version of a for loop.
Very simple.
It's called my fortress of function.
Not quite as clean as the for loop syntax but still it's cool that we actually understand what's happening
behind the scenes.
The key things take away itor return to the iterator on an iterable object.
Iterable iterable but they return iterators and we run this line then that iterator when we call next
on it just return to the next item over and over and over until there isn't a next item.
And it raises an error which we're catching here with Except And we're just breaking out.
OK we're done.
Please leave feedback or comments on this video.
This is one that I wasn't sure if I should include or not it's not essential to doing what we already
know how to do.
In Python We already know how to use a for loop.
This is just helping us understand how it works.
But leave feedback if you like this sort of video.
If I totally lost you.
If you want to see more of this or less of this whatever you think I'd just like to read it I appreciate
it.
OK.
Next up we're actually going to talk about how we can create custom iterators so that I could pass in
like an instance of my card deck here instead of a list.
So we'll see that next.