If you remember in the last section we saw how to create lists and then we had to get the data back
out using those square brackets the list brackets above the what are they called just above the return
key.
Well we actually used the same syntax.
So if we had this instructor here this instructor dictionary all we do to get the value out we pass
in a key.
So this is where the term dictionary comes from or where I think it comes from at least in the sense
that all this information is stored like a dictionary.
So if you imagine the actual physical dictionary if you've seen one if they still exist in this world.
So let's say I don't know the definition of the word.
I don't know.
Rooster.
So I flip through the dictionary until I find rooster.
That is the key that I have and I'm looking for the corresponding value and then I read in a colloquial
term for male chicken.
I don't know if I have no idea what the actual definition is.
And but the key thing is that we have a key and then we get a value.
Same idea here but rather than definitions of words we're looking for all sorts of data.
So we pass it in just like we did with lists instead of square brackets but unlike lists where we only
have numbers you know 0 1 2 3 as the indices.
Those are the keys with a dictionary we can use any any string or a number if it's in the dictionary
to find the corresponding value.
So we pass in the key and we get a value out or if we look for something that doesn't exist in there
we get an error.
So let's try it now.
So we have cat and if I want to know cat's age I would just do cat age.
I do need the quotes because it is a string.
I just do this.
It's going to try and use a variable gauge.
I could do this though.
This is this is good to know.
Let's say I had a variable called property because the string is cute ok.
I can pass that into cat property so I could use a variable.
And I get true.
So it's it's basically property is cute we're passing in is cute and we're getting true.
And if I tried to do cat of some key that doesn't exist like breed I get a key error.
And that's pretty much it to getting data out.
You use the key so the key is always going to be the piece of information that are almost always the
piece of information you have that you were trying to retrieve the corresponding value blessing.
And there is a more forgiving way a method will learn that allows us to basically ask if a certain thing
exists in the dictionary because right now if we weren't sure and we were looking for let's say we're
looking for a property here.
City and city doesn't exist.
It throws an error.
So is there a way for us to tentatively say hey is there a city in there please give it to me.
OK.
So that concludes the intro to dictionaries.
Next we're going to learn about iterating over them looping over them.
It's a bit different than iterating over a list because there's multiple pieces of data we have to worry
about keys and values.
So we'll get to that.
But for now hopefully this video made it clear how lists and dictionaries are both data structures they
store other other types other or other types of data.
But in very different ways.
And don't forget key value pairs.
That's a big take of a key value pairs.
OK we'll go way by.