All right.
So really quick disclaimer here is somebody who teaches programming.
I like to be transparent about my thought process and how I decide on just the order to teach things.
And because there's often dilemmas or there's concepts that depend on one another and you need to teach
all of them in order to use any of them.
And one one example of that really is ranges and for loops so ranges exist on their own but they're
never I really have not seen them used outside of for loops.
So you need to know for loops to use ranges but then to know for loops traditionally use them with ranges
at least until we talk about lists and dictionaries.
So we're kind of at a crossroads where like do we teach ranges and not do anything with them until we
go for loops or do I teach for loops and and just kind of really quickly say we'll come back to ranges
don't panic.
Which is what I ended up doing.
But we're now going to talk about ranges.
So with that long preamble over with ranges as we saw in the last video or just simple ways of generating
sequences of numbers so not random numbers but sequences that are ordered in a particular way.
If you look at the documentation it says that the range type represent an immutable sequence of numbers
and is commonly used for looping a specific number of times in four loops.
So that's really the key thing.
It's so commonly used for for loops that the documentation actually says this is what it's pretty much
only used for.
So back in the slides know here's a visualization of a range just a slice of the number line but it's
not as straightforward as only generating numbers starting at 0 going up to 6.
There is a lot of different variations of how we can use it.
So the first example actually only takes one number and it represents the end point.
So this will generate a range starting at zero.
If you only provide one number it's assumes it starts at 0 and it goes up to that last number but does
not include it.
So it's Xclusive.
So it starts at zero and it goes up to six inclusive which is the range we see here
Alternatively you can pass in two numbers 1 and 8.
In this case and it will start at one including one and stop at 8 excluding 8 so it can be a bit confusing.
But just remember it never includes that last number.
So this gives us 1 to 7 which is how we printed out the numbers 1 to 7 in the last video.
Next there are two that are a bit different.
So we pass in a third number and this third number is known as the step or interval.
Basically means how many numbers to skip or what the interval is in our sequence.
So in this example we generate the numbers from 1 to 10 not including 10 but we skip to every time.
So we start at 1.
We skipped two and go to three and then five then seven to nine.
So it gives us the odd numbers from 1 to 10 not including 10 which is an odd anyways.
And then we have negative one which does the same thing except that negative is going to allow us to
move downwards.
So we go from seven to zero and negative 1.
So we're going to step down one each time.
So the end result is that we get the numbers from 7 to 1.
And it does not include 0.
Just like all the others are Xclusive.
OK.
So if I hop over to Python The first thing I'll show you.
You can just declare range or create a range like this range.
Go from zero to 9.
I hit enter and you actually don't see anything useful you don't see the numbers it's generated you
in this case we see range zero to 10 which this is a shortcut for.
But that doesn't mean that we can't see the numbers.
If we wanted to we need to type list.
So I'm going to save that to a variable.
I'll just call it our equals range 10 and then I can run a list are.
And now it shows me the numbers that have been generated.
So let's do a more complex example.
Let's do numbs equals range and we'll go from 1 to 10 skipping to every time.
And if we just look at numbers it's exactly what we've seen.
But if I run list numbers now I can see it's 1 3 5 7 and 9.
So we're skipping to get odd numbers.
So if we did a for loop over this range it would run five times and whatever the item the variable we
provided would be set equal to 1 3 5 7 and 9.
So let me show you that now I'll quit out of here and I'll make a new file called range P Y and and
here.
Let's start by just doing a four numb in.
And this is the simplest one we could do something like this.
And we can print very simple and we'll run Python 3 range.
Y And I get 0 to 9 print it up.
But as we've seen we can also do things like this.
Let's go from ten to 20.
And this time it will be even numbers because we're starting at 10 rather than one which we saw earlier.
So if I run it now I get 10 12 14 16 18 doesn't include 20 because it's Xclusive.
So all I want you to take away from this is that when we write this range with whatever we pass in it's
going to generate a sequence of numbers.
Not always you know one two three four five.
It can be odd number intervals or we could even do you know by fives.
We could go from zero to 100 by fives and there we go.
We're counted by fives I have 10 15 20 and so on.
And right now we are just printing things which I realize is trivial.
We're just putting the exact number but the focus is on ranges.
But eventually the focus will not be on printing numbers.
We'll be doing much more complex things operations with the actual numbers that we're generating.