A Welcome Back in this video we're finally going to learn how to scrape it easy.
You just you take something out of a plate and a fork you just kind of rub it back and say oh my god
that is so awful.
What have I done.
Oh yeah.
That was my joke about scraping.
OK.
For real.
I mean get this played out of here.
We're actually going to start our web scraping in this video and we're going to use something called
beautiful soup.
It's a beautiful soup is a library package.
We need to download.
So that's the very first thing we're going to do.
And it kind of drives me insane.
But the name that we actually download is called B-S for now beautiful soup.
But for in our command line over here in Python.
Dash m Pip.
Install the S for and ired have it installed requirement already satisfied.
It should take a moment for you.
You mean you have your internet running and then you get the package.
Ok now that we have beautiful soob installed Let's talk about what it is and what it isn't.
It allows us to navigate through and extract data from him using Python.
But and this is a big big but it does not download H-2 him for us.
We have to manually make the request to get the data.
Let's say we're scraping I am D-B not saying it's a good idea to do that.
But if we were and I was I don't know scraping every single web page I could find spacing out the request
by three seconds.
I would use the request module to send a get request to one page get the data back and then I take that
each time it comes back I send it over to beautiful soup and I extract whatever information I want.
Maybe I'm trying to find links that I can crawl across and then send a further request to every link
we get back from whoever Danny DeVito web page and then every link we get back from Danny to Vito's
page.
We're then going to further scrape and keep going.
Anyway my point is that beautiful soup does not download the Timo.
So in this video we're just going to begin with Mocket HMO in a variable.
I've created a variable called edged him out equals and then I have a multi-line string where I've just
put h tim out inside of there their very basic.
It just says you know title first Tim L page.
We have a div with an ID and H-3 what with a data attribute a paragraph ordered list or some basic H.T.
mail stuff.
If you'd like to follow along you can download the file and type as I type.
So we're going to suppose that we got this back from making a request rather than it being in a variable
from the very beginning.
In the next video though I'll actually talk about making the request and then giving that data to beautiful
soup.
So where do we begin.
Well we have to start by initialising.
Beautiful soup.
After we import it we called this line here to actually parse the page Timo.
Remember HTL comes back as a giant string just like what we have here.
This is how it comes back from wherever we make a request.
It comes back as a string.
It's not an object it's not a class or anything not a dictionary.
So we pass that string in two beautiful soup as well as this string.
H tim Elda parser.
You have to do this because beautiful soup also supports parsing Zemo which is another markup language.
We want the aged him L-1 so we pass that in as well.
But that's always the same for us.
And then that we'll go and parse all of the HTML.
Assuming that it is correct each time there's no errors in it there's no missing brackets or tags or
something.
It goes through and it's actually quite complex.
The logic that has to happen and if we save the result to a variable we can then use that parsed h tim
L and navigate through it.
So there are several ways to navigate.
We can try and use a tag name so I could parse all of it and then say hey beautiful soup.
Give me all of the paragraph tags give me all of the H-1 tags give me all the anchor tags that sort
of thing.
They can use a method called Find which will return one matching tag or find all that will return a
list of matching tags so find one paragraph versus find all paragraphs.
And we can also navigate using CSSA selectors.
If you haven't seen or worked with C S S Don't worry.
But if you have we can use just as style selectors you can use a method called select but let's just
start with the basic tag name selectors.
So first things first I need to import B-S for in all we want from it.
I'm actually going to switch this up from B-S for imports.
Beautiful can spelt be a beautiful soup like that.
OK.
And then we'll just make a variable that's just called Soup equals beautiful soup and we passed in this
string of H Tim L that is called H Timo that.
And then we need to pass an h l dot parser and what will happen now is that soup if we just do pre-print
soup and then we also do a print type of soup.
I run it.
The representation that is printed to us looks just like the aged string.
However that class is not string.
It is a beautiful soup.
It's an instance of beautiful soup and now has a bunch of methods that we can use to parse it even though
it doesn't look like it has when it printed out.
I promise you it has parsed it so we can do things now like let's do print soop dot and then we can
do dot body.
So that would be this right here.
And if I run it like what we get.
This is the body.
OK so that's one thing we can also do things like print souped up body dot div.
There are two divs in the body.
Notice what happens.
I run it and we only get the first div So just be aware that this was the first div it had the three
in the paragraph in it.
We didn't get this bottom div So we'll talk about find all in just a moment.
We can also do this.
Print soop find and then passing a string div and this gives us the same thing.
Also notice when it's printed out it looks like it's a string but none of this is actually strings.
If we look at what this actually is souped up find div and what this returns.
Call it D and then the print type of d i run it.
It's a beautiful suit for element tag instance.
It's not a string it is its own instance of its own object.
So when we parse h him it's taking beautiful soup takes that giant string and it goes through and it
turns.
Each individual tag into its own object and then it puts them all together into the main.
What we have here soup this main variable whatever is returned from here contains all of the instances
of elements.
OK so we can do fine div but we can also do find all div and if I do that I'm only printing that's just
print D now and run it.
We now get a list and the first item in there is the first object that contains the div and then our
second object div.
OK so that's finding based off of a tag name we can do find or find all we can change this to be an
ally.
We do find all we get all allies returned in the list.
If I do find instead a find all we only get the first one as you can see here.
Let's make some space.
The next thing I'll talk about is selecting using attributes for example an ID or a class.
So here we have an idea on this div called first.
Now if I wanted to select using that I can do souped up find and then I'd just say ID equals first.
And this is going to find me whatever the element that has Id set to first and retrieve it and never
get that div and if I move this to the second lie and save now I get that second lie
Likewise I can select based off of a class an idea supposed to only be used once.
So you wouldn't use find all you shouldn't have to but we would use find all on a class.
So we have class equals special.
OK.
Oh I need two essays and if I run that you'll see that there's a problem.
It's like saying hey wait a minute that's a special word in Python so this won't work if I try it.
It doesn't thinks I'm declaring a class instead.
If to do class underscore.
So that's just something you have to remember about when you're working with beautiful soup class underscore.
And now we get those two items class equal special class equal special.
We can also select based off of attributes like this thing has a data attribute or data examples set
to Yes.
And if I wanted to do that instead let just duplicate this comment that one out of the argument name
is adder's like this and then pass in a dictionary and I'm looking for where data for example is and
I can tell.
Colon Yes.
So give me all.
Every item every element that has the data example attribute set to Yes.
So if I give that two things let's do this.
They div at the bottom it says by this and I right we get the age 3 and the div..
So this is how we can select based off of attributes whether it's you know a source for an image and
a track for an anchor tag.
We can also select based off of class and ideas we saw and tag them.