Hey I'll come back.
So one question I get a lot through all my courses has to do with style whether it's C S S or javascript
or Python.
People want to know how should I be styling my code.
You know what where should I have extra whitespace.
Do I need this whitespace and they break this up into two lines.
How should I named my variables.
We've already talked about some elements of style but there's a lot more to discuss.
Most languages out there have at least one popular style guide.
Python is a bit different in that there's really just one exact standard that everybody tries to follow.
If you are going to be sharing your code going to be putting it up online somewhere making a open source
repository then you should follow the PEP 8 style guide so I've included the link if you want to take
a look.
It's quite long.
There's a lot to talk about.
There's things like code out you know how much you should indent four spaces per indention level.
There's things like what else how long your string should be or your comments and when you should break
them as separate lines.
How many blank lines you should include.
So there are rules about you know you should.
After you defined you haven't talked about functions but want you to find a function.
You should have to find surrounding it at the top or import statements.
How this should work.
Basically my point is there is a lot and I am not going to ask you to learn all of this.
Frankly I can't remember half of this because I use a tool to help me.
I write my code with an eye for trying to make it look nice and not have these giant lines.
And that's sort of a side effect of me being onscreen and having to show the code I can't have something
that looks like a crazy tangled mess.
I just try and make it look ok.
But what I actually do before I upload code.
Let's say I have some massive crazy thing like this which is going to contain a lot of stuff we haven't
seen.
I don't go through this line by line and format it manually.
I use a tool I actually introduce this later in the course but I'm adding this video in because I know
a lot of people will be antsy to learn about this.
The video is in the modules section.
It's on a tool called auto PEP 8 and what I can do is I can take a file like this that has valid Python
code.
This works just fine.
It is ugly and I run this auto PEP 8 and then I do dash dash in place and then a name of the file and
that file is called ugly code.
Why and if I run that and go back up re reload and you can see that this is what it looks like now.
The exact same code has been formatted really nicely for me.
So going forward in my videos you're not going to see me spending a lot of time.
I mean just getting this indentation right manually takes forever and most developers I know who use
Python use auto PEP 8 to take care of it.
So my note to you is don't freak out about style at this point.
Make sure you're just being syntactically correct that your code works.
Then you can use a tool like auto PEP 8 and if you want you could skip ahead and learn how to install
it.
But I think it's probably better just to wait until you get to that section naturally because by then
we'll have covered a lot of this.
You know a lot of the craziness that you see here and it will make sense.
It will make more sense why you would use a tool like auto PEP 8.
You'll know how to install external packages by then and there's a whole bunch of other things you need
to discuss before then anyway as you go through the course and introduce new topics like functions or
classes or generators or decorators.
There's a lot of style that is tied to them where it won't break the functionality things will work
just fine but if you want to be up to date you want to follow the best possible style guide you can
come to PEP 8 and you can read it yourself.
If you have questions or by then will have installed auto PEP 8 and we can just use that.
All right.
I think that's all I wanted to say.
PEP 8 is a style guide that the Python community follows pretty rigidly but most people use a tool like
auto PEP 8 to take care of it for them.
You should just know that it exists and don't panic about style at this point.
Keep it in the back of your mind.
Once you start writing longer code and learn more topics in Python then you can start to worry about
it.