Already.
So we're talking to decorator's still.
Here's another example that's going to present a problem to us.
So let's just dive into the code.
I have it right here.
What we have is a simple decorated function.
It's called ADD and the decorator is called log function data all that it does is it prints things like
you're about to call and then the functions name.
And then here's the documentation in it call it printed docstring which is defined down here and everything
looks good.
If I call this if we do add 10 comma 30 printed.
Oh and by the way the wrapper finally calls a function at the end.
It basically logs what we're about to do.
The documentation for the function that's about to be called.
And then it calls the function.
OK.
So you'd expect to see something like you're about to call and it's unable to function.
Here's the documentation.
Add two numbers together and then finally Prince 40 I can do my math correctly.
Let's see if that's what we get.
And it is indeed we get you're about to call.
And here's the documentation.
Add two numbers together and 40.
That's great.
But the problem that I'm presenting has to do with ADH itself.
The wrapper that is returned which is now being called add if I try and print ad dot let's do Doc to
stars or let's do both why not do name as well.
All right so if I try and refer to this after the fact I'm trying to debug something maybe this is a
library I've written that somebody else is using and they're trying to understand something and they
want to get the doctoring or even tried to do help on add just like we did with term color when we downloaded
it.
We wanted to immediately run help on term color to see how it worked well with the way our decorator
set up.
This is what we get right now.
Hope is giving us the wrapper function help.
It's not giving us the ADD help that we set up with the ad docstring.
So instead docstring as I am wrapper function and name is wrapper.
So it's not giving us this it's like giving us this name this docstring it is inside when we print it
out.
But externally it's not.
So I hope you can see that distinction when I'm referring to add by name here.
Doc dot name.
Help add all that stuff it's not working.
It's referring to wrapper and we're getting this docstring.
So this could be problematic especially if other people are working with our code.
Like I said if we created a library that has decorator's you don't want this to happen.
But fortunately for us Python to the rescue there's a simple way of preserving metadata.
There's a module called phunk tools and from it there is something called wraps and wraps.
It is simply a function that we use as a wrapper function around our wrapper function and it makes sure
that all the attributes in the function that were decorated aren't lost by decorator.
So by importing wraps from phunk tools and then calling it right here.
So we're decorating the wrapper.
It ensures that the function that being passed in the function that's being decorated.
In our case add it's metadata won't be lost.
So up here we can just do from phunk tools import wraps and then right here we add that line wraps and
then it needs to match whatever we're calling the function that's being passed in.
But this is a very standard thing to do.
It's just friendly.
Good developer behavior to do this.
If you are releasing code to the public especially so let's test this now.
Now when I print to add doc or add name it shouldn't reflect I am wrapper function and wrapper it should
reflect adds two numbers together and add let's test it.
Indentation airier killin me this.
Where are you.
How dare I use a tab and so spaces there.
Also phunk tools with the single T.
Now if we run it.
Well first we're getting the correct help I forgot we had that in there giving us help for ADD and we
get the correct docstring and the correct name now.
All right.
So just a quick video here.
I just wanted to show you one of the problems that arises with decorator's and decorated functions not
maintaining their metadata.
Python gives this to us for free gives us wraps because this is a common problem when we write our own
wrapper functions.
Just put this at wraps call it with whatever the function that you're trying to decorate is and it will
preserve that function metadata already moving on.