All right.
Welcome back.
So this video is all about finding your path not finding your path in life.
You know I'm not going to tell you to express yourself.
Don't be afraid to try new things.
Pay attention to your dreams that sort of thing.
No I mean find your path through the course.
There are different places that you could start depending on your skill level and the computer that
you're working with.
So I made a flowchart.
I spent way too long on it and it looks just awful.
So I'm really sorry about that.
I'm not a designer as you probably noticed looking at these slides but here goes nothing.
Where should you start.
The first question is.
Mac or PC.
Mac slash any Linux machine or Unix machine is the same.
So really it's just.
Do you have a PC.
If you do then the first question is are you comfortable using power show if you don't know what that
is then you're going to start with the Windows PC Power Shell section.
If you do you can start by installing Python on a PC.
Likewise on the Mac section.
Are you comfortable using the Mac terminal if you are go ahead to installing Python on a Mac if you're
not focused on the Mac command line section.
So we use the command line throughout this course other Python courses find ways around it where they
have to use some some visual tools or Iguchi to get things done which works it's just not how most developers
do things.
So I preferred to be a little bit more realistic kind of teach the things that I would teach my students
in person.
But the only downside is that it's a little bit longer to get started if you're not comfortable with
the terminal.
But it's only I don't know 13 minutes 14 minutes of video so it's not too bad.
So this is the game plan.
Wherever you start there are two PC centric sections into Mac centric sections and then everything meets
up for all the Python content.
So if you have a PC and you don't know anything about power shell and the command line you start here.
If you have a PC and you are comfortable with the command line then you start here and you install Python.
Either way this is a short section and you start installing Python very quickly.
This is only three videos in this section and then we dive into Python syntax.
Same thing on a Mac.
Start using the command line and going through that section.
If you're not familiar with it if you are just start with installing a very short section three videos
onto Python and then from here on out it's all the same.
On top of that if you've already been programming in other languages before then some of this content
early on is going to be very slow for you because I teach things like variables and data type strings
and numbers operators comments which are very basic concepts in any language.
So if you've experienced those concepts with other languages then you may want to breeze through some
of this content.
You absolutely do not need to sit through every second video.
And in fact the exercises can serve as a way for you to check your own understanding.
You can skip ahead try an exercise.
And if you don't get it then you know that you need to go back and watch some videos leading up to it.
So there's a couple of options as you can see on the ugly flowchart.
Figure out where you should start.
I know the terminals not the most exciting thing and it can be intimidating but there's only two or
three commands that I'm going to show you.
And we need to use them there's a real reason we use them throughout the course we use a terminal to
actually execute Python scripts.
So we need to know how to do that.
All right.
One more video.