A Welcome Back in this video we're talking about something called dark tests.
So if you remember the docstring that we talked about a couple of times in this course you can add documentation
to your functions to your modules using those triple double quotes.
We can actually write test code in there as well.
And Python has a way of automatically running parsing and running those tests for us.
But the catch is that we have to use a pretty out there syntax.
In my opinion it is charming in a way.
I like writing tests but we'll talk.
We'll talk about the limitations as well.
I'm not presenting this to you as the best way of testing everything but it is good to know about.
So drug tests allowed to write tests or functions inside the docstring.
But the catch that I mentioned is that we have to write our code in a very very particular way so that
it looks like we're writing in a REPL.
What do I mean by that.
Well here's an example.
So we have these triple double quotes inside of here's an add function triple double quotes and then
this is the part I'm talking about.
This right here will turn into a test.
So by me writing this the greater and greater then greater then the prompt and then running add one
comment to I'm basically saying OK we should expect to add one comment to two results in three but we
have to follow this very particular syntax I expect.
Add eight comma high two results in a type error.
And it has to look like this.
It has to match what you would see in the REPL.
What's cool about dog tests is that if you create a module or library or package someone uses you write
a docstring automatically.
I mean you should have a docstring in there for anything that someone is going to use you put in this
code as a demonstration for how it should work to a user.
This is a human readable thing that I can look at.
Like when we saw the colorize example or any of the things we've worked with there's a docstring in
there that has a usage example that is both good for developers to look at but also Python can run it
to make sure that the code still works out as opposed to something might have changed.
And if you just write your test this way then it works as both documentation and as tests for we talk
about limitations.
Let's look at a good old example.
Ok here I have a similar set of tests.
It's shorter where I have a function called the ADD A and B and then we have our good old docstring
there.
Double triple quotes no triple double quotes.
And I've written two tests.
These are the syntax right.
So we use this little prompts.
And then I say when you run Add come three it should return five.
A new run at 100 for 200 You should get 300.
But right now I'm returning a times b.
So that's incorrect.
It's not going to work.
And if I run it I don't even have to actually execute add or anything.
There's a special command I can ask Python to run.
That will grab it will parse the doc strings and find all the tests run and then run them.
It looks like this python 3 dash em doc test dash V and then the name of the file.
Mine is called Doc.
Test demo up why.
So those two tests that I wrote are not going to work.
And I get this nice little verbose output.
So it starts off and says trying ad to come three expecting five.
And then it freaks out because it got six and it moves on to the next one trying ad 100 200 expecting
300.
And it tells me failed example expected 300 got 20000.
One item had failures two of two in duck test demo and zero past two failed total tests failed two failures.
All right.
So it's pretty cool in my opinion that it's able to do that.
It's built in you know parses all the code from here figures out what's a test.
It knows that.
OK the code that comes after this we need to actually run.
And then we should expect it to equal this.
If not it's counted as a failed test and we'll print it out to the user.
So if we just fix this for the plus side and now go back and run it call trying it expected 5 and I
was OK trying expected 300 OK to pass two past and zero failed.
All tests passed.
Cool.
Now let's add another test new function and another test.
Now let's go about it.
The TDD way.
So we're going to go with red green Reflektor.
Let's write a function called double and we'll start off with just double takes in an argument called
values.
And for now we'll just assume that at least.
But before we do anything we're going to practice TDD and we're going to write our tests.
So we need that docstring.
And in here just read the docstring double the values in a list.
That's our goal.
And then we write our first test and we do this one to three greater than signs double.
When we call it on I call it with 1 2 3 4.
That's one test we get right.
And what should we get back.
We should expect a list with 2 4 6 and 8 and then we can write another test case test case if we called
double with an empty list which we expect to get back an empty list and another one with a string this
time.
So if we call double and then we pass in let's say the list a b c we should expect this list the string
the string B-B the string CC.
And finally we're going to write one where we try something that shouldn't work.
If I called double with a list inside of it that I don't know I had that say true and then none.
We can't double those.
And if we wanted to test to make sure that we get an error this is the worst part.
I'm going to fast forward.
You see what I have to type look at that.
This is what I have to write.
I have to mimic exactly what we would see in the Python REPL.
So that is kind of a pain to write but let's practice TDD so I write my test and make sure we're in
the red.
Let's run the code.
Here we go and we get two pass and four failed.
Oh because it's running the first two I could comment this out.
It's running these.
So let's try one more time.
We're getting zero pass for fails.
We're completely in the red.
All right.
So now it's our job to make them pass red and then green.
So to make some of these passed we could get away with something really small like returning an empty
list that's going to make this work.
So let's run it now.
All right three of four one past three failed.
Ok now we go back and we continue to make other tests pass.
So let's just fix this and I'll just do two times.
Let's call it element for element in most put a missing list in values.
There you go.
That's coming in.
So we could do this also without a list comprehension.
We could use map.
You can do it manually by looping through and multiplying and appending to a list.
Up to you.
Now let's see if it works.
Moment of Truth here.
Three passed and one failed.
OK.
The one that's failing.
See here's the one that failed.
I think it is just the spaces in there.
That problem two four six eight let's see is that really what the problem was let's try again.
Yeah.
So finicky.
So that's my next point about Doc tests.
I think it's cool but I've spent a lot of time already in this video finagling the syntax.
This is a very specific syntax and it's unlike anything you type in Python otherwise and you have to
be very very careful.
OK.
Now I have a couple of examples to show what bothers me some of the problems you might run into here
is a perfectly good looking duck test in my opinion very simple function called Say hi that just returned
the string high and I just test that when I call say hi.
If you give me this string high.
But alas when I run it.
But if we get failed expected high.
And it got single string high.
Not double string.
So Duck tests expects all strings to have single quotes not double quotes.
So if you're comparing.
We have to put single quotes there because it's automatically going to try and compare two single quotes.
So frustrating.
OK.
So I mean I'll leave that one is a failure just so you can see as an example that it doesn't work.
I've added another one.
This one gets me all the time.
Looks perfectly good.
Just a function called True that and all it does is return true.
In our case it's not really the significant significant point when we called true that we expect true.
And that's what you should get.
But if we look when I run it it fails expected true Got true.
How do we know the difference and what's actually happening.
Well there's a little white space right there trailing whitespace and that's throwing everything off.
So we have to delete that and now I try and run it.
And now passes as you can see here trying to do that expected true.
OK.
And one last example.
This is called Make dict.
And when we call it with a list of two items say a and b I expected a misspelled true I expected to
return a verdict where both items are just set to true in a dictionary.
So the key is a and b are both the keys and they're true.
So I have that down here.
True for key in keys.
And if I run it it should work but nope it doesn't.
You can see here the problem is expected B to be first and then A and he got a first and then B which
normally is not a problem.
These are dictionaries that isn't posed to be an order that matters but in tests the order of keys and
a dictionary does matter.
So yeah it's a tenth of a minefield when you're writing these tests you get to be really careful.
You really have to mind your whitespace and your quotation marks.
It kind of drives me insane.
The issues it's index's is bizarre to begin with the syntax is weird.
It also clutters up our function so you can see things get really long for a single a single line function
that just returns a plus b.
I mean you probably wouldn't need to write test for that anyways but in our case it's like 10 times
as long.
And on top of all that Doc tests actually like a lot of the important features capabilities of things
like unit test which we'll see in the next video.
For example if we're working with it we're testing I don't know 10 functions and they all use the same
data and we want to test them with one object.
Want to run code before every test or after every test we would have to duplicate that and every docstring
using something like unit test.
We are able to say run this code before every test run this code after every test and it reduces duplication
and thusly the tests are just kind of brittle finicky grouchy.
What ever you want to call them they are not my first choice for adding tests plus if I am writing documentation
for something I want it to be thorough then I will write doc tests.
But I still don't really enjoy it.
In the next video however I'm going to show you how to write unit tests.