Hey welcome back.
So this video is a solution slash code along to the card and deck exercise.
I'm going to start off by implementing the card class.
It's nice and simple and short and I've actually copied the three kind of bullet points for the assignment
that have to do with the card class.
So let's start there.
I'm in a file I'm calling deck of cards.
Save it and let's define our class class card capital C colon and then we'll do what we need.
Let's see each instance of cards Scheppers suit and each should have a value.
So let's define Dondre in that.
And that's always the first thing it's going to be self.
And then we can do suit or value first.
It really doesn't matter.
Let's do value and then shoot.
And the only reason I made that decision is because most of the time when we referred to a card as human
beings we refer to the value and then the suit the ten of hearts the ace of spades doesn't matter otherwise.
OK.
So we have that and we are going to do is that self-taught value to be value self that suit equals suit
just like that.
And we have enough now where we can actually create a card so we can do something like card and then
we had pass in the value to be let's go with Ace and then hearts.
Perfect.
And then we should be able to print C and then print C dot suit and let's just start there.
So let's execute this.
And there we go we have this main card object this ID and then suit is hearts.
So now all we have is this Last thing here to define a method for us.
I never know how to say this to be honest.
This is always a challenge for making courses things that I just never speak out loud in my developer
life representation represent whatever it is.
R E P R So let's define that and it should display the card value and suit like Ace of Clubs J.
Jack of diamonds etc..
All right.
So that is our E.P. our self.
And let's just return an F string.
I should mention that if you are trying to get the test to pass that I provided for this exercise as
of now basically January 1st 2018 Tomi's coding challenges don't support Python 3.6 which is where the
strings are introduced.
So you actually need to use dot format if you don't recall how you used up format.
You can find it in one of the very very early videos but it basically looks like if we're going to do.
Ace of hearts we put these two planks in here and then we do a duck format and then we specify self
dot what we want first value and then self dot suit.
So this so go there.
This will go there.
I prefer the string but let's just make sure this works.
So now when I print see if we get a.
Of hearts.
Perfect.
Let's do one or two more.
Let's see to see three and let's do a ten of diamonds.
Make that capital just be consistent.
And then this of spades.
And that should be king.
All right.
Now if you print all those great it's working.
And that's actually the it to the card class.
I will just duplicate this comment out the version with the format I prefer using an F string like this
f up there of.
And then a closing quote should be good.
I want to mess up extra print at the end.
Double check still works OK.
Perfect.
So we're done with the card class.