OK we've seen how to make the most basic request but all we're getting back is this giant block of H.
Tim Alv it is really impossible for us to make sense of let alone do anything useful with.
So in this video I'm going to show you how we can ask a Web site that supports this at least not every
web site does but the Web sites that support this.
We want to be able to ask them instead of sending me to mail.
Can you please send me a plain text or can you please send me Jason and we'll talk more about what Jason
is again.
But these formats that are more friendly for Python and the way we do that with the requests module
is we can specify headers like this.
So we have a request get this part the same.
The first argument is that you are all that then we can pass in a keyword argument headers and it can
be a dictionary of key value pairs so Hetter one is not going to be what we would what we'd put there.
But this is where we would put something like please give me Jason please give me a plain text and then
we specify that it's with the header excepts meaning be the value of that type of data we will accept
back.
But before we make a request Let me show you the Web site and we'll request it's called I Can Has dad
joke dot com if you haven't heard of dad jokes or just really cheesy P.G. jokes like what do you call
a group of killer whales playing instruments in an orchestra or two peanuts were walking down the street.
One was assaulted.
Yeah very silly.
What do I mean stop here.
We're going to send a request here.
And the first thing the first time we send a request will be to get an h him l response.
What we see here the next time though we'll see how to send it so we can get plain text or Jason back.
So I'm going to make a new file and I'll just call it headers.
Why.
And I'm going to do the same thing.
Import requests.
And then I'm going to paste the you are well into a string.
Notice that the u r l.
H t t s not going to go into the difference really here but it just means HGP secure.
You've probably come across it before.
If we don't have that asthore we can't actually request that Web site.
So we need that and I'm going to just make a variable called your Allegan then I'll have my response
equals requests dot Ged's you are.
So by default it's going to give me Chimo.
I'm not sending any header that says otherwise.
And let's just do a print response text.
Ok let's see how it goes.
All right.
So I get this big thing of HMO.
All these are H.T. mailbags little javascript.
You can see buried in here somewhere is the actual joke.
I don't know where exactly here's the button that says submit new joke.
Here's a little information bio.
Anyway somewhere on here.
Oh here we go.
What do you do on a remote island.
Try and find the TV the TV island it belongs to.
Oh man that's terrible remote.
Wow.
So as you can see the information we might want if we were trying to build a little app that just posts
it just prints out a new dad joke every five minutes or something into the terminal.
This is all we want.
All this extra stuff is for humans to look at in a browser.
So what we can do is specify the format that we want our data and to do that we need to pass in a header
so comma and we'll do headers.
Key word.
Equals.
And it's a dictionary because we could pass in multiple headers but all that we want is accept just
like that and then the corresponding value is text slash plain.
So this is one other data type.
There's one which is text slash h tim L which is what we already do.
And you'll see if I do the same thing we get the same response.
But if I do text slash plain.
This request tells the server hey I'm looking for this.
You are right.
But can you give me the plain text version.
And let's see what that looks like.
What do you look at that.
Why are fish easy to weigh.
Because they have their own scales.
We're getting this just the joke.
That's it.
Now not every It should be really clear.
Most web sites aren't set up to just give you plain text like this.
This is a particular one I picked out because they have an API and they make it clear that you can use
it for these purposes.
But if I just ask Google copy this you are over for plain text.
Let's see what happens.
I still get the exact same thing.
So it's not set up to handle that.
So I just want to be clear about that.
Now plaintext is good but there's another format that's better for what we want which is called Jason.
Jason stands for javascript object notation.
Don't let that worry you.
You do not need to know javascript.
You don't need to know any javascript just know the reason it's called that is because historically
when it when it was created it was used to make requests with javascript and get data back to javascript
so that it could be quickly so it could be used quickly.
But the more important idea is that it's a data format that Python can very quickly turn into valid
Python code.
So if we look at whether this is right here this is actually a string that's coming back.
But if I change this to application slash J song rather than text slash him out or text slash plain
application slash Jaison this is just saying please send me the Jasen version of this site.
This is just standard.
It's always applications less Jason and if I try running this now I'm not just going to print a response
that text.
I'll also print response Jason which is a method and this will actually take whatever the response is
take the Jaison and turn it into Python so let's clear make some room and then run this OK.
So when I ask for a song this is what I get back.
This is Jason right here and this down here is Python and they might look.
I mean they look very very similar if we look at this.
Jason is going to paste it in here at the key value pairs.
This looks just like a python dictionary.
But technically if we do type of response from text that's all that I print
you'll see it's a string.
So I can't use respond to that text.
It's equivalent to this big string containing all of our data all of this stuff.
So I can't ask for you know give me the joke in that string because it's a string inside a dictionary.
So instead if you use response that Jason and save that to a variable Let's start by just doing data
because response does Jason data is going to actually be a python dictionary so I can do type of data
for example and print that
and it's a dict dictionary.
So that means if I just print data
I actually have access to these properties now like joke.
So now I can do things like print data joke because it's been turned into a dictionary.
So to make that clear when we send a Jason request it comes back in this format that looks very similar
to Python.
It's called javascript object notation but it comes back as one giant string.
So it's all enclosed in quotes and by running dot Jason up here it just tells Python basically turn
that into actual Python so I can use it.
And that's what it does.
So then I can do things like data brackets joke.
And now if I print that you'll see printing the quote or the joke.
Doctor if broken my arm in several places.
Doctor.
Well don't go to those places.
Yeah.
People who don't eat gluten are really going against the grain.
Great dad jokes.
OK.
So it's a lot to take in.
But what we saw in this just this single little change you made changing the headers from each team
how to Jaison.
We also saw plain text along the way and plain text actually in this example was simpler because it
only sent us a joke and that's all we want.
But imagine that we're getting a lot of data news data where there's 20 different news stories.
If that all came back as plain text it would be very difficult to use.
It would all all the data would be you know headline one you know terrorist something and then maybe
like Florida man did something else.
It would all just be one thing in plain text.
But if we have Jason instead we might get something that looks like this story one call and I don't
know.
Terrorist attack and then story two.
So it makes it easier for us to use it in Python once we convert this into valid Python.
So there's this is just a tough thing to teach.
If you don't have any experience with web so we can just just leave this in any request we make to an
API if it supports Jason we want Jason.
That's just a rule.
And then we'll turn the response into Python code with the response that Jay song it goes from a string
to an actual Python dictionary.
And then we can do things with it like print out the joke.
I could also do print data.
We do it on a separate line actually do an F string and just say status equal to data status.
We have to pay attention to quotes double single quotes that sort of thing.
Run this now.
You can see what did the judge say to the dentist did you swear to pull the tooth.
The whole truth and nothing but the truth status is 200.
OK.
So that was a lot but we're making a request.
We're asking for Jason.
Jason comes back.
Turn it into Python and then we can manipulate it.
And that is a pattern we will follow basically from here on out.
We don't want him out.
We want Jason.
It is made so API is nowadays are almost always Jason and they're made for other computers or code to
work with.
So that's what we've done here.
All we're doing is printing a joke.
But now what we could do is ask for a new joke every five seconds or in a continuous loop which is not
a good idea because it'll probably get blocked from the API.
So you definitely want to wait a couple of seconds I'll show you how to do that later.
So you don't just overload the server anyway.
Important stuff but kind of heavy.
I hope I didn't scare you away because we can start to do some really fun things with this basic boiler
plate.
Make a get request ask for Jason do something with it.
OK.
We'll continue exploring in the next video.