Welcome back.
So the last little bit of this crash course on sequel is going to do with selecting data out.
We've already seen how to select star select everything in a table.
Now I'm going to show you how to select certain parts do certain queries that are a little more specific.
Again this is there's a lot that we could talk about.
A short video.
This is really just so that we can then learn how to select using Python.
Coming up in just a video or two.
All right.
So back to our database here.
There we go.
We've seen how to do this.
So let's start from dogs.
What that star is saying is select all columns.
It's not saying select all dogs.
It's saying select all colors.
So if I wanted I could just say select name from dogs or select name Karma age from dogs.
And that's just specifying which pieces of the dogs.
But it's still giving me all of the dogs what I can of course narrow things down filter things a bit
more.
But before I do that I'm actually going to insert a few more.
OK.
So here are four more dogs that I'm going to insert just so we have a little bit more of data to work
with.
So all the way back over here I'm just going to read that file again and notice I commented out everything
else.
So it's only inserting new dogs.
So now if I do select star from dogs we have a little larger data set still not a ton.
So we've seen how to select individual columns but now let's filter it down so that we could select
only certain dogs.
Let's say we only want the dog whose name is piggy.
For some reason.
Well I would say select star from dogs where name and then I would say is piggy is capitalized isn't
it.
And I need my semi-colon.
Forgot about that.
So I had to hit it on a second line down here and we get piggy or let's select all dogs where their
breed is it what do we have to have a husky.
And now we get our two huskies and at the same time I could narrow it down and say only give me the
names of those dogs.
Champ and river.
But of course there's a lot more we can do.
If you go to the documentation for Sequel light you can click on select and you get these lovely charts.
They're actually pretty cool.
They show you the way the language is processed the syntax how it breaks down.
So there's a lot of different things that we can do but what we're focusing on is this little bit called
expression.
So we're saying select something from dogs where expression so where name is Charlie but we can also
say where age is less than 10 or something like that.
If you scroll down somewhere where is that expression right here and you click this is kind of hidden.
This shows us all of the options for those expressions there's a ton and it's very calm.
It can get complex.
What we're going to focus on are simple things like not so we could select all dogs who are not a corgi
or Hudes ages not between certain numbers.
There's different things that we can do.
So if you want to see a specific breakdown of all that you can actually see it here but I'm just going
to show you a couple of simple examples.
So let's start by saying.
Let's say I really hate him.
I really this is not true.
Let's say I don't like chihuahuas.
I'm not in love is too obvious but I don't hate them.
Let's say I don't I want to select all dogs who are not too obvious.
So I would say select star from dogs where breed is not Chihuahua.
Make sure spell right.
And there we go.
Oh that didn't work.
Notice we got Rowse right here.
And that's because it's capital C and now she is excluded.
Sorry Rose.
I can also chain things together so I can say leps I don't like chihuahuas or terrier's.
I don't want small dogs or pugs.
But a lot of work to type all of them.
So I'd say or breed is not and let's say pug.
Sure.
And I'm an idiot that likes everything because I can't do boolean logic.
The problem with that is it's saying select all the dogs where the breed is not to our or the breed
is not pug what we want is select all the dogs who are neither Chihuahua nor pug.
So I would say and breed is not pug and there we go.
Now we don't get the Chihuahua or the pug in there.
Sorry to Rose and Maggie.
Other things we can do I can select all dogs and say I don't want to adopt a puppy so select start from
dogs where age is greater than say I guess we only have one.
Let's say I want a dog who is older than 9 or all get us Rowse say older than 8.
OK now we get piggy and Rowse this is not a very comprehensive intro into selecting a sequel.
It can get very complicated when you start changing things together.
And we have to worry about multiple tables and joining them and that's not what we're doing here.
Of course one last thing I will mention because this can be useful if you're doing a search and you
don't you're not doing an exact match search.
Let's say this is trivial but I want to find dogs that have a name that has two g's in them together
g followed by G.
I could say select star from dogs where name and I wouldn't say where name is Gigi because that is only
going to find dogs with an exact name of Jiji which I think I've met a couple of dogs named Gigi although
not spelled that way but instead we would say where name like Gigi and won't work on its own but we
add in these two little wildcards percent signs and that basically represents any characters any characters
two G's together anywhere.
And now we get piggy in Maggie.
So there are some number of characters before and after but two G's same thing here.
So that's what those percent signs mean.
They just stand in for other stuff and then two G's together.
All right.
So that was a very fast and probably not very comprehensive introduction to sequel basic's we haven't
even talked about things like updating data deleting things but that's alright because it's not really
the point of this.
I want to just now move over to Python land and talk about how do we do this stuff from Python.
How do we make a table connect to a database first and then how do we submit queries how do we get things
to happen from a python file.