A welcome back here is the card and deck class from earlier in the course if you didn't watch those
videos.
Basically there's a card class.
Each card has a student value and there's a deck class that contains a list with 52 of those cards.
And there's things we can do like shuffle or deal cards off the top what else count we can reset a deck.
That's basically it.
Now what I want to show you is said if I had an instance of deck like this my deck.
And then I shuffle it if I wanted to be able to iterate over my deck like I don't know for card in my
deck.
I want to be able to do something with it like we could just start by printing the card right now that's
not going to work because Python doesn't know how to iterate over an instance of deck if I tried to
run it.
I get that deck object is not iterable so because really what would make sense for us to iterate over
a deck.
We just want to iterate over the list of cards.
What we could do really simply is just define anywhere on here let's do death.
It turned itself.
I like to do these on you know all the donder methods together.
It doesn't have to be that way though.
And we need to return something that is an iterator so this is not iterable but it's not an iterator.
If I call it I call it.
It tells me it's turned on iterator type.
So instead we could do it for one two three.
And now if I call this we get one to three so we could replace that set of 1 to 3.
We could replace that with Dot cards.
And now there we go we are iterating over all those cards.
So all we really did by adding this line in here is make it so that instead of having to do for card
in my deck dot cards.
Now we can just iterate over the deck directly and it only gives us the cards.
Whereas before this caused an error this is of course a very simple example.
But it is logical you know in a deck all that we really would want to iterate over our cards.