All right.
And this video we are going to refactor our quotes game so that we're not scraping every time at the
beginning what we're going to do is save the file or save the scrapes data to a CACP file so that we
can recall it from that file whenever we want.
But I am going to move this functionality to a separate file because we also don't want to be saving
this ESV file every time.
And I'll start by copying all the scraping functionality over everything from here up and I have a file
called cxxviii scraper Doppie y and in here we're going to basically run scrape quotes save it to a
variable called quotes and then afterwards save for those who write quotes to a file to see a file.
So we have a choice which format or what are we going to use to write to the CSP file a regular writer
or addict writer.
Because our data is a dict like this.
It'll probably be easiest to use a dict writer to do that.
We just come up here from we import dipt writer and we start by opening a file that doesn't exist yet
but let's call it quote out CXXVI in write mode as file and we'll do C S V dot or C Espey writer equals
dict writer and then we need to pass in first the file and then second we need field names.
And our field names are going to be just make a list called headers.
They are text needs to be a list like this author and then bio link.
OK so we passed that in and then we'll start by writing the headers so that C S V writer dot write header
and I kind of remember if it's singular we'll see something this simple where I know it's either right
or right header's rather than consulting the docs just faster to test it.
So let's see what happens if we just save the headers to the file.
So we're going to scrape and actually we could just.
We're not even using quotes and no reason to do all the scraping.
Let's just see if we're writing correctly.
If I remembered how to correctly you write to a file
and we have a quote CXXVI let's look at it.
OK.
It has our headers so that is indeed working.
Now we can uncomment the rest and actually write our rows.
So we're going to loop through for quote in quotes.
We're going to then do a cxxviii writer dot right.
Row quote the quote is a dictionary so it should work right off the bat right out of the off the bat
out of the out of the gate area.
Let's test it.
Moment of Truth takes a little bit to do the scraping.
See that's the file have you has a lot of quotes in here as you can see.
I've got about 100 quotes and they're all in the correct format.
Hopefully text author bio link.
Here is the text.
Here's the author.
And then here's the bio link.
So now every time we run this code we're going to go get new data.
So if they updated this site frequently or more often than not you know you're not be working with this
Web site.
Whatever site you're working with it will be updated pretty frequently whether you're trying to get
apartment data or camp site data or ticket data the data changes and you want to run your code and get
the latest data and you can do this.
But we're no longer being held up.
Well actually we are because we haven't refactored yet.
We're still scraping in here every time.
But in a moment we're going to change that.
And before we change it we could just make a new file called you know write quotes like this and then
it just takes in a list of quotes and we indent all of this and get rid of that down here we just get
that data and then we call write quotes and we pass in quotes.
So I've just made this into a function doesn't really make a difference.
It's a simple file but I'll do it here.
Celso best.
Now add in our sleep for a second or two because we're only running this every once.
I don't know.
Once a week or something we don't care how long it takes versus when we're actually playing the game.
We definitely don't want to wait a second in between every request.
Let's just make sure it works.
I will fast forward through this it successfully completed and if we look we have the same quotes I
think should be in the same order and we think they randomly change the order.
OK.
So that's working great.
We can leave this file alone for now.
And now what I'm going to do I'm going to leave my original and then make another version of where we
read from the file.
I'll call this one CSP game.
Let's go with a quote game that p y paste all this code in here.
But get rid of scrape quotes.
We're no longer going to scrape quotes at the beginning.
Instead we're going to read using the V module so from CSP import dicts reader and then let's make a
function and let's call this one read quotes and what it's going to do is open the file and if you want
to be fancy this should be file name here and then we'll open the file name comma and then as an R for
read as file and then we'll start with R C S V reader equals dict reader and then we need to pass in
the file.
And then what that gives us back if we I'm just going to not run the game.
And instead I'm just going to print CSFB reader or we can iterate over for thing in CAC reader print
thing and we just need to make sure recalling read quotes at the end of the day with the correct file
name which was quote step C S V.
So hopefully we see a bunch of stuff printed out.
This was called CSP quote game.
Yes we're getting these ordered dict in the list.
All that will do is convert them to be a list.
Right now it's not actually a list.
Remember we can iterate over it but it's not a list which is what we need.
So we'll just call quotes equals the list of CXXVI reader and then we can return quotes.
And honestly if we can just return this.
There's no reason to do it on a separate line so no when we call read quotes the moment of truth is
going to be down here we're going to set quote's equals.
Read quotes as in the file quotes that CSP and then we're going to start game with those quotes.
So there's no scraping happening anymore.
When we run this file it's using the data saved right here.
Let's see if the game still works.
I'm nervous.
Yea so far it works there's no reason it shouldn't continue to work but let's test it so it does have
to scrape here this is the only time we're making a request now.
And type Jane Austen correctly.
Got it right.
Play one more time.
This time I'll get it wrong wrong wrong wrong and we're done.
No sweet that is working.
So we successfully refactor this now we're no longer having good scrape for 10 or 20 seconds before
anyone can play a small change you can make it that we're not using time here.
That was in the scraping portion we're not doing that anymore.
So we can get rid of that if we wanted to.
We could also refactor this here.
It's not going to make a massive difference.
It's purely about making this shorter which some people would argue that it's better to keep the you
know the same functionality things that have to do with one another.
Together we could move this two separate function Kolb's print hint or something like this and we just
pass in remaining guesses like that and then down here I'll just define def print and it takes in remaining
guesses and it just has our conditional out didn't correct.
The only thing about using this approach is that we also need to have access to that quote which right
now we don't.
So we can also pass that in like this quote comma remaining guesses.
And then here we call it with quote It cleans things up a little bit modestly.
Not positive if I prefer it this way.
You can decide.
Just make sure it still works.
All right.
It's printing a quote Yes or printing a hint looks like it's working.
And that's pretty much it for changes that we need to make.
If you want to get really fancy possibly over complicate things because our data is pretty simple you
could make a class or to make a quote class.
And honestly I don't know if it makes sense to do that because it's only three pieces of data it is
the represented with a dictionary but you could also make a game class so you could instantiate a new
game but that might be overkill.
Not a bad idea if you want more practice but I leave mine as just a couple of functions.
Call.