Okeydokey.
So I decided to add the video on comments which I mentioned at the beginning of this section has nothing
to do with math.
It's just an oddball single topic that needs to go somewhere.
So I decided to put it between the two Mathie videos in this section.
So if you're looking for the weirder operators video that after this one this will be super quick.
So comments like I said it's a weird one off topic but it's an important one so comments are just a
way for us to write little notes instead of our code that won't actually be run.
So let me show you I'm actually going to make a new file so I don't have any files in this directory
and make a file and we're just going to call it comment.
Dot p y.
And then I'm going to open comments up.
Why if you don't have this double as you B.L. shortcut or for using Cloud 9 you could cloud 9 just double
click on comments IPY or you can use open comments that way and will use whatever text editor.
So I have this here and let's just start by writing something like.
1 divided by three and let's print one two out of three because remember if we just do one Redway three
without that print nothing will show up and we run this file because it is in a file.
We're not using the Python interpreter in the command line so we'll just start with this.
All right.
So back in the terminal I can run Python 3 common step y and we get 0.3 3:3 great.
So what we expect.
So let's say we wanted to add a note though that said something like always returns float division returns.
Well we can antimagic comment with this character the hash the pound symbol is actually called an octave
Thorpe.
It's kind of a piece of trivia that I might repeat too much in my courses but oh well to Thorpe.
So we can write whatever we want after this.
So a little note to ourself like division return's float even when dividing two ants and that's all
there is to a comment.
So if I didn't have this comment Python would try and run this and that would be a big problem.
Make sure you save your file before you do anything.
If I try and run it now I get the error saying invalid syntax because it doesn't know what the heck
is going on because that's English not Python.
So I can add my comment there.
Also as a side note if you are using an editor like sublime even in cloud 9 the text editor or atom
you can highlight something in that and type command slash in it will comment the entire line.
So wherever put command slash that line is commented out or you can just type single Octa thought.
All right.
So now if I do this hit the up arrow to rerun it I don't get any errors.
I don't have anything afterwards.
So down here I could do something like 1 divided by 5.
It doesn't matter.
You could comment out Python itself actual valid syntax and still nothing will happen because it's commented
out.
So this just tells Python ignore whatever comes after this and that's all there is to comments.
So let me just prove that one more time.
Run it again.
And this second line doesn't occur to Python it's like it's not even there.
Cloak of invisibility from the Python interpreter.
So on the topic of comments.
One thing that students often ask is when should I use these when do people use them.
We'll talk more about this when we talk about style and conventions but generally for you if you're
learning Python I think it helpful to add comments to yourself to remind you of things because often
just looking at a line of code.
It's not all that self-explanatory especially early on.
So you can add a comment or two to kind of remind you of what the heck's going on.
But also in the real world comments are used to help other developers understand what's happening.
So you might have some code that is very specific to something that you built and maybe I'm working
a team of 10 people.
I write some long thing that's 20 lines I could add a comment that says hey you know this little function
does X or Y and then anyone else in my team could see it and immediately just know what it does.
They wouldn't have to step line by line through it.
Now depending on the company and the team some places really would like you to comment your code a lot
other places don't want code don't want comments at all and they think code should be self-explanatory.
So it's really just a culture thing.
But if you're learning I highly recommend using comments I don't care personally with my students if
they comment every single line.
So long as it helps them learn and they're not just wasting time writing comments instead of code.
All right so that's comments.
Now back to our regularly scheduled not boring math program.