Pay.
Welcome back.
So we're continuing on with HTP requests.
And in this video we're going to talk about something called a queery string.
So what is a query string.
Let's start there.
It's a way to pass data to a server as part of a GET request.
It looks like this after our base you are l there's a slash question mark and then key value pairs.
This should look well.
It's a little similar to a Python dictionary in the sense that it's key value pairs.
We use an equal sign here and we separate them with.
And that the idea is this is a way to send data to a server to give more information about a particular
request.
For example when I go to Google and I do a search for Martin does one of my favorite animals American
Martin here's what it looks like by the way.
Very adorable but also vicious predator sharp teeth.
Anyway if you notice that you are well back here I'll refresh the page again.
I'll actually copy it to sublime so we can see it better.
OK.
Here it is.
It's pretty massive.
We have our base you are Al slash search it ends right there and then question mark and then there's
a bunch of these key value pairs.
So here's the first one let's separate them out.
Here's one we have another one.
I'll delete that and signed joining them together.
Then we have this here.
We got another one right here and I don't know what most of these do.
So a lot of this is you know Google's internal stuff but the two that I care about here we have.
Q which is usually for queery and then.
Oh Q Which probably stands for original query.
So regardless of what these all do a lot of this is Google magic.
The key point I want to make is that this is additional information that is being sent as part of the
request and we can have as many key value pairs as we want.
I think there is an upper limit about how long they can be but we can pass whatever info we want and
we could even at our own query string like ice cream equals vanilla if we wanted to and it will be sent
as part of the request but nothing will happen.
Nothing happens at all.
And let's try doing something like.
Q equals volcano.
You can see what we actually get.
Kind of interesting takes us to a page where volcano is filled in to the search form but it actually
doesn't send it.
So that's just the way that Google is set up.
Anyway we're getting sidetracked.
All I want to focus on is that the query string it's a way for us to send additional information.
So why does this matter to us.
Well a lot of times we'll make applications that allow a user to provide some information about what
they want to search for for example.
So let me show you an example of that I have using the dad jokes site.
I have a simple app that will make where I can actually provide a joke topic like dog.
And then it will go send a request looking for dumb dog jokes and it says OK I've got eight jokes.
Here's one.
My dog has no nose.
How does the smell awful.
Very funny.
Or I could specify a different query.
How about car archaeology really is a career in ruins.
So there's search the way it works is it just looks for no car anywhere.
Instead of the text.
So in this case it was career but that is not something that we control.
But what we're going to focus on is how we can take this data here and what we do is we pass it into
a query string in the request and back on the I Can Has dad joke dot com web page.
If we go to will if we just try searching first thing you should notice that you are well has changed.
It's now I can educate our com slash search which gives us this page.
But now let's do a search for oh I don't know Sister see.
Nope no jokes.
OK.
How about rose flower.
Don't buy don't buy flowers at a monastery because only you can prevent florist friers Oh boy that's
really bad anyway.
Notice up here are you.
Now contains a query string key value pair a single key value pair term equals flour.
So this is how we actually send a search request.
This form is just going to generate this request so if I type something else in here like fruit.
There you go.
You can see the request that was sent had term equal to fruit.
So if I send a request instead to term equals cat.
Now we get the cat results.
So this is a mechanism by which the search works.
We send a request to.
I can ask dad joke dot com slash search question mark means a query string and then we specify the information
and to do this in python rather than in the browser.
We could just send a request just like this.
You know you are l.com and then send our key value pairs already hard coded into the URL which has to
be a string and that's fine but there's a preferred way which is to do it by passing in what are known
as Paramo.
It's just how the requests get method is set up and we can pass in our key value pairs like this and
this way we could use variables we could have a dictionary that contained our harams.
It's easier than doing it this way where we have to actually you know interpolate the values in here
we can just use a dictionary.
So let's let's try and just make a file called harams that Y and the first thing we'll do is just copy
over what we've already done
just like this.
So we have our import requests we have.
You are well and I wouldn't change it to now be slash search because that's where the search end point
is.
We could send a query string to just I can has that joke outcome but it won't actually do the search
unless we tell it we're looking for Slash search in particular.
Then we're going to do the same request I get this time.
I'm just going to indent things like this so we have our headers.
But that at the bottom and then after our headers we can also provide harams and harams we can just
encode whatever information we want and the way that this is set up is that it is looking for something
called term.
We can go to the API documentation.
Scroll down until we find search somewhere.
There we go.
Search for dad jokes and pulser all zoom in.
There's a couple of things we can specify.
Page which is the page of results to fetch which defaults to 1 so if we get 20 or 50 results they will
be passionated the limit so this will limit the number of results we get.
So I could specify only want one result and the term which is the most important part that's what we're
searching for.
So let's try just doing sosh search.
Question mark.
Term equals.
We did Cat which gave us 5 results.
But now if I do ampersand so and and then it was the limit equals one.
I only get one back limit equals 2 and so on.
So hopefully now you can see some of the power of a query string.
This is how we can specify details about what we want now as a human we earn.
Typical web user.
We're not ever really editing this up here.
Usually we'll click a button that does that for us right.
Like a search for dog here and it makes a request and this form puts it into the query string.
But if we're doing it in Python as programmers we have to assemble them manually.
So we'll send a request to slash search slash search.
And let's just start by hard coding in.
Term is going to be let's do fruit's again just like that.
Actually that's too bad because there was multiple results.
OK so just to make this clear by doing this it's the exact same thing at the end of the day as me doing
this term equals cat.
The thing is that this is a more programmatic more Python way of doing it because this is easier to
change.
I could easily have this be a variable.
Like user input which is what will do eventually.
This is a little harder because if I wanted this to be a variable I could concatenated or use an F string
or something.
But rather than that I'm just going to leave it at this and then this.
Requests a package is going to take care of adding the query string in to the request so I'm going to
change this back to cats or cat.
OK now are doing responsa Jaison and then rather than printing data joke because our response might
look different.
Let's comment this out and let's just print data OK this file is called Paramjit up.
Why.
Let's test it.
So that's Python 3 harams.
And look at the results we get back.
So I'm going to copy this over pasted in so we can dissect it.
And that did not go how I thought.
I was hoping that it would go on multiple lines.
So as you can see we have things like current pages one limit was set to 20 by default next page previous
page we don't care about that.
Well we care about is results instead of results.
We have a list.
So let's start by just paring that down and printing data results.
And I'm going to get rid of this line because I will break everything.
Now here's our results.
It's a list and it's a list of dictionaries where each joke has an ID.
It has the actual joke and that's it then an ID and a joke an ID and a joke.
So one more thing I'll show you is we can just pass in another key value pair.
So we saw how to do this with limit but set the limit to 1.
So now we should only get one joke back.
And that's exactly what happens.
Put the cat out.
I didn't realize it was on fire.
Very funny.
So leave the video off here.
We've seen how to use harams which is just how this requests get method is set up we can specify key
value pairs at the end of the day.
This is exactly the same as UFS as us manually saying term Rekos cat and limit equals one.
It's just an easier or more programmatic way of doing it.
And in the next video we're going to make a little application that asks the user for what they want
to search for and we can also ask them for a limit how many jokes they want and we can specify both
of them in Paramus.
So that's coming up next.