Welcome back.
So we've seen the basic syntax of a function and we've seen how to return value.
We have enough now enough tools to define a function that does something a bit more interesting and
what we're going to do is to find a function that will toss a coin for us or flip a coin and it will
use random which we've seen before.
We've used Rand and we're going to use a different part of the random module and our function will return
heads or tails depending on a random toss or random flip.
So let's first make a new file and I'll just call it coin flip IPY Let's open it up and the first thing
we'll do is write from random import random and we're not really going to discuss this.
We're kind of skipping over it like we have in the past.
If you've watched those videos this is a module that comes with Python but we have to manually include
it that's all but I'll say for now when we talk about modules it will make more sense.
OK but onto the function part.
So what we want is a function called let's say flip a coin and it takes no inputs we haven't talked
about that yet but that doesn't mean that it has to do the exact same thing every time our silly happy
birthday demo does the exact same thing every single time through.
But because we're going to use the random module we can add an element of randomness if we can get a
different result.
Heads or tails.
So there's a couple of steps.
First thing we need to do is generate random number and we're going to go from 0 to 1.
And if the decimal number so it's going to be a float if it's between zero and 0.5.
Well we'll sign it that say head.
Otherwise we'll do tails and then we'll just return the string heads or tails and that's it.
So let's let's just generate the number to start.
So to generate a random number from 0 to 1 all we have to do is type random just like this.
So let me actually just demo this to you in the terminal Python 3.
And if you just type random like this it's giving us a number between 0 and 1.
So it doesn't include one but it includes point 9 9 9 9 9 9 9 9 9 and you can see they range from zero
to 1.
OK.
So we've got that.
This is going to generate the number and all we want to do you know we could set it to a variable.
So we could call it just R and R equals random and then it's just a simple IF statement.
If R is.
And let's do greater than 0.5 and then we'll just add in or else.
So what do we do if it's greater.
We're going to return and it's up to us which way we want to do this let's turn heads else return tails
Just like that.
And let's try this let's just do a print flip a coin.
So flip coin is going to be called executed although I caught myself here.
We need parentheses if we just print flip coin.
It's not going to actually execute it.
So we need to execute it which is going to then generate a random number save it to a variable called
R and then if R is greater than 0.5 will turn heads.
Otherwise will return tails.
Let's see if it works
you've got heads tails heads tails heads heads tails.
Cool.
So we can accept that it's random enough.
It doesn't matter if it's perfect if it's exactly 50/50.
It doesn't matter.
A quick change we could make.
I'll leave this version here.
But we could shorten this a little bit by doing instead of saving it to a variable.
We could just do.
If random is greater than 0.5 return heads else return tails.
OK.
So here is our slightly improved version or we're just not using a separate variable.
The only other thing I would mention is that by redefining flip a coin down here it actually overwrites
this version.
So if I just tried to run flip the coin again it's not going to run.
I mean they both do the exact same thing but it's not going to execute this version.
It's going to execute the overwritten version.
So we could tell that if I did in all caps like this which do we expect to see heads or tails.
Let's see.
And I need to add a decimal point there.
Here we go.
So you can see it's all caps.
So what this shows us is that we've overwritten flip a coin that was defined once.
It's now defined again.
This version has lost just like overwriting a variable.
OK.
So I'm going to get rid of this initial version and just keep this one here.
And this is our first function that does something a bit more interesting.
It has an element of randomness.
It doesn't you know just sing Happy Birthday over and over monotonously.
This gives us a different result each time through.
OK next we're actually going to see how we can write functions that except inputs.