Welcome back.
Next up we're going to see another built in function similar to math but this one is called Filter.
So just like with map where we can pass in the lambda and then an iterable collection filter allows
the same thing but it works in a different way.
So filter does what it sounds like it allows us to take a list or a collection a tuple and filter out
particular items that we want based off of an expression or condition.
So here's an example where we have a list of numbers from 1 to 4 and the results of running this filter
is that we're pulling out the evens and putting them into a new list.
And the way we we do it is we use filter and then our Lamda which is going to return true or false.
So anytime we use filter whether we're using lambda or named function we've defined it needs to return
true or false needs to be a boolean expression in that function.
And that true or false is going to be how filter decides what to put in the new list.
So as you can see here this expression for every x if x is not even if it's just x mod two equals zero
that itself will be true or false if that's true.
Filter takes whatever value you like to and added to the list.
But if we're on three for example this is false.
It's not even the divisible by 2.
So it's not added It's rejected and ignored.
So let's do a quick example.
I have a list of names here called names and let's say that I want to make a new list with only the
names that start with a letter a.
So Austin Anthony and downhill are angel.
And to do that we could use filter so we would do make a new variable.
Well let's call it a names equals and we can start with just filter and then the lambda we want I always
do the D first which is wrong it's lam does not land BA and it will just take a name you can call it
name.
It's ok in my opinion.
In my short single letter parameters because the idea is that it's a single line it's not ever going
to be used again.
So instead of doing name I'm fine with an and then we'll check if the first character and zero equals
a.
Just like that.
So this returns true or false.
And then we'll do that on every name and names.
So just to reiterate I have one too many Kolins over here may have a filter.
This will return true or false.
This lambda for every and or name in names.
Check the first character.
Is it equal to a.
If that's true add it to the new list.
If it's not ignore it and if we look at a name just like with math we get this filter object instead
of a map object.
But if we turn it into a list you can see we get Austin Anthony unhealth.
So hopefully you can see how this is helpful.
Yes we could still use this comprehensions so I'm going to talk about that.
But ignoring that fact there are lots of times you might want to extract certain things from a list
based off a condition.
And what do you know.
I have a little demonstration ready.
So here is a list of users.
Let's imagine I'm running a very simple version of Twitter and I have people who are active and people
who are inactive in the way I can tell is.
So there's a user name for each person Samuel and then tweets is a key and the value is a list.
So Samuel has two tweets.
I love cake.
I love pie.
He just is really into pastries.
But then we have someone like Jeff who has no tweets So let's say I work at this company and my job
my task is to reach out to all of the users who have never tweeted you know do some sort of annoying
thing like hey we notice you signed up but you never sent your first tweet.
Like here's an easy way to send your first tweet.
You've probably seen something like that.
Maybe not a tweet but from some other company.
So let's do that.
Let's pull out all of the inactive users so I can make a variable called the inactive users.
And then I'll set it to filter and what is the filter we want to do.
What's the true or false condition.
Well for every item in this list.
So let's start there.
We're going to pass in users.
Now for every user We're going to check if the tweets property in that dictionary because each user
has this whole dictionary going to check if their tweets property has a length that equal to zero.
So let's test it out.
I'm going to show you one way of doing it first so we could do your LAMDA.
And I'll just call each user you and then what check is you tweets that's going to just give us this
list and we could check the length of your tweets to see if it's equal to zero.
This is kind of a lot to take in if you're still shaky with this but let's just walk through it.
So for each user you is the temporary variable representing this first one here.
All right and we're checking you tweets tweets gives us this list and then doing the length of that
which would be two two is not equal to zero so that would be false.
So it is not added to the new list but Jeff his tweets the list the length of it is zero.
So we get zero equals zero which is then going to add him to our end result filter list.
OK.
So am I missing any Perens.
Looks good but I'm going to turn it into a list.
So we get this extra long thing.
And then let's just print inactive users
and we get Jeff who has zero tweets Bob 1 2 3 0 tweets and guitar gal who has your tweets.
OK.
So there's a couple of modifications we could make.
We could take advantage of the fact that an empty list is inherently falsie.
Remember that values like an empty list an empty string and zero are inherently falsie.
So I don't even have to check the length of anything.
I don't have to check if it's equal to zero.
If I do this right now you tweets is going to return true for every list or for every user except the
ones that I want so I'll actually get the opposite.
Let me just demonstrate that I get only the users who are active.
So I can negate that.
It's just not huge.
So huge tweets is going to return either a list or an empty list.
And if it's an empty list that's false.
So then we'd be saying not false which gives us true.
Let's verify there we go.
We're only getting our empty tweets.
People who have never tweeted next I'm going to show how we can combine filter and map.
So here's a list of names Lassie colds and resti And suppose you want to make a new list with the string.
Instructor is Plus you know Lassie and colds and resti So your instructor is last year's circulars colt
but only if the value is less than five characters.
This is what that would look like.
It's kind of intense to look at it but what we're doing is we're running map where map is going to take
each name and return the string.
Your instructor is name but what collection is it running it on.
Well that itself is a filter on names.
So this is going to run first and it's going to make a list where we only have the names who are shorter
than five characters so that's only a list containing cold.
And then we're going to run this map where we make a new list where we map your instructor is and that's
how we get your instructor is called.
I know it's kind of intense.
So back over here with a more practical example rather than just collecting our inactive users let's
say we only want to collect the usernames in our inact inactive users we don't want the entire thing
like this.
We can actually use Map to do that.
So I'm going to comment this out but I'm going to keep our filter like this but then I'm going to write
a map.
So we're going to have a map where all we want to do.
So we have a lambda and for each user We're just going to want the user bracket user name.
So this is a way to make a list where we're taking an entire user and only returning the user name.
OK.
And just to be extra fancy we could do that upper for no reason what collection are we going to run
that on.
Well if we just ran it on users it would do it for every single one in there.
But if we only want the inactive users we can filter first.
So on a single line it looks kind of insane.
So I'm going to indented like this and we're almost there except remember math doesn't return a list.
So we need to then turn this entire thing into a list.
It's crazy.
I hope I haven't lost you but all that we're doing here is first filtering out the active users and
only getting the inactive ones which we've already done.
But we're passing that in to map.
So map is building on top of this it's taking that list of inactive users and for each one adding it
to a list but only adding the username upper cased.
OK.
And let's just say that a variable called user names and then that Sprint user names the moment of truth
there go.
These are our three inactive usernames all capitalized.
A sigh of relief.
We're done with that.
So now the question that we're finally going to answer is What about miscomprehension of why complicate
things if we could just do a list comprehension.
For example this previous example of returning a list with the string your instructor is and then the
name but only four names that are less than five characters.
We could do that with a single list comprehension like this.
Right.
Or we do the string for name in names if length is less than five.
And that is way better in my opinion.
And pretty much everyone agrees this sort of syntax a list comprehension is the bread and butter of
Python.
It's what almost everybody would prefer to use but it's important that you understand that these exist
things like map and filter that lambdas are around.
Basically in this case for just an educational context it's something that you need to know about when
you move on to bigger and better things.
You might see one on a project you're working on the library of the package you download might require
you to use one.
Well it wouldn't require you to but it might have it in the documentation or something.
But if you can use this comprehension to do the same thing like we can here then we should.
But you know earlier when we had this button.
This is not something we could do with less comprehension.
We need a lambda.
So all of this stuff I've been showing you map and filter.
It's not something you're probably going to use very much but it's good to know it exists.
So don't hate me for teaching it but let me just show you how we could change this over like if we just
wanted to do our inactive users in a single miscomprehension all we have to do is for user end users
will just do user for user and users.
If and then we just do user tweets or we can say if not user tweets just like that we don't have to
turn it into a list right.
It's already going to be list.
It's my opinion so much nicer than this.
This is what you would end up writing know very something very similar if you're using javascript but
Python has these lovely beautiful expressions those comprehensions and I could just save this too.
I'll call it an active users to
and then just print inactive users to comments everything else out.
And if I run it now there are inactive users and to improve upon this earlier or the second example
where we use the filter and a list I could do the same thing where I just do user user name.
Upper.
And yeah it's kind of a long line but I think this is so much better than all of this here.
So let's try printing that and we get the same result.
OK and and titted this a bit.
So here's the version to extract the inactive users using filter and the lammed up.
Here it is using miscomprehension.
We don't have to convert it to just get rid of that printer as well here.
The only thing I guess I should update this in active users.
Let's go with user names instead.
If you're just looking at this code usernames too.
So here is the monster combining map and filter to extract the usernames and uppercase them only of
the inactive users.
And here's the exact same thing with a list comprehension.
So the moral of all of this is one I just needed to show something that used to Lamda that we could
wrap our heads around to you might see something like this you might see it around or if you're coming
from a language like javascript this might feel more natural but this is the python way and this is
what you'll see by far more more often.
So that wraps it up for now.
Now we're going to take a look at a bunch of other built in functions that we don't have to worry about
lambdas for.
It will be a breath of fresh air after this nightmare that this syntax is.