Hey welcome back.
This is the last of the introduction to beautiful soup syntax videos where we work with the dummy data
the string of which came up after this video.
We will be scraping for real.
We'll be sending a request and getting real time from a real web page.
But before then we have to talk about navigating with beautiful soup.
When I say navigating it means having a tag and finding elements relative to that tag or that element.
So if we have an ally I could ask beautiful soup to find me the parent of that ally or to find the parent
of the parent or to find the next sibling or the next descendant of the lie.
So it's a way of navigating moving around in the team.
Relative to something that you select.
And briefly just run through what we'll see in this video.
So we'll see how to do it two ways.
The first is to do it via the tags using attributes called Parent content and next sibling not methods
but actually using attributes.
And then we'll see how to do it with searching whether our methods find a parent and find the next sibling.
What we'll talk about as well as find previous sibling.
If you're still confused I think it will make I pray or make more sense in this example.
So I have a third file exactly the same starter code and I've just cleared out what we had down here.
So imagine that I select an element any element.
But let's start with the body.
I select the body.
So to do that we have a couple of ways the easiest way is just souped up body but we can also do souped
up find body but we'll do student body so that selects this the body and everything inside of it.
So to have access to the contents of that tag we've seen how to get the inner text like if I select
this H-3 we saw how to extract high but when we have nested edged him out if we do with the body how
do we select the contents inside of it.
And it's really straightforward we just do souped up body contents.
So instead of tag let's just call this data.
It's such a terrible name but let's just print data and what we should see is everything inside the
body.
OK but the form that we get it in is as a list.
So we have all of the tags.
Each one is an object.
It's being printed as a string here.
But each one is an object.
But there are these new line characters in here.
Why do we have that.
If we look at the age t m l those new lines are all over the place.
Here's the tag we're working with.
Body and then the first item in the list was a new line and then we had the tag div..
As you can see here so we had new line and then div and then after that div there's another new line
and then after that there's the oh well and then another new line.
So each one of those new lines occurs whenever there's a break between elements in our HMO assuming
they are on different lines.
So content gives us that list.
And if I wanted to find the first child or the first descent of the body what I would need to do is
instead of accessing zero I actually have to access one because there's that new line there.
So that will give me the div.
And this is silly because you know we know what the body is we know what the HMO looks like.
There's no reason to do this like the body and then the first item in it.
Well maybe there would be reasons why I can't think of one that this is more to prepare us for a really
common thing which is you select some item that has an ID or a class and you try to find the closest
thing that has a class or an idea you can select and then you navigate down into it or at least like
the parent you find a reference point in a starting place you can hook into and then use things like
dark content to move around because sometimes it's harder than you would expect to select the particular
things that you want.
So you get close and then you navigate towards it anyway.
So body contents now with contents one index of one gives us that did and we could actually called the
contents on that because that gives us this div.
So the content of that is this you can see let's see if that works there.
We have new line H-3 new line paragraph new line.
So that's this right in here instead of that div.
OK.
The next thing that we can do is we've seen how to access content to descend into the elements that
are nested down but I could go from this div to this ordered list.
These are siblings siblings meaning if they are on the same level of the hierarchy they are not embedded
in one another.
They are not nested and they're not in the parent child relationship like body indiv or body and oh
well they are siblings.
And conveniently we can just call next sibling which is an attribute so contents one is going to select
this div and then the next sibling is going to be oh well and this takes care of this.
You don't have to worry about the new lines in the contents.
Next sibling will give you the next item that actually is an empty mix sibling.
If you check it out gives us nothing apparently what's happening here.
Well the next sibling of this did remember the contents.
I have it back up here still where it was that somewhere up here.
Well if I lost it it's a new line.
Afterwards there sorry if it did.
And then a new line and then the oh well.
So it's treating this as the next sibling.
So if we wanted to we could just called dot next sibling again.
And so that's going to go from here to the next sibling which is the new line to the next sibling which
is that oh well it's kind of clunky but that gives us the ordered list OK.
And the other thing we can do a comment that went out if we do something like soop Dodd let's select
the this ally.
The first one that has a class of super special cells like that super dot find.
And then we can do well I don't like this in Texas much.
The class underscore equals but I'll do it.
I already started.
So souped up fine.
That gives us this.
And then if we called that parent save it to a variable we'll call this one data I guess just to save
our print statement.
So that gives us the lie.
Now I can go backwards.
We had dumb content to go in.
There's no nested aged him out here.
But if I call parent it gives us the oh well that is inclosing the ally.
And if I called that parent again you know we keep moving up on layer and that gives us the entire body.
OK.
So this is what we've already seen.
Navigating via tags.
There's also a subset of methods we can use where we can search and they're called Find parent find
next sibling find previous sibling.
So if we take an example that's going to come at this one as well let's go with data equals soop find.
And let's go with this div that has the idea of first.
So let's actually do top find and then Id equals first like that and to find the next sibling we just
call find next sibling.
And remember what I called next sibling here but it gave us the new line.
Let's see what happens when I call find the next sibling.
Now you can see we just get the next element is.
We're searching for the next thing.
That's the way that the method is set up.
Instead of giving us that new line.
So if I had done this souped up find dot next sibling like this that's going to give us that empty.
It's just a new line.
But if we use find new line it will skip through or find the next sibling it will skip over that one
until it actually finds an object an actual instance of an element to give us.
So that's the advantage of using things like find the next sibling and we can chain them together as
well.
So if I did find next sibling again first time we go from this div to this sibling then we're here and
we go to this sibling div data example yes that says by and there we go.
So we can chain them together to keep moving forward.
There's also a find previous sibling.
So if we started with a div like we did there isn't a previous sibling but let's say I start with this
bottom div that has data example set to Yes.
So I could select it by.
I mean there's a bunch of ways I guess select all divs and then take the last one.
Or I could use this attribute here.
I think that's what I'll do.
So come down here already duplicated this get rid of all of this and we'll run soup instead of find.
Let's do a select and then use our CSSA attribute syntax and we just take the example and that should
give us a go.
Well there's actually two of them aren't there.
And think about that.
All right so then let's check it set to yes in both examples.
No.
All right.
Well just do the one index of one which gives us this.
That's a lot of work.
Now we can use find previous sibling and that's going to go backwards.
So for here the previous sibling is here.
If we run it that's exactly what we get.
We get well and we can chain them together for the next one and give us this div and so on.
Another thing to mention is when we use find previous sibling we can actually pass in a string.
Let me show you.
I'm going to switch up my aged him just a little bit and move it around like this.
So now we have in our orderless there are still three allies but the two that have the class special
are now separated.
And if I select this first one using that class name which I actually already have I believe we just
duplicate it here.
OK.
So this is going to find the element that has the class super special which is this.
If I do find next to swivelling it's going to give me this right defaults and it does.
This item is not special but if I wanted to find the next sibling that has classes special I could just
pass in the class with that ugly underscore equals special.
And now this is saying find me the next sibling do a search for the next sibling that has class equal
to special which is this one.
And that's what we get.
Cool.
OK.
And the last thing we'll see is a way to search for parent.
You can just call find parent if we selected this H-3 here.
Very simply we can just do day to dot because soup find age three.
And then on that call do not find parent like this.
And so we start here and we're just going to find the next parent do that there we go we get that div
So we started here and we moved up to the parent and we could also pass something in here.
Operationally if we wanted to be really silly to do.
But right now the next parent is this.
But if I pass in a tag like body or event h t m l it will find the next parent that is h t m l which
is silly because there is only one age 12 element on a page so you could just do supercup find each
T.M. Anyway it's fun to show how it behaves.
This is going to skip all parents until it finds an instance of age to smell.
So that's why they're called searches are searching methods that allow you to navigate by searching
rather than in the dark just fumbling and calling.
Next sibling next sibling and hoping it's not a new line character.
These methods will actually search based off of what you're looking for.
OK.
So that wraps up the basics of beautiful soup.
There are some other methods and additional functionality we haven't gotten into.
Can always you know open up your docs and just call help on an item like if we just did help.
Data and see if we get a lot of things like.
Well skip all these Danders for now.
Keep going.
OK so there's things like clear.
So we have things like de-code contents encode.
Find find Also there you have is a find child.
We didn't talk about that one.
So you could search only within the children of an element.
There's get there's what else.
And it was there's a bunch of things.
So I just want to be clear we didn't cover every possible thing.
I just covered a lot of the essentials but at the end of the day when we're doing scraping it often
Personally I'm always looking at the docs for whatever module or package whatever I'm using whether
it's in Python.
Beautiful soup or a different library in other languages.
I'm always looking at the docks because there's so many little one off things that you have to do.
It's just too much to remember honestly this was more of just a crash course in beautiful soup but we'll
probably reference the docs as we go forward in the next video when we actually start scraping.
So look forward to that.
If that sounds good we are going to start scraping for real next video.