OK so we've seen how to define the simplest class.
Some might say dumbest class in Python.
Now let's talk about how would we actually give this User class some attributes.
So every user should have a first name and a last name and an e-mail.
Let's start there.
So how do I actually define that.
Well the first thing we have to talk about is the init method.
Anytime we make a new instance of a class Python will automatically look for the special double underscore
init method.
So it's you know look for it automatically.
You don't ever recall it explicitly and it will call itself whenever we make a new vehicle in this case.
This code will run.
So when we make a new user the user class init method will run.
So to prove that to you me define this init method.
So every time we make a new class we should have an init method and one thing I do need to mention we
need to put self here.
We'll come back to this self keyword in a moment but for now just trust me it needs to go there and
let's just start by printing a new user has been made like that which I guess that's a passive voice
but whatever.
And now let's make a couple of users.
User one user or two user three.
I am never calling and net Pythonesque going to do it for me.
When I say make a new user it immediately automatically calls init.
Let's prove that not good that a new user has been made.
It was printed three times even though I never actually called init myself.
OK so that was all just to show you know that this code runs when a new user is created.
You pretty much would never put a print statement in a net where you would actually do is initialized
the data that each user has and to do that we need to talk about the word self.
The self keyword refers to the specific instance of the User class or whatever class we're working with.
So when I refer to self Let's do something like self that name equals and I could start by setting them
all to have the name Perry for example.
But the problem with this there's no real problem.
But it won't actually allow me to illustrate how self works because all three of these will have a name
called Perry.
So instead let's pass in a name here let's go with first and then I'm going to go with self dot name
equals first.
And now we have to do is provide a name here when we initialize the user.
So let's go with either one.
Let me just do two users this time so the user one will be Joe and user 2 will be along like this.
So what I'm saying is when a new user is created provide Joe to a net so self always has to be that
first parameter.
We never actually explicitly pass anything in as self.
Python takes care of it.
Sort of behind the scenes magic.
So Joe is going to be assigned to the first parameter and then the word self is going to refer to this
exact user or hear the specific instance and then when this user is created self refers to this user.
So it's a way to refer to the individual instances the current user.
In this case.
So then when I set self name I'm setting the name attribute on this user to be Joe.
If that's what we pass in and on this user it will be Polonca and if I just execute it.
Now we don't actually see anything at the end of the day.
But if I did a print user one dot name can see user 1 now has the name Joe.
So let's expand it a bit and rather than just doing first.
Let's also do a last name and rather than calling it name Let's do first equals first we'll do self-caused
last equals last and we'll do age so self age equals age so these do not have to be the same names.
This is just the name of a parameter appear.
And this is what we'll be using to refer to it.
You know user one name or in this case that won't work and needs to be done first.
Now to match this.
So this is a name of the attribute like a variable.
Basically or a key in a dictionary.
And this is the value.
Typically you would name them the same thing but you don't have to.
OK so now when I actually initialize a user I need to pass in other pieces of information or I'd get
an error just.
I mean this is like any other function.
If I don't give the specified number of arguments and there's no defaults then it's going to cause a
problem.
So let's go with Joe first.
Let's go with Smith is last and age will be.
I don't know 68 then Blanca and her last name is Lopez and she is forty one.
OK so now we have two separate users.
Two instances of the user class they all follow the same blueprint.
Each one has a first name a last name and age but they have different pieces of data in each individual
instance.
So let's now do print user 1 and print user to do it first.
If I just actually if I just try and print user one on it's own you'll see all that we see for the representation
it's this stuff very helpful.
So for now we're going to access individual properties like first OK and I'll do one last as well and
then I'll do the same thing for you or two.
And let's just see what we get.
There we go.
Joe Smith Blanca Lopez if two instances of user that user class they follow the same pattern but they
have different actual pieces of information.
So to wrap that up we have the init method and we pass in self as the first parameter always we don't
ever pass it as an argument or anything it's automatically called whenever a new vehicle in this case
is instantiated and the way we instantiate a class is by referencing the name of the class conventionally
capitalized and then parentheses and then in those parentheses we pass in any data the arguments that
correspond to the net parameters.
So in this case V becomes a new vehicle an instance of the vehicle class with the following pieces of
information make Honda model a Civic and the year is 2017.
And then finally the self keyword self refers to the current instance of the class.
So it doesn't refer to the class in general the entire blueprint it refers to each individual instance.
Every time we instantiate a new class so we use self a lot inside of it where we usually take the parameters
and then assign them to properties called attributes on self and to the next video you'll see that self
pops up again because it always is the first parameter not only to a net but to any methods.
We go ahead and define on our own class instances.
But before we even get there it's time for an exercise.
You're going to find your own class.
And then after the exercise will come back and we'll learn to add methods to our classes.
OK.
See you then.