So this video will be a solution video to the previous exercise.
Building the dead dad joke 3000 program and all start by just making a new file called jokes.
Why.
And the first thing we know we need to do is important requests and we're going to have you know requests
get something and we're going to say we're too variable and we're going to ask the user for input.
So where should we start.
How about we ask the user for input.
Let's just call it term and we'll be get our inputs.
What would you like to search for out a space the end make it a little nicer.
And then let's leave it alone for just a moment.
Let's make our request and you are all we want is I can has that joke dot com slash search.
So I'll make another variable called you or well make this a string and we don't need the query string
at the end.
We just want slash search and from here we're going to pass in you Earl and let's see if the response
to a variable.
So we'll just call it rez equals requests get.
And we could just do our print Raz dot and we could start by doing text like this because remember right
now we're not asking for Jason we're going to get him back.
And let's see what happens.
Would you like to search for dog and eventually go all that javascript teenage female that comes back
that the browser would do something with.
So now let's change it up and actually ask for the Jaisalmer version which the way we do that.
Remember we have headers and we want except application slash Jaison by the way if you wanted to know
more about that and exactly how it works.
Go to the API documentation and it says API response format all API endpoints follow their respective
browser URLs but we adjust the response formatting to be more suited for an API based on the provided
header and the header is except excepted except headers text slash him.
The default response format.
So that's what we just got.
Application slash.
Jason that's what we want.
So this says you know you can specify what you want which we already knew because I showed you that.
But just so just to be clear if you didn't know that you could find it out here.
So we want applications slash Jaison.
And now if we try and print red text it doesn't matter what we search for it.
You can see what we get is the Jason response by the way.
We're not searching for anything.
So I think it just gives us 20 random jokes and or I think if just all of them and put them on pages.
But anyway.
So this right now is a giant string.
So we need to turn it into Jaison and that's nice and simple.
All we do is use the dot Jason method at the end so I'm going to put these on new lines to make it a
bit easier.
Put this down at the bottom just like that and we can actually just tack on Jason right here so we could
make a new variable and call it you know Jason Raz equals red J song.
Or I could just change it on at the bottom like this and I prefer it this way because all we want is
the taste on that comes back.
So let's try it.
Oh we're not printing anything.
Let's print dress now which should now be the Jason version.
And this is now a python dictionary.
And so we have things like current page limit next page previous page results.
What else.
Search term status is a bunch of things we have.
So now let's hook up our search term and to do that all we need to do is take the user term right here
add a comma and then do harams equals and the Parama we want is term which is this is not up to us.
This is how the API is set up.
But this part is a variable.
And we can just specify term and I know it's kind of confusing They're both called term.
So we could change this to user input maybe.
And then here we'll have user input.
I'm not a fan of shortening that an extra letter doesn't hurt.
OK so now the search term is going to be user input which is the same thing as doing term equals and
then whatever the user inputs.
Let's see if it works.
Oh we actually need to search for something now.
Let's do dog and it looks like we're getting dumb jokes.
My dog has no nose.
How does he smell awful.
Where do you heard that one.
I went to the zoo the other day there was only one dog in it.
It was a shit.
You are very funny.
OK.
So that's getting us results now.
So here's the next thing is we want to take the jokes out and we want to figure out how many there are.
And we have a couple of options.
If you notice first of all all the jokes are instead of results as a list.
So we can loop through that list or we could just take that list and figure out the length of it could
definitely do that.
So we could start there let's just print Reade's results which is a list and let's print the length
of that
and this will tell us how many jokes we got back.
So if I search for a dog we get eight.
If I search for something that doesn't exist.
Zero.
So that's one option.
And we could save that to a variable.
Call it numb jokes or something and then do if numb jokes is equal to one if it's greater than one.
If it's equal to zero but there's actually an even easier way if we look at what we get back from the
API aside from results after results and which is right.
Here we have search terms dog statuses 200 total jokes is 8.
So we can take we can take advantage of total jokes and just do this number of jokes equals rez total
jokes and that will now allow us to do things like if nothing jokes.
And where should we start.
Let's check first if it's greater than one let's just do a print.
There are many jokes if elif jokes is equal to one we can do a print.
There is one joke.
And then finally we'll just do an else well print.
There are no jokes.
So again we're not even using the actual length of the list of results.
There's a short cut that we get back from the API right here.
Total jokes.
Let's see if it works.
I'm going to search for something where there are no jokes we get.
There are no jokes.
Let's search for something like dog.
I think there was eight.
So there are many jokes and I don't know what.
There's only one joke for I think.
Oh a flower.
I think we tried earlier.
There we go.
There was one joke for flower.
Cool.
So now what's the behavior we want.
Well the else part is easy.
Let's just change this too.
Sorry.
Couldn't find a joke with your term.
And then let's let's do student string and then add in.
What is it called user and put like that if there's exactly one joke let's just also print rez just
like this so we can analyze the the way that the response is sent.
So let's try that again with flour and you can see if there's exactly one joke.
It's still inside of something called results and it's a list but there's only one item in that list.
So it still sends it in a list.
And that's important that our API behave.
This API behaves the same way in a predictable manner because if it just decided to send it not in the
list because there's only one item then it would break our code if we were trying to check for a list.
So what we'll do is print response results zero so that's going to be the first item in the list.
Just to double check that.
So we have this whole thing is response or rez results gives us this.
And there's one item so we use zero and that gives us this and then that won't even get the exact joke
just yet if I try it again I type flour.
It's still a dictionary and we need that joke key out of there or the value using the joke key.
Then we tack on joke try again.
Do flour and we get don't buy flowers at a monastery but above the law.
OK.
So now we need to go to this scenario where there are more than many jokes two or eight or 10 results.
We want to pick one at random and the first thing we'll do is import random and there's a couple ways
of picking a random element from a list.
We could generate a number.
Let's say there's no four items in our list.
We could generate a number from 0 up to 3 and then use that to access you know the index randomly or
we can use this special method that we get called choice and choice will take a list and it could contain
you know a couple of things in there and it will pick one thing at random and return it from the list.
So that's what I'm going to do and I'm going to do from random import choice because that's all we need.
OK.
So import choice and then down here I'm going to run choice on what what am I going to pick when there's
many results there inside of results.
And this itself is a list.
So I just want to pick one item at random from that list.
So for example here result's goes all the way down to here.
Pick one thing.
So just specified choice of Rez results.
And notice I'm using this variable in more than one place.
It would be better in my opinion to refactor this to make a variable called results equals rez results.
So cut that put that there.
And then here I can just access that results variable because I'm using it in two places.
So all I'm doing is just saving into variable so I don't have to access that key value pair more than
once.
And then choice results if I print choice results just like this.
Let's see what we get.
I search for dog.
All right so I just picked one.
What did the dog say to the two trees bark bark.
Same thing for you.
Again we get a different joke.
Why did the cowboy have a wiener dog.
Someone told him to get a long little dog along.
Get along lawn chair get that one.
So we want to do now is access.
Joke.
We don't want to you know print out the ID and all that extra stuff.
We just want the joke and let's change this sort of thing.
There are many jokes let's be specific let's say I found I need to make this an F string.
And what is the number of jokes it's called No jokes so let's say something like I found three jokes
about.
And then the term that the user entered and then we'll say here's one.
And then print the joke on the next line and then let's do the same thing here and string.
I found one joke about and then put in user input OK let's just test it.
I'll start by clearing my screen.
Let's look for Katz says I found five.
Oh I need to put joke five about cat.
Here's one.
Put the cat out.
I didn't realize she's on fire.
Dog found eight.
About dog here's one.
My dog used to chase people on a bike a lot.
So I had to take his bike away and then search for something that doesn't exist.
Sorry I couldn't find a joke with your term.
Cool.
So let me just fix this an ad I found Gnome jokes and put the word jokes in there.
And that's pretty much it for the base functionality.
And then if we wanted to just print a little header up top.
Remember we just want to import.
What was it called pi figured out like that and then we'll make a variable called hetter equals and
it's Pi dot and I'm just trying to remember this.
I think it's fuckwitt format.
And then let's do dad joke 3000 or something.
So tell you what you want to call it and we can just print the head or at the very beginning.
OK.
It works.
And let's look for the jokes about dad.
Oops 16.
And to make it colored we could also do imports term color and all we want actually from that is from
term color.
Import colored and to make that we'll just say header equals colored version of Hetter and then let's
set color to be magenta.
My favorite Well close to purple and then will print Hetter see if it works cool.
It works.
A little change we can make is just do a from Piglet for piglet format import figment that I called
it piglet format PI Feigley.
Geez.
OK.
And then here we can just change that down to figure that format.
Also a common question is if we should put these on the same line or not.
And according to the most common Python style guide to actually preferred to put them on separate lines
just make sure I didn't break anything.
Try it one more time.
OK.
Everything looks good do kitten.
You're kidding.
Nope no kidding jokes.
All right.
So that's that.
You know we could put this in different functions but it's pretty short as far as you know.
Twenty eight lines or so.
I don't think it really warrants wrapping things up into different functions but you totally could.