Hey I'm back here just inserting this between videos because I realized I never showed that you could
have multiple lifts.
And in fact you can have as many as you want in a single conditional statement.
So you need to have one if no matter what.
It's optional to have an else at the end but you can only have one because it's a catchall you know
otherwise.
But in between we can have as many Ellefson or else ifs as we want.
So here's an example that asks for.
What's your favorite color.
And if the user says purple the clear best color.
You know it's not even up for debate.
We print.
Excellent choice.
But then we have an else if so if this was not true.
Is this true color equal to teal if it is we print not bad.
But if it's not true.
Move on.
Try this one is color equal to seafoam will print mediocre.
If that's false color equal to pure darkness.
Well print.
I like how you think if people pick pure darknesses or color.
Great.
And then else otherwise we'll print you monster.
So let's quickly try it out.
I have a file called logic up.
Why.
So what's your favorite color.
Start with purple.
Excellent choice.
How about blue.
We get ALS because we didn't have an F or Aliff so it triggers the else let's do it again and this time
till this time we'll do pure darkness.
That's my favorite color.
I need to actually hit enter on the file first.
Now we can try pure darkness.
I was so so fixated on spelling that correctly.
I like how you think.
And then finally I think we're missing Seafoam.
And spell it correctly as you can see.
So I got you monster but just for the sake of being complete.
Here Seafoam.
There we go.
Mediocre.
And that about sums up this video.
Mediocre but it's good to know you can have multiple elf's right.