Hello it's called again still here I haven't totally lost my mind yet.
And in this video we're talking about set comprehension.
So I kind of like it in the video by saying that there was only two videos on set.
I kind of made the decision halfway through the video that it was getting too long and that it would
be better to split it.
So alas here we are with three set videos.
I'm sorry for deceiving you set comprehension.
It's the same idea behind list comprehension and dictionary comprehension in that we can very rapidly
create sets using sort of a shortcut notation.
We can copy set or manipulate them and make new versions where we you know operate on each item in the
set.
So here is a simple example.
Notice we use curly braces just like we did for dictionaries but there's a key difference.
We don't actually specify a key colon value we only specify one thing so it's not neither the key nor
the value because it's not a dictionary it's a set.
So it's just the item in the set.
So in this case x squared for x in range 10.
So that's going to go from zero up to 9 and square at each time and add it to the set and you can see
that there's no order.
Still it is a set and we go to your 164 4:36.
However that's established.
I don't know.
Let's test it out.
There we go.
That's our first simple set comprehension.
And just to showcase the difference just by doing this here X colon x squared for x in range what do
we get.
Now we get a dictionary.
As you can see here where we have you know a key of two.
And the value is two squared.
You have a key of three and the value is three squared which is nine and all the way up.
So just by adding the key colon then we end up with a dictionary.
But if we only have one piece of information it assumes that it's a set.
So here's another example let's do char upper.
Just like that for char in and then we'll do a string but this string will have some duplicate.
So let's do you know hello like that.
There's two L's.
What do we end up with.
Well we end up with one of each character upper case.
So because it's a set those duplicates are not allowed and also the order is all messed up.
So I have one more example and this one might be a bit scary.
This is actually a function which we haven't learned about yet but I put it here because it's where
we're going next.
So in the next section we'll be able to make more sense of this but what this does is it takes a given
string whatever we pass in any string and it will return true or false depending on if that string contains
all of the vowels.
Oh and you all of them not just one has to contain all of them and if it does it returns true.
But to start let's just analyze this bulk of the logic.
None of the functions syntax will come back to that.
So let's define a string first.
We'll just call it string and let's start with.
Sure.
Hello.
That's fine and then most Take a look at what's happening here.
And let's even simplify this more and just focus on the set comprehension.
So what's happening.
OK we are creating a set character for each character in string.
If the character is in a I O or you so we're basically just pulling out the vowels from a word into
a set and you can see from this string we end up with E and O.
Those are the only two vowels.
And you know we could change string to be.
Ha ha ha.
And if we rerun this take each character put it in a set.
If it's one of these we end up with a e n o.
So to tell if a string contains all five vowels we could just use this exact same logic but check if
the length of this resulting set is equal to 5.
So in this case if we just do Lenn of that X that same set comprehension we end up with three.
And we want to check if it's equal to 5 if it equals five.
It means it contains whatever the string is contains every single vowel.
So a word that does contain all five vowels is my absolute favorite tree on earth.
The sequoia tree.
So we can do string equals.
See if I can spell it correctly it's just a jumble of vowels at the end.
If you haven't seen these trees online check them out.
Pictures don't really do them justice.
They are so massive.
They are the largest living things on earth.
If you are able to see them if you live anywhere near California or you're out here at some point definitely
check them out.
They're so awesome.
Like you said pictures do not do it justice.
You just have to be there.
It's pretty inspiring.
OK.
More importantly this is a word that contains all the vowels.
So now if I try this we get true.
Because if we look at what set is generated it contains all the vowels and we're checking if the length
of that set is five.
All right.
And with that we are done with sets.
Also done with tuples.
Let's just quickly review what we covered so tuples or tuples are ordered collections of elements and
they are immutable meaning they do not change.
You make them and you leave him how they are.
And again there is an order.
Tuples are faster than less and they're useful sets however are unordered collections of unique values.
So there is no order guaranteed no order at all and they are not commutable.
We can add and remove using the method add and remove sets and tuples can be created either with the
curly braces and parents or the set or tuple function respectively and finally set comprehension is
something we can do.
It's useful if we're trying to convert other data types to a set like we saw we converted a string to
a set by pulling out the vowels or we could convert a range to a set and so forth.
So that's it for tuples and sets.
And now we get to move on to a big important exciting awesome topic called functions.
So I'll see you then in the next section unless you quit but I hope you don't.