Another company use case of decorator's is to enforce certain restrictions on arguments.
For example I could make a decorator that prevented a function from being called with any keyword arguments
or I could prevent a function from being called with any numerical arguments or something like that.
Let's let's go with the first one.
So I want to I want to make something called I don't know and sure no quarks and then whatever function
I define afterwards when I execute it the decorated function.
If I pass in keyword arguments instead of just plain arguments then it should raise an error or it should
return early or something like that.
And to do this it's pretty straightforward.
First thing you should do is just define our decorator so def ensure no quires takes function.
Let's say you are boilerplate wraps Fannie-Freddie imported that and then define our wrapper whatever
you want to call that with args and quires and then all we really want to do is just check if there
are any quires then what what to do it's up to us.
But for now we can just raise an error or we can print.
Let's raise I think a value error would be best.
We could create our own exception if we inherit from the base exception but let's just do this and just
say no core is allowed.
Sorry not a very professional error message and then Otherwise we'll just a simple return F.A. and we
need to just pass in args and quarks and then finally return proper and we should be good.
Let's test it out down here.
So let's just define a really simple function called Let's go with greet and greet just takes a name
and then all we're going to do is print enough string.
Hi there and then.
Name OK and in front of it.
Well put in sure no quarks.
So now when I call greet if I do something like greet Tony that should work fine.
Let's also use this as a check for any syntax errors.
Lord knows I probably have one.
Nope it worked.
Of course the one time and then if I tried to do instead.
Name equals Tony.
Using a keyword argument.
Perfect.
We hit the value error so we now have come up with a way of ensuring no keyword arguments with this
decorator so we could use the same idea to ensure you know a certain type for all arguments to ensure
that certain arguments exist.
There's there's different things that we can do and actually show you another example in the next video
where we can ensure that the first argument is something.
But we're going to make a dynamic decorator one that we can actually pass something into.
So we could say ensure first arg and then I could pass in.
I don't know what would be the first.
The first arg is burrito or something.
So that's coming up next.
But for now we have to find another decorator that helps us just ensure there is no keyword arguments
in a given function.