A Welcome Back in this video we're continuing with unit test.
We're not talking about particular assertions.
Instead I'm going to show you some functionality some features that we get with unit tests that are
really really useful when you're testing larger applications.
Oftentimes you have code that you need to run before tests or after all your tests whether that's having
to do with the database you know adding data to a database or creating fake data that you want to use
and all of your tests create a fake user account and you want to instead of recreating it in every single
test function you want it to be available everywhere.
We can define two methods called set up and tear down.
They do have to be named in a particular way.
And like you said in a larger application you might want some similar code to run before every test
so you put that code in setup and it runs before every test method.
Similarly if you have code you want to run after all your tests which if you're not using a database
is probably not that common.
And in our situation we're just going to focus on setup.
But imagine you are testing something with the database and you add a bunch of data into the database
for your tests.
You don't want to just keep it there if you call tear down.
It will remove it after every test.
So that's what they're done does.
So it's common use cases like I said removing or adding data from a test database or creating instances
of a class that you're going to reuse creating some data whether it's not whether it's in a database
or not just data that you want to use in your tests.
So here's an example.
None of these.
This doesn't do anything but we have these two tests tests first and test second.
But then we have set up and tear down.
And if they're named correctly inside of this test you know in a class that inherits from test case
whatever we put in here it's going to run before the code and test first and before the code and test
second and whatevers and tear down it we'll run after test first and after test second.
So to help explain this I have a class called Robot and I've already typed it up.
Doesn't really matter too much the details don't matter.
But it's a class called Robot.
Every robot has a name a battery level which is a number and a list of skills.
There's a method called charge where we just set self-taught battery to be 100 fully charged the battery
and then we have two methods that have different results different outcome depending on the charge of
the battery.
So to say when we say name if self battery is positive we're going to return beep boop boop.
I am self-taught name uppercase and subtract one decrement self-doubt battery.
It takes one battery to say name and if battery is negative we return low power police charge and try
again.
Similarly I might add some space with learned skill you pass in a skill to learn and it cost to learn
it and then recheck is cost to learn a lesson or it's battery greater than or equal to the cost to learn
if it is.
Then we subtract the cost to the end for the battery and we append skills to Penda new skilled skills.
Then we return.
So I now know whatever the skill is how to make a sandwich.
Otherwise we return insufficient battery please charge and try again.
Ok so very basic robot class.
Now that's right a few tests.
So I have a file called Robot tests why I'm importing robot from the robot file.
I just named them both.
The file is robot up.
Classes robot import unit test to find my class inherits from test case.
And let's start by testing the charge method.
So we do def test charge and to test that we're going to need to make a new robot.
So let's go with I don't know.
Megaman equals robot.
Oh and I do need to capitalize this.
That's the name of the class.
OK.
So well just passen name is Megaman.
And let's say battery is set to 50 at the beginning.
So what I want to do is call mega-event charge and then test that charge that charge is now 100.
So I would just do self-taught assert equal megaman dot and I'd check for battery Khama 100 and this
should work right.
That's how the method is set up right now.
Let's test it.
Yes.
Passing that's all good knowledge.
Add one to test say name.
I should mention we're not doing this TDD style.
I already wrote all the code that just to save time.
OK.
We want to test this.
Let's go back here and do the same thing again.
A def test say name.
And then here we're going to do the same thing make a new robot because we have to have a robot to test
because this is a function of whatever code is in here is scope's to this.
So we don't have access to it.
We have to redefine it down here.
OK.
So I make that again and then I'm just going to do a self-taught assert equal when I call Mega Man say
name.
I'm just going to copy the string here.
We should get it to be poop.
I am mega man in all caps pasted in.
But this on new lines people pee poop.
I am and then we replace this with Mega Man like that.
OK.
And on top of that we also want to check that the battery has gone down.
So that should be megaman dot battery should now equal 49.
Let's see if it works.
A robot has no X right now.
Tests say name that should be say name
and we need to run say name as well.
All right.
So this is how this should work.
Make new make a man make new robot we call say name it should equal this.
And after that happened the battery should have gone down.
And it works so I won't make you sit through watching me test all the other functions.
But if I wanted to test learn skill I would have to write well I would test another say name I would
test if battery was too low so would be another function then I would test learn skill.
If battery was too low to learn this skill or if there was enough battery to learn the skill.
So that's three different times three different functions at a bare minimum that I would be defining
and I'd make megaman again.
Instead however we can use setup to help us out.
And you might be thinking couldn't I just you know do this megaman appear and all of them had access
Megaman.
That is true.
That works.
But there's a difference because whatever side effects that happen this code would alter megaman and
every other test function we have would be using the exact same copy of this robot.
So if we set the battery to zero then I write another function to test that the battery should be full.
If it was already set to zero in the previous test function it's still going to be zero.
So with set up it really runs the code every time it doesn't run it want to rerun it before every function.
So I just write.
Def set up like this camel case itself and then we'll just use self-taught megaman equals and just copy
this just like that.
Now what we can do is reference self-taught megaman in all of these instances so I mean just copying
my cursor a couple times so it doesn't need to be self-doubt megaman but this code now has will run
before every single function and I can now get rid of this.
And this is well where I'm defining megaman Let's see if it works.
Awesome.
OK.
So you can imagine hopefully you know if we actually wrote tests for all the other functions and we
let's say we had you know 10 functions in that class we could be rerunning the same code a lot.
So set up is really really useful and tear down it's exactly the same except it runs after each one
of our test functions.
That's pretty much all there is to it set up.
You don't find it that way.
It must be called set up tear down must be called tear down unit test.
Looks for them automatically and it runs them you know before and after each test case respectively.