All right.
Time for another exercise here.
This is just a note to myself Here we go.
This exercise is going to combine for loops and ranges along with a little bit of conditional logic
so it's more complex than what we just did.
So the idea is that you're going to loop through.
Why do I do this.
I don't know why I put that on the separate that might be an accident.
Anyway you're going to loop through the numbers one through 20 and for each I should mention it's inclusive.
So it includes 20 and 1 and you get to loop through them and you're going to go through each and if
the number is four or the number is 13 you're going to print X is unlucky.
So 13 at least in the U.S. is considered unlucky and an 0 4 is unlucky in Chinese culture.
So if there's another number in your culture between 1 and 20 percent x is unlucky for it.
And if the numbers even print X even if numbers odd print X is odd So the results would look like this
one is odd to is even three is odd for as I'm lucky you don't have to do all caps five is odd six and
even so on 13 is unlucky down to 20 is even and we only do one thing for each number.
So you know four is both unlucky and even but we only printout out unlucky we don't pronounce even part.
OK so give it a shot the numbers 1 through 20 including 20.
I'll do another pause video.
Where's that thing.
Twan pause a video out there we go.
And in like three seconds I'll be back.
And surprise.
I'm back.
So let's go ahead and make a new file this one I'll just call.
I don't know numbers.
Why.
Maybe you can come up with something better.
And we're going to start but just printing the numbers 1 through 20.
So we're going to do for them in a range and the range that we want is from 1 to 20.
But remember that Xclusive.
So it doesn't include 20.
So if we just printed numb just like this and do Python 3 numbers up why it goes from 1 to 19.
So we need to add one here and go to 21
and make sure that works 1 through 20.
OK so now we're going to need to do is add a bit of conditional logic so we can start off with even
and odd.
And if you don't remember how to figure out if something is even in python we need to use modulo the
percent sign.
So that's also the remainder operator.
So any even number like 4 or 6.
When we mide to when we divide by 2 there should be no remainder meaning for mod 2 0.
So whatever the number is if it's divisible by 2 that number percent 2 is going to be zero.
So we can add a conditional.
So if the number divided are the number divided by two has no remainder.
That means it's even.
So we can start with this and we'll just do print and let's do an F string numb it even and let's just
start there.
Make sure that that's working.
OK.
So we get two four six eight 10 all the way down to 20 is even none of the odds are printing out.
So we could just add a simple else and I'll just copy this line here and replace it with odd because
there's only one choice.
If you're not even you're going to be odd.
And if I do this now we get one it's odd to is even all the way down to the last thing we have to add
is making sure that 4 and 13 are printed out as unlucky.
And what we want to do there is basically just check is the number equal of four or is it equal to 13
and we could we could add an elf like this and or we could do a separate statement.
Maybe we'll start with that.
Let's do a separate if and we'll just say if number is equal equal to 4 or is equal to what was the
other 13 then we'll print and just copy this again.
Numb is on life.
And if we ran this now what do you think we'll see.
Well what we actually get is for is even and for is unlucky or we get 13 as odd and 13 is unlucky we
don't want that.
So we can't have this be a separate statement and we can't put it as an elf because if we didn't.
Elif Well we'll see what happens.
Now let me just modify that and just pasted in.
You can probably imagine what's going to happen.
It will work one time but it won't work the other.
So you can see that for four.
We get fours even but we don't get four is unlucky.
But for 13 we get 13 is unlucky.
What's happening is that it's going in order.
So the first thing it checks is the number even.
So in the case of 4 it is even so Prince this one.
And because these are lips and else's they don't run unless the first one is false.
So in the case of 13 which is not even this is false then this is true.
So what we want to do is just move this check up top and do this first.
That's this special case that we're going to check first and then we'll check if it's even and we could
have gone the other way around and checked for the first where.
Now I'm mad to need to be equal to one.
The remainder mud modding by two on an odd number is always one.
OK let's see.
Now we get one is odd twos even three is odd four is unlucky.
All the way down to 13 is unlucky down to 20 is even.
Everything looks good.
OK.
So we're looping through numbers.
We had to adjust this to be 21 because it's Xclusive.
So that's how we get one to 20.
Also we needed to be very careful about the order we put these statements in or at least the first one
because something like four is both unlucky and even or 13 is both unlucky and odd.
We only want the unlucky to print out if you got this far.
Great.
That's a solution.
But there's a there's a change we could make and it's really a matter of opinion.
If you think that this is better or not but I'm going to just comment that out and duplicate this and
the change that the thing that some people might take issue with is how we have three different print
statements and they're basically doing the exact same thing.
They're printing out some is and then some status or some you know state for nothing.
So it follows the same pattern.
So what we could do instead is just have one print statement at the end and make a variable like state
or status or type.
And we don't even need to declare it first.
We could just do this.
If numbers for numbers 13 will say state equals unlucky
if it's even here.
Number two is zero will say state is even.
And then finally we'll say state is equal to odd.
Then we'll dent the print statement and we'll edit it so that it prints that print.
Numb is state.
So it assigns a state variable to be either unlucky even or odd.
And then at the end outside of the conditional still in the loop we're going to print the number three
is state which would be odd in that case.
And if we run this one we get the exact same result.
So it's really a matter of opinion.
Some people might gauge their code by how short it is.
So in this case you know this is an extra line.
But if you look at our print statements there so much less duplication.
This one is kind of following a cookie cutter pattern and anytime you see that that's often a place
where you can refactor your code make it a little bit better.
So this is my personal preference but that doesn't mean that it's necessarily better.
It is really a matter of opinion.
They both work and neither of them is clumsy or hideous.
Aside from the fact that they don't do anything useful and it's really silly exercise.
OK.