Hey welcome back.
So we have two other commands to quickly cover that have to do with removing files and removing folders
or directories.
Neither of these are going to be essential.
Just like you know creating a file you could do that using your text editor.
You can drag and drop files and folders to the recycling bin to remove them.
I think you can also right click and delete them.
But just to be consistent with what I showed in the Mac section the Linux section I'm going to show
you how this works using command line using the power shell.
So the command is very simple to remove a single file r.m for a remove and then a space and the name
of the file.
Unfortunately to remove a directory it is a little more complex.
We have to run this command Ahram.
But we also have to tack on dash our dash f o.
So the dash R means recursive.
If you're not familiar with recursion just think of it as it's telling Power Shell to delete everything
inside of that folder and any potential contents of sub folders and keep going all the way down until
it's totally empty.
So instead of just deleting the first level delete every Buffle afterwards and then the dash F O stands
for force which is telling it to prevent warnings.
Just go.
Just delete it.
So you do have to be pretty careful with this command.
It is dangerous if you ran this on your home directory or your root directory and you deleted that.
I'm not sure if it would allow you to delete your route.
I've never tried that.
I have no idea what would happen if you tried to delete some folder nothing is going to stop you.
It's just going to go and that's obviously very bad.
So just be careful with it.
Fortunately it is hard to type this right.
You're not going to accidentally type Ahram and space dash or space dash F O and then the name for directory.
But you just want to be careful anyway.
Let's do a quick demonstration.
Look at Power Shell open here.
I've got the gooey here so you can just see in real time what happens.
If I didn't want this Swing's file for example you know I could drag it up there to the recycle bin
or I come over here make sure I'm in the same directory playground and type r.m space Swing's and it
disappears.
I type ls and it's gone.
It's no longer over here.
Also if I look in the recycling bin it's not in here.
It circumvents that it is gone gone.
So be careful.
That's r.m you know I can show you can delete another file called monkey bars.
There it goes to delete a folder as we saw first and need a folder to delete.
So let's delete the entire playground directory that has these two things in it.
And to do that it's r.m.
But then I need to do the dash.
Our dash f o.
And then this is where it could be dangerous if you typed Tildy for example or an absolute path to a
different directory and you hit enter.
It would delete it.
I've never tried it and I'm not going to verify.
I mean maybe there's some sort of protection that doesn't allow you to delete certain system folders.
I kind of doubt it though.
So be careful but we're going to type the name of that folder which is playground.
There we go.
So P tab will auto complete to dot backslash playground.
I hit enter and our window changes entirely because the folder I was in is gone for I type ls.
There is no longer a playground directory.
So that's it for deleting single files and deleting entire directories that directory playground only
had a couple of files in it.
But if it had 10 other sub folders nested in a hierarchy they all would be gone and whatever they had
inside would all be gone.
All right.
So if you're new to power shell into the command line in general this section could have been a bit
overwhelming.
I was very apprehensive about putting this the beginning of the course.
If you're new to this I think it could really be discouraging.
So please hang in there.
All you really need to know are Ls and PWT and CD and you can combine those three things especially
the CD in LS to move and to find a file so that we can eventually execute it.
Then you're golden.
You can do everything else using your Kuei using subcontext or whatever you want to use which will cover
in the next section.
After this here's a quick quiz which is just meant meant to enforce some of the things we learned.
You don't have to do it if you don't care about you know the details of creating and removing folders
and files.
Move on to installation.
Thank you for bearing with me.
I'll see you in the next section.