Let's learn about the last data structure in this course graphs.
Graphs are one of the most useful and most used data structures in computer science when it comes to
modeling real life.
In short, a graph is simply a set of values that are related in a pairwise fashion.
And you can see over here, it looks like a little network.
There's connections to different nodes.
In a graph.
Each item is called a node or a vertex.
So this is a node.
This is a node.
Nodes are then connected with edges.
So that's an edge.
That's an edge and that's an edge.
And as you can imagine, graphs are great data structures to model real world relationships representing
links graphs ideal for cases where you're working with things that connect to other things.
Kind of like how the internet works, right?
We can use graphs to represent maybe friendships, maybe family trees.
We can use graphs to represent networks and the World Wide Web, or we can use graphs to represent roads,
one city to another and the roads that connect it.
As you can imagine, Facebook uses it for their social network.
Amazon uses it for their recommendation engines, and Google Maps uses graphs for determining the shortest
path to where you want to go.
So let me ask you a question.
Do you think this is a graph?
Well, yeah, obviously, we just went through it.
What about this?
And this and this?
What about this one?
All right, finally this.
Just getting a few more.
This, this.
And this.
Yep.
They are all graphs, even this one.
That kind of looks like a linked list.
That's a graph.
And as you can see in our mind, map graphs and compass things that we've learned before, such as trees
and link lists.
Linked lists are a type of tree.
Trees are a type of graph.
So in the next couple of videos, let's learn all about graphs.