Welcome to the best part of landing a job.
You've done all the coding exercises you can do.
You've prepared for the interview.
You've done the interview.
You've answered all the questions.
And now you wait.
And hopefully you hear back with good news.
But the game doesn't really end there.
As a matter of fact, this is the fun part.
This is what you worked for.
And there's an easy, obvious way of going about it, which is not practicing and not learning how to
handle offers or negotiation or a bit of a harder way where we learn how to do these things properly
so that overall we're able to have higher salaries, work for better companies, and just overall be
more satisfied with our jobs.
So we're going to take some time in this section to learn these skills that, again, will allow you
to grow a lot faster and be more satisfied with your jobs.
Let's have a look at what are we going to talk about?
In this section, we're going to talk about how to handle an offer when after the interview, somebody
says, hey, congratulations, we want to work with you.
Here's your offer.
What do you do?
Do you just say yes?
What about handling multiple offers?
A lot of people don't talk about this, but when you're interviewing, most likely you're interviewing
at a lot of companies and most of the time you're not just getting one offer, you're getting multiple
ones.
How does this work and how can you actually use them to improve the actual offers that you get?
We're going to talk about an important topic of handling rejection.
We're all going to get rejected one day.
I don't think I've ever met anybody who's been accepted to every single job that they've applied for.
We're going to talk about getting a raise and how it's actually a lot simpler than you might think.
And obviously, we're going to be talking about negotiation and some of the negotiation tactics and
techniques that is going to help you throughout these other videos and other lessons to prepare you
for the real world.
So lots to cover.
It's going to be a fun one.
Let's get started.