Welcome to our last section on algorithms, the last missing piece, and that is dynamic programming.
Sounds very important, doesn't it?
With this section, we're going to go over the very last piece of our mind map to complete our entire
knowledge graph.
So we're ready for interviews.
It's this last little piece of dynamic programming, specifically memorization, that we're going to
be talking about.
But what is it?
Dynamic programming is just an optimization technique.
And here's the fun fact.
Dynamic programming actually means nothing.
It's completely garbage buzzword.
And I'm not kidding.
Here, I'll link to a funny article on how the name came to be, but dynamic programming at the end
of the day is just an optimization technique using something called caching.
If you have something that you can cash, well, then you can use dynamic programming.
Now we're going to get into the details of what that means throughout the next videos.
But at a high level, dynamic programming is a way to solve problems by breaking it down into a collection
of SOP problems, solving each of those problems just once, and storing their solutions in case next
time the same sub problem occurs.
But let's get into that and understand what it means, how we can implement it to become better interviewers,
better engineers and better programmers.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.