We've talked about recursion and sorting.
We have a few more to go.
And in this section we're going to talk about searching and traversal, including breadth first search
and depth for search.
Searching is something we do a lot on our computers.
When we talked about sorting, some of you may have been like, it doesn't really sound that useful,
but searching.
We use that every day, don't we?
We look for files on our computer.
We run command F and search for things, search for words and documents.
We search Google, we search YouTube.
We search hashtags on Twitter and Instagram.
Searching is a big part of our lives, but how are all these computers and programs able to search things
so fast?
There's more and more data in this world.
More and more websites to search for.
How were we able to do these things so fast?
How is Google able to do these things so fast?
Well, in this section, we're going to build this foundation of how it all works.
And we're going to be talking about a few types of searching and traversal.
And hopefully by the end of it all, you're going to understand how places like Facebook, Google and
Google Maps work when it comes to searching at a fundamental level.
Let's get started.