Woo hoo!
It's finally time to learn our very first data structure and one that most likely you're very familiar
with.
Arrays.
Arrays which are sometimes called lists.
Organizes items sequentially.
That means one after another in memory.
Kind of like we have here.
We have some sort of data to index zero, let's say juice.
And then right after at index one, we have something else.
Maybe apple.
Maybe this is a grocery list in our computers memory.
It'll be one after another.
Because, remember, our RAM is a lot bigger than just seven slots.
And the Rays are probably the simplest and most widely used data structures.
And luckily for us, we're starting with this because arrays have the least amount of rules and because
they're stored in contiguous memory, that is in order.
They also have the smallest footprint of any data structure.
So if all you need is to store some data and iterate over it, that is go one by one, step by step.
Arrays are the best choice.
Especially if, you know the indices that is here on the left of the items you're storing.
And just as a quick glance and we'll go over this in more detail in later videos.
But lookup or access with arrays are constant time of one.
It's super, super fast.
Other actions or methods that we're going to go over such as push, are also fast, but then inserts
and deletes are o of n or linear time.
But in order to demonstrate arrays, let's actually use code to show you an example.
We have our little playground over here.
And again, you can use whichever language you prefer.
I'm just going to demonstrate this in JavaScript.
We can create.
A simple.
Array, let's call it strings.
And this array again using the square bracket notation.
We'll have a then be.
Then C and D.
And we just we've just created an array in JavaScript.
Now looking at this and based on what we've learned so far, we can make a couple of assumptions.
For example, to store the letter A, letter B, letter C, letter D, that's one, two, three, four,
four items.
If we were on a 32 bit system, that is we have one, two, three, four shelves to store the letter
A in zeros and ones.
Well, if that's the case, we just multiply four times four.
So four items and each item taking up for shelves in our memory.
That means we're using up 20 or 16.
Bites.
Of storage.
If we remember in our little example here that with a 32 bit system, we have one, two, three, four
shelves to store this.
This number.
Again, this is a bit of a simplified version of looking at it, but I hope you see what we're doing
here.
We're simply storing a BCD in sequential order in our RAM, our random access memory.
So the computer now knows where to find these items.
Therefore, when I do strings to.
I'm telling the computer, hey, go to the array called strings.
You should know where that is, because underneath the hood, you stored it for me.
And grab the third item.
Remember, the indexes are 012.
So grab the third item from where the array is stored on your memory.
And if I run this, I'll get C.
The computer is going to grab that information for me because here it stored it for me and here it's
grabbing it for me.
All right.
So let's do a few more operations with arrays and see what the pros and cons are.
Well in JavaScript we have a few methods that we can use with the race.
One is push, which simply allows us to add something at the end of the array.
So strings dot.
Push.
E.
And if we just remove this and let's have a console log of strings.
If I run this, I get a, b, c, d, e.
This string push operation because it just adds it at the end of the array.
Is an oh one operation.
All we're doing is adding whatever item we want at the end.
We're not looping through anything, so hopefully that makes sense.
Why?
That would be one that's very convenient.
What's another method that we get?
We can also use Pop.
And pop is the opposite of push.
Pop will simply mean to remove the last item.
From the strengths from the array.
If I click run here, you see that the E was moved if I do strings dot pop.
Again.
And Hit Run.
We see that this time around we've added E, then we removed E, and then finally D to be left with
A, B and C.
What do you think the time complexity of this operation is?
Once again, it's zero of one because we're not looping through anything.
We're just removing the last item.
And remember, our computer knows where last item is stored.
We're simply saying.
Go to index of, let's say, seven, the very last item and remove the bread.
Well, let's do something interesting here now.
What if we want to add an item at the beginning of the array?
Maybe in here we want to add the letter X.
Well, we have something called on shift in JavaScript.
And depending on your language, you'll have perhaps something different.
But the idea here is we simply do strings dot on shift.
And by the way, you see here how Ripple died.
It actually gives you the parameters that you can enter.
In this case, it just says what items, which is a string should I enter?
In our case I'll say I want to shift x, which is saying just add x at the beginning of the array.
If I click run here we see that X has been added at the beginning of our array.
What do you think the time complexity of this operation is?
And by the way, as we go through data structures and because we know big o notation, isn't it pretty
cool that we're able to think about code beyond just, Oh, I'm just doing this.
We can think deeply about what's happening underneath the hood.
Why might this operation be longer than this operation?
I find that fascinating.
And when I first understood this point, it really made me a better engineer.
And I hope you're starting to get this aha moment for you as well, especially if this is your first
time with data structures.
Now on shift.
What are we doing here?
Well, remember, strings are essentially stored.
If I move this to a new line.
The computer knows that this is a zero.
This is at index of one.
This is an index of two.
And this is at index of three when I add X with the on shift.
I'm all of a sudden adding X into our array.
But we now have to shift these numbers.
Because the indexes are still like this.
But this time around we have to say, okay, zero is now at X, A is now one, B is now two and C is
that index three and DX is that index for.
And just by me doing this, you might have seen something.
We just iterated loop through everything and reassigned the indexes.
And I did one, two, three, four, five moves or five operations to realign the indexes.
And this should give you a hint that is, this operation is over.
And depending on the size of the array.
That's how long it's going to take to do that operation we're looping.
So right away, we know that with the race, maybe it's not the best data structure for adding items
at the beginning of the array.
What if we wanted to add something in the middle of the array so we can use the method splice here?
Let me scroll down a bit and with splice I can say strings, dot, splice.
And again.
I get a hint of what I can do.
The first is the start number.
So I want to start at index of two and remember we have this array here X, A, B, C, so we're starting
at B.
And the second parameter is the delete count.
What do we want to delete or how many things from this index do we want to delete?
In our case, we don't want to delete anything.
We just want to add.
So I'll say zero and then the items that we want to add.
So let's just add a string that says Alien.
Oh, and let's remove this X from our original array.
That's better.
Let's hit, run.
And there we go.
We have X because we've shifted A, then alien b c.
So Splice told us go to index of 2012 where B was initially and ad alien instead of B and just shift
things over.
So what we've done here is if we go back to our example.
We have the.
X.
In Ray.
And we shift it these indexes of X.
And A are still the same, but we shifted B over and said, in here I want you to add Alien.
And we now have to go over everything and say to four alien, we want three for B, four for C and five
for D.
So what's our big O here?
We don't need this comma.
Well, our big O in this case, we did half of the operations because we changed.
Half the array.
We loop through half the array, so it would be zero of and divided by two.
But remember our rules when it comes to big o, we remove constants and simplify to just oh n worst
case it's going to be o of an operation.
All right.
I'm going to leave this for you so I can play around and try different methods on a race.
But I hope you understand how they work and how there's some good things that we can do, such as accessing
the array that is.
Of one because it's, well, extremely fast.
We know exactly where it is in memory.
We can push and pop, but when it comes to shifting or splicing or even deleting because with Splice
we can even do deletes, that's going to be zero even.
And if we go back to our chart.
We should now have a better understanding of why Erased lookups are extremely fast.
We know where they are.
We know why.
Push adding at the end of the array is extremely fast, but why?
Inserting and deleting might not be the best or the fastest when it comes to erase.
But here's the thing.
There's actually two types of arrays.
And in the next video, we're going to talk about these two types.
I'll see you in that one.