Welcome back.
I want to show you one of my favorite coding challenges that happens every year.
Every Christmas in December, there's something called advent of code.
And if you Google advent of code, you'll see that, well, the 2017 version comes.
But based on when you're watching the video, there will be the 2018 version.
But you can also go back in time and do the previous years.
If I go to 2016, we see our 2016 version.
Now as a community, our zero to Mastery community on Discord.
Every December we tackle this challenge and try to solve coding problems for 25 days straight.
And these are, in my opinion, some of the best logical problems they can solve with code.
They're really, really good.
And they get harder and harder each day.
But the fun thing is that you'll have a community of people to do it with.
And as you can see here, there's subreddits, there's hacker news communities that work together and
our own community where we compare each other's code, see who came up with what solution.
So I encourage you to do this even if it is in December, but get ready because in December we're going
to be doing this challenge together every December as a community.
Happy advent of code.