Welcome back.
As I mentioned in the previous video, there are actually two types of arrays.
One is called static and the other dynamic arrays.
Now, what is the difference between the two?
Well, the one limitation of static arrays.
Is that they're fixed in size, meaning you need to specify the number of elements your array will hold
ahead of time.
So in this case, if this was a static array, I would say create an array of seven items knowing beforehand
that in my grocery list I'm only going to have max seven.
Items.
Because arrays are allocated in adjacent blocks of memory when they're created.
There's no guarantee that after we've allocated seven shelves of memory that you can keep adding things
on, especially in order.
We solve this problem with static arrays that require us to say ahead of time, Hey, I only want seven
shelves of memory with dynamic arrays.
And dynamic arrays allow us to copy and rebuild an array at a new location, which with more memory
if we wanted more memory.
So for example, with our static array, if we realize that we forgot another item on our list and we
need eight items, what happens is we copy this entire array.
We allocate 14 blocks of memory.
And paste this list, plus the eighth item into that new location.
Let me show you how this works with code.
You see in languages like C++.
Let me scroll down over here in C++, which has static arrays to create an array.
You do something like this.
You'd say it.
A.
And this says, I want an array that has space of 20 items.
Or you can do something like Aunt Be.
Five.
And then fill up the array of five items with one, two, three, four, five integers.
That's what stands for numbers.
And because of this and because this is a static array, in order for us to add a six item on here,
well, we would need to copy this entire array and move it over to completely different area of memory
in order to create the space for it.
Now, luckily for us, when I showed you with JavaScript how to do this.
Well, we never had to worry about it, did we?
In our JavaScript example, we never really allocate a memory.
And that's because in JavaScript and other languages like Python, where you have lists and ArrayList
in Java, they work like dynamic arrays.
They automatically allocate memory.
According to the increase in size of the array.
So right off the bat, you're thinking dynamic arrays are way better, easier.
I don't have to think about memory because of automatic resizing.
And that gets into a discussion of managing memory which low level languages like C++ allow, while
higher level languages like JavaScript allow us to not think about memory and let the machine take care
of it for you.
There's times where maybe you do want to manage your memory and times where you don't need to based
on your needs.
Obviously, having more control over memory allows you to really tweak things and make things faster.
And that's why languages like C++ can be much faster than higher languages, higher level languages
like JavaScript.
But we don't need to get into that.
What we want to get out of this lesson is that dynamic array expands as you add more elements, so you
don't need to determine the size ahead of time.
But you may have noticed something with dynamic arrays.
You see over here how I have a pent at of one that is the same as the push command that we did in the
previous lesson.
But I have a star here that says it can be o n.
Why is that?
Well.
If we remember our array and let's remove the extra items here that we don't need.
So just say ABCD.
If underneath the hood JavaScript and our machine only created four blocks of memory for this array
and we add another.
Letter underneath the hood because this is a dynamic array.
It's going to loop over these items, copy them and move it to a different location with now eight blocks
of space.
So that we can keep adding onto here.
And you see here because we did this looping the operation becomes of an.
So that's something to keep in mind, although it's a minor detail, it's good to know how things work
underneath the hood and most of the time with the languages that you're working and during interviews,
you will be talking about dynamic arrays and you won't have to worry about allocating memory and thinking
about the possibility that you might have to copy the array.
That's really low level, but I wanted to show you how they work so that you have those fundamentals
going forward.
And I understand that when it comes to arrays, just because you're adding at the end using the push
command, you can assume that it's o of one most of the times or constant time.
But every once in a while you might encounter a situation where it's of n linear time.
I'll see you in the next video.