If you never ask, the answer is always no.
You should value yourself.
Most importantly, you should value the fact that you are giving your most precious resource.
That is time to an employer.
Make the right choice when selecting employers.
It is as much about what you want as it is about what they want.
Work for a company that respects your time.
Otherwise, why would you want to be there?
Good luck out there and thank you for being part of the course and the community and for supporting
my work.
I promise to create content that is not just for marketing, but that actually improves your skills.
I hope you keep following me in this journey and I hope you have a successful career.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.