Welcome back.
We're now into the tree data structure section right over here.
And as you can see, trees or length lists are a type of a tree that we've already talked about.
But there's a few others over here that we have yet to talk about.
So we're going to cover that and get familiar with the main different types by starting off with binary
tree.
Let's get into it.
A binary tree is something you've likely seen before, and it's a type of tree with a few rules that
are applied to it, but they're quite straightforward.
Each node can only have either zero one or two nodes, and each child can only have one parent.
This is a binary tree.
However, this is not a binary tree because it has three children, or at least one of the nodes has
three children.
And each node represents a certain state.
And this is very similar to what we've done in the past, especially with link lists.
If we take a look at an example here, in order for me to create a binary tree, well, I can just create
a function.
Say, binary tree.
And this binary tree perhaps will get a value.
And the binary tree, or in our case, let's just do a binary tree node will simply have a this dot
value associated with it, which is the value that we give it inside of the function.
And then we have two other properties, which is a pointer to the left side of the tree, which for
now will be null and a pointer to the right side of the tree.
That is this dot right equals.
No.
And that's it.
We can represent a binary tree node as simply having a value and then a left and or right property,
very similar to what we did, or a very similar principle to what we did with link lists.
Now we're going to actually code a tree and create a tree data structure, just like we have for past
data structures.
But I want to also point out a few terminology that we might come across and that are important.
In this case, we're looking at something called a tree that is completely full.
That means there are no gaps in the tree.
Let me show you what I mean.
A perfect binary tree has everything filled in.
That means all the leaf nodes are full and there's no node that only has one child.
A node either has zero children or two children, and also the bottom layer of the tree is completely
filled.
Nothing's missing versus a full binary tree, which simply says that a node has either zero or two children,
but never one child.
Now, why is this important?
Because this type of binary tree, especially a perfect binary tree, is really, really efficient and
something that is desirable.
When binary trees are perfect like this, they have two really interesting properties.
One is that the number of total nodes on each level doubles as we move down the tree.
For example, here we have one node and the next level we have two.
So we've just doubled the nodes.
And the next level we have one, two, three, four.
So we've doubled 2 to 4.
If we had another level, that's a perfect binary tree, we'd have one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight.
So we were doubling every time.
The second important property is that the number of nodes on the last level is equal to the sum of the
number of nodes on all the other levels plus one.
All right.
That was confusing.
What do I mean?
Well, here.
If I take the bottom level, that is one, two, three, four.
The second property states that all the nodes above it plus one is going to equal the bottom level.
So one, two, three plus one equals four.
That is what we had on the bottom, which means, in other words, that about half of our nodes are
on the last level.
And this brings up a really interesting point.
By organizing our data in this way.
We have half of this data in the bottom level.
If somehow we can avoid visiting every node, even if the node we're looking for is at the very bottom.
Perhaps there is some efficiencies that we can have.
And you'd be right.
Because of this type of structure, you're going to see a new notation of big O, something that we've
been waiting for a long time o log.
N And when we start talking about something called binary search trees, you're going to start seeing
this notation.
Yes, we finally got into another big notation.
But what does it mean?
In the next video I want to talk about O, log n and why trees allow us to have something like this
and what the implications are.
I'll see you the next one.
Bye bye.