Even the greatest of engineers sometimes get rejected, just like in dating.
Sometimes two of the greatest people in the world may not be the right fit for each other.
Rejections don't really mean anything, especially when it comes to interviewing.
Because nobody really cares about the rejection, doesn't go on your resume.
It doesn't go in your LinkedIn profile.
It just disappears once you get rejected.
You see winners and people that are good at interviewing just get up after a rejection and go on and
keep swinging.
I'm using a baseball reference here.
I hope people understand.
So here's the fun fact.
I myself got rejected from numerous jobs.
Does that make me a bad coder?
Does that make me a bad employee?
I mean, maybe.
But it also means that it wasn't the right fit for one another.
It's probably good that they rejected me because I probably wouldn't have enjoyed working for them or
I wouldn't have gotten the jobs that I had if I wasn't rejected by the previous ones.
You see, rejections are never a predictor of success.
99 rejections and one offer is better than two rejections and no offer.
So it's all a statistic game.
All you need to do is go out and bat.
Go swing.
Get interviews.
And no matter how many times you're rejected, all you need is that one.
And if you get more than one, that's just the bonus.
So when you get rejected, see if we can extract as much information or feedback as possible from the
company.
Tell them that you're constantly looking to improve and that you love some feedback.
I mean, they already rejected you.
What's the harm in asking?
Might as well get some information out of it and then finally ask them when it would be okay to reapply
if you're still interested down the road.
You see, I know a few people who have been rejected by numerous companies and they just kept applying
and eventually got hired.
Actually no person working at Google who did exactly that.
So don't burn any bridges.
Just ask them when you can apply again.
Just remember, think about how much of our life we actually spend searching for jobs versus actually
working.
We actually don't spend a lot of time in our overall life applying to jobs interview.
So if you look at the grand scheme of things, don't be disappointed if you don't get hired within a
week.
You should spend time looking for jobs and opportunities because most likely you're going to be there
for a long time.
So you want to make it count.
You also can't say that you're on hirable and get depressed or sad because you had a few rejections.
Sometimes Luck just plays a role in interview.
So just don't take it personally.
It's okay to fail.
I failed multiple times.
Everybody fails.
Sometimes you just have a bad day.
It's not the end of the world if you fail, right?
For companies, for example, they're more likely to say no than say yes because it is a big risk for
them to hire somebody.
You're going to start getting doubts in your mind about your abilities and your skills with all these
rejections.
However.
Like I said before, if you fail ten times, try ten times more.
All you need is that one success.
I promise you that if each day you're learning, you're getting better and better, your skills are
improving.
Then one day you will get that offer.
Most people just don't go out and keep adding.
I'll see you in the next video.