The most successful people that I know.
And I'm not just talking about developers.
I'm talking about all the successful people that I know are masters of learning.
We all have the same amount of time in the day.
23 hours, 56 minutes and 26 seconds.
However, some people are able to accomplish more than others.
Why is that?
I'm a big proponent of efficiency.
If you're able to learn something in much less time than somebody else, then you can compound the benefit
over your lifetime.
Now, I know many people have different learning abilities, but this isn't a contest with others.
This is a contest within yourself.
Figure out what makes you successful in learning.
Don't compare yourself to others, whether you're a visual learner, or maybe you need to take breaks
every 30 minutes.
Figure out what your best learning style is.
Learn how to learn.
Don't just watch videos blindly at two times the speed and expect to learn everything.
Find the most efficient way that works for you and keep practicing.
By learning to learn, you become a better developer.
As developers, we have to constantly learn throughout our career.
Our learning never stops because technology is constantly evolving.
So if you want to be a successful developer.
You have to learn your best learning style.
It is better to figure out what makes you tick, what makes things clearer for you now then later on
in your career.
Start early.
Figure out what is the best method for you because it's going to be a skill that you're going to use
throughout your career.