Welcome back.
We have our best friend visual go.
And once again, they have a great diagram for us to play with.
Now I'm going to give you four different graphs and you're going to have to tell me what type of graph
it is based on what we've learned so far, whether it's weighted, cyclic, undirected, directed.
So let's start off with this one.
What do you think this one is before I show you the answer?
Ready.
All right.
Well, this is an undirected.
There's no arrows on weighted graph.
And you can see that it's also cyclic because you can go zero one, two and back to zero.
What about the next one?
What type of graph is this?
Well, this is an undirected weighted graph that's also cyclic.
So you can see that we have weights on the edges here.
There's no arrows.
We can go anywhere we want back and forth.
And we can also make cycles.
What about this one?
This is a directed graph, but unweighted and yes, even six and seven are a graph.
But we see here that it's not cyclic.
It's a cyclic because there's no way for me to go back.
Let's say 0 to 1.
I can't go back to zero.
All right.
Last one.
What about this one?
This is a directed weighted graph.
We have the weights, has direction and when it comes to cyclic note, there are no cycles.
So it's a cyclic.
All right.
The final challenge.
What type of graph is this?
Ready for the answer.
This is a directed acyclic graph.
There's no cycles.
It's directed and it's a graph.
And this directed acyclic graph is quite common in called DAG and actually a project like Iota which
is a pretty popular blockchain project, uses this and uses fancy words like directed acyclic graph.
But at the end of the day, that's not that impressive anymore, right?
We know what that is, just simply a graph that goes in one direction.
I think it's time for us to learn how to build our own graph.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.