Welcome back.
Now hash tables are implemented differently in different languages, but most of the time the key and
the value can be any type of data structure.
We saw here that we can have a function as a value.
We can have another object if we want.
As a value, we can have an array as a value if we want.
And I mean, you can do this in arrays as well.
We don't just have numbers and strings in a race.
We can have arrays of objects, but you can also sometimes have keys that are more than just strings.
You could potentially have functions as keys.
And a value that is also a function or perhaps a number or an array, whatever you want.
Now in JavaScript, in an object like this, if you pass a key that is a number or a function, it actually
gets stratified and it only allows string keys.
But with the new version of JavaScript and ES6, you actually have something called map and sets, which
also may be familiar in other languages.
A map is created.
Like this.
And the difference between a map and an object is the fact that a map allows you to save any data type
as the key.
Remember, with an object you can only save the key as a string.
With the map it allows us if we want to even have functions as keys or erase as keys.
And another benefit of map is that it maintains insertion order.
What does that mean?
Well with an object.
There is no order, is there?
If we go back to our diagram.
Our data is inserted randomly in different places.
If we go back to our users example, we see that there is definitely no order.
When we grab all the values of an object, we start with, let's say Lisa Smith, which was entered
second, then John Smith, then perhaps Sandra de Sam Doe gets selected last.
There is no order like there was with Erase.
But there are some versions of hash tables like maps and JavaScript that maintains this order of insertion,
so that when we loop through items in an object, we have this maintained order.
Sets is another feature very similar to MAP.
The only difference is that it only stores the keys, no values.
So you see here each language, as we mentioned, comes with its own prebuilt versions of data structures.
But at the end of the day, all of them are hash tables.
But in order to truly understand how hash tables work, I think we should build one.
In the next video, we're going to do just that.