Welcome back.
We're going to do a fun little exercise here.
Now, instead of me just reading off what I wrote, I have a little ask for you.
You're going to use this cheat sheet and look at the step by step through a problem, which is a 15
step guide of what you should do when you're in a coding interview to solve a problem.
And I want you to use this as you watch a little video.
Now this video.
Is actually produced by Google and it demonstrates it's 24 minutes.
So it's a little bit long, but it demonstrates how you should answer a coding interview.
And in my opinion, this is the best coding interview that I've ever seen.
Now I want you to watch this.
And keep in mind that because we haven't learned data structures and algorithms yet, this is going
to be quite difficult for you to understand.
And that's the goal here.
When you watch this, it's going to be really, really hard to follow the actual coding, maybe some
of the language that they use.
I believe they're writing the code in C++.
So if you don't know C++, it might be difficult.
But that's not the point.
The point for you here is to watch this video.
But also read the step by step through a problem and see how the interview e.
In this case in this video follows these steps.
And these steps are what you're going to do when you solve a problem in a coding interview.
The fun thing is that at the end of this course, we're going to revisit the video.
This video.
And you're going to notice a difference from this very first time that you're going to watch this video
to the very end where what the interviewee does becomes second nature.
You understand what they're coding in, what they're doing to solve the problem and all these little
steps so that I succeed.
If you completely get this video and you understand how to run a successful interview at a company like
Google or any large company or maybe even startup, depending on what you like.
So to get started, I'll be right back.
You go watch this video.
You follow the 15 steps.
And after this, we're going to do a little problem of our own and follow the guide, the 15 step guide
to solve our own little problem.
I'll see you in that one.
Bye bye.