Welcome back.
I want to show you one last example, and this is probably the best example of why dynamic programming
is so important.
And as you remember, when I say dynamic programming, which sounds kind of confusing, just think of
caching, of optimizing something using a cache.
One of the best examples of why dynamic programming is so good is our good old friend Fibonacci sequence.
We learned about this in our recursion section of the course where the previous two numbers add up to
the next number.
So that 13 is five plus eight, 34 is 13 plus 21, and it keeps going, keeps growing, keeps growing.
And we learn how to calculate that, right.
We were able to calculate the Fibonacci number quite easily.
We had a function.
Fibonacci, which is a really hard name to spell.
I believe it's this way.
And all we did was we said using recursion, we had a base case of MN is less than two.
In that case we'll return an.
Otherwise we did some fun recursion.
We return Fibonacci and minus one.
Plus Fibonacci.
And minus two, so that if I want to find the Fibonacci number at index of, let's say six.
And I run this.
Oh and V no, this should be.
And as in number let's run that again.
I get eight because zero one, two, three, four, five, six is eight.
If I do seven, I should get 13.
Awesome.
This is something that we should be familiar with.
But let me ask you a question.
How efficient is this function?
And we've talked about it before.
Right.
It's not very efficient.
If I have a variable here that says let's call the calculations.
Which will equal to zero.
And we're just going to increment this.
Every time this function gets called.
And because it's recursive, we know that it gets called a lot of times.
If I do Fibonacci seven, how many calculations is that?
That's 13 calculations.
So 13 times that we ran through the Fibonacci function.
What if I increase that to eight?
21.
What about 934?
What about ten?
55.
All right.
It's increasing pretty fast.
What if I do 12?
144 calculations just to get the 12th index.
Wow.
What if I do 15?
610 calculations.
What about 20?
Holy moly.
Over 6000 calculations.
And just for fun, what if I do 25?
Oh, boy.
All right.
One last time.
Just because we're having fun.
30.
All right.
That's a lot of calculations.
And by the way, if you want your browser to crash, just type in 50 or 60 and see what happens there.
Regardless if we look at this, this well is pretty terrible.
Just to calculate the 30th number or index of a Fibonacci sequence takes that many steps, that many
calculations.
That is a lot.
It's not very efficient.
And we know this, right?
Because in our recursion section we talked about how that Fibonacci sequence and the way we're running
the function is o of two to the power of PN.
Really really bad time complexity.
As we saw just doing 30 calculations takes a lot of steps.
And remember, with recursion we're adding every nested function call adds to the stack, which increases
our memory complexity.
And we would never want to do an operation that costs this much in real life.
So how can we make it more efficient?
Can we make it more efficient?
I mean, if our function if you wrote that function, is your boss going to fire you because it scales
so horribly?
I mean, if your boss is horrible, maybe.
But if, you know, dynamic programming, you can avoid this.
Because what if I told you that we can do o n with this function?
Because with dynamic programming, we can.
That's right.
We can go from o of two to the power of n all the way down to o of n.
Sounds like magic, doesn't it?
And this is where we get to the next step of our dynamic programming.
We can reduce the time and space complexity of our algorithm by using memorization.
And we can do this because the solution to each sub problem is what we call optimal.
That means we do a lot of problems repeatedly that are the same.
In the next video, we're going to explain this concept and see how we can use memorization.
I'll see you on that one.
Bye bye.