This is something that we started our course with the idea that when learning something with our limited
time and resource, we need to make sure that we understand the most important concept.
Why are we learning this?
Why is this worth my time?
And why is this something that I should dedicate this time to?
Too often we see new things in the developer ecosystem.
It is always exciting to be working on the newest and shiniest thing that everybody is talking about.
But remember those libraries and frameworks and configuration files and tools?
Those things come and go.
They're always changing.
You can be a master of Webpack one day and two years later nobody cares because there's a better tool
out there.
The things that stick around are the fundamental computer science topics and software development practices.
Sure, these things change over time as well, but they always evolve slowly.
With y in mind when learning new things.
Make sure you understand why the solution was created.
What problem is it solving and why is this the answer to your problems?
If you're able to do this, you stop being a player in the game of catch up and the developer ecosystem
always trying to learn the latest library, the newest tool, the coolest functions to learn.
It's like a game of hamster who's constantly trying to keep up with the wheel, trying to run on that
wheel, but instead be an observer who is watching the ecosystem evolve from above.
Watch how new libraries come and go.
Understand the why of each libraries, what problems they solve.
Understand the big picture, why we do things.
But be the observer, not the hamster.
You'll have a happier, longer career overall.
Trust me, you won't be constantly trying to catch up with every library and framework this way.
This big picture vision is what makes a senior developer or a manager or a leader.
They don't have narrow vision.
They see the entire ecosystem and they are able to make smart decisions because of that.
So always start with why.