Every recursive function needs to have something called a base case or a stop point.
Remember my example at the beginning where I showed you how to recursively check out all the folders
in one of our projects?
We have to tell the program, hey, if the subfolder we're going to no longer has any more folders,
stop.
If this stop wasn't there, the function would just keep running.
So recursive functions have two paths.
One is the recursive case.
That is call the function again and run it.
And then the base case that is stop calling the function.
There's nothing more to search.
So how can we add this feature of telling the function?
Hey, quit it.
You're being ridiculous right now.
You need to stop.
Well, we can do something like this.
We can create a counter, and we'll say, this counter is zero.
And we can add a conditional statement.
We'll say that if counter is.
Greater than three.
In that case, just return.
Done.
Otherwise we'll call Inception.
But we also want to increment the counter by one.
So if I click run here, well, I have to call the function first, let's say Inception.
If I call this function right now.
What do you think will happen?
Pause the video.
Think about it, because I'm about to click Run in 3 to 1.
I get undefined.
Is that what you expected?
Just to show you something, if I comment this code out and we just do this interception where we just
keep calling Inception, Inception and perhaps do a console log here saying hello.
And I click Run.
I get maximum coal sack size exceeded.
OC We know by looking at this function, this version of the function, that it's never going to get
to console.log because as soon as it hits the first line of the function, it's going to go back and
say, Oh, I'm calling this and then it's going to go here.
It's just going to bounce back and forth, back and forth, never getting to console.log.
But if we go back to what we have before, well, our function clearly has ended.
It hasn't done StackOverflow.
And at one point its ended because we increment the counter.
So let me console dialogue here our counter and make sure that this works.
If I click run, I get zero one, two, three, four when it gets to four.
Counter is greater than three.
So we're returning.
Done.
But why is there no done here?
And this is a great illustration of how recursion works.
I'm going to copy this code.
And go back to our browser.
Over here.
Let me refresh this page to make sure that.
We have a clear global variable and I'm going to copy and paste Inception this time around.
I'm going to add the debugger keyword so that we can debug our code and go step by step through it.
Let's run Inception.
And see what happens.
All right.
We're back to our debugger.
We see that we have the whole stack here.
Inception has just been called by me.
And I also opened up this little tab called Scope for our case.
We want to just open up the script scope.
It shows us what variables we have available to us.
In this case we have counter, which is zero.
So I'm going to click step over.
And it's going to say, hey, we have a counter is equal to zero.
Is that greater than three?
No.
I'm going to skip over increment counter and run inception.
We see that that happened.
Counter has now been incremented because we've gone through this line and now we go to Inception.
We're going to run the function again.
And you'll notice that the call stack, when I click this, it's going to increase.
And we're going to go one more time.
Counter is not one.
Nope.
Don't return anything yet.
Increment the counter.
You'll see.
Counter goes to two and we're going to run Inception again.
And we keep going once more.
Passing through counter becomes three.
Adding inception to the stack.
And then one more time.
Three is not greater than three.
So we go one more time calling a session, adding it to the stack.
We now have these many stacks counters at four, and then we step over here.
Counter is now four, which is greater than three.
We're finally going to enter the if condition that's going to return done for us.
Let's see what happens here.
I'm going to click next.
And I click next again.
Look at that.
We have a local variable now that has return value done.
We've now returned.
Done.
And we're no longer going to call Inception.
The call stack is now going to start popping off these functions because it's going to say, oh, we
have a return keyword.
I'm going to stop whatever I'm doing at the bottom here and return from this function.
So this inception function is going to get return done.
But notice what happens next.
Oh I get return value undefined as we popped off the top item from inception from the call stack and
if I keep popping things from the call stack.
The return value is undefined and that's what we get.
Now.
Why is that?
Well, if we go back to our function, what you just saw was us essentially doing this.
We called Inception once.
Twice.
Three times.
And then four times.
And within here, when we finally got here, we said, Oh, return done.
So this inception function turns into done.
And then we go to this function.
Now, the problem with this and I know this can get confusing is that once we've returned, once we've
popped off the stack and we're now at this part of inception, but this inception never returns anything.
When a function doesn't return anything, it just returns undefined.
So we need to keep telling it to return this done and and bubble it up towards the very end.
And this is something that you have to keep in mind with recursion.
There's usually a base case and you always want to make sure you return so that the value that you want
gets bubbled up all the way to the top.
In our case, all we need to do is say Return inception.
This way, this inception knows to return whatever its result was, which was done.
And this inception knows to result, to return whatever this result was, which again is done, and
so on and so forth until we get done back.
Let's run this again.
Or and I have to call the function.
Let's do that again.
Inception.
And run.
And we're done.
Very, very nice.
If I go back here.
And go back to the console.
I encourage you to try this out this time adding the return keyword to inception and running through
the debugger to see what happens.
But what I just showed you is all you need to build recursive functions.
You have three rules.
One is to identify the base case.
Two is to identify the recursive case.
So we've identified the base case went to stop the recursive case.
That is when counter is less than three.
And then finally, our third step is to get closer and closer.
And return when needed.
And that usually.
You have to returns.
For the base case and the recursive case because you want to return something at the end of the function.
So let's comment this out.
We have an idea of how recursion works.
The function simply gets closer and closer and closer to the base case, and once it gets to the base
case, it finally returns and pops functions off the stack.
But that's enough talking for me.
I think it's time for us to do some coding exercises to get really familiar with this topic.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.