Welcome back.
I hope you are able to think about why link lists might be good or bad.
In this video.
Let's discuss the answer.
One key thing that you may have seen is that length lists have a sort of loose structure that allows
you to insert a value into the middle of the list.
By simply resetting a few pointers, just like we saw in the animation.
I can insert anything that I want.
And the only changes that happen is.
Somewhere in the middle here.
And this is the same for deleting node in a linked list.
And we remember with an array data structure how when we wanted to insert something that wasn't at the
end of the array, we had to add the item, let's say in memory space one into here and then shift all
the items down and index it down, which costs us a lot of time.
It costs us o of n.
The main difference between a race and linked lists is that in an array, an element or elements are
indexed.
So if I wanted to go to item at index five, I can do that easily in a link list.
You start at the head and traverse the list until you get to item five, which is O of RN.
And this idea of traversal is the same as iteration that we did with the race where we go zero one,
two, three, four, five.
Except we like to call this traversal because you don't really know when the length list will end.
You start from the head and you keep going until you hit null.
And as you'll see in our coding example, we're going to have to use something like a while loop when
we implement our own length lists because we don't usually know how long the list is going to be.
Another advantage that an array might have is that most computers have caching systems that make reading
from sequential memory.
That is memory right next to each other, shelves right next to each other, faster than reading scattered
addresses.
And that's something that we've talked about already.
Array items are always located right next to each other in computer memory.
Linked lists and nodes instead are actually scattered all over memory, kind of like hash tables.
So iterating through a link list or traversing through a link list is usually quite a bit slower than
iterating through items like an array, even though they're technically both o of n.
However, these inserts that we can do in the middle of a link list is a lot better than an array.
What about hash tables?
Remember this when we talked about hash tables?
Well, just like hash tables.
When we insert something into a link list, we just scatter it all over our memory and we can just keep
adding it.
Keep adding it.
And we don't have to do any of the on shifting or shifting on the indexes that we did with the race,
which is really, really nice.
You can also delete notes very easily versus with an array.
But the one advantage that it has over hash tables is that there is some sort of order to link list.
Each node points to the next node so you can have sorted data unlike a hash table.
So if we look at our big go of link list, we can see that pre spent, which is a common language we
say to add to the beginning of a link list.
Present is o of one append which is at the end of the list.
To add a new item is of one lookup, which we can also call traversal.
To look for an item.
Let's say we want to find ten is of PN because we have to go from the head all the way until we find
what we're looking for.
Insert is also often because we have to go one by one, find the index so we don't know how long our
link list is.
We find the index and then insert there, which technically could take over again and again.
Something that we're going to implement in code and have a better understanding of and delete is also
all event because we have to find the items.
Now you're thinking to yourself hold on, insert and delete and erase are also event.
So how is that better?
And that's something that we're going to get into when we actually take a look at the code.
Remember, this is the worst case, in which case we insert or delete the very last item.
And most of the times that won't be the case in link list.
Again, something that we're going to talk about a little bit when we code our own link list.
But looking at a diagram like this, it's really hard to truly understand how they work and what length
lists are.
So we're going to code our own.
And the next video we're going to talk about this final piece of the puzzle, what a pointer is, and
then finally code our own link list.
So we understand the big implications a little bit better.
I'll see you on that one.
Bye bye.