Welcome back.
If we take a look at our Fibonacci function that we created, this is what we're doing.
If I was looking for Fibonacci number of seven using recursion, well, we'd have to run all these calculations
recursively and all of these as well.
And you can see here what's happening, right?
Look where we're calculating Fibonacci of one.
We have this function running.
One, two, three, four, five times.
Calculating the same thing.
What about Fibonacci of two?
Again, look at all these calculations that are being repeated.
What about three?
And you see here where the triangles are overlapping, where we're calculating three over where we calculated
fib two and Fibonacci of one as well.
And then if we keep going to if you Bonacci number of four there again repeated tasks.
Triangles over triangles.
And then finally Fibonacci of six or five.
We see that once again, we just have more repeated calculations.
This does not look efficient, does it?
And that's what we saw in the previous video.
This is what we're doing with our calculations.
But if you notice here with dynamic programming, we can optimize this and use memorization to say,
hey.
Calculate Fibonacci of seven.
Go recursively down to six to 5 to 4 to 3 to 2.
And also to one.
And now as we go back, remember, as we start to return the statements and we go to fib of two or fib
of three or fib before, because we've already calculated these numbers.
We can actually return a memorised version so that all these calculations.
Are no longer needed.
Why?
Because.
Two, three, four and five.
Every time we ask for it.
In this case, we've already calculated on the left hand side, so we can use the cached or memorized
version so that these we can just ask the memorized function to just get for us.
We avoid all these calculations.
Look how simple that looks.
And I'm going to show you in the next video how we actually implement this with the Fibonacci sequence.
But to demonstrate to you that this is not only just this problem that we can use dynamic programming
on, I have a set of rules.
One is that you can think of dynamic programming as combining divide and conquer.
What we did with the tree like structure of Fibonacci number, where we use recursion and using reuse,
that is caching memorization with recursion to get savings in performance and use dynamic programming.
And these are the steps that I like to follow to see if a problem can use dynamic programming to optimize
it.
We first ask, can the problem be divided into sub problems?
That is, is it a tree like structure where each problem is broken down into smaller problems, into
smaller problems, into small problems, which usually indicates a recursive solution?
Again, something that we're very familiar with from our previous videos.
And now the third question is really important because you can have tree like structures that don't
have repetitive sub problems.
But if these sub problems are repetitive, that is we're doing the same calculation over and over and
the SAP problems.
Well, if the answer is yes, then we can memorize these SAP problems.
And once we do that, we see tremendous benefits.
And these benefits are used all over computer science to improve performance so that the fifth step
should be to demand a raise from your boss.
If you've implemented this because you've just saved so many calculations, so much time, complexity.
I want you to think like this instead of being intimidated by the confusing name that is dynamic programming.
You just need to know when a problem can use this technique.
And I'll leave some problems for you after this section to practice on.
But you want to just follow this pattern.
When a problem has solutions composed of solutions to the same problem with smaller and smaller inputs,
each problem is solved only once, and the result of each sub problem is stored in a table like a cache
such as a hash table like we've done in the previous video.
For future reference, we can use this table to obtain the original solution of a repeated problem.
Enough talk.
I think it's time for us to implement our own memorization with Fibonacci number.
If you want to challenge yourself, go ahead and see if you can encode it yourself.
Otherwise, in the next video, I'm going to show you how to improve our terrible performing Fibonacci
function.
And to.
Oh then.
I'll see you on that one.
Bye bye.