Welcome back.
I wanted to add a quick video to let you know about a common interview trick.
We're going to be doing some array questions after this.
But in interviews, you should treat any string questions like over here as an array question.
You see, strengths are simply array of characters.
Most of the time in an interview.
When you get a question like reverse a string, what you should be thinking is to convert this into
an array.
Do some sort of a loop on it or an operation using something like a split method in JavaScript and then
returning it as a string after you've finished the operations with them.
So that is a very common interview question where you're manipulating strengths.
Just keep that in mind and will actually demonstrate this in the next video when we do a very common
interview question.
I'll see you in that one.
Bye bye.