Welcome back.
Let's start off with the iterative approach that is no recursion.
If we want to run the function, let's say find factorial iterative five.
Well, we can create a variable, let's say answer.
And for now this answer will be one.
And all we're going to do is do a four loop.
We'll say let I.
Equals zero.
Or in our case, to simplify things.
Let's start at two.
And I'm going to explain in a second why we want to start a two.
I'm going to say I is less than the number.
And then we're going to.
Increment by one.
Now.
Why are we starting at two?
You might notice a shortcut here.
One factorial is just one.
Two factorial is two times one, which is just two.
So these last two bits, if somebody says one factorial or two factorial, we can just simply return
the number that they've entered because there's no real calculation that we need to do.
So this is a little shortcut.
So we avoid extra loops.
We're just saying that if the number that the user enters is, let's say two, so that is two is not
greater than number two.
The way we have it now.
If somebody enters find factorial iterative two, we're going to return one.
But instead we can just say maybe a simple conditional check saying that if number equals to two.
We'll just.
Say that answer equals to two.
So that if I run this function and just say to.
I get two if I say one.
I get one.
And there's other checks that we can do, obviously.
But for our case, this is good enough.
Let's look at what we can do inside of here.
Well, the way factorial works is to simply say answer is going to equal answer.
Times.
So that if I click run here and let's do five.
I get 24, which is actually not the right answer because five times four is 20 times three is well,
clearly higher than 24.
And that's because of a little mistake here.
We want to make sure that this is equals because we want to include the number five.
So if I run this again.
I get 120, which is the right answer?
Five times four is 20 times times three is 60 times two is one.
20 times one is just 120.
Perfect.
So hopefully you got that answer correct.
What about the recursive approach?
In the recursive version, we'll just do a simple check saying if.
The number is equals to two and we can do other checks as well.
But that should be enough for now for us to create a base case.
So if the number gets to two, we'll just return to.
There's our base case.
That's how we stop.
Next, we're going to return our recursive version, which will simply be number.
Times.
The function.
And in this function, we're just going to say number minus one.
And that's the key here.
We want to always get lower and lower until we hit the base case.
So if I hit run here, let's do recursive this time.
I'm going to move this up.
Over here.
And if I had run, I also get 120.
And this is a little hard to wrap your mind around, so you might want to copy this code and open up
Google Chrome developer tools like I showed you and go step by step.
But if we start with the number five here, well, this five equal to nope, then we'll say five times.
Fine factorial.
For.
Should be our answer, just like the diagram that I showed you.
And we keep going and keep going until we hit the base case of does the number equal to.
Now one last bit.
What do you think the time complexity of these two functions are?
While one uses a four loop.
With the loop being the number associated with it, and we're doing a bit of a shortcut here, so it's
technically less than zero.
NW But because of our big old rules, this is still going to be O of NW.
The recursive function.
If we look at this, we are looping how many times?
Well, we're calling the function function find factorial recursive recursive the same number of times
as the number itself.
So this also becomes o of n.
If you've got this question, good job.
It's a tough one if you didn't.
Don't worry.
We have another one coming up.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.