Hello.
I know, I know, I know.
The last two videos were kind of long, very technical.
If you weren't familiar with JavaScript, maybe they were a little bit tougher.
But the point was the process of solving a problem in a coding interview.
And over here, I've created a little playground for you.
You remember the Google interview video that I made you watch?
Well, I've implemented the solution that the interviewee created.
In here we have the naive solution, which is the nested for loops, and then a better solution that
uses just one for loop at the expense of creating something in JavaScript called New Set.
I left this here for you, for you to play around with and if you want to code it in your own language.
But I wanted to challenge you to see if you can implement this on your own, just like the person in
the Google interview did in your own language, the naive approach and then the better approach and
try to follow these steps as you code along, even though you already know the answer, even though
you have watched the interview video by practicing the steps and how you go from the naive to the better
solution, by following the steps, you're going to improve that interviewing muscle.
All right.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.