Welcome back.
You can't talk about recursion without talking about the Fibonacci sequence.
What is the Fibonacci sequence?
Well, it's this.
This sequence right here.
The pattern, if you notice, is that we're always adding the first two items equals this one.
So zero plus one equals one.
One plus one equals two.
One plus two equals three, two plus three equals five, so on and so forth, so on and so forth.
So the previous two numbers always equals the current number.
So I have another exercise for you.
This one a little bit tougher than the previous one.
Given a number and that the function is going to receive return the index value of the Fibonacci sequence.
So if I say that I want the DN to equal to, it's going to give me 012.
That is the number one.
This function is going to return one.
If I say Fibonacci number eight, I would get zero.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
I would get 21.
The function will tell me what number is associated with the index that I give it.
Once again, I have the iterative approach that is using just simple for loops.
And also the recursive approach.
I challenge you to try both of these and see if you can do it.
And a big hint here is that the recursive approach is actually easier than the iterative approach.
So good luck out there and I'll see you in the solution video.
Bye bye.