What would you say if I asked you what is the big o of the function?
Finding Nemo?
Well, to make this a little bit cleaner, let's just remove performance done now, because we've learned
that it's not very, very important and we can remove the console log as well.
And looking at this and this loop, what would you say the big O is?
In this video, we're going to learn about our very first big notation.
As we said, a runtime is simply how long something takes to run.
How does this function?
And its runtime grow as our input increases, as our input goes from just a single item in an array
Nemo to ten items in array to 100,000.
How does the efficiency of this function increase?
If we look at this graph and we say we have four items in the array, well, the number of operations
is going to be.
For, right?
Because we're going to loop through each item and say, is this Nnimmo?
Is this Nnimmo?
Four times.
No matter what, we're looping four times, at least with the way that we have this code set up.
If we have five items in the array, it's going to be five operations, five loops.
Six is the same.
Six items is six operations.
Seven is seven operations and eight is eight operations.
Do we see a little bit of a pattern here?
Well, we can draw a line through it.
This is linear rate as our number of inputs increase, the number of operations increase as well.
And here, ladies and gentlemen, we've learned our very first big notation.
We say that the Finding Nemo function.
Has a big o notation of.
Oh.
And.
Hmm.
That's a little bit strange.
This is just a notation that you have to get used to.
But we say big o of n, or what we call linear linear time.
It takes linear time to find Nemo.
Now, where does this end come from?
This end can be anything really.
I could put X, I could put fish in here if I want.
It's just an arbitrary letter and we usually give.
And when it comes to bingo, this is just a standard that you'll see across the board.
And simply means the big O depends on the number of inputs, the number of fish.
So if we just had the Nemo array, this would just be.
One.
If we had the everyone array, this would be ten.
And if we had the large array it will be 100,000.
But as the inputs increase, you see that the number of operations increase linearly with it.
Owen is probably the most common big old notation you'll find.
If we go back to the graph, you can see that Owen is right here in the yellow region that says fare
as the number of elements increase.
You see, that is just a straight line.
The number of operations increases by the same amount.
Because keep this in mind, Big O doesn't measure things in seconds.
Instead, we're focusing on how quickly our runtime grows.
We simply do this by using the size of the input, which we call N or anything else that we want.
Really.
And compare it to the number of operations that increase.
That's what scalability means.
As things grow larger and larger, does it scale?
So the Find Nemo function is o of nw linear time.
Another way to think about it is this if we had a compression algorithm, let's say this function is
this little compression and the input is this little box.
What's the big o notation of this function?
Well, if we had one element, it will just compress.
One item if we had multiple elements, again, we still have to run each box through the compression
algorithm to compress the box.
If we look at the function for the compress boxes, well, we're using the S five and six syntax here,
but we're essentially looping through each box and in our case we're just console logging it.
But you can see here that all of these all we're doing as the input increases, the boxes, the number
of boxes increases, the number of operations increase.
And that is own linear time.
Congratulations.
You just learned your first bingo notation, and this is probably the most common, but there's a few
others.
So what other big notations do we have other than linear time?
For that, you're going to have to keep watching.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.