Welcome back.
Now I'm not going to go over all of our steps that we used in the section where we talked about how
to solve problems and how to talk through your problems in front of an interviewer.
And we even watched that Google video of all the things you need to do, because that's going to take
way too long of a time.
I'm going to speed things up and just talk about the key points of how you would solve this problem.
Well, in order to reverse a string, the first thing we want to do is some sort of a check of our input.
We can't just assume that we're going to always receive a string.
What if somebody calls the reverse function with.
Well, undefined or with a number?
What happens then?
And a good thing to always start off with is to check the input.
In my case, I'm going to do a simple check.
Let's say that if there's no string.
So that is undefined.
Or perhaps that the string at length is less than two.
That means, well, if string length is less than two, that means I'm just receiving one letter.
Or no letters, in which case we don't really need to do any operations.
It's already kind of reversed.
And we can add different input validation here, such as using the type of keyword and JavaScript to
check if it's a string type.
But that's something you can just do on your own.
Actually, let's implement it since we're here anyway, just to show you so I can say type of.
String if it doesn't equal.
Straight type of SDR, which is the parameter we receive as an equal, the string type.
Well, in that case, we can just.
Return.
Hmm.
That's not good.
Otherwise, let's do some operation.
To reverse the strain.
Well, let's think about this.
We want to convert it into an array.
So I'm going to create a backwards array.
And this is what we're going to return from the function.
I'm going to return the array.
That is reversed.
But we want to return a string, right?
A reverses a string that should return a string.
Even though we're going to convert whatever we receive into an array at the end, we want to turn it
back into a string.
So in JavaScript we can do the two string method or.
The Joint method.
And we just say, join all the items in the array.
Now in here, we're going to grab the length.
Of the array or the string, because we're going to be using it a lot and we don't want to have repeated
code.
So I'm going to say length minus one is how many items we have in the string.
Or maybe we should name this items.
Number.
Or actually total items.
That's a better name.
Now these total items.
So we're going to loop through our string.
Will say let I equals to the total items.
So I is going to equal however many characters we have in our string.
And we're going to keep going until I is equals to zero.
And all we're going to do because we want to go from.
Back to front.
We're going to.
Decrement this.
So we're going to go from the length of the string all the way back.
So we're going to start off with I, e, r, d and a and insert those into an array that we've created
the backwards array one by one.
So in this loop.
All we're going to do is say backwards.
Dot push.
Each item that we're going to create so str.
And I know what you're thinking.
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Why don't we just convert the string into an array?
You told me all about converting strings into an array, and we didn't really do that.
And JavaScript actually has the string split.
Or we can run the split command to split things into an array.
But with JavaScript, we can actually just use strings as arrays and access each property like this
with bracket notation so that they essentially are arrays.
So we don't have to run any split commands.
This also works.
And all we're doing is we're going backwards one by one and pushing each item of our given string into
our array.
So if I console.log here before we run the joint command, the backwards array.
And I run reverse.
And let's reverse.
The string.
Let's run this.
Oh, and you may have noticed that this length didn't really come from anywhere.
It should be total items.
So this is the total.
Oops.
Total items.
This is the problem with live coding.
I tried to show that everybody makes mistakes, even myself.
And it's good because this way you think through the problem and these total items.
Remember, we want to keep going as long as I is.
Greater than or equal to zero.
So if I now run this.
Hey, look at that.
We have an array with all of our backwards items right in here.
And you see here that the return value.
That we get is the backwards.
String that we received because we join it at the end.
Very cool.
I hope you got that answer.
Or maybe you have a better answer than me, because what I did here is not necessarily the cleanest
way.
And depending on which programming language you use, you might have built in methods that simplify
this step.
Let me show you what I mean.
In JavaScript, for example, we can use some built in methods that come with the race to just simplify
this whole thing and make our code a lot more readable.
Let's create a new function, and I'm going to call this.
Reverse two, and this reverse two is going to once again receive some sort of an input.
I won't do any input validation for this one.
You can just assume that we can just copy and paste it here.
But in here, we can do a simple return statement.
Grab the string.
Run the split command.
Because this time around, we're not going to access the eye like we did up here.
We're going to convert it into an array so that we can use a built in method that comes in JavaScript
arrays called reverse.
And this reverse does what we just did here for us, and now we just join it at the end.
So by using a built in method called reverse, I avoided all this work.
How nice is that?
Let's see if that works.
I'm going to say reverse to going to run and look at that.
It's still working.
What about another solution?
Again, many different ways.
And let's say the interviewer says, is there a more modern, cleaner way that you can make this function?
And because in JavaScript there is the new ES6 syntax.
You can even create a one line function.
Call it reverse three.
That's going to take a string and it's going to do string dot split.
And again do the exact same thing using arrow function this time around.
And this should still work the exact same.
Look at that.
And if you want to get fancy, you can again use a new feature of JavaScript, which is the structuring
or not the structure.
This is the spread operator.
If I run this, we no longer need the split.
I can run this and I get the same thing.
Again, I just want to demonstrate to you that there are many different ways to solve a problem and
an interviewer is not going to reject you for a job just because you implemented it this way versus
this way.
It depends on how you deliver your solution.
And this is something that we talked about in our how to solve problem section.
How you want to talk through the problem.
Explain to the interviewer why you did.
And as long as you understand the pros and cons of each solution, that's what makes a great engineer.
I'll see you in the next one.