There we have it.
Our end to the data structures section.
Was it as scary as you initially thought?
Hopefully by the end of this section, if you've watched all the videos and done all the exercises,
you feel a lot more comfortable.
You can use the tools that you've learned to be a better engineer and make better decisions.
Hopefully you don't look as scared as this emoji did at the beginning of this section.
And we've learned that these data structures at the end of the day are our friends.
And by the way, I'm really proud of this slide.
I spent way too long creating this little thing that I have.
I have Mr. Hash Table here.
That's Mrs. Zare.
That's a little link list.
That's.
Mr..
Q Mrs. Stack's scary looking graph, and of course, Professor Tree.
Anyway, I hope you're no longer intimidated by these subjects, because all around us, when we look
at technology, they're all built by data structures.
We hold information and data structures no matter how many data structures they are and there will be
in the future.
Most of the building blocks are right here.
You see something like blockchain that has become really popular in recent years are just data structures
that we've learned about.
It has some aspects of linked lists.
It has some hashing that it does, which we know about.
And it also uses some trie data structure and trees having the fundamentals that you have now.
One day, maybe you'll build your own data structure.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.