Welcome back.
How was the exercise?
Were you able to figure out the append method?
Let me show you what I would have done.
The first thing we would want to do is to create a new node with the value.
And we can do that quite easily.
Saying const new node.
That's going to equal well, an object with the properties that we should be familiar by now we have
value that is going to equal the value that we get as the parameter.
And then the next.
That will be no.
So we have our new node here and we want to attach it now after the ten node.
Which is our very first note.
Well, we can simply do that by saying this dot tale.
Dot next which is the remember this part over here next equals null.
So that is what is the tail.
That is the last item in our list because this method doesn't know that we only have one item, we could
have 100 items.
We just want to add at the end.
So it's going to grab the tail and then grab the next value of the tail.
So it's going to grab the pointer of the tail and say, hey, instead of pointing it to null, pointed
to this new node that we just created.
All right.
We've pointed the tail to now point to the new node which has next null already set up.
And then we also want to say that this what we had as tail before, which was the value of ten is no
longer the tail.
We have a new last item that is this tail is now going to equal.
New node.
And because we are running this operation after this one, when we run this, the tail next is still
this node.
And as soon as we update.
This node to have a next of the new node we can now remove.
We can now update the tail to be the new node.
Because by that point, by the time this line runs, the next has been updated properly for this older
retail value.
And then finally we want to make sure that we add the length to equal to now.
So we're going to do plus plus.
And just for fun, because we want to make sure that we do this right, we're going to return this,
which is the link list.
Remember, this just references what this class is that gets instantiated.
So we're just going to say return this so that we get back our link list.
I'm going to remove the console lock for now and see what happens when we just run a pant.
Five.
I'm going to click Run.
All right, I get returned our link list, which has a head of Value ten.
Next is the new node that we created the value of five and next null.
And then the tail is value of five.
Next is null.
Perfect with a length of two.
Awesome.
It looks like it's working.
Let's do this one as well.
Append.
And there we go.
We have value of five.
So the head is referencing value of ten, which points to the next node, which has value of five,
which points to next, which is an object that is the tail.
Because of the way logging works, it won't show this nested.
It'll just say that this is an object.
But this is pointing to tail which has a value of 16.
Next null length of three.
How cool is that?
We just created our linked list, our ten, five, 16 link list, just like that.
I hope you got that right.
But if you didn't.
Don't get discouraged.
This takes some time to get used to.
Luckily for you, once you write it a couple of times, then it becomes, like I said, second nature.
So don't stress out because I have another challenge for you now that you know how to do a pen.
You should be able to do prep and right prep end is adding to the beginning of the list.
So let's say that in our list over here, we want to add one as our head now instead of ten.
How would we do that with a method called prep in?
This present is going to take a value.
And we're going to be able to run a command like my linked list dot pre penned one to add the one at
the beginning of this list.
So code here.
Good luck.
Let's see if we can solve this one.
And I'll see you in the next video where I give you the solution.