Welcome back.
Let's do a little exercise with just the general information we have about these two traversal techniques.
I have questions here for you.
And underneath it, I want you to answer whether you should use breath for a search or depth for search.
And these are the type of questions that you're going to get asked in an interview.
And it's good to understand I know that our knowledge is incomplete yet because we haven't coded anything.
But I want to lay the foundation so that when we start coding, you understand why we have these things.
So give it a go.
Try and answer these questions.
And in the next video, I'll go over the solutions.
Bye bye.