All right, we're on a roll here, so let's just keep going through a few more questions here.
What is your biggest weakness?
How would you answer this?
Well, here's the thing with these questions.
You better not give something silly like I work too hard.
Or My biggest weakness is that I care too much about my coworkers.
First of all, people can really see through that and label you as fake or a liar.
But again, every question should be something that makes you stand out, that makes the interviewer
say, Wow, I want to work with this person.
So how can we twist this around to something that the interviewer is going to say?
Yep, this person should be hired for this company.
It's very simple here.
One is you need a real answer.
Again, no silly answers of how gray you are.
Be honest.
Say something that you have as a real weakness.
But the key is you have to show how you overcame it, how you improved it.
So don't say.
I'm too passionate.
Maybe say something along the lines of Sometimes when there's a problem, I get straight into coding
without really thinking about the problem.
And as I'm typing, as I'm typing, I realize that perhaps I should have waited, planned out how I
should write my code, how it should be structured, what problem am I really solving before I start
just coding it?
So lately I've taken the time to make sure that I write pseudocode first.
Just commenting out the steps that I want to take.
While my assumptions are what my inputs are and from there, write out the steps that I want my code
to take before I actually dive into code.
You see what I did there?
I talked about my weakness, but somehow I turned it around.
Do something that makes me a great candidate.
Somebody that has improved from their past mistakes and now is working in a way that's ideal for a developer.
That's it.
There's not much to say here.
Just be honest, but use this question as a way to again show how you're better than the rest, how
you're a great candidate.
I'll see you in the next one.