Welcome back.
I've left for you the solution for the selection sort.
Now I'm not going to be going one by one through each sorting algorithm because it does take a lot of
time.
I don't want to bore you and lose you because there's so many more exciting things happening throughout
the next couple of videos.
So I'll leave this for you to see how it works.
It's not that much different from bubble sort.
We see that with selection sort.
We're setting the current index as the minimum, so the very first item in the array becomes the minimum.
But when we loop through the rest of the list.
We want to update the minimum.
If the current is lower than what we had previously.
So what we had here where we initially set the first item in the array 99 as the minimum.
As soon as we get to four, we're going to 44.
We're going to say, oh, 44 is less than 99.
Let's update the minimum.
So that index where 44 is is now the minimum.
And we're going to swap out those numbers just like we saw in the animation.
And it also is a really well documented thing on the Internet.
For example, if you are a python developer, you can just type in Python.
Selection sort.
And you'll find that, yeah, you can find how selection sorts it's implemented in Python and you can
run the program as well.
So depending on your language, you can usually click on the first or second link and show you how the
algorithm is implemented.
As you can see here, we have two nested for loops looping through the entire array.
So it's o of n squared for the rest of the sorting algorithms.
I will have the code provided for you so you can play with it and interact with it.
You see that the sorting works as expected, but it can also search for your own language.
To find the sorting algorithm so you understand it on a deeper level.
Let's talk about the next sorting algorithm in the video coming up.