Welcome back.
In the previous video, we talked about how new node over here gets repeated both times in append and
prevent.
And as we create more methods on our length list, we're going to have to constantly say new node value
equals value.
Next No.
And usually we want to keep things dry.
That is, do not repeat yourself in code and many implementations of link list.
You'll see something like this where new node is actually another class.
For example, I can create a new class here, and this is how object oriented programming usually works.
We have classes that interact with other classes to create our programs.
So you'll see a lot of implementations of link lists that have class of node.
And this node is going to have a constructor that takes a value and this value will have this dot value
equals to.
Value.
It's going to have this next equal to null.
Just like that.
So that way, instead of us saying constant new node and creating this new node every time.
I can just say every time that I want to create a new node, we can say let or convert new node.
Equals to new node and then the value.
So every time we have a new node, we just instantiate what we call create and run this new node.
Class that creates a node for us with a value property and a next property.
So you might prefer using this syntax, but because I find this can get a little bit confusing, especially
if you're not used to classes, I'm going to just keep things the way they are because, well, I think
it's easier to read.
And as you saw, it's fairly easy to implement if you want to do that on your own.
Okay.
Just a quick Segway.
Let's get back to finishing our link list in the next video.
Bye bye.