Welcome back.
It's time for an exciting interview.
QUESTION And this question comes straight from Google.
Given an array, let's say, that looks like this.
Tell me the first recurring character.
What does that mean?
Well, if we look at this array over here.
I want a function that I can enter this array.
This input is going to look through all the numbers and tell me which one gets repeated first.
So we look at two, five, one and two, and we say a two has already been seen.
Two is the recurring number.
If we look at another example, we see two, one, one and we stop here because one we've already seen
before.
We can say the first recurring character is one.
If we get an array that has all unique items, we just return on undefined.
So how would you go about solving this?
Give it a go.
See what you come up with.
If you need help, perhaps go on discord and chat with some of the community members and I'll see you
in The Solution video.