Now that we have a better understanding of how to calculate big oh, let's look at another exercise
that should be a little bit easier than the first one that we did.
What would you say that the big o of this is?
Well, if we go one by one, we see here that we have ov one again ov one.
And you know what?
If I keep typing, this is going to get tiresome.
So I'm just going to copy and paste.
So all of one here, we're just assigning variables.
And then we also see here that we have.
A four loop that is running based on the input.
We don't know what that input is, but we can just assume that we're looping based on however long this
input is, in which case we're running each one of these.
Oh.
Of end times or whatever long the input is.
So again, these are going to be run of in and of end times.
And if we go down here again, same thing, we don't know what the input is, but these are being run
of end times.
And then finally, this last line is just run once, so it'll be o of one.
So looking at this function, another font challenge function, we see that r o when our big o.
Is one, two, three, four.
So we have four.
Plus because we're just adding up the steps here.
We have over and that's happening.
One, two, three, four, five.
So five and.
So the big O here is we have four constant times and then five things that we're doing.
End times.
Or however long the input is.
All right.
That wasn't so bad, was it, compared to the first time around?
I think you're starting to get the hang of this.
So let's dive into the next video.
Let's start to figure out how we can simplify things for us so that we're not doing this mathematical
step by step count.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.