It's time for another exercise.
We've learned how to create a stack data structure.
But what about a Q data structure?
Luckily for us, a lot of the principles are going to be the same.
And if you are able to understand how the stack data structure works, then you should have no problem
building a Q data structure.
I've created a template to start us off here, and your job is to create these three methods peak,
which we're familiar with.
We want to peak and get the very first item in our queue or our line, as I like to call it.
And in our constructor, instead of having top and bottom like we did with a stack, we have first and
last, whose first in line, whose last in line.
And obviously a length of zero.
And your job is to create and fill out these methods.
On cue, remember is to add to the Q and dx q is to remove from the Q.
Remember that the difference between a stack that uses pop is that DQ removes from the front of the
list whatever is first.
And again, if you want, you can create another method called is empty and your goal is to create this
queue so that you can create a waitlist app where joy gets in line.
Then Matt gets in line, then Pavel gets in line, then Samir gets in line, and then you're queuing
them one by one with first come, first serve basis.
Good luck and I'll see you in The Solution video.