All right.
We're going to do this just for fun.
Usually breath research is implemented the way we saw it, just using a iterative approach.
But for fun, I want to see if we can do a recursive breath for search.
And in order for us to do a recursive breath for search, we can create a new function.
We'll have R here for recursive.
And in here we need to create a base case when to stop and we will stop.
If.
Q dot length is.
Zero.
Or we can just say when queue length is zero like this.
If that's the case, we want to have our base case and return the list.
But you'll notice here that I haven't defined what Q and list is like I did with our iterative approach.
And that's because if I go to the top year and declare these variables like I did, because in a recursive
function, this function will be called over and over, we're going to be resetting these variables
and lists over and over to an empty array.
So the way we would do this in a recursive function is that we need to actually pass.
Q and list as a parameter so that when we call it down here, instead of doing it this way, we'd have
to say.
That the Q will have the this dot root node.
But remember the Q has to be an array.
So we just wrap this in curly brackets and in JavaScript this shows that we have an array with item
of this root, kind of like we did with breath for search the first time around.
Right?
The initial Q had the current node which was this dot root, our root node.
And then the second parameter would be the list.
Our answer, which will start off with an empty array.
So now that we have these and that's a bit of a gotcha when it comes to recursive functions.
We can now do something similar to what we did the first time around with our iterative approach.
We'll say that our current node.
Use let here let cur node equal to this dot q dot shift.
Again.
Same thing as we did up above over here.
To grab the current node.
And then we can actually just copy what we did over here.
If current no left to push the left node.
If current node has a right child, then push it to the queue as well.
So I'm just going to copy this.
And add it over here.
Make sure the indentation is working.
That's better.
And finally, because this is a recursive function, we want to return the.
Function.
So that it goes through again and this time giving it.
The Q and the list.
And I know this can get a little bit confusing.
You might have to look at it, but going through it step by step in your head, you might want to grab
this code after this video to see how it works.
It's not that much different from the iterative approach.
And because this is referring to a method inside of a class, the way it works in JavaScript is we have
to say this dot breath for a search which refers to the class.
Use the method within this class and I notice here that we don't need this for the queue because queue
is just a parameter.
Now we also want to make sure that we push to the list when we're in here.
So just like we did above, we're going to say list dot, push the current node dot value again, exactly
like we've done above here we want to.
Push the list.
The Valley to the list because the list is our answer.
Now if I click run here, I'm going to get an error.
And this is a bit of a gotcha, a little bit JavaScript specific.
And one of the reasons that get frustrating with JavaScript is that this this keyword only works when
we're inside of the class, the binary search tree class outside of this, remember that we have the
tree class that we instantiated.
So this is tree dot root.
And if we.
Ron this.
We now have our list this time done recursively.
I'll leave this for you to play around with.
And see which one you like better.
But both of these now give us the same results.
949 421 615 170.
I'll see you in the next video.