Welcome back.
Now that we've implemented our binary search tree, I want to talk a little bit about balancing our
tree.
Usually in production, you want to have a balanced search tree.
There are two types of trees that are very popular when it comes to this.
Although we built our own binary search tree, you'd most likely in production use something like an
AVL tree or a red black tree that automatically rebalances itself so that we don't have those edge cases
where our balanced tree turns into a linear, unbalanced tree.
Now these topics, we don't need to code ourselves because they are a little bit complex and most of
the time you're using some sort of a library that implements it.
But I do want you to understand how it works.
So I'll leave resources for you for both read Black Tree as well as AVL Trees where if you click here,
you see that visual go also has it to demonstrate for you how it works.
If I want to insert, let's say.
77 and to my evil three.
Nothing's different.
We're adding 77 to the tree.
But if I now add, let's say 80, which will make our tree a little bit unbalanced.
If I hit go.
You'll see that I'm traversing down.
Traversing down.
I add 80.
And then all of a sudden, oh, it's on balanced.
It's going to go back.
And do a little bit of a switch or rotation to balance out the tree to make sure that the levels that
we have in a tree are always balanced.
And then we have rep black trees as well, which does things a little bit differently if let's say we
inserted nine here.
Then let's say we insert ten.
And then finally, let's insert 11.
You'll notice that.
Oh, it's not balanced.
We need to balance it out.
And once again automatically make sure that our tree does get balanced with something called red black
tree.
As you can see, the nodes are red and black here, and that's something that we use to keep track of
when we need to rebalance.
I'll leave resources for you if you want to learn more about them.
Just keep in mind that these two are usually the most popular for balancing binary search trees, and
in interviews you won't have to implement them.
You just need to be able to talk about them and why they are useful.
Something that we should know by now.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.