Another data structure down hash tables.
By now, you should absolutely love them because, well, they're very useful.
They're used everywhere.
And the funny thing is that it's probably the most common interview question where you use a hash table
to optimize something kind of like we saw in our interview question.
By using hash tables, we optimize those nested loops that are own squared.
Two o of n linear time.
This is a question that comes up again and again that I promise you, if you notice this pattern, it
will be extremely useful for you in an interview, and undoubtedly you'll have an instance where you
have to use it and follow this exact same step.
In this section, we learn that hash tables have really fast lookups, but remember, we need a good
collision resolution needed.
Usually we don't need to worry about this because our language and computer underneath the hood take
care of that for us.
It allows us to do fast inserts and depending on the type of hash tables such as maps and JavaScript,
we can have flexible keys instead of an array that has zero one, two, three, just numbered indexes.
The downside with hash tables is that it is unordered.
It's hard to really go through everything in order.
And also it has slow key iteration.
That is, if I want to grab all the keys from a hash table, I'll have to go through the entire memory
space as we saw when we built our own hash table.
Looking at the big cheat sheet.
We can see that.
Hash tables has a search insertion deletion of all of one, but in worst case due to collision there
are some o of MN operations that could happen.
And if we go to our.
Mind map.
We can now cross off hash tables off our list.
We understand the big complexity.
We also understand that with collisions, we might want to use something like link lists, which we'll
talk about very shortly.
In our exercise, we just simply used arrays.
We also learned the idea that hash tables and interviews are usually useful for improving time complexity,
especially of nested loops.
The trade off being that we can have fast access but more memory.
Going back to our question that we had a few lessons ago where we had to find the common item of two
arrays.
We had array one and array two, and we had to see if any of these arrays contain similar items.
We had one that didn't, and the second version where X and X both arrays contained X, it would return.
True, our first iteration of that exercise we had to use two for loops that were nested.
So that created a times B complexity.
However, using hash maps, we were able to just do one for loop and optimize this function.
Like I said before, this is such a common pattern that we'll be talking about it later on in the course
as well when we talk about dynamic programming.
If we go back to our cheat sheet that I shared with you at the beginning of this course, we can now
cross off a few things off the list that we haven't talked about in the good code checklist.
We talked about the good use of data structures, when to use hash tables over perhaps arrays.
The idea of code reuse and not repeating yourself is something we've been following and should be familiar
to all of us.
We also talked about modular code and making code more readable, which allows code to be more maintainable
and testable.
We talked about how usually in an interview we want to avoid the O and squared operations and we saw
that we're able to do that with hash tables.
But we did see that with a hash table.
We had to increase our space complexity to o of MN because we created this new variable that keeps track
of all the items in the array.
So that is the trade off.
And then we can cross off a few heuristics.
For those who don't know, heuristics are kind of like rules or simple tricks that are going to come
up over and over and over that you can use in an interview.
Hash maps or hash tables.
Are usually the answer to improve time complexity.
Again, hash tables.
Are some of the best way to optimize your code.
And looking at time versus space trade off, sometimes storing extra state and memory like we did with
hash tables can help the time or the runtime.
And then finally, space time trade offs.
Hash tables usually solve this a lot of the time.
You use more space, but you can get a time optimization to the process.
I know we've only talked about two data structures, but I think these two are the most important.
Moving forward, we're going to use them to learn about others.
Good job getting this far.
Take a nice little break.
Have some coffee and I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.