Welcome back.
Now, in the previous exercise and the exercise we just did, we see that we had to do a bit of calculation
and it was kind of annoying where we had to add things up, then have this plus five and plus four in
interviews.
You're never going to do this.
And you're asking yourself, Andre, why did you just teach me this?
And you're right, but now you at least understand how big O gets calculated.
But most of the time when you go into interviews, there's these set of rules that you're going to follow
where you don't need to do this, and you can just take a look at this function and immediately say
what type of big o it is.
For example, this function actually just turns into O of n.
This function.
Again turns into just o of n.
And this is a nifty little trick.
When we talk about Big O in interviews, most of the time you're only going to give one of these answers.
You're most likely never going to actually calculate precisely o of three n or of three n plus two plus
one.
So how was I able to simplify our exercises and just say that they're own?
And luckily for you, there's just several rules that we can follow when it comes to they go and there's
only four of them.
By following these four rules, instead of doing those small little calculations that we've been doing
up until this moment, you can just simplify your life so that big becomes really, really easy to calculate.
Let's tackle the first one.
That is rule number one.
Worst case.
Let's talk about that in the next video.