Welcome back.
Let's talk about depth for a search now.
We've implemented our breath for search and we feel comfortable for that.
But what about depth for a search going down our tree and exploring the deepest part of that tree before
we come back up?
And explore the right side of the tree as well.
And when it comes to depth first search, we have to be aware that there's three ways that we can actually
implement it.
It's called In Order, pre-order and post order.
Remember how we had.
The list that we got with breath for search.
Well, there's three different orders that we can return this list with depth for search.
The first one is called in order and it looks something like this.
We go with 30 3101105.
It's called an order because in a binary search tree, it gives everything in order.
If we take a look at this list.
Or this tree ideally in a in order traversal.
Using depth first search.
We would get something like this.
We would get one.
Then for.
Then six because we go one for six.
And then we go nine.
And then we go all the way down to 15.
And then we come back up to 20.
And then to 170, it's in order because well, look at that.
Everything is in order.
So this is really useful if you have a binary search tree like this.
And now the way that you can return it is called pre order.
And pre order starts off from the parent node down to 33 and then down to 105.
So we start off with the parent and then grab the child nodes left to right.
In our case, it would look something like this.
We would start off with nine because it's the parent one and then we grab four.
Because it's the next one in the list.
And then we go one.
As we're traversing all the way down.
Remember, we're doing depth for search, so all the way down.
And because we got to the very bottom, we now go back up and down to six.
So we see here we did 416.
And then we go to the right side to 20 and then grab 15, then 170.
And you're asking yourself, this seems kind of useless.
Why would we ever want to use pre-order?
I mean, in order we had everything in order, why would we ever need this?
And pre-order is really useful if you want to, for example, recreate a tree.
Right?
Because with preorder, I can just go nine is the root node.
Then we have four as the left hand side, one as the left hand side.
And then from there we have six.
On the right.
20 to the right of 915 and then 170.
We can recreate a tree really easily because it's ordered for us versus the in order method that didn't
have that order that we wanted if we wanted to recreate a tree another way.
And the last way to do this is called post order.
And post order is the last option that is going all the way down, grabbing 33 and 105, then going
to the top to the parent.
So 33, 105.
101.
So in our case, a post ordered depth first search would look like one.
Then six.
Then for.
And then going back up all the way down to 15, then 170, then 20, and then finally nine.
We searched the left hand side first.
The children come before the parent, and then we search the right hand side first, and the children
come before the parent.
Now, these three types of ordering are really specific, and although it may look confusing right now.
You'll see that when we write it in code.
It's not that difficult.
You just need to know that when it comes to depth for a search, you have these three types of reversals
that you can do that you may want to implement depending on your needs.
But the easiest way to show you how this works is well, to actually do it, encode it.
So let's do that in the next video.