Welcome back.
One of the most common interview questions when it comes to Q's and Stacks is this one.
Implement a cue using stacks.
Huh?
Yep.
You can implement Q's using stacks.
And it's especially easy if you create a stack using arrays.
Now this question is on lead code, which is really, really nice because we're able to see the solutions.
Explained.
As well as solutions in different languages.
If you go to discuss and type in, let's say JavaScript.
We get solutions that people have submitted.
You can see votes as well of the answer of how to do this.
If you want to check Python because let's say you're writing in Python.
Well they have that to.
Any language you want you can find here.
Now I have the answer for you as well.
And in this video right around here and the available resources, you'll see a ripple with my answer
on it.
But I want to challenge you and pretend you're in an interview to implement Q Using stacks.
How would you go about doing it?
You can actually even code it on the elite code website if you want.
Using whichever language you want and just a heads up here, if you are using JavaScript that they use
the prototype way of adding methods.
But the class syntax that I showed you is the newer version.
It's underneath the hood.
It's the exact same thing as doing dot prototype.
However, it just looks cleaner using the class syntax.
So that's what we did.
So good luck with that.
Have fun and I'll link to the solution code for you right over here.