And there we have it.
We've learned Stacks and Qs.
And an easy way to remember them is just simply plates and waiting line.
We learned why they're built on top of other data structures like link lists and arrays.
And we also talked about how to build stacks with the raise and link lists and also why we might not
want to use an array to build queues and also built a queue data structure with link lists.
We learned that stacks and queues are great for some fast operations that they have, such as removing
or inserting, such as at the end of the data structure.
We can also access the very first item in a queue or the very top item in a stack.
And we also have all our data ordered, which is really, really nice, but we don't usually use our
stacks or Qs to really do any sort of lookup or search through the data structure.
All we're interested in is the end bits of the data structure, so they make it really useful by restricting
our use of what we can do when it comes to Stacks and Qs, but making sure that what we're allowed to
do with these data structures are going to be really, really fast.
And there we have it.
We've continued to expand our mind map of data structures.
So we completed our stacks.
We learned how to create stacks with arrays and link lists.
We've learned about their bingo notation and we also talked about Qs and how we wouldn't really want
to use an array for our cue.
A very common interview question.
We learned how to use a linked list to create a queue, and also we learned about the bingo implications,
which is very similar to stacks.
We're getting closer and closer to filling out this mind map.
But before we do that, we still have a few more data structures to go.
But the end is almost near.
We only have trees and graphs to talk about.
For that.
I'll see you in the next part.