Welcome back.
I wanted to add a quick gotcha when it comes to heaps.
That is when you hear memory heaps.
That's not the same as the heap data structure.
You might have heard of memory heaps in something like a JavaScript runtime engine where we have a stack
and a heap, the two locations where we are able to keep memory.
Now this heap you can think of as free storage is a region in our memory where we can store arbitrary
data.
Languages like C also have this heap.
Now the naming is just coincidental and heap has no real relationship with the data structure that is
named Heap.
Keep that in mind.
Heap is simply a heap of memory.
If you're talking about a language runtime, for example, versus a heap data structure, which is what
we're talking about now.
I want us to clarify that for you, because when I was learning about heaps for some reason, I always
thought they were the same thing.
But they're not just throwing it out there.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.