Welcome back.
The beauty of what we just learned in tree traversal, which was oh and we're visiting every node is
that it's the same as in graph traversal because trees are just simply a type of graph.
So using the same technique instead of using left and right properties, perhaps there's ten children.
Well, we can do the same thing using depth, first search and breath, first search.
And this is really powerful, right?
Because graphs are used to model real life models, such as a recommendation engine in Amazon.
We can now see what type of items are perhaps related or the closest relation to the last book that
we bought.
And in that case they would use something like breath for a search or on Facebook to see what type of
friend requests I should be recommended.
If I have a connection on LinkedIn, perhaps I might use depth for a search to see what degree of connection
I have with that really important SEO.
We use depth for search.
And these are the bases of how peer to peer networks work, how Google Maps works.
Right.
Which is really, really powerful.
And I have a nice visual here.
I have our visual all go here.
Our good friend.
And they have left for search.
And I made this little graph and we can traverse now using actually let's do breath for a search first
and we'll start off with zero.
So I'm going to enter zero in here and see how depth where search would work.
We check all the closest nodes.
One, three, four, five, six, and then we start with one.
Does it have any children?
Yeah, two, seven and eight.
And then we go next in line three.
What about four?
What about five?
What about six?
They don't have any children.
Okay.
Let's go.
Keep going down to the next place that has children.
And we traverse the graph, as you can see, starting with the our closest neighbors and then going
further and further out with a depth for a search.
Let's say we're starting at zero.
And I hit go.
We go to one.
Then to.
Then seven.
And then we're going to keep going deeper.
Eight.
We're going to go to nine, then ten.
There's no more nodes, so we're going to go all the way back and go to the next in the list.
That is three.
Then four, then five, then six.
So just by looking at this, you might see what I meant when I gave you the information at the beginning
of this section.
That is, breadth for search is usually good for shortest path.
That is what's the closest to our node?
What are the most related items on Amazon?
Who are our closest friends on Facebook or closest connections on LinkedIn?
Versus depth first search, which is really good to see if something exists.
With death research, we're able to go really deep into a graph fairly fast, then breath for search
that might cost a bit of extra memory.
Let's talk about these two algorithms in more detail when it comes to graphs.