How was Mercer Short?
Pretty difficult, right?
I have the answer for you here.
And I'm not going to coat along because, well, this is one of those pieces of code that me just writing
in and typing it in a 30 minute video isn't really going to help your understanding.
I recommend that you go through this code line by line to fully understand it.
But if we take a look here, all we're doing in the first pass in the merge sort function is we're going
to get the length of the array, find the middle of the array, and then we're going to slice the array
into the left hand side and the right hand side.
So that if I console.log here.
And I click Run.
We see that the first time around.
We're just splitting the item right down the middle where we have 99 all the way up to one in the left
hand side and 5 to 0 in the right hand side.
In the next pass.
Because remember, we're doing recursion and this is being called again.
When we get to here, we're now dividing up 99 and 44 and 6 to 1 into its own past, and then 99 and
44 into individual items, six and two, one into left and right until we have.
Everything into one item.
And then we start splitting off this inside as well.
Now what about the merge function?
The merge function is going to be a little bit hard to read.
But if we take a look here, all we're saying is we have a results array that we're going to fill everything
with and we're going to have a left index and a right index.
And we're going to compare here is the left index.
Less than the length of the left array and the right index, less than their right array length, which
may make sure that we have items in our array.
If that's the case, then let's compare our left item to the right item.
And push into a new ray into our results.
Ray The item that is less in this case, it will be the left hand item and then we increment.
Otherwise, if the left item is higher than the right item, we do the opposite and the right item goes
into our results.
Remember this merge function is doing what we saw in the animation.
We're splitting the function down in the first part of the function and then in the merge we're going
to take the left and right.
Compare it and place it into the results array.
And then go to the next.
And keep doing this over and over and creating our results array.
If I console.log here left and right and I click run.
We see exactly what we're doing.
We have 99 and 44 and then two and one.
So on the left hand side and right hand side, 99 and 44 get compared becomes 44 and 99.
And then we compare two and one, which becomes one and two, then six and one and two, which becomes
1 to 6.
And we keep going, keep going, keep going until the very last step where we have two lists here and
we compare them zero and one, we place zero.
And the results are a.
And then we place one, two and just keeps going and keeps going.
Exactly like our animation.
Now, I encourage you to play around with this and perhaps go step by step.
It is a really hard algorithm to get.
The bad news is that the next algorithm is even more complicated.
But luckily for you, as I said, you won't have to ever do this in an interview.
You just need to know that Merge sort is a great algorithm to use because we get o of n log n.
Big o.
Let's take a look at another sorting algorithm.