Now we learned about binary heaps and we mentioned that unlike a binary search tree, there is no order
from left to right.
This 33 and 77, we can swap them and it will still be a binary heap.
The beauty of binary heaps is that they take up the least amount of space possible because it's always
left to right insertion, as we just saw.
So there's no concept of an unbalanced binary heap.
We don't have to rebalance it like a binary search tree because of this, because they do left to right
insertion, as we saw in the previous video, they preserve this order of insertion.
Which is pretty amazing, right?
And you can actually implement binary heaps using arrays versus what we did before with binary search
trees where we used nodes.
So the only guarantee that binary heap gives us is what I mentioned.
The parent is always greater than the children.
Now, besides being memory efficient and just compact because it's always a complete binary tree.
Binary heaps are really, really useful for things such as priority queues.
And you might be asking yourself priority.
Q Didn't we just learn about cues?
And isn't that the same data structure?
Well, no, because with Q's we just assume that it was first in first up.
You were the first person in line.
You should get to go first into the roller coaster or the movies priority.
Q Is something different?
It is a type of data where each element has a priority.
And elements with a higher priority are served before elements with lower priorities.
You can think of this as a club.
Let's say we have a nightclub that is very, very popular and there's a long lineup and we let some
people in.
Everybody's happy.
But then all of a sudden, Oh, we have some VIPs that showed up.
Well, they pay a lot more money than the other customers, so we're going to let them in first.
So now we have a different priority where even though they arrived later, they get to go in.
They have higher priority.
Another good example is an emergency room.
You want to treat the patients that have the most severe symptoms or conditions, right.
Another way to think about it is let's say we're lining up to get into an airplane.
We have the first person coming in, lining up, and then all of a sudden the captain shows up.
And because the captain should get on the airplane before a normal passenger.
The Captain gets now put as priority as the root note because the value is higher, or at least in this
case, the value is higher than the passenger.
So let's say A now their passenger comes on because we're doing left to right insertion.
We put the passenger to the right.
So now we know we're going to let the captain go in.
Then the first passenger, then the second passenger.
Next we have a stewardess that came in.
He or she should get to go before the passengers, but not before the captain.
Well, in that case, once again, we place the stewardess below the captain, but to the right or to
the left of the passenger.
And then we have another passenger that comes.
We do left to right insertion.
We see a right spot down here.
So we place them down here.
So we see how everything gets balanced, which is nice, but it's also really, really easy for us to
now let people into the airplane because we know the order.
We go from the top, then left, then right, then left, then right, left, right.
And we just keep going, keep going, keep going.
We know the priority very easily.
I'm sure you see where this might be useful in a lot of situation.
To review, we learned what binary search trees are.
They're great, but sometimes binary heaps or priority queues are even better.
Although searching through a binary heap is a lot slower than a binary search tree, you have an idea
of priority because insertion is done in order.
So you know who should be first?
Who should be second?
Who should be third?
And although we might have to bubble up inserts every once in a while if there's somebody that is has
really high priority.
Most of the time you get really fast answers with binary heaps.
And as we mentioned, lookups are slow, but you want to use binary heaps when you're just interested
in finding the max or finding the minimum if it's a min heap and a lot of the times in binary heaps
and priority, cuz you have a method called find max or find min that is o of one because you know right
away that the top root node is the max or the minimum.
So for those operations it's really, really fast and great.
And there you have it.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.