One common interview question that you might get is something along the lines of log all pairs of array.
Now, what does that actually mean?
Well, if we had an array, we'll just say boxes.
And this array is just.
Contains boxes numbered one through five.
Now this array if I want to log all pairs.
It means that I want to log one, two, then one, three, then one, four, then one, five, then
two, one, then 2 to 2, three to 4 to 5.
So on and so forth.
How will we go about doing that?
And if you want, you can pause the video and try to attempt this problem yourself.
Now in this case, what we want to do is, well, we create a function and we'll say log all pairs of
array that receives an array.
Let's just say array.
So we're descriptive here and in here.
We will do a four loop.
So for.
Let I.
Equals zero.
And we've done this before.
So if I is less than the array length and we'll increment I.
Now in here we want to loop.
So now in the first iteration of the for loop, we'll grab one, but then we want to loop through the
boxes again and log 111, two, one, three, 1415.
So we have another for loop.
And this time we'll say Let J equals zero.
If we want to loop from the beginning, or I could even say one if we want to start off with one, two,
because we're starting off at index of one right here.
For now, we can just leave it at zero, and we'll say that as long as J.
Is less than a dot length.
And we'll increment.
JJ.
And now finally in here I can just say console.log.
I and J.
Let's run this function and see what happens.
Oh, I have to actually call this function, so let's do that log.
All pairs of a ray and I'll give it the boxes array.
Oh.
And we want to make sure here that we're logging out the actual items and not the index of the array.
So we'll just say.
Ray.
I hear and the array.
Jay here.
And just so you don't get confused with the numbers.
Maybe we'll change these into letters so that it's more obvious what we're doing.
See.
D That's not D, that's D And we'll say.
E So if I click run here.
We see that we're logging all pears.
Aye, aye, aye.
Be a.
Keeps going.
Keeps going until e you can see the log over here.
What is the big o of this?
And this is something that you're going to see a lot of in interviews.
And a good rule of thumb is if you see nested loops, that means instead of having to for loops one
after another where we use addition, when you see loops that are nested, we use multiplication.
So this becomes o.
Of n times o.
Of n.
Which when we multiply them, becomes o of n.
Squared.
Oh.
To the end.
To the power of two.
And that's a good rule of thumb.
And if we go back to our graph, this function that we just created and I'm using the S five syntax
here instead of the four loops we did this over and squared is what we call quadratic time.
That means every time the number of elements increase.
So let's say we have two elements.
We have four operations that we do.
If we have three elements, this actually increases quadratic.
B That means instead of four operations, we now have one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine.
Because we have three elements to the power of two.
And you see here how the line is now bent and it increases, well, quite fast.
If we go back to our big old notation or big o graph, we see that O of n squared.
Well, it's horrible.
As in it's pretty slow as the number of elements increases, the number of operations increases significantly.
And a lot of interview questions are questions that ask you to solve a problem that initially is over
and squared and make it faster by perhaps making it into something that is a bit lower over here that
is is bad, fair, good.
Excellent, but definitely not horrible.
If we go back to our rule number three that we were discussing.
Different terms for inputs.
Well, going back to that example we had in the previous video.
Remember this?
Well, we said O of A plus B because we had two different arrays or inputs.
Now, if these loops were actually nested and they're not one after another.
The big o would have been o of a times b.
And that is rule number three, making sure to know that we have different arrays.
That means different notation for each array because we don't know the lengths.
And an easy rule of thumb is any step that happens in the same indentation.
So one after another you add.
And anything that happens with indentation that is nested.
You multiply.
So, again, different inputs should have different variables.
Let's move on to the last rule in the next video.