Welcome back.
We've learned about singly and doubly linked lists.
So let's talk about when you should use one over the other.
Let's start with the singly linked list.
The pro of a singly linked list is that it's a fairly simple implementation, especially compared to
the one.
It requires lesser memory, as we can see here, less block And because there's less memory when we
do things like delete and insert, because there is technically less operation, we don't have to move
around the previous property, it's a little bit faster.
Now the downside with a singly linked list is that it cannot be iterated in reverse or traverse from
back to front.
If we ever lose the reference to this dot head node of the list, the list can actually be lost in memory
forever.
So singly list is appropriate to use when you have less memory or memory is really expensive and you
want to be careful of how much you use.
And your main goal is that you want to do fast insertion and deletion and you don't really have that
much searching, especially when you have insertion at the beginning of a list.
A doubly linked list.
Well, the good side of it is that it can be iterated or traversed both from the front or from the back.
Another beauty is that if you need to delete a previous node, you don't need to traverse from the head
node and find what the previous node is which a singly list linked list has no concept of.
You can do that fairly easily with a doubly link list.
Now the downside is that it is fairly complex as we saw to implement and it requires more memory and
storage because of this extra property.
And there are some extra operations that we need to perform to make sure that we when we do insert and
delete that the previous property is updated as well.
So doubly link lists are really good when you don't have that much limitation on memory.
And when you want good operation for searching for elements such as searching backwards instead of just
forwards.
Most of the time in interview situations, you're going to see singly linked list.
You may be asked a theoretical or broad question about the difference between singly and W linked list,
but most of the time this is what you're going to see.
All right.
I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.