Let's quickly talk about a big old notation that you're most likely not going to encounter.
And if you're writing any code that has this big notation, you're definitely doing something wrong.
It's the most expensive one.
It's the steepest of them all.
And this is called factorial time or as I like to call it, the.
Oh, no.
We're not even going to do a demonstration on this because you're just not going to encounter it.
I just want to show you that it exists with O and factorial, and this is a mathematical notation with
the exclamation mark.
You can search for it and see how it works underneath the hood.
But with this, it means that we're adding a nested loop for every input that we have.
Yeah.
That sounds pretty terrible, doesn't it?
Again, just to keep in mind and to get this out of the way on factorial.
Probably never going to see it, but it's still it's there and it kind of looks cool.
So we can cross another one off our cheat sheet.
On factorial, you're adding a loop for every element that you're iterating over.
Yeah, it's an expensive one we're not going to see in much.
So I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.