Welcome back.
I wanted to have just a quick video to tell you about something interesting.
And this depends on your language.
But remember the sort method that we had in JavaScript.
Or perhaps your language.
I challenge you to figure out what sort of sorting algorithm it's using underneath the hood.
Now, in most cases, it's either going to be quicksort or insertion sort and merge, sort, combine
together.
So go out and search what sorting algorithm your language uses.
When it comes to JavaScript, there's actually no requirements to JavaScript as to which sorting algorithm
to use.
We have a script and JavaScript, which is the standard, but because the standard doesn't mention how
this should be implemented, different browsers that have different JavaScript engines, Chrome has
V8, Mozilla has its own engine, safari it's own engine.
They all implement them differently.
Well last time I checked in Mozilla they use merge sort for sorting and in Chrome and the V8 engine
sort is implemented with quicksort and also insertion sort for the smaller arrays.
I thought that was interesting.
Anyway, I'll see you in the next video.
Bye bye.