Whoo!
Another section done.
And we covered sorting, specifically sorting algorithm in this section.
Most of the time, when talking about sorting algorithms, we're going to be talking about o of n log
n.
We learned that there is a ton of sorting algorithms and we covered the main ones that get used more
often.
If you're really excited about the topic and you find this interesting, then well, good for you.
You're one of few.
I encourage you to search different sorting algorithms.
But to review quicksort you want to use when your average case performance matters more than the worst
case performance.
Because QuickSort allows us to sort in own log n, but in worst case in o of n squared.
Mercer, on the other hand.
Is great because it's always o of n log n, it's also stable, which means that it always gives the
same results in order.
If two items are the same.
Although the space complexity is a little bit higher than quicksort, it's definitely a useful sort.
We also talked about insertion sort, selection sort and bubble sort.
Those are fun when you're doing something quick and dirty and you want to just experiment around with
sorting, but in real life you're not going to use them.
And most likely in real life you're using the framework or languages or libraries sorting algorithm.
Their advantage is that they're fairly easy to implement in code.
And during the interview you might say something like this.
In those rare cases that they ask you to implement a sorting algorithm, you'll say, Well, because
we have a time constraint, I would like to use something naive and not efficient, like bubble sort,
which is slow in real life.
Instead of implementing something like merge sort, if it's okay with you because because we can assume
that merge sort is something that we can implement with a library or fairly easily with documentation.
Or you can say something like we can just use Mercer to divide and conquer the code to make it more
efficient.
And this way you show the interviewer that yes, you can implement sorting like bubble sort, but you
also know about things like Mercer to make it more efficient without having to actually implement it.
So by the end of this all, I hope you now understand the trade offs where you can look at sorting algorithms
and decide based on their speed, stability and their readability whether the input is already sorted
or nearly sorted.
How large is the input?
You can make the right decision on sorting.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.