Hello welcome to the course on Dollar Signs.
I'm super excited to have you here.
And we're going to have a fantastic journey together.
We're going to dive into four separate rounds of dollar signs and each one will feel like the convention
.
And in this quick tutorial I just wanted to introduce myself quickly and give you an outline of the
course.
So my name is Tor Maiko and I have been in this field for about five years.
I have worked for companies as a scientist and for consulting as a scientist I worked at a stranger
and I had exposure to many different industries and developed lots of skills and experiences which I
wanted to share with you in this course and moving onto the course outline.
I'm just going to jump behind my computer and I'll walk you through the different sections of the course
so that you know how to navigate there.
All right back behind the computer and here I've got the course as we see it.
So I'm going to zoom in a little bit so we can see everything a bit better.
And at the top here we've got the get excited section that's where we are right now.
Then we have that what is data science section which is a bit of an extended introduction into data
science and it tells you about the different areas or domains of data science.
Why data science is going to just grow in demand and is going to be a very popular profession in the
future and why you want to be on this wave early.
And also there's an important story here which is called course pathways.
Now this tutorial is important because it will allow you to create your own learning experience based
of the sections in this course.
And let me explain in a bit more detail what I mean here.
So here we've got Section 3 part one installation there is four parts to the course and they are quite
substantial So they have lots and lots of lectures and you might want to go through them in the order
that they laid out or you might want to combine them into your own learning experience based on what
you are after in terms of learning data science.
So here we've got Tablo eras.
We're using Tablo because it allows us to do visual data mining a very interesting topic which we cover
off.
Then we get an introduction here this introduction to Tablo then I explain how to use Tablo for data
mining.
Then I will show you how to do advanced data mining in Tablo we actually talk about statistical significance
of your data mining based on chi square tests.
Then Part two is modeling so we won't go through all the sections right now but because there's just
a lot of them but basically we refresh our stats in this section and then we learn how to build model
step by step.
So we go through simple linear regression multiple linear regression logistic regression building a
robust demographic segmentation model then we'll learn how to assess the model then we learn how to
draw insights from your model.
We will learn about model maintenance.
We will learn modeling tips and tricks and then we will move on to data preparation.
So this is part three and here this is also a very big part here we're going to learn what business
intelligence tools are and we'll set up all the software for this part of the course then we will talk
about data wrangling before the load.
We'll talk about how to use Sosias for uploading your daughter.
Then we will talk about how to handle errors.
And this is going to add some real Listen to what we're doing.
So there'll be very realistic errors that you will find in real life scenarios.
And here we will learn how to program in school for our science so some basics of skill programming
which we'll need in further sections.
Then we will learn how to perform data wrangling after we have loaded data into a database.
Then we will learn how to handle errors during the last phase of our extractions from load process and
there will be also another very realistic daughter said here.
So you will learn everything about cleaning data.
And finally part for communication.
So this is the part where we talk about how to work with people in the section we talk about how to
work with people and extract information from them to using your data science projects.
And in this section we learn how to present data science projects.
And I actually give you some case studies of my own presentations.
And finally at the end we've got some homework solutions because there will be homework throughout the
course.
So that's how this course works.
Make sure that you check out that tutorial that I mentioned on creating your own pathway because it
will also help you understand how you can structure these sections to gain the maximum benefit in your
specific situation.
And I look forward to seeing inside the course and until next I'm happy analyzing