Is
welcome to the modeling part of the course you're about to embark upon a journey which is interesting
and challenging which will take you from not knowing anything about stats to be able to build a full
fledged statistical model and to add that we're talking about building them all assessing them while
testing the model deriving insights from them all and even maintaining a model post delivery.
This section has over 50 lectures and we'll feel like a separate course in itself.
And that is why I wanted to take some time to make sure that our expectations are set before you commit
to this journey.
So let's go over some key goals that we want to cover off in this part of the course.
Keypoint number one there is a huge tendency these days to associate data science with our programming
and programming.
This quarter is not like that.
My goal is not to teach you our programming or Python programming.
My goal is to teach you how to be a scientist how to think like a data scientist how to create models
and what tools you use whether it's SPSS SAS or Python.
You can use any tool later on after you have learned the fundamentals of creating a model.
And so with that in mind we won't be going through our programming.
I won't be teaching you how to program an R R has a very steep learning curve and it could take a whole
separate course to teach you how to program it.
And I don't want to get bogged down in all of the coding.
I would rather focus on the actual modeling part of the things and explain the intrinsics of moment
to you because I personally believe that that is way more valuable.
And with that in mind we're going to be using a visual software package which is called Grettel it's
free and able to download it and stole it and that will allow us to get rid of that whole part.
We have to think about coding and understand it and you know like learn a lot of stuff about our in
order to get to the end result.
We can just actually focus on the motorway.
Point number two as mentioned before our end goal is to be able to build a full fledged statistical
model.
However I don't want to just give you a set of mechanical steps that need to fold to get to the end
result.
I want to help you understand what exactly is going on when you're running these small.
And that's why I will be focusing quite a bit on intuitional things.
We'll talk about the intuitional logistic regression.
We'll talk about intuitional multicollinearity and quite a few other aspects.
So by the end of this part of the course you should not only be able to create the model but be able
to intrinsically understand what is going on in the background when you're running.
And finally in order to get to our end goal step by step I have broken down this part of the course
into logical sections.
First we will have a stat's refresh.
Then we will talk about the simple linear regression.
Then we will move onto the multiple linear regression after that we will talk about the logistic regression
and then we will build our geo demographic segmentation model and after we've built it we will learn
how to test and assess our model then we will learn how to derive insights from our model then we will
talk about how we can maintain our model post-delivery and fight any kind of deterioration that might
be going on.
And finally at the very end of this part of the course I will give you some extra tips tricks and hacks
that you can take away to really improve your modeling.
So that's what we're going to be talking about in this part of the course.
I really hope you enjoy this journey and go through it all the way with me and I look forward to seeing
in the first section