Grade so last though we talked about creating a template for prox and today I'll give you another handy
trick.
That is not timesaving but is disaster saving.
I would say so this causes we're going to talk about archiving approx.
And a very important step.
So if let's say I'm working on transactional data and you see here that I have these converts and I've
decided actually I don't really need these converts I want to change something in this proc.
Well you once you've changed something you've save the proc you don't have that previous version right
.
So you have at least you have what you've saved which is good but you don't have the previous version
and a good way to to archive your prox or to save it is to archive the current version as is before
you make the change.
So how do you do that.
Well once you have the proc open so let's say I want to modify this proc but I want to save the version
as it is right now.
So first thing click modify alter so you have this code in front of you when you're in your script in
a skill.
Now before you do any changes before you do anything go to this proc and original that you just opened
and changed the name.
So at the start put in zeds it said That's what I usually put underscore b c keep b c k p and then the
date 2000 underscore actually underscore Day 2015 0 8 10 and then underscore.
So what does this tell me.
First of all when they click enter.
This means that this proc will automatically because it does with a zed who will dramatically go to
the bottom of my of this Kema.
So we don't we didn't talk about Skinner's reskill go to the bottom of of this folder of the stored
procedures folder.
And that means it won't bother me anymore it'll be at the bottom.
I know I have at the top I have all of my templates at the bottom I have all of my other prox or all
of the backups.
And in the middle I have all the stuff that I'm working with.
And once you have you know a hundred projects that you're working with It'll be very convenient that
these backups and these templates are not in your way there at the top at the bottom and also be convenient
that they actually have all the same structure.
So once you if you ever want to restore something then you just go to the backups which are at the bottom
and you look for the right date and you see.
OK so that's that's a date when I want to restore from.
And there is that table that I was looking for.
And as you recall products from different projects shouldn't mix up because we'll have a separate database
or a separate schema.
Hopefully if you can talk your DBA into it you'll have a separate database schema for every single product
but we get sidetracked.
So I've backed up this proc and now this proc no longer exists.
I can if I run this code if I execute now I'll get an error.
Why.
Well because I'm trying to alter an object that no longer exists.
How do we fix that.
Very simple.
It just changes to create execute.
Now you've exited it successfully So now you're very fresh here.
You'll see that this proc is back here and I already and I have a copy as well.
And now I will go back to my proc.
I'll press contrails Zed to return to alter so I just reverted that operation and now I can change it
as much as I like so if I go here and I changed convert or get rid of the convert.
As we discussed implicit conversion works just fine for us in these cases.
And I click execute.
Voila everything is good.
And now if I close this.
If it closes.
Now if I open up my current proc and then if I open up my backup and I put my backup to the side you
will see that in my current proc there is no implicit explicit conversion in my backup.
There is explicit conversion and so that's how you backup your file.
That's my proposed approach you can come up with your own approaches.
For instance you could press control S and save the file or instead of changing the name here before
you change before you change the proc you could actually use or create and create the backup by by specifying
the Zed's here.
But I think all of that is way more tedious.
This is the Fosse's approach that I've naturally come up with through years of my experience and I'm
happy for you to steal it away and use it in your work.