Know that we're in phase three of the tail process which is the final phase I thought it would be a
good idea to take a step back and look at the e-tail process as a whole at all of the three phases I
understand how they work together.
And then in the same tutorial we will also look in a bit more detail at what we will be learning in
phase 3 What exactly will be and hence the name for this tutorial.
We're all work GRV.
So let's get straight into it.
In our e-mail process in phase 1.
This was before Sosias we did some cleaning so we took the original data we put into the prepared folder
.
We looked at it using specific methods like opening text files in Excel to understand the formats of
the data and to format dates and dollars and other Scovel columns correctly so that when we pulled the
data we have less headache and then we put that file into the uploaded folder in e-tail Phase 2.
The goal was to get the file from the uploaded folder into the wrong table in our database.
And this was all done in SOSIAS.
And also as an intermediate step we had conditional splits sometimes you might need those to filter
certain roles out of your data which you cannot analyze because it corruptor there's insufficient data
.
So this part was only focusing on getting the file or the data from the file into the database.
And that was e-tail face too.
And finally in this section we're talking about e-tail face three.
And here we will be dealing will start with 4.0 in the row format then we will move it into the work
into a working table then we will move it into a derived table and all of this will be done in escrow
.
So we've already talked about a lot of retail and done a lot of practice with retail Phase 1 and Phase
2.
Let's talk a bit more detail about e-tail Phase 3 right now so that we're a bit more comfortable with
what's going on in this whole section of the course.
So in e-tail Phase 3 we start with the daughter in our rule table.
Next we want to move the door into a working table why it will because the road table it's all formatted
as Text and we want it's formatted properly so we want numbers with decimal points to be formatted as
floats numbers for decimal points or whole numbers on the formatters integers to go on dates formatted
as states not as text and so on so that our analytical tools can work with these values correctly with
all of our fields correctly and in order to do this transition from war or to work we have to engage
in a process which I call build and in short BLT.
And basically we're building a new working table from scratch in our database and then we're populating
it with data coming from our raw table.
And in order to facilitate this process we're going to use something which is called a stored procedure
.
We'll talk more about store procedures in the coming to Charles in this section.
But basically a stored procedure is a script in a skill which you can save.
So whatever you write in that sort of procedure that's the way we'll be looking at it is it's like a
encapsulation for code which you can execute and create the new working table.
But also if you exit it in a different way you can actually save your code and we'll talk more about
that in the coming.
But just conceptually this is how it works to get from a raw table to working table.
You have to have this procedure which will which will code and which will build your working table for
you and populated with the dog.
And here I'd like to highlight that this is practically the end of the e-tail process so once you have
the working table you're pretty much done.
You can connect different analytical tools like Tablo or Python and other tools to your working table
and extract the data and perform all of the manipulations that you need do the visualisations run the
models and so on.
So that is where our e-tail phase ends.
However you can take it a step further and I'll show you this in the course as well.
You can take it to a GRV table GRV tables a derived table so basically once you're working tables are
ready you might want to combine them in certain ways.
And although you can do that in your analytical tools and Tablo and on and so on it might be a bit easier
to do it as well because that is one of the biggest advantages of a skill that it is very good at Daughter
manipulation and allows you to combine tables very well that's what it is designed for.
So it's a storage facility.
And also it allows you to manipulate data very very easily got all the functionality for that.
So if you do decide to go upon embark upon this journey and create some derived tables were you combining
tables or do some aggregations on your tables then you also need a building process.
Once again this is just terminology that I use.
It's not it's not a native Asgill terminology.
And for this we will have a different proc.
So a procedure to and so procedure one proceeded to here related to your specific table the table that
you started with in raw.
If you have multiple tables and each one of them will go through this process.
And once again that is as long as you want to get to the GRV stage in in reality your e-tail and to
the left of this vertical line so once you have your working table you're done with your e-tail process
and from there you can do analytics.
However it is convenient.
While we are in a skill to sometimes connect the tables and move on to a GRV table so that it might
be a bit easier for analytical tools to handle it later on down the track.
And I will also show you how to do that in this section on the course.