Model Deterioration.  This is going to be an exciting topic, maybe even unique
On the whole internet I'm not going to claim that but maybe because I haven't seen it anywhere else
.
We're going to find out how models deteriorate
What does it look like when a model deteriorates
All right
So we have our cup curve our cup curve is a very powerful tool that allows us to see our model to have
a graphical representation of our model which includes as well how well the model is performing.
And remember we had this rule of thumb that you look at the 50 percent and you what crosses
your model line where your cap line is crossed by this vertical 50 percent line
So and that allows you to determine how well your model is performing how good this model is
And we had this rule of thumb where anything below 60 percent is a rubbish model
Anything between 60 and 70 is a poor model
70 to 80 is good, 80 to 90 very good, 90 to 100 too good practically
Very unlikely that that can be achieved.
So let's observe a model over time and see how it will deteriorate.
It's going to be fun.
All right
So we start off with our model and at the top in the top left corner we're going to say how old it is
this a brand new model you just delivered it
You're very excited about it
Very proud
And it's performing at 81 percent at the 50 percent mark
So it's a very good model
And let's see what happens to it next, six months down the track.
How well is it performing a bit worse.
75 percent
So it is just a good model it's not a very good model anymore.
It's just a good model but still still pretty solid.
It's giving good results good predictions you can derive value from it.
Then 12 months down the track.
What do we see here -  69 percent
It just crossed into the poor path or the poor thresholds so as you remember a 60 to 70 is kind of like
a poor model but it's still around the 70 percent mark still may be driving insides not as good as when
it was brand new 81 percent but it's kind of still do.
alright, fairly alright right but venturing into the poor territory, another six months down the track after 18
months after deployment holes are moldering only 63 percent.
That is definitely a poor model can really derive a lot of value from that.
But you know we we are not maintaining it so let's see what happens six months later 24 months down
the track.
Fifty five percent.
And that is already a red flag a warning.
Fifty five percent is not much better than a random coin toss just a 5 percent increase on top of a
coin toss.
And like what's the point of having that model was the point of wasting processing power and actually
using it in business processes.
This is kind of already useless.
That's why we call them rubbish models.
Total rubbish model.
And believe it or not six months later even this can happen.
And I've actually seen one of these models where it's driving a negative driving negative value for
the business 42 percent when if you use a random coin toss you'll actually get a better result.
Definitely this model isn't just rubbish it's actually doing worse for the business.
So that's how a model can ditcher it over time.
The time frames used over here are completely out of the blue so it might not be a six month period
between each one of these might be 12 month period might be a three year period depends on the industry
it could be faster, it could be a month could be two months depends on the dynamics in the industry in the
company in the population in the country and the economic environment and so on.
So it depends on what you're modeling as well so if you're not modeling populace like people and your
customer base and so on if you're modeling defects in a factory then your model might last
longer but then if something changes, for instance, the plastic with the materials change then your model
start might start deteriorating.
So it all depends on the circumstances.
But models do deteriorate over time and we'll actually find out why in the next tutorial
Hope you enjoyed this one.
I definitely find it quite visual and hopefully it illustrates the concept of moral degeneration quite
well.