This tutorial is going to have two parts.
First we're going to watch the intro for my presentation as it was and then we're going to watch it
again.
Plots with cool outs.
So I will actually highlight some things that I'd like to draw your attention to that are used in my
presentation.
So let's go ahead and get started with that.
As you probably gathered on the server and this presentation is one of the successes in this case I
don't want to just say you're going to use it to make your way home for the next.
It's so
so.
So those are all what.
All right just so everybody else is out.
Plus it's just to remind them of their funds and so on your list goes on HBO where else was pay for
members from fundraising.
There was a presentation in row format.
Now let's watch it again.
But with some notation it's a super intelligent design.
One of the success of this case to a jury.
I want to show the stakes.
My guess is to make your answer you come for the next day.
So.
So we're getting paid for what.
All right just so to speak.
This
it's interesting to hear funds this fall.
So what is your take on there is where else was today members from NBC
was.
All right so we're going to stop here.
If you'd like to watch the full presentation it is available at the end of this section.
Otherwise in the Nixa Tauriel we're going to go through these notes in a bit more detail and a look
for you that