In this tutorial we will set up the foundations of our data flow task.
First it lets her name the stars.
The convention I use is to put the date at the start so that I know when this upload was set up.
Now let's go into the data flow task.
Notice that the SSA s toolbox changes as we enter the data flow task.
Let's have a look at that again.
This is the toolbox when we are in the control flow.
And this is the toolbox when we are in the data flow.
Let's collapse all of the menus in the toolbox ignore favorites and Coleman and you will see that the
remaining three are called sources transforms and destinations.
This in fact represents our e-tail process data is extracted from the sources transformed with the transforms
and loaded into the destinations.
We will be mostly working with sources and destinations and I will explain why and the further down
in the course.
Let's set up our dataflow task go to sources select the flat file source and dragged into a working
area.
This will point to our CSP file with the data.
Next go to destination's and find only D-B destination and also dragged into your workspace.
This will point to a table in our database where we want to load the data into.
You can rename the source and destination if you like but you don't have to.
The last step we need to perform now is to connect the two.
You will notice that there are two arrows coming out of your flat plus or the blue arrow is where the
data goes and the Red Arrow is where any error messages will go.
You need the blue arrow connect the blue hour to destination.
Great you have now prepared the data flow in the next tutorials.
I will show you how to set up the flat file source and the database connections.