OK so let's get the data set for this section of the course as usual it's located at superdog assigns
dot com slash training.
Now if you scroll down to Part 3 data prep here you will see our data sets in section 6 each office
3.0 wrangling after the load to files data customer list and transactional daughter.
So both CACP files once you've downloaded them copy them into your folder for this section so into the
project folder.
There it is.
Now this is going to be a bit different to what we usually do in this case.
I'm not going to show you the upload the e-tail process so phases 1 and 2 I'm not going to do it with
you.
I challenge you to do them on your own.
There won't be.
I'll give you a heads up there won't be any errors in the upload process.
So if you get stuck or if you find any difficulties then just revert back to the previous sections to
see how we did.
But this will be a good exercise for you to upload these files on your own.
So you will need to upload both files and don't forget to disable the upload process once you've already
uploaded one file.
And then before you can commence uploading the second file and once you have uploaded these two data
sets into raw files in your database and then proceed to the next Tauriel and we will pick it up from
there.
I look for see in the next Turl.
And until then happy analyzing