In this tutorial we're going to install a school server on to our computers and if you really have a
SQL Server installed or if you're doing these exercises at work on your server there then feel free
to skip this tutorial.
However to have a look at the next one where I explain the importance of creating a test database and
how to talk to your database administrator at work to make sure that you can set up a safe environment
where you won't damage any of the existing databases and tables by doing these exercises to start off
with if you're going to need a browser go to Google and search for a school Server Express and then
just click on the top link that should take the right place.
Now bear in mind that this Web site changes all the time and it might look different at the time you're
taking this Clauss But never mind.
As long as you can get a skill Server Express that is great.
And here you can see that express the Express Edition is the free edition.
It's free to use.
It has limitations in terms of capacity of the database and how much ram it can use and so on.
But that doesn't really concern us because we're going to be using it for educational purposes and here
you can download a SQL Server.
Before we proceed I would like to say that we are going to be working with reskill server 2014 in this
series of tutorials.
If there is a later version when you're watching the Clauss you can go ahead and take that one although
it would be a bit more beneficial if you had the exact same version that we're working with here so
you can probably search for it up at the top.
But nevertheless just go with the version that you find first.
For instance if it's the latest one go for that and just click download over here you will need a Microsoft
account.
So if you don't have one already just create an account.
It's very easy to create.
So you can click sign up now.
I'm just going to use my account and here in this download section.
What is very important is for you to select the right version.
So for us we need a SQL Server.
We definitely the management idea.
But if you don't know management studio by itself you will just get the management studio where you
need the database engine as well.
So we're going to go for a skill server.
2014 express with advanced services.
So the name at the time when you're downloading this program might be a bit different or the description
might be different.
In essence what you're looking for is both the database and the management studio and on top of that
there's some additional features that we will be requiring in other sections of course.
So just download the most advanced version and you can find and do make sure that you're downloading
the right one for your type of system.
So how to find out whether you need a 32 or 64 bit studio.
Very easy.
Here's my computer I can if I go and right click on it and I go to properties here you will see that
it tells me that I have a 64 bit operating system.
If yours is 32 then you will need the other version.
So I'm just downloading the 64 bit operating system version.
And in English here just uncheck all these subscriptions.
Click Continue.
And that should start to download.
And bear in mind that this is quite a large file I think it is 1.3 gigabytes it will take quite some
time to download so maybe get yourself a cup of tea and I will fast forward this tutorial and we will
continue once the file is downloaded.
OK so once the file is downloaded it will look like this.
And if you double click it what it will ask you is where it should extract the files.
Here you can specify where you'd like to extract your files and once the files have been extracted then
the installation process will begin.
OK now we're selling us kill server on our computers after this.
A window pops up.
You need to select the first option which is new skills or a standalone installation and that will start
the process of installing a are on to your machine.
OK.
So this is going to be quite a lengthy process.
About half an hour it takes to install SQL Server.
Here you've got the license terms.
Just have a look through them to make sure that you agree for everything and then check the box that
you accept.
Click next here.
Microsoft will conduct a few checks on your computer and then it will proceed to some other menus that
you'll have to also look through the installation process is quite simple.
You don't need to change anything at all as long as you downloaded the correct package everything should
be select pre-selected for you.
I'm just showing you here what everything looks like like for instance local D-B does not have to be
selected.
We won't be needing that in our tutorials in this course.
And so from here you just leave all the default options and you click next to proceed.
And don't forget to change the root of it directly if you like to.
I prefer to keep it the default one.
Once again all options stay as the defaults.
Same thing just keep clicking through here just leave it on Windows Authentication mode.
Select the first option install and configure and then the installation process will begin.
This part of the session process took me about 18 minutes so depending on your machine it might take
a bit longer.
Might go a bit faster.
I won't show you the whole installation process.
I will fast forward through it over here.
There's one thing I did want to mention that when you get to the end of the installation process you
will see that this bar gets to the end.
But that's not actually that and there's still some things that need to be done so be patient.
You will be notified when the installation process is complete and you will see a window which looks
like this.
All right so this is the final window.
You should hopefully see this on your computer as well.
And here it says the status for every single element of the installation every single feature.
So just have a look through them to make sure that everything was installed successfully and after that
you're good to go.
All right now that Asgill server has been successfully installed Let's have a look and see what we can
find it.
You will notice that a desktop I can has not been created for this program.
And in order to find Asgill server we have to go through the start menu.
So I'd like to go to the start menu of your computer and in the Start menu.
Go to all programs and here just scroll down until you find the letter M and M You will see Microsoft
s file server 2014.
And if you open up that folder you will see an icon here.
You'll see many icons but you need the one with the yellow database and the top left corner.
And so which is going to right click it and will select Send to desktop.
Create Shortcut and knowledge's drag this from my other screen onto this screen and there you go.
That's a shortcut for our server.
So we'll just double click it and see what it looks like inside.
It might take a minute to load especially for the first time.
And there you go.
So you can see your server name of course just on server name will be different because it depends on
your computer name and all you have to do here is just click connect and there you go.
So you have connect to the server successfully and you can expand databases here and in the next tutorial
I will show you how to create your own test database.