OK so we have uploaded the file into our original data folder.
Now we are going to perform some cleaning on it.
We cannot change the file within the original data folder as we discussed.
So what we're going to do is take this file and copy it and put a copy in the prepared folder.
Now we can work with this file and make any changes that we need.
So let's open up this file in Excel.
We're going to bring up a copy of Excel and I'm just going to drag this file in to excel.
Here you can see that has several columns and not many rows.
That is because this is a demo file and we will work for a much larger file in the following sections
of the course.
So here you can see the different columns such as customer id name surname gender age date joined and
balance.
Now there are two specific things that you need to do of this file before you commence the upload.
You need to fix up the dates and you need to fix up the bounces.
So what do we mean by fix up the dates.
Well dates can have different formats and we want to have a consistent format in all of our data in
our database so that we know exactly how to work with it.
Plus sometimes you might get a date from a European country that structures its format differently to
the U.S. So you have to account for those things and make sure the format is consistent so your database
can recognize the date wherever the original daughter came from.
And the second thing is fix up the balance.
We need to get rid of the dollar signs the commas and make sure the decimal places are represented by
dots.
So let's go ahead and do that.
All you need to do is select the column that you're trying to fix so we just look at the format.
At this stage and right click on it and select Format Cells here for date we're going to set a specific
type of date.
So under date we're going to select.
It's actually not here for me so I'm going to have to go to special custom and I'm going to find date
here and I'm going to change it to.
This is the type the specific type of date that you need so it's y y y y hyphen m m hyphen d d.
That is the best date format for databases because whether this data came from the US or whether you're
working in the U.S. or whether you're working in the U.K. or any other country your database will know
exactly that the month is and if it sees the year the first four digits then it will see the month as
a second and then the date it will never confuse the month and the date.
So we going to click OK.
So you see the date has changed its format and now we're going to do a similar thing with the balance
.
We're going to format cells and now we're going to go to instead of currency we're going to go to a
number.
And here we're going to make sure this box is unchecked the use thousand separate because we don't want
the commers decimal places to and will click OK.
Now there we go so now there is no dollar sign.
And there is no comma in the balance.
So one more thing.
If your country uses comma instead of a dot for decimal places then you will have to change the regional
settings of your computer to to make sure this comma is changed to a dot because when we upload to a
database you need a dot.
So now this follows ready and let's have a look at it again.
I'm going to close this.
It's going to save it.
Yes.
And now what happens is if I drag the file back in here you will notice that the balance stays consistent
like we changed it but the date changed.
Again it's not the format that we selected.
And this might be confusing but this the only reason for that is that Excel displays that date convenient
to use so it looks at your regional settings and then it displays the data in that way just for your
convenience.
So the proper way to check your data is not through Excel so once you have modified it in Excel which
you need to be looking at is programs like Notepad plus plus soldiers bring it up here.
Here's notepad plus plus.
And if we drag our data in there now you can see that the date is in the correct format as is the currency
.
If your daughter said is a very large there is a different program called EDID pad light and we will
talk about that program later on in the section.
So that's the two things that you have to make sure are prepared the dates and the dollar amounts.
Once you've prepared those you're ready to proceed to uploading the other to the database.