Glad to see you back here today we are commencing our step by step elimination and as I mentioned there
will be a lot of steps.
So prepare yourself for this.
This is going to take a while and we're going to be really diving into creating a proper robust logistic
regression.
So let's get started.
This is our first iteration that we did last time.
Once again we're not discussing it efficiency right now because a lot of these variables are going to
be eliminated.
The coefficients are going to change P-value are going to change.
Everything is going to change.
Then we've got over here stats around the model.
So what we are looking at is adjusted r squared.
We want to see that we follow steps is it going to improve or is it going to deteriorate and that will
help us keep track of whether we're doing the right thing every single time or not.
We've got to our accuracy rate here 81 percent.
We can also look at that and see if it improves or drops off as we remove variables.
Here you've got your confusion matrix.
So you can see a few Type 1 errors and quite a lot of type 2 errors.
So those of false negatives when we said they won't leave but they actually left.
And so as we go through this process we're going to be trying to improve the parameters and statistics
of this model but most importantly get rid of the variables that don't have a significant impact.
And at the bottom we have a message from Grettel actually telling us that excluding the other constant
excluding the constant the top one we hear P-value was highest for variable 18 Spain.
So there it is actually telling you which P-value is the highest here you can see 0.6 1 8 1 and it is
indeed the highest of all them.
Why does Grinnel tell you that.
Well that's because griddles smart it already knows what you are probably going to do and that is the
backward elimination method and it knows for the backward elimination method you need the highest P-value
as you remember.
We take the highest P-value we excluded from our model if it is greater than our threshold and then
we redo that step again looking for the next highest P-value.
So that's what we're going to be doing right now.
Let's get straight into it.
I'm going to move this model over here because we're going to have a lot of them and I'm going to create
a new one.
So we're excluding Spain right.
Limited logic binary.
Let's find Spain and get rid of it.
OK.
So there's our second iteration and here you can see Grettel is telling us variable 18 has the highest
has credit card.
Let's have a look at that has credit cards 0.44 that is greater than our threshold so let's exclude
that as well.
It's going to start taking up some space limited logic.
Binary.
And we want to get rid of has credit card.
So meaning that living in Spain all the outlets that's right let's go through them.
First one was that if you live the baseline is France right.
So then we have Spain and Germany we have a dummy for Spain and we have a dummy for Germany.
The fact that this one is significant and this one is not.
What does that mean.
Well that means that people who live in Germany are substantially different in terms of their probability
to leave the bank to people who live in France whereas people who live in Spain because this variable
is not significant what that means is people in Spain are as likely to leave the bank as people who
live in France.
So all other things equal if you take three people one from Germany one from France one from Spain.
Then the person from Spain and France are going to be as likely to leave the bank.
So they will be they'll have the same likelihood to leave the bank whereas the person who lives in Germany
because this variable is greater than zero.
That person will have a higher likelihood to leave the bank.
So that means that perhaps maybe there's a competitor in Germany that is taking all of the people maybe
the departments in Germany not performing as well or the customer service is not as good or the product
that was rolled out in all of these regions and it didn't succeed for some reason in Germany.
So something is going on there and that's what we did we took out Spain because it's the same as the
baseline as France.
But we left Germany because as you can see it's very significant the next step what we're doing now
is we're taking out a credit card right.
So let's have a look here has credit card as you can see it's got a fish.
But before you look at the coefficient whether it's positive negative small or large.
Always look at the value of the pure use is not in your threshold or is like in this case very far from
your threshold threshold is 0.05.
Here is 0.44 So that means it's not a significant variable.
That means that we're not we can say with confidence that this effect is is predicting anything.
So what we're doing now is we taking this variable out.
And in terms of logic what that means is that people who have credit cards are not either less or more
likely to save a bank.
It doesn't matter if you take two people and hold everything else equal.
Then whether or not that person well one person has a credit card with the bank the other one doesn't
.
Then they'll be as they'll be they'll have the same likelihood or probability of leaving the bank.
So that's why we're taking out his credit card.
And I think I've already taken it out right.
Yep salesclerk OK.
That's our third one.
Now let's see where we're up to next one is estimated salary.
So we need to remove this variable because it's not significant.
It's the highest P values and the value is above the threshold.
Why are we removing estimated salary.
Well there could be a lot of reasons for instance it actually doesn't affect how likelihood of people
leaving or not or that another reason is that it could be calculated incorrectly that the algorithm
that calculates estimated salary might not be the best one.
And therefore we can see that this variable is not having any influence.
So maybe we can investigate that further later on or put that into our report that estimated Allergan
and have an effect.
However if you did expect it to have an effect then perhaps review the formula for estimates.
So let's run another one binary estimated salary take it up.
Okay.
So by the way we should be also we should be looking at all our squared.
So here you can see 0.1 5 or 7 0.1 5 0 9 and went up.
Right.
That's good.
Then here you can see zero point 1 5 0 9 0 point 1 5 1 1 goods is going up.
As you remember when our square increases that's good the models is these variables fit the model better
than these variables.
And also you can see that the actress says she's going to growing up as well.
So here we got eighty one point one percent.
Here it was only 81 percent.
That's also good.
And now what do we have.
We have ours at R-squared Zero Point 1 5 1 1 9 7 so it went up a little bit and accuracy actually went
up a little bit as well.
So that means we're not we have an X with a variable that we shouldn't have excluded.
Good.
So what are we excluding this time.
Is it.
Griddle hasn't given us any hint on what we should exclude and what that means is that all variables
have a p value of 0.1 or less so less than 10 percent 10 percent or less.
But for us it's not sufficient because our threshold is there are five.
So let's have a look through these and see if there's a variable that we need to exclude.
So first of all we look for the one of the highest P-value.
It's just one €10 here and it's got 0.0 8 7 3 so that's above our threshold and I not that far above
.
So here we got to be careful.
This might be one of those variables that we should exclude according to our rule but in reality does
help the model.
So that's where our adjusted R-squared will help us out.
Let's go ahead and see if we need to exclude it.
We're going to go limited logic binary.
And here we'll take tenure and take it up.
Okay.
And now just compare these side by side.
So what happened we took out tenure.
Did the R-squared go up or down.
So 1 5 1 1 9 7 1 5 1 1 0 6.
So it actually went down.
What happened to the accuracy accuracy was eighty one point two percent went down to eighty one point
one percent.
It's not a.
Just three people but.
So this is not your main criteria your predominant criteria should be the adjusted R-squared or any
other coefficient that you are following over here.
So it says that it went down.
It didn't go down that much went down a little bit.
So it's kind of borderline You can take it out if you like if you feel that it doesn't have any sense
to keep it in.
I'm going to I'm actually going to keep it in because I believe that tenure should be a factor because
the longer you've been a bank right you develop loyalty over time so you should the longer you've been
should be less likely to leave and here that's why we see it's a negative sign.
So they are less likely to leave.
But the fact that it's such an insignificant variable What is that is telling us is that the bank is
not doing a really good job of developing loyalty in their customers.
So there is something wrong with there and that is definitely something that should go in the report
that we were expecting and from maybe industry standards benchmarks that tenure is a good indicator
that you're going to stay off the bank but in this case it wasn't.
So that's basically what we will decide about and we'll leave it in for now but we'll definitely include
a comment or a footnote about this observation.
So now we're going to bring this over in here and you can see there's nothing else to exclude because
they're all above our thresholds.
So I'm going to return tenure
.
There we go.
So this is our model.
And if you think that this is the final model then it's actually not.
It's way too early to celebrate.
We still have some extra steps and I will show you some really cool tips and tricks starting from next
to total.
Next time we will talk about transforming independent variables should the variables be included in
their original form or should we actually do something with them before including in the model.
It's going to be a fun tutorial and I look forward to seeing you then.
Until next time happy be analyzing