This the Tauriel I will show you everything about the select statement.
It is a very simple operation in.
SAGAL So it's going to be a very quick tutorial.
So here we've got the select statement that allows us to select the top thousand rows of our table and
the way we got it was very simple it just right click on your table and you click select top tiles and
rows and this statement is created for you.
So this up here at the top it's highlighted in green.
It is a comment you can simply delete it it doesn't do anything.
The statement here is civil lect from.
So we're going to remove the top thousand because it's a constraint that tells skills or management
that you only want the top thousand rows and as you can see here there is exactly 1000.
Even though our table might contain more so we're just going to do that.
And here what you see is select and then a list of columns that we're selecting.
So if you want to specify a certain columned then you can.
You don't have to specify all of them.
So for instance we can specify just customer names so as to get rid of these and we'll just leave customer
name and country for instance so we'll leave these two columns.
And here we've got select these two columns from this source or from this table that we're selecting
from.
So if we run this now you'll see that there's only two columns that have been selected customer name
and country.
And in total there's much more than a thousand roses actually four thousand one hundred seventeen rows
.
Now let's look at how else we can select from the table.
If you don't want to specify columns for instance like like Preuss you want all the callers you don't
have to write all of them out.
The most common way people you select is with a star and a star basically means I want to see all of
the columns are available in the stable.
So if you write select star from this table then you will get all the columns.
Let's try that again.
Execute.
And so here you see that all of the columns have been selected and all of the rows in these columns
.
So basically now what we're going to look at is what is off to the FROM clause.
Here you see three parts D.S. training TBO and list of orders.
Right so D.S. training is the database that we're working in here.
So that's Diest training then Debo is the schema.
So we won't be talking about schemas because more of an advanced topic.
However you can see here that there is a prefix is kind of like a prefix or think of it as a subfolder
.
So it's it's a prefix behind these tables would be for these tables.
And so they're all D-B oles.
So in this case we saying we want that subfolder of the database.
And then finally a list of orders is the name of your table so that's the SO or is there.
And that's how a select statement works so let's create a new select statement from scratch to create
a new query just click the button here and you Quirino press control and on the keyboard that brings
up an absolutely blank window.
So what are we going to write.
We're going to select from this other table order breakdown.
So those go select star from there we we need the database name Diest training.
You can use this pop up if you like to help you out.
Then TBO by the way a skills not case sensitive you can write in lowercase uppercase.
Mix it up if you want.
And here it's already tell you which tables they are in.
TBO actually is not showing all of the tables because I've just uploaded them so it's low on my machine
so I'm just going to type it in.
For us it's order break down.
And if I click five or click execute here you can see that the columns all the columns of the table
have been selected.
So the beauty of select star is that you don't even have to know what is in that table.
So if you're seeing this table for the first time you can just click type and select star and it'll
bring up all the columns and you can investigate it's very useful for data mining and Dot investigation
purposes.
Once again because you don't need to know the table you can get to know it this way.
OK.
So that's how order break down.
One more thing I wanted to show you is that it gets a bit annoying to write this part out because we
know already we we're working in the Diest training database.
So we just want to work with the tables rather than every time type this out.
So there is a way you can do it.
Let's get rid of this part.
If I click execute now I'll get an error because it doesn't know where to look for this object.
But at the top here there's a dropdown and you can select which database you want to work and then you
Fusilier straining and you run the query now then everything is working fine however.
Might be a bit tedious to change it every time so we're going to go back to master and here this is
where we get the error.
I will show you how to specify the database at top.
All you have to type in is use.
Then the name of your database.
So for us it's d as training there's a pop up and after that type in go.
And so if you run that now you will see that this database is selected automatically at the top and
the table works.
And so that's how you use this skill statement.
It's one of the most important foundational elements of this scripting language.
And we'll be using it quite a lot throughout the next Charles