Edit pad life is a paid program is similar to notepad plus plus but has some additional advantages.
The descriptions both say that notepad plus plus and edit pad light work well with files under two gigabytes
.
However I find that notepad plus plus sometimes struggles but edit but lights always works really well
and much faster with very large files.
Also edit pad light is definitely much Vasa and excel when it comes to very big CACP files.
So if you're struggling opening your data sans file with Excel or even notepad plus plus then you should
consider giving it a bad light a go.
Also if you have a file well over two gigabytes that you need to investigate there is always a more
expensive version edit pad pro with its advanced features and extra bonuses that edit pad light is free
for personal use.
So if you're working on some of your personal projects at home you can get it at no charge.
If however you intend to use it for work then you need to purchase a license.
Personally I like the user interface in Notepad plus plus I'm much more and is free.
I recommend sticking with notepad plus plus but keeping edit pad light in mind in case you ever need
additional power.