All right so now what we're going to do is look at the graphs.
The first way you can bring up the chart of the linear regression model is you go to graphs and you
go to fitted actual Plaut and then just go actual versus fitted.
And here you've got your observations which are in red and the model the fitted model in blue.
Before we continue I'm going to bring up the other chart or show you the other way you can bring up
the chart.
So if you cancel that and you go to analysis and then you get to four costs and then don't fall for
costing anything you just click OK.
Then hear what you'll see is two things came up so the chart which will look at and the second and also
the forecasts.
So basically what happened here is Grettel took your existing record.
So here you got through your records and it's didn't print any information on the independent variable
so years of experience is not here as you can see but it does have salary.
So the actual salary that was in your file and then has got the predicted salary so the salary that
the models predicting for that record and you can just visually compare them here see the standard errors
95 percent confidence intervals if you like.
And also what this would have done if you in terms of prediction was it called prediction.
Well if you did have some records where there was an empty value for salary say 31 32 33 then it would
actually populate them for you it would create it would generate would still generate a prediction.
And that way you could for instance extrapolate what you have this line on to new salaries.
So you could see what the salary would be for people with four more years of experience than you have
in your data set.
So we're going to close that and we're going to look at the graph now.
So this graph is a bit more involved because it has a 95 percent confidence intervals here in green
.
So in in short in a quick summary what happened here is originally we only had the red dots of Krause's
meaning that that's how salary is dependent on years of experience.
So basically if you take nine years of experience then you can using this blue line you can predict
where the salary for nine years of experience will be and what the confidence interval is telling us
is that there's a 95 percent chance that that salary will actually be somewhere between these two green
lines on this vertical nine year line.
So basically doesn't have to be on the blue line and as you can see a lot of the actual valves are not
on the blue line some are but mostly they're not.
But we know that according to our data with a 95 percent chance it's going to be between these two green
lights.
And also what we can see here is that the blue line if it were to cross the vertical axis it crossed
somewhere at that's a constant value that we looked at which is twenty nine thousand and something.
So here we have it.
It's actually twenty five thousand seven hundred ninety two.
That's where the blue line would have crossed the vertical axis.
And as you can see well of course like there's not enough space here but because this access should
be a bit more to the left there zero would be somewhere here so there would be enough room for it to
cross and years of experience.
That's the slope that's basically the angle at which this blue line is going if.
Years of experience.
So basically the coefficient for years of experience.
So if this value was more than 9000 $449 then the slope of the blue line would have been higher if it
were lower the slope would have been lower so it wouldn't be as steep.
So this is basically saying that whenever you move from say from three years to four years from here
to here your salary increases by approximately nine and a half thousand dollars from here to here.
So that's how this whole simple linear regression works.
Hope it'll make sense.
Play around with the data maybe run a few more of these just to get comfortable with it.
And remember that we'll be working with this screen quite a lot going forward and I look forward to
seeing you next time.
Until then happy analyzing