All right so I think have had enough stats for now.
And let's get back to building these charts.
First of all we're going to do is we're going to look at some balance.
We were done one for eight.
Now there's a simple one for balance to really solidify in this technique.
So an interesting balance and we're going to create a bin.
And there's been many.
We're going to say that the size of the bill should be about ten thousand and click OK.
There we go.
So what we need to do is duplicate this chart duplicate sheet.
We'll call it balance.
And here all we need to do is take Brown's brain and replace age.
And as simple as that.
Right.
So one thing we notice here right away is that there's a lot of $0 balances or wild balances in the
zero dollar category.
They might be to anywhere between zero to 10000 but if you right click and click you data you will notice
that you go to underlying here you will notice that baluns been.
That's baluns that's the been.
And then if you look at balance you'll notice that they're actually mostly zero.
So even if we order them there is one.
Wait a second.
There's one balance three thousand seven hundred sixty eight dollars.
And the rest are zeros completely zeros.
So what does that tell us.
Well that tells us this normal like sometimes people in a bank they have zero balances and that's you
know just because they have other accounts or maybe they move the money out but did close this account
and things like that.
So in this case what we're going to do is we can just exclude this from our analysis of course we have
to put in a note that you're excluding something from your analysis but it just doesn't make sense because
you want to look at the actual value.
So people have bounds is how are they behaving what's going on there are they leaving or are they staying
.
And so on.
So just right click this call and Mitchell and exclude and select exclude and that's it.
It's gone.
So here you can see a filter.
We won't be talking about filters per se in this course.
It's a whole separate topic and I covered that off in a separate course from Tablo.
But basically what this filter does is if you just click here and show click filter you'll see the shock
Schalkwyk filter pop up on the right.
It's excluding a certain category which is the zero to ten thousand dollars bin.
And that's allowing us to just analyze everything else about it.
So what we can do now is perform our analysis as per usual.
Here you can see a very interesting picture.
It's a bit different to what we saw previously so I'll just show you age over here.
This was age right.
And you could see like there was obviously people who are not like our difference of theirs.
They're not conforming with the average in here.
They are higher.
There's a high chance of these people leaving lower chance of these people living in balance.
It's a bit different they're kind of more uniform here so you can see across the board it's around 20
percent some are higher so these early ones and the later ones are higher.
But once again here you can see that you have less records so there's a higher chance that this will
be a just you know a random error or just like some some sampling error.
And same thing over here you can see that this is just due to the way the sample was selected.
You can't really rely on these things for for instance for a two and a one.
You can't run a chi squared test.
You have to have at least four or five units or five observations in each cell to run a square test
.
So you can still run one for here.
But overall here you can see that there isn't that much of a difference maybe a bit over here.
More likely to leave a bit over here more likely to leave.
So that's that's very interesting.
We're good.
What we can do now is out to change the color of the top chart over here because it's balance and I'm
kind of used to using bounce as green.
There we go.
And so that's pretty much it for balance what you can do from here is the way the situation's different
is that you don't you don't observe something that is like screaming out at you.
You can continue investigating these discrepancies if you like and if that is important to your company
to understand like OK so that's 29 percent that's 25 percent.
Why is that higher.
So if you feel that that is an important step and see then you can apply the techniques that we've talked
about to this specific case and take it further.
However if you feel that this is more or less conforming with average and you'd rather focus on other
things you can simply leave it at that you can just say that from you know from our analysis it doesn't
seem that there is a a very high change across different categories in terms of probability of people
leaving and you know you just go from there and you focus on other things of course would be great to
cover everything but that's what we call it data mining you want to find the gems you want to find the
real golden nuggets rather than spending your time on things that won't give you much value so if you
target people with special offers who are in this age group between 45 and 60 you can really impact
the amount of people that's leaving your company but do bear in mind.
You have to also take into account the actual number of records so this distribution helps so you can
see that you might want to target these people more than these people because there's more of them whereas
in balance yes these do have a higher percentage of living.
But how much return on investment are you going to get if you try to fix this instead of fixing the
problem that you can perceive with the different age demographics.
So that's balance.
The other one I wanted to look at today was estimated salary Let's have a look at that because it's
kind of related to balance.
So we'll just duplicate this as we normally do because because it's fast and here we'll just say estimated
salary.
And let's take estimated salary and drag it.
Oh the Binz we haven't created a business so let's create have been created been.
So something 10000 and here just take the filter off.
So the there's no more exclusion.
So we just want to keep the filter on that sheet not on the sheet and estimate salary just drag it instead
of bondsmen.
And here you can see a different picture one more time.
So I'm just going to change the color here quickly color up to you.
Honestly what what color you think is the best de-select that color it's a gray.
So here what you can see is a very interesting picture a very uniform distribution here very uniform
distribution over here.
So first things first you look at this chart and you say all right.
Obviously there is no impact whatsoever from salary upon the probability of the person any all upon
the decision of the person to leave the bank so salary is not an important variable.
And we would leave it at that.
I've only had this chart like this chart.
This chart is selling something very interesting.
It's actually telling us that well look the there is an equal number of people in every single being
for estimated salaries so we're saying that you know bank there is the same number of people that earn
between 180000 $190000 as the number of people that earn between 30000 and 40000.
And as the number of people who earn between 80000 $90000.
So this really kind of contradicts the whole balance situation where we have this nice normal distribution
.
And like as it probably should be this is lots of people here probably like you can say that they earn
somewhere in the mid range.
These are people earning a lower range.
These people are earning in a higher range and you would think that balance would somehow be related
to estimates salary or at least.
Well you got a hint here that estimated salary is actually has the word estimated meaning probably that
the bank doesn't know what they're earning and they're estimating what these people are earning.
And you'd think that you'd use the balance to estimate what a person's earning rights somehow in the
calculation would figure there.
But doesn't look like it because there would be a trace of a normal distribution but there isn't here
.
So one thing you can report from here is that this is going above and beyond your task.
So here you know you've already said that no significant impact.
But then look at this you can say hey by the way it looks like the estimated salary calculation is completely
wrong or out of whack because it's not giving adding any value just putting people uniformly across
all bands and although that's not related to it that's how data mining works.
You will find that you will uncover very interesting insights about completely unrelated things to your
analysis while you're doing analysis.
And this is one of them so you can go back to the department that runs the system itself and say hey
your calculations are dated or is an error or something is wrong with it.
Let's have a look at it.
I can show you that this is not normal this is not how it's supposed to be and you know maybe just by
doing things like that you will add way more value than just by delivering a project.
And that's happened to me heaps of times that I was doing one thing and then I noticed something in
the data that led me to uncover something else.
And then something else and then BAM.
I actually delivered so much more value than I just delivered on the project.
Just because a project you're doing people already know what value they'll probably get from it.
Here you can uncover completely random things and that's just fantastic.
I personally find that that is the fun part in data mining.
You have a problem that you need to solve along the way you find additional insights and lots of them
.
So there we go that's what we found about estimated salary that probably the calculations wrong.
But the way the calculations are structured right now we can see that this variable does not have a
significant impact upon our variable or our probability to likelihood of person to leave or decision
of the person to leave.
So that's all for today.
And as a homework exercise I'll like to suggest that you look at the remaining two variables that we
have so there will be credit score and tenure and see what you can find there maybe you'll find some
anomalies and maybe you will try some insights.
I look forward for you next time.
Until then happy analyzing