We're getting to the end of completing the stored procedure.
So let's quickly recap on our progress up to now.
So far we have created a working table to store our data then we populated it with records from our
row table and along the way we had to exclude some anomalies.
They were present in the original data set.
Finally in the previous tutorial we leveraged our domain knowledge to exclude a one or more corrupt
record where the balance column was less than zero.
Today I will show you how to perform another quick but very powerful Q8 check to start off.
Let's select all of the records in a working table.
Our goal in this phase of the e-tail is to make sure that all of the fields that are important for our
analysis are clean.
Let's look at the zip code called For instance if our goal is to create a geo demographic segmentation
of our customers.
Then this field would be crucial.
How can we make sure that it is clean.
Well let's have a look.
Did you notice that all of the records have the same structure three characters then a space and then
another three characters we can use a structure to our advantage to fish out any non-conforming records
and to do this we're going to use wildcards or regular expressions in the additional exclusion sections
of the script type and then you select query we're going to select from the working table again.
And in the WHERE clause type in where.
Zip code not like and then a single quotation mark three underscores in a row a space three more underscores
and a closing single quotation.
Let's analyze this.
As you recall the underscore is a wildcard for any character but only one character.
That means that this regular expression specifies exactly the format in which our zip codes are presented
.
And because of the word that this select statement will pick out any records that are violating the
specified structure highlight the select statement and click execute to run it.
As you can see we have found four records in all of them the zip code is in a different format to what
it should be.
We can copy these records for further investigation.
However in this tutorial we will simply exclude them from our analysis replace Silex star with delete
and now run the query again forecheckers have been excluded.
And let's copy the result as a comment underneath our query for future reference.
We use the zip code as an example.
However you can apply this same simple yet very powerful method to any other column that by design is
meant to have a certain structure.
This will help you capture and investigate your records of violating the structure in the next tutorial
.
Show you one file Q8 check that you can apply to any dates columns in your data set and I look forward
to see the