Last time we checked for killing effects using Varians inflation factors and today we will look at using
the correlation metric metrics by the way.
I just wanted to say that we're not going into detail into the formulas into the whys and hows of these
methods simply because I just can't fit everything into this course.
I just want to show you the methods that exist and how you can apply them in practice because I think
that's that's the most important part.
And whenever you do need to learn the nuts and bolts of why what geefs are or how the correlation match
matrix is constructs and so on.
I believe there's lots and lots of ways you can learn that.
But right now we're focusing on the practical application of these things.
So we want to look at the correlation matrix that's another way to investigate any kind of possible
culinarily between your variables to create a correlation matrix in gril you need to go to dadda and
we'll talk about it just now once we've created a view correlation matrix and then select the variables
we want to check log w a wealth accumulation log bounds and what else age.
Let's look at those.
So I just put in for you can put in more Brize just put in for because this window once once you burn
more and it goes to the next line and it doesn't look pretty.
So what can we see here a correlation matrix is basically a table which is half filled.
It's how I feel because this other part here that's not there would have been a mirror image of that
one.
And in each cell you have a number which tells you about the creation of the two variables the one that's
at the head of the column and the ones at the head of the row.
So if you cross these rows and columns and say the correlation for followed bounce log that is 0.19
it for the Croatian for wealth accumulation and ages minus 0.2 463.
And correlation can be between minus 1 and 1 and is basically a parameter that tells you about how how
in line these variables are so when one variable changes how much how how similar does the other variable
change as well.
And the more correlated they are the higher the number will be.
So basically a correlation of one is ideal correlation and that's why you can see here that age of age
is ideally correlated and your variable of itself is always going to be idylic related.
And then zero is no correlation at all whatsoever.
So for example here you can see age and low.
They are very they have very very low correlation and minus one is ideal anti-coalition or negative
correlation which means that there they're still correlated but they change in opposite ways.
And so basically when you look at the correlation matrix you should forget about the minus a plus.
Just look at the absolute value here you can see that right away log bounds and log w a have a very
high correlation it pretty much x behaving as the same variable.
So that is very bad for our model.
Then we have low balance and wealth accumulation.
This is why previously we saw that there was there were some issues because they are also very well
correlated.
Age is an interesting one.
Age is not very well correlated with Flugge W.A. even though it's part of that calculation but it is
quite a bit correlated with wealth accumulation.
So as you can see the logarithm changes the variable and makes it less correlated with that variable
which is part of the calculation.
Basically here which is looking for a rule of thumb is anything above zero point nine is very high correlation
and you have to do something about anything above zero point seven.
Also very high correlation.
So not very high but I'd say just high correlation also suggests that to do something about 0.5 to 0.7
is moderate can cause a correlation.
Perhaps we're looking into 0.3 to and higher.
That's just like low correlation and perhaps you could leave that in the model but try to avoid those
kind of things.
And finally Anything below 0 0.3 is low correlation and as you get closer to zero there's pretty much
no correlation left.
So those are your That's your rule of thumb.
But it also ultimately depends on what variables you're looking into what your ultimate goal is and
things like that.
So that's how you read a correlation matrix and you're probably wondering by now why is it bad for a
model when you have what multi-colored Nardi in your marbles.
It's kind of intuitive when you think about it that you're pretty much double counting like here you
can see even though there are different variables you're double counting a variable in the model.
But why is exactly is it bad on like on an intuitive level.
I think it's worth covering this question so I'll bring up them for mail for logistic regression.
So we're looking at this bottom one here.
You can see that you've got lots of variables here.
So let's say that x1 and x2 just like Lague balance and log W-K are highly very highly correlated then
what happens is when the regression is trying to build this model it's slow it's tweaking X-1 a little
bit and trying to hold everything else constant to see how X-1 affects the probability and the left
side and based on like lots and lots of those iterations it will find the ultimate BE1 coefficient for
x 1 then it does the same thing for X it tries to hold everything else constant and tweaks this a little
bit a bit more a bit less and tries to find the ultimate coefficient for B2 that will explain how X-2
is affecting what we are observing the changes on the left and so on and then gets to X and the same
thing and hold everything else constant as much as it can as possibly can and tweaks this one a little
bit to left a little bit to the right looks at how the verbal is changing for those observations and
then tries to find the Beco coefficient that best explains this.
This association between the two what happens when you have two variables that are correlated to say
x1 and x2 are correlated well the correlation simply cannot find the correct coefficients for these
variables because whenever it tries to assess X-1 it's trying to investigate how X-1 is associated with
the dependent variable.
So what is doing is trying to hold everything else constant and just tweak X-1 a little bit to level
limit to the right to see how this will change.
Well what ever tries to do that.
This one also changes.
So as long as you change this one and this one will change.
Whatever.
Whatever tries to read always see that so it cannot assess the individual effects of the variables on
your dependent variable.
Same thing when when you get to X 2 it's tries to hold everything else constant and tweak X-2 a little
bit to left a little bit to the right and still it fails because X-1 will always change in its change
will be aligned with the change of X-2 and it just doesn't have those.
It just doesn't have the opportunity to assess the individual effects.
And that's what happens.
That's what I mean when I say that multicollinearity breaks in models it doesn't allow them to be constructed
properly and that's why you want to get rid of multicollinearity effects in your independent variables
.
So that's a very intuitive way of looking at multicollinearity and why it's bad.
Hope that's that's helpful.
It's quite a complex thing and I guess it's important to get your head around that so I hope this my
intuitive way of understanding it helps you understand it a little bit better as well.