All right so we're nearly done creating our first Bill de Proc..
And in fact we've done most of the groundwork already.
So we have the create table bit and we have the insert into it.
So today we're just going to add a bit more functionality to make it more versatile So let's say for
instance I've already inserted the data right.
So if I go to the top thousand rows the data is here.
But let's say for instance that I had to refresh my old data file because somebody supplied me a new
data file or something changed and some some reason then I want to rerun this bit.
Well I can't just run it right now if I insert into then I will increase the number of rows I will get
duplicate rows so I need to truncate my table first so get rid of all the dotted here and then run it
.
So I can do that I can to create a new query and type it in here truncate that table and so on but this
happens quite often.
So how about we add some functionality into a proc that will take care of those things.
So what I'm suggesting is we take this bit insert into and we copy it.
So this just Hetter of the section and then we pasted here above and we call this part just truncate
table and here we will say what are we going to say which is going to say truncate table this table
.
And it might seem dangerous but in reality there is nothing dangerous about putting this code above
the insert statement so if we've just created the table and we're about to insert data into it there's
no problem running a truncate in between because there is a there isn't anything in the table anyway
so we can after the create table if we're going to run this as one block once when we want to we run
the whole thing if we run it like that that's a problem not a problem because the truncate is just going
to truncate an empty table that's good.
But if we don't want to you're on the create table bit we just want to run the insert then we just select
from the bottom up to the truncate including the truncate and we run.
And then we're only going to have the 43 rows so we empty the table and then we rerun the upload from
the file.
So that's one handy feature that you can add to your proc and I recommend doing that because whenever
you need to insert into that will help you avoid the mistake of having duplicate records.
And you know doubling up on your data and other one that we're going to add is at the top here.
We're going to say now we're going to copy this bit and sort of truncate table we're going to put in
a drop table.
This is the part where people get scared like whoa we're going to drop the table.
So let's type it in.
So if object id this is an if statement.
We haven't discussed them in as well but we're going to be using them much.
We're only going to be using them to check if tables exist so if this table you need to take the table
without the square brackets and then put it into quotation marks for basically a string.
So this is now the name of the table as a string if it is not.
So just copy this text.
You don't have to like memorize it you can just copy it every time into a new prox drop table loops
table.
Then I want to drop the table.
So why are we doing that.
Well because you can drop the table.
I'll just explain why the if statement is required you can drop the table here once.
Yes I dropped it it's no longer there.
Refresh.
No table here.
Not anymore.
But then if I want to drop it again if I want to run this proc again while there the table is not there
if I execute I'll get an error.
And it's not nice doesn't feel nice.
You know in a professional procedure to get an error.
So that's where we put this statement.
And in this case it won't drop.
It won't even attempt to drop the table if the table is not has not been created.
Is not in existence.
So that's why we have the if statement.
Now returning to why the drop well drop is a very dangerous operation it completely destroys the table
for even asking you second time.
So be careful with it.
Don't drop tables that you can recreate.
But in this case if we're running the proc for the first time it's not a problem to have the drop at
the top because we you and how Intiman created the table yet so easy like that we run it and the table
gets created.
So we look here.
Refresh tables created and then it's not a problem to have the drop off to the Create before the create
table because if our intention is to create a table then we already know that we don't want the table
that we have that it really exists.
We've either backed it up or we we know that we want to override it.
So in that case the drop is just handy to have because then when when you want to create the table if
I just do that now I get an error.
But because the table already exists as we discussed.
So all I have to do is just highlight up to the top up to the drop table.
And so as you can see now you have elements of your search procedure you have the dropdown sums.
I'll just zoom out for a bit so we can see the whole picture.
You've got this element at the top which is a drop table you've got the create table element you got
the truncate table and you got the insert into.
And so now if you ever want to rerun the whole procedure from start to finish you just select everything
click execute it will drop the table creating a table.
Truncate the table which does nothing.
Insert into the table.
If you ever want to just reinsert data into the table before recreating it just run Lisbet.
So very very flexible on what you can do with your tables.
And that is us that's how we create a stored procedure.
And in the next tutorial we will discuss what we have created in a bit more detail