This story a little talk about ordering your tables now order in SQL doesn't have that much meaning
at all.
It's not like Excel where the way your table is order is important because people are visually assessing
it and working with it and looking at it all the time.
And Eskew well order has a much much lower importance because as Hill is a storage predominately storage
facility and people don't normally look through tables in Haskell people usually use scripts and programs
to access these tables and if they do require the tables to be ordered then there are special functions
to do that or special commands to that which will look at just now.
But most of the time it's not required to order tables because you're just searching for specific values
or you're aggregating values and you're manipulating the data.
So in essence order doesn't matter and as you saw in the previous tutorials Of course sometimes when
you're uploading the data it's ordered in one way in your text file or in your file on your hard drive
and then when you've uploaded its order in a different way.
Well that's no surprise because a skill doesn't really care about order in the first place.
All right so now we will look at ordering our tables in case you do need this functionality down the
track.
Here I've got a simple selects a star from statement and we're selecting all the records from an order
breakdown table.
Now let's see what we can do if we want to order this table by product name for example.
All you have to do is after your select statement and Officer and where clauses that you might have
.
So where clauses of filters they come first.
But after all that you just need to type in order by and then the column name that you want to order
by.
So in this case it's a product name.
There it is.
Product name and that's it.
So if I exit this now you will see now that the table is ordered by alphabetically by the product name
column.
And you can scroll down and you'll see that we have a 2 x here.
Now if you want to order the opposite way.
So you want to add this and then you type in as after you order by statement just type in D and E C
meaning descending and that will order it in descending order so X will be first and then a will be
at.
And now let's have a look at another example let's say we want to order by Salzer want the highest cells
at the top and the lower cells at the top.
Naturally what you would probably think of doing is typing in sales here and that would be correct.
That's exactly how you would do it in a format a table.
This is not a form Intel's table so let's what happens now so I'm going to highlight that and press
a 5 on my keyboard.
You can see that the highest sales are here.
But then it's $99 after nine.
Nine hundred ninety ninety nine and then it's again nine hundred.
And then it's like it's a mix it's not what we wanted.
Well the reason for that is because our table is not actually here you can see thousands of dollars
.
So the reason is that this table is formatted as Text.
All of the columns are here as text so when you click when you're typing in order by sales sequel is
recognizing sales as a text call and it's ordering it descending by say a by as if it would be working
.
Text and number nine in text comes after it comes last so anything that's starting with nine will come
here first and then then they'll go the ace or go and the Sevens and so on.
So basically a thousand It starts with a 1.
So therefore it's very very far down somewhere here.
Right.
But in terms of value it's actually greater.
So what do we need to do here is we either have to wait until we convert this table from our or table
into a working table and we'll learn how to do that in the next session the course or in this specific
example I'll show you how to work around this just so that you are comfortable that you can use the
order by clause properly.
So here we'll just quickly convert the sales call them into a number.
So we'll use the cost operator just type in cost then a bracket and then say after sales say as.
And then say float.
So now this whole expression is a new value.
It's taking sales which is text and changing it into a number with a decimal point which is a float
.
So now if I execute this you will see that everything is ordered correctly we even had six thousand
dollar sales here.
So here you can see that everything is in its actual order for value.
Once again if this column had been formatted properly if it were a number already then you wouldn't
have to do this cost a transitional step.
So that's how you order your columns if you want to order the quantity then and sort of float put.
Integer here so I.A. I give that a go see how you go if maybe discount quantity maybe order by category
just so that you're comfortable by.
We won't be using it much in this course if at all but it's good to know what the statement is.
You might require it at some point