Passion and the wow factor.
This is one of my favorite topics again.
How do you get your audience to say Wow how you really really impressed them.
Well I'll give you two tips.
One long one and one short one.
So starting with along with passion.
Be passionate about what you're talking about and your passion has to be contagious.
They have to really see it you have to show your passion.
Don't be afraid to show it when you get up there on stage or when you're just in front of people in
it in a room and presenting.
Don't think about all the things that you must remember to say you must not forget to say these things
.
You'll get lost in the detail and you won't have that effect.
All you have to be thinking about when you're walking out there is how you're going to connect how you're
going to share this knowledge with people get them excited like you can you can tell sometimes that
I do it when I'm in front of camera right like.
You can feel my passion for what I'm talking about my excitement my genuine excitement for what I'm
talking about.
And it does get contagious sometimes.
So that is what you're aiming for.
You should like it's data science.
Come on guys it's like it's the best profession in the world sex is profession of the 21st century.
We're doing this is we live in.
Living the dream.
Why not share it.
Why not share our excitement and happiness with people and they will feel that way.
If you are presenting like very dull and serious and all the facts and you know no jokes and just just
straight to the facts like a lot of people can do that.
Show them your passion.
That is the most important is the best advice they can give you.
Let your passion for science let it out.
Give it to people and that's number one and number two the short one.
Smile just smile when you're talking to people.
It dissolves them and it just creates that connection.
You've got to smile when you're presenting even if it's not a sense that aside is fun isn't it.