[Autogenerated] Hi, this is Greg Golightly.
And welcome to managing keys and certificates.
We're going to take a look at three main services offered by
A W S to manage keys and certificates.
First A W s Key Management Service or Kms Next,
iCloud, HSM and finally, Amazon Certificate Manager or a C M.
In order to encrypt data, you need an encryption key.
That key needs to be properly formed and unique so that the
resulting encryption is strong and it needs to be managed in a
secure way with controlled access.
Storing the encryption key in the database where your
encrypting the data or on the application server,
where your encrypting data is not a secure location.
If an attacker gains access to the database or
server and you've left the key there,
then the encryption hasn't really provided you any benefits.
The key needs to be available when you need it,
depending on the nature of the data,
your encrypting and how your application uses it.
A high volume application could be making hundreds or thousands of
requests to decrypt the data in a period of time.
If the key isn't available, then the application must wait to get the data,
the key must be durable.
Losing the key means losing all of the data that is encrypted with that key.
Finally,
you may have different compliance requirements that dictate
certain standards for managing your keys,
and you may need to audit the use of your keys.
Amazon Key Management Service, or Kms,
is a managed service that provides you centralized control over the
lifecycle and permissions of your encryption keys.
K M s uses hardware security modules or HS EMS that meet many industry
standards for secure key generation and storage.
You can control which users have access to administer each key
and which users have access to use those keys,
you can also enable automatic yearly rotation of master keys and kms will
automatically re encrypt previously encrypted data.
As a managed service,
Kms dynamically scales to meet your demand and is extremely durable 11 nines
and is integrated with many AWS services for ease of use,
including CloudTrail so that you can audit who used what
keys when and where they were used.
Because keys are stored in a secure hardware device, Kms is a regional service.
Keys you generate will only be available in the region.
You generated them and you cannot export keys from kms.
K.
M s is also a multi tenant service,
meaning AWS partitions a single hardware security
module for use by multiple customers.
If your application requires single tendency,
then you'll need to look into cloudhsm, which we'll talk about a little later.
In this module, when you generate a master key in kms,
you can import your own key or have kms generated for you.
You'll then decide which I am.
Users and rolls can use the key and which can administer the key.
Integrated AWS services generate a data encryption key
to encrypt the data in the service,
Kms uses envelope encryption to encrypt the data
encryption key with a master key from K.
M s.
You can choose to let AWS manage the customer Master key used to
encrypt the data encryption key for the service. Or you can manage the C m kay used for that envelope encryption