[Autogenerated] Let's go to AWS Kms and create a customer.
Master Key will assign permissions to administer and used the key.
Then take a look at some AWS services that error integrated with kms,
and see how easy it is to encrypt your data in those
services from the AWS console.
Select Key Management Service.
If it's not in your recently visited services, just type it.
I'm assuming a role I created called Kms Admin that has
the proper permissions to create a key.
Let's create a customer managed key.
I'll close this so we can see what we're doing.
Select Create Key,
for this example will create a symmetric key for data encryption,
and under the advanced options will have kms provide the key material.
Recall that you can import your own key material,
which would be external, or you could have it generated from a custom key store.
We'll stick with kms, then select Next.
Provide a name and a description.
I'll call this E.
C two key, and we're going to use this to encrypt E c two volumes.
You can add any desire tags.
Next.
We need to select who can administer this key.
I'm going to have the kms admin role allowed to administer this key.
You can select whether the administrators can delete the key or not.
Next will assign the key usage permissions.
I've created another role for the Kms user.
Note that you can also add other AWS accounts that can use the key will hit.
Next.
You can review the resulting policy that will be generated for
administering and using the key than when you're satisfied.
Hit.
Finish.
Here we can see the key was successfully created.
This is where you can administer and manage your key.
Here.
You can see some general configuration information.
You can view the type of key and where it came from,
as well as review the key policy Any tags and enable key rotation.
K M s will automatically rotate your key every year.
If you enable this option,
it keeps a copy of the previous key so that it can access any old data.
Then it will re encrypt it with the new key.
You can also view and modify any key administrators,
change the settings for key deletion and manage key users and other
AWS accounts that may have access to this key.
Let's go ahead and create another key for RDS.
I'll select the same settings as I did for the previous key.
Now we can see the two customer managed keys that I've generated.
Note that I generated these in the organ region so they will only be
available to Resource is in the Oregon region.
Let's switch to the kms user role than go to E.
C two and use one of these keys.
I'll launch an instance and when we get to storage,
notice the encryption column.
If I select the drop-down, note the options.
The default AWS CBS Key is the C M K, managed by AWS.
I could go ahead and use that or I could select one of
the master keys that I generated.
For example, the E C two key.
Now the volume of this instance will be encrypted with
the data key generated by Easy to.
But that key will be encrypted using the master key that we created in kms.
If we look under volumes we can see that this volume is encrypted
and the kms information about the encryption key.
Let's head over to RDS.
We'll get into the Wizard,
then under additional configuration under encryption
noticed the drop-down for the master key.
There's the default key that AWS generates for the RDS services.
Or you can select one of the keys that you generated in kms.
I'll select the RDS key that we generated.
I won't go through with the creation of this database,
but you can see how easy it is to manage multiple keys for different
services and different instances within those services.
Let's jump over to S3.
Now I'll create a bucket and make sure that it's in the same region as the
keys that I generated with S3 will first create the bucket,
then under properties we can configure encryption under AWS
kms we can see the different keys that were created This
time I'm going to select AWS S3.
This is the AWS managed C M k that will be used to encrypt the data
encryption key we can see that it saved correctly.
Next, let's add an object to the bucket.
I'll add an image and it uploaded successfully.
If we go to K.
M s and select AWS managed keys.
Here is the key that was generated by a W s to manage the
encryption of that AWS bucket note that you are not charged for
a ws managed keys that error in kms.
When you're done with a customer managed key,
you can schedule it for deletion notes Um,
guidelines To make sure that the key is not being used,
you'll be required to wait at least seven days before the kms key is deleted. This is to ensure that you don't accidentally delete a key that is in use.