[Autogenerated] AWS certificate manager or A C M allows you to centrally
manage provisions and deploy SSL TLS certificates.
ACM is integrated with A W s services like cloudfront
elastic load balancer and API Gateway.
To make adding a certificate to endpoints,
you create on these services very quick and easy.
Best of all,
ACM public certificates are free when you use them with integrated AWS services.
You just pay for the underlying services that error using the certificate
ACM manages certificate renewal for you so you won't have to worry about
getting an embarrassing certificate expired.
Message on your web-page Finally,
ACM private certificate Authority is a highly available managed private
certificate authority service that allows you to easily and securely
manage the lifecycle of your private certificates without the time and
expense of operating your own private C A.
For public certificates, you'll enter the name of the site,
then validate ownership of the domain via a see name record in your DNS
configuration or an email to the registered domain owner.
Once the site is validated,
your certificate will be generated and available to
use with supported A W s services.
To deploy the certificate,
simply select it from a drop down list in the AWS management
console and ACM will deploy the certificate to the resource you
selected for private certificates.
You must first create and activate a private See A.
You can then request private certificates and enter the name of your site.
ACM generates the key pair and issues the certificate from your
private CIA ACM can deploy the private certificate to the resource
you select or you can export the certificate.
Let's go to AWS certificate manager and create a public certificate
will then deploy it to a supported A W s service to see just how easy
that process could be from the AWS console,
go to AWS certificate manager.
We're going to provision a public certificate.
Note that if you have an existing certificate,
you can import that into a CME for easier deployment and
management will request our public certificate.
Enter the domain name for which you'd like to issue a certificate.
You can add another name to the certificate.
Depending on how customers arrive at your site,
you can choose DNAs or email validation.
I'm going to choose email for this example.
You can add any tags that you'd like then review your selections.
Once you're ready, select, Confirm and request From this dashboard,
you can see the status of your certificates.
Note.
The one that I just requested is pending validation.
If for some reason you're not getting the validation email,
you have an option to resend it.
Once I followed the instructions in the email I can refresh and see that
it has been validated and their certificate issued.
Now,
if you go to one of the integrated services like API
Gateway under custom domain names,
enter the domain name that you generated a certificate for and
select create notice under ACM certificate.
The certificate that was created is in the drop down list.
I could select this and use it to configure this
custom domain name for my API gateway.
ACM will then automatically deploy that certificate to this resource.
You're doing great.
We've covered how to use Kms to securely manage your data
encryption keys for use in many different AWS services.
You know about cloudhsm and when you might choose to use it,
particularly if you need a single tenant.
HSM have a high volume of keys or calls and for certain
applications that need direct access to an HSM.
Finally,
you can easily provisioned and managed both public and private SSL TLS
certificates with Amazon certificate manager with free public
certificates for use in services like Cloudfront,
Elastic Load Balancing, API Gateway and Elastic Beanstalk.
Join me in the next module to discuss protecting your account
and applications with AWS web application, firewall, shield and guard duty.