[Autogenerated] securing accounts with roles is another great way to limit
what can happen in an account when a user assumes a role,
they only have the permissions granted by the role we talked about.
Cross account access using roles in the designing for complexity on AWS course
and how Rolls can do help you avoid creating dozens of I am users in your AWS
organization for a single employees to do their job.
You can also use rolls to allow third parties to
perform actions in your account.
When you allow third-party access, you should also protect your account.
By requiring an external, I'd to assume the role.
Suppose you hired Globomantics to monitor your AWS
account for some performance improvements.
You created a role called perf monitor with limited permissions and added
the AWS account for Globomantics in the role trust policy.
You provide the role error N two Globomantics who can then
access your account by assuming the role.
Suppose a bad actor also signs up for Globomantics services and
gives the same role error end to Globomantics either through
guessing it or some other means.
The bad actor can now trick Globomantics into providing access
or information to your account for them.
This is known as the confused deputy problem.
Using an external IDE to assume a role can combat this problem.
When you create the role trust policy,
add a condition to check for an external I'd
Globomantics would provide you with this.
I'd as it should be unique for each of their customers.
Now, if the bad actor guesses the error N,
any requests to your account would have the external I'd for the bad actors
account instead of your account as assigned by Globomantics,
and any attempts to assume the role in your account would fail.
Note that if you are in the position of providing services to other
AWS accounts like Globomantics in this example,
you should always test that your customers policies error correct and that
requests that do not include an external IDE actually fail. Otherwise, their account could still be vulnerable.