Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to focus on actually providing our own custom seats
or markers with the watershed algorithm.
Previously we used a bunch of image processing techniques in order to automatically grab foreground
markers.
That was the six markers for those pennies.
And then we had the watershed algorithm then the side based off those markers where the actual segments
should go.
However a lot of times with the watershed algorithm it's easier if you can just click on the image yourself
and have that as the seed for the marker and then the watershed algorithm will automatically update
its segmentation based on the seats you provide.
Let's go ahead and see an example of this.
All right the program we're actually building will look something like this.
We're going to be able to open up an image here or have an image of a road with some sky it's sunset.
Notice there's an ocean here.
There's some mountains and then there's a bridge.
I'm going to be able to selectively click on different segments of this image.
So right now I'm clicking and color circle is popping up on the sky.
And then I can change color and choose another segment of this image such as these mountains over here.
And notice what's happening on the right.
This is the watershed algorithm.
Automatically updating its segments then it can choose a different color on my keyboard and maybe also
segment's out this ocean.
So then I'll use that as well and maybe I want one last segment for the bridge so I'll choose another
color here and then segment out the bridge.
OK.
And you you can begin to see how over the custom seeds are able to automatically segment just based
off a few points that you provide that share the same color.
And if you want to get more complicated than you can start looking at minor adjustments here or then
adding more color here on the green cetera.
So it's up to you.
You want to take this project but hopefully understand the idea is that we're setting seeds and then
we're going to automatically segment them.
So let's get started by checking out the code.
Ok so I already have our basic imports here of CB2 none pie and Matt plotless.
The next thing we need to do is actually read in the image and then make a copy of it.
So I would call the image road and say to image read and then say data forward slash road image that
jpeg.
Keep in mind you should be able to extend this idea to any of the image in our data folder or any image
you prefer.
And then we're going to do is also make a copy of the image that we can play around with.
We'll just say N.P. copy of the road.
You could also say road copy open and close print sees.
Let me quickly show you what this looks like even though we've already seen it.
So essentially this image.
Notice I won't be doing color correction in this case because we're going to be using open C-v to view
the image not map plot lib.
So I will comment this out and continue next I want to create an empty space for the results to be drawn
onto and I'm going to base this off the shape of the road.
So I have road shape here.
It's 600 by 800 by 3.
Remember if I just add an indexing call Colan to It'll give me back the first to 600 and 800.
That's what I'm going to use here.
Will say marker image is equal to and set up an image of zeroes of the same shape will say road shape
and this will actually just take in the x and y and will be data type.
We'll go ahead and have this be 30 integers or 32 bit integers and I'm going to create one more for
the segments that will also be drawing on we'll say the zeros and then say a rude shape and then say
the type is equal to any you I anti-hate.
All right so now I have markers and segments.
The main thing to notice here is that the marker image itself its shape is just 600 hundred.
The segment's image its shape is 600 100 by three even though they're all just zeros are all black.
Next when you decide on how to actually create the colors for the markers for this we're going to use
the map Cutlip color mapping.
If you check out the link in the documentation that is the link that's in the notebook that leads the
documentation.
It'll take you to this color maps reference we've already seen this page a little bit when talking about
very this versus gray color mapping.
If you scroll down you'll notice we have qualitative color maps and these qualitative color maps are
going to be indexable that way we can actually just grab colors off of these mappings.
So it's up to you which actual Color Mapping you want to choose.
Go ahead and just use tab 10 since has really distinct colors in order to use this or you need to say
is from map plot live import C.M. then you say see em if you hit tab you'll notice a list of all the
color mappings.
We're just looking for top 10.
And then if you passen a single digit it returns back red green blue and Alpha parameter lowest are
all scale between 0 and 1.
We're also going to need to change that so that they're skilled between 0 and 255.
So the first we're going to do is actually just index off just the red green and blue value.
So will say see em tab 10 and we're just going to show the examples for the first one.
So if we index Colin three that gives us the red green blue and then all we want to do is multiply this
by 255.
So we'll cast this as an umpire.
And then we can multiply it by 255 and then we get back this array.
And the way our function is going to work later on we actually want this to be a tuple.
So we're going to want something that at the end of the day looks something like this a tuple of red
green and blue values.
Keep in mind technically since we're using open C.V we should be switching this red and blue channel
but all we really care about is that we have distinct unique colors and this should be good enough for
our use case.
I would encourage you to explore the color mappings and see how the rest work out but this is enough
for our case.
So I'm going to functional lies the operation we did here.
So I will say DPF create RSGB
and then we're going to return this except instead of zero.
We're going to say I.
And now what I can do is I can say for I in range 10 I take a list of colors.
So let's make a and t colors list and then say colors append and then say create R G B of II if you
run that and now check out what colors looks like that's exactly what we need a list of tuples here
where each tuple is some sort of unique red green and blue color mapping that is related to this color
map.
Again the channels of red and blue are switched but that's not a big deal for us.
OK.
So now that we have that ready to go it's time to set up our callback function so we can come back down
here.
And now it's time to set up the process that you're probably already familiar with.
There's essentially three major components.
There's the global variables that will be defining.
There's the callback function and then there's the wild true loop that actually does things while True.
OK.
So we're going to separate these into separate cells so we can work on them one at a time.
The global variables one that was actually pretty straightforward which is going to have a variable
to start off with as the current marker the current marker.
This is essentially what was the color choice.
So this is the index position for the list of colors.
We'll start off at 1 and then we'll say Mark's updated is equal to false.
This checks if the markers have actually been updated by the watershed algorithm.
OK so two global variables not a whole lot to work with just check of the current marker.
What it is will be adjusted depending on the user providing a number input and then check that the markers
have been updated.
Next it's time for a callback function for it to keep this simple we'll just call it mouse callback
and then we'll pass the events the X the Y the flags and then the parameter call and the global variable
we're going to take in.
Just marks updated this current marker will actually pass that back using the while loop.
So we're going to check have the marks been updated.
And let's make sure that's a dealer.
So has the marks been updated.
That's why we're passing in globally and we'll say if the event that's passed back is equal to CB2 events.
If the left button is pressed down then the person is clicked and it's time to draw the circle.
So how do we actually draw the circle where we need to draw essentially two circles one for tracking
the markers that we send back to the watershed algorithm and the other for actually the splaying on
the user image that the user is going to see so we will say CB2 circle and we have the marker image.
The circle is going to go at positions X and Y where the mouse is currently located will give a radius
of 10.
You can always play around with that and then we'll passen the current marker.
So are more current marker there and then we'll say negative 1.
So this guy this circle this is for the markers pass to the watershed call later on.
So that's why this actually isn't really a color OK.
Next is what the user sees on the road image.
So in this case we'll say CB2 circle and on the copy of the road image.
So on route copy we'll put a circle on X and Y it have a radius of 10 and then we'll index off that
list of colors.
The current marker and this one also also be solid so I'll say negative 1 and then we'll just say that
the marks have been updated.
So say Marks updated is equal to true.
So run that also is doing is checking.
Did someone click on the left bounce down on that road image.
If so ticking over the markers and then also put a circle where the user currently clicked and now it's
time for our while true loop but for that we do that we want to connect the callback to a named window
so say named window.
We will call this road image and then say CB2 And let's set that mouse call back to the road image window
and then we'll provide mouse callback then we will say while true.
Let me create a little more space here.
He will say wild.
True.
Go ahead and show the image image show.
And we're actually showing two windows.
One is the results of the watershed segments and that's that window that starts off black.
So that's where we have segments remember segments.
If we come all the way back up here that was NPC arrows with the exact shape of six hundred eight hundred.
And the color channels.
So we have segments there ready to go for us.
And then we're also be showing the road image.
So we'll say CB2 show wrote image and we'll be showing the road copy there as it gets updated.
Next we have three main things we need to do.
We want to be able to close all windows want to be able to update the color choice and then we want
to actually be able to update the markings.
So first one that's easiest is just closing all the windows.
I will say is equal to CB2 waky wait for a millisecond and then I'll say if K is equal to 27 that stands
for the escape key.
Go ahead and break.
So it hit the escape key.
It'll break out of this while true loop.
And so at the bottom outside of this wall truly I will say C-v to destroy all windows.
Notice again this is outside of this while loop just as we've done in the past.
Next we to figure out how to actually update the color choice.
So before we do that there's actually going to be kind of a part to that one and it's clearing all the
colors.
So instead of having to restart this program over and over again in case you want to play around afit
we should be able to clear all the colors and we're to do that when the user presses the seat key so
clear all the colors upon press and the key will say Elif K is equal to ordinal of lowercase c.
So that means that the CQ was pressed.
We're going to essentially reset all the copies of all the images we'll say road copy is equal to a
copy of rote.
You can also use that copy there who will say marker image is equal to zeros road shape colon to else
set the data types equal to their integers.
So we don't get messed up when they're being drawn on also say segment's is zeros wrote that shape the
type is equal to p u.
I n t.
OK.
So this essentially just resets these two images to what we initially had them as up here and these
two lines.
So it just resets them to black or it's empty.
So we have our marker image that's holding all the markers for the watershed algorithm and then we have
the actual segments displaying the segments and those will all be cleared if the user presses the C
key.
And we also make a fresh copy of the road.
Next we want to update the color choice.
So I'll say if the key being entered is greater than zero and if the characterized version of the key
being entered That's the actual number if it is a digit then we're going to do is set the current marker
equal to the integer form of the character of K so this k when you actually click on your keyboard it
sends a specialized number code and often that will have nothing to do with the actual number being
pressed.
So I think if you press two on your keyboard it sends back the number 51.
So what I want to do is transform that to its corresponding character which is what the S.H. are those.
So it turns that key press from 52 to the actual number press 2 and then that's the last string.
So then we transform that string into an integer which we can then set as a current marker so that we
can do an indexing call up here.
OK so all is doing is just basically reading in.
What did you press on the keyboard as far as the numbers 1 through 9 are concerned.
OK.
So we took the current marker and reset our updated color choice.
Then if the marks have been updated remember the marks are updated.
If someone ever clicks down on the left button to want to update both images.
So if the marks have been updated then we'll say marker image copy is equal to a copy of the marker
image and then we'll say C.V to we'll call watershed on the road image with the marker image copy.
And the reason we do a copy here is because this marker image is still being manipulated in the window.
So we want to make a copy of it so we can pass in the copy to the watershed algorithm.
Then once you've done that we can say that the segments are equal to zero road that shape for the data
type is equal to the 8.
Integer I will say for color index in range and we inside the range here.
So this the number of markers provided.
So one of the other variables we can have a peer in the global variable or the find earlier is just
the number of markers we actually intend to use.
So let's just say there's markers 10 that would be the numbers zero through nine.
So we'll say comments here.
Zero through nine.
Go ahead and run that.
Save it.
So have number of markers again.
Is this colors list is bigger.
You can maybe have more than that but you'll get a little tricky trying to record a number 15 instead
of just numbers 0 3 9.
So I'll say in range and markers then the segments of marker image copy equal to
the color index will then set that equal to the colors at that particular color index.
So this is pretty much what is coloring the segments.
And it's doing that essentially through a number pi call.
OK so we're going to do here is run this and make sure everything works.
Go ahead and do shift enter here.
So here are images.
Let me go ahead and hit see to clear.
So anywhere you click you should eventually see a dot and if using tab 10 the first bar is probably
going to be blue because that's the one.
Unless you happen to switch out the blue and red channels go ahead and on your keyboard hit see and
then that should immediately clear again.
Next we're going to do is choose a different color.
So go ahead and click a number on your keyboard and then click on the sky.
So this is number two for me.
Click number three on your keyboard and then hit maybe the ocean over here than hit number four on your
keyboard and select these little groups of mountains do a couple of clicks here and then maybe select
five and go ahead and selects the road and you should eventually see the image segmentation happening
over here on the right.
Remember you can always hit see to clear out the image again.
So let's try this again maybe try the road first.
So go ahead and do a couple of lines there for the road then choose the color to do a little bit for
the mountains here.
Then 3 for the see and then four for the sky.
And you can see the image is being segmented based off the marker sees that you provided and really
in fact you don't need this many seeds.
But it's good practice just in case you know the images quite noisy or something.
All right.
So that's it for this project.
You now understand how to set up your seeds manually based off an image and you can click on it do the
callback and then call watershed to automatically segment the image for you.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.