So I'm going to create a couple more cells here and I'm going to upload a new image that we haven't
actually seen yet and it's an image of a gorilla.
Will say CB2 read inside your data folder where we happened to have it.
We're going to upload gorilla japanned and we're going to upload it as a greyscale and let me also just
get the display function working on the copy and paste the display function from the notebook against
the display function.
We've always been working off display image or display.
So I'm going to run that and let's display the gorilla.
So will this play gorilla run that and actually let me clarify the c map is equal to gray run that.
And so here we have this picture of a gorilla.
It's quite a large image.
If you actually check out the gorilla shape it's about 30 100 by 2000 more or less.
So what we're going to do now is calculate the histogram and then we will equalize the histogram and
visualize the difference and that will run this again on the color version of this image.
So let's first do this in black and white.
What I would do is just calculate the histogram values here.
Say two values as for the gorilla image is Seabee to calculate just say gorilla
channels 0 because we're just focused on one channel and only has one channel greyscale.
We're not doing any mask.
The mask is none his size is equal to 256.
And then the range is equal to zero comma 256.
OK.
So this ranges.
There we go.
Then the next step is to simply just plot out those values.
So we will say Pulte plot just underscore values run that and there we see the actual histogram.
So here's the histogram on the greyscale image.
Looks like we have a lot more kind of lighter colors and then a couple of darker colors but not so much
pure black.
And if we take a look at the image it looks like a big chunk of those lighter colors are from the rock
behind this gorilla and the gorilla itself is actually pretty like color.
There's nothing too dark or too black maybe a little bit around that's for a little bit around here
on the edge.
But really you can see here there's just that little spike of dark but most of it seems to be a lighter
gray and it can tell just because a greyscale image.
Now let's show you how we could equalize the histogram.
So going to make a version of this called equalized gorilla or cube gorilla and the command is actually
really straightforward.
It's just you call equalize hissed and I encourage you to have auto complete that and then just pasand
gorilla.
And first off lushest display.
What that result looks like.
So I don't actually even need to calculate the color histogram to do this.
I can straight up just color on an image and then display the result.
So I noticed just how much the contrast has been increased here.
So when we equalize the histogram we've definitely increased the contrast.
Notice now that those light rays are essentially now the minimum value of 0.
And those darker values kind of around the hair for and over here on the edge Those are the max values
of black.
So compare these two images a lot more color depth here in gray and upon equalize in the histogram.
Now you see a much higher contrast and if you wanted to you could calculate the hyster values for that
equalized gorilla and display the result.
So let's go out and calculate that I going to copy and paste this command except now all passen the
gorilla run that an ellipse.
Make sure everything's OK.
Q underskirt gorilla.
There we go.
And we'll say appeal to plot his.
And I notice the behavior you get.
So you get these constant spikes down because there's zero value there.
But if we compare this to our original it's definitely been more flattened out.
So we can see here that we tend to kind of quickly decrease as we go past 50 and then if we come back
down here the decrease is much shallower as you go beyond 50.
So it's a much shallower drop compared to the original image here.
It was a much quicker drop.
OK.
So that's the difference.
And really the effect is a higher contrast and keep in mind you can actually do this exact same thing
for a color image.
So the way we do that is first going to read in the color gorilla.
So reading the image again except this time I was going to read it in as a color image will say CB2
read data forward slash gorilla.
And if I want to show the gorilla or create a show gorilla where it's convert it's the correct color
space.
So we say CB2 color pasand the color gorilla and then say color underscore BGR to r.g.
Display what the color version of the gorilla looks like we're going to say peel tea.
In fact we can actually just use the display function with the fine we'll say display or show gorilla.
So this is what the color version of that image looks like.
Here's the gorilla.
It's in full color.
If we actually want to equalize the histogram of a color image essentially increase the contrast of
a color image the way open CV works is you actually translate that first to an H S V color space.
Remember that's the hue saturation value.
So I mentioned earlier we really wouldn't be dealing too much of HSV.
This is one of the few instances where we do just because the way the equal ice histogram function works.
So what you will do is create an HSV version of the gorilla will say HSV is equal to CB2 and then change
the color space of the original color gorilla.
So we read in and we're going to change it from the default blue green red to hue saturation value.
So we have this HSV version of the gorilla and then we're going to do is grab that value channel because
the value channel is really the one we're interested in.
So we'll say HSV colon colon and the zero channel that's the hewe the one channel that's the saturation
and we're issued right now.
The value channel.
So this is going to be our value channel right here.
And if you check out kind of the minimax values here these are the ones that go from 2:55 to zero.
So we're going to do is we're going to equalize the value channel.
So I will copy and paste right here and then I'm going to set that equal to the results of CB2
equalize histogram of that particular channel.
So I'm taking that value channel equalising that value channel and then replacing the original values.
So we're going to run that.
And then what I'm going to do in order to display the results I'm going to convert this HSV gorilla
to the R.G. be that we're used to.
So we will say the equalized version of the color gorilla is equal to CB2 CVT color HSV and then we're
going to take that HSV and then convert it to color space from HSV to red green blue and now it can
display the equalized color gorilla.
And now we see here much higher contrast than in the original color gorilla image.
So if you come back up here we have a lot more color that seems to be a little darker.
And then when you come around here now notice the rock behind the gorilla is much brighter.
And over here on the edges it's much darker as we increase the contrast and we're able to do that simply
by just isolating that value channel in the HSV apply equalize hissed and replacing those original values
with the equalize histogram version and then converting it.
This is just for display purposes to R G B and then we have our high contrast gorilla.
OK.
So in this lecture we learn how to equalize histograms to create higher contrast images as well as how
to apply masks to only calculate the color histogram for a particular section of an image.
That ends our discussion with histograms.
We will see you at the next lecture.