Welcome back in this lecture we're going to go over the solutions for the image processing assessment.
Let's open up the assessment notebook and work through solutions.
All right here we have the image processing assessment notebook.
Now let's work through the solutions.
We have some convenience code here for you so go ahead and run that.
We've ran in the imports and we'll set this display image.
Now our first task is to open and display the draft pick image that is located in the data folder.
Hopefully by now you're pretty much a pro opening files of say CB2 emerita and inside the data folder
we're going to call in giraffes.
Let's make sure it's actually I'm spelling it right.
Wraps.
There we go.
And because I want to display this I'm going to reassigned the color channels will say CB2 CVT color
lets say image CB2 color and by default we have BGR and we want to convert that to our job.
So if we run that wups CV to underscore that we up OK then we'll say peel t.
Actually we have the display image.
So we'll say display image.
I am g run that you should see these two giraffes somewhere in the savannah OK.
The next task was to apply a binary threshold onto the image first I can to you what happens if you
try to apply the binary threshold onto the raw image and then I'll show you how you can actually get
the results expected in the notebook.
Although depending on how you interpret this is technically correct.
So to say read and thresh one is equal to CB2 and the command here is just threshold and then we'll
pass in the image we pass in the midway point so that's commonly just between 0 2 5 5 1 to 7.
You can always add justice and then the max value is 2 5 5 and they'll say CB2 and call thresh.
And in this case we just on a binary threshold.
Now if you apply this directly onto this color image what's going to happen is it's going to apply that
binary across the three color channels.
So that is technically technically a binary threshold.
So you can display the image and show thresh one.
And this is a binary threshold on the image.
However it's doing it across all the color channels.
So if you actually want to fix that where you can do is reload the image in greyscale so you can just
come back appear load this.
And in fact we only need this first line and remember as the second parameter you can just say comma's
0.
Run that again and then you see this in grayscale.
And if you actually want the color mapping to be grayscale you can just provide the map Gray for that.
And then we have the binary threshold on the greyscale image.
So everything is either black or white.
OK so then the next task was to open the drafts thought Jay pick file for the data folder and convert
its color space to HSP and display the image.
So you can say image is equal to CB2 image read.
In this case it's in the data folder.
It's called giraffes.
And if you want to convert to a different color space or meannesses image CB2 see color as in the image
CB2 dot color underscore.
And in this case we're going from blue green red to HSP and then we can display the results of that
image even though the kind of really what makes sense to be kind of a funky looking pair of drops.
So here we have it now and the HSV space.
OK.
The next task was create a low pass filter with a four by four kernel filled with values of 1 over 10
and then used to the convolution to blur the giraffe image.
So let's go ahead and try that out.
We'll start off by creating the kernel as asks a couple of the four ways you can do this but probably
easiest is to say N.P. ones shape is equal to four by four.
And then we may also specify the data type.
So we'll say data type is N.P. float 32 as we did in the lecture.
And this case was divided by 10.
So the lecture I think we divided by 25.
And if we display the kernel we get back to the expected results.
Let's now return the image afresh.
So it's easy to read and will pass in data and grab the giraffe's shape.
And I going to make sure to convert it to the correct color space.
I'll say whoops.
CB2 dot.
CVT color.
Pass the image and then will say CB2 color.
In this case we're going from again B G R to R G B.
OK.
Run that and then we'll say the result is equal to c v to filter to the.
And then we'll pass an image for the desired that we can keep the input that so will say negative 1.
And then we pass in the kernel and let's display the result.
So the splay image of that result.
Go ahead and show that and you can see here.
It basically looks a little blurred.
It looks a little brighter next.
We wanted you to create a horizontal Sobol filter so that's Sobol X from our lecture of a kernel size
of five of the Grayskull version of the draft's image and then display the resulting gradient.
So again we want to read this in greyscale.
So we just see a say image C-v to read elysée data giraffes run that and then we can say Sobol X for
the X gradient CV to Sobol and then we'll say image for the actual depth will define it as CV 64 f just
like we did at the lectures and then we'll say Remember it's the X that comes first.
So I'll say one for DX 0 for D-y and the kernel size again this kind of up to you but which is five
and then let's display that image so that splaying those results of simple X and whip's looks like we
forgot to read this in greyscale.
Let's try that again.
Zero.
Now we run it.
OK now it's making a lot more sense.
And then we can just say See map is equal degree.
OK so now we have the simple X gradient.
Then at the very end we want you to plot the color histograms for red blue and green channel.
The draft image is pretty much the exact same code that we did during the actual lecture color histograms.
Part one will see image CB2 Let's read in the first image data draft's or set my list of colors.
So color say blue green and red.
We have it in the open C-v order and they'll say for I must see a well in enumerates color.
Will say the result of the histogram is C.V two.
And then we just call calque just in this case repassing the list or an image instead of a list.
The channel that we're looking for which is just the index I mean we're not using a mask and it will
say 2 5 6 as that max range value and we'll define that range there.
And then we can go ahead and then plot just our ok and then we'll say here fealty title really whatever
you want to call it my histo.
So if you run that you should see a histogram that looks more or less like this.
Keep in mind your default colors may be slightly different than the ones here.
So what we can do is we can say Piazzi plot and then set the color to equal to the color code.
So then when you on this night you get the matching color code so red is red blue is blue and green
is green.
OK.
So that's it for this assessment.
If you have any questions for the post to the Q&amp;A forums.
But keep in mind you can always reference the solutions note book and pretty much all of this was a
carbon copy.
At least the commands were for the lectures.
So if you got stuck on something definitely review the lectures because essentially all the code came
from the previous lectures.
Okay thanks.
And we'll see you at the next section of the course.