Welcome back everyone to part two of deep learning on custom images.
A quick note.
In part two we're actually going to be building out the model and I'm going to introduce some slightly
different imports to reflect some of the most recent changes to cars.
These are just a few different imports.
Essentially just the wording is slightly changed.
So for instance we'll be saying Max pooling to D instead of Max Poole to the like we did in the previous
lectures.
Since we're using the latest version of course as of this filming it's Cara's 2.2.
They both actually still work.
So you're going to find both in online resources quite often.
But I do want to show you the latest updates the syntax changes.
So these functions are going to work exactly the same.
They're just spelt slightly differently.
Also we'll show you how you can add in activation functions separately from a dense layer.
So just a couple of minor changes.
Just want to give you a heads up.
So if you start wondering why is the syntax slightly different than the previous lectures.
That's why I want to show you the most recent updates to the documentation.
So as always these libraries tend to change quite often so you'll always want to check the official
documentation to see what the latest updates are.
But since Max pool to me is still quite commonly found in online tutorials I wanted to introduce that
one as well.
But let's go ahead now use max pooling to the.
It's the exact same function.
It's just spelt slightly differently.
So we're going head over to the you know book and build their model.
All right.
Here we are at our model and previously we set up the image data generator along with a bunch of random
manipulations that could occur things like rotation changing the width and height rescaling Shearing's
zoom range and more make sure don't introduce a typo there and then we can see the range of transformations
it does on the dog image.
And as I previously mentioned we're going to be changing our syntax very slightly for some of the imports
Soulsby saying from Karris that models in poor sequential Elisei from carious layers in poor are an
import activation which is something we haven't seen before it's basically a way to add in an activation
function after you provide a dense layer and then we also do a drop out which is another layer we haven't
seen before.
And then everything else you actually have seen before.
Flaten convolution to me and then as I previously mentioned we have both Max pool and Max pulling to
the.
We'll go ahead and use max pulling to the because the updates to the latest documentation.
Just to reiterate here there's really no difference between Max pool to the max pulling to the if you
actually search the documentation on pooling layer's the latest updates.
Now also a pooling of energy.
But if you were actually to be using tensor Flo's version of Cara's they still call it if you look up
here Max pool to the.
So that's why both versions still exist.
Tensor flow which is running on the back and then our version does it without the i n g.
And you can see here it actually links to both classes.
They have aliases Max pool to the point to the exact same function.
It's just an alias a different way of importing it.
So let's go in and create the model.
Will same model sequential.
And then we're going to add in a couple of players we'll say a model and I'm going to add in a 2D convolutional
for and we're going to start off with filter's equal to 32.
We're going to go for slightly smaller kernel size three by three and then my input shape is going to
be 150 by 150 by three.
So I chose this input shape a little arbitrarily tried to choose something that was more or less around
the average of these images.
And depending on what your images are you may have to choose something larger or smaller.
And what I wanted to do is I'm actually going to define above this model.
Input put shape equal to one fifty one fifty three.
So you can go ahead and do that.
And then if you want you can replace this tuple with the input variable.
It's up to you.
But we'll be using this input shape and basically we're going to do is when we actually call flow from
directory there's going to be another variable or parameter.
And if you shift tab here you can see it there's target size and you can manually then set the target
size to be 150 by 150.
And what Chris is going to do is it will shrink down images that are larger than that or stretch out
images that are smaller than that.
So Ill make sure they're all the same size 150 150.
That way you don't need to worry about manually resetting all the sizes yourself for all your images.
OK.
So we have the input shape ready to go.
The last we're going to do is set the activation.
And for all these convolutional is we'll just say that the activation function chosen is the rectified
linear unit.
Then after that we'll go ahead and add in a max pulling function will say Max pulling to the same thing
as Max pool to the just an alias.
And then we provide a pool size and will choose two by two and then what I'm going to do is I'm going
to copy this.
And since these images are quite complex we're going to add in two more convolutional layers with Max
pulling.
And I'm also going to do is add in a couple of more filters later on.
And you can feel free to experiment with filter's here.
Maybe start off of 64 unreduced on the 32 or start of 32 and then up to 64.
Really it's a lot of experimentation and a lot of reading about the latest papers and what filters work
best and what kernel sizes work best if you want.
You can feel free to add more published next pulling but after this we're just going to say model ad
and we're going to flatten this and then we'll say model ad and we'll add in a then Slayer and I'll
go ahead and say 128 neurons in that then Slayer.
Typically we also provide an activation function.
So notice we can provide active phase activation function within dance but I also want to show you that
if you needed to you could provide activation separately.
So if you wanted to maybe easily swap out activations you can do that as well.
So you can say activation are you and that's the same thing as providing within the dance as well.
Okay the next one is adding in a dropout layer.
So the dropout layer is actually a layer that we haven't seen before of course.
And as we previously mentioned what this does is it helps reduce overfitting by randomly turning neurons
off during training.
And here we're going to randomly turn off 50 percent of the neurons.
So you provide a percentage that you want of neurons randomly turned off.
So we're going to turn off 50 percent neurons randomly during training and that's going to help with
overfitting that it will say model ad and I'm going to add our last output and it's just one year on
because this is a binary target class it's either 0 for cat or 1 for dog and then we'll say model.
And I can add in the activation sigmoid again up to you whether you want to do this as one line or two
lines just different syntax here.
That may be reflective of Curiosus future.
Finally we're going to say model compile and I'll say loss is equal to binary cross entropy Stradling
binary classification binary meaning we only have two and then we'll say that the optimizer is Adam
and then the metrics we're going to be using our accuracy.
So go ahead and run that let's make sure we it.
So that should be con with a V.
So let's fix those run that again.
OK.
So got rid of those typos and then let's say model summary and there we go you can see the letters as
well as the different shapes.
Now it's time to train the model.
So the way this works is you're going to create image training generation objects for both training
and testing.
You need to choose a batch size so a good starting point for batch size is 16.
And again it really depends on the situation.
There's no real right or 100 percent correct answer.
You don't want to do too huge of a batch size.
Otherwise it'll take too long on each cycle to train your network.
So 16 is a fair amount especially for images of the size.
And then I'm going to say training image generator is equal to imagen.
And we're going to call that flow from the rectory and we're going to point it to the training data
which right now the way I've organized it is under Katz dog train.
And then what we need to do is provide the target size so the target size is the shape so we can say
target size and you can either manually say 150 50 or you can just provide what we already define which
is input shape and then say Colan up to 2 because remember we find the 150 about 150 further up in this
notebook.
Next we find the batch size we will say batch size is equal to batch size.
And then the class mode is binary because we're only dealing of two types of classes and after running
that you should see some sort of report on how many images it found belonging to how many classes were
going to do the exact same thing for the test.
Feel free to just copy this and paste it here and switch where it says Treen folder to test and then
we'll call this the test image generator.
Run that and then I'll say it found so many images belong into two classes in that Test folder.
And what's nice about this is off of that train image generation object you're going to have a lot of
different methods and attributes but a really useful one is class indices and this will actually tell
you what index belongs to what class.
So it's going to define zero as cats and one as dog notice.
It basically just kind of goes in alphabetical order or whatever or order it found the folders in and
then just labels them 0 1 and so on.
OK now it's time to actually get the generator.
This is going to take a really long time to get a good model.
I'm going to run it just for any POC so you can see what it will look like.
But then we're going to load up our own model sort of say model fit generator you're going to pass in
the training image you're going to set the amount of epoxy you want to train for.
How many passes.
So here we can say just one pass and the next parameter you can specify is steps per e.
Keep in mind typically eat Poch means that you've done a single full pass through the entire training
set.
So if you didn't have that IPAC here one IPAC would be a pass through all almost 19000 images.
Sometimes in your training that's just too much and you don't want each IPAC to be an entire set through
the training pass.
So what you could do is limit that by saying a certain amount of steps pretty.
You're only allowed to do 150 steps per Poch.
Remember we're also taking batch size into account here.
So that means you're grabbing batches of 16 150 times and you're labeling that as an epoch.
So that's really a close around 2400 training images instead of the full 18 thousands per epoch.
It's up to you how big you want to make these steps pretty you can think of this more as of a limiter
on the full Poch and it's really just to save you training time.
Granted you're not going to get as good a results if you don't train on as many images but it will take
way longer if you don't limit the steps for epoch that after that we're going to pass on our validation
data.
So we say validation underscore data and that's we're going to pass the test image generator.
And what's nice is as we actually fit the trainer We'll also be evaluating at the same time on the test
data and the validation can also have a certain amount of steps.
So we'll say validation steps is equal to 12.
So we'll go ahead and run that a should end up seeing a result.
So here's just one IPAC and those right now it's only going through 150 steps for that one epoch.
If you don't have that it would end up going through the entire training site.
OK so we should expect really great results here because we only did one epoch and we're not even going
through all the data.
Keep in mind you may get warnings as it trains.
You can feel free to ignore these warnings.
They're basically just telling you that it's not able to read certain images certain images in the data
set are blank or they're super small or maybe they're pure black.
So if you get these warnings there's no need to worry.
It just has to do with the particular images in the data set.
OK so I fast forward in time a bit that took around a minute to train on one epoch where we limited
the stats per eat pop.
And as I mentioned these are just warnings if you would like to ignore those warnings and not see them
then you can just copy and paste these two lines of code above the results model that fit generator.
It basically just says import warnings filter ignore the warnings.
Again these are just warnings or not actual errors.
It's basically just telling you.
Sorry I couldn't read that specific image.
I'm going to go ahead and skip it.
Typically that happens we have really tiny small images and if you actually take a look at some of these
data images.
There's like micro images of cats that are like one by one pixel so it's just going to go ahead and
skip those.
OK.
So go ahead run that.
Even though it's not really relevant to us anymore and we can also then evaluate the model.
So now we have the results remember we were validating during this process of fit generator and results
has a history that we can then call A.S.C. for accuracy.
And if you run that it will show you the historical results of its accuracy.
So on this very first pass remember only ran for one epoch it got 53 percent accuracy.
If you were to run this for more than one Apoc you would actually then see an array of historical accuracy
that you could plot.
Let me bring in the lecture notebooks so you can see what this would look like when I'm bringing in
over here.
So in this lecture notebook that we have here for you this is an example of training and evaluating
the model on 100 epochs.
Granted there's only 150 steps pretty Poch.
So you can see here it trained for hundred pocks to quite a bit of time.
I think I left it running for about two hours.
And if you then see historical accuracy it will show you this historical array of accuracy that you
can then call Piel t plot on and you get to see the accuracy plotted out and eventually it will begin
to level off.
So we're looking at around 80 percent accuracy on our training set and then we can't predict on new
images.
We're not going to get very good prediction if we use the one IPAC model.
So instead we're going to load a model that already trained for you.
In fact it's this model right here the 82 83 ish percent on the training set and I've saved that model
for you inside of the same folder that this note book is in.
So let's go ahead and load it up and come back to my notebook here and remember to load a model.
We just say from.
We import that load model functionality so that command in case you don't remember is just from carious
the models import load under underscore model.
And then we can say that the new model is equal to load model.
And in this case it's called Cat Dog 100 epochs thought H5.
So go ahead and load in that model.
It might take a little bit of time because it's quite a large model it's around 30 megabytes which is
pretty big for a model.
And then what we're going to do is predict a new class.
So let's imagine that we just train this results or whatever your model happens to be called for 100
epochs and then we save that and then we load it up again.
Now the question is if I'm presented a new image of a dog that I haven't seen before how do we actually
predict whether or not it's a dog.
So we're going to do is the following.
And again this is the process for predicting on an image that it's never seen before.
All we need to say is the dog file and actually find the path.
So let's go ahead and grab data.
We'll say cats.
It's actually just under cats for me here.
So undercuts dog.
I'm going to grab a test from dog and let's just grab kind of around that number here.
So there's lots of images you can choose from.
I'll just use any dog image.
I encourage you to do the same.
And what we need to do then is say from Paris pre-processing import image and what we need to do is
we need to resize the image that the neural network expects that we train on 150 by 50 pixel images.
So that's what we're going to do here.
We will say dog image is equal to image and I say load image will pass in the dog file and then say
target size is equal to 150 by 150 So there is our dog image and then we're going to turn it to an array.
So I will say dog image is equal to image and then say image to array and then pass in the dog image.
OK.
So check out the size right now.
Now there's two more steps we need to do before we actually predicts on the stock image.
The first one is right now the dimensions are 150 by 150 by three.
We need to change this so that the neural network thinks it's a batch of one image.
So we need to be one comma one fifty one fifty three.
So in order to do that we can use important up-I as MP and expand expanded Dimensions we'll say dog
image is equal to the dots expand dimensions and then pasand the dog image.
And then say axis equals to zero.
And then if you check out the document shape it will have been expanded once along the axes remember
you shouldn't rerun the cell multiple times.
Otherwise you'll keep expanding it.
OK so now that we have that in place we're going to do is make sure all the values are between 0 and
1.
So we'll say dog image is equal to dog image divided by 255.
And we want to predict.
We can say model predicts.
And there's a couple of things we can do here.
One of the rectory predict the class you can say pretty classes and then pass in the documents run it
and I'll predict that it's class 1 which remember if we come all the way back a peer that's a dog.
So it successfully predicted on a test image it's never seen before.
That is a dog that it was a dog.
If we want to see how sure it was that it was a dog we can just run predict by itself.
Pasand dog image and Ill say what percent sure it was so it had a prediction probability that it was
around 57 percent probability that it was a dog.
So 50 percent is the cutoff.
If it's less than that they'll think it's a cat.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture.
I hope you found that useful and I hope you now know how to train on your own image data.
Do you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums and make sure to check out the notebook
that goes with this lecture.
We'll see at the next one.