Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss in further detail how to open image files in a notebook
in the previous section of the course.
We saw how we could open an image file by using the python imaging library then using some PI to transform
it to an array and then using Map live with its show command in order to actually display the array
as an image inside of the notebook.
This is a lot of steps and the open sea the library can actually help fix some of the steps by making
it a little shorter.
So we're going to do is use open C-v in conjunction of live to weekly read and then image as an array
and then display it.
All right let's get started by opening up a notebook.
OK here we have a new notebook and I'm going to do a couple of imports.
We're an important umpire and P and then we'll also be importing that live pipe plot as Piazzi.
And since we want to see the images in the notebook itself.
We're going to say map plot line in line and that's a percent sign before that map published in line
come in.
Keep in mind if you're following along some sort of ID which is just a PI script this is only for the
Jupiter note book.
OK.
Now we actually need to import the open see the library and the way we do this is we simply say import
C-v to run that.
And if you have your environment activated then you should see it import.
OK.
Now I want to quickly show you a potential error and a potential error is if you actually try to use
the image reading capabilities of CB2 with the wrong path.
So I'm going to say image variable is equal to CB2 and then I'm going to call the in the read it which
stands for image read and the way this command works.
If you simply pass in the actual file path to the image is the JPEG file or the PNB file.
So for example I could say data forward slash and then I should be able to tab auto complete this if
I'm doing it correctly and then see that puppie jpeg.
So that automatically reads it in.
And if we check the type of the variable object it reads it indirectly as a pie array.
So we no longer need to have that intermediary step of transforming the actual image file into an umpiring
open CV.
Does that automatically for us by doing CB2 Imrie.
However there's a big potential error here and the potential error is if I were to say image is equal
to CB2 to Emory and what I'm going to do is I'm going to purposely pass in the wrong file.
So critics say wrong path does not and then just a bunch of jibberish.
A peg.
So there definitely isn't a file with all this jibberish J pig and this patch definitely doesn't exist
on my computer.
You'll notice that when I run this I actually don't get an error.
And instead what happens is it just returns back none type.
So there's a big potential here for actually getting an error because you're not warned if you pass
in the wrong file path.
So a lot of times beginners get stuck here because they're saying hey I'm able to do the image read
and I'm not getting an error when I run this command.
So my path must be correct.
But that's actually not the case.
You should always be checking if you ever have any doubts.
The type of the variable that's returned by CB2 that Imrie if it's returning a none type then you're
not providing the correct path to the image.
OK.
So let's actually grab this line again and make sure we read in the correct path.
Check the type of image and there we go it's a non-pilot right.
So again keep in mind if you provide the wrong path you don't get the error.
Instead it's just a nun type.
So we're going to continue here and I'm going to show you what the image actually looks like.
It's Remember a pie array.
And if you take the shape of it it's 13:00 by 1950 by three.
So now I no longer need to worry about transforming this into an umpire right.
Now let's imagine we wanted to show this image while I could just say realty show and then pass in the
image.
However you'll notice something kind of strange happens here.
It's showing the image in kind of a weird bluish tint.
And the reason for that is because open C-v and map plot lib expect different orders of the red green
blue channels.
So that's an important distinction to note.
So the way that plot lib thinks of image for red green blue it's going expect the red green blue channels
to show up in this order.
So it expects red then green then blue.
However open see what it does is it read them in in a slightly different order.
It reads them in as blue green red.
So what happened is when we actually read in that file with open C-v we're reading it in as if it was
a blue green red channeled image and that public is displaying it as if it's a red green blue image.
So some of these channels specifically the red and the blue one they're accidentally getting swapped.
So that's why when we actually display the image after reading it in with CB2 that Imrie we get this
kind of weird coloration.
So what we need to do is actually transform this to go from blue green red to red green blue the way
a map it expects it so C-v to actually has functionality for that.
What we do is we say CB2 dot CVT color.
Notice the see is capitalize on that color and then the way this function works as you passen FARC or
the source.
And then you pasand some sort of color code.
So we already have our image that's the source we're going to say.
I M.G. you say CB2 dot and then all caps color underscore and if you hit tab here you'll notice that
there's a bunch of different options.
So essentially open C-v that library can convert from any color space to any other.
So you know this as a bunch of different codes here to go from green red to blue green red.
So the main syntax here is you provide color underscore and then it's current channel ordering like
blue green red and then you transform it to a different channel coloring.
So you notice a ton of options here where they're really not using all of these options really a few
of them.
The main one we're going to right now is to go from blue green red to red green blue.
So that's just a simple transformation.
That's all we actually need and a kick out of this now.
So all we're saying is take this original image and you read it in as a blue green red channel image
convert it please to red green blue.
That way I can display it correctly with realty show talking about going to call this fixed image is
equal to CB2 that original image and then the color space is going to get converted.
So now I have my fixed image here.
And I say peel teeth that show and then I can display my fixed image and now I see it in the correct
color channel coding.
So again all that's happening here is open C-v is reading things as if they were blue green red and
that plebe expects things to be red green blue.
So if you don't do this color conversion you make it's kind of a strange thing here.
All right.
Now the next thing I want to show is let's imagine you have a colored image but you immediately want
to read it in as a greyscale image.
Well open C-v can actually do that for you as well.
So we're going to take our original Emarine command because it adds color code to it.
So I'm going to say image underscore Gray is equal to CB2 and I'm going to call him read.
So our original image reader and then I'm going to pass in the original file path again.
In this case data we should be able to tab autocomplete that.
And then as a second argument I'm going to pass an image read codes are going to say emerita.
And if you hit tab here you'll notice there's lots of different ways to read an image such as reduced
color.
You can't ignore orientation and so on.
The only thing we're going to say here is underscore grayscale solution to choose greyscale.
And what this does is it says hey no matter what colors this image has.
Go ahead and do a fresh read of it an important as a greyscale image.
So I'm going to read that in and if we check the actual shape here.
Notice now it no longer has that third dimension because you read it in as a greyscale image it no longer
has a need for three color channels instead it's just a bunch of values that go from zero to 55.
So if you check the minimum value here or actually goes from 1 in this case because that's how pure
black I guess.
And then we'll check the max here.
The max is 2 9 so there's actually no pure white either.
So let's go ahead and see what this great out version looks like.
We're going to say realty show and check out this great out version.
And there we have our Grayskull version.
Now you're probably wondering why is this not in black and white.
So that again has to do with the default color mapping that show uses the default color mapping as we
explained previously is that viridis which takes Dharker values and shows them as kind of a blue and
then takes lighter values and shows them as kind of a yellowish green.
So what we're going to do here is just say See map and say it's great.
And then it's just going to choose a color mapping that actually corresponds to grayscale.
So that's how you can read in color images as grayscale the things that go here.
As I said CB2 that read I passed then the source of the original image file and then said CB2 immured
greyscale.
And if you actually want to display the image using that lib as grayscale then you actually need to
specify that the scale the color mapping for it should be gray.
Keep in mind you can check out the map Cutlip color mappings and choose other color mappings if you
want.
So for example magma is one that would take dark values close to zero.
Treat them as kind of a dark blackish purple and then take light values as kind of an orange.
But if our use cases we can actually visualize grayscale.
So just say See map is equal to agree.
OK.
So just a few more things I want to talk about as far as basic image manipulation.
I want to talk about resizing images and then also kind of flipping images around and saving image files.
So we're almost done here.
Let's talk about resizing images.
It's actually pretty straightforward.
All we need to do is do the following.
I'm going to say a sugar image again.
We have image and whoops go ahead and show t show image.
So that's our image right now.
And in fact we never actually saved our conversion.
I don't believe so.
We do have a fixed image so let's take that fixed image and show it.
So this is our original image we can actually see the scale here from zero to around 13:00 then from
0 to around 1950.
If I want to actually check the shape of this I can say fixed image check the shape and it's 13:00 by
1950.
So if I want to resize the image I can actually do it a simple resize command will say CB2 dot resize
and then the arguments it takes is the source and then the Deeside or destination size.
And you can scroll down and check out the parameters here.
Couple more but really all we need to worry about is passing in the original image.
We'll say Fix image and then we can pass on the new dimensions we want.
So for example if we wanted to really squeeze this down I could say is make the width now maybe like
half of it.
So let's go ahead and choose 1000 for the with and then let's go ahead and make the height really squeezed.
Let's go ahead and make it just like around 400.
So it's going to really squeeze the image here and then we'll say something like.
New image is equal to CB2 that resize.
And if I say to him Show this new image.
Notice here kind of how squeeze that is.
So right now we have zero to 400 and then 0 to 1000.
So keep in mind that I mentioned here they're actually swapped from the original shape.
So this 1000 is actually connected to this 1950 and this 400 is the resizing for his 13:00.
So that's a little confusing at first that it takes in the x and y kind of the opposite way that the
umpire thinks about it.
But it's just something to get used to.
And you can sort out the resize and the dimensions used here in order to understand that relationship
better.
But luckily there's a skill bar here that kind of clearly shows the relationship.
So he went from zero to 13:00 down to zero to 400.
So it changes 13:00 to 400.
And this 1950 to 1000 and noticed that it conveniently does this for you across all three channels that
we don't get any distortion across the actual color channels.
So we were able to resize often you're probably gonna want to resize by ratio instead.
So that's actually quite simple.
So if I want to resize by a ratio I just need to choose my With ratio and my height ratio.
So let's go ahead and make this whole image 50 percent smaller.
So I will say my weight ratio is 0.5 or 1 1/2.
And then also say that my height ratio is 0.5.
So I essentially want to reduce the image by 50 percent ratio.
Then the next thing I'm going to do is create a variable to hold my new resized image call it and you
underscore image and we're going to use the same resize command but the parameters are going to be slightly
different.
We're going to first take in the image that we want to resize.
So I want to resize that fixed image and then you pasan 00 as a tuple and then you get a pass and the
image again is the premolars are a bit strange.
And the way they're passing him in.
But this how resized works.
If you want to do it by a particular ratio so it's the image you're going to resize tuples of 0 0 and
then the image you want to resize again and then provide the width ratio and the height ratio.
So you're going to pride with ratio and height ratio.
They don't need to be variables you could've just passed those values indirectly.
But there's a little more explanatory.
So then we're going to run that and then say pilt t him show.
Then you image.
You'll notice that it's been resized to half of the dimensions.
So if I take new image here and then check its shape.
It's now 650 by 9 7 5.
Now we can adjust this further.
Maybe I only want the ratio to be reduced to 80 percent of its original but median what the height ratio
to be reduced to 20 percent of its original so the way to read these is for example here are saying
20 percent of original height.
So it's not 20 percent off between percent of the original so far to rerun these you'll notice now the
height is 20 percent of its original height but the width is almost same.
It's about 80 percent of the original with so I second check the shape there.
You can see it's 260 and then 15.
So if I were to say to 60 times five that's 13:00 which is the original.
Which makes sense because five times 20 is a hundred or hundred percent.
OK.
So that's how you can resize based off a ratio.
And there's three more things we want to show you before we finish off this lecture.
I know it's going a little long but all we're going to do is show you how to flip images along the horizontal
or vertical axes.
The way you do that is you just create a new image variable and you say CB2 flip and then you pass in
the image you want to flip.
So let's go ahead and pass in our original fixed image.
And if you type in zero here as a second parameter and then show Hilti him show this new image you'll
notice that it's now been flipped along a horizontal axis essentially showing it upside down.
If you want to flip it along the vertical middle axes do you just when you say one here.
So again the original shows the dog on the right side.
So now flip that along this vertical midway point so another dog looks like on the left side.
If you want to do both flips at once you can say a negative one.
So again just CB2 flip the image you want to flip and then either 0 1 0 or negative 1 and will actually
be using the input command to generate more images and we actually have four deep learning purposes
later on in the course.
So that CB2 flip.
Let's also quickly show you how you can save an image file.
So if you have an image file that's a pie array inside of your notebook.
So I'm going to say type and then let's go ahead and say fix image.
That's an umpire Ray.
If I want to write this to a new file I can say CB2 I am right.
Essentially the opposite of I read.
And then you pass and whatever file path you want to say that too.
So I can say totally new wups underscore new thought JPA.
So that's my image here.
And then I just pass on what I actually want to write.
So in this case we'll say fix them.
So this takes the fixed image variable that's an umpire and then writes it to this jpg file and it can
write to quite a few different file types you can check out the documentation here.
As far as all the different file types you can save too.
Ok so I want to run this and totally new that J peg.
I just saved it to the same folder that the stupid note book is in.
So if I expand my file browser here you should be able to see somewhere here totally new that jpeg or
whatever we happen to call the file.
And you can also click on Last-Modified to kind of find that so few seconds ago I saved totally knew
that jpeg.
So that's how you can save files.
And the very last thing we're were talk about is how to display these images slightly larger inside
of a notebook.
You'll notice that this is actually quite a really large image.
13:00 by 1950 that's actually almost the size of the monitor but the notebook will kind of shrink it
down to display it so that it fits in the notebook.
However you can adjust the essentially canvas space allowed for the notebook to display the image on
and the way you do that is a little bit of that live.
And don't worry about understanding this code.
Just understand that we're going to be referencing this code.
So we say figure Piazzi figure and then we say fix size is equal to.
And then you actually give some dimensions in inches so we can say 10 by eight.
So that allows a blank canvas space of 10 by eight inches.
Then you say X axes is equal to Fig dot adds subplots 1 1 1.
So it just says essentially one by one subplot a single image and then we say X that show and then whatever
image you want to display.
So this is some really heavy kind of a little more complicated map plot lib code.
The only thing you really need to understand here is we're going to be kind of functional using this
code later on the course so you'll see me copy and paste these three lines.
Essentially the most important thing is this figure size.
Now you can designate a larger blank canvas area for this image to fill out more than the actual default.
So for a show here you'll notice now I have a lot more space to work with or if you want to make weightless
less space.
You could say something like too by to show it.
And then you have less canvas to show.
So essentially just to find out how much blank canvas space can I use in the Jupiter notebook and you
should keep mine.
I'm actually quite zoomed in on my browser I'm 300 percent zoomed in.
So your results may look exactly like mine.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture.
I know there was a lot but the main things were just using Open see the lib to actually display images
inside of a notebook.
Coming up next we'll talk about how to use open C.V in a script setting.
We'll see if.