Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to briefly go over the course curriculum before we actually begin the course and the technical
content.
I want to build an understanding of our particular learning path and why we're starting where we actually
do and how we approach the various topics in this course.
So let's give a brief overview of main topics and the structure of the curriculum of the course.
So my overall goals for this course is free to be able to understand computer vision applications.
And as we learn about more and more topics we're going to start relating them to real world applications.
At first we're not going to understand enough about computer vision and open C-v to actually make the
jump to some sort of real world application.
But as we continue to build off of the little bits and pieces that we learn along the way we're going
to be able to make more and more connections to computer vision applications like being able to build
out our own license plate blurring software or being able to understand how deep learning image classification
works.
But in order to make that leap we're gonna have to learn the building blocks along the way.
My other goals for you after completing this course is to understand how to use open C-v and Python
to work with images and videos and more importantly be able to apply these skills to your own projects.
If we were to jump ahead directly to deploying learning computer vision you would be able to do the
projects we show in this course but then probably wouldn't have the skills to actually apply that to
your own projects.
So that's what we're going to start with the very basics and build our knowledge and understanding as
we go along that we once you complete the course you're able to apply everything you've learned to your
own projects.
So we're going to start off with learning about a library called NUMP pie.
And if you take in some of my other courses you may already be familiar if not pie in this particular
section we're really going to focus on two things about pi.
The first thing is how to work arrays and slicing and indexing arrays and that's the main data type
that Num. PI holds.
And then the second main part is how to actually read images and display images with some PI.
After that we'll have a section on image basic's with another library called Open C-v for open computer
vision.
And we'll begin to work with open C.V in order to work with just the very basics of images and how to
draw images simple commands like that.
Once you've learned the basics of Pi and open see how to work with images of both those libraries will
start the more complex and advanced functionalities of image processing of open C.v.
So these are where we're going to be learning about Advanced Open C-v operations that are actually useful
in real world applications.
Then once you've gotten a handle on images we're going to move on to video processing of open C.v.
So we'll kind of go back to basics however instead of dealing with image data we're going to learn how
to work with existing video files.
MP force or die.
AVI files and we'll also learn how to deal with streaming webcam videos all of the open C-v library.
After that we'll move on to object detection.
So we'll learn the various different methods of the tech the objects and images and videos.
So we're going to start with a basic template matching that is to say if you're given an image can you
find that image in a larger image and then we're going to work all the way up to things like face detection
so we can actually detect faces in photos and videos.
Once we understand object detection we'll move onto object tracking.
So this directly expands from the knowledge of the previous section to actually then track and detect
objects in videos.
So object detection allows you to detect in a single image object tracking allows you to kind of continue
that detection through various frames and track it in a video.
Then we move on to kind of the more final sections of the course which is deep burning of computer vision.
And that's where we begin the compain combine the knowledge from all the previous sections with the
latest tools and libraries like Harris intenser flow.
First they are deep learning applications and they will also be able to download state of the art neural
networks in order to perform image classification on your own data sets.
So keep in mind of course is a very gradual buildup in computer vision.
I know a lot of time students want to jump straight to the awesome deep learning applications but it's
really important that you take your time with these topics as they can be pretty advanced.
Now this understanding of fundamental concepts will like to apply these skills to your own projects.
OK.
I'm super excited to get started now.
The technical sections.
So we're going to get started and the next lecture is going to help you set up everything you need in
order to open up our course notebooks as well as have our provided environment work for you.
OK.
Let's get started.