Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss opening image files using open C-v with Python scripts.
So in this lecture we're going to be using the open C library to display images in their own separate
window outside of Jupiter.
For more complex video on image analysis that we performed later on in the course we're going to need
this play outside of Jupiter.
Now while we will often just use pilt that show as we showed in the previous lecture display images
inside of the notebook we're often going to also want to use open C-v on its own.
Now the caveat is that often Jupiter since it's based in the browser it interferes with closing the
window.
So that means that many times Jupiter lab can display a new window if no issues but the kernel will
crash when you actually try to close that open C.V window and to fix that potential issue.
All you need to do is simply restart the kernel inside of the notebook.
And these issues actually tend to appear more on Mac OS and Linux than in Windows.
So I'll try my best to recreate the issue here and show you how you can potentially solve it.
But don't be surprised if you actually don't run into any of these errors or issues.
So again if you get the kernel error more often you may simply just run your code as a separate Python
script so to show these potential issues.
And we're also going to show you how to open and display images directly with open C.v.
Now Matt Plup lib and we're showing both the notebook and as a separate script.
So let's get started.
OK here we are in a brand new notebook.
I'm first going to show you how to open up an image in a notebook and a potential error that can happen.
So we're going to say import CB2.
And this is all going to go in the same cell.
And that's actually quite important for this.
So we're going to say that image is C-v to that image read and we're going to import that image that
we've been reading.
It's that puppy image can go ahead and make sure it is all capitalized here.
Data puppie jpeg and then we're going to do is say C-v to dot and then this has its own show command
and it takes in two parameters here.
One is whatever you want to call the window name.
So you can say puppy make sure there's no spaces in that when the name.
And then the second parameter is the actual image you want to display.
So in this case I want to show that puppy image.
And then finally we say CB2 thought wait capital K E Y and that's basically going to be a signal for
us to be able to click the exit button and close that window.
Later on we'll see some more sophisticated techniques that allow us to escape key or Q In order to close
windows.
So I'm going to go ahead and run the cell and everything's in the same cell.
I'm going to run it and after you run that cell you should notice that has an asterix there meaning
that it's currently running the cell.
And if you look back down at your taskbar you should now see kind of a little extra window that Jupiter
lab icon.
And if you click on that window now you see the puppy image in its own separate window.
Now it's kind of interesting about this is that you actually cannot resize this window.
So open TV is just going to display the same dimensions.
Everything in my case fits on the screen.
But if you're running this on a laptop with a smaller screen this may take actually the entirety of
your screen.
So keep that in mind.
It's quite a large image.
And now I'm going to do is I'm going to go ahead and exit this out.
And once you exit you should then notice kind of something output here like negative 1.
So that's if everything is running correctly.
However often on Mac OS or Linux what's going to happen is if you run this and then you get back the
window and you try to exit and you're going to induce the error here.
What may happen is as you try to exit it's not closing and things start slowing down.
You suddenly get puppy isn't responding and there's some sort of error.
And basically here happened is your Colonel died.
So you get some sort of thing like would you like to shut down Python et cetera.
So in this case if you're getting this sort of error that means you need to run this as a script which
we're going to show in just a second.
But in order to actually show you how to do this or we need to do is you need to close the program.
So if you're on a Mac OS or Linux you can kind of force quit that particular windows just right click
at the bottom taskbar hit force quit.
So in this case and a close the program close it cancel.
And now what you need to do is kernel restart.
You need to restart the kernel.
So if you don't restart the kernel that means the code's not going to run.
And we should do it just to make sure that everything's running say prints new or print something do
shift enter and you should now see a 1 next to whatever cell that is.
All right.
So we just saw how we can open images using open C-v directly in that show.
The CB2 version of it from the notebook.
However we also noticed that there's a potential for the kernel to crash due to the way Jupiter works.
So now we're going to see how to open files using open C-v and the normal Python that PI script.
So before continuing on to this part of the lecture you should make sure you understand how to run Python
scripts.
Your command line before beginning of the lecture and in general you should already have those skills
before enrolling into this course and this pretty basic Python but you can always check out some of
the previous lectures in the intro section and the Jupiter lab overview section in question and a review
on that.
But let's go ahead and move on and actually write out a Python script.
All right so here I am back of the notebook we're using before.
Let's go ahead and now run this as a Python script with a few extra lines of code in order to alleviate
any kernel errors you may be experiencing.
So I'm going to copy all of this code and then I'm going to come back here I'm going to hit my little
plus sign as a new launcher and I'm going to scroll down and I'm going to create a new text file.
And right now this is the text file I need to add about my file.
So I right click and rename this rename to something unique such as my puppy dot pie.
Make sure you don't call it something like open C-v that pie that may screw something up so don't call
it non-pilot pie.
Make sure it's unique name.
So now we have my puppy that pie and I'm going to paste in the code I had before we're going to make
a few adjustments.
This code.
So what we're going to do here is a more recent import CB2 CB2 read.
But now for this show I'm gonna put this inside a while loop.
So I will say while true show this image.
Now if I were to just have that by itself.
The problem is this just continually showed that image forever over and over again.
So I need to have some sort of break condition to break out of this while loop and what I'm going to
have is two conditions.
I will say if C-v to dot weight key and then I'm going to pass in a number and the what the waky function
does is it basically says have I waited at least this many milliseconds.
So you can provide any number there you want and then we're going to say ampersands and I will say 0
x f f equals equals 27 and then we'll say colon break.
OK.
So what is this actually doing because this is a really strange line of code.
And in fact we've actually linked in our notes to this stack overflow post that essentially explains
what's going on at 0 x f f so often when you're working in an open C-v you'll see a loop that looks
something like this.
If CB2 waky and this kind of a weird symbol O X F-F equal to and sometimes you'll even see it as ordinal
of some letters some string and then it'll break.
So what that's actually saying is it's a hexadecimal constant which is all these ones in binary.
And then it's using this bitwise comparison ampersand or.
And along with that constant.
And what this essentially says if you're to translate this is if we've waited at least 1 milliseconds.
So that's the first part CB to wake you saying Make sure you wait at least one millisecond and then
the ampersand is and we pressed the escape key.
So this essentially translates to as far as 27 that it's passed that a signal from the keyboard and
it's Press the escape key later on.
We'll see how to add in our own key commands for keyboard.
And in fact in that stack overflow they decided to use ordinal Q which essentially says wait for the
cue to be pressed.
So we'll explore that later on especially with drawing with images.
But right now I'll stick with what is most often default which is 27 which is the symbol for the escape
key or the number for the escape.
So say if you've waited at least one millisecond and we've pressed the escape key go ahead and break
out of this while true loop meaning no longer show this image.
And then after this while true loop we're going to say C-v to dot and we'll type out destroy all windows.
Notice how the ANWR uncapitalized there and then I'm going to save my changes.
Make sure you save your changes if you see a gray circle up here that means your changes haven't been
saved.
So you need to control as are command us.
OK so I'm importing CB2.
I'm reading in that file.
And while this is true I'm gonna keep showing that puppy in its image and its new window and I know
that at least one millisecond.
And then wait for the user to press the escape key before a break out of this while loop.
And then I'm going to destroy all the windows the close everything.
So make sure you save that and then let's actually run this script.
So to come back to my launcher I'll create a new terminal and then I'm going to say Python and then
I'm going to type out my puppy pie or I'll hit enter and you should see the cursor blinking here and
what's going to happen now is over at the bottom you should not have an image and you see this puppy
image and we're going to build to do no escape on our keyboard and that will close the image.
OK.
And that's how you can use the open see the show method correctly within its own Python script.
And when we're working closely with C-v to that show which we'll be doing a lot for using videos or
interactive images for some more complex analysis.
Oftentimes we'll be running scripts and what's nice to do and what my preferred workflow method is is
putting everything in one cell in a notebook first and then just copying and pasting over to the PI
file I really like that because Jupiter has a lot of those special functionalities such as being able
to do shift tab in order to understand what's actually going on or seeing tab.
So you can take the advantage of Jupiter and then just put it all to that pie.
So that's a big reason are using Jupiter ALAP for this course to have notebooks scripts and terminals
all easily available to us.
OK.
So don't worry too much about understanding the exact details behind this line.
Just understand that all is doing is saying wait a millisecond and then check if you press the escape
key.
If so break out of this.
All right.
So that's it for using open C.v.
If you have any questions feel free to post that Kewaunee forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.