Welcome back so far we've seen how we can stream video from a U.S. Speed camera and how it can open
already existing video files.
Now let's see how we can actually draw on video.
We'll first learn how to draw a static object.
Then we'll learn how to actually interactively draw on a video.
Let's get started.
Let's begin by working through how we can draw on the video.
Hopefully you notice that the procedure is actually really similar to how we already draw on a regular
image.
It's just in this case we'll be drawing on a frame we'll import CB2 and then we'll start the capture
CB2 the video capture.
And I'm going to be streaming directly from a USP camera.
And let's go ahead and grab the width and height of the stream.
You remember we can do this with Cap get and then we're going to do is pass in here the property we
actually want to grab.
So in this case I want to grab capture prop and it's going to be the frame with.
And as I mentioned before we usually want to cast this as an integer to avoid any errors.
So I'm going to copy and paste this line and will do the exact same thing for the with Susan for the
hype so let's capture the heights.
And instead of saying with here we'll say height OK.
So there's our width and height and we're going to be doing is we're going to be drawing a rectangle
onto the actual stream we'll say while true
grab threats and Frane from reading that current capture and remember the frame is essentially just
a single image.
So we can use CB2 rectangle just as we've done in the past we passed in the frame and then we're going
to pass in the actual coordinates of the first point and the second point.
Now in deciding the coordinates we're going to be calculating them based off the width and height of
the actual current capture.
So let's do this let's go ahead and start off our first point.
X and Y at let's say the halfway point of the width and the halfway point of the height we'll say with
forward slash forward slash 2 and Y is equal to height.
Forward slash force slash to.
Now the reason I'm doing two forward slashes is because I want to make sure that these x and y coordinates
stay as integers because depending on your brake system you sometimes get errors if you try passing
in a float there.
So what I mean by that is if I were to say for instance 10 divided by five you'll notice that I get
back to point zero.
However if I say 10 forward slash fours slash five I get back an integer 2.
So this four slash four slash allows us to return an integer.
That way we make sure these coordinates stay as integers and we'll do the same thing for the width and
height.
So what I'm going to do is the width and height of the rectangle width and height of rectangle.
So not the actual video stream just at the rectangle will have that be one fourth of the actual video
stream.
So I say with divided by four and then height divided by four.
Again keeping things as integers.
So this is going to calculate the top left corner and then for the bottom right corner.
Well we're going to do is say that the bottom right corner will be the Xplornet Plus with and then the
y coordinate plus height.
And hopefully when we actually draw this will become more clear what this actually ends up looking like.
So the frame for point one will just passen the x and y we just cultivated and then 4.2 will add in
the width and height that we just calculated.
And you can play around these values.
Right now we're just basing them off the width of the height that way depending on what your USP camera
is you should be able to use this exact same code that I'm using.
If you actually know that mentions that you're recording it you could pasand straight up values here
if you want it to.
Then when you decide on a color.
So let's just make this some primary color well say 0 0 2 5 5 and then give this rectangle a thickness
just as we've done before.
Well go just say four pixel thickness.
And then once you've actually drawn the rectangle then we'll show the frame say frame show that frame
it's really important that you don't reverse the order here.
Otherwise you'll be showing the frame and then drawing a rectangle on it.
You want to draw the rectangle first and then show that frame.
Then after that will give a command that allows us to escape from this we'll say Wait key Wait a millisecond
and then we'll give the Cuban as our exit 1 0 x f equals equals ordinal Q And then we will break out
of this.
Finally we'll go ahead and release to capture and say CB2 destroy all windows.
OK.
So let's kind of quickly go over what we did here.
We're capturing the video.
We're grabbing the width and height of the actual video being returned.
We decided to set the top left corner at the middle point of the width and the height and then the actual
width and height of the rectangle itself will be a quarter of the whole size of the image.
And then we went ahead and drew that rectangle and then we're showing it the frame after trying to rectangle
on it.
So let's run this and see if it works.
So there we have it.
We can see the rectangle right around here.
And what I'm going to do now is to escape and then we're going to show you now is how to interactively
draw on a video.
So often we're going to be doing in our course is actually just these x and y coordinates will be defined
by some sort of object detection such as where it happened to see a face.
But just in case you ever want to interactively draw something on a video.
We'll go ahead and show you how you can do that.
Keep in mind we don't really do this that often during the course but I do want to show it because this
is now the appropriate time to show that.
OK so let's get started showing you how you can actually interactively draw on a video as a quick note
if you get any errors during this process.
There is a huge potential for typos here.
So please try running our provided notebooks and files first before posting the Kewney forums.
If you get any sort of error because there's lots of potential for typos here.
OK.
So here I am at our previous cell.
I don't delete the stuff we actually don't need since we're not drawing based on the height and width
any more and instead will be the finding ourselves based on our mouse click.
I don't delete those lines here and then I will also delete this rectangle line.
So we're just starting with the very basics of capturing a video displaying it and then at the end breaking
what we need to do is to find a couple of things we're going to be defining a callback function and
this callback function is going to be drawing a rectangle.
And then we're also going to be defining some global variables and then on this frame we're going to
be drawing on the frame based off the global variables.
And then also pass the global variables.
What we're going to need to do is make the connection.
So connect to the callback.
Those are main steps.
Let me quickly show you what the finished product is going to look like before we actually code this
out.
So this is what the finished product should look like.
Notice I'm going to click once left down and you see this little red circle there.
Then I'm going to choose point two for my rectangle and then it's going to create the rectangle.
And if I click again will erase that rectangle draw and you circle points and then again do a rectangle
So that's essentially going to be doing here interactively drawing.
Let's get started going to quit this and we're going to Flete Dakota have there because that was the
actual code for running this and going to type it out ourselves.
OK.
So the callback function I'm going start at the very basics here.
We'll call it the f.
Draw a rectangle.
And as always these callback functions are going to take an event the x and y coordinates and then loops
the flags and then program and then right now actually leave a pass here.
Let's find the global variables the global variables are going to be point one of the rectangle which
will start off 0 0 and then point to the rectangle which will also start off at 0 0.
Remember point 1.
Then make sure that T either see already commencing typos.
So point 1 that's the top left point to the bottom right.
We're also going to create two tracker's top left clicked and started off as false and then bottom right
clicked and also started off as false.
And what these are going to indicate is whether or not I clicked the point that I intend to be the top
left.
And whether or not I could the point that I intend to be the bottom right and as those get clicked up
the point one and point do.
Once these are both true that means I'm ready to draw my rectangle.
OK then let's connect to the callback.
So we already are capturing this.
Let me just put this right here on Connect to callback just for organization purposes.
So I have my capture and just as we did for images I'll create a named window and I'm going to call
it test and then I will connect this to my callback will say CB2 and we'll set a mouse callback also
on test and then we'll connect that to that draw rectangle function.
And notice here this is still called frame on the show.
And I want to make sure that name matches.
So we'll also call that test.
So we've connected to the callback we have are global variables the only two steps left is to draw on
the frame based off the global variables and then use this callback function to actually update the
global variables.
I'm going to start by defining how we're going to draw on the frame that way this callback function
makes more sense.
We'll come over here.
Drawing on the frame based off the variables.
This is we're going to do.
We're going to say if the top left has been clicked that means top left is now equal to true and it's
up to you how you want to do this.
Top left click.
That's already a boolean.
So overbilling is say is top left clicked colon but it's more or if it's easier for to read if you say
equals true.
You can do that as well but since it's already a boolean to me this is a little more readable.
Will say if the top left has been clicked meaning if it's true I'm going to draw a little circle the
circle just going to be a little marker for me to kind of keep track of where we are.
So I'm going to draw a circle on the frame that I just read in in the line above here frame capture
read that little circle is going to have a center around point 1.
So that means when I actually click for the first time I need to define 0.1 topless being clicked or
draw a circle at point 1.
Let's give it a radius of five.
It's up to you how big of a circle you probably noticed I was clicking at little circle and let's give
it a color.
Well go ahead and have the color be red so 0 0 2 5 5 remember for open C.v.
It's going to go blue green red.
So that's white.
That last one is 2 5 5.
And let's fill in the circle.
We'll say thicknesses equal to negative 1.
This is just so I can actually have a visual marker of where I clicked on the top left.
Now I will say if the top left has been clicked and the bottom right has also been clicked then I'm
ready to actually draw my rectangle.
By this point I show up with point 1 and point to the find will say CB2 rectangle and I'm going to draw
directly on the frame.
My point one may point to my color choice which is go ahead and also make it red.
And then my thickness in this case will give it a thickness of something like 30 pixels up to you again
whatever thickness you want and that's all I need to do.
So this is going to draw a little circle.
When it click on top left and when I clicked both top left and the bottom right then I'll finish off
by drawing my rectangle.
So that's step number three.
The last one is how do we actually update point 1 and point 2 while we're at it.
Also top left click and bottom right clicked.
So let's make sure we actually hit bottom right clicked Yep we're good to go there.
Well actually need to read in these variables on a global will read in.
Point one point to we'll read and top left click and we'll read them lips.
Bottom right clicked and I encourage you to use tab autocomplete to save some time.
And let's get rid of this pass.
There's going to be a mouse click.
So I'll say if the event is equal to CB2 events will go with left button down.
So once that click that left button down if top left click is equal to true and bottom right clicked
is all also equal to true.
Again I could have written this just if top left click and bottom right clicked.
So if both of those have been equal to true that means the rectangles already been drawn which means
this is essentially the reset.
So we want to check first if we're going to reset or not.
So this has reset the rectangle essentially erase the rectangle.
So if I want to reset everything then that means I essentially want to reset the global variables as
they are here.
So it's going to copy this and paste it.
Meaning I will reset point 1 to be zero point two to be zero and say top left is now false and bottom
right is now false.
So this is resetting the rectangle and it checks if the rectangle is already there because the top left
click and the bottom right clicked OK.
So let's say I haven't actually clicked anything yet.
That means if my top left clicked is equal to false then I haven't clicked first so I'm going to say
Point 1 is equal to wherever I clicked which is going to be at the x and y passed back by that callback.
So point 1 is now equal to x and y and I will update this to say yes I did actually already click Top
left.
Notice here that differences between one of these in double equal signs versus single equal sign so
I'm assigning top left as now true.
Now the top left click is true.
It means point 1 has been defined which means top left click is going to be true here.
So I to draw a circle based off just point 1.
Now if I've already clicked top left but I haven't clicked the bottom right then I have the third situation.
And then finally what I'll say here is Elif bottom right clicked is equal to false then take point two
and said equal to x y and then set.
Bottom right clicked equal to true.
Notice here how this last one is.
If that way it works in conjunction with the top left being clicked.
So now after running through this I should have top left clicked as true and bottom right click this
true meaning we set both point 1 and point 2.
These are both now true meaning this is going to execute.
Top left clicked and bottom right.
They both clicked.
So I draw a rectangle with point 1 and point 2.
Let's run this and see if it works.
So I run this.
It's connected to my Web cam right now on a click once to my left.
So it looks like I have the circle there.
Let me click again and I draw the rectangle.
Let's see if redrawing a new rectangle works.
I click over here that rectangle is now been reset to 0 0 and then I click over here and looks like
my rectangles are working just fine.
OK.
So that's all there is to it.
Let me quickly do a review of everything we've done.
Keep in mind the n won't really be interactively drawing on too many videos but all we're doing here
is we set the callback function.
It's checking for events.
It's having some sort of logical operation with these variables to keep track of things.
It has these global variables.
We do the connection and then based off those global variables that are updated in the callback function
we can then draw on the frame we want to make sure that we draw the frame first before we show it.
All right that's it.
If you're getting any errors please make sure to run our provided code that rakli because there's lot
potential for typos here.
Thanks and we'll see at the next lecture.