Welcome back to four of your cup project.
Well we're going to bring all the functions together and write a little bit of code to actually run
the program connect to our camera and then our fingers.
Let's get started.
OK.
In this final cell we're going to begin actually grabbing our video.
So say video capture or of this from a live stream.
So put zero.
And we actually want to calculate that background using that background function.
The accumulated running way average so I'm going to initially say number of frames is equal to zero.
And they We'll have a little counter for the first 30 to 60 frames.
We're going to calculate the background average before we actually put her hand into the image or into
the region of interest and then we'll create our Waialua pier.
Let's get a little bit more space.
We'll say it while true will start grabbing information so we'll see.
Read off the camera equals
and then we'll create a copy of the frame to pass around to our functions.
So I'll say frame copy is equal to Freyne copy and then we're going to grab a region of interes off
the original frame.
So that is going to be dictated by whatever numbers if you scroll the way back up top you have here
this is essentially just defining that red rectangle from the first video.
And you can play around those valleys depending on how your camera set up.
So I say our A-Y top two are A-Y bottom
and then we're going to say Khama are ally writes all the way to our ally left and then we're going
to get a greyscale version of this image.
So I'll say CB2 CVT color and then pass in the region of interest and then say go from color underscore
B.G. are to and it's BGR because we're reading directly from open C.B and then we're going to apply
a little bit of blur to the grayscale image.
Just help us average things out better.
So say Gaussian blue or gray.
Is a 7 by 7 kernel and then passen zero as that parameter.
And then for the number of frames we can go ahead and say for the first 60 frames we're going to calculate
that accumulated average off the greyscale image.
Now we're going to pass in our first accumulated weight.
Remember we first default to 0.5 and then if the number of frames is less than or equal to 59 we're
going to put some text on the actual screen to say hey wait recalculated the background.
So say see we to put text here will pass and the whole frame copy and then we'll just say wait's getting
background.
And you can pass and whatever warning message you want you can choose a location of where to start.
Again you may choose different values depending on what you're actually the speed camera looks like
and where you want the font to show up.
You can choose that you want where it's going to go if Hershey simple x.
And then again you can choose a color thickness you want.
So I'm just going to pass on some default values here for red coloring and then some thickness values
will say comma to OK and let me zoom out just a little bit make sure my princes are balanced.
Yep.
So essentially saying wait getting background for the first 60 frames and after that we're going to
say else.
So is this else lines up with this number of frames so we essentially have this thing kind of the first
60 frames accumulate the average we should be updating the accumulated weight.
And then if the number of friends is less than 59 put this text on the screen.
Otherwise if we're past the first 60 frames now we're ready for someone to enter their hand into the
RVY Square.
So it is a hand is equal to and whoops we forgot to actually show the image.
So after we put the text we should be showing this.
So say show and we'll just call this finger count and we'll be showing the frame copy that we're actually
writing text on.
OK.
Now that's that is done we'll say hand is segments pasand the greyscale image so that will grayscale
and then pass into the segment function which actually segment's the hand region.
First we want to check if the handle is actually calculated.
So we'll see if hand is not none there we're going to proceed to do some more function calls here.
So if we're actually texting a hand as an external contour then we're going to unpack this.
So say thresholding hand segments is equal to hand.
So recall that from the segment function if we come back up here the segment function either returns
None or returns thresholds and hand segment.
The reason I use the tuple and packing later on is because I can't really use tuple and packing of this
none.
Which is why when I first call it over here I'm saying hand is equal to segment gray.
So it may be none at first but if it's not none that I know I can unpack it into the threshold that
hand segment parts.
So here I am doing a little bit tuple and packing folded hand segments and then we're going to do here
say CB2 dot or we're going to say draw contours person my frame copy and then pasand the hand segments
and then we're also going to add along to this are right and our Y top
and then say negative 1.
You can choose whatever color you want but basically this is going to be highlighting your hand in the
real image.
So we'll focus on that and just a little bit that can give us a thickness of five.
So it's actually just to clarify draws contours around real hands and the lifestream.
So we're essentially going have two in those one of the threshold at hand and then other with your actual
region of interest in the hand that you see.
So we're drawing contours around that.
Then it's time to actually count the fingers so say fingers is equal to count fingers and we pass the
threshold that image and the hand segment that was calculated from the hand for the segment function
and then we're going to display the count.
So say CB2 put text and we're just going to pass that into the frame copy finger's going to be an integer.
So in order to actually split as text me a precedent as a string.
So it's the number of fingers there.
And this should be updating again.
You can basically put it wherever you want.
So it's going to put it at 70 50 and then say CB2 font again.
Really whatever you want as far as the font.
Well this is the same values as before for color as well.
And then font size let's just go ahead and say to here make it a little smaller.
And then let's also show a threshold at Image.
So we're going to create a new window called threshold in and we'll pass and the threshold that image
there.
So we'll see one window which is essentially showing the frame copy it's trying the contours around
your hand that's putting text saying how many fingers are showing up.
But in a separate when the walls will show the threshold that image.
And this really helps if debugging basically allowing you to adjust your background adjust values such
as if you come back up here.
This threshold minimum value that means that you may need to adjust that depending on what you view
in this threshold that image.
So we going to win windows there and then what.
Once that is done over here towards the outside check the indentation carefully we're actually going
to draw a rectangle of our region of interest or say frame copy.
And then I left Aro I top the top left corner and then let's grab the bottom right and say are I right.
And Arwa bottom Pessin whatever color you want we'll just make it red and then Besler thickness you
want let's call it five and then add 1 to the number of frames because remember we're still saying number
phrase equal to zero.
So we have to do some sort of calculation for them or frames.
So we'll do it here.
So after the first 60 frames will no longer be running this little weight getting background message.
And then after that we'll say to him Show will say finger counts
on the frame copy.
And we have just a couple of things left actually escaping out of this will say CB2 waky one and then
ampersand 0 x f f and they'll say if K is equal to 27.
Go ahead and break.
And then outside of all this after we break we'll release the camera stream and then also close all
the windows OK.
Let's save that.
Make sure you run all the cells to define all these functions.
And let's check out make sure it's working.
And it looks like it's opening here.
So you should see something like Wait getting background.
So here it is.
And it looks like I have a small typo.
I said thresholding it's a threshold.
Let me go ahead and fix that.
So it looks like that's happening right after I call Hans segment's underneath hand segment.
Max let's come back up here
and then we're going to say thresh hold it.
So go ahead and restart your kernel we'll say restart colonel
and then run all the cells again.
And once the waiting for background has gone away you should be ready to then enter your hand into the
region of interest and then after a little bit you should see the threshold that image come up.
In my particular example I was having some trouble with my window and the light changing.
So it was picking up some other items there.
Those go ahead and zoom in and see if overall the general concept is working over here in the top left
is my actual finger count and I was having a little bit of trouble at the light in the room as well
as the radius for the circle I chose.
I chose kind of a larger rate is so I had to really extend certain fingers to be able to get them to
count.
You may want to adjust that depending on the size of your hand so you can see I'm holding three fingers
up and then for a stretch that pinky out otherwise it detects as three so bringing in the pinky a little
closer has three versus four again.
But the very basics should be working.
If you extend just one finger out versus two versus three or four and then you can always just escape
on your keyboard.
Once you're done and ready to continue on with some other code.
All right that's it for the cup project.
Hope you enjoyed it and I hope you can see how you can expand these.
Just general simple ideas.
Once they're combined can create real software they can find real applications for things and I hope
you enjoyed the course.