Welcome back everyone.
To finish off this section on video basics open C.v.
We're going to have a quick assessment project and this lecture will have an overview of the actual
Assessment Project and show you what the finished results should look like.
Feel free to also treat this as a code along by jumping over to solutions lecture and coding along with
us.
Let's get started.
All right so this is what your project task is.
You really just have one task and that is to create a program that reads and a live stream from a camera
on your computer or if you don't have a USP camera go ahead just open up a video file and then wherever
you click left mouse button down create a blue circle around where you've clicked.
So I'm going to show you an example of what the finished product should look like.
But I've also written a guide here to help you out.
Or if you want to make the challenge harder just go straight off this description.
Open up a new notebook and don't use our guide but there is a middle ground here for a couple of hints
as far as the different steps you should take.
And then if you scroll down you'll notice there's lots of code here that's basically commenting what
the next steps are to do.
So this is a really similar project to what we did over when we were drawing our red rectangle in the
previous video.
Now it's up to you to do something very similar except you're going to be drawing basically blue circles
on that video stream.
Let me show you what this actually looks like as a completed project.
OK here I am.
I'm running right now the live video stream.
And once you complete this project you should be able to then click on anywhere in the video stream
and see a blue circle that's empty pop up OK.
So that's it for the project in the next lecture.
We're going to be going over solutions.
I'll see you there.