Welcome back in this series of lectures we're going to talk about blurring and smoothing images a common
operation for image processing is blurring or smoothing an image and smoothing an image can help get
rid of noise or help a computer vision application focus on general details.
Keep in mind there are many methods of blurring and smoothing and we're getting over quite a few of
them.
Now often blurring and smoothing is combined with edge detection edge detection algorithms detect too
many edges when Schoeni high resolution image without any blurring.
And since we're going to be learning about edge detection later on in a feature section of the course
we might as well understand blurring and smoothing at this point.
So just to show you a quick example of why blurring or smoothing an image is useful.
Let's imagine that we have an original image of a dogs all the way on the left.
We have a dog's face and if we try to detect the edges in that particular image without any blurring
we would get the middle figure.
And you can see here that it's too noisy of an image has too much detail.
So we're detecting far too many noises.
And if we want to detect just general edges and shapes what we can do is we can blur the image first
and try to smooth it out and then apply a edge detection algorithm on it and we'll see what we have
although in the right where we can clearly start to see the edges of the distinct dog's face.
So we're to be exploring quite a few methods.
One method we'll be exploring is called gamma correction and give a correction is actually not so much
a smoothing or blurring but instead it can be applied to an image to make it appear brighter or darker
depending on the gamma value chosen.
So over there on the right hand side I have an image and right in the middle we have Gamma's equal to
one or the original image and that's the second from the top.
And then we can apply a gamma correction to make the image appear brighter or darker.
And if you've ever kind of messed around with any sort of photo apps software where you can make an
image brighter or make an image darker that is gamma correction in action.
So we're going to actually show you how you can do gamma correction open C-v.
Then after that we're going to be exploring kernel based filters.
Kernel's can be applied over an image to produce a variety of effects and the best way to explain really
how the kernel works is through an interactive visualization.
I'm actually going to go and open my browser to start with the I know slash slash image dash kernel's
and that's going to help us understand what we actually mean or talking about kernel based filters because
a lot of smoothing and blurring operations actually the pen on what's known as a kernel operation.
Let's go ahead and go to this link and then explain further.
OK here we are at the link on image kernel's and this link is a really nice visualization of how kernel's
actually work in an image kernel is essentially just a small matrix use to apply effects and those effects
can be anything really depending on the kernel and the ones we're going to look at in this particular
series of lectures are the smoothing and blurring effects we can see here that we have an image of a
person's face.
And here we have all the way on the right the tiny little original image and then we kind of blew it
up so we can see each of the pixels and the particular values.
So notice all the value should be somewhere between 0 and 255 because it is a gray scale image.
So right now we're just inspecting a black and white image.
And if you're at this link you can begin to kind of hover over and see how each particular value as
you kind of hover over it you get to see the value on the left hand side of the actual lightness or
darkness.
And then it highlights the corresponding image or pixel in the image on the right hand side.
Now what we're going to do is a plie a kernel and there's different kernels that you can apply and a
kernel is essentially just a matrix and you can see here that there's different types of kernels so
we can actually choose the blur kernel.
In this case the kernel is going to allow us to blur the image above.
So the way this works is we take a three by three block of pixels on the image on the left hand side
and we're going to multiply each pixel by the corresponding entry of the kernel and then take the sum
that some then becomes the new pixel on the image on the right.
So let's actually go through this process we're going to start over here towards the actual top left
of the image.
So notice here how right now on the original input image I'm scanning a kernel and this kernel is a
3 by 3 kernel where the values are if we scroll back up these particular values right here.
And this is known as a blur kernel because after lots of studies they've seen that this can actually
blur an image effectively and there is as I mentioned many different types kernel's ones that sharpen
one that do outlines etc. but since we're focused on blurring it's moving we're just gonna look at this
blur kernel first.
So we have this kernel and what we're doing is we take as we scan the image we take those nine values
of the three by three grid of pixels in the original image and they're going to multiply by each corresponding
value in the kernel.
So here you can see that if I'm looking at that corner then that's two or six times that point 0 6 to
five.
But the kernel plus the other multiplication of two or five times point 1 to 5 and so on.
So you end up adding all those images and then you end up getting an output.
So one seventy eight and that becomes the new corner image of the output.
So notice here when we apply the blur we can actually see even though we're quite zoomed in on this
image it does appear to have blurred the image.
Now something to note is that as you are scanning a three by three if you start looking towards the
edge of an image you're actually not going to have enough pixels so something you can do is just end
up having the output image with a border.
And there's different ways of dealing with actual borders of images.
When it comes to kernels and we're gonna discuss that in more detail specifically when we talk about
convolutional neural networks that heavily depend on the sort of kernel function in order to apply changes
to an image and learn larger and larger features.
But right now the main idea I want you to understand is we can take an image of values just like we
have here.
We have all these images.
This happens to be scale and then we can apply a kernel to it and all the kernel does is it takes the
shape of the pixels of the kernel.
So right here we have a three by three kernel.
So we take three by three pixels and then we multiply it by the kernel values and then we sum them up
and that's our new output value.
So we can see as you move along what the new output values are and is a great way to visualize this.
And I encourage you to come to his Web site and then check out other ones so the Sobol ones we're actually
going to be checking these out as well.
So you can see here how it ends up detecting certain edges on the left or on the right.
OK.
So in the next lecture we're actually going explore these further with open C.v.
I'll see you there.