Welcome back in this lecture and continue our discussion of directly drawing an image for a mouse by
adding in functionality with event choices we're going to be using the same code that we worked with
last time.
So let's continue where we left off.
OK.
Here we are at the previous script that we use.
Remember all we're doing here is recreating a function that takes in these parameters and events the
x and y coordinates of that event with the mouse flags and then parameters and then we're checking if
a particular event occurred.
And if it did then go ahead and do something to that image such as drawing on the image.
Then we also have a named window and the mouse called back connected based off the window name to the
image being shown.
Now what we can do is actually check for multiple events.
So right now we're only checking if the left button was clicked down.
What I'm going to do is add another event will say LCF or Elif event is equal equal to CB2.
And then we can type event and if hit tab here you can see the various events that are available to
such as moving the mouse by pressing a particular key.
In this case let's go ahead and go with events right button down.
So we'll go ahead and do something else.
If the right mouse button click down and let's just go ahead and add another circle but this time it
will be a different color.
We'll have it be a red circle.
What does this actually mean.
It means that I'm going to be displaying the same image.
However on checking for multiple events if event passed back during the actual mouse callback happens
to be a left button down then I'm going to draw a circle of particular color green and if happens to
be a right button down that is going to draw a red circle.
Let's run this.
Here's my drawing and I'm going to do two left clicks.
So there are my green circles and let me click on my right mouse button and there are my blue circles.
So I think I actually said red when it should have been blue because remember we have blue green red
with open C-v not red green blue.
So the blue and red channels are switch there.
So I apologize for misspeaking but you can see now how you can now add in different colors based off
different mouse events so just alternating left and right click here.
OK.
Coming up next we're going to continue by showing you what you can do in order to have behavior that
affects as your mouse is being dragged.
So right now you can click once but if I dropped my mouse nothing happens.
Coming up next we're going to show you how you can organize event calls along with some global variable
calls in order to actually account for a mouse being dragged along.
We'll see you there.