Welcome back everyone to this lecture on tracking API with open C-v.
Now there are many object tracking methods that we haven't covered already and to cover each and every
one of them with a manual implementation would basically require an entirely new course.
Now fortunately many of these object tracking methods have been designed as simple API calls with open
C.V that is going to allow them to easily swap and replace tracking methods depending on your actual
video and the object you're trying to track.
We're going to explore a few of these easy to use object tracking API.
And then the next lecture we're going to to explore them open see V we set up a nice note book that
actually lives and interact have a little input choose a tracking parameter for your API and then go
ahead and test out some video.
But I want to do just a very brief overview of the tracking API as we're going to implement in the next
video.
So we're going to start off with showing you the boosting Tracker and the trackers based off the added
boost algorithm that's where it gets a name from.
And that's actually the essentially the same underlying algorithm that the hard cascade based face detector
that we played around with used and the evaluation occurs across multiple frames.
Now free to the truck API.
I want to go over a few pros and cons.
The pros for the boosting tracker is that it's a very well-known and very well studied algorithm.
However the cons is it does actually know when the tracking has failed.
So it could keep tracking your face and then maybe your face actually leaves the video.
The boosting tracker is going to think that it's still detecting something and it's still tracking something.
And also keep in mind that there's now very improved there are much better techniques available.
So typically you won't use boosting as your first choice is a very well known and steady algorithm you
can read a lot of literature on it but there's many improvements that we can make on that boosting tracker.
But it is available as an API.
So an improvement off the boosting tracker is known as multiple instance learning tracker m i l tracker.
It's actually very similar to boosting but it considers a neighborhood of points around the current
location to create multiple instances which is where it gets its name from.
And you can check out the project page for more details and you can check out the resource links for
this particular search for information about each of these trackers that we're going to go over in case
you want to dive into the mathematics or the original publications of each of these trackers now as
far as pros and cons of the M-file tracker.
The prose is actually has very good performance and doesn't drift as much as boosting.
So I would recommend using m i l tracker instead of boosting tracker.
Now some of the cons is that it has a failure to track an object that actually may not be reported back.
So again that means if you're tracking a face in a video and the face happens to leave the email tracker
might still think it's tracking something and it also can't really recover from full obstruction.
So if something happens to cover your face while you're tracking it.
The e-mail tracker may not be able to recover and then it's going to think it's tracking something else
or detect a failure to it or say it's having a failure to detect the tracking.
They'll move on to the Casey tracker which stands for Colonel ised correlation filters and this exploits
some key properties of the m i l Tracker and the fact that many data points membered the emails multiple
instances or multiple data points.
Some of those data points will actually overlap and the cakey tracker used some kind of convenience
mathematical functions of those overlapping data points to lead to more accurate and faster tracking.
You can see so far we're century just building improvements off the previous tracker.
So M-I else building building improvements off the boosting tracker and KCA is building improvements
off the email tracker so KCA if it performs better than MVL and Boosey and it's a great first choice.
In fact in general I would recommend you to start off KCMO tracker and if that performs to your needs
then you essentially have no need to explore other more exotic trackers.
Now one of the cons of the KCA tracker is it can't really recover sometimes from the full obstruction
of an object.
Again if you happen to be moving too fast or something obstructs the object from you that you're trying
to track the KCA tracker will just say failer to detect and then it may not be able to recover and detect
the face again if it comes back onto the screen.
Now we can also use the TLT tracker which stands for tracking learning and detection.
And this tracker follows the object from frame to frame and that the sector localizes all appearances
that have been observed so far and correct Strecker if necessary then the learning estimates detectors
errors and updates that to avoid these errors in the future.
So it's a pretty sophisticated tracker.
Now some of the pros is that it's actually good tracking even with obstruction in frames or if you have
fast moving objects.
So previously all the other trackers we learned about you know they're pretty good.
They're not able to really deal this problem of something moving very quickly or some sort of obstruction
of the object or tracking.
So again TLG performs well with obstruction and even large changes in scale.
So if you have a car that's moving really fast and close to the camera suddenly that car may appear
larger Fieldy can actually see all of that.
Now one of the cons is that it may provide many false positives because it's implementing certain techniques
to try to attempt to be good at even obstruction or large changes in scale.
It may sometimes accidentally track something that is no longer your original object which is a false
positive track and something that you're not really supposed to be tracking.
So it's essentially the cost you pay for being good at tracking of obstruction or large changes in scale
is that you'll get these false positives.
I think he is tracking the correct thing when it's actually not.
So keep that in mind.
There is a cost to pay for that.
And then finally we'll talk about the median flow tracker.
And internally this tracker tracks the object in both forward and backward directions in time and measures
the discrepancies between those two trajectories.
Now the pros is that it's very good of reporting failed tracking.
So if it doesn't see the object it's pretty good at saying immediately hey the object is no longer in
frame.
I can no longer track it and it works really well.
Predictable motion.
So if you have something moving on some sort of racetrack or something that you know more or less it's
going to be doing the same movement over and over again.
They just want to keep tracking it.
This is really common in some scientific case studies that the medium flow is a good choice.
The cons is that fails under a large motion.
And what I mean by large motion is a large jump from frame to frame of the object you're trying to track
which essentially just means you have a fast moving object.
OK so let's look at how to use these tracking API.
Open C and Python.
And again I recommend you check out the resource links for more detailed information on each of these
trackers.
We'll see you at the next lecture where we open up a notebook and play around he's tracking a piece
that he's set up for you will see it there.