Welcome back everyone to this lecture on gradient descent and back propagation.
If you've dabbled in machine learning before or if you even looked at some online articles you've probably
already heard of the term grading the sense.
Let's quickly go over a high level overview and then discuss back propagation gradient descent is an
optimization algorithm for finding the minimum of a function which is useful to us because we want to
minimize that cost function.
Sort of find a local minimum we take steps proportional to the negative of the gradient.
Let's go ahead and go through a very simple example in just one dimension.
So basically what we have here is our cost on the y axis so the result of that cost function and then
on the x axis we have a particular way that we're trying to choose.
So remember we end up choosing a random white in the beginning.
So let's say that Bluepoint initiate that ran the weight that we chose and we want to somehow choose
a weight that's going to minimize that cost and we can see here just visually when they mention that's
basically at the bottom of that parabola so the weight gradient descent works in just a high level overview
is that you end up taking the gradient which we know is a derivative of the function at that point and
then seeing which way it goes in the negative direction and then we end up taking a step by step a sense
along that gradient until we finally see that we get that minimum and more cost.
So we see here just visually what the parameter value to choose to minimize our cost is.
So finally this minimum is really simple for one dimension but our cases are going to have a lot more
parameters.
So we're not going to do that visually or with such a simple diagram.
Meaning we're going to need to use built in linear algebra libraries that are deep learning library
will provide using greened the sense we can figure out the best parameters for minimizing our cost.
So for example find the best values for the weights of the near on inputs and we're going to go a lot
more into the mathematics hungry and the sense when we actually go through the math example.
So now we just have one issue to solve and that is how can we quickly just the optimal parameters or
weights across our entire network in that one example we just showed for a single weight.
But what if we want to actually go and then fix all the weights or adjust all the weights for the entire
network.
And that's we're back propagation comes in basically back propagation is used to calculate the air contribution
of each year on after a batch of data is processed and it relies heavily on the chain rule from calculus
to go back through the network and calculate these errors and the way back propagation works it calculates
the air at the output and then distributes back through the network layers and it requires a known desired
output for each input value.
Remember that supervised learning needs some sort of comparison to actually get that error.
All right so we now know enough terminology in theory to begin working.
Of course we're going to be using a data set of features of counterfit versus real bills.
Keep in mind we're still working on just numerical features.
We're not actually reading an image stated that rectally.
Later on we're going to learn about convolutional neural networks which is going which is going to allow
us to actually handle image data that rectally the actual jpeg or PFG files.
Ok so that's it for theory.
Coming up next will work of course in Python.