Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss gradients.
Gradients is an extension of the morphological operators that we talked about in the previous lectures.
Understanding gradients will eventually lead us to understanding edge detection which allows us to perform
operations such as object detection object tracking and eventually even image classification.
Let's get started an image gradient.
Formally speaking is just a directional change in the intensity or color of an image.
So here we can see two examples on the left hand side we have the outsides as white and then the actual
intensity or color is changing as you go further black towards the middle.
Same situation or similar situation in the picture on the right you have on the right hand side there
it's pure white and then eventually the gradient is a directional change to black as it goes towards
left.
So there are algorithms that can actually then track this sort of direction.
And in this lecture are mainly going to be exploring the basic social Feldmann operators often just
called Sobol for short.
Later on in the course we're going to expand on this operator for general edge detection.
Keep in mind that gradients can actually be calculated in a specific direction.
Here we see a picture of the cat within X the frictional gradient calculated and another y their actual
greeting calculated.
So let's go ahead and show a basic example of this.
Here there's an image of a bike.
I'm going to show you the results of some gradients.
Keep in mind what this image is actually showing specifically the bricks here you can see the bricks
both have horizontal lines and vertical lines.
And then we see the bike as well as what it's Lockett's to.
So if you calculate a normalized X gradient from the Sobol operator notice that you end up only seeing
things in the mainly vertical direction.
Essentially shows you the vertical edges so you can no longer really clearly see those horizontal lines
in the brick because we're putting this on a normalized X gradient.
And if you apply normalized y agreed and then you actually see the horizontal edges.
So there we can see clearly the horizontal edges of the bricks and you can see there that the actual
tube that the bike is locked to tends to fade away because most of that is actually vertical and eventually
we're going to be able to do things like a normal gradient magnitude which shows us both sides of the
story.
Here we can see both the vertical and horizontal edges and this is eventually going to lead up to when
we discuss general edge detection.
OK so as far as the actual mathematics behind this you can think of this as just a general operator
that Sobol OPERATOR What it does is it uses two three by three colonels.
And we're already familiar of colonels and how those operate which are involved with the original image
to Cockley approximations of the derivatives.
One for the horizontal changes and then one for the vertical changes.
Essentially as we discussed gradients are a change in color or intensity.
So change has to do with derivatives.
If you're calculating the rate of change and these kernels are then able to calculate approximations
of those changes.
So we have one in the horizontal and one for the vertical OK.
So in general we're going to try to step away from that matics there if you are really interested in
mathematics behind these operators You can check out the Wikipedia article on the Sobol operator.
It actually has a really nice for math breakdown of those details.
But you can generally understand that you're applying some sort of kernel and we know how kernels are
applied but now we're just doing one for horizontal changes and then one for vertical changes and we
should then be able to calculate gradients and later on edges.
So for our use case right now we're just going to focus on understanding the syntax of using Sobol with
open sibi.
OK so let's explore various great operators and then later on we're also going to combine these concepts
with a few other image processing techniques that we've already learned.
Let's get over to the notebook.
OK here I am at the notebook.
I've kind of had an already copied and pasted a couple of lines of code from the gradients notebook.
The first four lines were just classic imports that were already familiar with.
And then this line or this function I should say is the display image function that we've already been
using and are familiar with.
The only thing to note here is that it's automatically displaying the color mapping as gray.
So go ahead and feel free to copy and paste those from the notebook.
We're already familiar with the contents of these cells.
The image we're going to be working with is a Sudoku puzzle.
We're going to say image is equal to SIFI to read.
And then inside of wherever your data folder is that goes with this course.
Go ahead and open Sudoku JPA.
And as a second parameter passing zero.
So it's red in grayscale OK.
Let's go ahead and display this image so we can see what it looks like.
We'll say display I am g.
And there we have it.
So this is just a Sudoku puzzle.
Notice it's on a background some sort of table cloth with flowers.
And we have some clear lines.
They are here.
We have some thick lines for the actual grid system and then we have both horizontal and vertical lines.
So that's why I chose this image because clearly there's some sort of grid pattern here and we'll be
interested to see what the x ray versus the white gradient is OK.
So let's actually show you how you can perform these mobile operators using open sibi.
The first thing to do is calculate an X gradient Sobol Sewell's say Sobol X and then say equals 2 and
he would say CB2 what's Sobol a lowercase o CB2 Sobol and then we're going to pass in the image we want
to analyze and then we in a desired depth.
So if you actually do shift tab here remember previously we had past a negative one to have the input
desired that be the output desired that.
But in this case we actually want to pass in our own desired depth parameter and you can check out the
link in the resource lecture.
It again goes back to a stack overflow post which is a really nice explanation of what that is.
But that is essentially just the precision of each pixel.
You can think of it as just like 8 person 24 32 versus 64 bit.
So we'll go with the highest precision possible and say CB2 and the syntax for this is C-v underscore
64 f essentially 64 floating point precision.
And the next two parameters if you shift tab here is the derivative in the direction and the rivet in
the Y the action.
So we have the X and d y.
So what we will do here is say Dayaks is one since we're calculating the X gradient and say why is zero
and then a K size is equal to.
And this is a side you can mess around with.
It should be an odd number but you can begin playing the kernel size and see how that affects your output.
But we'll go ahead and run that and let's display the result we'll say display image and then pass in
our Sobol X gradient.
And here we can see remoras the X gradient.
So we get the vertical lines and the vertical lines are very clear.
We have the vertical lines and we can't really see the horizontal lines in the grid system.
Let's not try the white gradient of the Sobol operator.
I'm going to copy and paste the same piece of code but essentially switch out that the X and the D-y.
So instead of saying we want to zero we're going to say zero.
Come on and else rename this to be the white gradient to the Sobol So I run this.
I say the split image and now if I see Sobol why I should now clearly see horizontal lines.
Keep in mind that doesn't mean it's going to completely erase any vertical lines because in fact these
grid lines here were actually quite thick compared to the grid lines in the middle.
But we can definitely see that there's a clearer picture of the horizontal lines.
When we come to the white gradient Now there's one more gradient type.
I want to show you.
And that's using Laplace and derivatives and what that method does is it just calculates the Laplante
of the image given by the relationship.
And let me actually open up the Wikipedia page on the general applause.
Operator So if you google search Laplace operator this is kind of one of those fundamental operators
in calculus.
Eventually if you scroll down here you'll see that to them mentions which is what we're dealing with.
Just a greyscale image.
You have the Laplace operator shown as the second derivative in regards to X plus the second derivative
in regards to Y.
So we're to be calculating these with Sobol operators because we already can perform a Sobol operator
in the extreme.
And the Wikipedia which are approximations of these sort of derivatives and we can use a kernel to do
so.
Again you can look up the full details on using Laplante and derivatives.
It's actually really well detailed in the open C-v documentation.
But for our case we just want to show you the results of that.
So we'll come back to Jupiter live here and using the A-plus in gradient calculation is really simple.
All we do here is say some sort of variables will say Laplace in applause line is equal to CV 2.
And then we call applause.
And here you don't need to specify the X or Y because it's going to do both.
As we saw in the formula we'll just say image and then the desired depth which we want the full details
so I'll say CB2 CV underscore 64 F..
And let's check out the results of that one we'll say the splay image and then passen the policy in
and here you can see in this case it attempts to do edge detection more or less a really great detection
on both x and y.
So it's gotten rid of some of the noise here but we can clearly see these gradients on the edges here
from when we went from white to the black edge to white again and the numbers are very clearly shown
here as well.
OK.
So maybe eventually you want to use some sort of application to look at a picture of a Sudoku puzzle
and automatically fill it in with some numbers.
What we may want to do is combine this with previous ideas.
So previous ideas that we discussed are things like blending images so maybe the applause wasn't exactly
the result you wanted and you wanted to blend the results of the Sobol in the white gradient and the
Sobol in the extreme in what we actually already know how to do that.
Well just come over here and use the Add weighted function so we could do something like one that is
equal to C-v to add weighted and then say source 1 is equal to Sobol X and then what's nice about this
approach is we can choose the Alpha and Beta values.
So if we like the results of Sobol Y and maybe horizontal lines are a little more important for our
particular application or vertical lines or a little more important we can then selectively choose how
strong each X or Y gradient will be shown.
So that's what's nice about doing this add a weighted approach will say Sobol y and in my case of just
having both kind of equally represented here.
And let's go ahead and leave gamma zero lips make sure I have that right source to source to run that
and it's going to display that image that's blended.
So say display image blended and going to run that and now I can see the blended result of the X green
and white green and so will.
So it's nice here is that I can clearly see some edges and maybe beyond this you also wanted to perform
things like thresholding or morphological operators so he could do as well.
Are things like maybe provide a threshold on this image so we can say ARYEETEY.
Th one is equal to CB2.
And then we can call threshold passen an image.
That's actually the original image right there.
Maybe you pass on some sort of threshold like hundred fifty five is the max value and then choose a
binary threshold so will say binary and we can display the result of that as well.
The split image th one and you can see this one also ends up trying to edges but then it doesn't actually
see the grid lines on the inside.
So you can then begin to combine ideas like trying to detect the threshold of maybe this splendid image
and see how that works.
Or maybe use some morphological operators.
So in other morphological operator we learned about was the morphological gradient operator.
So let's quickly do that.
And in fact we'll try doing it on the blended one and see how that works.
So let's quickly make a kernel we'll say this kernel is equal to the ones and that shape will be a four
by four.
And let's have a B in integers also.
You I antedate.
So we don't get any bugs there.
And then we'll say the gradient is equal to C-v to morphology X well Placide.
Well pasand that blended one and then say C-v two more.
And then let's do another gradient calculation even though technically the Greens have already been
calculated.
But if you run that this way you'll should see kind of a clear black and white result and this will
eventually lead us to things like edge detection.
So if I display this image of the gradient calculation on that blend that image we end up seeing something
that looks like this.
So the numbers are blurry but now I can clearly see the whites and maybe you want to do a binary threshold
on this.
Maybe you want to get rid of some noise cetera so you can definitely combine a lot of the ideas that
we've already discussed along with calculating gradients and eventually we're going to see is a lot
of these ideas are combine when we end up calling just general edge detection functions.
OK.
So these are the very basics of gradients.
This kind of air base building block so we can eventually understand edge detection.
Coming up next we're going to discuss color histograms.
And then after that you'll have an assessment for the section we'll see at the next lecture.