Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
The first step of the training.
So we made that loop to loop over all the different steps which are going to be 1000 total which corresponds
to the number of update we're going to apply to our policy or in other words the number of steps of
gradient descent.
And here we go with the first step inside this for loop which is to initialize the perturbations deltas
and the positive and negative rewards.
So indeed we are going to apply a lot of perturbations and I remind that these perturbations will be
sampled following a normal distribution and we already made a method here in the policy class that simple
these perturbations deltas.
So of course we're going to use this function to sample the perturbations.
This will remind return a list of 16 directions because here we did a full loop on the HP Data and be
directions which is 16 and therefore we're going to get some perturbation deltas for each of the 16
directions that will initialize the perturbations and then we'll initialize the reward.
So we've made two separate variables.
We were positive and we were negative.
We were positive.
Be initialized to zeros but will contain Liron all the reward obtained by applying the perturbations
in the positive directions and reward negative.
Same will be initialized to zeros but later on will contain all the reward which will be attained by
applying the perturbations in the opposite direction as the previous positive directions.
All right so let's initialize of this.
It's going to be all clear once we start typing everything.
So first we want to initialize the Delta.
And as we just said we're going to get those deltas by applying the simple delta method from our policy
object which is an instance of the policy class.
All right so policia object from this policy object we use the simple deltas the simple deltas method
which I remind we can see here doesn't take any argument.
So all good that initializers are perturbations dealt us and we get 16 matrices of perturbations for
each of the 16 different directions that we're testing.
Great.
Now let's initialize the puzzle if we want.
So I remind these are going to be the rewards that will get by playing the perturbations in the positive
directions.
And so we're going to call these rewards positive underscore we want and we want to initialize them
as a list of 16 elements because indeed we'll get these rewards for each of the 16 directions and how
can we initialize a list of 16 elements.
Well that's very simple.
Well first we want to initialize them as only zeroes because we'll update these words later.
And so to initialize a list of 16 zeroes.
The trick is to put a zero here in square brackets and then multiply this by the number of elements
you want to have in your list which is of course H-P that and B directions and you can notice I didn't
forget the HP hyper parameter object because this and the directions here is a variable of this object.
And we will create the HP object later on.
All right so prefix that initializes the reward will get by playing the perturbations in the 16 positive
directions order and B directions positive directions.
Now we need to initialize the same but for the words we'll get by applying the perturbations in the
opposite directions.
And I'm going to call this new list negative rewards but be careful.
Please do not confuse it with some negative words like some rewards below zero.
It's just that negative is the opposite it's positive to highlight the fact that these words are the
words will get by applying the opposite perturbation as this one.
So it's just to highlight the position here between positive and negative but it has nothing to do with
some negative values below zero.
OK.
Please keep that in mind.
And therefore now to initialize.
Well those negative rewards or those rewards we get by playing the perturbations in the opposite direction.
Well that's the same you know we want to get 16 couples of words into positive directions and we words
in the opposite negative directions and therefore we will also initialize this list as a list of 16
zeros.
Each of the 16 elements corresponding to the 16 directions and therefore what we all need to do here
is just to copy this and paste that just below.
All right.
And here we go that initializers are perturbations deltas are we words in the positive directions.
And are we words in the opposite directions.
Good step done.
Now we can move on to the next step which will be to update our positive rewards.
So far they're equal to zero.
And now we're going to explore the policy on one full episode which I remind is from the beginning until
either the AI falls or until it plays one thousand actions.
And so what we're going to do is that for each of the 16 directions we're going to explore that on one
full episode using our explore function and we'll get the positive rewards for each of these 16 different
directions.
So let's do this in the next story.
And until then enjoy.