Hello and welcome back to the course on augmented random search in today's tutorial we're going to talk
about maximizing rewards.
So what is this all about.
Well to start off with let's look at our perception and how it interacts with thing varment.
So for simplicity's sake we're going to take a perception with three inputs and outputs as we discussed
previously.
The outputs are simply the weighted sums of the inputs.
And so basically it's a matrix multiplication of the inputs times the matrix or the vector of inputs
times a matrix of weights of this perception in order to get outputs.
So let's have a look at an example.
And so here we got Mujer code environment with a humanoid that's learning how to walk.
Let's have a look.
This is going to be quite funny.
There is that's one of the most efficient ways of walking apparently according to this AI.
And so as you can see what happens is the model moves most moves or at some point it falls falls over
and that's where this episode would end.
There are certain times when the episode can end.
So this whole this whole period from Start from where the model starts to when it finishes it's called
an episode.
They're the moral perform certain actions during episode and the episode can end when the model falls
over and there's no recovery from that.
The episode can and for instance when a tie in time runs out or when the model reaches a certain goal
it depends on the environment.
For instance in this case we were had Michiko and this episode is ending when the is falling or so because
you can see the model falls over here and from there what happens next.
Well in order for the AI to learn how to walk certain feedback has to be provided to the AI by the environment
because if there's no feedback remember the AI is just a black box.
It's getting inputs right and it's getting like from how the environment is what a situation in the
right environment is right now what forces are in play and it provides outputs.
But apart from that it needs some kind of mechanism for it.
In order for it to be able to develop learn.
And so what happens is the environment provides a reward reward to that artificial intelligence based
on how well it performs.
So the longer it stayed upright the further it went.
The higher reward the reward will be the sooner it fell the
less.
Far more like the closer it is to the start of the episode when actually fell the lesser the reward
will be.
And so this reward is then used by the AI to adjust the weights.
That's how the process works.
Now how exactly or just the way we'll talk about that in the next tutorial.
But for for now what is important for us to understand is that this is the feedback loop.
This is the feedback mechanism that works in order to help the AI in this case the Erris to learn and
it learns by adjusting the ways because ultimately there's nothing else that it can do is nothing else
specific to this AI.
These inputs are provided by the environment.
These outputs go to the environment and only thing the only component of the AI that the AI itself is
in control of are these weights because adjusting the weights it will change the output so you can you
can increase or decrease the weights and then output will be different and same similar here.
And again we'll talk about this in the coming Tauriel.
But what I wanted to highlight here is the understanding of how can we better get an intuition for this
from the real world.
And my favorite example is if you take a child if you take a baby that's learning to walk then how is
it getting feedback how is it getting reward from the environment.
Well for instance if it gets up and then it tries to put it's like left foot for the right foot forward
then left foot forward again.
And then for instance it tries to put his left or right forward over its shoulder.
It's going to fall over.
And what it's going to get after falling over is pain is going to get a bruise.
But that's more for like the parents to see that you know the baby fell over.
But in terms of the baby itself it's going to get pain and that is the central nervous system signaling
to the brain that that was a bad decision.
Don't do that again.
That that is not what we want because the central nervous system through evolution through DNA is is
coded to know exactly what are in what is good for our survival what's on.
So for instance walking is good.
Falling over isn't and that's why when you fall over you get a signal a central nervous system of pain
in order to train you or the baby to not do that again.
And so in this case or when the baby does get legs start walking you know that the parents are clapping.
It gets to its target destination for instance it was chasing the catechize the cat or gets to the couch
or something like that.
And the central nervous system rewards the baby by saying hey you did a good job.
You know like you know you're happy.
And so basically from there the baby learns how to walk.
Of course it's much more complex for humans.
So it's just a set of weights a matrix of weights that we're updating in our brains.
But the concept stays the same.
That's why through these rewards the AI learns.
OK so the higher if I do certain things then I get very rewards and therefore I'm I'm adjusting or it's
in the right direction.
But that's running a little bit ahead.
We'll talk about that in the next tutorial.
And I look forward to seeing you there.
Hope you enjoy it today.
And until next time enjoy AI.