[Autogenerated] Hi, My name's Mike Brown.
Welcome to my cause.
Designing hybrid networks and Progress.
I am a senior cloud instructor working a five month training in the UK
specializing in Amazon Web service is AWS is one.
The biggest providers of cloud service is today.
Most a dress projects involved work of existing organizations.
A large group of those organizations will wish to extend
their networks into the age west cloud.
In this cause.
We're gonna take a detailed look at Age of West hybrid networking.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include site side
VPN 80 West Direct Connect transit gateways billing on B G P
for Aid West Hybrid Network.
By the end of this cause, you have detailed knowledge of aid US hybrid networks.
They'll make you a valuable member of any 80 West networking team.
Before I begin this cost,
you should be familiar with the basics of VPC implantation.
From here.
You to feel comfortable diving to aid US networking topics with courses on
design and implementing a dress networks security address networks on
integrating a dress networks with application service is I hope you'll
join me on this journey to learn hybrid network designs in eight of us with designing hybrid networks, and Eddie West coughs up a little sign