[Autogenerated] Hi there.
Welcome to this model in our designing hybrid networks in aid of West costs.
My name is Mike Ground are in this Montreuil.
We're gonna look at design the hybrid network architecture using software V p.
N's.
In this model, we're gonna introduce software VPN.
Well, then discuss software VPN.
High availability on wagon demonstrates from a software VPN option.
So let's start off by introducing software V.
P N's a couple of questions.
First, do use V pens on your network today.
If so,
what hardware and software to use Undead West software
VPN allowed you to retain control.
You will have control of both ends of the
connection and not just the on premises.
Remember,
with a manage BP en you can't perform any configuration on the
virtual gateway device was just being deployed.
We're a software VPN.
You have control not only of the VPN software but also the operating stone,
so you can continue to configure and reconfigure the VPN as
needed software VPN to allow you to retain skills.
Think about the question of the previous side.
If you answered yes,
those questions that it's probable your staff of already trained
in particular technology be able to retain and use those skills in
our cloud move might be a benefit.
Also, if you've answered yes the previous questions,
you may have already purchased licenses for on premises equipment they
are using right now to manage your V p N's software.
V P N's introduced.
Bring your light and scenarios and bring your own license could save you money.
There's a couple of options when going down the software v.
P en route, you could deploy an e t.
Two instance use in an air mind from the marketplace.
These might be limits based AM eyes like open VPN or it could
be an am I from a manufacturer like Cisco.
The alternative is to deploy E C.
Two instances using your customized AM eyes.
This gives you the more flexibility to use whatever VPN
configuration that meets your needs.
When using software V.
P N's,
you respond for the patching management and maintenance off the C
two instances that terminating your VP ends.
You're also responsible for the high availability of the software VPN service.
In this example,
we have head office with a deployed Rua that's running VPN software.
We don't have our V p c with two subjects deployed to digress into some,
that one we're gonna deploy software.
VPN Instance, This is a highly specialized,
easy to machine, the view of customized all you perch for the marketplace.
We make sure this instance is publicly accessible,
and then we create a VPN connection between it on our own primitive eyes.
Now, you could just leave it at that.
But here we have single point of failure.
We have a single point of failure because you've only got one rule at head
office on a single point of failure in AWS because we've got a single easy
to device managing the VP on that side here we've deployed a second
instance is subject to subject one and subject to and different
availability zones on our route run premise creates a sites like the P in
connection with each device.
Now, if the villa but his own goes down or one of our instances fails,
we saw off site site capabilities.
Of course we'd have to address the single point of failure head office as well,
by possibly adding the second rule of there
comparing software and aid Westman v.
P.
Henson if using software VPN, you're responsible for the high availability,
maintenance and scalability off the VPN.
If you use an address, manage VPN.
They all fall into a dresses responsibly with a dress.
Manage VP ends.
We use cloudwatch to monitor those re peons with software v.
P N's.
We can deploy a custom honoring solution or configure
our 82 instances on the VPN software.
Two.
Apart into Cloud Walk With Software VP ends you
control Bull Friends of VPN Connection,
offering a wider range of choices around the types of
software used and hardware used to create.
The VP ends with in a dress manage VPN.
You control the on premise End of the connection.
You might be limited in the number of devices that supported by the
ageless band VPN on premise and your definite limit just using I P
sec as a security protocol across that VPN software VPN support
bring you on license and they allow us to leverage the existing
skill set of our employees.
Finally, the might be compliance reasons why we use the software VPN Bye.
Implement a software VPN we will be approved.
Orders were full control of the entire site site v.
P M.
Process.
When making your choice as to whether to use a software VPN own a dress,
manage VPN.
The best practice advice is to use the address man free
pen first on only move away from this. If the address manage VPN doesn't meet your requirements.