[Autogenerated] Hi there.
My name is Mike Brown on Welcome to our course Designing hybrid networks.
In their progress in this model,
we're gonna take a look at design in a hybrid network arc
toucher using aid us manage free pens.
We're gonna start with model by trying to answer a question.
Why are eight us manage repentance?
We're going Discuss static and dynamic site site V P N's on Dragon.
Discuss a South called Cloud Hope on client VPN endpoints.
So let's begin by trying to answer that question.
What I did us manage free pens.
80 West manage free pens are deployed using Aid West components.
These type of VPN, zehr clusters,
hard levy pins and we can deploy them using seven different models.
If we have a requirement for V P N's,
then why not let a good West all the hard work for us?
Let a good West worry about support, maintenance availability, freeing a part.
Time to work on other parts of our network anywhere.
Spanish free pens.
Use I P sec to secure I P traffic.
Traveling between the VPN points each address manage for you.
Pen connection has two tunnels for redundancy.
Each tunnel supports up to 1.25 Think about the fruit,
but there are several factors that could affect that fruit boat.
These include the capabilities off the customer permit equipment,
the capacity of your connection between yourself and AWS network.
Leytonstone your collection and average pocket size.
When you come to deliver an age with manage VPN,
there are several models that you can follow.
In this first example, we will deploy a virtual private gateway.
Virtual private gate was deployed in attached Ravi PC.
We then use the VPC route tables to route the VP
inbound traffic towards our gateway.
We also configure a customer gateway.
The customer gateway near the west represents your arm from his equipment.
Includes the public I p address of your own primitive us on the type of ruin.
Even stack our dynamic.
We're gonna use one kept intact device.
Finally, in this model, we deploy a VPN connection.
The VPN connection links the virtual private gateway to the customer.
Gateway on creates are two total end points.
In the second model,
we still deploy a customer gateway on the customer get where it's
still used to identify the on premise device.
This model then uses a transit gateway.
The transit gateway replaces the virtual private gateway on the VPN connection.
Our VP sees form attachments.
The transit gateway on the transit gateway replaces our
virtual private gateway in the VPC route tables.
The transit gateways then used to form a VPN
attachment like the vegan connection,
the VP An attachment brings up two tunnels that on purpose device
could establish a site to site VPN connection with.
In this example, we're following Model One.
We have a V P.
C deployed to Eddie Breasts on that VPC has two subjects.
We have a headquarters office and a head office.
We've deployed a single ruler.
They will be used to establish the site site peeping connections
with the aid of us manage VPN components in here to breast We've
complied a virtual private gateway.
We will have configured a customer gateway on the VPN connection and this
will establish the to toe Len points on the Aid West Side.
So I'm from a tree were well established site site,
the pain connections with both the timeline points in this example,
we have a single point of failure,
namely the rule at head office If that route goes down,
we lose our site site connection.
So if you want a bit more redundancy, you might go with this model here.
We've still got a single virtual private gateway attached Dr V.
P.
C.
This time we've deployed two rules at head office on each of
those rulers established a connection with the two tunnels in
a dress on the a d Westside.
Off the relationship, we still use one virtual private gateway attached to a V P.
C.
But this time we would need multiple customer gateways because we now
have multiple public endpoints at head office on,
we'll need multiple VPN connections to link those customer
gateways to our virtual private gateway.
This south works well, and as you'll see in a demonstration,
he's not that difficult set up.
But what if we had multiple VP sees honey FPPC nearly site site collectivity.
Well, for this to work,
we would need multiple virtual private gateways as each virtual
private gateway has a 1 to 1 relationship with a V p.
C.
Then we need a customer gateway that represents our on from this device.
And finally we need a VPN connection for each virtual private gateway
to link it to the customer gateway with each VPN connection creating
two tunnels to route traffic between headquarters on the VPC attached
virtual private gateway.
Once we've configured the on promise device,
it would connect to eat to the timeline points.
If we imagine this across a more complicated network with lots of VP sees
each one requiring everyone virtual private gateway.
Things will quickly get difficult to manage and expensive.
This next example follows model to we still have our
multiple VP sees a mega Rua head office,
but this time we deploy a transit gateway.
The transit gateway itself is not attached to a single VPC.
Instead,
multiple VP sees concrete attachments to the transit gateway
on the transit gatewaycan create a VPN attachment just like
the VPN connections for Model one, the transit gateway VPN attachment Well,
actually create two tunnels on our headquarters device will be
configured to connect to both of those tow line points.
This model, then, is lot near and should be easier to manage its scale.
But we must think about availability and cost.
It may be that the transit gateway is simpler and easier to manage its scale,
but the benefits we get from that might not outweigh the cost of
deploying the transit gateway With transit gateways.
We pay a fee for a transit gateway.
Attach one hour, so for every hour your V P C is attached to the transit gateway.
There's a cost.
Virtual private gateways.
We pay for sight sight.
VPN connection ours.
So the longer sites like VPN connection is up, the more we pay.
There's also a cost for transferring day out through the site site VPN.
When using a virtual private gateway for transit gateways,
we start to pay the site site VPN.
Connection costs Under is a cost per gigabyte of data
processed through the transit Gateway.
A virtual private gateway could be attached to a single VPC.
Where's the transit?
Gateway supports multiple attachments to Buffy Peces.
VP ends on appearing connections toe over transit gateways.
If you're using a virtual private gateway,
there's no additional configuration that you can perform with transit Gateway.
It's a parts additional features like equal cost multipath ruin
unlawful route table so we can segment traffic.
So although transit gateway cost a bit more, it might be easy.
It's vengeance scale, and it definitely has a lot more features. The virtual private gateway