[Autogenerated] in this section where then discuss route 53 traffic policies.
Little Mannix has a particular requirement they'd like I help with They
got website hosted on the sea to machines that their customers access by
going through an application little balance.
They also have a static website hosted in S E book it that
contains basic information about good Mannix.
We've been asked to provide a solution that directs all
customer traffic to the corporate website.
But if the carpet website is unavailable for any reason,
then customers should be directed to the static Web
site content hosted in S three.
Take a minute to think about Globe Mannix requirements.
What a do a solution.
Would you recommend to meet those requirements?
One possible solution would include using roof of three traffic policies.
Room 53 connects a global traffic manager.
So if you got service,
is that distributed globally Paps with copies of your
carpet website in North America and Europe,
you can use Route 53 to direct people to most appropriate copy of your website.
To do this,
we can create a traffic policy on associate that traffic
policy We want more policy records, a policy record is a name toe i p.
Just mapping it might be in a record of a quite a record.
In fact,
it could be any of the standard records that roof to three supports traffic
policies have assessed to resolve that name to a specific I.
P address.
All set of I P addresses.
Traffic policy can work of a variety of empires, even horse unaided.
Dress on premise.
All the third pie trying policies can altering corporate health
checks so that we only resolve names too healthy.
I p addresses.
When we create a traffic policy,
we've got a range of ruin methods that we can choose from.
We've got fail over rooting, for example, we fail of ruin.
We send all the quest to a specific M point as long as it's healthy.
And if that end point isn't healthy, we fail over to a backup en pointe.
We've got Wade ruling.
We've waited ruin.
We consent half a quest in one direction, on half in the other.
We've got the location ruin policies with J location.
It'll take into account where the name is Lucy.
Request is coming from and use that location to send
you in a particular direction.
That way, if we got copies of our content in Europe and enough America,
we can send every in Europe to European and points.
I have enough America, Enough American points.
We've got multi value answer with multi value answer.
We could return a range of I P addresses in response
to a name is Lee Shin request.
The client that made the request,
then will choose which of those I P addresses used to connect to our service.
We have late into base ruin.
We've laid in Sabates ruin.
We will direct requests the best performance and point at that moment in time.
And finally we have the approximate ruin.
Do you approximately ruin uses the location of the endpoint and not
determine which couple of your service requesters should be.
Rue Ito.
When configuring ruin policies, we can configure,
basically ruin policies on the records themselves so we can go to the
hosted zoning Route 53 select a record and locate the routine method
section by default the ruin method or beset too simple.
But we can change that.
Tow anything methods mentioned on the previous side.
If you only want one level of Decision American and
have a small number of them points,
then configure the routine policy on the record itself Makes sense.
Traffic policies then allows to map out multiple levels of decision making.
Perhaps you want people to be guided to a particular geography and
then inside that job for you have multiple copies of your service
and then you want to use fail of ruin.
Any time you want to combine multiple different types of ruin,
you have to do that by creating traffic policy.
We can create traffic policies,
use individual editor access through 43 so giving what we now know about root in
policies on Globe Mannix requirements which were in policy.
Would you recommend for Globe Mannix?
One possible answer would be to use fail of a
1,000,000 policies with health checks.
Using fail of a ruin, customers can be guided to the corporate website host.
Uneasy too, sat behind applicator love answer.
Using health checks,
we can detect when that service is not available and then direct people to
the S three hosted Web site because we only want one level of decision
making and I've only got two possible M points,
then we could settle this policy on the records themselves.
Alternatively, by creating traffic policy,
it might make it easier for us to make adjustments later onto scale tomorrow,
end points without into create new results, records and edit the ones that already exist.