[Autogenerated] So let's begin by trying to answer the question.
What is a hybrid network?
Architecture?
If you asked to describe a hybrid network and stature, what would you say?
I'm sure there's lots of things he could write down.
They might include connecting on premise network to a V P.
C.
I guess.
Fundamentally, that's what hybrid network after through all about.
When discussing hybrid network arc touches,
you might have a conversation about throughput.
Does your collective it need to be high speed and always on Oh,
can you route traffic over it?
And that when describing hybrid network contentious,
you might also have a conversation about security?
Does traffic needs be encrypted?
Doing point seemed to be authenticated.
A lot about security today is provided by I B SEC,
but your design might use a non i p ___ base protocol.
The choice of protocol might impact the features that we can use inside ed.
Worse, to create a hybrid network architecture,
hybrid network architects and Eddie breasts well most often
involve a connection from on premise into your V p.
C.
But these hybrid network architectures could also provide transitive ruin
capabilities so traffic can flow between your offices.
So when asked to describe hybrid network architectures to a colleague,
your conversation might involve these talking points on more
when connecting to results is deployed.
In a digress,
we can use the public i p address of those resources public I Pierre does.
It can be attached to 82 instances, too low balances.
We can also connect to the public endpoints of products.
I guess three on dynamodb the second option when connecting to results.
There did Wes.
It's collect their private appearances.
This will involve creating a VPN connection or dedicated
circuit using any West direct connect.
In this example, we have a free PC deployed to our Aid West account.
This VPC contains two subjects and has a gateway device attached.
We then have a good cause with the network crew with connective its Internet,
and we use our ruler to collect the get where device
needed breasts to quit VPN connection.
Everything going across this VPN connection will be encrypted.
The two endpoints Rudolph any kid reach over on the devices
commit configured the check the integrity of each packet
sent with this be pen collection.
Place results is 2.20 Wes on resulted to fight headquarters.
We'll be able to route to each other.
This is a typical example of hybrid networking.
In this next example,
we've got a Web tear deployed to AWS the servers in that Web tier
of accessible through a low balance that hates.
Q.
We got applications here on a day of it.
This is a typical example of a military application.
The unique thing here is respected.
Tears between us on on premise.
To allow the different parts of application to communicate.
Reach over.
We'll create a VPN connection so that the Web tear can communicate
application to and debt best securely on the outside.
Then we got a customer who's going to use a friendly
name of application and have that name.
Result fruit D N S o N i.
P Address D.
N s Will result that friend the name the public I P.
Address of the AWS Low balance.
In turn, the lower balance that will lower balance.
I request to the weapon here.
If the Web here needs to communicate with the applications,
here are the database the Web T will send that requests over the VPN
connection with this hybrid Rockets Design How Web taken Take
advantage of the scalability on elasticity.
The Aid West offers, while we can keep them, are sensitive.
Parts of application on premise fall under our control.
This type of architecture is also used. Joe migrations into a digress.