[Autogenerated] in this demonstration.
Where could be working with Route 53 traffic
policies throughout this demonstration?
Where could be working with the Midwest Council on
DHF All along this demonstration, you'll need your own AWS account.
I'm signed into the 80 West console specifically the Route 53
dashboard inside here hunger and select traffic policies to
create a new conflict policy.
We click create conflict policy.
We then provide a name on optional description for our policy with
the policy name and version description filled in.
Well, then click Next.
We're now given access to the traffic policy campus through here,
we can offer our traffic policy or we can impart on existing
traffic policy and make changes to that.
We're gonna offer a new policy.
Firstly, we have to pick a start point.
The start point represents the type of record this policy will work with.
If we click on the Dennis type drop down,
we can select from this list of records.
I want this polished Woke up a records, so I leave the area code selected.
Then we click connector.
If we scroll down a little bit,
we can see the list of options for the first step in a traffic policy.
Little Mannix.
Traffic policy needs to be a failure of a policy.
So we select fail over rule.
Our failure of a rule is gonna have to end points.
The primary endpoint is, well,
one all traffic to go unless that primary point isn't healthy.
In which case traffic should go to the second round point.
If I select connector next to primary,
scroll down a little bit and choose new endpoint,
this end point then represents the destination about traffic.
If we start the drop down next to type,
we can see all the different kind of endpoints.
Globe Mannix website sits behind an application.
Love answer.
If I select LB application, Little bouncer,
we can see the value is already being filled in.
And that's because globe Mannix only house,
one application little bouncer deployed.
I'm happy with traffic going to that in point as long as it's healthy.
So we have to configure health checks.
If I could come to drop down next to health checks.
I already have a globe Mannix health check configured,
which I can select,
so our traffic policy will use the value of the self check to
determine where this end point is healthy are no,
it's healthier.
The end point will be used.
If not, traffic will be sent to the second round point.
So if I scroll down a little bit and again,
click connector, scroll down Dittmar and choose new endpoint again.
If I quit the drop down next to Value Globe,
Mannix has configured and Esther you book it with some site
content that their customers should be directed to in the
event that their main website fails.
So if I choose S3 website in point,
I make sure I choose the glove money's book it that
contains a static Web site content.
This traffic policy meets Globe Mannix requirements.
So if I now say, create traffic policy,
it won't take a minute to create traffic policy.
Now we must make sure the correct hosted zone is listed in the host's own box.
He can see I'm gonna be working with the glove man
Exhausted zone The final piece.
This puzzle then, is to enable a policy record.
So the pulse of echo box I type for this example Www and what we're asking
Route 53 to do is to create this record in the Globe.
Manic stop comes on.
And then whenever Route 53 gets a new resolution,
request this record to assess that request through the traffic policy.
No, it's the price at the end here.
This policy record is gonna cost me $50 per month.
You'll be charged an additional $50 per month for every record
you won't assessed through your traffic policy.
I'm half of a single record scroll down, I select.
Create policy record.
Once the traffic policies create, I can create new versions of trying policy.
Andi.
I can add additional policy records to be evaluated through the policy globe.
Mannix needs were quite basic, which is one level of decision making.
Using that failure of a rule, all traffic should go.
Fellow balancer, This is not healthy.
Then it should go to the stock website hosted a street,
but traffic policies come in more complex.
This is an example of our complex traffic in policy
with three levels of decision making.
First of all,
we have a fail of rule on that feel of rule has a primary on second round point.
If the primary path is chosen next we have awaited rule
that sends a percentage of requests in two different
directions from the way it rule.
We have a location rule that sends European traffic in
one direction on the rest of world.
You never.
As you can see from this example,
these Route 53 traffic policies commit very nuanced decisions about
which I p address to resolve your name requester.
One final thing to show you.
Here.
This is Theglobe Mannix Health check.
And this is checking the health of this end point. And it's his health check that was used in our failure of a routine policy.