[Autogenerated] in this demonstration.
Well, take a look at some surprising results and tools available to us in AWS.
Throughout this demonstration,
we're gonna work in with B A U s Consul on the Aid West Documentation.
If you want to follow along this demonstration,
you will need an address account on a Web browser.
I'm back in the U S.
Consul this time in the building and cost management dashboard.
This is a great tool for keeping track of how much
you're spending inside a duress.
Here.
We can see cost a new sitter parts we consent budgets.
And if I would click bill details,
we'd see a breakdown of our expenditure so far this month.
I never told us.
Kidnappers manage costs is trusted.
Advisor Trusted Advisor makes recommendations based on best practice.
One of the domains supported by trusted advisor is cost optimization.
If I select cost optimization,
you can see that all the recommendations are great out.
That's because I'm not the correct support level.
You must be the business, our enterprise support level.
In order for the cost optimization demand to be turned on when it is turned on,
it'll make suggestions on how you can save money in your account by
taking your results is against best practice guidelines,
both Building management interested.
Advisor.
A great Once you started deploying resources to AWS.
But what about when you're the design phase?
I am trying to figure out how much you are designed.
What costs Once deployed?
Well, we could start off with the simple Mumford calculator.
The simple move.
A calculator allows you to input details regarding the service
choices you're about to make in a deep breath and then give you an
estimate of how much till social cost.
For example, if I scroll down to V.
P.
C on select Amazon BPC, I can then choose a region.
For example, you west, too, and into a US too angular.
Deploy a site site VPN.
So I fill in the veep in connection section here.
I've selected that I'll have five deep in connections, 100% immunization.
You can see it's given me an estimated monthly bill.
If I scroll down a little bit, let's add some debt out in this case,
five terabytes if a scroll back up and this time we'll
click on estimate your monthly bill and he gives a
breakdown about Bill for that month.
So the VPN connections on the Data 600 fight $2.55 per month so we
can use the simple of calculator Jonah Tsang fares to keep a track
of our estimated spend a new a tool.
Available to us is the AWS pricing calcula.
The address pricing calculator works a bit like the simple monthly calculator.
We select Queer Estimate and then we select the service is
that we want to deploy into a digress, for example,
VPN.
When we search VPN, the VP service appears.
I don't we could say configure and now it works a bit
like the simple man for calculator.
We have VPN selected,
we can choose a region and then we can provide
details about pours VPN connections.
And it will tell us an estimated monthly bill So that
same five VPN connection selected.
It tells that monthly estimated bill will be under Net $2.
50.
This new pricing calculator it's a replacement for the simple Mumford
calcula and should the calculator you use going forward,
the final two alone show you is the total cost of ownership calculator,
the total cost of ownership calcula It's not as relevant for
your hybrid networking designs this tool.
I'll just to find your workloads, as they have been in on premise now.
So what physical service do you have?
What virtual service do you have?
What story do you have on the report that the TCO calculate it generates?
We'll give you your estimate, Spend on premise now and then.
Compare that to the estimate.
Spend if you deploy the same resources into a de Bresse.
The final thing wanna point out in this demonstration is the
Aid West documentation specifically here we're on the air Due
West Direct Connect pricing page.
It's fruit pricing pages like this that you'll find the
latest pricing for your region during your design and
planning of your integration with AWS.
I encourage you to seek out the letters price information.
We've covered a lot over the last two hours.
We started off by introducing hybrid architectures.
I'm discussing what I bring network architecture is,
and we gave, you know, view of some of the key components.
We went on to introduce site site V.
P n's Direct Connect on dradis ghost transit.
VP sees transit VP sees is still out there, and it's still popular.
But new design should take advantage of transit.
Gateway's first and only fall back to use in transit.
VP sees it turns it gateways don't meet your requirement.
We went on to discuss some of the supporting service.
Is the weather deploy when working with hybrid network architectures?
These included Hybrid Name A Solution Group 53
Traffic Policies on Transit Gateway.
We also briefly discussed Resource Access Manager on how we can use RAM to
share resources between Amazon Web service accounts.
We then went on to look at a dress man's V,
P N's and Software VP ends in detail,
and we discussed how software VPN they're still popular for bring you a
licensed AL years and you want to take advantage of existence.
Skill sets on premise.
We did say that manage three pens are highly available by design,
and if you deploy software V P N's,
you'll have to decide what level of high availability you want to deploy.
A manic.
We also discussed client VPN points on.
We discussed how we could use cloud hope to route
traffic between our different branches.
We then went on to discuss Aid West direct connect on how we
provide high availability for Ed US Direct Connect.
We finished off this cost with conversations around B g, p.
And we discuss what B.
G P is on.
How we could use B G p with direct connect and site site VI pets
in this final module with discuss pricing.
Specifically cites I v P M pricing, Direct Connect pricing.
And we've had a look at some of the pricing tools and
documentation that you can use Junior design of hybrid
network in architecture In this module, we just go sight sight billing aid US.
Direct Connect Billing on.
We gave you a quick cost summary.
Thank you.
Spending the last two hours.
I hope it's cause of giving you the information you need to
start your hybrid network in journey.
For those of you thinking about the Age of West advanced networking exam,
make sure you've you've given courses in the pool side here.
Divorce, advanced networking track.
Finally feel free to leave any comments or questions you might
have in the discussion sector of this costs.
Have a look at the learning checks to test your knowledge
on If you'd like to please leave a star.
Wayne.
My name's Mike Brown on upsy on a portal site. Courses in the future