[Autogenerated] in this demonstration whether we're working with B G,
p and sites like v P N's throughout the demonstration where you've been
working with the aid US counsel on to follow along this demonstration
and we do encourage you to follow along,
you'll need an aide to US account.
I'm in the address console specifically the VPC dashboard.
If I scroll down a bit, find the VPN section in the VP in section.
I'm going to slap customer gateways and then create custom a gateway.
We create custom gateways in a previous section.
So in here you provide a name for Gateway the public I p address on the
previous excise we selected steak this time limits like dynamic.
By selecting the dynamic readable,
we're asked to provide an autonomous sister number.
No, it's here that autonomous sister numbers being suggested for US 65,000.
Now you can use this default,
or you can use an autonomous system number that
matches your on premise configuration.
This could be a private autonomous system number you've chosen to use or
public Autonomous is the number that you've registered for.
If you're happy with the air, send choice select,
create customer gateway the next thing,
we're gonna look at the site site VPN connection.
So if I select sites like VPN connections and then click create VPN connection,
he'll find a name.
The details of the virtual private Gail Transit
gateway on a customer gateway selection.
And again, we get a choice of ruin Options.
Even static are dynamic this time.
We'll leave it set to dynamic.
If I scroll down, there's nothing else that we have to configure.
Here.
You can configure Go on Total Sense, sir,
including the I P addresses used for the tunnel connections.
Appreciate key.
Use, little connections.
And if you click the advanced radio balloons,
you'll also be a configured The eyepiece exceptions as well.
Have a play around with them if you need.
If not, click create VPN connection.
We'll take a little while that VPN connection to be created.
You can see here it's still pending, but over them what?
We've seen the van over B G P settings First configure
on the west Side of relationship.
Now that a VPN captain is available,
we can select the download configuration options.
If I slept that and choose my vendor and platform,
I can download a configuration file for my own promise device.
If I was, like downloads, download the file and then open it.
Here is the downloaded configuration file and specifically
have scroll down to the B G P section.
This is the configuration for Cisco Cloud Service Ruler.
We can see the command that starts the Ruby GP
process on this autonomous system.
Number 6 5000 Is that on the sister number off the
on premise side of elation ship.
Well, then get the neighbor details on these.
The details off the West Side relationship, including the I P.
Address off the air.
Depressed neighbor device, andi autonomous sister number used.
Collect that neighbor.
Your configuration might look a little bit different for your on premise device,
and it might take a little bit of editing,
but these configuration files were great.
Start enough point on, if used correctly,
will lead to fewer errors in this model.
You learn what BDP is.
I went through some of his key features.
We discussed using PGP with sites,
ivy pens and direct connect on gave you a quick demonstration of using
B G P recite site connections in our next module.
Well done, second billing for direct connect in sight.
Side VP ends.
I'm take a look at a cost summary going through some the
key points for the last two hours.
So join me there. I will continue on AWS hybrid networking journey.