[Autogenerated] in this section will try and turns the question.
What is a direct connect hosted connection when
working with force The connections.
We work with a partner that's a member of the Direct Connect Partner program.
This partner will help us establish a direct connect connection between
our locations and address one of the benefits of her.
See connection is the part speech choices we don't have to accept.
A one gig are tangled connection.
We can set off a 50 megabits and work up in increments
when we purchase hosted connection.
We're buying a virtual interface,
so Eat Hosted connection will connect is Eva to a V P.
C.
Our public aid were service by allowing us to create a public life.
Our private Biff.
Like most things in life,
there's both benefits and drawbacks to use in her see connections.
One big benefit.
If you get a lot of help in establishing a direct connect circuit,
it may be a simpler book, an appointment paying a fee on a given day.
The pattern will show up at your location and plugging some equipment,
and then you'll see the horsey connection established in
the direct connect console for you to accept because we
have more bandwidth choices.
We can choose a band with that suits our requirements
rather than having to go for one day.
Got anger circuit.
This can reduce the cost of a circuit,
but also we're not wasting bandwidth on money on through Put that we don't need.
Also, some hosted collection providers offer Marvel silly instructions,
which we might not be a get over Ford with a dedicated connection.
One of the drawbacks of her sick connection is the fact that
each connection is a single virtual interface.
So if you want more perverts interfaces,
you have to bind mobile connections, and this could increase your costs.
The more vicious you need, the my life you are go for dedicated connection.
Also,
the additional partner costs taken to account for the work
they're doing to establish connection for us.
If your organization only two single biff and definitely if
you need less bandwidth than one gigabyte,
then hosted connections might be the way to go.
Remember afterwards and connections configured,
it appears in your connection pain.
In the direct connect dashboard,
you must accept the connection before you can start
routing traffic across it status punctual.
We talked about from the problems that glove man face it,
and I think that connects solves those problems.
For starters,
the larger offices will take advantage of the increased
bandwidth on the particular performance to give them the
farm's improvements they need.
This, in turn,
means that Globe Mannix can start using more Reed West service is on move in,
move there on Premise Service's into eight of us.
It also means that traffic that was taken a bandwidth on their
standard in that connection is now moved away.
Freeing up that bandwidth for over service is also because we got a
direct connect connection will now be communicating with s3 and over
80 West Public Service is across that link.
Keeping that traffic away from it as well are making our
compliance people happy and finally, to satisfy the encryption requirement.
Globe Monique's house Well established European connections
over top of our direct connect circuit,
encrypting traffic from on premise into our VP sees we don't have to worry
about using encryption when connecting to service is like s3.
Those connections use Hey, https endpoints.
So the traffic of there is always encrypted in this module.
We've discussed the benefits of using a due West Direct Connect.
You've learned about the different components that used
to create a direct connect connection,
and you've learned about some of the silly assumptions we have
when we're establishing direct connect circuits.
We finish this model by discussing direct connect her
stick connections in our next module.
Well, because in Diamond Crew in with B G.
P. So join me there and we'll continue on AWS hybrid networking journey.