[Autogenerated] before taking a look at site site VI.
Pens on air to West Direct connect in much more detail.
I just want to try and answer this question.
What is a transit VPC in this example?
Glove.
Manning's has got three.
VP sees each VPC is deployed to a different region.
Globe Mannix requires collective it between these three peces on.
One option they have available to them is a feature called VPC Peering.
VPC.
Peering allows us to connect,
VP sees without having to deploy any gateway devices.
So in this example,
glove Mannix VPC one on glow mark three pc to come appear together.
By creating the paving connection,
I'm making the correct adjustment to root tables and knuckles.
Easy to machines deployed to e V P.
C.
We'll be able to communicate region.
We could also Pierre glove Mannix vpc too.
On glove Manning's VPC three Again once development,
brute tables and knuckles have been adjusted,
we should find that results is deployed to V.
P.
C.
Two can route to results of deployed in V P C.
Three on vice versa, but with this period in place,
can result is deployed to BBC one roots results is deployed to V.
P.
C.
Three on the answer here is no in AWS transitive ruin like this is not allowed.
We cannot send traffic between two vpc Zvi referred.
Of course.
In this example,
we could establish a VPC peering connection between VPC one on V P.
C.
Three and with the appropriate adjustments, Mazar is deployed to e V.
P.
C would be able to route to each other,
and that's finds the quite basic scenarios.
But the more VP sees you have, the more pairing connections you have,
the more complex this type of room becomes a transit VPC provide transit ruin.
In this example,
we have two VP sees each one has a deployed virtual private
gateway on we have our headquarters location ana in neck
planted ruler sat between them with a V p.
C.
Where we've deployed marketplace devices.
These might be Cisco in a great service, rulers.
Or they might be customized E.
C.
Two instances that you create yourself evil way.
These devices in the transit vpc are fully into your control and your
responsibility to manage and maintain these devices.
Quit beeping connections to the virtual private get within
three p c onto the route from premise.
With this architecture in place, traffic from headquarters controversy,
the transit VPC on be sent on to any of the VPC that we are connected to.
This type of activity was commonplace, and he still use a lot today.
But as we'll see in a late model,
Aid West has released everyone managed device called a transit Gateway Face
designed to replace these marketplace devices on transit,
VP sees in this model we introduced Glove Mannix on we
discussed hybrid network connectivity options.
We introduce site site,
VP ends and Aid US Direct Connect and you introduced to Transit.
VP sees the goal of this Montel was to know only interest issue to the cause,
but also introduce you to the service is that we'll be
discussing in much more detail in the month.
ALS that's come in our next module we're gonna discuss some of
the supporting service is that site site,
VP Ends and Direct Connect will use will discuss the annex for hybrid a dress.
Deployments will discuss Route 53 ruin policies on how they could be
used to route traffic toe on premise in the cloud,
and we'll introduce you to air to West Transit Gateway,
which is the Aid West manage replacement for transit VP sees.
So join me there. I will continue on AWS hybrid network and journey.