Hello and welcome to this XlV B A for beginners Course.
My name is Abderahmane Abou and I will be your instructor on this course.
So a little bit about myself.
I have a degree in chemical engineering.
I have five years of experience is a data analyst and eight years overall experience in
Excel on.
And I have been an online instructor since 2015 and I'm a certified Microsoft Excel expert
.
So first of all,
who should take the scores?
So this course is geared towards beginners who want to learn xlv a So if you only know how
to record Macron's But you don't know how to write VB a code than this course is for you.
If you are aware the experienced with writing VB a code than this course is not for you.
Okay,
so let's discuss the course contents.
So first of all,
we're gonna have an introduction section where we're going to understand what the objects
in excel VB are and what are the methods and properties.
And we're going to understand the V b a syntax amongst other topics.
And we're also going to be introduced to the visual basic environment we're going to learn
about the range object,
the cells collection,
object,
and we're gonna learn about dealing with worksheets in xlv a on.
Then we're gonna go into variables and then we're going to learn about dealing with
workbooks and xlv b a and then we're gonna go through XlV be a logic such as finding the
last row if statements,
case statements and also some other topics.
We're also going to discuss loops on this course and then loops help you repeat some pieces
of code over and over again until a certain condition is satisfied.
And that's when you need to break out of the loop on.
Then we're also going to learn how to interact with users using message boxes and import
boxes,
and we're gonna learn how to do air handling on.
Then we're gonna learn about events in Excel vv eight.
Okay,
so I'm still excited to start that course with you and without further ado,
let's get started