Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about the Project Explorer and the Project Explorer is this window
here that is open on the left and in Excel.
Actually,
each workbook is considered a project on its own.
And at the moment you can see here that I've got only one workbook open here.
The rest of the workbooks.
The rest of these projects are actually system workbooks.
There are related to the Silver tool and excel in other tools as well.
It's actually the only workbook that I've got open is the workbook called VB editor intro.
Now,
if the Project Explorer is not showing on your screen for any reason,
you can view it by going to the view many here at the top and then clicking on Project
Explorer.
And you can also,
alternatively,
click on control on R on your keyboard.
You can,
of course,
close the project,
explore by clicking on this X button here on this close button,
and you can also move it around if you want.
If you click on the title and drag it around,
you can move it around and you conduct it back again.
here by moving in and noticing some sort of off a shadow that will appear there and it will
be docked back again.
Now,
Currently,
on my workbook I've got only one sheet,
which is cold cheat one he can see also a modules holder.
Will you have your modules and these air?
Basically the containers of your mac rose off your VB a code.
And whenever you record a macro and you don't have any modules,
Excel actually will create a module automatically.
If you record a macron,
you will also see any user forms that you create.
You will see them here as well on the Project Explorer.
If you have multiple modules as well or multiple folders of modules,
you will see that also on the Project Explorer.
Okay,
so that's a guys for the Project Explorer.
Thank you very much watching this video I'll see on the next one