Hey,
guys,
Welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss how we can disable the events and how weaken re enable them again.
Okay,
so if we disable the events,
anything that is triggered as a result of any event is not gonna be triggered.
Okay,
So any code that is triggered,
for example,
by double clicking a cell will not be triggered.
Okay?
The events are disabled.
This feature in Excel will be disabled,
and we'll see why we're going to need to use that.
Okay.
But first of all,
to disable an event you can write application dot enable events equals false.
Okay,
this is how you condense able events and to re enable them again,
you can write application dot enable events equals true.
Okay,
So if you run the first line of code here for the disable events of procedure to run that
events will be disabled.
So,
for example,
on this before DoubleClick sheet here,
where we explained that before DoubleClick event and we said that if we double click on any
of these names,
it will be transferred to sell l three.
This will not happen.
Okay,
Because events or disabled so any code this triggered as a result of a certain action will
be disabled.
Okay,
So to re enable the the events again and re enable that feature,
you can just run the application,
enable events equals true.
So if you run that and we double click here because here the names are being transferred to
sell l three.
Okay,
so the events are now working,
and of course,
you can include these line of lines of code in any procedure that you write even in event
procedures,
and we're going to see why these are useful.
Okay,
if at any point,
you just want to check if events are enabled or disabled,
not enable them were disabled them.
But just check.
Are they enabled or disabled at the moment at this moment,
are they enabled or disabled?
You can go to your immediate window.
This is a nice little trick.
Okay,
so you can go to the your immediate window here,
and if it's not enabled,
you can click on view here and then click on immediate window to view.
It can write a question mark and then application dot enable events.
Okay.
Do not write equals two or false or anything,
destroy this question mark application.
Don't an evil events and press enter you will just tell you.
Is it true or four?
So if it's true,
then they are enabled.
If it's Fallston in events or disables,
this is a nice little trick that you can use to check if at a certain moment events are
enabled or disabled and in future videos,
we're going to see ah,
why enabling and disabling events or useful?
OK,
so thanks for watching this video I'll see on the next one.