Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the worksheet change events.
So the work she change event gets triggered whenever a cell in your worksheet gets changed
,
either by yourself as user or by an external link.
So any change,
really,
that happens to a cell in your worksheet is going to trigger the worksheet change event.
Okay,
so let's illustrate that by a simple examples I've got here a sheet cold work,
she change event and just going right,
click on it and click on view code,
and then go to work sheet on this menu here and then click on change even.
Okay.
And then I'm just gonna delete this worksheet selection change event because we don't need
it.
And now I'm just gonna put a message box here.
You made a change on your worksheet.
Okay,
this message box is gonna be triggered whenever I make a change on a cell in my worksheet.
This is different from the selection change,
though This election change gets triggered whenever you select a different cell.
But you see now it's not being triggered because this is not what triggers it.
What triggers it is changing something on a sheet.
A case?
You change the contents of a cell.
Then this message baskets triggered.
You made the change on your worksheet.
Okay,
so this is how you can trigger the worksheet change event.
Even if you delete the contents of the cell.
This also triggers the worksheet change even.
Okay,
so let's have a more sophisticated example.
so let's say on this column on column B.
What I want to do is when I put a value,
I wanted to be multiplied by a 1,000,000.
OK,
so let's say on this column,
you need to be entering values.
The are million's okay.
And you just want if you want to put two million,
you just put a two and then excel adjust multiplied by a 1,000,000 it will be two million.
The value will be two million.
But you don't wanna type two and then six zeros or two multiplied by 10.
Race to the par six each time you input the value,
okay?
Or so you don't want a multiplier value by a 1,000,000.
You don't want to type a lot of zeros.
You just want to put the number okay and then accept will multiplied by one million.
Because this is our objective on this column on column B.
We want to do that.
Okay,
so let's see how we conduce that.
And we're going to face some obstacles actually,
to see how we can do that.
So I'm gonna go here too.
My worksheet change event.
And then I'm going to start typing if Target because this has a target parameter.
And the target is basically the cell that you changed.
Okay,
So if target dot column equals two okay,
that means it's in column beats in the second column.
Then let's put Marr and if here Okay,
So if target dark column equals do what do we want to do?
We actually want to multiply our value by a 1,000,000.
OK,
so target of value is equal to target thought value,
okay.
And then multiplied by we can't put a 10 race to the part six here.
We cannot do that.
We will get an error.
You can't do that in VB A.
What you want to do is to actually call a worksheet function,
okay,
so you can actually call a function a normal cell function,
normal worksheet function from XlV B A.
So how do you do that?
Okay,
so is this something new work that we're gonna learn here?
Application.
You could write application dot worksheets function and then dot and then you choose the
function.
There's a function called power in Excel.
Okay,
this is a functioning normally excel called power.
Okay.
And what this function it does is a accepts two inputs.
The first imp.
It is basically the number that you that you want to race to a certain power cyst the base
.
Okay,
So is gonna be 10 and then,
Ah,
the power itself is going to be six.
That means that the value of the cell that we're changing is gonna be multiplied by tend to
the par six.
A target of value cause targeted a value multiplied by 10 to the power six.
Okay,
So see what's gonna happen if we just leave the code.
Is that because this is not gonna work as we want to see what's gonna happen here?
Let's say I want to write two million.
Okay,
So I want to write just two,
and then excel will just convert it to two million or make it.
Two million.
OK,
so I'm going to write to here and look at this numbers.
A very big numbers to multiplied by 10 to the power 306.
So that's two multiplied by 10 to the power 306 0 that's not the number that we wanted.
We just wanted 10 2 million.
That's it.
We don't We didn't want this big number.
So what happened here?
What's happened?
Well,
what happened is that the change that you made in the cell has been action recursive lee
cases.
It's like in a recursive action,
because you changed the content of the cell and that triggered to change.
And then the change triggered another change,
and another change in another changed and an excel kept actually multiplying the value by
tend to the power six,
you know,
until it reached.
Actually,
the the biggest number that an Excel cell can handle in this case,
actually,
biggest number that Excel Cell can handle is I think it's 10 to the power 307 or something
like that.
But this is the biggest number that the cell could handle,
so just kept on multiplying the number the result by tend to the party six is like to buy,
tend to the par six.
And then it takes the product of that and then multiplies it by 10 to the par six.
And then it takes the product of that and then multiplies it by 10 34 6 and keeps on doing
that until reaching the highest value that Excel can handle.
Okay,
so this is what basically happened.
The number kept on multiplying itself by 10 to the poor six.
Okay.
So to help you understand what happened better.
Let's step through the code,
go through the code step by step.
Okay.
Eso I'm actually going to lead the content of the cell here,
and you can see here that the event still has been triggered,
but we're having a zero because it's multiplying zero byte under the par six.
And so it's resulting zero.
And even with the recursive reaction is just resulting a zero.
So I'm just gonna go back here,
and I'm gonna put a break point in my code at this line so that the code would stop
executing at this line here,
and then we're going to start executing it manually.
So I'm gonna put too in here and you consider this.
The event has been triggered,
but it's the code stopped at this line at the break point that I set.
No,
I'm gonna press f eight to continue executing the code.
So the first time it's been executed,
it's resulted in two million.
Now this has triggered a change event and then it's it's resulted in multiplying it by
another 10 to the poor.
Six is now what tend to the poor 12.
And if you keep pressing,
F eight is now 10 to the power to multiple but tentative poor 18 and then it is stunned to
the poor 24 then it's time to a poor 30 of 36.
So I'm executing the code manually using F eight.
This is actually one of the best ways to troubleshoot events event codes,
in case you're having a problem with with VB a code that you've written in an event.
Okay,
put a ah break point and then start executing the code manually.
OK,
so we're doing that.
You can see her.
The code is still being executed and the event is still being triggered.
It's ah recursive reaction.
OK?
It's like a chain reaction is just a a change,
you know,
triggering a change which triggers a change which triggers a change.
And this keeps happening until we actually where we going to stop?
We're actually going to stop at the highest number that this cell could handle.
OK,
so if there was,
ah,
higher numbers,
Excel would still,
you know,
keep on multiplying the result by 10 to the power six.
Okay,
then we and the if and so on.
Actually,
excel still wants to do it,
but actually,
this is the the highest number that Selcan handles.
Excel wants to still execute the change,
but there's no we can't go any higher on the cell because this is the highest number that
we can go on the cell.
Is this crazy?
Okay,
so I'm just going to stop all that craziness,
and now we're going to see how we can solve that problem.
So I'm going to remove the break point and let's see how we can solve that problem.
Okay,
so this is where disabling events is handy.
This is where disabling events becomes handy.
So,
actually,
if you add on application dot enable events for the line of code here application that
enable events equals foals here before we execute this line of code.
And then we could actually enable the events after the if statement.
Okay,
So before ending the sub,
where at any point that we find convenience a convenient.
Okay,
so application dot enable events equals true.
We will not have this problem.
Okay,
so let's see that again.
Let's right to Nikon's here.
We just got two million is,
too,
with six zeroes beside it.
So what happened here is we actually checked that were in the second column here,
and then we disabled the events,
okay?
And we executed that line of code,
which is multiplying to buy 10 to the par six.
Okay.
And then we enabled it back after there was nothing to trigger the event.
So this is what happened.
Now,
if you write any number here five,
for example,
we're gonna have five million a proper 5,000,050.
We're gonna have 50 million.
Just 50 million,
not a you know,
50 by tend to the power 307 or something like that.
Okay,
so this is where the disabling events comes handy.
this is Ah,
simple example.
You need to make sure to use your tools,
your tools,
right.
And you need to know one to disable the events in order to get the results that you want.
Okay.
To thank you guys for watching this video,
I'll see on the next.