Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna have an exercise for the work seat events.
So in this exercise year,
we've got this exercise worksheet,
and what I need you to do is to write an event procedure for this worksheet here called
Exercise to fill the entire row of a selected cell with the color vb red.
And as a hint,
he will need to use the property called entire row for the range object.
So what this event is going to achieve is basically,
if you select a cell,
its entire row gets colored in rat.
Okay,
so I need you to attempt that exercise.
And I do have the answer here for the exercise in this exercise answer module.
Of course,
you need to copy the code.
If you want to try the answer,
you need to copy it and put it in the exercise worksheet and make it an event.
So if you get stuck,
have a look at the answer.
And if you have any questions,
please leave them in the Q and a section off the course.
Thank you very much.
Watching this video also on the necks