Okay,
guys.
So now we're going to discuss the workbook after save event so you can get the workbook
after save event by going to your ah vb a editor and then double clicking on this workbook
here and then selecting work burke from this menu and selecting after save from this menu.
So the workbook after save event triggers any code that you right after saving and to be
more specific,
it's actually after attempting to save.
And that means that it gets triggered whether the save was successful or whether it's was
unsuccessful.
Okay,
so you can actually use it in combination with the before save or actually this is what
we're gonna do on this example.
So we've hade the before save event.
We've had the example where you ask a user toe under his name and the name is entered.
Any presses control and s and tries to save the workbook.
If the name is entered,
then the workbook is gonna be saved.
If the cell is blank,
any presence controlling s he's going to get this message box here cannot save please under
your name.
So we're gonna actually use the workbook after save event.
and we're gonna have a message box that says Save Waas.
We're gonna have a space after walls and we're gonna come Contin eight that with the
parameter here in the workbook after save even this cold success And this parameter here
success takes two values either two or false.
If the save was done successfully,
that is gonna have a value of true.
If the save was not done it to say it does not go through and look does not get saved,
then it's gonna have a value off fulls.
Okay,
so what's gonna happen here is that we're gonna try to see the workbook.
I'm going to try to save it control and s here.
This cell is blank.
There's no name.
Enter.
This is why the work before save event displays this message box it says cannot save.
Please enter your name and to prove that actually,
it will run.
I mean,
the after save event will run even if you're save was unsuccessful.
I'm gonna click OK here.
And you're going to see the message box here.
This message boxes the one triggered by the after save event and he says save waas false
okay,
Because the value of the parameter that is called success was false.
This is why he displays save waas False If I enter my name or really anything in this cell
impressed control and s again.
He says save was true.
And the first message bought message box.
The first message box that was for the before save event was not triggered because there
was a name entered.
Okay,
because the if statement does not trigger the message box unless the cell is empty.
OK,
so as you can see here,
it tests if the cell range B one the Selby one is blank than council equals true,
Which means that the workbook is not going to be saying and the message box appears,
But otherwise the message box will not appear.
Okay,
so basically,
the workbook after save event gets triggered whenever you actually attempt to save a
workbook and whether the save was successful or not.
Whatever code you put in here on the workbook after save event will get triggered.
Okay,
so I hope that was informative for you.
Thank you very much watching this video I'll see on the next one