Okay,
I So now we're going to speak about the properties window.
So the properties window enables us to it.
It the properties of whatever object we select from our Project Explorer.
Okay,
so this is the properties window.
Now we can view the properties window by going to the view menu here at the top and
clicking on Properties Window.
And alternatively,
we can click on F four on our keyboard.
Okay,
so now if I select module one,
you can see here that the only property I couldn't edit is actually the name of the module
.
Now,
if I select cheat One,
for instance,
here he can see here that I can also modify its name.
And it can also enable calculations or disabled them enable of format conditions,
calculations and other things.
So you can see how I can get a different properties off the sheet.
I can enable or disable pivot tables as well.
We've got different properties that weaken edit here on the worksheet.
And you can see here that there are two ways of actually arranging the properties,
either in an alphabetic way or in a categories way.
Okay,
so you can see here we can either arrange them in alphabetic order or put them into into
different categories.
But here,
actually,
we've got only one category for the worksheet object.
But actually,
both these stabs contained the same properties.
It's just that they are arranged differently.
Now,
if I select this workbook,
you can see here that the workbook has mawr properties to be modified than the worksheet.
And of course,
they are also arranged in two different ways either alphabetic or categories.
But both ways actually have the same properties.
Now,
if you need to change any other properties here on the properties window,
you can just go in and change it so you can go in and type,
for example,
changed the name often object,
or you consider act something formal dropped on menu here.
Okay,
so this is how you can change the properties of an object.
But actually,
most of the changes that were going to do to object properties were going to do them
through the code window through writing VB a code.
Okay.
And we will be discussing the code window on the next lesson.