Hey,
guys.
Welcome box In this video,
we're going to discuss the workbook.
New sheet events of the workbook.
New sheet event runs whatever code you put in it,
whenever you insert in you sheet so you can get it.
Of course,
by opening your VB editor,
double clicking on this workbook and from this man,
you're gonna select workbook.
And from this men,
you're gonna select new sheet.
So whatever he could you put in,
it will be run whenever you insert in.
You she So,
for example,
I could put a message box you have inserted in you sheet.
Okay,
so now whenever we insert in you sheet,
let's just inserting you sheet here because he here that the message box pops up,
you have inserted a new sheet,
and actually this code runs after the sheet is inserted.
So actually the sheet is inserted first,
and then the code runs.
Something else that we need to learn about is actually the S h parameter.
Okay.
And this H perimeter is basically a worksheet object,
and it refers to the worksheet this just been inserted.
Okay,
So something else that you can do is that you could give each new sheet inserted a number.
Okay.
So,
for example,
if we insert a new sheet in our case here because it's gonna be the fifth sheet in the
workbook,
it's gonna be assigned the number five.
So you can do this.
You could write.
Shh.
Stop Name equals this work.
Booked out worksheets dot count.
Okay,
so now is going to be given the number five,
or actually,
each sheet is inserted.
Is gonna be having a number that is gonna be equal to the number of worksheets that would
be available after inserting the new worksheet.
So,
for example,
us instead of a new sheet here in Syria,
has been given the number five.
That's instead of another one has been given a number six because it's the sixth.
And unless you insert 1/3 1 has been given the number seven because it's seven.
Okay,
so this is the workbook new sheet event.
I typically don't use that a lot,
But if there is something in your business or something in in your applications that you
would require it for its there,
you know how to use it.
Okay.
And if you find something that this event would be really useful for and you liked it.
Please let me know about it.
Let me know about what application you used it for.
I would be interested.
So that's it for the workbook.
You sheet.
Evan,
thank you very much.
Watching this video I'll see on the next.