this video,
We're going to discuss the workbook sheet calculate event so the workbook sheet calculate
event gets triggered whenever a calculation happens in any sheet on your workbook.
OK,
any sheet that would have calculations happen on it will trigger this event.
However,
if you,
for example,
change the value of a cell.
But that does not trigger any calculations,
this event will not be triggered.
Okay,
So,
for example,
if you enter your name in a cell and this does not require any calculations toe happen,
so there are no other cells.
The are reading your name from from that cell that you entered your name on and no
calculations are required than actually this event will not be triggered.
This event also has a parameter cold as h here as an object.
It's a sheet object,
and it actually refers to the sheet that the calculations happened on.
So let's have an example.
For example,
I'm just going to write a message box here that says calculations happened in.
I'm gonna put a space here,
and then I'm gonna close the double quotes.
I'm gonna have an M percent and concurrent innate that on s h dot name.
So actually is going to say calculations happened in sheet.
Whatever.
The name of the sheet is that the calculations happened on.
So,
actually,
let's try,
for example,
here in this sheet,
CI 28 I'm just gonna try writing my name here,
okay?
And this has not triggered the event because no calculations were needed when I entered my
name.
Even if I enter the number five year,
there are no other cells reading from that cell.
So no calculations air needed.
And this is why the event has not been triggered.
If I enter equals one plus one,
this will trigger calculation is says calculations happen in Cheat 28.
Ah,
very So.
Shh.
Actually refers to the sheet that calculation happened on if you even right equals two,
okay,
this for a sally's of formula.
And for that,
Excel will need to do calculations.
So this is going to trigger the event.
OK,
so,
actually,
as you can see here,
this triggered the event.
If you enter your name and there is another formula,
for example,
reading the cell or reading from the cell that you entered your name on this trigger
calculation so this actually will make the event got triggered.
So Ah,
that's it,
Guys for the workbook sheet calculate event.
I typically don't use it a lot because this event can actually slow down your workbook
because it's gonna run a lot if you use it.
Because pretty much any change that you do anything that you select world triggers and
calculations.
So this would run a lot and would slow down your workbooks.
They need to be using a very cautiously.
Okay,
you need to be careful if you're going to use it and make sure if you're going to use it is
the lost resort and that you've researched all the other options and that you absolutely
need to use it.
So thanks,
guys,
watching this video and I'll see you on the next one.