Hagos welcome backs on this video.
We're going to discuss the workbook sheet,
deactivate event.
So the workbook she deactivate event triggers whatever code you put in it.
Whenever you deactivate any worksheet on your workbook.
And also it has a parameter is called S H,
and this parameters Stipe is worksheet object.
And it basically refers to the worksheet that you have just deactivated.
She could have a message box,
for example.
Here you have de activated and then a space,
and then we're gonna come Canton eight.
That on s h dot name.
So now if I deactivated sheets all known,
she two.
If I activate T 28 for example,
is going to say you have deactivated she too.
So that s H dot name refers to the name off the sheet that's just been deactivated.
You could also may be put in if statement to make it run on Lee for a certain sheet.
So you could say if a ch dot name is equal to sheet to then and then we're gonna have an
end.
If so,
if the name of the sheet is equal to sheet too,
and that means the name of the sheep There's been deactivated,
Goes Shh.
Refers to the sheet that's just been deactivated.
So the name of the shed this just been deactivated is t two.
Then you would run the message box,
okay.
And make sure to write the name of the sheet with the same upper and lower case letters.
Because if you write the S at the beginning,
for example,
here of she to a small letter and here it's a capital letter,
it will not work.
So I'm gonna go to Xi to from she 28 you will see here that this code will not run because
the name of the deactivated cheat is not she too.
Okay,
But now,
because she to is the one that is active.
And if I deactivated,
the code is going to run because I put a condition that it would only run or the message
box,
I mean,
would only run if the name of the deactivated sheet is she to.
So you could do that.
Although,
actually,
you could just go ahead and write this code in sheet to in this sheet to events module here
,
have the select worksheet here and select deactivate on this way you can write whatever
could you want to write in?
The work should deactivate event for that specific sheet,
but,
you know,
sort of the way to do it.
And maybe you don't know the name with sheets.
Or maybe you have several sheets cold A have a having a certain ah prefix on them.
So maybe sales 1 may be Or and then there is,
ah,
sales to,
for example,
very sales to,
and sales three.
Okay.
And you want the code only to run.
If the the name of the sheet has the word sales in its weaken do that,
actually.
So this can be done by by doing what is called a wild card match.
Okay,
so this is something actually knew that we're gonna learn so you could write if it's h dot
name like and then you would open double quotes and then you would put an asterisk and put
the name the sheet that it would be like so its sales,
for example.
And this means that the name is going to contain sales in it,
and we're gonna put an Asterix assessed risk as well and then close the double quotes,
then maybe message box.
You have deactivated a sales sheets.
And actually,
when you do a wildcard match,
this uswest a day beginning means that the name,
the word sales could have something before it on this one means that the word sales could
have something after it.
But usually from searching for Ah,
a certain word I put put it as if it would have something before or something after it
could go more specific and ad only one of those two asterisks if you want.
So let's try that now if I deactivate any other sheets.
If I select cheat one,
for example,
actually,
of just the activity that a sell sheet which was sales ah three or sales to I don't
remember.
But anyways,
one sales sheet has been deactivated and this is why the message box has been triggered.
Okay,
and now if I deactivate this sheet one that does not contain the word sales in it,
nothing will happen.
OK,
but if I goto any other sales sheet and I deactivated and go to maybe sheet to hear from
sales 12 sheet too,
the code has been triggered,
so this will work with any sheet that has award sales in it,
for example.
Okay,
so this code is gonna work for any sheet that has the word sales.
Um,
I don't typically use this event a lot,
but if there's something that this event would prove useful for you to use it in,
please let me know.
I would be really interested to know it.
Okay,
so that's it,
Guys for the workbook sheet.
Deactivate event.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see on the next one.