Okay,
guys.
So now we're going to speak about the workbook window resize events of the workbook window
.
Resize event gets triggered whenever you try to resize a window in the workbook that the
event is written for.
So this event actually is written in the workbook ice cold workbook events.
Okay.
And I've got to windows open for it.
Now there's workbook events one and workbook events to.
Okay,
if I'm just selecting the windows,
nothing is gonna happen.
But if I try to resize them,
you can see here The message box that have written in the event husband trigger to your
window has been resized whenever he tried to resize it,
you know the event will be triggered.
OK,
but if we go to another totally different work,
Bushes is another workbook than the workbook that the event is written for.
This is called Book Four,
for example.
And now if I try to resize that one,
nothing happens.
The event will not be triggered because the event is written in this workbook module for
the workbook that is called workbook events.
I typically don't use it a lot at all.
Perhaps they've never used it.
Never needed to use it.
But there is an application that you would feel that it's suitable for Please let me know.
You know,
the if you if you use it and it works for you and there's something useful that you would
use it for,
Please let me know.
I'll be interested to know it.
Okay,
thanks,
guys,
for watching this video I'll see on the next one.