Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna have an exercise for the workbook events.
So we're going to create a workbook event in this workbook here called workbook Events that
pops on input box whenever you try to insert a new sheet.
And this input box would prompt you for the name that you would like to give to the new
sheet and then applies the name to the new sheet.
So here,
if I try to insert a new sheet,
you can see here I get an input box says please type the name that you would like to give
to the new sheet and then I can type any name,
maybe test click,
OK,
and the name is applied to the new sheet.
So this is the kind of functionality that you need you to create using workbook events.
Okay,
so please attempt exercise,
And if you get stuck,
you can have a look at the answer here in this exercise answer module.
Of course,
you need to copy the code to this workbook here to be able to run the event.
Okay,
so pleases them.
They exercise.
And if you have any questions,
please leave them in the Q and a section.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see on the next one