and this video,
we're going to discuss the immediate window and the locals window and the watch window,
which are tools to help us troubleshoot,
are coat and do air handling and debugging.
So,
first of all,
the immediate window,
you can view it by going to the view menu here and then clicking on the immediate window or
you compress control and G on your keyboard,
and the immediate window allows you to run code on the fly.
You can just type question mark and then,
for example,
I'm going to run a message box here.
I would say I'm just trying the immediate window,
and I'm just gonna close my brackets and press enter and then you can see here.
I'm going to get a message box pop up that says,
I'm just trying the immediate window.
And don't worry about the message box.
If you don't know what the message box is,
we're gonna explaining in detail in the future.
But I'm just demonstrating the ability of the immediate window to let you or to allow you
to run code on the fly.
The second window is the locals window,
so you can view the locals window by going to the view menu here at the top and then
clicking on locals window So the locals window allows you to see the names of your
valuables and the values and their types when you're running your macro step by step,
for example.
So this is useful in trouble shooting and debugging your macro,
and we will see that in the future when we go into the air handling section.
So this is a very useful window for troubleshooting and air handling.
The third window is the watch window,
and you can view the watch window by going to the view menu here and then clicking on watch
window.
So the watch window allows you to monitor expressions or variables,
and an expression is basically it can be like a formula containing multiple valuable,
so it allows you to monitor expressions not only variables,
and you can see their value on their type and their contacts as well.
And you speak about that later,
and it also allows you to stop running gear macro when your expression reaches a certain
value.
So when it reaches the value of true or when it reaches one or zero,
so you can determined that and said that up on the watch window.
OK,
so this is also very useful in troubleshooting and debugging your coat.
guys.
So that's it for the immediate and locals and the watch windows.
Thank you so much watching,
I'll see on the next one.