Hey,
guys,
welcome backs in this video.
We're going to see how we can deal with modules,
so modules air basically containers for your coat.
And in order to insert a new module,
you can go to this menu and click on the arrow and then click on module to insert a new
module.
You can also go to the insert menu here and then click on module and have now inserted a
new module and Excel or the V B.
A environment by default has named a module to okay,
and you can rename a module by selecting it,
and then the properties window for it will appear.
Then you can just delete its name and give it a new name.
I'll name it my module.
The name that you give it needs not to have any spaces,
and it needs not to be part off the reserved keywords or the reserve boards in V.
B.
A.
And actually,
there is a lecture listing their reserved words in V B A.
So you can check that,
and I can make an experiment here.
I can just put a space between Mayan module and hit enter,
and you can see here that this is not a legal object name.
Excel is not accepting it,
so I'll just rename it my module with no spaces.
That's great.
So I've renamed my module,
and you can also delete a module by right clicking on it and click on remove it.
Remove on so it will list.
Remove and then the name of your module.
So I'll just click on that.
And actually,
when you asked to remove it,
you can actually have the option to export it before you're moving it.
So maybe you wanna you want to save the V B A code,
and it maybe you want to have it,
because you might need this vb a code later on in a different workbook or so because you
can actually import it later,
and we will see how to do that.
So Excel gives you the option of exporting its.
It asked you whether you would like to export before you're moving it or not.
Let's say I want to export it.
If I don't want to exploit it,
I will click on no,
and then Excel will just delete it without saving it or exporting it.
So if I click on Yes,
because I want to,
Let's say,
Want to save the code I click on Yes.
And then,
actually,
I can save it.
I'll save it on my desktop Here should just save that.
Okay and Excel deleted it.
But I saved it before Excel deleted it.
So I do have the code.
If there had been code on this model,
it's actually a blank module on.
Let's say that I want to import it again.
I can click on this.
Click on this modules folder or right click on any module,
OK,
and then click on import foil and then I will select my module here and just double click
on it.
I'll click on it and click open on.
Then Excel will insert the module again into the V B.
A environment basically Okay,
This was just an overview about how to deal with the modules.
Thank you very much,
guys,
for watching this video and please follow me onto the next video