and this video,
we're going to start writing our first macro on.
Also,
we will get to know the range object in Excel.
So the range object in Excel is basically an object that allows us to deal with cells in
XlV b A and to start writing our first macro,
we need to first will go to Developer Tab on the ribbon here and click on visual basic.
And that's to open the visual basic environment.
Now,
to write a macro,
we need to insert a module first of all,
So to insert a new module,
we could go to this insert module to here,
click on this arrow and then click on module.
Okay,
we can also go to the insert tab on the ribbon and click on module.
so that's another way to do it.
Okay,
so now I'm going to start writing my first macro.
So to do that,
to start writing a macro,
first of all,
I need to give it a name.
So I need to write the word sub and then write the macron's name.
And the Macron's name should not include any spaces,
and he cannot contain dashes as well.
It can contain underscores so you can separate words with underscores.
But I'm just going to name it first macro.
Okay.
And then when I press enter,
I pressed Enter several times just to give myself some space.
And when a press enter XlV b A will insert the end sub statement which marks the end of my
macro.
At this end,
sub statement is going to be inserted automatically.
Now the macron's name cannot contain some certain words that are reserved in XlV B A.
I'll include a pdf in the resource is section about these words for you.
Okay,
so basically the sub statement and the name of the macro marks the start of my macro or sir
procedure and the end sub marks the end of my PSA procedure,
or macro,
and between the sub and the end sub statements,
I'm going to write Maher instructions.
I'm going to write some lines of codes that excel.
VB A will perform step by step from top to bottom.
So vve a will go through these instructions from top to bottom and execute them that way.
Okay,
so this is how instructions are executed in xlv b A.
There is sticky,
executed from top to bottom.
Of course,
you can move around in the macro by writing some special lines that we will learn about
later on in the course.
Okay,
so let's start dealing with the range object.
So,
first of all,
we're gonna learn how to change the value of a single cell,
OK?
And I'm gonna have the visual basic environment open here,
and you're gonna be able to see part of the Excel grid here and the background because
we're gonna perform actions here with the V b A environment,
and you're gonna be able to see the results of these actions in the background.
Okay.
So to change the value of a single cell,
you can write range,
then open brackets and then open double quotes.
And then you put the reference for the cell.
I'm going to change the value of cell a one,
Okay.
And then close double quotes.
And then I'm going to close parentheses year and then equals 15 for example.
Okay,
so I'm gonna put the value of 15 in cell a one.
So in order to run the macro,
we need to either click on this button here at the top,
which is the run button.
Or you can also hit F five on your keyboard.
So I'm gonna click on this button here,
and,
as you can see here,
the value of 15 husband inserted into cell a one.
Okay,
So if I need to affect actually a range of cells,
not just a single cell.
And this is actually for a contiguous range of cells.
We're gonna actually put a colon after the reference for the first cell and then put the
reference of the ending cell.
Okay,
So I'm gonna effect,
for example,
a 12 f Then,
I'm gonna put the value of 15 in range a 12 f done.
And this is actually how you can select a range of cells in Excel as well.
So in excel.
If you right here a 12 f done.
Okay,
You're gonna be able to select the whole range a 12 f done.
OK,
so if we execute this line of code here,
if I press on the run button here,
the cells a 12 f done are gonna be getting the value off 15.
Okay,
so to start writing another line of code.
You can just press enter on your keyboard.
I'm gonna press enter again because I like to have more than one line actually separating
my my lines of coat because this makes the readability easier for me.
But actually,
any space that you put between the lines of code will not affect your macro at all.
It will not affect its speed or execution at all.
Okay?
And I'm gonna start writing,
for example,
another line of code here.
So range,
then I'm gonna open parentheses,
open double quotes,
for example,
Jeanine,
and then closed.
Double coast close parentheses equals 150.
Okay.
And as you can see here,
even though I typed the word ranging all in uppercase excel actually corrected it and it's
made only the first letter is uppercase,
and the rest of the letters are lower case.
And even though also,
I have typed g nine,
the G in lower case,
this will not affect the execution of the code.
Okay,
So Excel was still understand that this is sell Jeanine.
So I'm gonna delete the values in these cells here,
and I'm gonna execute the code again.
Here So if I execute this code,
you can see here that all the cells from a 12 f done have acquired the value of 15.
And Celgene owing has acquired the value of 150.
Okay,
now,
of course,
as we stated earlier,
Excel has executed these lines of code step by step.
Okay,
so the first line here,
a one two F 10 equals 15 has been executed first,
and then the line G nine equals to 150 has been executed second or afterwards.
And of course,
you do not notice that because they're both executed in a flash.
Okay,
but just know that they are executed step by step,
okay?
They have not been executed together.
Actually,
this line of court has been executed first,
and then this line of code.
Okay,
so I've seen how to affect the value off a single cell.
And also,
we've seen how to affect the value of a contiguous range of cells.
We're going to see as well now how to affect the value of none contiguous cells.
OK,
so I'm going to leave these lines of code.
I'm gonna delete this,
Aziz.
Well,
here on my Excel grid,
and I'm gonna start affecting a range of none contiguous cells.
That means that the cells are not beside each other.
OK,
so I'm going to write range on,
then open parentheses,
open double quotes,
and then maybe l a one and then comma and then f done.
Okay.
And then close double quotes.
Close parentheses equals 1000.
Okay,
so this actually will put the value of 1000 in cells a one and F 10 but only in these two
cells.
Not this sells between them.
So if I run this code here for you,
press on my run button,
you can see year on,
sell a one and sell f done on Lee.
Only these two cells the value of 1000 has been put in these two cells on lee.
And actually,
the cells between them are still blank.
So this is how you can affect the values of none contiguous cells.
Okay,
so I want to show you as well that you can actually mix between a range of contiguous cells
and a single cell in one range objects statement here,
so you can write actually range a 12 f turn,
and then a comma,
and then f 15 equals 1000.
And what's gonna happen here when we run?
This statement is that sells a 12 F 10 are gonna acquire the value of 1000 and sell F 15 as
well is going to acquire the value of 1000.
So I'm gonna delete here the values on my Excel grid here,
and I'm gonna go back to my visual basic environment.
And when I click on the play button here,
what's what's gonna happen here?
You can see her cells a 12 F then have acquired the value of 1000 and sell F 15 as well has
acquired the value of 1000.
Okay.
And this is equivalent to actually writing that on two statements.
Okay,
so we can write range.
A 12 f turn equals 1000 and then range of 15 is equal to 1000.
So if we leave that and then run the code again,
we're going to get the same result.
Okay,
so if you run that,
we're going to actually get the same result here.
Okay,
guys.
So in this lecture,
we've written our first macro and We've had an introduction to the range object.
In the upcoming lectures.
We're going to dive deeper into the range object,
and we're gonna learn a lot more about it,
so Ah,
thanks,
guys,
for watching this video.
I know.
See on the next one.