Okay,
So in this lecture,
we're going to see how we can put a text in a cell using V B A and the range object.
Basically.
So I've created another macro here and ah,
name that.
My underscore texts.
And that's Ah,
away,
actually,
two separate different words and on a macro is name because you can't put a space between
two words,
but you can put an underscore,
but you can do a dash.
Actually,
an actual give you on errors.
If we try that my dash tax,
it will give give you an error.
So,
actually,
if you need to separate the two words,
you can put an underscore between them.
Okay,
so let's say you want to put my name as a text in cell A one.
so Britain money name here.
And then I'm gonna run this macro so it writes my name into the cell and you can see her
that I put my name between double quotes.
So that's kind of a rule in V B.
A.
If you need to write text,
it needs to be between double quotes,
because this is considered basically a string,
and we'll talk about the V b A data types later on.
But this is a string.
A text on a text needs to be put between double quotes.
So thank you guys for watching this lecture and please follow me onto the next one.