in this video,
we're going to see how we can deal with main drain jizz in our VB.
A coat and ah,
named range is a single cell or multiple cells that you can give a certain name to it.
And then you can refer to that single cell range of cells using that name instead of their
of the cells names.
They're saying C three or a three or C 32 d five.
You can name that my table,
for example,
and that just refer to it as my table.
OK,
so to create a name dreamed,
you can select yourselves first of all,
so you can select a 12 f then,
for example,
and then go to this name box here and then just Ah,
right,
my underscore table,
the all name at my table.
Okay.
And then a press enter.
So now my table refers to that range of cells.
So I've selected my table here from this drop down menu,
and then it's now referring to this range of cells.
I can put a value into this range of cells.
So put a 12 left in two b equals then and then I can write,
equals some,
for example.
And then I can hurt too.
Ah,
this strange is my table.
Instead of ah selecting this strange to be a a 12 F 10 or writing it as a 12 f them and
then if I hit enter it will give me the summation off that range of cells.
Okay,
on a range can be a single cells.
Well,
so you can select a single cell on Just name it,
ma.
You sell or whatever.
On duh you could you can apply a name to a single cell.
Okay,
so let's see how we condemn eel with named ranges in our V v a coats,
old elites that here how the have done.
And then I'll write a new macro.
So my names range.
Okay,
so it's a very simple you're we're just gonna write range and then open parenthesis is and
then open double quotes and then write my underscore table.
And you can see her that I've written it all in lower case and that won't make any
difference.
Is the name Dreams is originally having uppercase letters as the first letters on the two
words on my and table.
So actually have written it all in lower case and that I won't make any difference because
Excel will ignore the difference in the casing off the letters.
Okay,
so that one cause any problems.
So if I run the macro,
you will just put the value of 10 in all the cells in that range.
So it's very simple.
You write range and then open parentheses and then open double courts and you write the
name of the range and you called the courts and close parentheses.
And this is how you can refer to a name grease.
Okay,
so I thank you guys for watching this lecture and please follow me onto the next one.