in this video,
we're going to talk about the value and text properties for the range object,
and we'll see how the differ from each other case.
I'm gonna go to my vb a editor here.
I'm gonna insert in you module.
I'm gonna make a new micro's sub Molly value,
for example.
Okay,
so if I say range a $1 value by type that and then I put it equal to 12 and I run that it's
gonna put a one equals to 12 okay?
And actually,
the dot value property is the default property for the range objects.
As you've seen on the previous video on a previous video,
we ignored the dot value property and we just set a one equals to 12 and it would still put
a one equals to 12 or equals to the value that you've put after the equal sign.
Because the DOD value is the default property.
So if you omit the property the dot value property,
Excel will assume that you mean the dot value property when you write that statement.
Okay,
Now let's do something else,
which is just going to give this 12 a bit of formatting Okay,
so I'm going to make it $12 so the value is actually 12.
But how it looks is that it's $12 So this is how it appears to me.
But the actual value is 12.
And I'm just gonna verify that by writing a message box function,
and I'm gonna ask it to give me range a $1 value,
and we'll talk about the message box function later on.
But just for now,
you got to know that all it does is that it displays a message box and it gives you what's
inside the message box function.
So I'm going to run that and you'll see that a message box has popped up and it's got the
value for range a one.
So because of us,
for the value it gave me 12 because this is the value that's in cell a one.
However,
if I ask for the text So there's another property for the range object,
which is called the Tax.
It's gonna give you the actual text that's appearing to you.
So if I run that you can see here that has given me $12 because this is the text that's
appearing in the cell.
Okay,
so now we've seen how the value and the text properties differ from each other.
The value property gives you the value off the sell off.
What's inside the cell on Dad?
Actually,
the text property gives you the text that's appearing to you in the cell.
So that means that if you've got some formatting applied to the values off the cell,
it will actually give you the text,
which includes value and the formatting,
Basically.
And actually what you get as an output from the text property is basically a string.
So a text basically okay.
And we'll talk about strings and the data types of different data types in vb A later on.
So thank you guys for watching this video and please follow me on to the next.