in this video,
we're going to speak about the select method for the range object.
So the range dot select method.
What it does is that it's elects your range,
okay?
And that range could be either a single cell or actually multiple cells.
So I've created a macro here called Select Underscore Range.
And for example,
if I type range a one select and you can see here as I'm typing the word select,
Actually,
I'm getting suggestions year by this Oh,
to complete function in Excel V B A.
So you can see here that the select methods is gonna pop up here,
sport to the choices.
So if I click on the top key on my keyboard,
you can see here the of being able to select the select method.
And now,
if I run the macro what this method does,
is it simply select your range?
Okay,
so this is going to select cell a one.
So watch here,
sell a one when I click on run and concede here that sell a one has been selected.
You can also use the select method to select You're named range.
So remember guys,
when we created a named range cold.
My underscore table previously so that named range actually exists right now.
So when I run this,
it's going to select my named range,
which waas between cells.
A 12 afternoon.
Okay,
so this is simply a select method.
All it does is that it selects your range.
And this is an important method that you probably use a lot because you'd want to select to
sell and do stuff to it.
Okay,
so ah,
this is the select method remembers.
Select is a method because methods are actually verbs or something that you would do.
OK,
so you're doing something.
You're selecting your cell.
So that's why select is a method.
Okay,
so thank you guys for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.