Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the range dot address property.
So the range thought address,
property.
What it does is that it outputs the address off a range,
and it has actually some arguments.
But all these arguments or all these inputs are optional.
Okay,
all of them are optional.
So even if you don't enter these inputs,
the range that address property is still gonna work because these inputs will get some
default values case off created and macro here,
or a PSA procedure called range Underscore address and let's have an example.
So all right,
range a one dot address.
And actually,
if we just run that it will still work.
But if you open parentheses,
you will see the arguments or the inputs that you can enter into the range,
start address property,
and is because year all the inputs they do have square brackets around them,
and that means that they are optional.
So any input that you see the house square brackets around,
it means that it's optionally.
You do not have to provide it,
okay?
And if you don't provide any of these inputs,
they will got some default values,
and you can know the default values that each input gets.
If you search this on the Microsoft Directory Network,
you search for the range dot address property.
Google that,
and you will know it.
You can actually highlight that and press F one on your keyboard.
And this will take you to the page explaining it on the Microsoft directly network case.
As you can see here,
this is the range dot address property in Excel.
And you can see here that there is an explanation for each input and what the default value
would be if you do not input a value for any of these inputs.
Okay,
they will get some default values,
and this is all explained here.
Okay,
so back to our range dot address property.
The first input here,
the row absolute.
This stakes values of either true or false.
Okay.
And if this takes a value of true,
what's gonna happen,
is that the rope part off the reference for yourself.
So here the reference for your cell is a one.
The rope part,
which is the one is gonna be absolute.
And that means that is gonna have a dollar sign before it.
You know,
about absolute and relative references in Excel.
This is actually one of the basics in excel.
So if you could give this a value of true the rope part of your self reference will have a
dollar sign before it.
And before the column,
Absolute as well.
If you give this a value of true,
the column part will have a dollar sign before it as well.
And actually you can either put a value of true or you can also put a one okay,
And you couldn't put a false or you can put a zero.
Okay,
so one is equivalent to true,
and zero is equivalent to false as well.
Says say,
I'm gonna put the rule absolute to be true or one and the condom absolute to be true or one
as well.
And if you put this inside a message boxes but this inside a message box and see what we
get,
we're gonna actually get dollar sign,
a dollar sign one.
So the whole reference for the cell is gonna be absolute.
So if you run that you can see here We got dollars on a dollar sign one day.
And if we,
for example,
make the calm absolute a false or a zero,
that means that a column part which is the A in the cell reference,
a one is not gonna have a dollar sign before it was gonna be a dollar sign.
One if you run that can see that.
Okay,
of course,
if we put that as a zero is going to be just a one without any dollar sites,
OK,
so you got the idea is just it controls how the address is displayed and whether the rope
part or the column part our absolute or relative.
So this is what the role absolute and the column Absolute inputs control.
Okay,
so if you put another comma and we go to our third import or third argument because here
the third impetus called reference style as Excel Reference stall and it takes.
Actually,
two values either excel a one or excel are one C one on these air.
Basically the two ways that you can refer to the Excel cells in excel.
Okay,
so the excel a one is basically the very common way of referring to cells,
which is a one a two c one c two d one d do d to ah,
the excel are one C one style is on obsolete style of referring to cells.
It's not used by 99% of the Excel users and just don't want it,
you know,
dive deep into that sorority.
I don't wanna confuse people,
so I'm not gonna dive deep into that.
You just stick to the Excel a one style OK,
which is the common style that everybody uses.
And this is actually the default value for this inputs.
If you don't give this input any value,
it will default to excel a one which is actually what's required because this is the style
used by 99% of the Excel users.
Okay,
so now if we had another comma here,
we will go to the external input for the range dot address property,
and this impotent takes values of either true or false.
And if it takes a value of true than what's gonna happen is that it's going to display the
full address for the range,
including the workbook reference and the worksheet reference as well.
Okay,
so that's put that as a true or one Okay,
so true.
And one are the same basically.
And if you close the brackets and we will close the brackets for the message box as well
and we run that you will see here that we get actually the full address for the cell.
A one.
Okay.
So you can see here it says range,
object of excels and which is the name of my workbook.
And then sheet one,
which is the name of the sheet.
Okay.
And then the reference for the Sella's.
Well,
okay,
so this is the full reference,
including the workbook and the worksheet references,
and probably won't use that.
Ah lot.
But they just wanted you to know what it does.
OK?
And of course,
if you put a fool's for it,
if you put a zero,
then he well,
just display the cell reference.
And this is actually the default value.
So if you don't put anything on that external input than it will just get the value of
false OK,
so moving on to the relative to import this relative to imp,
it actually is only used when you put the reference style input to be R one C one which is
actually the obsolete way of referring to excel cells that 99% of the Excel users do not
use.
So I'm not gonna go into that,
okay?
Because you probably won't use it a toll,
so I won't go into that.
Okay,
so the two inputs that you're gonna use most frequently are actually the role absolute.
And the column absolute.
And we've explained them.
And actually,
if you don't put any values in them,
they will default,
too.
True.
That means that both of them will be absolute.
So the row and the calm references will both be absolute.
So if you just write range a $1 address,
Even if you don't write the brackets,
this will default to true.
Okay,
So if I don't write the brackets,
even for the range that outers property and just want to write that inside a message box,
you can see here that we get both the row and the column to be absolute.
Okay,
so I want to show you something else as well.
If you write a one to C six for example dot address.
Okay.
And if you run that actually,
the role absolute and the common absolute will default to.
True.
That means you've got a one to C six old absolute,
the row and the column references,
OK?
And of course,
if you just put both as fools the role absolute in the column.
Absolute.
Okay.
And you run that again Here,
you'll see here that you get them as relative the e one to C six old.
The whole reference is relative.
OK,
so just to wrap up what the range dot address property does is that it outputs the address
for the range that you use it on.
And,
of course,
you need to know the difference between absolute and breath of references in Excel.
To be able to understand that range dot address property fully.
And if you don't know the difference between the absolute and relative references in exiled
recommended,
watch a video on it or read the article or something,
it should be part of the basics of Excel.
And if you're taking a V b A course and he should be an intermediate to advanced user,
but you could watch a video on absolute versus relative references on YouTube or something
to be able to understand that fully.
OK,
so thanks guys watching this video and I'll see you on the next one