Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about this.
Sells collection,
object.
So the cells collection object is a collection object that allows us to deal with cells
just like the range object.
However,
we do that in a different way because instead of providing the name of the cell like a one
a two b one b two c three,
we actually provide the row number and the column number for the cell.
Because the intersection of a certain row and a certain column I would give us a cell.
Right?
So this is how we deal with the cells collection object.
Instead of providing the name of the cell,
we actually provide the row number and the column number for the cell.
Okay,
so let's have an example here,
suggests a I right cells.
And then I opened some brackets,
okay.
And you can see here we've got to imports the row index and the column index,
and actually,
they are both optional because you can see they have got square brackets around them.
However,
we actually need to input the row index and the column index because this is the only way
to refer to a certain cell.
And even though they are optionally needs,
you need to be impotent because if you don't import them,
then you're referring to all the cells in your sheet.
So,
for example,
for right cells don't select it with or without the brackets.
This will actually select all the cells in my sheet,
as you can see here.
So back to our cells collection objects.
So if I write sells one comma,
two duck value equals 50.
So this will actually put the value of 50 in the cell that is in the first row.
And in this second column,
that means is gonna be Selby one.
So if you run,
that can see here,
the Selby one has acquired the value off 50.
So basically,
as you've seen here,
we needed to specify which sell we needed to deal with,
because the cells collection object contains all the cells.
So when use it,
if you need to deal with a certain cell,
you need to actually specify which sell you are dealing with.
What more thing I'd like to tell you about the cells collection object is that you're
dealing with cells just like what you were doing when you were using the range object.
So actually,
most of the methods on properties that we've explained when we were explaining the range
object are actually going to be applicable to the cells collection object as well,
because at the end of the day,
you're also dealing with cells,
right?
So because both the range object and the cells collection object the deal with cells,
they will have the same methods on properties.
Okay,
so someone would ask a question here if the cells collection object does the same thing as
the range object which is dealing with cells,
why would we bother to learn about it?
So actually,
in the future,
when we learn about variables which are basically containers of data so each variable can
contain some data and this data could be a number,
you could have a variable X here in the row number in the cells collection object with Roe
index,
and this variable could have its value changing,
especially if you're using a loop,
for example,
and a loop is basically you can think about it as laps around a track or rotations around
the track.
So in the first rotation,
the value of X could be one.
And then on the second rotation,
the value of X could be,
too.
And then on the third rotation,
the value of X could be three and so on and so forth.
And actually,
when the value of exchanges this means that you will be dealing with different cells,
right,
goes sells.
One comma,
too,
is different than cells to calm a two.
And that's different than sells three comma two right?
So when the value of exchanges the cell that you're dealing with changes.
So basically the fact that the cells collection object except numbers and you can plug in
variables in the cells collection object,
this gives it a lot of power,
and this will be clearer.
Actually,
as we progress through the course and when we reach the variable section,
we explain variables.
But I just wanted to highlight the power and the potential off the cells collection object
.
It is truly powerful.
One more thing I'd like to tell you about this sells collection object is that you can
actually input the column index as the column letter.
So instead of importing the number for the column,
you could put the letter for the calm.
So,
for example,
if I write cells one comma,
see?
But you actually need to write the letter in between double quotes,
this will refer to cell C one.
Okay,
so if I run that he could see her.
That cell C one has been given the value off 50.
Okay,
I So that's it for the introduction to the cells collection object.
We will speak more about it in depth as we progress through the course.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see you in the next one.