Alright,
guys.
So now in this section,
we're going to start dealing with worksheets.
So we're gonna learn how to deal with worksheets,
and the first thing we're gonna learn is actually selecting worksheets.
Okay,
So when you're selecting worksheets,
if you need to select a certain sheet,
you actually need to call the worksheets collection and then tell Excel which sheet you
would like to select.
So here I'm gonna call the worksheets collection object and then tell the worksheets
collection object.
The I need sheet one from that collection.
Okay,
is we have described before in the introduction lecture on how the syntax of BV a works.
So here there is a collection you're gonna call one member of the collection,
which is sheet one,
and then you're going to write dot select.
So this is a method select is a method,
So this will make you select sheet one you can see here.
I've got two sheets in this workbook sheet.
One and she too.
So I'm gonna actually select she to here,
and then I'm going to run this code,
and this will select sheet one,
as you can see here.
Okay,
guys.
So now we've seen how we could select a worksheet with the work she dot select method.
But I actually wanted to show you something else about the select method as well,
which is that there is a parameter in the select method cold replace.
And I'm here on the page for the worksheets dot select method on the Microsoft Directory
Network,
which I actually got by Googling because highlighting it in the V B a editor and pressing F
one did not get me to that page for some reason.
But I just googled worksheet dot select method MST in and I was able to get that so you can
see her there is actually a replaced parameter.
What this replaced parameter does is that it allows us to select several sheets at the same
time.
So remember,
guys,
parameters are like adverbs.
They actually describe how the verb is done.
So this is actually going to describe how the dot select method,
which is considered a verb,
you know,
as we're mimicking the structure of the English language,
is we've explained before,
So the replaces going to describe how the dots select method is going to be done.
Okay,
so if you put replace equal to false.
This means that there is not going to be a replacement when you do another selection.
So that means that you're going to select multiple sheets at the same time.
But if you put it equals to two than that means that you will not be selecting multiple
sheets at the same time and is actually this true is the default value for the replace
parameter.
Okay,
so let's go back to the visual basic environment and see that in action.
guys,
so we're back to the visual basic environment.
So let's say I want to select she to in addition to sheet one at the same time so it can
actually select two sheets at the same time.
You could do it in the Excel environment.
If you press control,
you know,
select one sheet press control and select the other one year in a select two sheets at the
same time.
So we want to be able to do that in visual basic as well.
I'm just gonna Owen group them to be able to just select sheet one.
So let's say I wanna select she to.
In addition to sheet one.
So I'm going to write worksheets she to dot select And then I'm gonna press space and I'm
gonna write the replace parameter,
so I'm going to write,
Replace colon equals false.
Okay,
So the replace parameter when you said it equal to false,
you're gonna actually be able to select both these sheets at the same time.
So actually,
the first selection is gonna happen on then the second selection will have the parameter
replace equals two false.
And that means that it's gonna happen in addition to the first selection.
So if you run that,
you consider that both sheets have been selected at the same time.
So if you actually add 1/3 sheet,
you can also select it this way so you can select the three sheets at the same time.
So if you add a line so I'm just gonna copy that and just replace it with she three,
you can select the third sheet as well.
So if you keep adding the selection lines with replace equals two false,
you're gonna be able to select that particular sheet in addition to the sheets previously
selected.
Okay.
And of course,
if we put to replace equals two true than your sheet will not be selected in addition to
the other sheets,
but it's actually equals two.
True,
by default,
if you're gonna set a equals the true,
you're not gonna write it,
right?
But if you run that with,
you know,
without putting the replace or by putting the replace equals true,
then actually it will just select sheet one and then selectively to But when When it
selectively to is gonna de select sheet one and then whose election three And when it
selects C three is gonna de selection too.
So that means that in the end,
you will just have she three selected because it's just in a selected one and then select
you to and then selection three.
We can run a actually step by step by pressing f eight.
So here,
if you run,
that line of code is gonna select sheet one,
and then if you run,
the 2nd 1 is going to actually to.
And then if you won,
the third one's just gets the luxury three.
So it just selects them exclusively.
So the newly selection sheet does not get at it to the old cheat So that's it for the
worksheets start select method.
This is one of the basic things that you will need to learn when dealing with sheets,
which is how you can select sheets.
Okay,
thank you very much watching this video and I'll see on the next one.