Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about how we can add sheets to our workbook.
So,
basically,
to add sheets to your workbook,
you can type sheet,
start,
aunt,
and you can also alternatively type worksheets dot Add as well.
So worksheets start ad will add sheets and sheets.
Thought ad will also add sheets.
And we will actually explain the difference between the worksheets collection and the
sheets collection on the next video.
Okay,
so don't worry about that at the moment.
Now,
if you write sheets,
start,
add and then press space on your keyboard.
Ah,
bunch of parameters are gonna appear here on the tool tip you could.
Also,
instead of pressing space,
you could open a bracket and these parameters air going to appear as well.
And then you can write your parameters and close brackets,
and you're gonna be able to add sheets.
Okay,
so let's say we typed sheets dot ad and then we press space.
You'll have some parameters here that will appear for you.
So we've got the first parameter here.
The before parameter.
The before parameter allows you to add a sheet before a certain worksheet okay or before a
certain sheet.
So you will actually give that parameter the reference of the worksheet that you need to
add the new sheet before it.
So let's say we want to add the new worksheet before she too.
So we would write worksheets and then she to in the value for the before parameter.
And then if we press comma,
if you type a comma here on your keyboard,
you will go to the after parameter,
which works exactly as the before parameter,
except that you will actually give the reference of the sheet that you need to insert the
new sheet after it.
OK,
but you cannot actually use the before and after parameters at the same time.
So it's either the before or the after,
but you can't use both.
At the same time,
you will get an error,
so if you put another comma,
you will go to the count parameter and the count parameter takes a number,
and this number indicates how many sheets you want to insert.
So if you put you know one,
you will have one sheet inserted and one is the default value.
If you put too,
you will have two sheets inserted and so on and so forth.
So let's say we're gonna put a to here so that we can answer two sheets at the same time.
And then if you put another comma,
you will go to the type parameter,
which we will explain in a bit.
Okay,
So don't worry about it at the moment,
I'll just remove the comma for it here.
And you can also see that all the parameters here are optional because they all have square
brackets around them.
And that means that you do not have to provide these parameters for the sheets,
that ad or the worksheets dot ad method to work.
Okay,
so we've written it this way,
and this sheet start add line of code will actually add two sheets before she too.
So if you run that,
you will have two sheets added before she too.
So on the left hand side of she to actually sheet for and she five have been added.
As you can see here,
however,
if you type your code this way,
it will not be easy undescended ble for other people who read your code because people do
not normally memorize the order off the different parameters.
So you're here.
You haven't specified your parameters explicitly.
Okay,
so it's a better coding practice.
It's a better practice to actually explicitly specify your parameters.
So to write,
for example,
before colon equals work she cheat to on.
Then you would write a comma,
for example,
and then count colon equals to.
So this way,
whoever reads your code will understand that you're trying to add some new sheets.
Okay,
one sheet or more.
You're trying to add them before she too.
And you're trying to add two sheets.
Okay,
so anyone who reads this goat is gonna be able to understand what you are trying to do.
So it's a better coating practice in general to explicitly specify your parameters.
This way with the colon equals and remember,
guys,
parameters are like adverbs.
They explain how the verb is done.
Okay,
So the verb here is the ad.
The ad method is considered are verb,
and our adverbs are before and the count they describe how the method or the verb is gonna
be done.
Also,
one of the benefits of explicitly specifying your parameters is that you do not have to
type them in the same order as the order specified on the sheet.
Start add method.
So,
for example,
here we could write the count parameter before the before parameters would write.
Count equals two comma before equals worksheets.
She too.
So this way the macro will work as well.
So if you run that,
we will have two sheets instead of before she to here on the left hand side of the sheet to
and actually outer sheet four on the right hand side of sheet for.
So if you run that,
you will see here that sheet six and cheat seven have been inserted before she to.
Okay,
so that's another benefit of explicitly specifying your parameters that you do not have to
right thumb in the same order that is specified by the method.
Okay,
so let's move on to the type parameter.
So we're gonna write type calling,
equals on,
then actually to have a list of the she types you're going to write excel sheet type,
and then a dot and then you will have the options for the different she types that you can
insert.
Okay,
there is actually something called the chart sheet,
Okay.
And if you run that,
we'll actually have to charge sheets inserted before she too.
So they're gonna be inserted on the left hand side of she too,
And on the right hand side of sheet six.
So,
as you can see here to charge,
sheets have been inserted,
and this is actually reflected when you right click on any sheet and click on insert,
you will have the different cheat types that you can insert here.
There's a chart cheat.
There is a macro sheet,
so there is actually on option to insert a macro sheet as well.
So except she type,
there is a democracy which you probably have never used.
And we don't use these regularly.
Charge cheetahs well,
is really used.
But I just thought of letting you know that there is an option to do that in v B A.
Okay,
so now you know how you can select a different she type.
The default value is actually excel worksheet.
So that means that if you don't specify the type and as we've seen before,
the default she type is the normal worksheet that we are all familiar with.
Okay,
guys.
So Let's see how we conduce something else.
I'll just comment this line of code so that you would not be executed.
And something else that we can do is that we can actually insert in you sheet before the
very first sheet in the workbook.
And the very first sheet in the workbook is actually the sheet on the very left hand side.
So remember guys,
when we were speaking about one way off selecting an object from a collection which is
using its index number,
and we said that this is not a very favorable way of doing it.
When we were speaking about the example of kicking the first bowl,
regardless of what the bull is.
And if the bowling bowl is the first bowl on the very left hand side,
then this is actually gonna hurt right or something is gonna go wrong.
So here we're actually going to do that.
We're actually going to select a sheet based on its position,
okay?
Not based on its name.
So we're actually gonna add a new sheet before the very first sheet on the workbook,
which is the sheet on the very left hand side.
We're gonna write sheets start,
add and they're gonna put a space and then before colon equals sheets and then open
brackets and then one and then close brackets.
Okay,
so this means that actually,
we're gonna add a new sheet before the very first worksheet in the workbook.
And the very first worksheet is the sheet on the very left hand side.
So if you run that,
you will see here that sheet eight husband inserted before she three which was the very
first sheet on the workbook Are the sheet on the very left hand side on?
Of course,
Onley One sheet has been inserted,
although we haven't specified the count because the default value for the count is one.
Okay,
OK,
something else that you can do.
Another Turk that you can learn is actually to add a new worksheet after the last
worksheets in your workbook.
OK,
so the last worksheet on your workbook is the sheet on the very right hand side here of
your workbook.
So to add a new worksheet after,
we're gonna use the after parameter and we're actually here to specify the number we're
gonna use the sheets,
start count property,
right,
Because the sheets dot count property will yield the number of sheets that are in our
workbook.
OK,
And this will work regardless of the number of sheets.
So this is something that will make it dynamic.
When use the sheets start count because you're always guarantee that in you sheet will be
added after the last worksheet on your workbook,
which is the sheet on the very right hand side of your workbook.
And you could make it the before as well.
So this will make and you should be added in the place just before the last one.
Okay,
all the time.
So if you run that,
you will see here that a new sheet will be added after the lost worksheet in your workbook
.
And if you're running again,
sheet knowing has been added.
So if you're on again,
you will see she done added after it and so on and so forth.
Okay,
so this will add in you worksheet to your workbook in the very last position,
which is in the position on the very right hand side,
regardless off the number of sheets on your workbook.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys on how to add worksheets.
Thank you very much watching this video and L c on the next one