and this video,
we're going to see how we can move sheets using XlV b A.
So to move sheets in xlv b A You could write the name of the worksheet,
so worksheets sheet one dot move and there is actually a before or after parameter that you
I need to put if you need to move it in the same workbook.
OK,
so let's say work seat seat,
one dot move,
and then it's going to be put after calling equals worksheets.
She too.
Okay,
so this is gonna move sheet one to be put after she too.
And that is to the right hand side of she too.
So if you run that you can see here that sheet one has been moved to be after she to or to
its right hand side.
If you remove the before or after parameters,
what's gonna happen is that it's gonna be moved to a new workbooks in your workbook will be
created,
and sheet one is gonna be moved to it.
So if you run that,
you can see her sheet one has been moved to a new workbook.
And then you could take that workbook,
Do whatever you want with it,
And we will learn about workbooks shortly in the course.
Okay.
So Ah,
thank you very much,
guys,
for watching this video.
I'll see you on the next one.