Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about variables.
So what is a variable?
A variable is basically something that gets its value changed over and over again in your
macro or in your procedure.
Okay,
so at some point in your procedure,
its value could be a one.
So,
for example,
let's say we would have a variable named X the value of X at the beginning of the procedure
or the macro could be one.
And then during running the macro,
it can become a two and then a three and then a five and then a seven.
You know,
its value can change over and over again.
While you are running your macro,
you can think about it as basically a bucket that you put a value insight,
okay.
And this value can change over and over again while running your macro.
So why would that be useful or beneficial?
Like,
why would I use variables?
I'm gonna show you a simple problem,
and we will use variables to solve that problem.
And you will basically discover how useful variables are.
So basically this say we've got a rectangle.
Okay,
We can recall from studying basic math in school that the area over rectangle is equal to
length.
The length of their Tanger multiplied by the width okay on the perimeter is equal to two
multiplied by the length plus the width,
so it add the length past with and then multiply that by two to get the perimeter off a
rectangle.
So let's say I want to display the area on my rectangle here in Selby to and I want to
display the perimeter on my rectangle in cell C two under this header here names perimeter
in Cell C one.
So let's say that the length off my rectangle is equal to two on the wits is equal to three
.
Okay,
so I can say range.
Be too.
So I want to display the area in Selby to it and say Range V two is equal to the length,
which is two and then the with,
which is three.
And I can also say to display my perimeter that the range C two is equal to the length is
two and the with his three.
So that's two by two plus three cases.
It's two multiplied by two plus three Okay,
so the area is going to be a six,
and then the perimeter is gonna be a 10.
So if you run this macro,
you can see here that the area has been displayed in Selby to its six,
and the perimeter is 10.
So let's say I want to calculate the area on the perimeter of a different rectangle.
But this time the length is four and the with IHS five.
So what I need to do is to change here the values of the length on the wit.
Okay,
so the length is four.
And with this five,
So I'm changing the values here of the length and the width.
And if I run this macro,
Okay,
you can see here the area has become 20 and the perimeter has become 18.
so say I want to calculate the area of 1/3 rectangle.
The different rectangle.
The length is three,
and the width is four.
I will need to change the values here again and change the lens to be a three and the wits
to be a four.
And then I would run my macro and get my results.
So you see,
every time I need to calculate the area of a different rectangle.
I will need to change the values here in several locations.
So I need to change it in the formula for calculating the area on.
I will need to change it also in the equation for calculating the perimeter.
Okay,
so this is not very efficient,
right?
Because I need to change it several times.
So how about I can use a way to change it just one time?
Okay.
So I can create a variable called El for length on I can put it equal to two.
For example.
Let's say want to calculate the area and the perimeter for a rectangle that has a length of
two and the width of four.
So I can put this equal to two and with equals to four and can also change it in the
equation here so I can make it l by W and then also here to multiple by l plus w.
You can see here that now the equations are referencing the variables,
the length and the width.
So whenever I need to change the variables,
I will need to change them in on Lee.
One location or whenever I need to calculate the area of a different rectangle,
I will need to insert the length and the width in only one location.
So I will need to do it here once Onley length equals two with e equals four.
If I run this macro,
you can see here that the area is eight and the perimeter is 12.
Okay,
so now we need to change.
The only ones to say length is five with the six.
Now,
if around this macro I can get the area and the perimeter here on the left sequence here I
you'll need to only change it once.
I don't have to change it several times.
So imagine that you've got lots off sentences are lots of lines of code referencing your
variables.
You can just make only one change on this change will be reflected in all the lines of code
are on the sentences referencing these variables.
That's a very simple example.
You will see the power of variables.
They're much more powerful than that.
But this is basically,
like a very simple use off variables why they would be useful.
This guy's was just ah,
simple introduction to variables and we will go much deeper in the upcoming videos.
Thank you very much for watching this video on.
Please follow me on to the next video.