Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're gonna learn how to declare variables,
and we're gonna have a demonstration off the different variable data types.
So basically,
in order to declare a variable,
you just right the word dim.
And then let's say I wanna name my variable my var,
for example,
And then you write as and then you're gonna have here a menu pop up so you can start typing
the type of the variable.
This menu pops up a sport of the intelligence or the auto complete feature in Excel.
Viva.
So let's say I'm going to declare my variable as a bite,
for example,
So it's gonna be the bite data type,
and you could see here that as a type bite,
it started to get selected from this intelligence menu.
So then you compress stab on your keyboard,
the top key on your keyboard,
and you can see here that excel,
even adjust the casing so as to make the word dim have the D as a upper case as an
uppercase letter and the word bite as well.
So now,
actually,
we have reserved an amount of space in the computers Ram or the computer's memory for a
variable called Molly Var.
Okay,
so we have told the computer that we want to reserve on amount of memory for this variable
and because it's type is going to be a bite than it's gonna take only one bites in memory.
So now what we need to do is to actually populate the variable that is called my var.
With the value it is now ready to receive a value.
So in order to give it a value,
you can just write my var and then equals and then give it a value.
So you need to actually give it a value between zero and 255 because this is the allowable
range.
So let's say I give it a value of zero now if I run my macro step by step.
So I'm gonna press F eight on my keyboard to run it step by step,
and you can see here that the value of my var is equal to zero.
After this step is executed,
the value of money of our is equal to zero because this is the value off put in it.
You can see here this balloon appearing when I hover over it and note as well that if you
give the my var a value that is outside the allowable range.
So to say I'm going to give it 256 because it's type is a bite.
And you can see here that the allowable ranges between 0 to 255 and the number must be an
integer.
Then you're gonna actually get an error.
So if we run this macro,
we're going to get an error is called the Overflow Error,
and it indicates that you have given the variable e value that is outside it's allowable
range.
So you need to make sure that your variable receives a value that is within its allowable
range at all points in your procedure.
Now I want to also create another variable.
I'm gonna call it Molly of r two,
and I'm going to make it as bullion,
for example,
and you could see her as a start typing Boolean.
It starts to appear on the intelligence feature or the auto complete feature here.
When I press tab here,
you can see her that Excel has completed the sentence and one more advantage off declaring
your variables is that usually excel will use the intelligence feature to try and predict
which variable you're trying to type.
However,
sometimes it does not work.
So if I try to take my var normally,
Excel should give me some suggestions.
But if it doesn't work,
you compress control and space on your keyboard,
and you can see here that I'm getting some suggestions and I'm getting actually the first
to suggestions are correct.
So it's suggesting that I want to type my varro my var to so actually on your computer.
It could work without pressing control and space.
But if it doesn't work,
just press control in space and you're going to get some suggestions.
This is one MAWR advantage off declaring variables.
So because it's a bullion when I press equals X,
l will predict that I'm either gonna put a value of true or false.
There is no other value because brilliant only accepts true or full.
So it's going to give me suggestions here in case of the bullion because it can easily
predict the values it's either two or falls.
There is no other option.
So if I select true,
for example,
and I press tab on my keyboard.
Now,
if I run this macro,
consider mal ivories.
255 have replaced its value so as not to get an error.
And my var two is equal to true.
Now,
when I run this line of code on,
I'm running it step by step using the F eight key on my keyboard.
Now,
of course,
if you give the my var to variable a value other than true or fools,
you are going to get an error as well.
Okay,
guys.
So I've actually declared another variable called my date,
and its type is gonna be a date because I want to show you how to write dates in XlV.
Be a now we could,
right?
My date is equal to now in order to right dates and xlv A.
There are several ways to do that.
One way is to press the pound key on your keyboard,
which is by pressing shift and three and then you write the date.
But it needs to be in the American format.
So if we want all right.
The fifth of June,
for example,
is gonna be,
06 slash o fire 2016 for example.
And then we close with another pound sign and I'm actually going to write that in Cell E
too.
So I'm gonna write this state and Celie too.
So if you run this macro,
you can see here that the date husband written this is the fifth of June and actually it
appears here in the international or British format because my computer is formatted this
way.
My computer is formatted according to the international system,
not the US system.
So even though I have written it using the U.
S system,
it's appeared it on my excel as the international system.
Because this is how my computer is formatted.
If your computer is formatted as the U.
S system is going to appear as the U.
S.
System,
so that is one way off.
Writing dates another way is to use the dates value function and the date value function
accepts the date as a string or as a text,
so you need to put it between double quotes and you can just type the date as a text and it
can accept actually,
the date in several ways.
So,
for example,
12 of Gen 12 John 2016 this one is gonna work.
And 12 Jan Comma 2016.
This one is gonna work as well gives you the same result.
Okay,
so it can recognize several ways of writing the date as a text.
And even if I right here,
like the international format,
So 12 01 2016 is going to recognize it as well,
and it's gonna put it correctly in the cell.
However,
the way for writing dates,
the I would recommend the most is actually the date serial function,
because this avoids any confusion on how to write dates.
Because sometimes if the computer is formatted in the U.
S.
System and you writing the date in the international system,
or vice versa,
this could cause issues.
However,
the date serial function is actually the best way of writing dates in XlV b A.
And I would recommend you use that whenever you can try to stick to that one all the time
because it simply takes three inputs the year on the month and the day as integers.
So you put the year for example,
2016 comma.
The month is gonna be January 01 And then today the 12 of January,
for example,
let's actually delete this one first.
Go back to the visual Basic Editor.
If you run that,
you will have your date type correctly.
So my recommendation always stick to the date serial function for typing dates in xlv.
B A.
Now,
in this lesson,
we're not gonna try every data type because some data types,
for example,
the long and the single on the double are just gonna work normally,
as long as you give them values within their ranges.
Okay,
so we're trying to discuss the data types that could potentially cause you issues,
and that could be a bit tricky.
Okay,
so I've also declared another variable called my string here as a string and then we can
actually take My string is equal to Joe,
for example.
So now the variable my string is gonna be equal to Joe and weaken Display that in a message
box message box.
My string.
So if you run this macro here,
we're gonna have a message.
Boxes.
Well,
pop up with my string and actually know Did the message box function,
and we'll speak about in detail later on in the course.
But it does,
except the string data type.
So you need to make sure that you're putting a string in the message box,
and it can actually,
if you're displaying the number,
it will automatically convert it to a string data type.
So if the number is an integer data type,
for example,
in most of the cases it will do an automatic conversion and converted automatically to a
string data type.
So the problems do not arise often.
But you just need to know that it should accept a string.
But we're gonna discuss it later on in detail as well.
Now,
the string variable that we have just declared here is actually a variable length,
so that means it can accept pretty much any length for the string.
So 0 to 2 billion characters.
It's a lot,
so pretty much any length.
If you needed to be limited,
you just Stipe a star.
And then,
for example,
I'm gonna make it limited to two characters.
If you run that,
you're not going to get an error.
You just gonna have the E for Joe shaved off Okay,
so it's gonna be J and O only because it will only allow two characters.
But for all practical purposes,
you're usually not going to see people declare the string variable as a limited string.
It's gonna be just a variable strings.
So you're not going to see this store and then the number for practical purposes,
you're very rarely going to see that people are not going to do that.
Usually when you see a string variable declared,
it's just gonna be a variable string which is just dim the name of the variable,
my string as string on that seat.
Now I've created another procedure here called variant data.
Time to explain the variant data type and the very in data type is simply just a jack of
all trades.
It can accept values of any type.
Okay,
so the very indeed a type you can declare a variable as a very berating dim my var,
for example,
as variant.
So this declares as a variant.
And also if you don't write it at all and just write,
my var is equal to Jack,
for example.
Okay,
so this is a taste and then message box.
My var.
This also works,
and if you run that macro,
we can see here Jack appears in the message box.
So because my var was not declared here at all XlV B A will just assume it's a varying data
type.
It will just give it a very in data time.
So the very in data type happens when you either declare a variable as a variant and give
it a value,
and it can take any value or not declare it at all.
If you don't declare it at all,
it will also be given the variant data type and the very indeed a type can,
of course,
except other types of values,
so it can accept texts.
Here,
as we've seen it can also accept dates.
It can accept anything you can accept.
Bullion values can accept basically anything.
It's just the jack of old traits,
and as you could see her as well,
we've written the variable without needing to declare it,
and the macro worked fine.
But despite that,
it is actually a best practice to declare the variables that you're going to use and
declare them with the appropriate data types and not to declare them always vary in,
for example,
so give them appropriate data types in order to maker macro as efficient as possible.
This does not make a difference on Small Micro's,
but it does make a difference on Big Mac Rose with loss of calculations and loss of stuff
to be done.
Okay,
so this was it,
guys for declaring variables.
Thank you very much watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.