in this video,
we're going to speak about Constance and Constance.
Air basically values or tax that their value does not change.
Like,
for example,
the pie value.
The pie value is a long decimal,
but it starts with 3.14 and then a lot of other digits.
And for the sake of simplicity,
we're just gonna approximate it to 3.14.
So this value is a constant.
So you can actually declare a constant to be either public so that it can be used from any
procedure in any module in your workbook or it can be declared as a private.
And in that case,
it can be only used in the module that it's been declared in.
So to declare a constant,
all you need to do is to write public,
to say we're gonna declare a public constant.
So you're going to write public,
Const.
Let's say we're gonna call it pie value as single.
For example,
this ever gonna declare its status up to be a single equal to 3.14.
Okay,
so we're declaring a constant is gonna be public's.
It can be used in any sir procedure and in any module in a workbook,
and its data type is gonna be a single,
and its value is gonna be 3.14.
So this is how you can declare a constant so the value of this constant can be used in any
macro in our workbook.
So in this case,
if you run this macro,
for example,
here,
we're going to get the area of the circle and it's gonna assume the value of the pie to be
3.14.
So if I run through this macro,
actually step by step,
you can see here the pie value is 3.14.
It got its value from this public constant and were able to get the value off our area.
We could do that as well.
For the second circle,
you can see here that actually the pie values recognised a 3.14.
Even before calculating the area,
it's recognizing the constant that we have declared.
Okay,
so this is how you can declare a constant.
And this can work,
of course,
in any module.
Sufi,
if you have actually another procedure in module to here,
have got another PSA procedure.
School circle three.
You can calculate the area of that circle is going to recognize that this pie value is
equal to 3.14.
Also,
you could make the constant private,
and in that case,
axity the value for it would be only recognized in module one.
So if you run these macros and module one,
you're gonna be able to get the area of the circle.
Normally,
however,
if you go to module to and since the constant has been declared to be private to only
module one if you run actually,
the macro in module tool if you step through that step by step using F eight on your
keyboard is here.
Actually,
the pie values empties,
not recognizing the constant pi value because it's been declared as a private okay.
And we get the areas zero because it's empty is actually a zero.
You're multiplying something.
My zero,
you get a zero.
Okay,
so this is how you can declare either a public or private constant.
You can also declare a constant to be specific to just a certain serve procedure boy
declaring its value inside the sub procedure,
berating Const.
And then the name of the constant as whatever data type you wanted the clarity as to be
equal to its value.
Okay,
so you can actually do that as well.
You can make the value of the constant Onley specific to a particular sub procedure.
This is what we've done here in these two sub procedures.