and this video,
we're going to learn how to deal with workbooks.
So,
basically,
to deal with workbooks,
you need to call the name of the workbook from the workbooks collection,
just like we were doing so with sheets when we were calling the name of the sheet from the
sheets collection over the worksheets collection.
So to do that,
you just write workbooks and then you open brackets and then between double quotes,
right,
the name of the workbook.
So let's say I'm going to deal with the workbook,
that it's cooled my workbook here that I have got open at the moment and you actually then
need to write the extension as well and then close double quotes and then close parentheses
and then dot and use whichever method or property would like to use here.
I'm going to use the activate method,
which actually activates the workbook.
Please note that not writing the extension can sometimes work,
but in other occasions,
actually,
it can give you an error.
So it is better actually that you write the extension for the workbook.
And when we actually get the name of the workbook and a message box in a few moments you're
going to see the AXITY.
The extension is part of the name of the workbook,
so it is actually an essential part,
and you need to write it.
So now if I run this macro,
no noticeable change is gonna happen because the workbook that is called my workbook is
already activated.
However,
there is another workbook that I've got open as well.
They schooled other workbook.
So if I write other workbook here has enabled the workbook that I need to activate on I run
the macro because here that other workbook has been activated.
Another way to deal with workbooks is using the active workbook statement.
So the active workbook statement basically refers to the workbook that is currently active
.
So,
for example,
currently,
the active workbook is called other workbook.
So I say I'm gonna write active workbook dot name,
and I'm gonna have that in a message box.
So we're gonna have a message box pop up with the name of the active workbook,
and I'm actually gonna comment the first line of code as well,
so as not to be executed.
And if you run this macro,
you're gonna have the name of the active workbook in a message box.
And as you can see here,
the extension is part of the name.
Okay,
so make sure that you write the extension when you write the name of the workbook.
Another way to deal with workbooks is actually using that this workbook statement.
So this work booked our name,
for example,
will give you the name of the workbook that has the macro written in it.
So it's not the active one is actually the one that has the macro written in it.
So currently,
this macro is written in module One in the workbook that is called Molly Workbook.
So when we get the name of the workbook using this workbook statement,
we will actually get my work.
But because this is the workbook that has the macro written in it.
So now I have commented this line of code the second line of code,
and I'm gonna run this macro,
and we get the name of the workbook that the macro is written in.
And please note as well that you cannot activate a workbook unless it's open.
So if the workbook is not open already than you need to open it first by using the dot open
method,
which we will discuss in a future lesson.
Okay,
guys,
to this was an introduction on how to deal with workbooks and the upcoming lessons.
We're going to learn more about workbooks.
Thank you very much for watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.