in this video,
we're going to discuss the work picked out clothes method and the work picked up.
Close method allows us to close a workbook.
So I've got a workbook here called Closing Workbooks.
And if I want to close this workbook a dry,
active work booked up close,
I could also write this work booked up close.
And it could also write the name of the workbook using the workbooks collection side right
,
workbooks,
closing workbooks,
dark clothes.
So if I run this code,
you can see her that I get prompted on whether it would like to save my teen years or not,
which is actually the normal thing.
That happens when you make changes to a workbook and you're trying to close it.
Excel will prompt you on whether you'd like to save the changes or not.
I'm not going to see the changes for now.
I'm gonna press cancel and actually the workbook dot close method has some parameters
actually were only going to discuss the safe changes in the file name because the root
workbook parameter is actually an obsolete parameter that was being used until office 97 on
Lee,
there are only gun,
Discuss the safe changes and the file name the safe changes parameter allows you to either
save the changes that you've done or not.
So if you put that equals true than be changes air going to be saved and you're not gonna
be prompted on whether you would like to see the changes or not.
So the workbook will be closed and your changes will be safe.
If you put it equal to false,
then the workbook will be closed without saving the changes.
Okay.
And there is another one here that it's called the file name,
and this allows you to basically say the workbook to a certain destination.
So I'm going to say that actually to I test folder on my desktop.
Okay,
so there is a folder on my desktop called Test folder.
I'm going to save it with the name tested excellence em on that folder.
So you need to actually write the complete path and include,
as well the name of the file that you need to save it with.
Okay,
says this access a save,
as basically you're saving it as a certain name in a certain location and actually in order
to do that.
Of course,
you need to have the safe changes to be equal to Troop,
right,
cause you cannot ask Excel to not say the changes and at the same time,
savior in a certain location.
So if you run this macro,
what's gonna happen is that this Excel file will be closed.
And it's gonna be also saved as this name in the location that I've specified.
So to run that we consider that the Excel file husband closed.
And if I go here to my test folder,
you can see her that there is the test file that I saved.
Okay,
guys.
So I have actually reopened my file now,
and I would just like to tell you that doing a save as using the clothes method is not the
recommended way of doing it.
It is actually more recommended that you would do it using the dart save as method,
which we're going to discuss in an upcoming lesson.
So ah,
thank you guys for watching this video and I'll see on the next one