Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss adding and saving workbooks using XlV be a sotto adding new workbook
.
You just use the ad method with the workplace collection.
So you write workbooks,
start add.
So if you run this macro,
this actually opens a new workbook.
And this is similar to clicking on file here and then clicking on new or actually pressing
control and end on your keyboard.
They're just opening a blank new workbook.
You will notice also that the workbook start add method has an optional parameter,
which is actually template.
This template parameter allows you to open a workbook based on a template,
and you need to actually provide the location off the template that you need to open the
new workbook based on.
So I'm going to actually open a new workbook based on a template that I've got in my
templates folder.
So I need to paste the location of that template,
which is the default location for the Templates folder,
and it's called Sales Template and its extension is dot excel tm.
Of course,
your path could be different.
You can actually check the path of your templates by going to file and then going to
options and then on the save menu here,
you're gonna have your default personal templates.
Location.
Okay,
So back to our visual basic environment.
So if I run this macro,
we're gonna open a new workbook based on a template,
which is my sale.
Stempler here safely run that you're going to see a new workbook husband opened based on a
template that I had created.
So I'm gonna close that for now.
OK,
so to actually save the changes to a workbook,
you just use the workbook dot save method.
So if you want this workbook dot save this is actually going to save the changes to the
workbook that contains this macro,
which is called adding and saving workbooks.
So if I won this macro,
you're just saving the changes,
and that is similar to pressing control and as on your keyboard or going to file and then
safe.
Now I've actually activated the workbook that schooled book one that we've just opened.
But we haven't saved yet.
So this workbook has just been opened,
as we've seen by using the workbook start add method,
but it has not been safe to a location yet if you used the workbook dot save method on that
workbook.
So now this is the workbook active.
So if I use the active workbook to save method,
if I run that actually,
this workbook is going to be saved and it's gonna be safe to a location.
So actually,
we haven't been asked for the location,
as you could see here and the statement executed.
Fine.
So where has that workbook been saved while?
Actually,
it has been safe to the default location for saving workbooks for Excel,
which is usually the Documents folder.
So here is the my documents folder,
and you could see here.
Here is book One.
So this is why it's not recommended to use the workbook doubt save method to save newly
openwork books or workbooks that have not been saved yet because you don't get to determine
the location for saving the workbook.
And you also don't get too Name it with a certain name,
you know,
Let's say you don't want to name it with book one.
You want to give it another name,
so the workbook dot same method does not give you the option This is why it's also better
to use the workbook save as method,
which actually we're going to see on the next video.
So thanks,
guys,
for watching this video and I'll see you on the next one.