Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the open method for the workbooks collection object.
So we're going to see how to open workbooks using XlV B A.
So basically,
to open a workbook in excel VB a use the open method on the workbooks collection objects
you write workbooks dot open and then if you type of space,
you're going to see a bunch of parameters.
We're going to speak about the most important ones.
So basically,
one of the most important ones is the file name,
and this is actually a mandatory parameter.
You have to provide that one.
And in the foul name,
you basically provide the path and the foul name and extension.
So the same as when we were providing the file name on the save as method,
for example.
So basically,
I'm going to provide the fall path,
including the name and extension.
So we're gonna actually open the test file that we created on the test folder on my desktop
.
So if you were in this code,
you're actually gonna be able to open the test file on my test folder on my desktop,
So I've been able to open it.
As you can see her.
The follow the file has been opened.
So I'm gonna close it on.
I'm gonna go back to my visual basic editor on If I type a comma,
I can start typing the other parameters.
So here there's a prompter called Update Ling's,
which actually configures how you can update the links.
So actually,
there are some valid values,
just three or four valid values for this update links parameter and to know what the
valiant values are.
Well,
we're just gonna highlight it and press F one on our keyboard.
And now we're actually on the workbook.
That update links property.
And as you can see here,
there are actually three voted values for the property.
So actually excel update links always and excel plate links never and extra update links
user setting.
So the 1st 1 updates at the links,
no matter what.
So their links our always updated.
And this 2nd 1 actually ensures that the links are never updated.
And the 3rd 1 updates the links according to the user's setting for the specified workbook
.
And I believe you need to actually know about the update links feature in Excel,
which actually when?
When you have some links to other workbooks,
you should have that on the file menu.
When you click on file on the upper left corner of Excel,
you're gonna have a section on the lower right.
This says update lings and you can configure how links air updated from there.
So actually,
this is its corresponding feature in XlV Be a basically.
So it actually accepts one of these three values,
and you can actually choose to put one of these three values according to what you want to
do.
So let's go back to our visual basic editor.
OK,
so we're back to the visual basic editor,
and another parameter here that you can use is actually the read only,
and the read only parameter accepts values of either true or false.
So if you put a true the foul that you open will be just street only you won't be able to
it it and save in it.
And if you put a false than it's not gonna be read,
only you're gonna be able to edit it.
And,
of course,
the default value for it should be fools,
as when you provide a false value or would you don't provide the value at all.
The foul can be edited.
So if we provide a true value for that one here and open our best foul,
so run the macro.
Basically,
you can see here that the fall has been open as read only.
And if you try to edit it and then try to save so press control and s is gonna tell you
street only,
and you need to save it to a different location.
So that is how the read only parameter works another parameter,
which is actually the password parameter.
So the password parameter allows you to put a password that you're gonna open the file with
.
So basically,
if the file has a password this past,
or it can just go into the password field for the foul that you're opening says to open the
file without needing to type the pastor because you're typing in the code.
So basically,
for example,
I'm gonna open a file that was cooled password and had a file called VB a course,
using that coat.
So,
as you can see,
I'm going to try to open the file password that we had created before that had a positive E
b A course.
I'm putting the password here in the code.
And if I run that macro,
the fall will be open and the password will be typed.
You know,
while the code is being executed,
I won't need to input password because I've put it in the coat.
If actually,
I try to open a file that has a password and don't tied the pastor parameters.
So I don't specify here that I'm gonna be asked for the password as if I'm opening the file
.
And it has a pastor's from us where the pastor to If I run that because here that I'm being
asked for the password,
you know,
on I have to type it.
In this case,
there is also the right rez password.
The right rez.
Password parameter here is actually a parameter that allows you to type the password for
the writing restriction.
Okay,
so I'm gonna type the password for the file that we had created that well schooled right
rez and had a positive right rez.
And this is actually gonna type the password within the code without me needing to type it
So?
So if I run this code,
you consider that the file has been opened on the password has been typed as well.
Well,
the funds being open because I talked the password into the code.
And of course as well.
If you don't specify that parameter,
then when you open the foul that has a writing restriction password,
you're gonna be oss for the password.
So these are actually the most important parameters according to the scope of the courses
is a beginner.
Of course,
I believe as a beginner,
knowing these parameters is more than enough for you at this stage.
So ah,
thank you guys for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.