Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about the V B a speech or the V B A syntax,
or how the V b A language is written so v b A is an object oriented language as we've
explained before,
and that means that objects or announce they come first.
So in order to understand the V b a syntax or how the V B A language is written,
we're gonna actually compare it to how the English language is written.
So in English,
you would say,
kick the bowl.
However,
in VB a objects or announce our most important so they come first.
So if you want to say kick the bowl using V B A,
you would put the noun first.
So if you want to write a sentence using Vehbi,
eh,
you would write the noun first sowed right now ndadd verb or object dot method,
and therefore,
if you want to say kick the bull using the V B a syntax,
you would say bull dot kick.
So is it can see here.
The noun,
which is the bowl,
comes before the verb,
which is kicked.
Two.
It's a Boldak cake.
If you want to say in VB a Syntex,
some other examples as well that you would write using VB.
A Syntex is like dinner dot eat or car dot drive.
So if you want to open a workbook in V B A,
you would say workbook dot open.
If you want to activate a worksheet,
you would say worksheet dot Activate some examples of objects or announce in Excel Off
course,
or the cell is an object of workbook.
The worksheet a chart as well,
is an object,
and we've explained that before some examples as well off collection.
We've explained collections before in XlV b A.
So some examples of collections or they're considered as actually plural noun are the cells
collection,
which is a plural or it contains cells,
and also the Worksheets collection,
which contains worksheets and workbooks collection,
which contains all workbooks as well.
So we're just reiterating the idea of having collections in Excel VV eight.
Now we're speaking about collections because we want to speak about how to identify items
in a collection.
So if you've got a collection of items,
how do you identify a certain item in a collection to make sure that you use the right item
or the item that you intend to use.
So,
for example,
if you've got three bowls here,
we've got a soccer or a football bowl and we've got a bowling bull and we've got a
basketball.
So how do make sure that we kick the right bull,
which is,
if we're gonna kick a bull?
It should be the soccer bowl,
right?
We don't want to kick the bowling bowl,
and we don't want to kick the basketball.
So there are actually two ways of identifying an item in a collection.
There is a less used way in a less recommended way,
which is using the index number,
and although it's a less used way,
you will use it sometimes.
But you're not going to use a lot as the other way,
and the other way is using the name.
But let's speak about using the index number first.
So if you wanna use the index number and you want to kick the first bowl in this collection
and the first is basically counting from left to right,
then you would right.
Bulls won dot kick,
so if you right bulls won dot kick.
This way you will be able to kick the soccer bowl.
However,
what happens if these Bulls got reordered?
And that means what happens if one of your friends puts the bowling bowl to be the first
bowl from the left hand side and you right?
Bulls won dot kick and you kick the bowling bull.
Ouch.
That's gonna be a painful experience,
right?
It's gonna be very painful to kick a bowling ball.
So this is why it is not recommended to use the index number to identify an item in a
collection.
So the better way is to actually use the name of the object.
So it's better to write roles.
Soccer dot So if you do that,
you will make sure to kick the correct bull,
which is the soccer Bowl,
regardless of its position in this collection.
So if the soccer bowl is the first or the second or the third,
you're going to make sure that the soccer bowl is the bull you kick.
Okay,
so it's better to use the name of the item rather than its position.
Now let's speak about methods or verbs,
so methods in XlV be a or verbs have actually parameters and parameters act like adverbs in
the English language.
So if you say Bulls soccer dot kick and then you would right direction,
Colin equals right force Colin equals hard.
The direction and the force are considered parameters or adverbs in XlV v A,
and they describe how the verb or the method which is kick is done.
So here were saying that we want to kick the bull to the right and with the hard force.
So if you see a call in equals operator,
this indicates that you've got an adverb or a parameter,
and parameters are.
Adverbs can sometimes be confusing because if you know the default order off the adverbs,
you can leave off the name.
So if you know that the default order for the direction and the force are that the
direction comes first and then the force parameter the nuclear I,
instead of writing bulls sucker don't kick direction called equals right force calling
equals hard.
You could write bulls soccer dot kick right comma hard.
Of course,
we do not have a kick method in XlV B A,
and we do not have a direction and a force parameters,
but you get the idea.
So in V B A,
you could write shapes that at shape.
So we're using the ad shape method on the shapes collection object in order to add a new
shape,
and then you would right left call unequal stand top Colin equals 20 with Colin equals 30.
Height colony equals 15 and these parameters are adverbs identified.
The position off the shape when it is inserted so you can actually write shape.
Start at shape 10 comma 20 comma,
100 comma 15 without explicitly writing the parameters and it will still work.
Okay,
the code will work absolutely fine.
However,
if you do that,
if you write the code without explicitly writing the parameters,
the code will be confusing,
right?
If someone else reads your code and you write shapes that at shape 10 common 20 comma 100
common 15.
If somebody reads your code this way,
they will be confused.
They will not understand what you mean because not everyone remembers the positions off the
parameters or the order of the parameters.
Right.
So writing the values of the parameters without specifying the actual parameters is a bad
programming practice So even though your code is still gonna work,
it is actually a about programming practice.
And it is better to explicitly right your parameters or adverbs.
Okay,
so we've spoken about parameters.
Now let's speak about properties or adjectives.
So properties,
what they do is that they describe an object.
So,
for example,
when you're I active,
she dot name equals my sheet.
The property name here gets the value off my sheet,
and that means that the name of the active sheet is gonna be my sheet.
And also,
properties do not use the colony equals construct.
Okay,
so the colony equals is exclusive for parameters.
So whenever you see a colony equals,
that means you've got a parameter here,
and you can set a variable equal to the value of a property.
So,
for example,
you can set variable X to be equal to the name of the active worksheet.
By writing X equals active,
she dot name,
and we will see how to do that in the future,
on the course as well.
Okay,
so let's summarize what we've explained on this video.
So a noun in the English language is equivalent to an object in XlV B A and a plural noun
is equivalent to a collection and think of different collections as different families.
A verb in the English language is equivalent to a method in XlV B A and an adverb is
equivalent to a parameter.
And also an adjective in the English language is equivalent to a property in XlV v a.
Okay,
so I hope that was informative for you about understanding the V b A Syntex.
Thank you very much,
guys,
watching this video and I'll see on the next one.