Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to explain how to get the loss column on your data set using Excel VB eight.
So getting the loss column in your data set using XlV be a involves three main steps.
The first step is to actually start at the Lost column in Excel,
which is column number 16,384.
And then the second step is to actually press control and left on your keyboard to hit the
loss column on your data set.
And then the third step is to actually ask what column on my on.
So it involves three main steps just like getting the loss throat.
It's the same idea.
We're just doing it in a different way.
So let's see how we can apply that using code.
So if Grady here,
ah variable have declared a variable called L C as an integer,
and you can safely declare as an integer because the number of columns in Excel or actually
16,384 and they are less than the 32,000 something maximum value for the interview data
types Utkan safety,
the clear as an integer without worrying about the loss column going over the limit and to
get the loss column.
It's just gonna be the same idea we implemented on getting the last row.
It's just implemented in a different way.
Okay,
so to get the lost com,
we're going to write cells and then the row that we're starting at.
It's better here to start at the first stroke,
because the first stroke contains your column headers and your table's gonna always contain
headers.
So you're going to guarantee that you get the correct loss column just as we've explained
on getting the last row.
That is better to start on a column that you are always guaranteeing to have data on.
Okay,
so here it's better to start on a road that you're always guaranteed to have.
They don't.
So we're going to start to choose.
We're so we're going to choose to start on the first row,
and then the column index number is gonna be actually columns dot count.
Okay,
because we want to start at the Lost column in Excel.
So the column number for that is gonna be columns dot count,
and then it's gonna be dot end instead of excel up is gonna be excel to left and then it's
gonna be dot column So we're doing actually,
the three main steps that we've explained.
First Step is to start from the loss column in Excel,
which weaken go to by writing sells one columns,
columns,
start count and it's gonna be the cell in the loss column and in the first row as well.
Okay,
and then dot and excel to left.
This is the step when we press control and left on a keyboard.
And then the third step is to ask which column on my on.
And this is the part that represents thirst.
Step the dot column property were asking for dark column property,
which represents what column are you on?
So now if we go through this micro step by step here.
So when we execute this line of code for l see,
you can see here that the value of L Z is equal to four.
Our loss column is the fourth column INCHES column D.
So I sit.
This is how you can get the loss column on your data set.
Okay,
so Ah,
that's it,
guys,
Thank you very much for watching this video,
and I'll see on the next one