Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see how to get to the next row.
And that is the row after the last row on our data set.
And we would want to do that in order to add new rose to our data set,
for example.
So how can we get the row number for the next row?
Well,
it's very simple.
You could just do the same one here,
the same for metaphor getting the last row.
Except that you're just gonna have a plus one.
So this formula for getting the last row yields an integer,
which is the last row if you had a +12 that you go to the next row,
right,
So then you can start typing values on the road that is the next euro.
So in our case here for start topping values,
we're going to start topping values on road number 20.
So you could write,
for example,
sells the rolling next number is gonna be an r,
then comma one,
we're gonna type in the first column,
which is the name we're gonna type,
for example,
Jack,
and then sells on our common to which is the day it's gonna equals date serial,
Listen to random.
They 2016 07 days.
05 for example.
I'm actually going to call people out here,
so Comma three is equal to we're gonna put an item Soul.
So say 15 on then The wonder is Comma Four,
which is for the fourth column to say we're gonna type the sales amount to be 100,000.
So if you run this code,
we're actually going to go through it step by step.
Here on our is equal to 20.
This is an extra.
We're going to start executing these statements,
so on the value for the next row and first column is gonna be Jack and then the dates and
then 15 and then 100,000.
Okay,
so this is how you can get the value for the next throw.
It's very easy now.
There is another way actually,
that people use sometimes subbed extra other way.
That's great.
And use of procedure here and what some other people do as well,
too go to the next row,
is actually using the range objects.
So range,
for example,
here on that.
Remember,
guys on the range object would just enter the reference for a cell.
So let's say we're gonna enter,
arrange a and then concoct any on that in the value of an R.
Okay.
And this way we got range for example,
a 21 because the next year we're going to type on is a 21.
So a 21 is gonna be equal to Jason.
Whatever.
And then we could do B and congratulated on an Are that's gonna be date serial,
whatever 2016 0403 for example,
And then range,
see,
and on our 1% and are is equal to 12 for example,
and then d m person and or is equal to 50,000 for example,
This is another way off,
actually referring to cells when you have variables,
although it's less common way and it's a less recommended way.
So using the cells collection object is better,
but sometimes people do that so they would refer to a cell.
If the road number is a variable,
do just concoct innate.
The column name,
which is your economy,
for example,
on using the UN percent on the N.
R and the n percent is actually used when you need to concoct innate texts and,
you know,
pieces tax on another piece of text and we'll see that a lot,
actually,
in the course.
And you do that in Excel in the normally Excel,
we need to concoct in a two piece of text on a piece of tax use.
The N percent as well.
You should be familiar with that case.
If you're on this code,
we're gonna have these values.
Spot on Road 21 cases is another way that people could write it.
I'm just showing you that so that if you see in somebody else's schooled,
you wouldn't feel that is weird.
Okay,
guys,
So that's it for the next row.
Thank you very much for watching this video on.
I'll see on the next one.