Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss with statement and xlv b A.
So the with statement ing salvi B A is a statement that allows you to save a bit of space
and a bit of code typing or key strokes on your keyboard.
It doesn't give you any extra functionality,
so it's not like if you don't use it,
you will be missing.
Anything is just safe sometime and keystrokes.
So basically,
the with statement allows you to apply different methods and properties to a certain object
that you choose to use with the with statement.
So let's say here I'm gonna add the value of 52 range.
They want to sell a one,
and then I'm gonna make the fund bold.
I'm gonna make it italics,
and I'm gonna make it.
So I use to be 12.
So if you run this macro,
that is gonna happen here in a cell,
a one you can actually dual these actions using the with statement as well.
So the structure of the with is basically with and then range a one.
So who want to do the same thing using the with statement so with range anyone.
And don't forget to write the end with because this marks the end of the actions that
you're going to do to your objects.
So you with that particular object,
you're going to start writing.
What do you want to do with it?
OK,
so you're going to start writing the methods and properties that you want to take actions
with.
So basically dot value and you can see here that the intelligence for V B A is working the
auto complete feature and VB is working because it's understanding that this is a with
statement.
I'm trying to do stuff to their objects.
So dark value equals 50 and then dot fond I doubt bold equals true.
And then dot fund dot italics equals true as well,
and then dot font size equals 12.
So this with statement is gonna accomplish the same thing as these statements and notice
here that I've actually indented my code a bit.
So I've invented what's between the within the end with by actually hitting tab on my
keyboard.
So if I actually press,
enter here and I'm at the beginning of the line.
If I want to invent that line a bit.
Press tab on my keyboard.
Okay?
And I'm just inventing.
Get for readability.
So this does not affect the execution of your code or anything.
It's just effects the readability.
It makes it more readable.
It gives you the sentence or the feeling that these actions year that I'm taking on that
object are between this with and this end with statement,
they are enclosed inside it.
So it just makes your code more readable.
Doesn't affect the execution of your coat.
So I'm actually going to highlight the previous code,
and I'm actually gonna comment that code.
So I'm gonna comment all that block of code so that it wouldn't be executed,
and then I'm actually going to delete the contents of that.
So I'm going to clear everything so clear value on formatting and everything.
And then if I execute that code,
you can see here that we've done the same thing,
basically,
So this with statement allows you to do the same thing as the above four lines of code,
except that you do it with less keystrokes.
So if you don't use the with statement,
you will not be missing any functionality.
It's just that you're gonna save some keystrokes when you use it.
So sit guys for the with statement.
Thank you very much watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.