Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
I just wanted to go over the comparison Operators in XlV be a really quickly because these
comparison operators air going to be used in comparing expressions to each other.
So there's this is something is equal to something or less than or greater than or not
equal to.
You.
Probably used the's comparison operators when you were using the Normal Excel grid,
but I just wanted to go over them really quickly.
So get the equal sign you got not equal to get the less than so in greater than son.
This is less than or equal to and the greater than or equal to.
So I believe you should be familiar with them already.
But I just wanted to get them out of the way because we're going to use them.
Ah,
lot in this course,
and I'll be also including a PdF document listing these comparison operators.
So thank you very much watching this video guys I don't see on the next one