Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about another structure that you can use as an alternative to,
if then else.
If which is using nested ifs,
however,
it's not recommended that used nested ifs as their execution time is higher or the coat
takes more to get executed.
But I'll just show it to you just for you to know it.
And in case you see on somebody else's code,
you'd understand what they're trying to do.
So basically,
I've got some code here written using Dennis it if structure and it's actually doing the
same thing as what we were doing on the if then else if sir testing the value on Selby 18
this cell here in green and we're checking the value.
And if the values one will get a message box one,
and if it's too,
we're gonna miss it.
Books,
too.
If it's three,
we got a message Box three,
and if it's forward,
get a message box.
So four.
And as you can see here,
this is the structure of the nested ifs.
The Necid ifs air basically,
and if condition and then on the els you put another if inside it.
Okay,
so he said if then else.
But in the else you don't put an action to be executed,
you actually nest another if inside the else.
Okay.
And so this if can also be accompanied by an else,
okay?
And then you can nest.
And if inside the else for the second if so,
this way you're creating nested ifs.
And then there's another.
If here in nested inside the els for that third if and so because now we've got,
like,
four ifs 1234 we would have to put four and if so,
this is why it's not recommended.
First of all,
it's complicated to right.
And the second thing is that the code will be executed in a longer time.
So if you touch this code,
for example,
let's say I'm gonna put the value here to be four,
for example.
So let's see how many steps it takes for us to reach the message box that says four.
So I'm gonna run through the code step by step.
Here,
212345 6789 10 11 12.
Okay,
so we've taken,
like,
12 steps to reach that message boxing and actually end all the end ifs.
But if we try to execute this goat here with if then else if it's 12345 six,
six steps,
seven with the end if,
okay,
so seven steps instead of 12.
This is why the if then else,
if structure is more efficient,
it executes the code in less time.
Okay,
so so in case that you can do something with the if then else if and you can do the same
thing with nested ifs,
it is recommended that used the if then else if structure and you can see her as well
because it's complicated to read the nested if structure,
you can see her them inventing my code here so as to make it easier to read.
So as you can see her putting the if and then I'm in vending the result and then the els.
But and then then thing,
the if inside the else to given indication that the if is nested inside the else on them,
doing indentations so as to make it easier to read,
but is already a bit complicated to right.
And it's not efficient in code execution in terms of execution time as well.
I mean,
because this is a small macro.
Probably you won't feel the difference.
But if you're doing something complicated using Vehbi,
eh,
there will be a difference in the execution time.
Okay,
So this is why this structure administrative structure is not recommended.
It is recommended that you stick to if then else if structure Ok,
so that's it,
guys,
for the necessity of structure just wanted you to be acquainted with it.
So as if you see it in somebody else's code,
you'd understand it.
Okay,
although it's not recommended to be used.
So thank you guys for watching this video and I'll see you on the next one.