Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the not logical operator.
So the not logical operator,
what it does is that it converts true values to fulls and vice versa.
So we will also convert to full value to it.
True.
So you're in this simple macro here.
We're gonna create a variable,
which is X,
and we're gonna put a value of three to the X variable.
And then we're gonna have an if statement here.
So here on the first part of the if statement,
it says,
if not,
X is equal to three.
Then give me a message.
Box X is not equal to three.
So basically,
X is equal to three.
This part here will yield a true because X is actually equal to three.
However,
because it's put inside a not logical operator.
This means that this true yielded by this part,
we're actually become a full,
so this whole thing will become a fulls.
So that means that this if statement when executed,
it's not going to go and execute the message box because the condition here,
which is not X equal to three,
is equal to false because you could see her That the form of an if statement here is that
if condition is equal to true,
then you can go ahead and execute the code.
So this part here not x equal to three is actually the condition.
And this is going to become a fool's right,
cause X is equal to three.
This is true,
but because is inside,
not,
then it's gonna become a false.
Now,
if you look on the following else If part here,
we will see her X is not equal to three.
This part here will yield the fools.
But because it's put inside and not,
then it's gonna be a two.
So here the condition is going to be equal to true.
And actually,
we're gonna have this message box executed.
X is equal to three.
So let's run through that and see what happens.
So here we're gonna sign X equal to three,
and then we're gonna test this.
This condition,
not X equal to three,
is gonna be a full.
So the message box the 1st 1 here is not gonna be executed.
And then we're gonna test the else.
If here and you consider that the message box has been executed.
So basically,
in a nutshell,
the not logical operator converts to true to a fool's or a full Stewart.
True,
and it's important to know about that logical operator.
You could find it in somebody else's code,
or you could use it to convert a true value to a fool's or vice versa.
So that's it,
guys,
for the not logical operator,
thinking very much watching this video,
and I'll see on the next one.