Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss this lucked case statement.
So the select a statement in Excel Vivier can perform a similar task to the if statement so
it can perform the same task as the if statement,
although it has some limitations.
So the if statement is basically more flexible and can have more uses.
So the structure of the select a statement is basically select case and then he test
expression and that just expression could be a value of a sell.
It could be a value of variable.
It could be a formula.
So like X plus y salat case X plus y.
So I'm gonna test the value of X plus y.
It could be also the value of a property,
for example.
So select case,
a surgeon test expression,
and then we're gonna have some cases,
some different cases,
so case condition one.
So we're gonna have some conditions that we're gonna test against that tests,
expression and condition basically is the value being one or the value being two,
or it can be also the value being 40 or 50 or 60 or it can be the value being between 10
and 15 as well,
and we'll see how to perform that or could be the value being less than 10.
For example,
all these are possible conditions that we can put on.
We will see how we can apply these.
So if condition one is Matt,
then code one gets executed or whatever code under condition one gets executed.
If that is not met,
we go and test against condition too.
If the condition is true,
then were basically gonna execute the code under and we can put as many conditions as we
want.
You know,
so condition and means that you can put any number of conditions and under each condition,
have some code to execute.
And we can also write case else in case else basically is.
If none of these conditions is true,
we execute whatever under the case else.
So it's like the else in the if statement and then we have an end select to indicate the
end of our select case statement.
And please note that if any of these conditions is Matt than the rest of the conditions are
not going to be tested.
So if we're testing and condition one gets met,
then we're not gonna test condition two or three.
And we're not gonna execute the case else.
Of course,
we're just gonna execute code one and then go to the end,
select and end the select statement.
So that is similar to the if then else if statement if any of the conditions gets met,
it's were basically gonna exit the if then else if structure.
So let's see the case statement in action.
Okay,
so let's build a case statement together.
So basically,
let's say I'm gonna put Range D to value is equal to two,
and then we're gonna do a select A statements of select case and then range D to value.
So after the select case,
I need to put whatever expression I need to test,
which,
in this case,
I'm testing the value of range D two and then I'm gonna put the end select statement here
so as not to forget it.
And then we would put our tests or are conditions so case,
too.
So in case the values equal to two message box,
too,
and we could have also case less than seven message box less than seven case 40 comma 50
Calma 60.
Message box 40 or 50 or 60 case 12 to 15.
Message box between 12 and 15.
Case else.
Message box.
Something else.
Okay,
so let's try to execute that.
Select a statement here.
So if you go through that step by step,
so first of all,
we're gonna put the value of cell D two to be equal to two mucus ear.
It's been given the value of two,
and then we're gonna test the value of cell D to,
And then we're gonna execute that condition here case,
too.
So we're actually going to check if the value of cell D to is to and that is actually going
to be the case,
or we're going to get a message box,
too.
And you can see here that we've jumped straight away to the end,
select and we've not tested any other conditions and select and sub let's say we're going
to change the value of D two to be equal to five,
for example,
and let's test our conditions year.
So basically,
we're gonna put the values equal to five.
We're gonna test the value here if we test to that test is gonna be fools,
and then we're gonna test Case is less than seven.
So we're going to get a message box less than seven,
and then we jump to the end,
select and then and soap.
So,
as you could see here,
we test each statement.
And when we find that one of them is true,
we're actually gonna go straight away to the end,
select after executing the code under that particular case statement.
And please note that actually,
if you want to do the test for less than seven,
you don't have to write.
Case is less than seven.
You could write case less than seven or less than eight or whatever and then XlV be were
actually correct your code automatically.
And we understand that you want toe test.
If the values less than seven and it will add the is by self.
So I haven't written the is although you can write it,
of course,
but you don't have to memorize.
Remember to write it.
Now we're gonna do the third test here,
or case 40 common 50 common 60 because this test is basically another way of testing,
and it means that the value is either 40 or 50 or 60.
I've actually deliberately try to show you different ways off performing the test.
So here I'm performing a test for the cell D to being equal to a certain value than here
being less than certain value.
And here being one of three values,
for example,
And here,
being between some values,
some trying to show you different flavors of writing the case statement of different ways
to do different tests.
So here,
if we put the value of D 22 b equals to 40 for example,
and try to go through the code step by step,
he will see her that the test for 40 common 50 common 60 is going to go through and we're
going to get the message box and select and sub.
And also,
if we try to put 14.5,
the test the lost one here between 12 to 15 is actually gonna work because it can actually
detect decimals as well.
So the number doesn't have to be an integer.
Okay,
so says it all between 12 and 15.
And if the value does not meet any of these conditions,
of course we're going to go to the case else.
So,
for example,
if you put it as 52 for example,
we're actually going to go to the case else.
Something else.
One more thing I want to tell you about the case statement is that the or an and logic ALS
cannot work with the case statement.
So this is why it is a bit limited than the if statement.
So if we replaced the value of D two to be 40 for example,
and then were placed 40 comma,
50 comes 60 with 40 or 50 or 60 and we try the test,
the case statement will not work.
As you can see here,
it's by passed that test than its than the one for case else because we're not able to use
that Syntex with the case statement.
Also,
if we try to use,
for example greater than 39 less than 41 for example,
this will actually give us an error.
So the case statement does not work with the or and end logical.
So please bear that in mind.
So that's it for the case statement.
It's basically a way of performing tests on a certain expression and taking actions based
on these tests being true.
So ah,
thank you guys for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.