Okay,
guys,
so so far in this course have been seeing code that would be executed on Lee ones.
But what if we need to repeat our code?
Repeat,
executing our code over and over again.
That's when we need to use a loop.
And a loop is basically a way for you to execute your code over and over again.
But we're not gonna go through the code over and over again forever.
There's gonna be a point when we would need to stop executing our code or else our macro
will go through an endless loop and will never stop.
Right?
So how you stop executing the code is determined by either the number of times that you've
asked Excel to repeat the code.
So if you ask Excel to repeat the code for 10 times,
so Excel will stop executing the code after the 10th time.
Right?
Or you could ask Excel to keep on repeating the code until a certain condition is met and
when a sitting condition is met.
That's when Excel stops repeating the code that's called like exiting the loop,
and we'll see how to do that.
So that guys was a quick introduction to Loops.
It's a way of repeating some code over and over again.
It saves a lot of time.
It adds a lot of power to your code,
and we will see how useful loops are on the upcoming videos.