Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the first type of loops,
which is the four next loop.
So the for next loop has a very simple structure,
which is for the value of a counter.
And this counter is gonna be a variable equal start,
which is gonna be asserting value.
Such is one,
for example,
to end,
which is gonna be an ending value such as 10.
So for X,
for example,
equals 1 to 10 we're gonna execute some code,
and then next counter,
which is next X,
for example.
So that means that X is going to take a value of one,
and then this code is going to be executed.
That's gonna be the first pass on.
Then when we reach the next X statement,
we're gonna go back and increment the value of X by one to become a two and then execute
the code.
And then we're gonna go to the next X statement and then go back again,
increment the value of X by one to become a three and then execute the code,
go to the next X statement and so on and so forth and we're going to keep on executing the
code until the value of X reaches the end value,
which is 10 for example.
Okay,
so when the value of X reaches 10 acts,
is going to take the value of 10 execute the code for the 10th time and then because it's
the n value.
When it reaches the next X statement,
it's not gonna go back.
It's just gonna execute any code below the four next loop.
So that is the structure of the for next loop.
And please note that the start and end values are going to determine how many times the
code in between is going to be executed in the upcoming videos as well.
We're going to learn about the exit for statement,
which is going to enable us to exit the for next loop at any point if a certain condition
is mad.
So we're going to learn as well how to exit the loop without depending on reaching the end
value for the count.
So let's see an example for the four next loop.
Okay,
guys.
So I've created a set procedure here,
cold for next loop,
and I'm gonna dim X as bite and then for X is equal to 1 to 10 Next X and then what we're
going to do is that we're gonna print the value of X in the immediate windows or debug dot
print.
Exe.
So this code,
what it's going to do is that it's going to give X the value of one at the beginning and
then print the value of X,
which is gonna be one.
And then it's going to go.
The next X statement is gonna increment the value of X by one to become a two on so on and
so forth.
So let's go through the coat together.
Basically,
the value of X is gonna be printed here in the immediate window.
So I'm going to go through the coat step by step here by pressing F eight on my keyboard.
And as you can see,
her first of all,
the value of X is equal to one.
As you can see her when we highlighting it is gonna print the value of X here,
which is gonna be one.
And then when it reaches an X X statement and because the value of X is still less than the
end value.
We're gonna go back an increment,
the value of X by one to become a two.
And then we're gonna print the value of X year.
And then we're gonna increment the value to become a three.
After reach the next X statement,
print it on.
If we keep doing that,
you can see here that the values of X have been printed tear at the bottom.
And after we reached the value of 10 here is the next X statement.
Now the value of X is a 10 as you can see here,
and we reach the next X statement.
So what's gonna happen?
We're not gonna go back.
We're gonna exit the loop because we've reached the end value for X and we've exited the
loop and we're gonna execute any code after the loop.
And at the moment,
Onley the end sub line happens to be the line after the code.
So we're gonna execute the ends up line here and just and the macro,
so that simply is the for next loop.
This is the simplest structure for the for next loop.
The value of X is incremental by one.
By default,
however,
we will see shortly how we can change the incremental value or the value that X is
incremental by.
So we could make it get implemented by to for examples,
it's gonna become 135 and we can increment backwards as well.
Like we can do a countdown.
So 10 86 we can do that as well.
We're going to see that shortly.
Another example that we can have year is actually using the cells collection object inside
the for next loop.
So,
as you can see here,
this is a four next loop for X equals 1 to 10.
The action that we're going to take or the code we're going to repeat is basically cells X
comma one equals X.
So at the beginning of the loop and on the first pass,
X is gonna be assigned a value of one.
So this is going to yield sells one comma,
one equals one.
This is gonna put the value of one and sell a one,
and then X is gonna be incriminated by one on the second pass.
So it's gonna be cells to calm a one equal stew,
so sell a two is going to be populated with the value of two.
And basically we're gonna fill the cells a 1 to 8 10 with the numbers 1 to 10 using this
coat.
And remember,
guys,
when we're speaking actually about the cells collection object and we said that is very
useful because it uses numbers instead of saying sell A to,
for example,
we specify the number for the road number and the column number for the cell.
So this is why the cells collection object is useful.
And we've spoken about that,
and here we're actually demonstrating how useful it is.
So if we run the code step by step here,
using F eight on our keyboard,
you can see here first of all,
X takes the value of one.
And because extrude the value of one,
you can see that the value of one is put in cell a one.
And then on the second past,
we're gonna get the value of to put in cell eight to And if we keep on pressing F eight on
our keyboard here,
the value of X Nolly stench is gonna go sell eight and put a 10.
And because we've reached the end value for our loop.
We're not going to loop again after the next X statement here,
we're gonna execute the following statement which is ends up.
So we're gonna exit our micro.
So it's another example actually of using the for next loop with the cells collection
object to loop through cells we're going to see as well how to look through cells using the
for each loop later on in the course.
But this is one way to look through cells.
There's another way which is using the for each loop as well.
OK,
guys.
So now we're gonna see how to change the increment ation value for our variable.
So we said that by default,
the value is incremental by one.
However,
we can change that value.
So here we're going to make our value get incremental by two.
So,
for example,
the first pass in this loop is gonna be X having the value of five.
And then the second pass is gonna be X,
having the value of seven,
therefore incremental by two on,
then the third pass is gonna be X,
having the value of mine and then 11 and then 13 and then 15 on how you change.
The implementation value is basically using using this step word to this step word controls
your incantation values.
So here we've written Step two and our value gets implemented by two.
If you're right three than the value is gonna be implemented by three and so on and so
forth.
So if we go through this code,
step by step here is here on the first pass the value of excess gonna be five.
And then when we reach the next X statement,
the values gonna be implemented by two sonar the value of excess.
Seven.
You can see here that the values printed here at the bottom seven and then nine and then
beloved and then 13 and then 15 and then when reached 15 we exit the loop on and sub.
Okay,
so this is how you can change the increment ation value.
You can also increment backwards.
So here for X equals 2 15 to 5 step negative two is gonna increment backwards or do a
countdown.
So basically,
X is going to take the value of 15 and then on the second pass is going to be 13 11 97
until we reach a value of five.
However,
I want to show you something,
actually,
because this is not gonna work with the variable type being a bite.
And the reason for that is that the bites value is between zero and 255 forgotten over flow
.
And although the value of X is not gonna be outside the range of the bite,
actually,
I believe that the value of X is given a value of negative two,
which is outside the range for the bite.
So is given a value of negative too,
I think.
And then it's added to the current value of X.
So adding a negative to to a current value of X would just incremental backwards by
negative too.
But it doesn't work.
The bite does not work.
So it is better to do an interview in this case.
And then if we run this code,
we're going to actually have a countdown.
15 13 11 975 and then and sub.
Okay,
this is how you can control the increment ation value for your variable,
and you can do a negative value that is,
you can count down as well.
You can also do a decimal value for the incantation value.
But you need to make sure to change the data type for your variable to something that can
hold decimals because the inter jury cannot hold decimals.
So here we can do 15 to 5 with a step negative,
open five.
And that means that we're gonna count down by 1/2.
So 15 14.5 14 13.5 in this.
And it's a too long.
So I'm just gonna execute the macro straight away,
no step by step until we reach the value off five,
as you can see here.
And you can also do a positive decimal as well.
So if you make this just opened five and you make this 5 to 15 you can increment with a
step of positive or 150.5 as well.
Just make sure the you select the correct variable data cyp.
Okay,
so let's see it,
guys,
for the for next loop.
Thank you very much watching this video.
I know.
See you on the next one