Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So so far,
we've seen that the only way to exit a four loop is to actually reach the end for the
counter or to reach the lost pass in the loop or their loss.
It aeration.
So,
for example,
for X equals 1 to 10 that means that the loop will not end unless we reach X To be equal to
10 we do the 10th pass or the 10th iteration through the loop.
However,
there is another way that you can exit a four loop at any point in the loop using the exit
for statement.
Now,
we're gonna have an example here.
And although it's a trivial example,
a represents the case when you want to exit a four loop based on a certain condition and
you will not know when this condition is going to be satisfied or which inspiration it
could be satisfied.
In the first iteration on the 10th the duration,
you don't know,
he just want to exit the loop when this condition is satisfying.
Okay,
so this macro here that we're gonna have is going to represent that case.
So let's go through the macro here and know what it does.
So,
basically,
on column Max,
here I've put the values 12 30 in cells X one to X 30.
The first step in this macro is that it's going to determine what the last row in column X
is which is gonna be row number 30 and then is going to say for I equals one to L.
R.
And eyes basically our counter and our L R is going to be 30 at old times because the last
row and column axis 30 there's something that will not change.
First of all,
we're going to generate a random number,
and this random number is gonna be an integer between one and the value of the L R,
which is basically 30.
And I don't need you to worry about the four minute for generating this random number.
Okay,
I just want you to focus on the fact that this formula would just generate a random number
between one and the value of L.
R,
which is 30 and then we're basically going to start selecting the cell based on the
iteration loop.
So we're going to select cells.
I common 24.
So basically,
if we're in the first iteration.
We're going to select Sell X one.
If we're in the second iteration,
we're going to select Sell X two and so on and so forth.
And then we're gonna test if the value of the active cell is equal to the random number.
And if that's the case,
we're going to get a message box that says we reached our goal after our situation.
So we're just gonna report that we reached our goal after I iterations and actually always
gonna be the number of the inspiration.
Basically,
this is why we put a variable for for this cause we don't know when we're going to reach
our goal.
And our goal is to basically have the value of the active cell equal to the random number
that we generated.
That is between one and 30 and then we're gonna exit for and this exit for statement.
What it does is a exits,
the four next loop,
and it works for the four each lupas Well,
that we're going to see in the future just gonna exit it and execute any statement after it
,
which in our case,
Siri's just gonna be the end sub statements so as to exit the macro.
However,
what happens if we don't reach our goal?
So if we go through all the 30 cells and we test the values in the 30 cells against the
random number and we never have a random number equal to the value of the current active
cell,
we're gonna have a message box.
We haven't reached our goal with a sad face here.
And then at this point,
because we're gonna have I to be equal to the value of the last year or I to be equal to 30
.
We're gonna have all our reiterations finished.
So we're basically gonna end if and actually there won't be any more passes or it orations
on the loop to do so.
Gonna execute any statement after the for next loop,
and it's gonna be the ends up statement and we're just gonna exit the macro.
So here the purpose of this micro this procedure is to show you the scenario when you're
going to do a loop and you wanna exit the loop based on a condition.
But you don't know when this condition is going to be satisfied,
and hence this is why we're generating around the number.
Okay,
So as to have the condition be satisfied at a point that you don't know when it's gonna be
satisfied.
Okay,
so you don't know on which pass off the loop or which alteration you're gonna have your
conditions satisfied.
And this why you're using is it for you testing for a condition and when it's satisfied to
use the exit for statement.
So start executing the macro here.
I'm gonna go through it step by step by using F eight on my keyboard.
So here,
I'm going to get the value of the last row to be equal to 30 and then here is gonna before
I is equal to 12 thirties.
We're going to do 30 passes on this for next loop.
However,
with my exit,
if we satisfy her condition before the 30th pass or the 33 duration.
So now we're gonna generate a random number is trying to remember is 25 we're going to
select cells are common 24 which in this case,
because eyes equal to one is gonna be so x one and then we're gonna test is the value of
the actor cell equal to the random number.
The value of the active cell is one.
And the value of the run,
remember,
is equal to 25.
So they're not equal and a re on the loss situation.
No,
we're not.
So where we going to do?
We're just gonna go into another pass on the loop,
going to generate another random number.
It's 25 as well.
We're gonna test is equal to the value of the active cell.
No,
it is not.
So we're going to do again and keep on doing now.
The active cell here is for and run the numbers 30.
So no actor sells five and render numbers 28.
So no.
Six and seven.
No,
they're not equal.
Seven and 21.
They're not equal nine and eight.
They are not equal 11 and four.
So we're going to keep on doing that until they become equal.
And they're still not equal on any pass.
See you guys,
the Rendon this factor here were generating random number,
and we don't know on which pass.
We're gonna have to exit the loop 23 10.
No,
they're not equal.
So here we have not reached our goal.
We've done 30 passes and we could not get the value of the active cell to be equal to the
random number so we can execute the macro again.
And it says again here,
After 30 passes,
we have not reached our goal.
And here we restart Goal after 11 alterations.
So you can see here the after 11 it rations.
We've managed to have a random number equal to the value of the active cell.
And what happened here is that a message box reached our goal.
Author 11 It's orations got executed.
And then we executed the exit for statement and we exited the loop basically,
and we executed the end sub which ends our macro.
Okay,
so this macro,
although it is trivial,
it's a trivial example Over illustrates the run in this factor when you want to exit the
loop.
But you don't know on which iteration you're gonna need to exit that loop.
So I hope that illustrates the exits for statement for you.
It is used to basically exit your loop at any point,
and you can use it with a condition to exit a loop because you don't know on which it
aeration.
Exactly.
You're going to need to exit the loop this while you put a condition on.
Based upon that,
you execute the exit for a statement and you exit the loop.
OK,
so I hope that was informative for you.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see you on the next one.