Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about the four each loop,
so the for each loop enables us to loop through objects in a collection of objects.
So,
for example,
we can loop through all the worksheets in a collection of worksheets or the worksheets
collection.
We can look through all the cells in a range because arranges essentially a collection off
cells.
We can move through all the workbooks in the workbooks collection as well.
We could look through all the charts in the charts collection,
so it enables us to loop through each object in a collection of objects.
And usually you will have the relationship between the object and the collection as being
just a singular and the plural.
So,
for example,
worksheet and work sheets worksheet is the object,
and the collection of objects is the work sheets collection.
Okay,
so it's gonna be pretty easy and pretty consistent in most of the cases.
So the structure off the four each loop is basically for each object in collection,
and then you would have some code to perform and then next object.
And here the object after next is optional you don't have to write the object.
So this is a structure for each object in collection.
So for each worksheet in worksheets collection,
for example,
some code that you're gonna apply on it and usually you would have the object itself
referenced in that code.
So you're gonna,
for example,
display the name for that particular object.
So for each worse sheet just worksheet name,
we put it inside a message box or debug dot print for that name or so and then next objects
.
This is the structure off the for each loop.
So let's see an example off the for each loop.
Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna have an example for the four each loop and this example,
What it does is that it loops through all the worksheets in the active workbook.
So here,
first of all,
we've created an object variable that is called Ws,
and it's type is gonna be a you worksheet on.
Then you were saying for each ws,
which is basically a worksheet in worksheets,
and this worksheets would refer to the worksheets collection in the current active workbook
.
OK,
so this will work on the active workbook,
not a sense city on the workbook that the macro is is written in.
So you need to make sure that the workbook that you need to loop through its worksheets is
the one that is active.
If you want to make sure that you would look through the worksheets in the workbook that
the macro is written in,
you write this workbook dot worksheets or whatever work booked out worksheets,
OK?
And we've learned before how to refer to a workbook on previous videos.
So this will make sure that you would loop through the worksheets in the workbook that the
macro is written in.
So what's gonna happen here when we lived through the worksheets?
We're gonna actually not select each worksheets because you're going to see here when we
loop through.
If you look on the bottom left corner here,
you're not going to see that the word sheets are being selected.
So looping through the worksheets does not essentially mean selecting OK,
so we will not select them.
We can do stuff to the worksheets.
The are allowed without selecting the worksheets.
But we do not have to essentially select um and then we have the next w s statement here
that basically enables us to go to the next worksheet.
And if all the worksheets are finished than we will basically exit the loop and ah,
please know as well that the ws part here is optional You don't have to write next Ws you
could right next.
But being explicit is a good practice.
Ok,
now let's run through the loop step by step here.
So I'm gonna press f eight whoever each worksheet in this workbook that worksheets and then
debugged apprint w esta name What this is going to do?
Is this gonna print the name of the worksheet in the immediate window here below?
So everybody execute this step.
We've started looping and we first of all,
look through she one as the first sheet to look through,
and we typed its name here in the immediate window.
And then we're going to move through the next seat and we take the name of sheet to and
notice here that she,
too has not been selected.
Okay,
if you need to select the sheet than you need to type a statement that says ws star,
activate to activate the worksheet and then if we continue looping,
we would look through the third cheat and this is the lost sheet.
So we're not gonna loop anymore.
We're just gonna exit the for each loop and and sub.
So this is how you can look through worksheets in a collection of worksheets,
okay?
Or basically in a workbook.
Now I want to show you something else as well.
Which is what happens if you leave it like that.
As for each ws in worksheets instead of this workbook of worksheets,
instead of being specific,
what's gonna happen here is that you're gonna loop through the worksheets in the current
active workbook.
So currently got the workbook called for each loop that has sheets 12 and three as the
So we will actually have the names of these sheets typed here in the immediate window.
I've got another workbook,
that school book one here that has sheets called one x two x and three X.
Now,
if we go through the macro this way,
we'll actually type the names of sheets one x and two X and three acts because Book one is
the active workbook.
So here,
if you leave it like just worksheets.
And you don't specify in which workbook is just gonna loop through the worksheets in the
active workbook.
OK,
so basically,
it's a better practice to specify which workbook contains the worksheets that you need to
loop through.
Okay,
this is a better practice and is going to make you avoid problems on the next video.
We're going to see how to move through mawr objects.