Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to have more examples for the for each loop.
So we're going to see how to loop through more types of objects.
Okay,
so let's see how to loop through a range of cells.
So a range of cells is a collection that contains cells.
Because a range is a collection of cells,
the range does not contain anything but cells.
So if we want to loop through a range of cells,
we need to first of all,
create a range object so dim see as range,
for example here and I named it see because it sends for cells.
But you could name anything,
and then we would write a for each loop.
So for each see in range.
And let's say I want toe loop through the range of cells between a one and 18.
So range sells one comma one and cells turn calma.
One next see?
So this is our for each loop.
So first of all,
we will select that particular cell,
and then on that cell,
we could put,
for example,
the row numbers of cedar values equal to see dot ro.
So what's gonna happen here is that we're gonna loop through the range of cells between a 1
to 8 10 We're going to select each cell,
and we're gonna put the row number for that cell in that particular cell.
So let's go through the coat step by step here.
So,
as you can see here,
looping through,
we're going to select cell A one.
Currently,
we are and sell a one,
and then we're gonna put one here in cell a one,
and then we're gonna go to sell a too and select it and we're gonna put two and sell a to.
And if we keep on executing the code here is gonna go through each cell and put the row
number for that particular cell in that cell.
OK,
so this is a simple example on how to look through a range of cells.
By the way,
if you remove here,
the line of code for creating an object variable has arranged.
This will work as well.
But on your code,
you will not have the 02 complete feature here.
So you will not have suggestions on what properties or methods are for that.
See object here that you're using.
And by the way,
XlV B A will still recognize this as a range object,
even if you don't declare it as a range object.
Because Exelby understands that if you are looping through a range of cells than each one
of them is a range or a cell,
basically,
so even if you do do not declare,
it will still work.
But,
of course,
it's a better practice to declare your variables.
Okay,
so let's have another example on how to look through workbooks,
so to move through workbooks.
It's the same idea as well.
So we will declare a workbook,
objects a dim WB as workbook,
for example.
So declare a workbook object variable.
And then we would say,
for example,
or each WB in workbooks next WB.
And please note that this would loop through workbooks that are currently opens of the
workbooks,
your looping through need to be already open.
So what we would do,
for example,
is that we would have a message box,
wb dot name,
and currently I've got to work books open.
I've got the workbook for the for next loop and the workbook for the four each.
Duke So if I run this step by step,
so if I step through the macro,
we're gonna display the name of each workbook.
So now we've got the for each loop workbook on,
then before next loop workbook and displayed their name.
And then there gnome or open workbooks.
So we're gonna exit the loop and and sub.
Okay,
so we've seen how to move through different types of collections.
We've seen out to look through worksheets and seen how to look through a range of cells.
And we've seen how to look through a collection of workbooks.
And this same concept can be applied to any other collection in Excel V B A.
So you can loop through a collection of pivot tables and you can also look through a
collection of charts and so on and so forth.
Also,
please note that you can use that exit for statement with the for each loop the same way
that you can use it with the four next loop so you can use the exit for to exit your loop
at any point.
So that's it,
guys.
For the for each loop.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see you on the next one