Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another type of loops which is the do Loop and the Do loop has a
general structure of do and then whatever code you need to be executed over and over again
and then the word loop.
However,
if you use the do loop in this structure,
the loop will just keep on getting executed over and over again.
And it will not stop unless you do something special,
like use the exit,
do statement or use a go to statement.
Or so this is why it's actually got to variations.
The are used usually,
and these two variations are to do until and do y o.
So the do until has a structure of do until condition is equal to two and then some code
and then loop.
Or alternatively,
it could be written as do and then code,
and then loop until condition is equal to true.
So actually,
on the do until whatever code you put inside the loop will be just performed over and over
again until a certain condition is true.
So whatever that condition is satisfied and becomes to the loop will seize to be executed.
The Lupul just and and you will exit the loop and perform whatever code is after the loop
and on the do while,
as you can see here,
it's got a structure of do while condition is equal to true,
and then the code,
and then loop,
or do and then the code,
and then loop while the condition is equal to true.
So the do while structure we'll get whatever could you put in there performed over and over
again as long as a condition is true while a condition is true,
so as long as this condition is true,
the code is just going to be executed over and over against.
This is the difference between to do while on do until to do until it's performed until a
condition is true and the do while is performed while a condition is true,
or or as long as a condition is true.
So if the condition turns is out to be false on the do while the loop is just gonna end and
we will execute whatever code is after the loop.
So what's the difference between the two variations on each structures so What's the
difference between the one on the left and the one on the right,
for example?
Well,
the difference is on the one on the left here.
The condition will be evaluated before the code is executed,
so we will not execute the code at all before evaluating the condition.
However,
on the one on the right,
we could have at least one pass through the code before the condition is evaluated.
And so,
in terms of performance,
the variation on the left here can be faster than the one on the right.
Because with the one on the left,
you could have the condition to be equal to two and not have to execute the code,
not have to do that.
One passed through the code and this could save you time on your code.
So the one on the left here could save you more time in case the condition is evaluated to
to before going through the code one time and the same goes for the do while as well on the
do I owe.
The one on the left here can save you time as well,
because the condition is evaluated before the code is executed at least once.
So this conceive you time as well.
So this was a quick introduction about the Do Loop on the upcoming videos.
We're gonna go into more depth about the do loop,
and we're going to see some examples as well.
So thanks,
guys.
Watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one.