Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to speak about how to record a basic macro.
So in order to record a basic Makary need to go to the developer tab on the ribbon and then
click on record macro.
So this way you're able to record some actions and then play them back whenever you want.
So as you can see here,
I've got a dollar box that enables me to name the macro so I can name it my micro,
for example.
And the naming of the macro has some restrictions.
So,
for example,
you cannot put a space on the name of the micro.
So if I put a space here and click OK,
you're going to get this hour here.
The syntax of this name is not correct.
So basically,
you cannot put a space.
You cannot put an exclamation more a dollar sign.
So basically,
there are some signs here on the keyboard that you cannot use.
However,
you can actually use an underscore if you want to,
so I can emit my macro this way.
And here you can assign a short cut key so it can be control and any other key on the
keyboard and you can make it control and shifted.
And here,
for example,
also,
you have the option to store the macro either in this workbook,
which is this work with this currently open here in the school Book one or you can store in
a new workbook.
So this way,
if you click OK in,
your book will be open and the MCA will be stored in that workbook.
Or if you choose to store in the personal macro workbook this way it will be starting in a
workbook called the Personal Macro workbook.
And this enables you to have the macro available in each and every workbook that you open
in excel.
From now on,
I'm just gonna choose to start in this workbook and I'm gonna click.
OK,
so this way I've started recording the macro What I'm going to do.
I'm going to select cell a one and type my name and then press enter and then I'm going to
stop recording.
So now I've recorded a macro and only does is that it puts my name in cell a one.
Now to examine that macro,
you can go under the developer top here,
you can go to my crows and here on my macro,
you conclude con ed it and then you can have a look at the code of the recorded macro.
You can also click on old and F 11 on your keyboard.
And here on module one year you will find the macro.
And a module is basically a container for your Marko's.
Think about it this way.
We'll speak about it as well later on in the course.
Okay,
so we've recorded a macro and xlv B A has just recorded our actions and transformed them
into some code.
So now I can actually delete here the contents of cell a one.
And if I just go to Macron's again and here on my macro,
I click on Run the macro is going to run and is gonna put my name in cell a one.
So as you can see,
Your Excel just repeated our actions again.
And our actions here are to be secure so that sell anyone put my name in the cell and then
because when you press enter,
you go to the cell just below it.
So here we've gone to sell a to sell it to has been selected.
And if you do not understand what this code does,
do not worry.
By the end of the course,
or even by the middle of the course,
you be able to understand it perfectly fine.
So don't worry about the code at the moment,
OK,
one more thing I want to tell you as well is that if you need to save a workbook that
contains a micro's,
if I press controlling as to save my workbook here and here on save eyes,
if I click on browse,
you can see her.
I have the chance to save the workbook.
You need to make sure to save it as an excel macro enabled workbook.
You cannot save it as an Excel workbook because it normal Excel workbook will not save a
macro.
One more thing I want to show you as well is how you can assign a macro to a button or a
shape so you can insert a simple button here by going to the insert button here under the
developer tab and clicking on button.
And here you have a button,
and then if you click OK,
the button will be inserted.
So in order to assign the macro to that bun,
you can right click on the button itself and click on a sign macro,
and then assign your macro here that you recorded called my macro,
for example,
and then click.
OK,
And then whenever you press that,
bend them back,
crow is going to run.
You can also do it with the shape so it can insert any shape here,
insert a shape and then right click on it a sign,
macro and a sign the macro as well.
And this works with any form control here under the developer tab on the insert button here
so you can insert any active extra form control and then assigned the macro to that control
using the same way.
And if you need to edit the text inside so you can right click here,
click on edit text and you can at it the text as well.
Okay,
so that's it,
guys,
for recording a basic macro.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see you on the next one