Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss to do until structure.
So I've got an example here,
and it's actually the same cold,
except that I've done it as do until loop instead of just a do loop,
a simple do loop.
And here what we're going to do We're going to select cell a one and then we're just gonna
execute that code here,
which is to go one cell down until the value of the active cell is equal to 10.
As you can see here,
in column may have written some numbers year between one and 27.
And if we try to execute this code,
well,
first of all,
so that cell a one and then we're just gonna go one cell down until the value of the active
cell is equal to 10.
And then what happens when the value of the active cell is equal to 10?
We stop and we exit the loop and we go to the ends up statement.
And as you could notice here,
we actually check for the condition first before executing the code which is going one cell
down.
So this is the do until structure.
If we switch that to a loop until structure and we try to execute that code.
So we're gonna sell Excel a one,
and then we're going to go down one cell and then check for the condition,
go down one cell,
check for the condition,
not check for the condition,
and then go down.
One sell.
Well,
guys,
this is the difference here.
So as you can see here,
we execute the code first,
and then we check for our condition.
And in some cases,
depending on the scenario and what you're doing,
the do until will be more efficient than the loop until okay,
but this of course,
depends on situation and what you're doing in your code and everything.
So that's a simple example for the do until loop.
Thank you very much.
Watching this video I'll see on the next one