Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna have a simple example for the do while loop.
So we're going to do the same,
actually,
as what we were doing on the example for the do until so here.
I've got some code and is going to select cell a one.
And then while the value of the active cell is less than 10 we're actually going to go one
step down or one cell down.
So as long as the value of the active cell is less than 10 we're just going to keep on
going one step down.
So if I execute this code using F eight,
I'm first consider Akseli one and then I'm going to check.
And as long as the value of the cell is less than 10 we're going to keep on going One step
down.
So now here we are on cell a 10 that contains the value of tens to here.
This condition is not gonna be satisfied because the value of the active cell is not less
than 10 because it's currently tends is not less than 10.
So we're gonna exit the loop and execute the end soap.
Now,
if we switch to the do loop while structure.
So here,
if I execute this code,
you can see her that we actually,
instead of checking for the condition first and then executing the code,
we execute the code first,
and then we check for the condition.
We're going to get the same result in this case.
But in some other cases,
using the do while structure is better than using the do loop.
Ah,
wild structure.
It old depends on your code and what you're trying to achieve.
And so,
but in a lot of cases,
using do while loop is better than using Do loop oil guy.
So this was a simple example for the do.
Well,
Lou,
thank you very much for watching this video I'll see on the next one.