Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to see the exit do statement.
And also we're going to see a do loop where actually we would create a counter to count how
many passes or how many interational we've done in the loop.
So here,
we're gonna have actually the same example that we had previously on the exit for statement
where we hade a random number generated,
and we wanted it to be equal to the value of the active cell.
And this Rendon This factor is a scenario that you might face where you don't know on which
iteration or in which passed.
You're gonna need to exit the loop.
So here I've got some variables.
The last row where we actually get the last row here on column X,
I is basically our counter and also the random number.
So we will actually activate the worksheet that's called Introduction that has our example
here.
And then we're going to get the last row on column X,
and then we're gonna actually select the first cell in column acts,
and then we're going to set the initial value for our counter to be zero.
Okay,
and then we're going to start our do loop.
We're gonna create a random number on each pass on the loop.
And also,
we're gonna increment our counter by one so as to have this counter count how many passes
or how many alterations were done in the loop.
So we'll create a random number and we will test if the value of the active cell is equal
to the random number.
And here we are on the first cell in column X currently.
And then if the random number is equal to value the active cell,
then we're going to get a message box that we've reached our goal after whatever number of
it rations and we will exit the do loop.
And also,
if that's not the case,
then we will test if we are on the last row.
If eyes equal to the last row.
So the number of iterations that we've done is equal to the last road.
And if that's the case,
if the number of it orations is equal to the last row,
then that means that we have done all our 30th durations and still we haven't reached our
goal.
So will display a message,
Boxes says.
We haven't reached our goal and exit the do loop.
However,
if we still have it orations to do so,
the number of it orations is not equal to the last row.
We will actually execute this statement,
which is to go to the next cell and then weaken,
Do another iteration and then we can increment our counter by one and start doing another
iteration and so on and so forth until we reach all 30th orations.
So let's go through that macro step by step here.
So,
first of all,
I'm going to select the worksheet called Introduction Here is to make sure I select the
correct worksheet.
I'm going to get the last row on column acts,
which is 30.
I'm also gonna select the first cell here in column X and then I'm gonna set the initial
value for my counter to be zero.
I'm going to start my do loop.
So now the value of all he is equal to zero.
Now we're going to give it a value of one source to incremental it by one,
and to indicate now that we are in the first pass on the loop we're going to generate a
random number and we're gonna ask the question,
is the value of the actor so equal to the random number?
The random members currently 22 the value the active cell is currently one.
So there no equal.
So we're gonna do the loop again and keep on doing it until the value of the actor cell is
equal to the random number.
So if I keep on executing this macro,
if I continue press here the play button and this year we haven't reached our goal.
So we've done 30 passes through Lupin,
generated 30 numbers,
and they've never been equal to the value of the active cell.
We could run it again and we still haven't reached our goal.
And we can try again and we still haven't reached.
Our goal is really a random thing.
So and here we've reached our go after 11 integrations.
So you can see here that we managed to reach our goal on one pass here and exit the loop
before we've gone through all the it orations.
OK,
so the exit do statement does the same thing as the exit for statement,
except that we use it with the do loop.
And we've seen here a technique as well on how to count the number of iterations that
you've done in a do loop.
So maybe you would want account that for whatever reason,
maybe you're testing your macro and you want to include that technique in order to know
when you reach your goal.
After how many alterations,
Maybe you'd want to run it several times and know on average,
after how many alterations you reach your goal.
So that's it for this example where we learned the exit do statement,
and we've learned as well how to count the number of inspirations that we've done in a
doodle.
Thank you very much for watching this video and L c on the next one.