Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna have an exercise for the do loop.
So we're actually going to do the same exercise that we did on the for each loop.
But we're going to do it.
This thing using a do loop toe haidl the sheets in this workbook except for the exercise
sheet.
And of course,
you know your hint that you're going to use a property for sheets,
which is the doubt visible.
Here's the link for the property.
If you want to read about it on MST on,
so please attempt the exercise.
And if you get stuck,
I've actually got the answer here on this module called Exercise Answer.
You can have a look at the answer if you get stuck,
but please attempt the exercise first.
And if you have any questions,
please leave them in the Q and a section.
Thank you very much for watching this video,
and I'll see you on the next one