Alright,
guys,
let's have some examples for the different types of errors that we might encounter in xlv B
A.
So if you write workbooks my workbook and then I miss the second double quote here and a
close of rockets dot open You can see air We got a compiler,
but before we even got them SMIs itch box for the compile Ari kas here the R code turned
red.
So this is a syntax error.
Your co turning grad means you have a syntax error.
You have a grammar or spelling mistake.
So our grammar spending mistake here is that we didn't put the second double quote.
So this is a Syntex er now to have an example for a compiler.
Let's say we put instead of workbooks,
we put just the word workbook here.
Now this is still not generated this Syntex air because the word workbook is a word that is
part of the XlV be a dictionary.
So VB a recognizes this word as part of its dictionary and so he will not tell you there's
a spelling mistake.
However,
when it tries to run the code,
it will generate to compel er because although the word workbook exists in the V B A
dictionary.
It is not put in the right context.
It's it does not make sense to put it in this context.
So if you run the code here,
you'll get a compiler because the word workbook cannot be used in this context.
So you need to use workbooks,
not workbook.
So this is a compiler now to have an example for a run time error.
If we write worksheets,
my worksheet dot select.
As you can see here,
our code has not turned red.
So that means that there isn't a syntax error.
And also we can check for compel ER,
and we can do that even before running our code by going to the debug menu here and
clicking on Compile VB a project.
So if you click on that and we don't get an error,
that means that there aren't any compel Er's on our code.
And if we run this code,
though,
we will get in error.
And the reason for that is that although this action is a valid action to select a
worksheet called my Worksheet,
we will not be able to do it because we do not have a worksheet that is called my worksheet
in this current workbook.
So if you run that,
you're getting harassed out of range,
and that is because we do not have a worksheet in this work work that is called my
worksheet that we can select.
So this is a valid action.
However,
we cannot do it because there isn't a worksheet that's called my worksheet that exists now
.
The errors that you're gonna be dealing with the most or that you're gonna be encountering
the most are actually one time errors because syntax errors are gonna be pretty obvious
when you write your code,
you will have it highlighted in red indicating the part of your code is having a problem.
And most of the time you'll be able to figure out what the problem is on.
Compel ours as well are going to get you an error and that part of the code and actually
your cold will not start running in the first place.
So be able to discovery pretty early over run time.
Errors can happen,
actually,
after the code runs for some time.
And even after you try the code several times where on some trials.
Your code runs fine.
And on others,
your code would generate an error.
So this is actually the error type that you're gonna be spending most of your towing
focusing on and handling,
which is the run time errors.
So,
on the upcoming videos,
we're going to be focusing on how to handle one time errors.
We're going to see different methods and techniques to do that.
So thank you for watching this video and I'll see on the next one.