Okay,
guys.
So now we're gonna introduce a very important statement that you're going to use Ah lot
when handling errors,
which is the on error statement.
Okay,
so let's say I've written this line of code here.
Worksheets,
my work,
she does select.
And actually,
there isn't a worksheet that is called my work shit in this workbook.
So if you run that,
you will get a runtime our sister out of range Soil press end year and try to deal with
Blair.
The simplest form of dealing with the air is to write on her resume next,
so honor resume.
Next.
What it does is that it just simply ignores the error.
So this statement is gonna cause an error.
We'll just ignore it and execute anything after it.
So maybe message box.
We have ignored the error.
And if we just execute that,
let's do it step by step,
actually.
So on her resume next year.
And so now any statement there's gonna cause an error that is gonna come after on air a
resume.
Next,
the error is just gonna be ignored,
OK?
And please note that is gonna be for any statement that would cause an error.
Not just this statement here.
Worksheets might work.
She does select any statement that would cause air.
From now on,
after executing the honor resume,
next line of code is gonna be ignored.
So now works.
It's my work.
She select this schools in Arab,
but it actually is gonna be ignored.
And then we'll execute this message box,
and that's it.
OK,
so here the macro ends.
And so if we write actually another statement that would cause an error.
So my worksheets Another where?
Sheet.
I'm just gonna call it another worksheet.
Select.
So this one as well should cause an error.
But because it's part of our mockery execute this statement here on our resume Next,
this is going to affect this statement there is gonna be ignored.
And this statement is,
Well,
area is gonna be ignored and then going to get our message box.
that's a very easy way to who ignore errors.
But you're just ignoring them.
You're not handling them.
You're not creating a work around or a solution for the air.
Okay,
but this is the simplest form.
Sometimes you're going to use it is the simplest thing that you can do.
There are more sophisticated or more complex stuff that you can do on handling errors