Okay,
guys.
So another way to handle the errors that is more sophisticated than just ignoring them is
actually using the on error.
Go to statement.
So with the on our go to statement,
you can create a point that you Congar 02 in case that there is an error.
So,
for example,
here on our code,
let's say we have this line of code here.
Worksheets,
my worksheet select this line of code will create an error,
a runtime error because we don't have a worksheet that is called my worksheet that exists
in this workbook.
So I've got here this statement that is written before it on error go to create my
worksheet.
So it will go to this point here called Create my Worksheet in case of having an error.
So on this point called create my worksheet me to have some code to handle the error.
So,
for example,
we can create that particular worksheet that is called my worksheet.
So you could write worksheets dot ad and then active sheet.
The name is equal to my worksheet.
This is one way of doing it.
This is one way off creating a new worksheet.
There is also another way is where she dot ADOT name is equal to my worksheet.
So if we run this code this way,
it's stepped through it step by step here,
so I'll start running the code here.
We're gonna run this line of code here that is going to throw an error.
So what's gonna happen because of the air?
We're gonna go to the part here for creating a new worksheets are gonna go to create my
worksheet.
And if you execute that,
you can see her that a new worksheet has been created this cold Molly worksheet.
So this is a way of handling the error in case the work she does not exist.
We're gonna go to create it.
Okay,
so this way your code would not throw an error.
so let's say that I have more code,
actually,
after selecting my worksheet after the line of court for selecting the worksheet called
Molly Worksheet.
So let's say I'm gonna put in cell a one I'm gonna put today state.
And now let's say that this line of code has failed,
so I'm gonna go to create the sheet.
So what if I want to resume executing the lines of code after the one that's caused the ER
,
we can actually write the line of code resume next,
so resume next will actually go back to the line of code that's caused the error,
but it will not executed.
It will execute any line of code after so start executing any lines of code after the line
of code that's caused the error.
So now I'm gonna delete this worksheet here called Molly Worksheet.
I'm gonna go back to my visual basic environment and let's start executing the code step by
step here.
So on our go to create me worksheet and then you can see here,
I'm gonna execute this line of code,
which is going to throw an error.
So we're gonna go to create the work sheep.
And so I've created it.
Now watch what happens when I execute the resume next line of code here,
it will go and execute any lines of code after the one that's caused theorist.
So here,
we're gonna execute this one here that is gonna put today's date in cell a one.
Now if we execute the following line of code,
it will actually go and execute the line of code for adding a new worksheet called my
Worksheet,
which is gonna cause an error because we already have a worksheet called my worksheet.
So in this case,
we need to exit the macro,
so it's better to write exit sub here after I've done what I wanted to do and put my date
in cell a one.
If I don't want to do anything more,
I will just exit the macro.
Okay,
so it's better to do it this way.
If we delete the worksheet,
called my worksheet and start executing our code again here,
we're going to select the work she called my worksheet and it doesn't exist.
We're going to create a new work.
She called my worksheet and then resume next,
put the date and then exit the macro.
So this is a more advanced way than just ignoring the errors.
To use the honor,
go to statement and use the resume next statement here in case we want to go back and
execute any lines of quote after the one that's caused the air.
OK,
so thanks,
guys,
for watching this video.
I'll see you on the next one