Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss the UN ergo 20 statement so the on error go to zero.
What it does is that it resets the air handling status in your VB a code to the default
status which is basically throwing an error.
So in case that you do not do any error handling,
what's gonna happen is that when VB encounters,
an area is just going to throw the runtime error on the message box and you're going to see
a message box.
It says runtime error.
This is the default air handling status in xlv B A.
And what this is useful for is if we have different statements that can potentially cause
errors on our code,
and we want to treat each statement differently or handle the error that could potentially
be caused by each statement differently.
So,
for example,
here on this example,
we've got the line of code worksheets,
my worksheet select.
This could potentially throwing error.
However,
if we run it right now,
while the work she does called my worksheet is created,
it will not throw an error.
And we've got this statement here on error go to create my worksheet.
But what if I put another line of code that will create an error?
So I put range a one equals one divided by zero.
So this will create a division by zero error.
Now,
watch what happens when we run this line of code.
So let's start running the macro step by step.
So this line of code will not cause an error for activating the worksheet called Molly
Worksheet because it already exists over when we run this line of code,
it will actually go to the create my worksheet.
Because remember,
guys,
when I told you that when we write in on our statement,
it will actually start a status of her handling for any statement that follows this
statement.
So as you can see her,
if we run this line of code and it will cause an error,
it will actually go to create my worksheet.
And it will create a worksheet that is called my worksheet.
While we do actually have a worksheet already.
So this will throw an error.
So actually this air was handled using the same way as the ER that would potentially be
occurring from this statement and this is something that we do not want to do because this
is a division by zero.
It's not related to creating a worksheet,
so we would want to handle it differently.
So if we add a statement here on error,
go to zero.
This statement resets the air handling status in your VB a code.
So now we will go to the default,
are handling status,
which is actually that if we encounter inner here,
we're gonna have a division by zero error and then we can actually put another type of
error handling.
So on air,
go to message box,
for example.
And then we would have here a message box placeholder here and we would have a message box
.
You cannot divide by zero,
and it is better as well to put an on error,
go to zero statement here so that any statement after that one here would not be handled
the same way unless you have more statements that can be handled the same way or that can
take the same error.
Handling goes on our go to message box so you can put them here in between the owner go to
message box on the owner.
Go to zero.
So,
as you can see here,
we've used the honor go to zero statement here to reset the air handling status so as to go
back to the default status and start a different status for handling this different error.
So it begins here.
If we run the code right now,
where she eats my work,
she does selects that this will not cause an error.
And then we go to the default air handling status and we start a new era handling status,
which is to go to the message box.
And now this statement causing her will go to the message box.
You cannot divide by zero,
and then we'll reset our handling status again and exit the sub.
So we use the honor,
go to zero statement to reset our handing status because not all hours should be handled
the same way.
So that's it,
guys,
for the honor,
go to zero statement.
Thank you very much for watching this video and I'll see on the next one