Okay,
guys.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss another feature in error handling,
which is how to set up a break point on your code.
So a break point enables your code to stop executing at a certain point that you will
specify.
And this is gonna be especially useful in events because you cannot execute events step by
step.
By pressing F eight on your keyboard,
you will need to set up a break point to stop the coat from executing and be able to
troubleshoot it.
So to set up a break point for your code,
you can just click inside the line that you want your coat to stop executing at.
And then in this gray bar here,
beside it on the left,
you can just click this way.
You've tuggle the break point,
and if you run your code,
it will stop.
At this point,
it will not go beyond it.
So if I just stop executing my code here if I want toe untouchable,
this break points Ooh,
remove the break point.
I can just click on this red circle here,
and it's gonna be removed.
Another way to tuggle a break point as well is to go to the debug menu here and click on
Double Break Point.
Or you can also press F knowing on your keyboard.
There is another way as well,
which is using the debug toolbar here.
So if you right click at the top and enable the debug to bar,
you can just click on this hand here,
which struggles a break point as well.
So I just wanted you to get introduced to the concept of creating a break point to stop
your coat from executing at a certain point,
because we will need that when using events,
and you can also use it in normal.
Macron's where you would want to stop your code from executing at a certain point and check
the values of some variables,
for example,
or so.
So that's it,
guys,
for troubling a break point.
Thank you very much watching this video and I'll see on the next one