Hey,
guys,
Welcome back.
Soon this video,
we're going to discussed a before right click event.
So therefore right Click Event does the same thing as the before DoubleClick event,
except that it just triggers the code on right clicking instead of double clicking on a
cell.
Okay,
so what happens when you right click on a cell?
So I'm going to right click.
So we get this menu.
This is what happens when you right click on a cell.
This is the default action.
OK,
so I'm going to right click here on my before,
right click worksheet and click on view code.
And then I'm going to select from this menu and select worksheet,
and I'm going to select it before Right click.
I'm just gonna delete here the selection change event and as you can see here,
is got two parameters.
The target as a range and the cancel as bullion.
So if you've guessed that the council would just disable the menu when right clicking Well
,
you did guess that true.
So let's say we want a message box to pop up on Lee.
If we right click on cell C three.
OK,
so we're going to do that.
So if Target,
I thought address.
And then I'm gonna put a full scum of false so that I can write the reference for the cell
without the dollar signs.
Okay.
Equals C three,
then message box.
You right?
Clicked cell C three.
Okay.
And if Ok,
so if I right click on any cell,
nothing's gonna happen.
Okay?
Just any other sell other than cell C three.
If I right click cell C three,
though you get the message box and notice here that has been executed before the default
action for right clicking,
which is viewing the menu.
Okay,
so it gets executed before viewing the menu.
Whatever code you right gets executed before the menu pops up.
Okay,
so what if I don't want the menu to pop up?
Well,
if you've guessed that we need to put a cancel,
the council equals true,
which is ah,
similar to what we've done on the double click to in order not to enter the cell editing
mode.
Well,
that is true.
Okay,
So we need to put the council equals true.
If we put the council equals true,
we right click,
and then you get the message box or whatever code you've written executed.
However you don't get the menu.
Okay,
so it works the same way.
Justus.
Double clicking.
Except it's for right clicking.
Okay,
so you can do some.
Ah,
nice stuff with that.
You could maybe have a ah,
form control.
Pop up whenever you right click or something like that.
Okay,
so that's it for the before,
right click events.
Very easy.
And I'll see you on the next.