Hey,
guys,
welcome back.
So in this video,
we're going to discuss calculate event.
So the calculate event happens when you just calculate the values in your worksheet and the
values get calculated whenever he changes cell.
Okay?
And actually,
this happens for the whole workbook.
No,
just this particular sheet.
However,
you doing the event for for that particular sheet.
So we are on a sheet called calculate event and of gruesome random numbers here in Ah,
these cells okay.
And they're being generated by a function called ren between.
So this function will recalculate each time I changed the value of any other cell,
okay?
Or any cell actually in the workbook.
So if I just change the value of a cell,
numbers re calculate,
okay?
And now I'm also going to show you how you can calculate a sheet or a workbook as well,
so you can go to a former system on the ribbon click on calculate,
cheat,
and this will calculate your sheet If you click on calculate.
Now,
this will calculate your entire workbook,
which includes your sheet as well.
I don't typically have a lot of uses for the for this event.
Like I probably have never needed to use it.
But in case you need it,
it's there.
OK,
I'll show you as well the example that Microsoft ah ha's on their websites.
Okay,
so this is the example that Microsoft has on their website,
so he's actually just to oh,
to fit the columns A to F.
Whenever you do a calculation for the worksheet,
it's not particularly,
you know,
the best,
but we will try it.
So I'm gonna right click on the calculate event worksheet here,
click on view code,
and then I'm gonna goto worksheet and select the calculate event.
Okay,
And now we are in the worksheet calculate event,
okay?
And ah,
now let's run this.
Let's run this event.
So I'm just gonna change the value of any cell in this event.
Will run.
You can see here that Columns eight to have have had an odor fitting.
This is similar to selecting the columns here and double clicking on them.
And this will do the 02 fitting.
And also there is a recalculation done.
Okay.
And this will trigger your calculate event as well.
And one thing I want to tell you as well which is some sort of a word of caution.
You know,
this event will run whenever you do any sort of calculation on your workbook.
Ok?
Because your workbook were weak.
A candidate for any cell that you change the value off.
Okay,
so this event will got triggered a lot.
so if you've got some sort of any looping code,
you know,
any code that would take time to execute any A code that has lots of actions.
Okay,
this could slow down your workbook.
I haven't needed to use it.
But if there is ah,
use for that event for you,
I would be interested to know it basically.
Okay,
so Ah,
thank you very much.
Watching this video I'll see on the next.