Hello, and welcome to this course,
Working with Files in Java Using the Java NIO API.
We are first going to cover how to access files on
directory with this path object from Java 7.
My name is Jose.
I'm a Java Champion and JavaOne Rock Star,
and I'm very glad to be your steward for this course.
This course is about handling a text file using the JavaSE API.
So we are going to first cover how to access files in
general within directories using this API.
And then we will see how to write or read the text
content to files using the JavaSE API.
And after that, we will cover a very important and useful use case,
which is how to access the content of a CSV file.
You know this CSV format that can be generated by Excel,
for instance, the well‑known Microsoft spreadsheet.
Well we're going to see how to analyze the content of a
CSV file using the JavaSE patterns.
And the last part we're going to cover is how to move files around,
take a file from a directory, move it to another one or copy it to another one.
And in this part, we'll also see two very important patterns from Java 7,
which are the walk pattern.
This pattern has been updated to support the stream API. And we will also cover this part.