Being able to find a specific file in a set of directories is nice,
but it is not necessarily what you want to do.
Sometimes you want to visit a set of directories gathering some information,
something like counting all the JPEG files you have under those directories,
for instance. This could be a use case. And for that, you
need to visit a set of directories.
And in that case, what you probably need is some kind of visitor pattern.
Just providing a B predicate is not enough.
It is not going to solve your problem.
To address this problem,
we have two patterns called the walk pattern that allows
you to walk through a set of directories.
The first one has been made available in Java 7 and is called walkFileTree.
It takes a root directory as a parameter and a FileVisitor,
which is a callback, that is going to be called for any
element found in this hierarchy of directories.
And then we have a second pattern, more recent, that leverages the Stream API.
Instead of visiting every element using a callback,
it will provide all the elements in a stream, lazily computed so that you
don't lose any kind of performance. And you're going to process the content of
this directory with a map/filter/reduce approach.
So, let us see those two last patterns, walk patterns, in action
in this live coding part of this module. You will see how to
visit a hierarchy of directories first using the FileVisitor and second using the Stream API.