So what can you do with this path object?
Well, basically, you can do the same kind of thing as with the file object.
You can access file in roughly the same way,
but you can get more information,
especially specific attributes dependent on your file system object.
So in a nutshell, a path is just used to access a file or a
directory on the given file system. You can get information
on this file or directory,
especially the different elements directory you are going to go through
to access this file and the same if it is a directory.
You can check if this element contains symbolic links or not. And
through different factory methods from the Files class,
you can have more information on the file or directory represented by this path.
Basically,
can you read it, can you write it, can you execute it? Is this file or directory exists or not? This kind of information.