How can you create instances of this path object? Path is an interface.
So to create instances of it, to get instances of path,
you have to use factory methods.
Now we have two patterns to create those path instances. The original
patterns from Java 7 use a Paths factory class with an s,
and we have two get factory methods on this factory class.
And starting with Java 11,
we have factory methods directly on this path interface.
Why don't we have these path factory methods directly on
the interface right from the beginning?
Well,
just because in Java 7 it was not possible to
create factory method on interfaces.
This became possible starting with Java 8, so it has been introduced later on.
So let us see those patterns.
The first one is called the get method. And to this get method,
you just give a string a character,
representing the path on the file system that will access the file
or directory you need. The second one gets this path element by
element without giving the separator, and the factory method will
create the path accordingly.
And you also have a third one that is going to take a URI as a parameter.
Now you have a pattern to create this URI,
which uses another factory method. And once this URI has been created, you can
pass it to this get factory method to get your path instance.
And if you are using Java 11 or later,
you can also use the of factory method directly
accessible from this path interface.
So here are the main patterns on how to create a path instance on the default file system of your application.