Elastic Beanstalk is an application service that makes it easy to
run your code and scale it on AWS. Under the covers, it's simply
running your code on EC2 instances,
but it takes the typical use case of running an application and adds a lot
of conveniences that make AWS much easier to work with.
There are a few ways you can deploy an application on EC2
instances in AWS without Elastic Beanstalk.
The manual process involves a lot of configuration,
custom installation, and navigating the command line.
Any manual installation would need to solve for scaling by creating AMIs or
utilizing CloudFormation or other recipe scripting tools.
Monitoring of the application would also be tricky,
possibly utilizing third‑party services or creating custom CloudWatch rules.
And there are plenty more things that you would want to set
up when deploying your application on EC2.
Sounds like a long list of stuff to do, right?
I'm not trying to make it sound bad to scare you away from EC2,
but rather to showcase what Elastic Beanstalk is taking care of for you.
All the scenarios I just listed are automatically managed by Elastic Beanstalk.
Deploying your code with Elastic Beanstalk can take place from the web console,
through the AWS command line tool, or through the SDK.
The configuration of rules for scaling are set up once for a
given application environment and are then set,
letting you deploy your application as you make changes
without any additional tweaking required.
In addition,
Elastic Beanstalk lets you easily monitor and collect logs for your application,
even when it's deployed on multiple EC2 instances.
The main abstract structure in Elastic Beanstalk is an application.
This is the root‑level organization, be it your web application or web service.
An application will need a unique name to
differentiate it from other applications.
Inside each application can be many application versions.
This is the actual code that will run your
application with many different revisions.
With this code, which is just an application version,
you can deploy it to an environment.
An environment is the rules and configuration that manage actual EC2 instances.
Each environment can run with a different platform,
for instance Java or Node, and can be configured with certain EC2 instance types.
Configuring each environment in Elastic Beanstalk is where you'll spend
most of your time since you can set up the deployment,
load balancing, and scaling rules there.
Application versions,
the different versions of your code, are stored in S3. Elastic Beanstalk
gives you an easy‑to‑deploy screen listing them all,
but the actual bits and files themselves are stored in an S3 bucket.
There's also a limit to the number of application versions that one
application can have, and the default is 1,000.
Usually, if you ever hit this limit,
you would just go and delete old, unneeded versions of the
application. Monitoring is another one of the great things
about Elastic Beanstalk.
The options aren't as robust as a full monitoring suite, but the data
is aggregated from all your application instances.
This means that you're able to truly see how your application
is doing and not just any single instance.
You're able to see metrics such as CPU, number of requests, and network traffic.
And if you see any of your metrics spike or freak out, Elastic Beanstalk
also provides the functionality to easily pull the logs from all of your
instances so you can figure out what's going on.
This can get a little overwhelming if you have more than a handful of
instances since you'd have to read through all of the logs, but it's still
nice that AWS provides an easier option besides logging into each EC2
instance and manually downloading the logs.
Elastic Beanstalk is a free service from AWS.
The only thing you'll pay for is the EC2 instances, load balancer,
and S3 storage that is being used. Honestly,
I think it makes Elastic Beanstalk almost irresistible to use since
you be using those resources anyways if you were running an
application in AWS. With this free resource,
you're really just getting a more convenient and feature‑rich way to run your applications.