Simple Storage Service, which is also called S3,
thankfully because, man, Simple Storage Service is a tongue twister.
It is a service that stores files.
Although you can host files to end users, that's not all it's used for.
S3 is sort of a catch‑all service used by other services in AWS,
like CloudWatch and Elastic Beanstalk, for instance.
It's widely used throughout AWS as the place to store files.
S3 can be used for any type of file,
and the only limitation is a maximum size of 5 TB,
and that was not a mistake.
The maximum object size is actually 5 TB.
According to AWS documentation, I haven't actually tried this,
the largest file size that you can upload in a single put operation is 5 GB,
but there are other methods to upload a larger object in separate operations.
Buckets are the foundational structure in S3.
A bucket is your root resource to which you can add, delete, or modify objects.
There are all sorts of configuration options that you can set on buckets,
like permissions, hosting options, and logging.
Buckets can be configured to trigger events when changes happen,
preserve old versions of any objects,
and automatically replicate objects to different regions.
Once created,
buckets are assigned URLs to which you can access
the objects contained within them.
When the permissions for objects are modified to allow anonymous access,
S3 can be used to host static files for websites.
There are a lot of options Amazon has added to S3 that make it
extremely flexible and useful in a variety of situations.
S3 makes it simple to use for hosting a static website.
Within the bucket configuration options,
there is the ability to enable static website hosting for the given bucket.
You still have object‑level permissions to give access
to anonymous or authenticated users,
but the bucket itself will respond to requests and be
enabled to interact with Route53 URLs.
This is a quick and easy way to get a static website up with very minimal cost.
If hosting a site like this or even just assets for a
website‑like images sounds like your use case,
you may be wondering how to solve the latency problem
I mentioned in the last module.
With S3, you can automatically replicate files to other regions,
but AWS provides a better solution.
By using another service from Amazon called CloudFront,
you can cache your content, sometimes called edging your
content, at locations around the world.
We'll talk about CloudFront more in the next module.
Now let's talk about how much this is going to cost you.
S3 is price‑based on three aspects, amount of data stored,
number of requests for objects made, and amount of data
transferred. Prices are different per region, and base
costs get cheaper as volumes go up.
But here are the prices for the first tier of each in the Oregon region.
Also note, these prices are per bucket.
AWS charges 2.3 cents per gigabyte of data stored.
Pretty reasonable. Requests are priced differently based on the
type of request, but put requests are basically half a cent per
1,000 requests. And for data transferred,
the first gigabyte per month is free and then 9 cents per gigabyte up to 10 TB.
Overall, I think S3 is pretty reasonably priced for storage and
has a low barrier of entry, not to mention that there is a free
tier giving you 5 GB of storage and some free requests and data transfer for the first year.