The AWS command line interface, or CLI,
is a unified tool to interact with different AWS resources from a command line.
Although it's certainly possible that you might use the
CLI manually in your own terminal,
most developers find the CLI useful when writing shell
scripts. Being able to execute commands in AWS with a
simple script isn't just a time saver,
but also increases the ways you can use AWS. For instance,
automated build systems can run shell scripts that deploy
built application artifacts to the cloud,
creating a simple, but powerful continuous deployment pipeline.
Because the AWS CLI is a unified tool,
you can interact with almost any service. When executing a command,
you type aws to run the CLI itself.
The next argument is the service that you want to do something
with and, beyond that, is the specific command and any flags
or parameters for the command.
Here is the documentation for what services you can interact with using the
CLI, and you can see that almost any service is accessible. Installation of
the AWS CLI is simple and straightforward.
Once installed,
you'll need to do an initial configuration which involves adding an access key,
secret key, and default region.
You can add or remove access keys from the security credentials menu in
the console. And once those have been configured,
you can start using the CLI to interact with the services in your account.
Now let's try it out.
I wanted to replicate the example from the last clip where
we sent an item to a DynamoDB table.
So we'll start by entering the aws command.
Next will be the service we want to use, which is DynamoDB.
Since we want to put an item into our table,
we'll use the put‑item command, then the ‑‑table‑name flag,
followed by the table name.
The last parameter we'll add is the flag for item and our item in JSON format.
If we run this command, it should execute smoothly.
We can check our DynamoDB table and see that the item was successfully
added, just like with our SDK before. You can probably imagine one of the
differences with the CLI and the SDK is that it can be easier to do things
dynamically in code. A way to add a dynamic nature to your command line is
with shell scripts, and that's really where the AWS CLI is probably used
more than manually.
I built a short,
simple shell script that put some more items in our
DynamoDB table. You can see each command is simply running
the AWS CLI. Nothing is different.
I can run that shell script from my terminal like so, and it will execute
both AWS CLI commands and put the items in my Dynamo table as we can see.
The CLI is great for doing things quickly with little overhead or for
automation tasks and shell scripts.
Since the level of interaction roughly matches the SDKs and web console, there's not much you can't do with the AWS CLI.