As described before, AWS is a collection of services that
interact together to enable an application to run.
I thought it would be helpful to explain how these services interact
with each other from a high level. Nearly all services interact with
each other over typical TCP connections.
It really depends on the service as to which port it might use.
For instance,
each type of database you might be using has its own port of choice.
So there's not a single protocol that all services use.
Usually, you are initiating these connections in your application by
making requests to the AWS services. If you create all of your service
instances in the same virtual private cloud,
then they will have local IP addresses, and you can make super fast
connections to them. When beginning your development with the various
services of AWS, it's not an all‑or‑nothing process. Since all the
services interact mostly the same on your local development machine as
they do in the cloud, you can add and build on services as you like.
For example,
a common first step for a content management system web application
might be to connect to a database service in AWS.
Then, you could connect and begin using S3 for static file storage.
You can work with these services exactly the same on your
development environment as you would in the cloud,
making the development to deployment experience as painless as possible.
The biggest change once you move your main
application to the cloud is securing it,
which isn't something you can do while your app is being developed locally.
Once in the cloud, connections and permissions between each service
are managed via security groups, which are essentially light
firewalls around each service instance. Controlling access in
security is done with pure configuration completed with the web
console and is mostly straightforward.
Most of the bugs I've encountered with services interacting in AWS
have been from misconfigured security groups.
There's a lot more we'll go into in the following modules as we
cover individual services, but this should serve as a basic
explanation for how things are working in AWS.
Since this course is targeting developers, I will gloss over some of the gory details of infrastructure.