Amazon was not the first or only player in cloud computing.
In fact, there are many, many companies providing robust solutions for the cloud.
It can honestly get a little confusing sometimes trying to understand the
differences between them to make an informed decision.
In this section, I thought it would be good to talk about some of the more
popular competitors and the differences between them and AWS.
First.
Let's talk about the elephant in the room, Microsoft Azure.
Both companies residing in the Seattle area only makes the
competition between them that much more fierce.
Azure was started by Microsoft around 2010 as the cloud
became a major player in computing.
The general model of Azure is kind of the same as AWS.
Provide a range of computing services with on‑demand
scalability and flexible pricing.
Speaking of pricing,
it can be difficult when comparing pricing between the two services
since they don't offer the exact same sized offerings.
It does appear that Amazon's pricing is more competitive,
but that really shouldn't be the main factor when
deciding on a computing platform,
especially since the pricing is close enough between the two.
So what are the differences between Azure and AWS?
In the past few years,
Azure has caught up to AWS in terms of cloud service offerings and global reach.
Those aren't as much differentiators as they once were.
One of the main differentiators is running Microsoft products,
such as Windows Server and SQL Server in the cloud.
A recent announcement from Microsoft,
removing the option for customers to migrate their licenses
for these services to competitor clouds,
indicates to me that Microsoft is likely to begin
consolidating their products onto Azure,
making it the easiest and cheapest place to run these products.
So if you currently use or would need to use Microsoft products in the cloud,
Azure is probably the best provider to use.
Beyond that,
I've noticed that working in both of the consoles feels quite different.
Perhaps it's just that I'm extremely familiar with AWS's UI.
But I've found Azure's interface to feel much more
cluttered as they try to provide a more unified experience
with all their available services.
Navigating the AWS console does require more clicks because
each service has its own dashboard portal,
but I actually prefer that over Azure's approach.
This is really just a personal preference though,
so try both out and see what you like.
There is a lot more to compare between Azure and AWS,
and Pluralsight has a great course comparing the two.
Definitely check it out if you're torn.
It's called Understanding the Difference Between Microsoft Azure and Amazon AWS.
In Gartner's 2019 Infrastructure as a Service Magic Quadrant report,
they added Google Cloud, sometimes called Google Cloud Platform,
to the leader section, joining AWS and Azure.
It's a big win for Google as they continue to grow their market share,
attempting to take the third place spot from Alibaba Cloud.
So let's take a closer look at Google Cloud.
Google unveiled their first cloud offering,
App Engine, in 2008 and released it to the public in 2011.
Since that time,
they've added more services and consolidated them into
a single cloud platform offering.
While there does seem to be some specialization in the big data,
AI, and Kubernetes spaces,
it's hard to see the real differentiators between AWS and Google Cloud.
Their data reach and locations seem similar.
The market share of AWS does dwarf Google's at this point,
and I think the Google Cloud web console needs some more time to mature.
As Google Cloud grows,
it should be interesting to see how they
differentiate themselves from AWS and Azure.
The last service provider we'll look at is a little different than the others,
but it should be familiar to many developers,
and that is the provider Heroku.
Heroku originally started as a cloud computing platform for Ruby on
Rails applications back in 2007 when Ruby was one of the hottest web
languages of the day. For many years,
it was exclusively Ruby before expanding and now
supporting just about any major web language.
In addition to languages, it also began to introduce more and more
connected services like database and enterprise solutions.
Its main value proposition is the simplicity to deploy and scale an application.
I've used Heroku myself, and I can attest it is
really easy and quick to get started.
There's a really slick command line tool that can
deploy your app in a couple of commands.
I do highly recommend Heroku for new developers getting their
feet wet with deploying hobby applications. But with simplicity
comes a tradeoff, lack of options.
Heroku focuses on doing one thing well,
simple and streamlined application hosting. And they
succeed over many of their competitors, even AWS.
Unfortunately, their services don't offer many of Amazon Web Services options,
and their global reach, with only eight regions, falls far short from AWS.