And that's it.
We've reached the end of this module, introducing you
to the world of Amazon Web Services.
There was quite a bit to cover in the first module to prepare you for
going even more in depth with AWS throughout this course.
So let's go over what we learned in this module.
We started by discussing web application hosting and the
main drivers for moving it into the cloud.
Amazon grabbed on this new paradigm and developed a
business to support and profit off of cloud computing in
the form of Amazon Web Services.
The two major drivers of AWS popularity continue to be pricing and scalability,
and we talked more in depth about the geographical
reach of AWS throughout the globe.
We talked about how AWS services interact and what you
can expect when working with them.
Finally, we discussed a few of Amazon's competitors like Azure,
Google Cloud, and Heroku.
Hopefully,
this helped you identify AWS as the best solution for your use case
because there's a lot more for us to cover in this course.
In the next module, we're going to look at what I call the core services of AWS.
These are the basic services that you are likely to use no
matter your type of web application.
This is going to be a slightly more technical introduction into
what is really going on in that web of services.
We'll look at EC2, Amazon's cloud computing service,
which is the most commonly used service on AWS. Next is S3, the
essential service for storing static files.
And actually, I might have been wrong because this
might be the most used service.
Most web applications also require some sort of database.
So we'll look at the Relational Database Service. And finally,
we'll look at Route53,
which is a service for configuring URL routing to your application.
And with these four core services, we'll cover the main things that you will need to get started with Amazon Web Services.