We've reached the end of our module on extended services in AWS.
We've looked at quite a few services that extend well beyond
the core services covered in the last module,
and you should have a good picture now of the robustness of AWS.
Let's wrap this module up by recapping each service that we covered.
First, we looked at Elastic Beanstalk,
an application deployment and management service.
Under the covers, it's deploying your code to run on EC2 instances,
but it takes care of so much that you'd be doing yourself a disservice
if you didn't take advantage of what it provides.
Next was Lambda,
the simplest way to quickly execute code with the least
amount of configuration required.
We also looked at DynamoDB, a fully managed NoSQL database solution.
Virtual Private Cloud is used to organize and
control access to your AWS resources.
It's essentially free, so it's highly recommended to utilize its
advanced networking features to secure your application.
Then we looked at CloudWatch, the monitoring service that's integrated with
most existing services. Setting alerts is absolutely essential to staying
informed with how your AWS resources are doing.
And finally, we revisited CloudFront, a content delivery network service,
and saw how we could easily configure it to reduce latency around the
world. That's it for all the individual service overviews. In the next
module, we're going to look at how you, as a developer, will interact
with the various services in AWS. We'll start with an overview of the web
console, which I've already previewed a bit. A lot of the configuration
and monitoring time you'll spend with AWS will happen in this web app.
Next,
we'll look at some of the various software development kits that Amazon supports
and see what types of actions you can perform in your code,
such as connecting to RDS databases or S3 buckets.
Finally, we'll look at the command line interface tool.
This CLI makes it easy to send files to S3 buckets, deploy to Elastic
Beanstalk environments, or orchestrate many more AWS services.
If you've been waiting for the gritty details of what you'll be doing with AWS,
the time has arrived. I hope you've enjoyed this module, and I'll see you in the next one.