All right so we have another really quick exercise.
This one is definitely a little easier than the last.
Basically it's the same idea.
Here's an image.
This is Tim himself that I wrote and I want you to reverse engineer it to take this.
This is about my dog Rusty.
You do not have to use the same image if you do want to and you want to use the exact same image make
it look exactly the same.
It's included in the description so I'll let you decide on which heading this is what this is right
here.
What heading this is.
Decide on where this link actually goes to I.
Rusty doesn't have an Instagram or not one of those dog owners Thankfully I decided to link to just
some some Instagram that was just dogs of Instagram I think.
So any link really will do there.
So again pretty simple one image one link one list a few headings and one weird looking yet painfully
adorable mutant dog