All right so this will be a solution video like always you can just find the code in that description
and download that.
But I'll give you a chance to follow along if you want to code along while I create this solution.
OK.
So first thing as always we need a file.
I created one called Rusty h t m l create a file save it dot each team up.
We need our skeleton our boiler plate.
Let's give it a title of rusty steel.
And then the first thing that stands out is the largest heading which should be an H1 and that just
is rusty Still
the next thing is some text that I think should probably be a paragraph.
So hi I'm a dog wolf so let's see what we have going on so far looks good.
So next up we can tackle the image.
So I have a few images of resti here.
They're all pretty adorable.
I'm going to go with this one.
So I'm going to copy the image you Arel in case you didn't know about that right quick copy image or
else you'll be doing that a lot.
Any time you want to use an image in your aged him L..
So we need an image tag.
We set the source equal to that you are all.
Remember there's no closing image tag just self-closing image source equals something.
Let's take a look.
OK so far so good.
Let's go ahead and add in some of my favorite places.
So let's go with an H for to start.
And let's see how that looks.
That looks a little bit small.
So that might be an age three.
And this really isn't the point of the exercise so you don't have to spend too much time.
OK.
There you go to page three.
It's really more just identifying that something is a heading not so much matching exactly the size
because we can use the Assessed later on to specify you know it sounds like there is only six sizes
of headings.
There are six different headings but we can style any of them to be 50 pixel font size 51 52 at 100
200 370.
We can do whatever we want.
Style wise but there are just six elements.
So again we're not really working with any style yet.
So if we want it to be exact.
This is an H3.
So next up we have a nice little list an unordered list with three allies the beach the dog park and
the fire hydrant.
These actually are his favorite places in order.
So maybe this should have been an ordered place rather than an unordered list.
That's for another day.
Let's double check.
Looks good.
The only other thing that we need now is our final paragraph at the bottom.
Make sure to follow me on.
And then a tag
inside that HIV one Instagram.
And then I have just dogs of Instagram open.
Feel free to use any link whatsoever.
It really doesn't matter.
Let's check it out.
Make sure to follow me on Instagram.
It is purple because I've been to this link before.
So like I said you've not visited our blue links or you have art by default purple.
We can change that with the SS later.
All right so let's just compare again.
Looks good to me.