In this video we're going to pick up where we left off talking about four more font and text related
properties.
The first of which is called font weight.
And so the weight of a font refers to how bold or light weight the text is basically how thick the actual
font or how thick the lines are.
So I'll give you an example here.
We'll select all paragraphs and all say font weight.
Bold.
And so this is one of the options we can say Fontanne weight is bold.
And then I'm going to go to this file and refresh and you'll see that the paragraph becomes bolded.
Likewise you can go back and I can change you back to normal or you could just delete all of this but
if I change it back to normal and now goes back to the normal font size.
One thing I'll point out is that certain fonts will let you use a numeric value as well and that ranges
from 100 to 800
and it's not any number between 100 and 800 It's every hundred.
So one two three four five hundred six hundred seven hundred and eight hundred.
So that depends on the font itself if you have that.
So it looks something like this.
That would be the lightest and this would be pretty heavy and this would be the heaviest.
So we'll see how to use that actually in the next lesson when we talk about Google fonts.
So changes back to bold for now.
So line height does exactly what it sounds like it does.
It controls the height of a given line.
So if we go back to our browser here we take a look at these paragraphs.
Notice the line spacing here.
How much space there is between this line and the next.
And if you've ever had to change line spacing in something like Microsoft Word before you say turned
in a paper in high school or college and then needed to be 1.5 or 2 point line spacing we can do the
exact same thing with CCS SS So its line height let's select the paragraph line height and then we just
give it a number.
And this will multiply the current line height which is always determined by the font itself.
We have a larger font.
We're going to have a larger space between lines.
So let's refresh and now we get double spacing so we can you know multiply that by 5.
Usually you don't do much with line height aside from maybe one point five or two.
OK.
So that's the line.
I go back to two.
Well it's two one point five.
The next one is text the line.
So just like Microsoft Word or any word processor text the line controls how the text of a given element
is actually aligned.
If it's to the left to the right or to the center.
So let's take our H-1 to start and center.
So if we inspect it you'll see that the H-1 takes up this entire length of the screen.
But the text itself is only on the left side.
So if we use text line we can say text align right and we'll move all the way to the right side.
And if we do text align center will move to the center.
So let's start.
So what's the H-1 and less do text the line right.
Save refresh and you can see that each one is now in line to the right and we can do the same thing
two paragraphs.
But let's text align Center them so text align center save her fresh.
And it's a small shift but you can see that now our paragraphs are aligned center rather than left.
So one last property is text decoration and text decoration is used to give text and underline effect
or a strikethrough and also something called an over line which is just underlined except on top.
So let's give all paragraphs a underline effect.
So we just do text decoration underline and we refresh and we get a lot of underlined text and we can
do the same thing for H-1 and we'll do straight through
line through.
And there we go.
We get this line through.
OK so that's the basics of font and text based properties and C Ss we're going to now in the next video
actually talked about including custom fonts