Well come back.
So this video is going to be pretty short.
We're just going to discuss how we make lists in HCM out.
So how do we make numbered lists or bullet point analysts.
How do we have nested busts.
This is something that we do a lot on our Web sites.
It's all sorts of thing you know academic papers did a lot and they still do.
Which is why it was originally incorporated in each team.
So there are two types of lists that we can define.
One is an ordered list which would look something like this.
And another is an unordered list which works the same way except we have bullet points here.
So we'll start by talking about an ordered list and the tag for that.
It's called an AOL stands for ordered list.
And if we just do that and refresh this page nothing changes.
And that's because an ordered list on its own doesn't mean anything.
We have to provide it with list elements or list items which is what Ally stands for every numbered
point that we want every item in the list needs to be an ally tag.
So we're going to make a list.
Let's do something short let's say a list of colors so red she can copy this line.
Orange yellow.
So this list is ordered.
I refresh the page and you can see I get a list with numbers there.
And you can change this with CSSA you can change it to be Roman numerals.
We'll talk about that.
And another lesson what's important though is that it has an order.
So if we copy this we do the exact same thing but we change it to be a u l and I refresh the page you'll
see that I have a numbered list which is ordered and an unordered list with bullet points.
So just by changing Oh well.
Well I go from ordered to an ordered both of them require list items inside what we can do just to show
you we can nest any of the other tags that we've seen like strong or emphasized.
So let's make it red folded just like that.
And you can see red is bolded.
Likewise we can also nest other lists inside of a list.
So let's say I wanted to have a list under yellow I wanted it to list a few shades of yellow inside
this ally.
I can actually add in another a much do and an ordered list and you'll see there.
This is the first time I've certainly this can type the tag name and hit tab in autocomplete.
So I have another well an unordered list inside of that I'm going to name my first shade of yellow which
is sunflower and then another ally and another shade of yellow which will be banana.
Let's take a look.
You've got an ordered list with numbers one two three.
And then inside of that third list item I have another bullet point first with two types of yellow and
you'll see I end up at this nested list structure.
So then of course under banana I could do another list something like let's do another.
This time let's go back to an ordered list.
Another lie.
I'm really running out of ideas for bananas.
Let's just do a frozen banana
and non frozen banana and you can see we get a numbered list inside of a bullet point of least inside
of a numbered list.
OK.
So that's what I want to show about lists.
We can combine all of these together to make some interesting things we can build things I italicised
them we can put a heading before a list so I could do something like
my color list.
Very exciting.
I know we're getting there though.
This is underlying everything that we do every Web site uses these types of elements behind the scenes
.
So even though these are not beautiful sites yet they're not very useful.
It's really really important.
So next we're going to do a quick little exercise I mean if you build something we're going to give
you a little image how we construct it and then we'll meet back up afterwards.