Welcome everyone to the image basics of open C section of the course in this section we're going to
begin building an understanding of how to use the open see the library specifically how to open images
and draw on them later on a further section of the course.
We're going to expand to learn about many more functionalities at the open sea the library has So the
open CV or open source computer vision library.
It's a library of programming functions mainly aimed at real time computer vision and computer vision
just means using a computer to analyze images and videos.
Very similar to the way a human analyzes something that they're looking at such as image or video such
as determining whose face they see in an image and the open source computer vision library it was actually
created all the way back in 1999 by Intel and it was written in C++ it's still written C plus plus we're
going to be using However the python bindings that way we can directly is the Python programming language
as well as Python libraries such as Matt pata lib or some pie along with open C.
Keep in mind often when you're Google searching for tutorials on open C.V it's still really popular
in C++.
So you may find some solutions and answers in C++ instead of Python.
So that's sometimes a little bit confusing for beginners.
They're looking at the code and it's in a totally different programming language that isn't Python.
So keep that in mind there's still a lot of research out there that are in C++ rope and CV and not yet
in Python.
However there is a full documentation for Python ANSI plus plus you just have to be aware of which one
you're looking at.
So in general the open C-v library already contains many popular algorithms for computer vision including
object detection and tracking algorithms that are already built into the library.
So we're going to start with the very basics doing things like opening files and drawing on images and
slowly working our way up to understanding how to perform things like object detection and tracking.
So the overall section goals here are to be able to open image files.
Open Sivi in both a notebook setting and the python script.
Which is why we're using Jupiter laughs as we're going to be able to use both of those.
Then we're going to be able to draw simple geometries on images.
Often the way you're doing things like object tracking you want to actually track the object by drawing
for example a rectangle around the car as it's moving.
So we have to understand how do we actually draw on videos and images and then we also want to be able
to directly interact with an image through callbacks.
So I mean directly interact.
I mean opening up an image and being able to click on it and then draw some sort of object.
OK.
So those are section goals.
Let's go ahead and get started.
We'll see you in the next lecture.