Welcome everyone to the section of the course on object detection the goals for the section are to understand
a variety of object detection methods.
And we're going to slowly build up to more complex methods as we go along.
In this section of the course so we're going to start off with template matching template matching is
probably the simplest idea behind object detection and all it does is it simply looks for an exact copy
of an image within another larger image.
Then we'll move on to just general detection methods like cornuta detection which is looking for corner's
edge detection which expands on this idea to find general etches of objects and then grid detection
which combines both concepts defined grid like patterns in images which is really useful for lots of
applications that will move on to talking about contour detection contrary detection allows us to detect
foreground vs. background images and also allows for detection of external versus internal contours.
For example grabbing the eyes and smile from a cartoon smiley face and realizing that those are internal
contours versus the external contour of the actual circle that holds the eyes and the smile and all
the work of that exact example later on.
That will move on to general feature matching.
And this is going to be one of the more advanced methods of detection specifically detecting matching
objects in another image and it's going to work even as a Tarka image is not shown exactly the same
in the image that we are actually searching.
Then we'll talk about the watershed algorithm and it's an advanced algorithm that allows us to segment
images into foreground and background.
And it also allows us to manually set seeds to choose segments of an image and we'll be working with
both those concepts that will move on to facial and eye detection.
We'll be using Haar cascades to detect faces and images.
Note that this is not yet facial recognition.
We're only going to be able to detect if there is a face or if there's a set of eyes in an image.
We won't be able to yet say whose face or whose eyes they belong to.
Later on when we talk about deep learning then we'll talk about actually recognizing unique faces or
unique images.
At the end we'll have a really cool project assessment.
We're going to build a full computer vision application that can actually blur license plates automatically
given an image.
So Ill see an image the where the license plate is and then we'll apply our own blur to that license
plate.
So it's going to be this really awesome application.
All right let's get started by talking about template matching.
We'll see at the next lecture.