Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture on convolutional neural networks.
Now previously we created a neural network for already defined features.
But what do we have the actual raw image data we need to learn about convolutional neural networks in
order to effectively solve the problems that image data can present such as how to deal with two that
missional data.
And how do you have multiple color channels like the red green and blue color channels and for that
we're going to need to understand how tensors can be used in order to form our data correctly with high
end color channels.
Okay.
So let's continue by learning about CNN's.
Now it's really cool but convolutional neural networks is just like the simple perception model.
They have their origins directly linked in biological research.
Recall that when we were designing our preset Tron model we directly converted a biological neuron into
our own artificial representation.
And we're going to do a similar idea with convolutional neural networks and the biological research.
We base this off of is from a pair of scientists David Heibel and Torsen Weisel who were studying the
structure of the visual cortex in mammals and their research is actually so fundamental to the field
of biological vision that actually won them a Nobel Prize in 1981.
One of the key components that their research revealed was that neurons in the visual cortex had what
they call a small local receptive field that is the same these neurons are actually only looking at
a local a smaller subsection of the entire image that the person is viewing.
And then these local subsections can then later on overlap and create a larger image and visual field.
What's also important to note is that these certain neurons in the visual cortex are only activated
when they detect certain things.
They realize that neurons may be only active when they detect the horizontal line or a black circle
etc..
So we can see here we already have this idea of local portions of the entire image.
This idea of these local subsets directly inspired the artificial neural network architecture that would
become the convolutional neural network and it was famously implemented in the 1998 paper by man in
the can who is actually now the director of AI research at Facebook and they created what they call
the Linette 5 architecture that was first used to classify that dataset.
So when you're learning about convolutional networks maybe you're Googling around you often see a diagram
that looks something like this.
And when you're reading papers on different convolutional neural network architectures you see a lot
of images that look like this.
And I remember when I was first learning about convolutional neural networks this basically looks like
a foreign language to me.
It was pretty hard for me to understand what was actually going on.
Each of these steps so we're to break down the various aspects of the convolutional neural network seen
here and the two main aspects we haven't really seen before are these ideas of these convolutions and
subsampling or pooling.
So that entire feature extraction portion is we're really going to focus our attention to and learn
about in this come illusional neural network lecture.
That second half of classification is actually stuff we've already covered before basically fully connected
networks and soft Max regression for multiple outputs.
Well we're going to focus on is this idea of convolutions and subsampling or pooling.
So in order to learn about that we need to break down into various topics.
So will first have to review what are tensors then we'll compare a densely connected neural network
to convolutional neural network that will dive deeper into convolutions and filters will learn about
padding as well as pooling layers or subsampling and then we'll also review dropout.
So let's get started by talking about tensors.
Recall that tensors are just n dimensional arrays that we build up to as we increase levels of dimension.
So we start off with just scalar numbers.
Those are just individual digits or floating point numbers.
Then we can have a vector of numbers essentially just a one dimensional array of various scalar numbers
that we can actually have a matrix when they mentioned higher up for that which is then basically a
list of vectors.
And beyond that we have tensors Where are just higher than missional arrays.
So tensors make it really convenient to feed in sets of images into our model which is why it's really
vital that we understand tensors and their shapes when we end up building these models.
Intenser flow so we can imagine that if we have a group of trainee images such as those thousand training
images and the data set that we can have for them missional tensor where one dimension are the images
themselves along another dimension we have the height of the image in pixels so that pixel representation
in the height along another dimension we can have the width of the images and then if we want we can
have four of them mentioned for the color channels where right now for em the digits were only dealing
of grayscale.
But later on for color images will have three channels red green and blue.
So let's explore now the difference between a densely connected neural network those CNN's any convolutional
neural network and recall that we actually already been able to create then only connect to neural networks
easily with the T.F. estimator API.
So remember a densely connected layer basically just looks like this where every neuron in one layer
is directly connected to every other neuron in the next layer.
Then for convolutional air we have a different approach.
Each unit is connected to a smaller number of nearby units in the next layer basically directly inspired
by that idea of the biological visual cortex where you're only looking at local receptive fields.
So now the question arises why bother if it convolutional neural network instead of a densely connected
neural network Well the this dataset was 28 by 28 pixels.
So that's 784 total pixels.
When you feed it in the most images are going to be much larger at least 256 by 256 pixels.
And that would be 56000 total pixels and that's just for a relatively small image of 256 by 256.
So as your images get larger and larger if you were to have a densely connected neural network that
would lead to way too many parameters and it would just be unscalable to image images because you'd
have so many parameters that you've already fit.
So instead of convolutions and convolutions also have a major advantage for image processing that are
directly inspired by that biological research.
We can know intuitively that if we're looking at an image pixels that are nearby each other they're
much more correlated to each other for image detection which is directly related to this idea of those
convolutional layers only being connected to those local neurons.
So each convolutional neural network layer looks at an increasingly larger part of the image and having
units only connected to nearby units also aids in invariance.
So convolutional neural networks help with regularisation and they also limit the search of weights
to the size of the convolution.
Let's go ahead and explore.
This is a very high level overview what the convolutional neural network would look like as it relates
to image recognition.
You would basically just start with some input layer which is the image itself then come layers are
only connected to pixels in their respective fields.
So if we kind of think about this on a to the plane we can see that the illusional errors only have
those local connections and then another higher level of convolution is again only connected to the
local connections of that first convolutional layer.
Now there is an issue here as you get towards the edge of the image there may not be any input neurons
from the actual input data so we can fix this by adding a padding of zeros around the image.
Then this is just generally known as padding OK.
Let's now walk through a one dimensional convolution in more detail and then we're going to expand this
to the idea of a two dimensional convolution.
And this is going to begin to look like some of those images we first saw describing the architecture
the convolutional neural network.
So again let's take that back revisit then only connect in your own networks and convert that to a one
dimensional convolution.
So here we have an example of how densely connected neural network.
Again same idea.
We have one dimension of neurons densely connected to every neuron in the next layer that's the blue
layer.
And again densely connected to everything in the output layer.
However let's convert that first input layer to a one the convolution So what we see here is just local
connections to that next layer of neurons and what's really interesting is we can then treat these weights
of these local edges as what we call a filter.
So let's take an example of one filter we can see here on that bottom we have y is equal to w one or
wait 1 times the input X plus W2 or two times the input x 2 and that will be the output Y which is then
fed into that next neuron.
So if w 1 and 2 are equal to 1 a negative one respectively then we have the equation.
Why is equal to x 1 minus x 2.
So I kind of chose these arbitrary weights here and given that they've chosen one a negative one.
We ask ourselves well what is why at a maximum so one is that maximum activation there and that occurs
at x 1 equal to 1 and x 2 equal to zero.
And that is basically an example of a filter that is specifically designed for edge detection because
remember edges when we represent them as pixels are essentially just a large difference in the actual
darkness darkness of two pixels that are right next to each other.
So if we have one pixel one right next to it we have a pixel zero.
Then we're essentially describing an edge of really dark pixel versus the really light pixel.
And we can see here if we describe these weights as one common negative one then when why is that a
maximum we have an edge so we have a filter here that's essentially now an edge detector.
So then we can apply that to the rest of these edges.
So we have a set of weights that can act as a filter for detection and we can then expand this idea
to multiple filters.
So here's an example of having just one filter.
So that's the same way across where the filter size is too because I have two weights there and the
stride is two.
So let's talk about this stride term.
You can see here in this first layer of pink neurons I'm moving up these weights two neurons at a time.
So if we start from the bottom I have w 1 and w 2 I repeat them every two neurons along the input and
that's known as a stride of this filter.
And if this visualization doesn't make a whole lot of sense to you don't worry we'll later on show you
in other visualization representation of filters that might make more sense.
So really lock in on this idea of stride.
Let's fix this so now we have a stride of one.
So if we're going up one unit at a time then we have something that looks like this.
We can see there'll be one and there'll be two.
But now we're only moving up one year on at a time.
So we have blue than orange than red.
So you can see here this is a stripe of two moving up two neurons at a time.
This is a streite of one moving up one neuron out of time.
Now remember we can see here that we have some neurons that aren't connected.
That is where we could have added in some zero padding to include more edge pixels so I could add in
a top neuron above my top pick neuron and just have that be zero.
So I can kind of finish off that stride count.
So that was just showing one filter we can actually then expand to multiple filters or multiple sets
of weights.
So here I can see this is a representation of two filters where my stride is still one.
But now my filter size is two seconds here and added another set of neurons ready to accept another
set of weights for another filter.
And we expand this idea to any number of filters we want.
So here I have four filters.
So now four different sets of weights filter sizes now two and streite is still one.
So each filter is attempting a different feature and realistically the representation would kind of
get a little messy as we begin to draw arrows to every feature as we are every filter as we come in
through the input.
So instead of trying to represent it like this you'll often see it represented as sets of blocks.
So for simplicity simplicity we're going to begin to describe this and visualize all this as a set of
blocks instead.
So we're going to convert our input to just be one by L..
This one dimensional convolution.
We just have one set by a length L of pixels and then we describe that set of filters as just this tensor
which is the number of filters by the number of units in that actual layer.
So we now have these concepts of these neurons converted to these block images for it to the convolution.
We're mainly going to be dealing with images.
So it's a really similar structure.
We have our input image but now instead of being one D it's to the where we have a height and width
to the image itself.
And then for that next layer we have this tensor of the number of filters and the number of units for
the width by the number of units for the height.
So now we have this three missional tensor object and we can see that subsections are going to directly
be related to this tensor.
So if we're looking at a local section of the input image of a height and width then it actually directly
belongs to a local section of that next tensor.
So again height by with my number filters if we're working of color images it's basically a really similar
concept except we add in one dimension for the number of color channels.
So for a grayscale images we just have one color channel but for color images we typically have three
red green and blue
and it's the same idea here you have height width and then color and actually then corresponds to number
filter's number of units still the number of units for height.
Now convolution filters are commonly visualized with a grid system.
So in case the last explanation of convolution filters wasn't clear enough.
Let's go ahead and walk through how they work with grids on a to the input here on the left hand side.
I have an input that's already been padded with zeros.
So my original input was just that inner four by four grid where ones represent the darkest pixels and
negative ones represent the lightest pixels.
So if we pretend this is a handwritten digit it's basically a zero.
And then I've padded it with an edge of zeros as far as pixel values around that I take a three by three
filter.
So I have weights inside this three by three filter and I'm going to apply it to the image and then
one I'm going to do is multiply the pixels in the image by the basically weight values in the filter.
Then once I multiply by those filter weights I'll get some results and then I'll take the some of that
and I'll end up with whatever value in this case it was 0.
So this is a way people commonly visualize filter's with a grid system where you have the filter of
weights on a grid and you multiply the input by the filter weights and then you take that result take
the sum and then that's going to be your output value for your convoluted image.
Now stride distance also takes into account how fast you're going to move across image with your filters.
Here we see a stride distance of one as an example.
So I'm basically taking the filter moving over by one pixel and then applying all those changes.
Or I could do it too.
So here I'm moving over by two pixels and then applying those changes.
Let's go ahead and jump to a really cool visualization Web site that again shows this process in even
more detail.
I'm going to jump to it now.
So here I am at Sentosa the I O which has a really awesome visualization Web site and they have this
really interesting visualization for convolution kernels which is basically what we've been explaining
here.
And on the left hand side you can see I have this little red cursor that's highlighting a pixel value
and then it highlights the corresponding pixel in the actual representation of the image.
You can kind of move around the play of this and then well we're going to do is walk through applying
a 3:23 sharp kernel to the image of the face from above.
So here we have our filter or a kernel with those weights.
Here we have zero negative 1 5 et cetera.
And then what we end up doing is the following.
So here's our input image.
You can see my little convolution filter moving across.
So I have those pixel values I multiply them by the filter or kernel waits and then that ends up representing
once I sum them the output of that actual location in the output image.
So you can kind of move along and see how this is working.
So we kind of hover above this.
I then I have nine values that I'm going to multiply by my filter weights and then take that sum and
then that's going to be in the output image at that location.
So this is a sharpened filter.
We can also see other convolution kernels such as a blur.
So this is the result of this blur filter.
You can see the weights there.
And I encourage you to check out the resources and play around of this but hopefully this gives you
a good idea of the actual process.
So again we're just passing along this filter and then getting out the output so you can see here as
I go along the edge as a straight distance of one there is my actual value of the output as I multiply
by those filter weights and then take the sum.
OK let's go back to the presentation.
So we just covered those convolution filters and if you have multiple filters you could visually represent
them like this.
Here we can see we have multiple three by three convolution filters and this is the sort of representation
that is actually being shown in that original convolutional neural network diagram.
So here's that five by five convolution.
So earlier we were using three by three.
The here they're using five by five.
So that's exactly what we saw here.
And now we have an understanding of what convolution is and how a convolution filters work.
But we still have to discuss subsampling or pooling.
So in the very next lecture we're going to continue right where we left off here and talk about pooling
and subsampling.
I'll see you at the next lecture.