Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to talk about histograms again and we can continue our discussion with two additional topics.
The first one being histograms on a masked portion of the image and the second one being histogram equalization
as you mentioned in the previous lecture we can actually select a specific region of interest and only
calculate the color histogram of that mass section.
We're going to show you how to create a mask and then achieve that effect.
That should be just kind of a brief little overview of applying the mask and then Cockley in the color
histogram.
The larger part of this lecture is histogram equalization and histogram equalization is a method of
contrast adjustment based on the images histogram.
Previously we saw how we could use gamma correction to increase or decrease the brightness of an image.
Now we're going to show you how to increase or decrease the contrast of an image through histogram equalization.
Here we have a little figure.
And on the left it shows what the original histogram or color histogram of the image looks like.
And we're essentially going to flatten it out or equalize it.
And we're going to walk through an example of what that actually looks like.
So here's an example of an original image is essentially just a bunch of.
So on the left here we have the actual color values.
And then in the middle we have just a small image.
There's not really anything there just a little white circle with lots of gray around it.
And then we see the original color histogram something to note here is that the histogram for this original
image.
It doesn't have any values at 0 or 255 so it doesn't have anything that's pure white and also doesn't
have anything that's pure black or we're going to do is apply histogram Equalization which is going
to reduce the color depth.
And what we mean by reducing the color that is you're actually reducing the shades of gray or if you're
working on a particular color channel then you're reducing the number of in-between colors between 0
and 255.
So again take a look at the original minimum and maximum values in the story.
I've highlighted them here for you.
Currently the minimum value is 52 and the maximum value is 150.
What we're going to do now is apply histogram equalization and definitely check out the resource link
in this lecture for the full mathematical breakdown of how this actually works.
It works for a cumulative distribution function.
But right now we're just concerned more of the effects of applying histogram equalization.
So after you apply histogram equalization notice what happens to those left values that minimum value
that was 50 to now gets transformed to 0 and that max value which was 154 then has transformed 255.
And let's take a look at what happens to the actual image itself.
So notice it's kind of just this blurry almost gray almost white circle there and now it's clearly been
high contrast so that the circle in the middle is clearly now white.
And then we have a clear border edge and the histogram is also now more flattened out.
And now it extends all the way from the minimum possible value of zero all the way to the maximum possible
255 so notice again how the minimax values have now been equalized to be 0 and 255.
We also now see less shades of gray.
So this results in a higher contrast.
Let's see though the results on a normal image.
So here we have a left hand side image of just some hills of some trees on them.
And then we have the actual histogram.
So the red represents the histogram for those grayscale values and then the black line represents the
cumulative histogram there.
And essentially what that does is it just keeps adding things up as you go towards the max possible
value.
And if you apply histogram equalization what happens is the cumulative then becomes kind of a linear
step function.
And we get much higher contrast in the actual image.
Again we're going from something with low contrast and if we apply histogram equalization then we get
something with high contrast and we've also flattened out the histogram a bit.
Keep my we don't make the histogram perfectly flat.
Instead we're really focused on is making that human live process.
So if we take the correspondence histogram in red versus the cumulative histogram in black we take that
human history and make that much more linear than before.
So that's the actual real process and the mathematics be high histogram equalisation really focus on
that aspect making that cumulative histogram a much more linear Okay.
So let's explore these concepts with open C.v.
Let's open up the Jupiter notebook.
All right here I am in the notebook from the previous lecture where we ended up calculating some color
histograms for various images.
I'm only starting off by using this rainbow image right here.
So let me copy these two lines of code.
And come back down here.
Run those.
So we've uploaded rainbow and show rainbow.
And let's quickly check the shape.
And in fact let's reassign rainbow just so we don't mess around with it too much.
Well re-assign it's image and English chick image shape.
OK so we're doing dealing with 550 by 413 on three color channels.
Now it's time to create a mask.
So probably the easiest way to create a mask is just by using them pie will say a mask is equal to zeros.
And then check check the image shape.
And in this case we're only concerned with the mask on the x and y dimension.
It's not like we're going to mask certain colors out.
We just want this on the to the plane and then that mask will be extended to the three other channels.
So in that case we're only concerned with these first two.
So the shape is going to be Colan too.
And if you take a look at this what the actual result is it's the same as the first two indices.
So we have 550 in 413.
So that's all this is.
So it looks like a complicated man but it's really just grabbing the x and y components and the next
we're going to have the mask be an integer
and so if we take a look at our mask now what we're gonna do is reassign some of the points to be pure
white.
So remember right now the mask is pure black.
So if we were to say peel t him show the mask it's a bunch of zeros.
So it's pure black.
And let me actually make the same map here Gray so we can actually see that.
So in grayscale it's going to be completely black because they're all zeroes.
Now what I want to do is get a rectangle.
Kind of an arbitrary piece that you want to have you as a region of interest.
And that's what I'm going to choose as my mask.
In that case there's really no right or wrong answer as far as like what she amass or what should it
be amassed.
That's up to you.
But what we could do is take her mask and let's just take a slice of it will go from 300 to 400.
And then we'll say from 100 to 400.
So we're taking a slice about 100 pixels along this direction.
So from 200 to 400 over here on Y and then from 100 to 400 to this block over here.
So most of the X-axis there and going to reset those all equal to 255.
So they're all white.
And then once I'm done that let's show the results we'll say mask and then say See map gray and you'll
notice that from 300 to 400 on the Y and from 100 to 400.
Now we have an area that has been mass off and we've already seen mass a little bit with bit wise.
And in the bitwise OR operations and we're going to be using those same operations to essentially filter
through just on the white space the original rainbow image.
So remember the rainbow image if we say Show image this is the rainbow image and it's actually kind
of incorrect the way I'm showing right now I should be showing you show rainbow.
There we go.
So this is the color corrected that we're going to be doing is we're going to be masking that image.
So let's come at this out and then create a master version of that image by saying masked image is equal
to CB2 bitwise.
And now we're going to pass in the image twice and then say mask is equal to the mask we created.
So that is the masked image.
And we're also going to create a version of show mass image.
So it was a show masked image is equal to CB2 wise and then we're going to pasan show rainbow twice.
And then passen the mask.
OK.
So again the reason I'm doing both a masked image and they show masks image is this one is purely for
visualization purposes.
That way I can visually see the correct red green and blue color channeling order.
This one on the mask image that's for the actual histogram calculation.
OK so let's display what the actual image now looks like with our show masked image.
And there we have it.
And so now I'm only seeing this portion of the rainbow.
Notice now how this portion of the rainbow doesn't appear to have that much red compared to the original
image.
So we should expect that our color histogram also reflects that.
Let's calculate now the histogram asked values will say histogram mask underscore values and we're going
to just Kukla on the red channel.
So I'll say CB2
calque hest and the way this works is as a list you're going to actually pass in the original image.
So we're going to pasan rainbow and then the channel we're looking for is the red channel which in this
case since open.
Remember it's the fall is blue green red that means red is an index too.
So we will say channels is equal to two and then we'll say mass is equal to the mass we created which
remember is up here.
This is the actual mask object.
OK so then we have the mass we created and then the other parameters we're going to say are the his
size and ranges.
So those are going to be the same as before we will say his size is equal to 256 and then Granges is
equal to zero to 256.
OK.
So a lot going on there but we'll go ahead and run that and let's do one more for good measure.
However this time we won't apply the mask so we will say just devalues red.
So I'm going to delete that and it will set mass equal to not just for comparison sake.
So let's run that and I'll actually plot these out.
We're going to say Piazzi plot and we're going to start off with just mask values red and I'm going
to title this just so we can understand what we're looking at.
This is the red histogram for mass at Rainbow and what is the actual mass rainbow looks like.
Well it looks like what we have up here.
Notice there's not a whole lot of red going on.
So let's actually run this and see what it looks like.
OK.
So you'll notice just as we predicted in this red histogram there are very low values for red and most
of the values are actually 0.
And then as we continue going on we see less and less pure red values.
So not a whole lot of red going on there.
Now let's check out what happens if we're to do the same thing for the full rainbow image.
Remember the full rainbow image.
We actually display it.
Let me just explain quickly here guilty in show show rainbow.
This one actually has quite a bit of red including representation here in the purple area and Violet
area.
So we're going to do the exact same thing or to Kilty plot except in this case we'll do the no mask
values read and then we'll say for no more himbo.
And if we run that Lotus now we see way more red over here.
So we're pretty much doing the exact opposite of the mast and that's because we could see that much
more of the image is actually represented through the red channel and that's the basics of applying
a mask to a histogram.
So in general we really won't be doing color histograms that often and when we do do color histograms
we probably won't be applying a masks to any particular area but just in case we need to understand
that basically you can always just reference the code in the note book on how to create a mask which
you've seen a little bit of before and then how to actually just calculate it and then pass in that
mask.
And this step right here of mask image and show a mass image that is kind of an in-between step so we
can clearly see what was going on there.
But really all you need to do is create this mask right here which is essentially just creating black
and then filling in your particular region of interest with white and then you can create the mask that
way.
OK.
We're going to go ahead and then move on to the main part of this lecture which is the histogram equalization.
Remember that's a way we can display contrast.