Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to actually use cars as a convolutional neural network with the data set.
Make sure you take a look at the previous lecture or recover details about the dataset.
Let's get started.
By opening up Jupiter lab right here I am in a freshen up a can Jupiter lab.
I won't say the following from carious dot datasets import this.
And then once you have that you may see a little sign that's telling you you're using a particular and
that's totally fine.
And then we'll say the following will say X train.
Why train such as just a little bit of tuple and here and then comma X test Y test and then set that
equal to this load data.
And what this is going to do is it's going to load the end this data for you.
Keep in mind it may take a little longer for you.
I've really fast internet connection right now so there's the data and the next thing I want to do is
just visualize the data just we can get an understanding of it.
I know we already saw the visualization in the previous lecture but it's always nice to do it yourself.
So I will be importing map lib so we can actually do this.
We'll take a look at the actual shape of our training data.
So here we have sixty thousand and then 28 by 28.
Notice right now there is no color channel so we may have to reshape this data to actually have that
color channel.
Then the next thing I want to do is just grab a single image so I will say single image is equal to
extreme and it is going to grab the very first sample by indexing at zero.
So if I take a look at the actual array it looks something like this.
You can see some values but most of them are zero.
Which kind of makes sense because most of the image is probably white and then we will say peel t show
and I'll pass and that single image.
And if you pass in the gray Color Mapping we actually end up getting the inverse here but you get the
idea.
If you actually want the more realistic Color Mapping where the digit is dark all you need to do is
to reverse any color mapping you have the Color Mapping name and do underscore are run that you should
see then this dark 5 on the white background.
OK now that we understand what the training data looks like let's take a look at the actual labels.
So I'll start with the training labels.
We take a look at why train.
Notice right now it responded back with just 60000 values indicating the actual number.
So here it just says 5 because this number its label is 5 and then the next number is 0 and so on.
However we translate this to one hot encoding because if we take a look at the shape right now it's
really just 60000 values.
And what could happen if you tried to feed the values this way.
Is the network gets confused and it thinks this is some sort of regression problem.
As if 5 0 and 4 our values on some sort of continuous scale instead of actual distinct categories.
So it may think that there's values like 4.5 that are in between some of these labels.
The network itself won't understand that these are categories.
If you feed them in this way.
So what you need to do is actually convert them to one high end coding.
So I'll show you as an example what this will look like will say from Cara's utils and.
And then say import to categorical.
And what we're going to do is we're actually going to grab our Y test in y train and pass it into this
two categorical function.
So I will create y underscore cat test and y underscore cat train.
So these are my categorical versions of the Y train and Y test and only need to do is pass into categorical
and then pass in the labels and the second argument is a number of classes.
And in this case I have classes 0 3 9 so I have 10 possible classes and it's going to be pretty much
the same thing for this second one except it will be.
Why train so go ahead and run that and then double check that these new variables like categorical test
looks something like this.
Notice now it's been one hot uncoated.
In fact let's take a look at why cat train is 0.
You remember why that train of 0.
That's the five right here.
So we converted this 5 to be 100 coded.
So if I go along and start counting in the expedition's zero one two three four five.
Bingo.
At the fifth in the index position I'm one hundred could it to be a 1.
Now clearly these are categories.
This is something that a neural network can understand.
And it works especially well with the sigmoid function which is going to output zeros or ones.
OK so now we have our categorical test and training labels.
Let's move on to processing the X data.
So we're going to come over here and let's check out that single image again.
So here we have that single image.
And notice this one actually hasn't been normalized.
So if I take a look at the max value
it's still 255.
We should normalize this to be within 0 and 1.
There's lots of different ways you can do this but I want to show you just manually how you do this
process in case for some reason you didn't have access to sikat learn.
The idea is really simple.
All we need to do is divide by the max value and it will normalize everything to be between 0 and 1.
So we can say X train is equal to extremely divided by X train Max.
In this case that's also the same as saying divided by 255.
So I can just copy that run that and then I'm going to do the same thing for X test.
So X test is equal to x test divided by X tests Max.
And if I take a look at one of these images now.
So let's go ahead and say scaled image is equal to x.
Train 0 for Take a look at the scaled image.
Notice now they're just zeros and all the values are now between 0 and 1.
This is going to help our network.
Otherwise it may kind of blow up on us with such large values and we'll say check the max.
There we go.
It's one.
And yet all the ratios will still be there.
So I should still be able to show my scaled image say See map is equal to gray.
Underscore are run that.
And I see the image just fine.
In fact visually there is no distinct difference between having a scale from 0 to 255 versus just the
same scaling scale down from 0 to 1.
Now the next step is to reshape the data because if I take a look at my data right now specifically
my training data.
So if I take a look at x train or X test and ask for the shape of it it's right now sixty thousand by
28 by 28.
However I want to make this into a generalized network that can work on just any sort of image data.
So in that case I need to reshape to also include the color channels in this specific case we just have
one color channel which is why they just left the empty but I'm going to reshape this so we can actually
see how the actual multidimensional arrays would look with for them actions.
One for the number of training images.
Then your X and then your Y and then the color channels.
So let's set this up we'll say X train is equal to x train.
Reshape it to be 60000.
Whoops by 20 eights by 28 and then by one essentially just the finding of the fact that there is a channel
there.
So if you run that nothing really gets distorted We just happened to clarify that we have one in one
dimension and that fourth dimension there is a single color channel there and will do the exact same
thing for the Tesa.
So I will copy and paste this code except remember the test set is a little smaller.
It's 10000 images.
So we change the 60000 to 10.
Run that and then your accessit should essentially be the same thing just reorganized to have that x
in colored color channel.
And I can check the shape there to confirm this.
And there it is 10000 by 28 by 28 by 1.
Now we're ready to do.
Is that the data has been processed.
We've understood the data.
We visualize that.
We also fix the labels to be 100 coded.
It's time to actually build and train our model.
OK.
So in order to build out the model we will say from Cara's dot models import sequential just as we did
when we were starting off with the very basics of cars.
We're going to be using a sequential model essentially just a bunch of sequential series of layers.
And then for the actual layers we're going to be using.
It's going to be a little more than before previously we just used a dense layer that now since we're
using convolutional neural network we're going to be using a Slayer as well as a convolutional 2D layer
because working up to the images.
And then a max pooling layer also to the.
And then a final air called Flaten which flattens out the two dimensional image.
Let's go ahead and import those.
And the first that let me scroll down a little bit give ourselves some more space.
The first step is actually create the model so we create the sequential object and then we're going
to start off with a convolutional air.
So we'll say model add in and we'll add in this con the to the layer and we're going to set filters
to 32 filters well set the kernel size 2 4 by 4 and obviously these are things you can adjust and play
around with.
But these tend to be pretty good standard values.
Typically the kernel size is three by three or four by four and filters 32 is a good choice for these
particular images.
They're pretty straightforward and simple but if you're dealing with very complex images you may want
to actually up the number of filters used.
Now we have kernel size there.
The next parameter is input shape and that one is actually something you can't really mess around with.
What is the actual input shape of each individual image.
And it's pretty straightforward it's just 28 by 20 by 1.
And if you had color images it would be the X and Y and the three color channels.
So I'm going to copy and paste those.
So at 28 by 28 by 1 images and then we get to choose an activation function and typically the rectified
linear unit or three.
Works quite well.
So we'll use that one OK.
Now that we have a compilation of convolutional Leor we need a pooling layer
so will say model add and then we're going to add any Max pool to the.
And then we get to choose the pool size and two by two is a good default size to start off with.
And again this pool size is something you can experiment with.
Often what people do is they'll read the latest publications and people will say what actual size sizes
kernels or filter's or pool size that they use.
And you can kind of copy the best ideas from the latest papers and then add them to your own networks.
OK once we have the pooling layer we need to do is eventually transform these convolutional employing
layers into something that a single dense layer can understand.
So in order to do that we need to flatten that out.
So Will same model add.
And we're going to add in a flat layer because remember these two layers can understand too that missional
images.
Our very last layer is going to be a single layer of 10 on the sigmoid function that takes in and outputs
the correct label which means we eventually have to flatten out the two dimensional stuff to be one
dimensional.
So we can do that with this Flaten.
So this ends up going from to the to the OK once we're able to flatten this out.
Well we're going to do is add in one more dense layer we'll say a model at pass and then Slayer and
then we need to choose a number of neurons for this dense layer.
Really there again is kind of no right or wrong answer but typical values here specifically for this.
And this data set to perform well is 128 say activation is rectified linear unit again lots of stuff
you can experiment here.
I encourage you to kind of play around with these number of neurons in this last dense layer.
The last one is something that we actually can't really play around with.
It's going to be the output layer which is essentially the classifier.
So this will take in or output to 10 and it's activation is going to be soft max.
So that will directly output what the classes it thinks it is.
They will say model compile and I will be choosing categorical cross entropy as their last function
then will also be choosing an optimizer which is going to be a mess.
And then the metrics that we're concerned with we'll just take a look at accuracy OK go ahead and then
run that and then we'll say model summary and this will summarize your model in a really cool way.
It just tells you the different layers the output shapes and the relevant parameters then are ready
to train our model.
So we will say model fit and we'll passen our extremely data and all person our categorical why train
data and we'll go ahead and run this for two epochs and IPAC is just one entire run through the entire
training set.
So we'll be running through the entire training set twice.
So go ahead and run this.
Keep in mind depending on how fast your computer is this may take some time.
I have a pretty fast computer so you're going to see it run pretty fast in real time.
But let's go ahead and fast forward until this is done training.
OK.
It just finished for me.
It took nine seconds on the first six seconds on the second one so pretty fast.
We're going to do next is actually grab and evaluate the model.
So remember we can say model metrics name so has lost an accuracy.
These are the things reported right here.
We're already getting like 90 percent accuracy in the training set which is pretty darn good for just
two bucks.
So let's see how it actually performed on the.
You'll see a model evaluates on X test and y categorical test.
So if you run that you'll notice that even on the Tesa as well it gets 98 percent accuracy.
In fact it's performing up slightly better on the test set than it did on the train set.
So it's good that you're getting good performance on both training and test.
They should be relatively similar.
Otherwise if you're performing a really poorly on the test set that really well in the training set
that means you're probably overfitting the training set.
OK so now that we've evaluate our model let's go ahead and actually predict classes on images that the
model hasn't seen before.
We'll say from S-K learn that metrics in.
And let's just do a classification report.
We'll say predictions.
So how do we actually use this model to predict on new images that it hasn't seen before.
All we need to do is say model predict classes and this is where you can passen images that it hasn't
seen before.
In our case we already have images it has seen before.
That's ex-best so it will run that and we know the correct answers for that.
It's white cat test.
So remember we have the correct answer here.
Let's actually then compare the values using the cat classification report.
Say Prince classification report and compare Y test and those here I'm saying why test because these
classes if you take a look at the results of the predictions they're actually in the original format
so they're no longer 100 coded.
The result of predict classes actually predicts these classes correctly.
But lucky for us we saved that white test.
So we have it right here and there is one of them that's doing pretty good.
So I'll say why test compared to the predictions run that and we're getting about ninety nine percent
precision recall and EF 1 score that's really quite well.
So complex neural networks can easily saw this otherwise seemingly complex problem of classifying hand-reared
digits.
OK so let's move on to showing you how to work on another similar dataset with convolutional neural
networks and Cara's and images will see their.