Welcome back everyone.
We're going to continue a couple of examples using cures for convolutional neural networks.
This time we're going to work with color images.
We'll be working with the famous Safari 10 dataset which is color images of various objects.
Let's get started.
OK so here we are in Jupiter Lab. we're going to begin by importing the data set we'll say from curiousest
datasets.
Import Safar A10.
Go ahead and run that.
And then we will actually load the data by saying X train y train Khama X test Y test.
Make sure that's an underscore and then set that equal to Safar 10.
The load underscore data.
So go ahead and run that.
And if we check the shape of our actual data there is fifty thousand thirty two thirty two and three.
So this is actually already formatted to have three color channels.
Let's take a look at just one of the training data points.
So there's 50000 images each 32 by 32 or three color channels.
And if we take a look at a single one and check its shape then we get 32 by 32 by 3.
Let's actually view some of these nor to view them we do an import that lived up high plot as Piazzi
And just in case you need it you can do that live in line for viewing in the notebook will say Pulte
show and then say X train 0.
And here we see an instance of one of the types.
So this is a frog.
It's a little blurry to see.
But if you kind of squint your eyes a little bit or back away from the computer screen you can see it
it's a frog and other object type is horses.
So here you can see an image of a horse again pretty low resolution just 32 by 32 but the general shape
and outlines is what we can tell here.
Also the fact that we have color.
So what we want to do now is actually a little bit of pre-processing.
If we took out the max values here noticed that they go to 255.
So we're going to do is just divide x train and X test by 255.
We will say X train is equal to x train divided by 255 and X test is equal to x test divided by 255.
Just as we did for the this dataset.
So now this is scaled if we check out the shape of our X test this is 10000 images.
We have 50000 trainee images and then 10000 images for testing.
And each of these images is 32 by 32 with three color channels.
Now if we take a look at the labels such as white train you'll notice that the labels are actually still
in their normal integer category forms.
So we need to convert these to be one high and coded just as we did in the previous lecture.
So we will say from carious utils import to categorical.
And this is actually the same function as we did before.
So there's two ways to import it.
You can then do from the tills or from Cara's thought you tale's just want to show you both options
in case you're run into both during the documentation.
OK so now let's go ahead and convert our white labels.
We will say why cat train is equal to two categorical.
And then we'll pasan why train.
And for this specific set there's 10 possible labels and then we will say why cat test is equal to two
categorical why test 10.
So then go ahead and run those to have the actual categories.
Now if you're interested in what the actual ten categories are you can check out the Wikipedia page
for Safar 10.
So it's from the Canadian Institute for Advanced Research.
You can see it has airplanes cars birds cats thier dogs frogs horses ships and trucks.
So it's actually not all animals.
There's also some messes of Transportation there as well.
And what's also cool from the Wikipedia article you can check out the error rates and their publication
dates.
So in August 2010 the error rate was twenty one point one percent.
And we're going to blow that out of the water even if just using simple cares and our own little models
here.
And then you can check out kind of state of the art 1.4 8 percent error rates.
So let's go ahead and come back here.
We have a categorical one hot and coded labels.
So those are good to go.
Now it's time to actually build our model.
We're going to do is say from Cara's that models import sequential and then from carious the layers
import dense Canvey are delusional to the.
Also to max pool to the.
And then we'll import Flaten and let's construct our network.
So I begin by saying model is equal to sequential and we're going to have a convolutional there.
So we'll add that in model add convolutional to the.
And also the number of filters to 32 kernel size will be four by four.
The input shape for these images if we say put shape that's equal to 32 by 32 and of three sensors three
color channels and then the last thing I want to mention is what the activation is here we'll just choose
activation is equal to rectified linear unit.
Okay then we're going to do is have a pooling layer.
So right after that we will say model the add and then say Max Poole to the and then say pool size is
equal to 2 by 2.
And what we're going to do is have a second set of convolutional errors.
So in fact I'm just going to copy these exact two layers and then paste them again because these images
are slightly more complex.
They're a little larger than this or 32 by 32 instead of 28 by 28 plus we have the three color channels.
So another convolutional there is probably a good idea then we'll go ahead and flatten the images or
see a model at Flaten
and then we'll have a dense hidden layer.
So we will say model and dance.
And again it's up to you how many neurons you want in this dense hidden layer.
What's really common especially in working with image data is that people like to add in neurons as
it gets more and more complex and orders of two to the power something.
So you'll see often values like 1:28 and then that up power is then 2:56 and then 5:12 and so on.
People and researchers tend to do that and will go ahead and follow their example.
So we'll use 2:56 again there's no no real right or wrong value here.
We can play around with it and encourage you to do so and we'll say this dance is going to have an activation
function of rectified linear unit then we want the last layer to be the classifier will say model add
dance and there's only 10 categories so we'll say 10 and this activation is going to be a soft Max that
we will compile this by saying model compile the last will be equal to categorical cross entropy
that the optimizer will be equal to armis prop and the metrics used.
Let me scroll down here.
We'll just use accuracy as our main metric.
Go ahead and run that and then let's check out the model summary.
So here we can see all the various layers we're doing are using an outside to fit the model we'll St
model fit x train and we'll pass in the categorical values for white train and go ahead and say verbose
is equal to 1 so you can see a little more details as it's training and then say e pocks and I personally
train this model on 10 e POCs that actually takes a little bit of time.
So if you have a slow computer you may want to lower the number of epochs and as a quick mention we
actually have an h file for you if you have a slow computer you don't want to wait for the training
time.
You can load our file and the file is called and let me copy the string from our notebook.
It's Safar underscore 10 E.
H5.
So if you look at our file we have a file here ready for you.
It's fitted already to 10 e POCs if you want to use that instead of training your own.
That's totally ok too.
You can check out the SpaceX lecture on how to load in that sort of model.
So we have several H5 files ready for you to go if you want to use those instead.
I'll go ahead and fit this and let it train.
All right so I fast forward in time.
It looks like we're hitting around 80 percent accuracy after 20 pucks.
That's all right.
We could keep trying for more epochs But we'll sit on that for now.
Now go ahead.
Just quickly evaluate our model.
We're going to say model number took up the metric names its loss and accuracy just as shown here.
So let's evaluate on the Tesa we will see model that evaluate and say X test and then say y categorical
test run that that will evaluate the model and we can see here on the test set.
It's actually not performing super well.
It's performing about 63 percent accuracy.
So let's actually perform a classification report.
There may be certain types of images that are harder to classify than others will say from S-K learn
metrics import classification report and let's grab some new predictions off data it hasn't seen before.
So will say model predicts classes and then person X test and let's run a classification report on that
it will print out the classification report on why tests and predictions run that.
And now we see a classification report.
So we can see here it's doing fairly similar across all categories.
It's probably Category 2 and 3 where it's not doing that well.
But overall there isn't some category that really stands out as super well and there isn't really a
category it sounds as very poor.
What I want to quickly show you is we've actually trained a larger model for you in case you want to
load it and play around with that.
And if you actually look at our lecture notebook that corresponds with this lecture.
So open up right here this is the Cara's CNN Safar 10 0 2 notebook.
If you take a look at this notebook as you scroll down and go all the way to the bottom you'll notice
there's an optional large model.
So if you're running on a faster computer you can go ahead and run this larger model.
We've gone ahead and added some more layers and specifically we have a much larger dense layer that's
five hundred and twelve neurons.
Now it can go through this and see that it actually still doesn't perform super well but it performs
slightly better on the actual predictions.
And we went ahead and say that as larger Safar 10 model H5.
So feel free to play around with those values and feel free also run this for more epochs.
We can do is also run this while you're sleeping at night in case you want to test the accuracy that
way.
But you can see that it begins hovering around the 70s here.
So if you start getting very slow growth in accuracy and you're probably hitting your limits.
OK.
So that's it for this project.
Coming up next we're going to expand on this and show you how to work with custom images.
Keep in mind for these custom images we're going have to download an external data set we'll see at
the next lecture.