Welcome back so far we've seen how to create deep learning networks for the dataset and then for the
Safar 10 data set.
Those were small images and we went from greyscale in the end this dataset to color images and the Safar
10.
However we still haven't learned how to work for custom images in a real world situation.
You're not going to be able to just simply upload images using a curious import tool instead you'll
have to work with raw jpeg or DNG files.
This lecture is designed to show you how you can work your own custom image data sets and for that we're
going to need to download a preexisting data set that has the raw image files.
We're not going to be using an import tool like Harris.
Instead we'll be downloading a data set of just raw images and we'll be showing you how to resize them
also how to perform different operations on them to make them suitable for training and then will actually
work with those real custom image files to build out a neural network.
So in order to do this we need to first download the file.
Let me show you how you can download the file.
Make sure you viewed the previous lectureship for this one because it does contain the file link.
OK let's get started.
All right.
In the actual course overview page.
Again this is the course overview page.
You should then be able to click on course content and then come back down to deep learning for computer
vision and right before this deep learning on custom images.
We have this lecture link for cats and dogs.
Go ahead and click on that lecture.
And if you were actually in the course curriculum viewer you could also just come over here and then
search for it.
It's in Section 8.
We have the links for cats and dogs zip.
So what you need to do is you either click on this link for cats and dogs is it.
I also wrote the L here in case that click isn't working for you.
But once you click on this link to open it it should look something like this for you.
Let me bring in that file.
So once you click on that link you should see something that says cats and dogs start xit.
It won't be able to preview it's around 730 megabytes So it's quite a large file once you have this
window open.
You just need to click on download go ahead and download the file and make sure that you keep track
of where the zip file was downloaded to.
OK so once you download the file go ahead and open your file explorer and locate the file.
All right.
So I've downloaded the folder and it's in my downloads folder right now.
We are going to need to do is you're going to need to move this zip file to her ever your notebooks
are that can be either in the course directory or the actual deep learning folder or if you happen to
be running notebooks in the Downloads folder.
Then go ahead and just leave it here again wherever you're working with your notebook file.
That's the IPY and by extension you're going to need the zip file to be in that same location once you've
moved the zip file to the correct location.
Go ahead and extract it.
You can extract it using the built in extraction tools either in windows or in Mac OS or you can download
a program such as Seven's it and just extract the files here.
So we'll go ahead and say extract here and this is a really large zip file so it will take a little
bit of time.
I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done.
Extracting it should take a couple of minutes.
Again we're dealing with real images here so this is a very large set of images and are essentially
images of cats and dogs.
OK let's fast forward until this is done.
Extracting once you successfully extracted the contents from the zip file you should be able to open
up this cats and dogs folder and then see two folders.
Test entrain then within each of these folders there's two more folders.
Cat and dog.
And then if you open up that then you have the actual images and those here they're all essentially
just numbers that jpeg.
So we're going to go over this in more detail.
But essentially whenever you are working on a real image files with carrots and building your own neural
network for them they have to be in this organization.
You need to talk little folders one for your test data and one for your trained data and then inside
these folders you need a separate folder for each category of image.
So notice if I can.
These are all cat photos and if I come back the test of hit dog These are all dog photos and these file
names are exactly the same between the test and the train folders.
OK now that we have all the data sorted out.
Let's open up a Jupiter lab notebook and get started on building up our own custom network.
Let's begin by taking a look at the actual images.
So to do that we're going to import that live high plot Haspiel T and then also import CB2 And just
in case you need to do it.
Depending on your version of the notebook go ahead and say I'm not putting it in line right.
I'm going to read in a cat image will say Cat 4 is equal to to imagery and right now the way I saved
my folder is in the same directory that my current notebook is in.
I have the cats and dogs folder.
Again it depends on where you actually unzip this file or what path you're going to put here.
So keep that in mind.
Pay very close attention to that.
So I'm going to say cats and dogs and inside of that graph from the training folder and inside of that
there's a folder and then for j peg.
That's an actual cat image since I read it in live TV too.
I need to say CB2 thoughts CVT color and convert it back to the correct color display color underscore
and we're going from blue green red to green blue and let's show that image.
OK so here we can see what the image of this particular cat looks like.
Notice it's 0 by will actually check the shape will say Cat 4 shape is 375.
For five hundred by three color channels.
Let's now upload another image from our dataset.
Let's upload a dog will say dog is equal to CB2 image read and inside my cats and dogs.
I'll go ahead and grab again from the training the dog folder and let's say to touch it.
Will also do a color correction.
I mean just copy and paste this color correction command paste here and then just replace it with dog
run that say appeal t him show dog and there we have this dog on a leash.
Now something that's important to notice here is that this is real image data.
This actually isn't formatted any particular way.
As far as the shapes of the images.
So this dog shape is actually a completely different size than this cat.
So this cat is a 375 by 500 image.
The stock is a 1 9 9 by 1 8 image so all these images there are different sizes.
So this is reflective of real world data.
You're probably not gonna be able to manually upload images that are all the exact same shape and form.
Especially if you're trying to gather tens of thousands of images.
So what we're going to do is prepare the data for the model.
Now there's too much data here for us to read all at once in memory.
We're close to overegg gigabyte of information here.
But luckily Cara's actually has some functions that will automatically process the data and generate
a flow of batches from a directory.
So it's called the image data generator and it's part of the pre-processing package from Cara's you
will say from Cara's da pre-processing image import image data generator.
OK.
So even though we have a lot of images right now it doesn't really help us if we only train on these
images alone.
What we should do is also do slight transformations on the images maybe do a little bit of rotation.
That way if I see this sort of dog.
But it happens to be facing in in their action or the image is a little tilted or maybe it's inverse
me or the dogs looking to the right and sort of to the left etc. if we're able to also generate images
that have random fluctuations to them you'll create for a stronger model.
So the network will be more robust to different dog images and that's part of what the image data generated
does.
I will make an object called imagen and then say image data generator and it's going to take a ton of
parameters so let's walk through them.
And technically these are a lot of these are optional.
But I do recommend them specifically for data sets where you need to create more images.
So one parameter is the rotation range and this will randomly rotate images so you can provide how many
degrees they should randomly be rotated.
And I would just kind of a minor rotation.
You don't want something extreme like 180.
Otherwise you'll be training on upside down dogs which is quite unusual.
Hopefully so we'll see rotation ranges around 30 degrees.
And then we'll also specify a width shift range and this will shift the pic with by a certain maximum
percentage.
So kind of stretch out the images along the x axes and the percentage here actually give it as some
value between 0 and 1.
So we'll say 10 percent.
That means we're going to randomly resizes images X by 0.1 and we'll do the same for the height.
So we'll say height shift range is equal to zero point.
Now we may also want to rescale the images.
So essentially normalizing it.
And if I take a look at the max value and dog right now it's 255.
So let's go ahead and normalize that and luckily image data generator can do that for us.
We don't need to manually do division ourselves we just say rescale and what we want to multiply for
the rescale in this case we're going to multiply by one over 255 which is the same as the vitam by 255.
Next we can also apply a shear range what sheer does is it means it actually cuts away part of the image.
So essentially the opposite of expanding an image is to cut away from it or crop it.
So we'll go ahead and allow it to crop 20 percent that way.
It also is more robust and doesn't train really on things like shoes or things around the dog.
OK.
So we have sheer range and then we can also add in a little bit of zoom so we can say zoom range and
we can zoom in by a certain maximum.
So let's go ahead and zoom in by maybe 20 percent then well we can also do is add a horizontal flip.
So a horizontal flip essentially flips from the dark looking this way and the shoes on this side the
shoes and the right hand side and the dog looking the other way.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And for that we provide a horizontal flip and set it equal to true.
Keep in mind there's also a vertical flip but again we don't want to train on upside down images of
dogs.
So it's not really helpful to us although horizontally flipping that is helpful because it can create
similar images of the dog.
You know standing in the right way up but slightly different.
And then film mode will go ahead and say nearest.
So as you can imagine if we're stretching and rescaling the images and rotating them we're going to
have some missing pixels that we need to fill in.
Specifically on stretching the image.
So we're going to do is we're just going to fill in those missing pixels with the nearest value.
OK.
So we have our image data generator.
Let me show you what happens when we actually run an image through the image data generator.
So I will say imagen and then you call random transform and pass in one of the images are going to pass
and the dog image.
So when you run this you'll get back an array of the transform image which means you can show it.
So I will run this and here he can see in effect.
Keep in mind this is a random transform all of this happens randomly and it's up to 10 percent so it
could be 5 percent shift maybe an 8 percent high.
It could be rotated by 10 degrees 15 degrees anything below 30 and so on.
So you're not going to get the exact same image I got here.
You should get some something kind of random maybe a whole twist et cetera.
So you can already those lots of things are happening here.
We've decided to stretch out the image.
We've also rotated it slightly and we've also done a horizontal flip.
So this is going to help provide more training images and keep the neural network more robust to just
general images of dogs and you can keep running this over and over again to generate different types
of random transformations on the image overall.
You do keep seeing a picture of a dog but they're all slightly different.
And that's going to help the neural network train.
Next we want to do is generate many manipulated images directly from a directory which is why we needed
the specific structure mentioned in the beginning of this lecture.
So what we do is the following will say image Jeon thought and what we're going to be calling is we
call flow from directory and when we're flowing from of that victory we're going to do it once for training
and then once for a test.
So it looks something like this are actually not going to run this right now but I just want to show
you what it actually looks like.
It's essentially a generator a just point it to the train folder where inside of the training folder
if we take a look at that folder again remember inside your training folder you have a folder for each
category.
So let's say we're trying to classify it between dogs cats and birds.
You would have another folder here called Bird and then it would be filled only with bird images.
So again the structure you need is train test and then with within each of those you need a folder for
each category you're classifying.
In our case it's pretty straightforward.
And if you're to run this you get back this sort of iterator.
So Ill tell you how many images it found and how many classes it thinks it belongs to.
And the reason it automatically knows two classes is because it knows that there was only two folders
within the train folder.
So that's how that works.
And we're going to be using this later on for both train and test.
Plus we'll also add in a few more parameters later on.
OK.
So now the next step is to actually create the model.
So in part two of this lecture series we're going to create the model.
Show you what it would look like if you're going to train the model.
And then since this sort of network actually requires around a hundred epochs we're going to load a
model that I've already trained for you that we don't need to wait around maybe an hour for this to
train the pending on how fast your computer is.
So let's go ahead and head over to the next lecture where we build out an example model and instead
of training it will show you what the model looks like.
But then load up the resulting model.
OK I'll see at the next lecture.