Welcome to part one of our cap some project we're going to be focusing on some global variables and
setting up a background function.
So first come to find some global variables and then afterwards we'll set up a function that updates
a running average of the background values in a particular region of interests.
This will later on allow us to test new objects such as a hand entering into the region of interest.
So let's talk about our overall strategy for actually counting figure fingers.
First we're going to grab a region of interest that was that red box you saw in the previous lecture
then we're going to calculate a running average background value for some amount of frames like 60 frames
of video and then once the average value is found then we can have the hand enter the region of interest.
So to understand this visually we set our NY calculate that average running value for some amount of
frames like 60 frames.
Then once a hand actually enters we can detect the change and then apply some thresholding techniques
to isolate the hand and isolate the Hans segment.
Now once we actually have that threshold at hand segment we're going to have that hand enter the region
of interest and we're going to do what's known as a convex hole to dry polygon around the hand and we'll
talk about convex hole and more detail later on though once we have this polygon what we can do is we
can use a little bit of clever math to calculate the center of the hand then using some more math will
calculate the center of the hand against the angle of the outer points to and for a finger count.
So you notice that this polygon should in theory have points at each particular finger and then based
off a distance from the center we'll be able to detect whether or not that finger is extended.
And then we'll also be able to use some angle in order to calculate some distances between fingers.
So keep in mind the strategy won't be perfect if you're holding up your fingers here like Spock is.
And you'll notice he's actually holding up all five fingers.
Our particular method isn't going to be able to read this because it's going to detect his fingers as
three fingers being held up.
It's not going to detect a space between for instance his index and middle finger and his ring finger
and pinky finger.
So unfortunately our technique is a little too naive to actually understand someone holding up all five
fingers in that fashion.
All right.
Let's get started with the average background function and some global variables in imports.
I'm starting a brand new notebook.
But if you want to follow along or reference the notebook code all you need to do is open up the capstone
project folder and then you should see a finger underscore count notebook file which if you open it
has all the code that we're going to be working through through this series of lectures.
OK let's go back to our new notebook and began typing some of this code out.
First we actually need to perform some imports.
So we're going to import too we'll import them pie as NPE and we're also going to say from S-K learn
the metrics import pairwise later on we're going to be using some distance calculation to actually calculate
how many fingers are being held up and we're going to be using a library called sikat learnt for that
which should come with Anaconda already.
So go ahead and import that really right now we're just going to be using CB2 later on throughout the
series of lectures we'll introduce this pairwise now that we have our imports.
We're going to create some global variables.
We're going to start off by creating background as none and then we want to say accumulated weight as
a variable and set that equal halfway point between 0 and 1.
So say 0.5 and then we're going to set up a region of interest that is the actual red bounding box that
we're looking for.
And at first we're just going to have it be empty.
We're going to calculate an average background value and then later on we'll actually insur or hand
into that region of interest and we'll be able to see how many fingers we're holding up.
It's up to you what your region of interest should be.
We're just defending it as a rectangle.
And I'm going to define it as our top as equal to 20 or I bottom is equal to 300 are all I write is
equal to 300 an r y left is equal to 600.
These are essentially going to be the corners of the rectangle that I draw on the screen.
Again you can play around with these values if you want the bounding box to be at the center of your
video stream.
You may just want to actually calculate it based off the width and height of the actual video camera
stream.
Again it's really up to you.
I just found these values convenient for my particular USP camera.
So you may need to change these values if they're too close to the edge.
So those are all the global variables we're going to find for now.
And then up next we're going to create a function that will find the average background value.
We're going to call this function calculates accumulated average or X whom underscore avi G and it's
going to take in a frame and it's going to take in some value for the accumulated weight.
So he's going to say accumulated weight
and then we're actually going to grab the global background value which starts off as none.
So the very first time around this background is going to be none.
We haven't sensed it from the frame yet.
So for the first time if the background is none then we're going to set the background to be a copy
of the frame being passed in.
And later on we're going to use this function as part of a larger piece of code.
So say if background is done say background is equal to frame copy and then we're going to call it as
type fliped and then we're going to return
so the very first time around we're going to set background and make sure it's capital N going to check
if the background is done meaning the very first loop background is done here.
We're just going to set background equal to a framed copy and this actual function isn't going to return
in accumulated average and it's going to return them if the background happens I actually have a value.
Meaning it's no longer done.
Well we're going to do here is say to and we're going to call accumulated or accumulated weighted so
accumulate weighted.
And what that does is you passen if you take a shift tab here you can check out you passen the source
to the destination and then some alpha value and this function what does is a calculator the way that
some of the input image source and the accumulator destination so that the station becomes a running
average of a frame sequence.
So it's actually going to be accumulating the weight based off the running average.
So we're going to do here is the following.
We're going to pass in our current frame and then pass in the background and then we're going to have
a current accumulated weight.
Now notice what I'm doing here I'm not actually going to return this accumulated weight.
Instead I'm just going to be affecting the global background here.
Again something to note here.
I'm not returning anything on this function unless it's the very first time.
I'm just going to return on for everything else when I call this function.
I'm just grabbing the global background variable and then I'm going to update with the accumulated weight.
So that's it for this function.
Again we did our imports we set up some global variables and we have our accumulated weight function
coming up next we're going to do is learn how to segment the hand region in the frame we'll see at the
next lecture.