Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to give a general overview of machine learning and the machine learning process.
So before we dive into deep learning and yolo and neural networks it should be the case that we have
a fundamental understanding of some intuition behind the machine learning process specifically the kind
of machine learning that we're going to be conducting which is supervised learning now because different
students have different backgrounds in math.
We're going to get the mathematics behind these different methods pretty light.
But if you're really interested in the mathematics behind machine learning and the algorithms we're
going to be using you can check out the resource links as we go along.
And a really great textbook on just general machine learning is an introduction to learning by Gareth
James and I would really recommend that if you're interested in machine learning you take a look at
this book.
It's actually not really related to image analysis or deep warning on images.
It's just the general textbook about the math behind machine learning and general machine learning concepts.
It's a great book.
It's freely available online.
Again live coverage of algorithms that really aren't introduced in this course but I still really love
this book and recommend that to all my students.
OK that's enough for that plug of the book.
Let's go ahead and continue.
So what is machine learning machine learning is a method of data analysis that automates analytical
model building using algorithms that we learn from data.
Machine learning allows computers to find hidden insights without being explicitly programmed to look
pretty much all our image analysis with open C-v and Python.
We've been telling the computer what to actually do with the image we've been telling it to perform
morphological operators or perform certain filters or thresholding machine learning is kind of going
to flip that on its head where instead of going to give the computer the images and the desired output
such as classifying something as a dog or cat and the deep learning algorithms are going to be able
to work out on their own.
The best approach to take and I know that's kind of a very high level overview but really that's the
idea here that we're kind of flipping it around.
We're giving the desired output and the input and the computer's going to figure out what it needs to
do instead of the reverse which is what we have been doing given the input telling the computer a list
of instructions of what to do and then getting our desired output.
So what does machine learning used for.
It's used in a bunch of stuff things like fraud detection such as getting a call from your credit card
company saying they have a fraudulent detection on your account.
New pricing models pattern image recognition tech sentiment analysis recommendation engines a whole
plethora of applications and we're really focused on how we can apply machine learning to image analysis.
So the kind of machine learning we're going to be conducting in the section is known as supervised learning
and supervised learning algorithms are trained using labeled examples such as an input where the desired
output is known.
For example we're exploring how we can give the input of a picture that has a category label such as
a picture of a dog or a picture of a cat or someone has manually labeled that you have an image of a
dog or an image of a cat.
That way once the machine learning model has been trained we can give it a brand new picture that we
don't have a label for and it will attempt to predict whether it's looking at a dog or a cat so the
learning algorithm is going to receive a set of inputs along with the corresponding correct outputs
and the algorithm learns by comparing its actual output with the correct outputs to find errors.
It then modifies the model accordingly.
And supervised learning is commonly used in applications where historical data point can predict a likely
future event such as historical image data can then predict what new image data is.
So let's take a look at the machine learning process.
And this is really the core of this particular lecture.
So this is the machine learning process and we're going to go through it step by step.
Again this is the supervised learning process.
The first step is to actually get your data.
And since we're working with image data you'd have to actually grab the images and these can be sourced
from customers who are uploading images.
Maybe ask every customer to upload an image of what their living room looks like or different furniture
in their living room or maybe have sensors like on a self-driving car you're taking pictures as the
car is driving and getting images of the road for maybe late detection techniques or that sort of thing.
So again we have to figure out how we're actually going to get our data in this particular course.
We provide all the data for you so that job is pretty much already done for you.
So once you actually have the raw data those are the raw images or raw videos then you move on to data
cleaning and formatting and for image data carriers actually has a lot of nice built in tools in order
to clean and format your data correctly.
So it's often the case that you actually have real image data that comes in a bunch of different sizes
maybe different formats or maybe it's skewed differently.
Pictures are rotated and using carrots we have an image data generator object that can stretch and resize
images as necessary plus perform a lot of other applications on them.
So we'll be viewing that closely later on in the section of the course.
So now we've acquired the actual images.
We've cleaned them up resize them perform different operations on them and then it's time to actually
take that image data and split it up and we split it up into a test set and a train set or test data
and training data.
So the first we're going to do is just grab the training data.
And typically a split could be something like take 30 percent of those clean images and set them off
as test data and then take 70 percent of them and set them as training data.
So let's focus on that training data.
What we do is we apply our model on the training data and have it learn simply on the training data
and then we build and fit the model to that training data.
Then we want to evaluate how well our model perform.
So we take that we take that test data that we set aside and then we actually test the model on that
test data essentially trying to predict on the test data.
Well we actually already know the correct label.
So then we can evaluate the model and see how it performs.
Then in case we want to adjust parameters in our model we can take it back to the training and building
phase and then fit the model again and then retest and we can redo the cycle over and over again until
we're finally satisfied with the volume evaluation metrics that our model is performing with and we'll
discuss classification metrics in the next lecture.
So once we've done that we can deploy our model essentially predicting on new incoming data that was
outside of our original dataset Now image classification and recognition is a very common and widely
applicable use of deep learning machine learning with open city and kurus.
So we did continue now by learning about how to actually evaluate it classification task and we're going
to review if we go back here really this step right here.
So we're going to review the step of model training and building and then how we actually test and evaluate
our model so that's really the key component that we're going to be viewing throughout the section of
the course.
OK.
So let's go ahead and continue on to the next lecture where we learn about classification metrics and
how to evaluate a classification algorithm.
We'll see it there.