Welcome everyone in this lecture we're going to have a quick crash course in high res when we actually
read in image data.
The computer is going to read it in as an array in the next lecture.
We'll describe that relationship between images in arrays and through the tail print now.
Let's go ahead and focus on just pure non-high how to create arrays in a few operations.
Indexing and slice on arrays are going to head over to Jupiter lap now.
OK here I am at Jupiter Lab. I'm going to go ahead and open a launcher so that's the plus button in
case you don't have it and then click on notebook here.
And now I have my two notebook let me collapse that file and I can also close the launcher.
So the first thing you need to do is actually import non-pilot and although we do this as we say important
of pi as an p and zoom in just a little more so you get a nice clear view of that.
OK.
Now pi has already been installed as part of your environment so you should already have it.
There's a couple of ways we can create arrays.
Most often we'll just be reading images and that will automatically create theory for us.
But in case you're interested for a couple of other ways if you have a normal Python list such as my
list is equal to one 2 three if you wanted to check the type of my list here I'll report back that it's
a list but we could do is cast it as an array by saying and P-doc array and then passing in my list
here.
And then notice if I just have it be returned the returns back in array object.
So I could say something like Mirei is equal to an array.
And then I have my array here and a customs check the type of my array and report back.
Yes in fact this no longer is the normal Python list.
It's actually a name PI array.
So it's nice about these pirates is they're going to be able to take in a different dimensions so I
can have a two then missional array.
So let's show you a couple of ways to create arrays that are more than just a single list being cast
into energy one method I could use is the arr. method.
And arrange what it does is if you do shift tab here Ill give you the documentation string.
Basically it returns evenly spaced values within a given interval.
So you give a start and a stop and an optional step size.
So here I could say start at zero and then go up to but not including tens of thousands the stopping
point and then give it a step size.
Well go ahead and say zero through 10 first.
So here's my array 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
Essentially this is the range version in non-pilot.
So as you may know Python has a built in range function.
A range is not Pye's version of that Scicos up to but not including tenths of 10 was that stopping point
as a third argument you can pass in a step size.
So by default it's just taking a step size of one integer or plus one at a time.
If we say two here then I'll take a step size of two.
So go zero to 2 to 4 to 6 to 8 and so on.
OK.
Now often what we're going to be doing is creating a two dimensional or three damage array.
All of one single value so that zeros is a useful function.
We're going to be using quite often zeroes.
The main argument you do is just the shape so what shape do you want the Saray.
Now we're going to do here is say shape is equal to and then you pass any tuple song to say I want a
five by five.
Right.
And here we have five rows by five columns.
So just to make that clear I'm going to say Give me a 10 by five or eight.
And I notice now I have 10 rows.
So the first dimension the index position here at 0 that's going to be the actual number of rows and
then the number of columns is the second one.
So.
So here we have five columns.
Now you'll notice each of these zeroes has a little decimal point after it.
That's because by default none pi is going to automatically create floats instead of just pure integers.
So arr. created integers and zeros is going to create floats.
So it's zero point instead of just 0.
So if we check the type of 0 by itself that's an integer.
If you check type of zero point zero that's a float.
And then if you just check the type of zero point that's also a float.
So keep that in mind.
These are all floating point numbers.
So zeros is something we're going to be using often throughout the course.
The other one we're going to be using often is N.P. ones and it's going to be the same thing it takes
a shape argument.
So you say shape is equal to and you can see two by four or whatever shape you desire.
And then we see one point for two rows by these four columns.
Keep in mind you don't have to declare the shape parameter.
Often you'll just see it done like this and that's the same thing.
All right.
So that concludes talking about how to create a raise from scratch.
The main ones we really need to know here that we're going to see all the time throughout the course
is that zeros which creates an array of zeros for us and the ones which creates an array of ones for
us where this first value in the shape is how many rows you have or the height of the array.
And the second one is how many columns you have or the width of the array.
So a little bit counterintuitive as far as relating the first one number of rows to height.
And the second one number of columns to width but that's going to make a lot more sense when we start
reading in images.
OK.
Now let's go over a couple of operations.
I'm going to shift into a couple of times here to get some new cells to clear some of the old stuff
out of the way.
So now we're going to do is to start off by setting what's known as a seed sort of say the random seed.
And then pasan 1 0 1.
What this does is it allows me to create the same random numbers each time.
So I'm doing this because I want to have some random numbers for this next series of operations.
So if I want to create random data I just say that random rant I and t anti-d's shift map here.
Basically this describes this particular function.
It's just going to create and return random integers from low inclusively to high exclusively.
So that means I'm going to say here grab me from 0 to 100 give me 10 random numbers.
Notice how my seed and the creation of the Saray are actually happening in the same cell.
The reason I have 101 here is just a seed number.
The actual value is pretty arbitrary.
But I want Judis the same number I do.
That way when you actually create these random values you get the same random numbers.
I do.
And you can do a google search on things like random generation or random number generation to actually
figure out the complex mathematics behind these seeds.
But for our purposes that's kind of irrelevant at the course.
I just wanna make sure you get the same random numbers I do.
So if you run this in the same cell when you get that array you should not get the same values here
95 11.
81 in Oregon to do is immediately after that.
Create one more moreI.
So say any random ran Diante and say grabbing numbers from 0 to 100.
Give me 10 more numbers and then check out that second array value.
You should get the same values I do.
If you do not get the same values I do.
Go ahead and just rerun the cells again in the same order.
OK so now we're going to show you a couple of operations that are useful such as finding the max and
min and mean of an array.
So we want to find out the max value of an array.
You can say a r r Max and this returns back the actual max value.
So notice here the max value is 95.
If I wanted to figure out the location of that max value I simply need to say RMX and then return back
the index location of that value.
So index 0 just like a python list.
You'll notice here that we have 95.
OK so we can do the same thing for men.
So I can figure out the minimum value by saying are that men.
So those are minimum value in the story was nine.
And if I wanted to figure out its location then I just say Aardman and it's at index location 7.
So if I count over starting at 0 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 and then at 7 we have the minimum value of nine.
OK.
And finally if you want to figure out the average value or the mean you can just call our mean and then
we have the average was sixty point eight.
So it calculates the mean something else you can do is you can reshape arrays.
This is sometimes useful.
So if I check out the shape parameter.
Notice how I'm just calling shape with no princess here.
It returns back a shape 10 comma and then nothing because it's actually just a single vector.
What it could do is say reshape this to another set of them mentions.
So if you shift tab here you'll say OK what shape do you want it in now.
Well let's imagine that I wanted to reshape it to be two by five so now it's reshape this to be two
rose by five columns.
If I try to choose values that don't make sense such as 2 by 10 it's going to give you an error it's
going to say hey I can't reshape an array size 10 into shape 2 by 10 which makes sense because if you
have an array of two by 10 that means there's two times 10 elements that means 20 elements.
However you only had 10 elements to work with.
So that's why it's giving us an error here because those dimensions don't make sense but we could always
reshape to something that does make sense.
Like five to six five times to ten and we have 10 elements that works out just fine.
OK.
So that's the basics of operations that we need to know.
Lastly we want to understand indexing.
So I'm going to make a couple of more cells here to clear up some of this space and I'm going to create
a variable called mat for Matrix will say that arr. 0 to 100 and then immediately after this instead
of doing this in two steps going to do it all at once that I need to reshape this to 10 by 10 and if
I check my mat I have the Saray of all the numbers from zero stopped until a hundred or 99.
And then if I want to check the shape of this it's 10 by 10.
So let's imagine that I wanted to grab a single digit from this array.
What I do is I use indexing.
So let's say I want the value RHO index 0 where column is index 1.
So what value is that.
Well Roseborough is this first row.
Column 1 is the second column because if you start counting index 0 1 so that's going to hopefully return
back 1 and the notation for this or syntax for this is M-80 or whatever your matrix or array happens
to be called.
And then you pass in the row comma the column run that and we get back that value of 1.
I would encourage you now to pause the video and try to choose a number somewhere in the matrix and
then see if you can index out that number.
So for example see if you can grab just the number 46 for this matrix based on the logic we showed you
here.
OK.
So let's quickly show you how to do that.
So if I wanted 46 then that's 0 1 2 3 4.
So that's Rona before.
And it's at column 6.
So here we just actually wrote out row and column.
But you can pass the numbers there actually and there there's 46.
So that's also the reason we chose these particular values from 0 to 99 because you can really quite
clearly see the index locations.
Notice how the first number here is representative of the index of that actual row and the number here
is representative of the index of that column.
So 46 is actually quite easy for Comus 6.
Now let's imagine you wanted to grab all the items in a row or all the items in a column.
You did that with slicing.
So we say Matt and then we're going to say Colan and then pass some column value.
Let's go ahead and pasand column one so that returns back is every single value for every single row
in the column on.
So if I take a look at my metrics again notice here that my matrix has this column 1 11:21.
So that's the column I asked for and with the colon you ask for everything.
So in this I mentioned those were the rows.
So asked for the value of every single row just for that particular call.
So it's essentially just asking for that entire column back in here that the shape returned is 10 common
nothing.
If you actually wanted to get it in this shape then you would have to say Matt colon come a one and
then reshape to the particular shape you wanted.
So if you wanted it to be one row by 10 columns you could get something like this.
Or you could reverse it to have it this other way that looks more like the original.
Keep in mind the pinning on what you're running you may not actually see this output format of the same
way but hopefully you can get the idea here of the different shapes something can be returned then.
OK.
So that turns back an entire column if you want to back an entire row.
It's essentially the opposite.
You ask for every column particular row.
So let's get arow here which is row 2 and them will say colon give me everything there.
And now we get back everything in that row.
So notice when to ask for the array.
I'm basically saying OK go 0 1 2 and then give me every single column for this row which is just that
row itself 20 21 22 and so on.
Finally often you can actually grab just mere chunks of this.
So the way we do that is through slicing and then we use slice notation just like you do for a normal
Python list.
So let's imagine I wanted to grab this first three by three here.
What I could do is say starting at index 0 colon three for those rows and then for the columns do the
same thing zero colon three.
And what does is it says OK grab all the rows starting at 0 up to not including three.
So here all the rows 0 1 and 2 and then grab all those columns 0 and then one and then two.
So we can expand this to get a better idea.
So if I kept going with those particular columns it start giving me more of those rows give me the additional
column they're 0 1 2 and 3.
Essentially this is just normal Python slicing notation just the same way you would slice a normal Python
string or a normal Python list.
But now it's happening along to that mentions Don't worry too much.
This notation is a little confusing to you.
We actually don't really see it that often throughout the course.
Usually what we end up doing is we just take a quick slice of maybe everything and then reassign it.
So the last thing I want to show you is if you want to actually reassign these numbers to a different
value you could say it equals zero.
And then if we check out the Matrix again the original Matrix has now been affected.
And now that entire chunk is equal to zero if you want to actually effect a kind of copy of the matrix.
We could do is say my new mat or whatever we happen to call this variable.
And the same math and then call copy and that's of command we'll see throughout the course.
So sometimes you want to make a copy and then maybe set all the values to something else.
So if I wanted to reset all the values if I look at my new map right here is a copy of that matrix that's
already been affected.
Let's actually just turn everything on this top half zeros.
So how do I do that.
Well I want to grab everything from let's say 0 up to bet on including six.
So I want to grab all those rows and then I want to grab all the columns.
So I'm actually going to grab everything there and let's set those all to zero.
Let's set them all to ninety nine just so it's really obvious.
We'll do 999.
There we go.
And if I check out my new mat now we go ahead and set.
Kind of that first top half into 99.
OK.
Again really just doing normal Python slicing notation that you've seen before if you already experience
python lists and strings.
Just doing it along two dimensions.
And as I mentioned we really don't do that often throughout the course.
It's just a few times we want to reassign some image pixels.
OK.
So that's the basics of not pi.
Coming up next we're going to learn about pi.
Well we actually learned first what an image actually is in reference to a computer.
And then we'll learn how to directly work with non-pilot images.
Thanks and I'll see you there.