Welcome back everyone.
In the previous lecture we talked about streaming directly from a USP camera.
But sometimes you're dealing with video files that already exist.
Maybe you downloaded a video from YouTube and then you want to kind of play around with it so we can
do is you open C-v with existing video files.
Let's check it out by jumping over to a new notebook.
All right.
Here I am at a brand new notebook inside of a single cell.
I will say inport CB2.
And then I need the command to actually read in an existing video file.
Keep in mind we actually provided some MP for files for you.
So if you open up the folder and checkout data and begin scrolling down you should be able to see some
empty force here.
So I have a hand move finger move video capture etc. So there's different P4 files or if you're able
to follow along the previous lecture you should also have the video file you created earlier.
So I have my super video.
And before in our case open up my super video and before since it's a shorter video and the way we do
this is really similar to the way we captured a stream.
We just say CB2 video capture.
And last time we provided a zero which says grab the default webcam in this case we just provide the
file path to the video we want to actually show.
So in our case it's my super video that before or any video.
And often students sometimes actually provide file paths that don't exist.
And because open C.V is pretty flexible it just returns an empty object and something to do is say if
Cap is Open's is equal to false.
That means that we weren't actually able to open up this file.
So in that case you should print out error file not found.
So if you get error file not found that means that you weren't actually able to open this.
Sometimes it's also not able to open it.
If you use the wrong codec.
So again as you previously mentioned if you're writing your own file you have to use the correct codec
whether you're on Ubuntu Windows or Mac was computer open C-v sometimes is able to write something that
looks like a file but it's not able to open it.
So if you for sure know that the file is there but you're still getting the error when you're trying
to open it.
You may want to try rerecording it with a different codec so keep that in mind.
All right so we say if Cap is opened that's equal to false print error file not found and also mentioned
here for wrong codec.
So we have that going for us.
Now if that doesn't trigger an error then we're ready to actually display.
Will say while Cap is opened meaning while the video is actually playing We're going to grab the frames
just like we would with a normal capturer will say is equal to cap read and if it's actually returning
something meaning the video is still playing.
If AURITI is equal to true so it's still returning frames.
Well go ahead and show those frames.
Say CVT or C-v to see me in show frame and then display that frame and lets add in some code that we
can quit out of this well we are displaying the frames if we want to well say Wait key wait 10 milliseconds
and 0 x f f and depending on what you want to equal 27 for escape or if you want a particular letter
you can do the ordinal of Q and then we'll say break.
Now this is a pretty short video that we just recorded.
But if you're dealing for the long video you probably want to have the option to escape.
That way you don't have to watch the entire thing.
And then I'm also going to add an L statement here that says else break.
So what is this.
Else break for.
Notice that this else is lined up with this if statement the very first one.
And basically what this says is while the capture is actually working and it's open go ahead and keep
reading the capture while you're still returning something.
Show the frames and if you want you can break out of it if you're not returning anything.
Meaning you've already shown all the frames then break out of this while loop because we're no longer
open and we're no longer actually viewing any video.
You've already seen the whole thing.
So you want to make sure you have that break there outside of the While loop.
We're just going to release the capture and then for good measure will destroy all windows.
OK.
So let's check this out.
I'm going to play this and there's the video there.
Now as you probably notice the video was played extremely fast and that's because video capture when
pointed that rectally video.
It's not actually really meant to display the video for a human user.
It's really just meant to quickly read in every single frame and then do something to it.
And that makes sense because the computer can watch the video much faster than a human it can.
It just needs to look at every single image and that's good because if we want to eventually write or
manipulate videos we don't have to wait an hour for an hour long video.
Instead we can just do all our operations and not need to worry about showing it.
But if you do want to play back the video at a speed that is understandable to a human.
We need to do is add in two extra lines of code so here we're going to import the time module that's
built into Python.
And then every time we show the frame we want to show it at the same frame rate that it was recorded.
Now in our case I actually know what the frame rate was because remember we wrote this with writer at
20 frames per second.
So what we're going to do here is say time sleep and then sleep basically says have a delay of X amount
of seconds.
So we wanted to delay one over the frame rate per second which makes sense because that will then display
the frames at the exact same frames per second as we recorded it.
So in this case 20 is going to be whatever your frame rate is.
So you can play around this number the pending on what the frame rate for the video is.
And you can always capture the frame rate information using the same way we captured width and height
information from the previous video.
So again all I'm doing here is I'm importing time and then I'm delaying how fast I'm showing these frames.
This is only going to be useful if you yourself want to view the videos.
If you're trying to do an operation on a video and don't have any intention of watching it you don't
want to sleep otherwise.
Ill take just as much time to do the operations on the video as it does to watch the video which isn't
very efficient.
But in our case we actually want to playback the video at a rate that makes sense to us.
So I can run this and there we go.
Now I can see the video running at 20 frames per second so I'm delaying how fast it's showing the frames.
OK.
So again it can read in the frames much much faster than a human can see them.
If you want it to show the frames at a particular speed you just need to have a delay here using the
sleep.
OK.
If you have any questions on that feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But again it's just logic here.
We're displaying it with a delay of a certain frames per second.
So it's one second divided by the frames per second.
All right.
So that's how you can display video files using open C.v.
We'll see you at the next lecture.