Welcome back everyone.
In part one of this lecture we're going to begin by talking about how you can actually draw on images.
So to start off with a couple of shapes such as rectangles and circles and they'll move on to things
like drawing text onto an image.
Let's get started by opening up a new notebook.
Laurie here I am at a new notebook.
We're going to start off with what is going to quickly become the basic imports we do every time and
that's going to be important.
Two important umpires and pee and then Matt plotless that pipeline's Pulte and stating my live in line.
Next we're going to say is create a blank image and the blank image is going to be the zeros.
And we're going to give it a simple shape of 512 loops by 512 and they're going to give it three color
channels and we're also going to specify that the data type for the type is equal to N P dot integer
16 bit.
So I N T 16.
OK.
So let's go ahead and check that out.
We're going to say Blinkx image.
The shape is five fold but five top three that 512.
That's just an arbitrary choice here.
So it's kind of small enough to show.
So when I say PTM show let's go ahead and show our blank image.
And as we suspect because everything is colored 0.
So there's three channels of just five top five top zeros.
That's going to show up as just pure black.
Now let's show you how you can actually draw different shapes onto the image.
I'm going to start off by drawing a rectangle on this image.
So the way this works is you call CB2 dot and then you call rectangle and then you pass in the image
that you want to draw on.
So in this case I want to draw on that blank image and then what's going to happen is it's going to
except two points point one which is a tuple and then point two which is another tuple of coordinates.
So Point 1 that's going to be the vertex of the rectangle So the first vertex essentially the top left
corner and Point 2 is going to be the bottom right corner.
So let's see how this would work.
Let's say I want point 1 to B.
X is equal to 384 and Y is equal to zero.
So I wanted to be somewhere around here.
So in that case I'll say go execute the three four and then go to zero and then point to where I could
say is go all the way close to the edge so I'll say go all the way to 5 10 not 5 12 that way.
It's not on the actual border but a little off the border will say five 10 and we'll go ahead and make
this one go down a bit.
So it's going to go let's say around 150 and then we can assign a color and the color is just going
to be R.G. be code.
So in this case I'll just make it one solid primary color and then the thickness is another argument
you can do.
And this is just how many pixels thick do you want it to be.
So if you want make it really thick will say 10 pixels.
Notice here.
This isn't actually going to return anything.
It's actually going to act directly onto the image.
So this is kind of a permanent marker that you can draw on the image so keep that in mind.
So now it went ahead and spit out the array.
But as I said this happens in place.
So if I take another look at this blank image.
In fact if I just copy and paste peel t him show blank image I'm going to paste here and you can see
I have my rectangle.
You can also see that my thickness looks a little different on the left one and bottom one of the sides
versus the top and the right.
That's because that thickness essentially starts at the middle of the line and then works its way out.
So it tries to do five pixels to the left and right and then five pixels to the bottom and top.
But since we're pretty close to the edge on some of these it was able to actually fill out all those
pixels which is why it looks a little on even.
So what we can do is either shift these points to be a little further off the edge so we can shift this
over to maybe like 500 and shift this over to actually have to be off 0.
So maybe we say 10.
Run that again and actually want to reload or blink image.
So Arisa our blank image.
We're going to run this again.
And then let's see if this works a little nicer.
So we run that and I can see the edges are a little more equal here.
OK.
So that's how you can draw a rectangle.
Again point 1 that's is top left corner and then point to the bottom right corner.
So you just find these two corners or the vertices and then it's going to automatically draw a rectangle
for you because you really only need those two corners and it's going to assume there's going to be
a straight line on the horizontal and vertical axes.
OK.
So let's practice by drawing a square right in the middle.
How would that work.
Well all we need to say is CB2 dot rectangle.
And then I need to pass in the image I want to draw all say person A blank image to draw on.
And then I need to choose my top left point and then my bottom right point.
So if I want this to be kind of right in the middle I know I have five hundred and twelve as kind of
a middle point on both.
So let's make point number 1.
Let's have that go let's say 200 200 right with these guys meet.
So we'll say two hundred.
Two hundred and ten point two.
We want that to be probably slightly off.
So saying let's go 300 300 300 300 and then we get to choose a color.
Again this is just an RG Because it's really up to you what color you want to 5.
And then let's go ahead and give it a higher thickness.
So say something like thickness equal to 10.
Run that it returns back the array in case you wanted to save.
That has all the updates you notice most of it zero.
These thoughts basically signify that there's more to the array that it's showing.
And let's actually say peel show the blank image and now we should see a nice blue square here with
even sides.
OK.
So again all for all you need to do for that is to find two corners.
The top left corner the top right corner at the x and y points for that to find some sort of color using
red and blue.
And then the final thickness as well as what image you want to draw on.
Now we're going to do is show you circles.
So for circles it's a very similar process we say CB2 circle and then you pass in the image a blank
image.
And I'm actually going to label these parameters that way you can clearly understand what they represent.
So I am JE's the first parameter.
Well that's just the image you want to draw on.
Then the next parameter is the center parameter.
So that's the X and Y of where the center of the circle is going to go.
So let's imagine I wanted a circle over here kind of at the top left.
Well that can be x is equal to a hundred and Y's equal to 100.
So the center will say is 100 100.
Then if you have the center of a circle you can define the circle with a given radius.
So how far from that center do you want to expand.
So we'll go ahead and give it a radius of 50 pixels.
And then let's choose a color for it.
Let's give it another primary color we'll say it's red so red green blue 205 on red 0 0 on green and
blue.
And let's give it a little bit thickness.
That way we can actually see it.
We'll say it's an arbitrary choice there.
And then right after that we'll say realty show.
Now we're going to show the blank image OK.
So there we have it.
There's our circle again kind of pixels but that's because we're dealing for pretty low resolution image
size 5:12 by 512 pixels.
That's you can do a circle if you actually wanted to have a filled in circle or he filled in rectangle
in order to do that.
All you need to do is actually just have the thickness be a negative one.
So let me show what I mean by that.
I'm going to copy and paste this code come down here and let's draw another circle but this time will
draw center over on the bottom right.
We'll go ahead and say that its center is going to be 400 400 and I'm going to have it be filled in
now by passing in a negative number into the thickness we'll say negative 1 thickness.
And then when I run this there is a circle.
And now it's filled in with negative one and the same thing applies for rectangles.
If you want to filled in using say negative 1 instead of providing an actual thickness then I want to
show you how to draw lines and text and we'll finish this off in part two by showing you how to do polygons.
So we're going to show you how to draw a line now to do that.
It's CB2 dot and you may have guessed it line and you need to do is provide the image you want to draw
on and then the first point of the line in x and y coordinates and then point to the second point of
the line and x y coordinates as well as some sort of color and some sort of thickness.
Very similar to what we did for rectangles.
Let's go ahead and just draw a line that goes from the top left corner to the bottom right corner.
So that's going to be at 0 0 all the way down to Point two at the bottom right.
That should be 12 by 512.
And then the color will go ahead and say I just copied some red green blue codes that happened to show
teal and let's make the thickness equal to 5 or say peel t show and let's show the updated blank image.
We can go ahead and run that.
And now we see we have this line going from point 0 0 connected to in a straight fashion all the way
to point 512 512.
All right so now we know how to apply lines rectangles and circles.
And we also know how to fill in effect the color and effect the thickness of the actual circles and
rectangle lines.
Coming up next we're going to show you to finish this off and part two is how to write text onto a figure
and also how to create your own custom polygons.
So we're almost finished with this.
We'll just finished up those two topics in part to see if they're.