Welcome back everyone to part two of blurring and smoothing.
In part one we actually didn't really coat anything we just explain a little bit about blurring and
smoothing what gamma correction is and also what a kernel is.
Now it's time to actually use these functions of open see the let's get started opening up the Jupiter
notebook.
All right.
We're going to start off with a couple of imports.
I want to import CB2 and then just in case I need them later on important unpleasant.
And we'll be displaying images as well.
So we'll say import map plot lib pipe plot as T and map plot lib in line OK.
Now the image we're going to be using is an image of bricks.
And the reason we chose this image for blurring it's moving is because usually you can see each outline
of each brick really clearly.
So what we're going to be doing is blurring this image and then later on we'll actually also add some
text to the image to see different effects.
However what I want to do is do a couple of convenience functions.
And in fact I'm actually just going to copy these functions directly from The Notebook.
So go ahead feel free to do the same this first camions function that's in the notebook for this lecture.
It just loads the image because we're going to be blurring the image and the blurring happens in place.
I want to have a quick function that allows me to just quickly reload this image over and over again.
However you may need to actually edit the string here so I'm going to edit it because my data folder
is in the same directory as its notebook so I'm going to get rid of that.
Thot thot thot.
Forward slash.
OK.
So there's my load image function.
Let's check that it works.
We're going to say load image and there it's load in the array of the image.
OK.
So that's working that I'm going to copy and paste the display image function.
So Copy that.
And again I just copied this from the notes and we've already seen this function a couple of times.
It just displays the image a little larger.
And now with these two functions I should be able to do the following I is equal to load image and then
display image on I.
And if you run that you should see the bricks right here.
Again it's just a white wall of bricks with some blue painted on top of it.
And we're going to be performing different sort of blurring and smoothing effects.
The very first effect actually to be performed though is gamma correction recall from the previous lecture
that gamma correction allows you to increase or decrease what is perceived as brightness in the actual
image.
And it's pretty straightforward.
All we need to do is load up the image which she already did and then choose a gamma value if you choose
a game a value of less than one then we are going to end up doing is making the image appear brighter.
So I'll choose one over four as our gamma.
It's less than one.
And if you want to affect the image and all you need to do is say N.P. power and then pass in the image
and then pass in the Gamma.
So all this is going to do is take every pixel value in the image and raise it to the power of gamma
which in this case is 1 over 4.
And let's have this be the result and then we're going to display image of result.
So look so we have that image not defined.
It's actually just I there we go run that and now we can see because we chose a gamma of less than 1
The image appears to be brighter.
And I just start going with smaller and smaller values of gamma like 110.
And you read this again you're eventually just going to fade out into white.
So keep that in mind if you start using game values that are above 1.
He'll end up making the image appear darker.
So if I choose a game of two and rerun these then knows what happens.
Now the image appears darker.
Here's my original image and I look at the blue here it's much darker and you can choose really high
values gamma like 8 and you'll see that it almost hurts looking black.
OK so that's gamma correction.
Again the practical effect is just increasing or decreasing brightness of the image.
And all you really need to do for that is just a little bit of simple math.
Take the pixel array values and then raise them by the power of gamma which is conveniently done with
that power says that for all the layers across the image that we're going to move on to our first blurring
and the blurring we're going to do is what's known as a low pass filter with a 2D convolution and to
start off the first thing I want to do is actually want to write some text onto this image.
And the reason for that is sometimes it's a little hard to see the difference between a couple of the
blurring and smoothing techniques.
And if you write a little bit of text on the image that differentiation becomes a little more clear.
So let's start off by just loading our image afresh.
We will say I am g is equal to load image or load I am g and what I'm going to do is say font is equal
to CB2 font and I'm going to choose Hershey complex I just tab autocomplete there and then CB2 we're
going to put some text onto that image.
So say image the text we're going to write is bricks and the actual position we're going to put it in
is a 10 600 the font face for choosing is the font that we just to find the font scale going to be a
little larger around 10 and the color just to make it obvious against the blue note to make it red.
So 2 5 5 0 0 and then the thickness is going to be four OK.
So let's let's actually display that image
and don't worry if you get this sort of value here.
Basically what that means is you have some values that fall outside of the range are to 1 or two hundred
fifty five.
So it's just clipping them down again if you get this warning.
Not a big deal.
You don't need to worry about it.
OK.
So here we have now the image of the bricks and now it says bricks on top of it.
We're going to be constantly reloading this image so you're going to see me come back and copy and paste
this code a bunch of times so keep this code handy.
It's going to be used over and over again in this lecture.
But the reason I added this text is I can see due to this particular font that there is some lines in
between some of the markings of the letters.
For example in this I there's some space in between those two lines or this are just a space between
those lines.
Same as in that C and that curve and that be when we actually perform blurring and smoothing those spaces
are going to be blurred out or move to different degrees depending on what kind of smoothing techniques
we apply.
So that's the first thing you can do.
And the next we're going to do is set up our kernel for that low pass filter and the kernel for this
is a really simple one the kernel we're going to decide on is N.P. once the shape we're going to give
it is 5 by 5.
Remember from the previous lecture we see a kernel of three by three.
So this is just a little bit of a larger kernel.
And that data type are going to choose to make sure everything is compatible they say the float
32 bit and then I'm going to take the whole thing and divide it by 25 so that everything is at 1 over
25.
So if I took out my kernel those it's a bunch of 0.04 and if you did one over 25 loops one over 15 one
over 25 that's equal to 0.04.
So here we have a bunch of ones and all those ones I divide by 25.
So now I have a bunch of 0.04.
And that is my kernel then what I'm going to do is just apply a to the filter on it.
The syntax for that to the filter is simply going to be CB2 filter and then to capital-T and the output
of this is going to be any variable you wants.
Often people just say DST as destination.
So we have that destination output that DST variable.
And that's going to spit out after you apply the kernel to the entire image.
So we have seen to filter to D and then we're going to do is pass in the image so we want to actually
apply the filter too.
And the second parameter is known as desired depth and we do as you just passen negative one.
That way the output that that you desire.
Negative One means I want the input that to actually assign the desired output.
And if you're a little curious what does that actually means you can check out the links in the resource
for this lecture.
There are some good stack overflow links as well as links to documentation that describe the site depth
and a little more detail on image filtering as well as Image type versus image.
Really for our use case we don't really need to worry about that we're always going to be using native
one which defines that we want the output to be the same as the input.
And again there's more explanations here.
OK so we're going to come back out here.
And once you chosen negative one so that the input that is the same as the output that what we want
to do is pass the kernel.
Remember we already defined the kernel up here so we have this variable we're going to apply the entire
kernel to it.
And then once we do that let's display the resulting image will say display AMG and then DST we run
that again you don't need to worry about this particular warning is just telling you that it clipped
some values that were either above 1 or above 255 and you'll notice that things do appear to be blurred
now if we take a look at the original image.
Notice here that we can see the bricks very clearly and we can see the blue in between these lines in
the text and that's where we have the text there because it makes the blurriness smoothing really obvious.
And if you come back down here you'll notice that there appears to be almost like a pink in between
where there used to be that spacing in the letters and it doesn't happen to every single letter but
it happens to the majority of them.
And I would encourage you to play around the kernel size make it smaller make larger She has different
values and see how that affects the actual image.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and reset everything.
We're going to do is come back up here.
And then copy this command.
So this is a command we're going to be coming all day.
So you can feel free to functionally is it going to copy come back down here and reset my image and
then I'm going to print something like reset.
So we don't see that trinary OK.
So we've reset the image.
We have that loaded image and now we have that fresh text on it.
We're going to also show you now is how you can smooth based off averaging.
And you may have expected.
There's actually a default blur colonel that we showed you in the previous lecture.
You can actually just apply that kernel by saying CB2 Doppler.
And then you pass in the image and then you pass in whatever kernel size you want for the default blurring
kernel So previously we manually the find the kernel and then use that filter to the to apply the kernel
to the image.
Now we're just going to use CB2 built in blurt kernel.
Same concept here except now they've chosen specific values for the Blar then they're going to say blurred
is equal to that.
The result of blurring the image and Elyssa splay those results so the split image blurred.
We run that and then we can see again here that the image has clearly been blurred the lines are not
so distinct.
And then we can see a little bit of that pink coming along in the bricks.
And here I would again encourage you to kind of play around with the kernel size so we can even make
something like 10 by 10 and see how that affects the actual results.
So you can run that and you can see the colonel got really large then the blurring became more intense.
OK.
So there's other things like Gaussian blurring and median blurring which just take a group of pixels
and then go along and calculate the averages and then make those the outputs.
So as you may suspect that we're just going to copy and paste this line of code or we're going to reload
the image fresh.
So now I have my fresh image and you can always check on this by just displaying it.
So Fidei if I say the split image I see that nice crisp outline with the bricks.
So I'm going to comment that out and then let's apply a Gaussian and median blurring which is you just
averaging techniques very similar to what actually the CB2 that blurred those.
But in this case only to say CB2 dot gaussian blur.
And what this does as far as arguments it takes in it takes in the source image the kernel size.
And then what you choose as your Sigma value and for your Sigma value if you come down here the sigma
is going to be the standard deviation.
And usually people just tend to assign Sigma X and then Sigma Y is then set automatically to Sigma X..
OK so we're going to do here is pass in the image passenger kernel size again things can play around
with and then just by playing around I'd to choose a single value 10.
So we're going to say blurred image and let's display that blurred image and also something I want you
to keep in mind is there is no right or wrong way to the spoiler images.
There's no right or wrong kernel size.
A lot of it is often just guess and check.
See what works well specifically see what works well with the pipeline of application you're trying
to discover.
So if you're trying to edge detection you probably try a bunch of them from Blur's and then see which
one works the best with your particular edge detection technique.
But let me go ahead and run this.
And here we go again.
We can see the blur happening.
So you can see a little pink here.
The lines are not so clear.
And we're going to show you a very similar blurring technique.
So we went with gaussian blur.
We showed you blur.
We showed her own custom kernel blur.
And another one that you can do is median blur for the median blur.
All you need to do is say CB2 median blur.
And then the parameter is just going to pass in the image and then case size.
So the kernel size this has to be a square kernel.
So it ends up just taking one argument so we can just say 5 which basically translates to five by five.
And what we do here is just say median results are really whatever you want to call that variable.
Analysts display their results so say the split image and say median results run that and there we have
that sort of blurring.
So this one is really interesting because you'll notice that the foreground here of this text it doesn't
actually appear to be blurred in the middle of these lines as before.
So if we come back up here we definitely see that pink hue coming into play as well as the background
being Blar with this sort of medium blurry.
It actually tends to be really good at removing noise from an image while trying to keep certain details
in check.
So you notice that we've removed what essentially is some sort of noise from the brick so it doesn't
look as detail but we're able to keep in the detail of the actual text of bricks.
So that's what makes median blurring a really interesting technique for reducing image noise.
And if you've ever played around with Photoshop and you've seen some filters for removing noise from
an image usually what they're doing is they're actually just applying a median blur.
So let's go ahead and see this in action in a more realistic example.
Right now we've been playing with his Brick's image which is a really realistic use case instead.
I want to show you an image that already has noise and how we could remove noise from it.
We're going to see image or AMG is equal to CV to him read.
And I'm going to read it from the data folder.
There is a picture called Sammy.
But Jay peg.
And then we need to actually correct the color for this image.
We will say CB2 CBT color pass in the image and as usual say CB2 color blue green red to red green blue
so run those commands and then display this image and you should see a picture of my dog Sammy.
OK.
So this is a picture of Sammy.
This is what a normal picture of him looks like.
And I ended up doing was I decided to make a noisy version of this image.
So I went ahead and with a little bit of code I made a noise image and I want to load it for you know
we're going to say noise image is equal to CB2 image read.
And in that same data folder there is a picture called Samie noise.
And this one actually already color corrected for you.
So if you run this and display the image here you say display image the noise image you'll notice it's
actually the same image but it's way noisier.
So we added a bunch of noise to this.
You can see here the way that this is I just randomly chose values and or Ramli chose pixels and made
them ran the values.
So this way there's kind of this weird noise that's happening here.
So here's the original image and then here's the noisy version of the image.
Now let's see if we can use median blur to try to fix this sort of noise try to remove it.
So what I will do is say median is equal to CB2.
I'm going to call the median blur function.
I'm going to pass on the noise image and the passive 5 by 5 kernel for the medium Blar and five actually
ends up being a really common value.
So I would recommend starting with five and then working are way higher if you need more Blar then let's
display the result that will display median.
So running this we get to see that it looks like the noise has been reduced.
Now it does come at the cost of some detail.
If we compare this to the original image we can see kind of the finer details of the grass is actually
a really large image that's more than twelve hundred by a thousand more or less.
So we do have quite a bit of detail here.
This is the noisy image and if we did a blurring on that we got rid of a lot of the noise.
What ends up happening is it blurs in with the pixels that surround it and it comes at the cost of a
little bit of detail so you can see that fine detail of the grass or maybe the trees in the background.
But essentially from a human perspective it looks a lot better than what we had before in this noisy
image because here we have a bunch of random pixel colors.
Now we're able to reduce that noise.
OK.
So that's it for the medium blur.
The last thing I want to show you is a bilateral filtering.
It's just another way to blur an image.
So just for the sake of completeness I want to show it.
Let me reload in this image right here.
So I got a copy and paste this load image with the BRICS scroll all the way down.
Run that.
So we have our bricks reset.
Let's make sure of that.
We'll say the image and there are bricks and then if you want to perform a bilateral filter we actually
will see this later on the course.
But I do want to show it just in case you're interested in it.
All you to do is say whatever the output is go FCB to bilateral philtre.
And then the parameters here are source and the D Sigma color and sigma space and you can actually check
out this link explains how bilateral filtering works.
Essentially what it attempts to do is reduce unwanted noise and keep edges fairly sharp.
However it's usually slower compared to other filters.
So we're going to use some default values here.
Say image 9 and then 75 and 75 for those lvalues and let's display that image will display the or in
notice.
Now it looks blurred and it's actually been able to keep a little more detail around the lines in between
the letters of the bricks.
So it's kind of similar to median blur as far as being able to reduce noise in an image and still keep
edges really well.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture against a bunch of different blurring techniques.
Usually we're going to go to the simpler ones like a medium blur or just the built in blur.
The main idea here is that we can reduce noise and images that are noisy or we can reduce the amount
of detail we need when we're performing other tasks like edge detection as long as you feel comfortable
with the idea of applying a kernel to an image with filter to the.
And we're just applying any sort of general blur.
Then you're pretty much good to go.
All right.
Thanks everyone.
We'll see you at the next lecture.