Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss contour detection contours are defined as simply
a curve joining all the continuous points along the boundary having the same color or same intensity
contours are a very useful tool for shape analysis and object detection and recognition.
OPEC has a built in counter finder function that can also help us differentiate between internal and
external contours.
It has a lot of functionality packed into just a simple function call.
Let's go ahead and take a look.
All right here we are at the Jupiter notebook.
I'm going to read in from my data folder an image called internal underscore external.
So if you start typing I end you should see internal underscore external that PMG.
And as the second argument is going to pass and is 0 to read it in as a grayscale.
And if we check the shape of the image notice it's just x and y.
There is no color channels.
So let's see what this image actually looks like.
And I'm going to map this in grayscale and it's a pretty simple image.
The main thing I notice here is that we have and triangle and the foreground space is white and the
background is black.
Then what's interesting is you have a smiley face with two black circles for eyes and a black circle
here for the mouth.
And then we have kind of like a pizza pie shape here with a bunch of pepperoni on it.
And what we're going to do is we're going to be able to find and extract contours.
What's really cool and interesting about the fine contours function of open C.V is that it can actually
detect internal contours such as these pepperoni slices or the eyes or the smiley face versus external
contours such as the circle the triangle or this circle of a wedge cut out of it.
And what we're going to do is we're going to find the contours function and then we do this is we simply
say CB2 dots find contours and you can have autocomplete that you passen the image that you want to
analyze.
And there's a couple of different metrics or ways to actually find contours.
So there's a built in functions and if you say CB2 thought are ETR underscore and then hit TAB there'll
be some different ways here to actually find the contours.
So what we're going to be using is c c o MP.
So complete.
And what this does is it's going to extract both internal and external contours organized in a two level
hierarchy.
They can then index and call off of.
If you're only interested in internal contours or external contours there's other methods here.
For example you can use external to only grab external contours.
Right now we're just these this complete one that grabs all the contours for us and the third parameter
here.
If you do shift tab that's going to be the actual method.
We're just going to be using chaine underscore approx.
Underscore simple as our method.
OK.
And this is actually going to return back a few objects.
It returns back an image the contours themselves and then the hierarchy that organizes them the hierarchy
depends on actually what type you call.
But in this case it's we're calling for both internal and external contours We're also going to return
to a hierarchy here.
So let's run that.
Let's check out what these actual objects are.
If we look at the type of contours it's a list and then the length of contours is 22.
And if you were to count out these actual contours such as the number of pepperoni slices the circles
the eyes and the smiley face you would get 22 contours.
And if we check up the type of hierarchy so check out that hierarchy is a pie array and if we actually
show you what it looks like it's essentially a bunch of lines that find where the contours are.
And then a parameter that actually defines whether they're internal or external.
So let me show you how you can actually then use contours here and hierarchy here to show external contours
versus internal contours.
It's a bit strange because it kind of have to know the way it's organized.
So we provided some code for you in the note book that that way you can just have that skeleton code
to reference.
So I will set up an empty array and I'm going to call this empty courageous external contours and this
is going to be just zeros in the same shape as the image.
And it can be image or I m g doesn't really matter.
So same thing.
So if I check out external contours shape there it is 6 5 2 1 0 8.
And if we check out the original shape 6 5 to 180.
OK so the image returned back.
That's basically the same thing.
In fact we can actually show it image here.
It's essentially the same thing.
OK.
So now that we have this and zeros this is going to be external contours just a pure black in the same
shape as the original image.
Now what I want to do is actually draw the contours on and there's a draw contrast function with an
open CD.
The only thing is I have to know how to actually read and understand this list of contours using the
hierarchy.
So we are going to do.
And typically you don't really memorize this you just reference it from either documentation or notes
like the ones we provide for you.
We're going to say for I in range of length of contours.
So remember I in range of length of contours if we actually check what this is by passing this in to
a list that's just a list number so for 0 1 2 3 4 5 all the way to 21 the length contours because since
we have 22 are we're also counting 0.
That works out.
So we have four in range of length of contours
hierarchy and then we're going to do a little bit of indexing here.
We're going to say zero.
I 3 and then equals equals negative 1.
Essentially what that is doing is its indexing for each of these rows.
This last column right here.
This negative 1 or 0.
So Or it can also be 4 depending on what type of contour it is.
Again we're just checking out the last column here.
That's what this indexing is doing.
And with the eye it's doing it for every single row.
So we're checking if the hierarchy value at that 2 column is equal to negative 1 then that means as
an external contour.
So it's external If it's not equal to negative 1 than it's internal.
So we have negative one there.
It's an external contour.
And then what we're going to do is say to draw contours and we're going to draw external contours
contours and then I to find find for white and then negative once it's actually filled in.
So let's run that.
So what this did is it went through that contours list and that checked hey if the hierarchy for that
corresponding contour and if we actually check out the list of contours we can show you these are essentially
just arrays that define how to actually draw the contours.
So it's saying okay for that contours check of the hierarchy is good if it is then onto this black external
contours member that's the zeroes here.
Go ahead and draw that specific contour and then we'll be able to view it.
So let's actually view the external contours.
We'll say PBT and show external contours and let's make the map great.
And here with the fine contours and the hierarchy where it's equal to negative one it actually detected
the external contours.
So these are things that are actually directly touching what it believes to be the background.
So this triangle the circle and the circle with the slice taken out of it.
Those are all external contours because their boundary is touching the actual background.
Now the internal contours were things like it come back to the original image.
These guys right here the pepperoni slices and the eyes and the smiley face the edges of those contours.
They're actually not touching the background they're touching a foreground object.
So those are known as internal contours and all we can do is essentially run this exact code.
But then instead of words equal to negative one we're saying not equal to negative one so I'm also going
to redefine this external contours but we're going to make it internal.
So let's grab that pace right here.
And we will say internal contours.
So basically following the same process and creating a default black object that I can draw on just
an array and then for all the contours what I'm doing is for internal.
What I will say is that third column is not equal to negative one that it's an internal contour.
And I'm going to draw onto my internal contour and let me make sure I have the right internal contours
contours twenty five.
So let's go ahead and run that and then let's show the internal contours internal contours.
See map is equal to grey.
Run that and then it went ahead and displayed the internal contours and there you have it.
So that's how you can actually then use find contours and draw contours to display contours.
The last thing I want to actually note here is the way that works with the hierarchy.
It can actually then define this set of contours as different than the smiley face.
And if you come back up here you'll notice that in the last third column we have negative ones.
Those are the external contours.
We have these three zeros.
Those are the eyes and smiley face of the world the smiley face of the actual smile.
And then we have four.
Those are all the pepperoni slices.
So you'll notice they're actually numbers them differently depending on a grouping of internal contours
So if they're within different external contours it will group them differently.
So what I would encourage you to do is we can then test on this by saying only give me where it equals
four and let's rerun this again.
So we're going to say now let's redefine going to rerun the cell external contours check the shape again.
That's looking good.
And I'm only going to do it where it equals four and then let's see how that works.
So those are all the pepperoni slices.
Now let's try again but this time I'm going to choose just where two equals zero.
So we will say zero there.
Let's rerun this so we get the fresh background run these again.
And now I only get the smiley faces.
So it's really cool is not only does it give you organization between internal and external contours
it also gives you organization within the internal contours themselves depending on what external countered
they were found inside.
So that way may be fuel for some reason only wanted to display the internal contours of a particular
object such as a smiley face.
You can go ahead and do that.
OK.
So that's it for this lecture.
And we'll see you at the next one.