Welcome back here we are where we left off last time.
Last time we tried this or B match detector and it didn't do a very good job in fact that kind of got
confused.
Given how similar the other cereal boxes were to the reeses puffs cereal.
So now we're going to do is use soft descriptors as I f t and sift stands for scale invariant feature
transform and it does really well when you're dealing with image sizes or are at a different scale.
So I notice this Reese's puffs cereal box.
It's actually much larger than the cereal boxes that are found in this target image.
So that could also lead to some confusion when trying to match up features.
So this sift the Scripter can account for that.
And the way this works is we first start off by creating a safe object will say Ayas SCAF t is equal
to CB2.
And then we call X features to d dot sift underscore create and then once we've done that just like
we did before we're going to find the key points and descriptors with sift.
So we will say K.P. one and D.S. one.
So the key points and descriptors as I have t and we will detect and compute recess and then none.
And I'm going to copy and paste this because it's the exact same for the other one except it's going
to be cereals.
All right.
So nothing different so far we've done the same thing as we did last time we created this object.
And then we're going to the text and compute where their actual description matches.
Next up we're actually going to calculate those matches.
So now that we have the Scripters for each of them we want to compare them.
So we're going to do this by brute force we'll say CB2 B-F matcher and then we're going to calculate
our matches and a slightly different manner.
We're going to do the following.
We'll say from that brute force matcher call k and n match.
And what this does is it takes two sets of the Scriptures and then a value k.
And if you check out the documentation what it does is it finds the K number of best matches for each
descriptor from a query set.
So right.
Right now we have D.S. 1 and 2.
And if we take a look at these and then let's show one of them looks like these are essentially just
descriptors of where it found features.
So what we're going to do is given these two sets of descriptors I'm going to use cane and match to
find the top two matches.
So again we're finding the best matches for each descriptor from a query set.
So we're going to have two matches for each of these descriptors so let's run this and then take a look
at what matches actually looks like so matches.
Notice there are pairs.
There's the first match and then the second match.
So this first match is a better match than the second match.
And if we asked for K's equal to three then we would have the third best match that we could keep going.
So right now this first column all these values.
That's the first best match.
And then the second column is the second best match.
And what we're going to do now is apply a ratio test in general.
Just intuitively you could think that if this first match is pretty close in distance to the second
match then overall it's probably a good feature to match on.
That being said if you have a strong match in the first column and then the second best match is actually
pretty far away in distance.
Then overall this entire descriptor is probably not a very good feature to match on.
And we're going to apply what's known as a ratio test to actually check for this to check if these two
matches are relatively close to each other in distance.
And then we can think of this entire script there is probably a good match.
And the way we do that is the following.
I'm going to keep matches there so we can reference it.
I will create an empty list called good.
And this is going to hold my good matches and I will say for match one comma match two in my list of
matches.
Remember I have pairs of matches there.
I'll say the following.
If match 1 distance is less than 75 percent of my match to distance then it actually probably have a
good match.
So I will say good append.
And as a list notice here the brackets are going to append that match 1.
So what this is saying is if match 1 distance is less than 75 percent of match to distance than the
Scripter for that particular row was a good match.
Let's keep it and keep in mind I'm just keeping one match and keeping the first best match.
But I am comparing it to the second best match for that descriptor.
If these are off by a lot.
So if this is greater than 75 percent then it's probably not a good match.
And I'm just going to toss it away.
So this is called a ratio test because we're essentially taking the ratio of match 1 to be less than
75 percent of matched 2.
And in general keep in mind that less distance means a better match because we're using some sort of
distance metric to evaluate these matches and the greater the distance the poorer the match the less
distance that means the better the match.
So we'll go ahead and run this.
And now if I check out my list of good then I have a list of all the good matches.
So let's take a look at the lengths of good.
It's seven the.
And let's take a look at the length of matches that one was one thousand five hundred one.
So we can see that we actually had a lot of poor matches that we ended up tossing away.
And now we're left with the very best matches about 78.
OK so now it's time to actually draw these matches and see how they performed.
So we will say sift matches and just like we did last time we'll say to draw matches except this time
we'll say draw matches cannon because that's what we used here in calculating these matches.
Draw matches cannon and then same parameters as before will pass increases.
The key points for that one will pass and serials.
The key points for serials and then pass in my list of good matches that are already filtered and we'll
say none for mask and then say flacs is equal to 2.
So we get the same drawing style as last time.
Run that and let's display that image.
We'll say this play with matches run that and you'll see that it performed much much better than our
previous feature matching it was now successfully able to find where Reese's puffs was in the actual
cereal aisle.
Notice how many features we matched here.
What's also really interesting is you notice that the family size features here are also well-matched
to the family size showing that Cheerios picture.
So if we take a look at the original picture appear.
So this is the cereal aisle.
Notice that family size is actually quite visible here in Honey Nut Cheerios.
However it's missing in this recent puff cereal.
And our target image here had a family size in it.
So that means it actually found the match in that Honey Nut Cheerios.
So keep in mind if you have many similar images it could still be an error in the actual matching.
But as we can see most of the matches are actually really well detected onto that Reese's puffs cereal.
OK.
So that's sift descriptors with an additional ratio test.
Now we're going to do is a Flann based matcher for the plant based matter.
We're first going to show you how to grab the matches and then we're going to introduce a more complex
parameter drawing mechanism essentially just a dictionary that allows you to draw only the clear matches
but yet show all the points where it did find the feature to possibly match on.
It's going to be a very similar process to what we just did.
And in fact the results are also going to be quite similar.
So let's start off.
We're going to end up saying swift is equal to CB2 X features to the and we'll say sift underscore create
just as we did before.
Then again using self-organised say is essentially the same as we did last time.
In fact I can copy and paste the commands.
It's just this key points in the Scriptures one and two and then we're going to copy and paste those
in.
And now what's different is when you define the Flann parameters so F L A N N Flann means fast library
for approximate nearest neighbors and it's actually going to be much faster than the brute force methods.
But it's not going to find the best possible matches.
Instead it's just going to find general good matches.
Now you can play with Flans parameters that we're about to show you in order to try to increase the
precision or the quality of the matches.
But that comes at the cost of slowing down the algorithm.
So just in other words Flann is much faster than brute force matcher but it only finds approximate nearest
neighbors which is good matching but not necessarily the best.
OK.
So let's go ahead and show you the parameters and we're going to be using the default parameters.
So the way we can construct this is we say Flann and we'll say Flann underscore index underscore k d
tree.
So that equal to zero.
It's also going to take in some index parameters we'll say Index parameters is equal to.
And we're going to create a dictionary just by passing this into the DCT dictionary algorithm will be
set to that Flann index tree Katy tree and then say trees is equal to 5.
So I would encourage you to use these default parameters and then you can kind of play around with them
see if adding more trees helps.
But again the more you mess with the parameters the more you slow down the algorithms is really just
meant for fast detection especially if you have a really large image or a large number of images that
will say search parameters is equal to dictionary.
And we'll set checks equal to 50.
It's up to you how you like to find dictionaries.
You could also have just done this with something like this where you say checks 50.
So again we're just use a dictionary here because it's a little more readable.
OK so we have our parameters.
And then what you'll do is say Flann is equal to to flammed based matter and we'll pasan those index
parameters as well as the search parameters.
Run that and now we can actually grab the nearest neighbor matches using this flat object will say matches
is equal to Flann and match and then passen the Scripters the S1 the two and will sit with the two and
we're going to do a very similar ratio test as we did before.
We'll say good as an empty list and we'll say for I actually for match one match two in matches if match
one distance is less then let's say 70 percent of match to distance what's it could play around of 75
percent as well if you want it to then roll.
Take the good list and we'll append match one to it.
OK so we'll run that.
Now we have good matches.
Now it's time to draw them Gool say Flann underscore matches is equal to CB2 draw matches.
Kanon Kinnear's neighbors just like before passen recess and key points one pasand cereals and key point
to then say good.
There's no umask here and say flags and you can set flags to zero or two we'll show you the changes
between those two right now.
We'll say this play Flann matches and if you're on a Flags equal to zero what it's going to do is going
to show you all the features it's matched on except only draw lines on the best ones here.
OK.
Or at least the ones that thinks that are good.
If you only want to see those lines you get set flags too.
As we have been doing.
And then you just get those lines themselves.
OK.
So we get really similar results here as we did with the swift and for a really large image this Flann
matching would have been where actually this line right here this flag based matcher would have been
a bit faster when you were searching for the matches than the brute force method.
OK so now let's show you a couple of extra parameters you can do for actually drawing a mask.
So often what people like to do is they like to draw these lines in a specific color and then show all
those dots from Flag 0 as a different color.
So you'll see these lines as green and then all those dots as red.
So we can see where we have potential features to match on but only see the connections that we're concerned
with.
And that way we can do that is by simply adding the following.
We create a mask.
So I'm going to actually rerun the cells.
So we'll run this one again.
Create the new set object create the script there's rerunning those flammed parameters rerunning Flann
here rerunning matches.
But then after that I'm going to enter to insert a new cell and this one will be called matches mask.
And it's going to create a mask and it's going to be a little bit of complex little comprehension.
All we're going to say is 00 for I in range think of the number of matches and we'll be using this match
as a mask and editing it as we go along.
OK.
So there is our matches mask and if we take a look at it it's just a bunch of zeros right now in the
length of matches and we're going to do is turn some of these on by changing them to one depending if
we have a good match or not.
So let me comment that out over here.
Back in this ratio test what we'll say is I and then we'll select this as just a single tuple so right
those princes around it.
And then we will enumerate matches here that where we can actually keep track of the index marker.
And then it will say is for I am much one match to enumerate matches.
We'll keep doing this right here.
But then we will also say the following.
And actually we no longer need good here because the matches mask will do that for us so we can get
rid of good.
And instead what we're building out is a mask.
So we'll say matches mask index eye.
So for that particular pair of 0 0 change it to 1 0.
And essentially what that is going to do is it's going to label these lines as one where we actually
have a good match.
So all we're doing is we have this giant list of zeroes and instead of appending things to a good list.
Now we're just keeping track with indices of this mask of where we had a good match.
So it really similar process.
Go ahead and run that and now we're going to be using this mask to create a drawing parameter dictionary.
We will say drop harams is equal to dictionary and it will specify that the color of a match is green.
So this is the color of the line and then the single points that we saw basically all these single point
we're going to color them something else will say a single point color.
You have to make sure your spelling is correct on this.
Well make those red and then the next thing we're going to do is say pass the matches mask and this
actually then defines where we had a match and where we just have a single point because remember now
it's essentially a list of ones and zeros where we happen to have a good match do that ratio test and
now set flaks equal to zero because zero flags actually shows all these little points.
And then we come back down here to draw this after I run this dictionary I'm going to get rid of good
and instead pass in all my matches.
So now all my matches remember if we take a look at that parameter all matches.
Those are both sets of matches of K-8 equal to two.
What I am going to do is instead of appending them to a list of good I will be using this match mask
along the dry parameters to filter them out based off color.
So we'll still say none here.
And instead for flags we'll say to Asterix and say draw harams a should see something that results like
this.
And all this is doing is it's taking these drawing parameters to color where you actually have good
matches versus where you have all these other points from Flag is equal to zero.
And again if you want to you could just change Flack's equal to 2 to just see these lines by themselves.
But often people want to color these just so they can see the relationship between the actual points
and all this is doing again is we're creating this mask object here.
And from that we're creating these drawing parameters where we say color matches green and then color
single points red.
And if you want you can then play around these values.
You can turn this maybe to zero and make this blue.
And if we were to run this again now you see the lines are blue.
OK.
So this is the match color.
And this is the single point color and you need to pass in the mask and we say flacs 0 that we we actually
see the points.
I believe if you were to change this back to 2 then you would only see the lines and there it is.
So not much point in doing this whole dictionary if you're only going to say flags equal to 2.
Besides just setting up the color.
All right.
That's it for this feature matching lecture.
You can definitely check out the resources if you're interested more in the details about the actual
algorithms behind this open C-v calls in general will just be making the syntax calls necessary to match
features.
And we're going to be building off of this when it becomes time to talk about ODUOR detection and object
tracking in general.
All right we'll see you at the next lecture where we discuss the watershed algorithm for image segmentation.