Welcome back.
Let's complete this section with a quick assessment of your new skills.
Let's open up the notebook.
The note book is called zero for Dash image basics dash assessment and the next lecture will go over
the corresponding solutions notebook.
Let's get started with a quick review of the assessment.
OK when you open your notebook it should look something like this and basically just says always you're
going to have a bunch of tasks in bold that you need to complete.
So the first task is to open the dog underscore backpack that shape pick image that is located in the
data folder that goes along this course and display in the notebook.
And I've shown a little hint here that I want you to make sure you correct the R.G. order.
So if you open up the dog backpack a peg and try to display it right off the bat.
Remember that the coloring of red and blue may be switched.
Sure can one make sure that you read it in the correct order and use open C-v to correct for that number
we show you the function for that that I want you to flip the image upside down and display it in the
notebook that I want you to draw an empty red triangle around the dog's face.
So here's what the dog looks like.
And then scroll down I draw a red rectangle around the dog's face.
So here's the dog with the rectangle.
And then here is now the rectangle.
It doesn't have to be perfectly centered around Doc's face but you can kind of guesstimate given the
x vector axis and the Y dimensions here where the actual corners should go.
So again this task just draw an empty red rectangle around the dog's face and display the image in that
notebook.
Then the next task is to draw a blue triangle in the middle of the image.
So kind of centered around the dog's face just as it were roughly in the middle of the image.
It can be lower it can be higher.
So don't worry too much about these exact points.
I just want you to be able to kind of guesstimate somewhere on the image and then draw the triangle
there.
So remember the size and angle of the triangle is up to you.
Here I made it in equal lateral triangle so all three sides of the same.
That's what was easiest that way these bottom points actually have the same height.
So along the y axis These are both around looks like 700.
So that's a little hint to kind of help you out there.
Again just drawing a blue triangle in the middle of the image and then we have a bonus task and the
first task is can you figure out how to actually fill in this triangle.
It actually requires a different function that we didn't show in the lecture.
So you have to use your stack overflow and google skills in order to figure out how you would actually
fill in a polyline object term or.
You're going to use a polyline to actually build that out.
And then I want you to figure out how you can actually then fill it in.
And there's a link here that gives you really strong hints on how to do it in case you get stuck on
that.
Again that's a bonus tasks since we didn't exactly show you how to do that.
During the lectures and if you scroll down you actually have one more task.
Sorry.
That final before but for this task.
Note that you may need to run this as a script specifically for Mac OS or Linux user where you're going
to be doing is creating a script that opens the picture.
This dog backpack picture that is and allows you to draw empty red circles wherever you click the right
mouse button down.
Let's quickly show you what the finished product should look like here.
So if you finish that task at the end that should look something like this where you have the dog backpack
image.
And if I order right click anywhere I get to see these empty red circles.
OK.
So that's it.
Best of luck on the assessment.
Coming up next we're going to go over the solutions see other
OK coming up next we're going to go for the solutions.
I'll see it there.