Hi everyone it's Jose here.
And thank you so much for enrolling in the course.
And welcome.
This is the course overview lecture.
I have a quick favorite to ask of you and ask that you please don't skip this lecture.
I know it's very tempting to just go straight ahead to the technical material but we're going to cover
a lot of important things in this particular lecture.
It's going to be pretty brief but there's a lot of important topics.
Well we're going to discuss here is how to get help during the course semi-useful course taking tips
how to get the actual notes and technical files for the course and also quick note.
Please check your automated welcome message for some nice useful information.
There's lots of useful links there that covers a lot of what we're going to talk about here.
OK.
So probably the most important question is how do you actually get help during the course.
So you're taking the course semi-technical pops up and you don't know how to solve it and you want to
ask the question.
So the first thing I would say is please double check against our provided files so we provide a file
for pretty much every single lecture video.
So you actually have the technical code available as well as the scripts and our files will are guaranteed
to pretty much work with all the correct versions of the libraries.
So there's different versions of a lot of the flask and Python libraries that we're using.
And we actually have a method to make sure that you use the exact same versions we do upon filming of
the course.
So that way as long as you run our files with those exact same versions that we provide they will always
work.
So please double check.
Always try to run our provided files first before posting a question because often as you're following
along with the videos it's really easy to make a simple typo and that can set the whole thing off.
And it's sometimes hard for us to catch those typos from our end.
So always please double check against our provider files by running them directly.
OK.
So let's say that they didn't work you're still having some sort of confusion.
That's totally OK.
What I would recommend doing first is to search the flash documentation and do a quick google or Stack
Overflow search about 80 to 90 percent of all questions have already been answered either through a
quick Google search or Stack Overflow search.
So you definitely don't want to have that as your quick response so a simple Google search of your error
code or your point of confusion often renders a really good answer on stack overflow and often in the
queue in a post where we're going gonna do is link you to a useful Stack Overflow searches ourselves.
So definitely check that out first.
OK.
So let's say Google did when Oscar flow but still couldn't find the answer you were looking for.
Maybe it's a little more related to a particular lecturer and of course no problem.
What you should do is search the previous Q and A post.
We have lots of students already in the course so it's highly likely that you're going to have a similar
question that someone already thought of to go ahead and search the previous Q A POSE.
OK so you've exhausted all those options and still have the confusion that is now unique upon the Kewney
forums.
No worries we're happy to help you out.
All you need to do is post and you question the question answer forums instead of course and will be
there to help you out.
The last thing I want you to please keep in mind in reference to getting help is with thousands of students
inside our courses.
We have more than half a million across all our courses and we can't really help out too much personal
homework assignments outside of the Course material.
What we've done for those kind of questions is we set up the court chat server and that's specifically
set up free to share those types of questions of other students and that we connect other students and
help each other out.
Personal homework questions and those kind of things were not really well suited to answer them.
We're really well suited to answer questions related to the course material itself or just questions
on video lectures so we really appreciate your patience with that.
And please keep that in mind.
And if you want more information on the dischord chat server check the automated welcome message.
It has the links for that.
OK so let's say your question is more about a platform issue.
Maybe the video is blurry or is taking a long time to render or having issues of the to me app.
The best way to do that is to get help by either opening a support ticket on the support page on Timmy's
Web site or their rectory email support.
You to me that com.
So these are things like video player issues certification issues enrollment or payment issues.
I actually don't control any of that.
I'm just a creator of the course and I teach the technical content the actual platform view to me is
separate from that.
So you don't want to e-mail them for those kind of issues.
All right let's go through some quick useful tips for taking the course.
What you should do is you should check out the bottom settings on the video player.
There's lots of useful things there you can adjust the quality of the stream and you can also adjust
the playback speed.
So maybe I'm going a little slow for you.
You can always watch the videos that 1.5 x or 2 x speed.
I personally tend to watch videos at 1.5 or 2 x beat myself or maybe English isn't your first language
so you want to watch them a little slower.
And eventually there should be automated captions for this actual video as well.
So you can click the automated captions on there.
And I also want to point out for easeful tip of taking the course there's probably a lot of material
that if you have some experience you're already familiar with it.
So please feel free to jump around sections if you already feel familiar of some of the material.
And we're going to cover the entire curriculum in the next lecture to give you a good idea if you want
a jumping off point.
OK.
Finally let's talk about how to actually get those notes.
So in this very lecture there's going to be a resource link and you should see either in the course
curriculum tab page or as you started watching this lecture you saw a blue pop up that contains a zip
file and that zip file has all the resources for all the lectures so all you need to do is download
that zip file unzip it and that's it.
You now have all the files and all the notes.
And as we go along for certain sections We'll explain how those notes are laid out but pretty much they're
all in the same order and they're numbered in the same order as the Course Lectures themselves.
OK.
You can also check out the link in the FNQ lecture for the resource link as well.
So it's the same ZIP file there and last but not least a huge thank you for enrolling in this course.
If you have any other questions always feel free to message me things about other courses that take
what paths to follow.
I'm always happy to help out.
Just shoot me a message here on to me.
And again thank you so much for enrolling in this course.
OK let's continue on.