Welcome everyone to the section of the course on a larger flask applications.
So far we've been putting a lot of content into a single app that py file and as your applications begin
to get larger a flask it typically makes more sense to separate portions of the application into their
own files such as creating a model stop file a form that py file.
And views that py file.
And in fact we've already seen that a bit through a previous lectures separating some of these components
that are getting too large for a single app that PI now for even larger applications.
It actually begins to make sense three factor the files into separate components or directories.
So then you'll actually have multiple forms views and templates for each major component of your web
application.
Let's re-imagine how we could restructure our puppy adoption site from the previous lectures.
Well we're going to do is going to split our apple pie into separate components for each major aspect
of our web application.
One component for the puppies and one component for the owners so we're going to do is we'll have our
apple pie file and the forms and views that go with it.
And we're going to separate those into their own directories.
We'll have at the Rectory for owners and we'll have forms and views and templates that are related to
owners and then we'll have a directory for puppies were formed views and templates that are related
to puppies will go.
We're also going to be able to use the blueprints library to connect these separate modular components
back to our main app Pietie I'll keep in mind.
We're still keeping that app up high.
However now it's going to just be referencing those subcomponents.
This is really going to help you organize your code as you begin to create larger and larger flask applications.
Let's view what the file structure will look like.
This is best done by checking out the structure exampled a text file that's within the larger flask
applications folder.
I want to open up that text file and walk you through it then in the next lecture we'll restructure
a project to fit this larger structure.
All right.
I've gone ahead and opened up the structure example text file and this basically lays out the structure
we're going to be building.
So you can see here the level designated by these actual indentations.
So you can see what's inside my project and then what's inside my owner's we're going to walk through
this overall directory to explain how we're actually going to structure a project now.
So we still have at the very top level are at thought py file and this is the main application file
to be called when you actually start the server for your web application.
Then we're going to have a requirements that textfile.
This is a file of Pippin's false statements for your app.
So we're going to go over had actually create your own requirements text file then you're going to have
a migration folder which is just created for migrations by automatically calling those flask DB calls.
And then finally we'll have a large main project folder and this is where the subcomponents will be
in separate folders.
So at this top level you're going to have your models PI file in it that PI file as well as your actual
sequelae database.
And then also within my project have an owner's directory and a puppy's directory then within both owners
and puppies you have forms and views that are related to things about the owners.
So if you want to create a new owner that's going to be inside the forms that py file within the owner's
directory.
If you want to create a new puppy that's going to be within the forms that PI file of the puppies and
then views associate of owners or puppies.
That's going to be within those subdirectories as well.
Now if you have a view or a form that doesn't really fall nicely into one of these categories like owner
or puppies then you can always feel free to just put it back at the same top level or even just include
it in the app that py file room or not everything's going to be able to nicely fit into a subcomponent.
So that's really going to depend on case by case.
And it's really up to you if you want to organize it in this fashion.
Or if you want to just have one large app that PI file or forms and views at the top level again a lot
of this starts to become kind of personal choice.
Then again other owners and puppies they're each going to have their own templates folder and they will
say owners again or puppies again and then the template files that belong to those particular components
like an owner or add or delete list puppies.
Then at the same level of puppies and owners you're going to have your static file that's where you
would store your CSSA javascript images font files etc. and then you'll have template files and do templates
that probably don't sync well.
Any component such as the base H-2 him and the home page HTML file.
The homey smell file that really doesn't belong to a particular component like puppies or owner's son
said.
We'll leave it at this top level template files and then within these puppies and owners we're going
to introduce what's known as blueprints in order to successfully connect them to our top level apple
pie.
OK.
So coming up next we're going to completely restructure our original adoption site to look like this.
Keep in mind in the very next lecture it's super easy to accidently make a typo.
So in case you get something or some error that's not letting you run the completed application.
Make sure you copy and paste directly or just run our files directly from the larger flask applications
folder.
OK we'll see at the next lecture where we begin restructuring our project with blueprints.