Welcome back.
We just finished our team crash course and now it's time to move on to talking about C Ss and this crash
course.
We have a few goals we want to complete by the end of this section.
Once you've gone through this CSSA crash course you should understand how to connect H.T. e-mail to
your C Ss understand basic CSSA syntax.
Understand selector types.
Be able to perform element inspection inside your browser and then finally connect CSSA fonts.
If you already have an understanding of just connecting stylesheets the H Tim L in general you can feel
free to skip this section of the course.
All right let's get started.
I'll see in the next lecture.