Welcome back in this lecture we're going to go through it.
An example of the basic template so far we've only returned back each T.M. manually through a python
string.
Realistically we're going to want to connect the view function through under an HMO template that is
to say needs to mail file.
So we've already created for page Flast will automatically look for HTL templates in the templates directory
which means you need to make sure your folder that's actually holding oyur HTL files is called templates.
Later on we're going to discuss how to separate larger applications to have multiple template directories.
For now we're going to render templates simply by importing the render underscore template function
from flask and returning an HTML file from our view function.
Let's see this action by heading over to our text editor or a here I am back in my text editor what
I'm going to start off with is I have a basic thought py file and it's underneath a folder called flask
underscore examples.
I'm going to create a new folder here and the new folder is going to be called templates and it's at
the same level directory as my base pi.
And then inside of templates I'm going to create a new file and I'm going to call this basic dot h tim
L.
So this is an HCM file.
So let's go ahead and type out h T.M. which should fill this out for us.
Remember you have to save as an e-mail file to get the auto completion and then we're going to do here
is just inside the body we're going to have a head or one tag that says Welcome to the site that is
going to save that.
So I have a basic team.
Now it's time to link this to my actual flask application.
We'll come back to basics up high and we'll say from flask import flask as we've done before and we're
going to import render template or create my flask application by passing in that name variable and
then I'm just going to have a single page just the home page going to be my index page.
And in order to actually render that table file I say return rendered template and then I pass in the
name of the file.
Basic h tim L.
And what else is going to do.
It's going to automatically look in the same level directory for a folder named templates and then it's
going to look inside that templates folder for a file name based studies T.M..
So you need to make sure that this string matches exactly with the name.
You call this h him I'll file and that's a and all file has to be in the templates folder at the same
level as whatever that PI file you're running.
Once you've done that we're going to say if name is equal to mean take my app and run it.
And let's go ahead and set debug.
Equal to true.
Just to make sure we can easily debug in case we get any errors I'll say Python basic that pi.
Let's run this and it looks like it's running in my browser going to bring my browser over.
Just so it can check this out.
And I bring it over and it says Welcome to the site.
So I successfully connected my flask application to an aged team file and hopefully you can see that
you'd easily be able to expand this by creating more functions and creating more each time files.
The last thing I want to show before we finish up this lecture is how to connect to a static file.
So we're going to do is back and on each team I'll file.
I'm going to say H2.
Here is a pic of a puppy and let's create an image test and we're going to set the source to forward
slash static forward slash puppy underscore pick that shape.
Now we've actually provided a picture of a puppy for you inside that course notes or if you want you
can go to something like an splash and that's a free Web site for photos.
An splash that is really useful especially when you just rendering example web sites or bring it over
just so we can see what it looks like.
Here's on Splash it's free photos and you don't need to worry about things like copyright.
It's basically all donated by photographers so I can look up something like puppie do a search here
and eventually we'll see cute pictures of puppies.
So let's go and just grab one of these.
I kind of like this guy right here.
It's going to click on this.
Going to right click save images and let's save this to a static file.
So I'm going to save this under flask examples.
I have my templates folder here.
What I'm going to do is create a new folder I'll see file new folder and I'm going to call this static
and then inside that static folder I'll save this and I'm going to rename this puppy underscore pick
dot G.P.A..
Save that.
That's downloaded now.
And if we come back to Adam I should now be able to see a static folder here.
Expand this and then see Papy underscore picked that jpeg.
And that's exactly what the source is pointing to.
It says Go back up a directory and then check out the static folder and then check out puppie pick a
peg.
I'm going to save this and let's rerun our actual site.
And when you see it you should see something like this says here's a pic of a puppy.
Let me zoom out and you should see this cute little guy there.
All right.
So we just explored how we can render HVM template and also how we can create static files such as an
image link to it in the HTL template and render that as well in our flask application and technically
you already have everything you need for a very simple landing page where you just display information
and images are going to continue to expand on this and we're going to continue to talk about how we
can insert things into the html template as a quick review.
The main thing to remember is you have rendered template as your function and you're just going to return
that in your html files.
They need to be inside of a folder named templates and technically so that it can be called other things
because you're manually passing in this file path.
But in general your static files such as images should go under a folder called static.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you in the next lecture where we continue to build our understanding of templates.