Welcome back in this lecture we're going to discuss how to actually submit a form as well as how to
add labels to our form input elements.
Now there are two main methods for submitting the form information.
One method is the get method and another method is the post method.
When you work out of elf forms the get method is going to request a representation of the specified
resource.
That is the information you provided in the form.
First simple HTML forms.
When we actually use the method to get what we'll see is that we're going to send back the information
to our action your L and they will make more sense when we actually see it in practice.
And just a little bit the other method you could provide is the post method and the post method it will
submit data to be processed and will be using the post method.
Once we actually learn how to connect the database with flask to the form for it.
Now we're just going to supply an action your free redirect after submitting the form.
The last thing will cover in this lecture is that right now our forms are just currently empty boxes
and there's no real way of knowing which one is for the email and which ones for the password.
So we're going to discuss how to add basic labels to the forms themselves.
That way you can have a little bit more organization.
All right let's jump over to the text editor and get started.
All right here I have my basic form back my basic but each time I'll have an open forum text and my
clothes form tag.
Let's add two inputs one for an email and one for a password.
So the input type is email and then the next input type will be password.
And right now they have no name and no value will add those in just a second.
If I refresh my page I should see two boxes one for the email and then one for the password.
However I can't really tell which is which.
So it would be nice if I could add a label the way we do this is if the use of a label type or create
a label tag and notice the label tag has a for attribute and what you're going to do is connect this
to an id attribute for the input so will say this label is for my email tag and then what I will do
is inside of my input.
Also id attribute equal to the same string email tag and this string is basically an arbitrary choice.
It can say whatever you want as long as the four attribute in your label matches up with the id attribute
for your input and then in-between the open label and this close label tag you just type out whatever
the label should be.
So I will say email will save this refresh and you should see a label right in front of that email.
So let's do the same thing for the password will say label will say for I'll just make up a string pass
tag and then set an ID equal to that same string pass tag and then will say password.
Colon.
Save refresh.
And now I get some nice labels connected to their respective input boxes so I can tell that it will
be email and this one should be password and I can zoom in a little more so you guys can see this more
clearly.
Here's just email here's the password.
Keep in mind if you zoom in too much you'll start getting some formatting errors and we can always do
is add a break element.
So that's B.R. and that will automatically induce a break in between whatever elements there are on
the page there.
So if I refresh this now I get email break and then password OK.
So I have my email labeled as well as my password label what I want to do now is add a submit button
and also add an action in a method for my form itself.
So here at the bottom I'm going to say input type is submit and I'll give it a value of submit.
I'll save this refresh.
And now I see this nice submit button here and then what I want to do is actually have some sort of
action that's going to occur upon submitting the form so to do that I'm going to add in an action attribute.
And this is essentially a redirect.
It just asks when you hit submit on the form what next page should I go to.
And typically this action is going to point to another HTL file on your own server.
But right now since we're dealing with just a basic single team I'll file.
Let's go ahead and redirect to for instance Google all say HTP colon forward slash forward slash W.W.
thought Google dot com and then I will say method is equal to get.
And I'll zoom in just a little bit so we can see everything inside the form.
So now I'm saying OK once you hit the submit button go ahead and go to Google and get the information
that's inside of this form.
But right now this e-mail information and this password information does actually contain a name or
value.
So let's provide those.
I'm going to say that the name is user e-mail and that the value we can just say something like e-mail
here.
So what happens when I save these changes and update it the value will automatically show up as a value
inside of the e-mail.
So typically what's going to happen is this value is going to get replaced by whatever your actual user
provides.
So instead of saying email here they'll delete that and let's say something like my e-mail at gmail
dot com.
So value will just act as some sort of value for it to start off with name user email is the name that's
going to be associated with this e-mail that's passed back.
Let's do the same for password.
So for password we're going to do is just set the name equal to password.
And again you can set these names to whatever you want.
And if you want it you can set a value.
But instead we can also do is set a placeholder so a placeholder is probably more common than setting
a predetermined value.
So a placeholder is equal to password hit save and you refresh what notice with a actual placeholder
as you get this sort of feints text here.
And when you click on it it basically goes away.
So that's usually more useful than providing some pre-determined value.
So let's replace the pre-determined value for email with a placeholder as well.
We'll save this refresh the page.
And now I see a nice email here.
But the moment I click on it and start typing I get to provide my own value.
OK so it looks like we have every thing set up for what we need.
We have an e-mail that's labeled rumor that's connection between this for and ID as well as setting
the form action and the method.
So let's provide after we save this and refresh an e-mail.
So I will say Jose Jose dot com just to make it very obvious that it's my e-mail a somewhat real e-mail
and then password will just put in some password so I'll put password and then notice what's going to
happen when I hit submit.
If I actually expand this and zoom in a bit you'll notice that I was able to successfully pass in not
just the name but its corresponding value.
So now I see here that user e-mail is equal to Jose.
And then there's a basically a placeholder for the at symbol.
Since I can't really directly pass that in I passed it as per cent sign for zero.
So Jose that COM and then I say.
And then we just have these name value pairs so password is equal to.
And in this case since we're just using the get method.
It actually literally passes back the passer provided.
Later on we'll discuss much better validation methods for this as well as better security methods.
But that's essentially the main idea.
I'm just going to provide these name value pairs back to either the next each team page or back to my
server.
When you learn how to operate this flask and Python.
OK.
So that's really the basics of everything we covered here.
Again let's come back to our a text editor and explore this a little further.
We'll come back here my browser expand this text editor.
All we're doing is we're saying give me an action page.
So that's the redirect page again.
Typically it's going to be an HTML file it's living on your own server and then you'll describe a method.
Right now we'll do the simpler one get later on we'll change the post and then we added labels in order
to understand what each text box was referring to.
And then we have these name value pairs.
So we have a name and then we'll have a corresponding value that the user will provide and we can't
either set a default value or we can set a placeholder.
So the placeholder shows up as that great text that we have here that if we delete this we then get
to see and then you have a submission and that will pass in and perform the redirect action OK.
That's the very basics of actually submitting a form and adding labels to a form if you have any questions
feel free to post to the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.