Welcome back everyone to part two of our Google example for flask.
Authorization with flask.
That's the main part we're going to be focusing on and this lecture is actually getting our client id
in our secret ID keys so we should always do is check out the flask dance documentation to see if there's
any updates to the API.
So let's go ahead and go back to that QuickStart documentation for Google.
OK so here we are with flask dance and notice for every single Quickstart Guide.
For example if you open up the hub or the Quick Start guides there's instructions on how to actually
set up the application.
So this instructions before the code is what you need to do.
And we're going to be doing it for Google.
So the first thing it tells us do is visit the Google developer's console.
Now keep in mind when you visit this console your formatting may look different than mine because Google
is constantly updating you.
However there should be some sort of API has an authorization section and will want to set up some credentials.
So it's going to do that open up console that developers that Google dot com.
And that should take you to a page that looks like this.
Eventually you should be asked if you're not already to sign into the Google platform.
So let me sign in.
All right.
Once you've actually signed in to the developers console you should see some sort of dashboard.
Keep in mind as I keep mentioning Google's dashboard UI and interface may change often so your screen
may look different but the same information should be here.
That's all we're looking for is where we actually set up credentials.
And in this iteration of dashboard it's over here under API and services.
There's a little key here that says credentials go ahead and click on that key.
And then if you haven't set up any credentials you'll get something that looks like this.
So we want to create credentials so I'm going to click Create credentials and I'll say oh off client
id or click on that.
And then when you actually set up a auth client id we actually set a consent screen.
So it says you must first set a product name on the consent screen so they can feel your consent screen
right here.
You'll have your e-mail address shown product name shown to users.
I'm going to say my flask test home page you are l.
That would be actually linked to your deployed your URL.
You can go ahead and just keep that blank for right now.
Product logo.
Again we can keep it blank.
Essentially all these optional until you add the player app.
Terms of Service So all these you are are going to be optional but you'll link them to whatever you're
deployed you are ELAS suddenly click save here.
Save that and then now that I set that up I can finally create my own client ID.
So we're setting up a web application.
The name here we'll go in and say web client 1.
And as far as restrictions the main one we need to focus on is this authorized redirect you are I and
every QuickStart if we come back here will tell us what you should actually pasan.
So it says once you've done that you'll see two new fields authorized javascript origins and authorized
redirects.
So when you do is we need to put this localhost log into Google authorized into authorized redirect
your eyes starting to copy this come back to client id and paste it in from my redirect your.
We don't need to worry about the javascript open Origin's so click on Create and then that will create
that link and then click on Create one more time then you should see a screen telling you hey here's
your client id and here's your client secret.
We're going to copy those and stick them into our application so I'll copy my client I.D. and come back
to Adam where we were setting it up.
So let me bring in the item.
So right here I have made Google blueprints.
I still need my client I.D..
So let's set that up.
I'm going to pasan or paste in the client id that I just created and then the next one I'm going to
do here is pasand the secret silts go back to our Google app and then we're going to copy the client
secret.
So copy that as well.
And then let's bring in Adam again.
And then I'm going to paste that in.
So there I have my client ID and my secret ready to go.
So essentially all we have to do now as a quick note you will typically set these as environment variables
at the command line instead of pasting them in and having them here in our blueprint.
So my client idea set up in my client secret is set up as well.
Let's save these changes and then I'm actually going to run my Python application and see if everything
worked out.
So say Python app thought pie or any flask examples or Ruby up in to save this run that.
And whoops let me make sure that I actually ran this.
Looks like I forgot to actually run this at the bottom so let's set that up.
So at the very bottom as always we'll say if name is equal to me take my app and run it and notice I'm
going to not run it in debug mode because I want this welcome to actually return an internal server
error.
If I have it in debug mode it'll help me debug it but I actually want that bug to show up.
Basically I want the internal server error so make sure when you say if name is local to Main just say
app run don't have it in debug mode.
OK.
Now let's say that and actually run this there we go so looks like it's running.
Let's bring in our browser and make sure that all worked out OK here and in my browser.
Let's first see if I'm able to visit this welcome page without logging in.
So if I click welcome page here they'll say internal server error sorry.
Encountered an internal error.
Unable to complete your request as a quick note.
I would recommend that you try to log out of your Google services and view this in incognito browsing
or private browsing.
That way it doesn't accidentally sync up in case you're already logged into Google somewhere.
So we should get an internal server error on this welcome because I'm not logged into Google yet.
So let's revisit the home page.
Come back to my home page and then it says here log in here.
Google.
So let's click that now you'll notice I actually got an error.
It says redirect your mismatch as hey the either and you or I and the request was this one.
1 2 7 0 0 0 1 0 0 0 0.
Log into authorized.
It doesn't match the one that we set in the off client.
Now this because in the O off client we set local hosts instead of this you or I want to 7 zeros are
1 5 0 0 0 0 0.
So what you need to do is because we're testing this out locally.
I'm going to add in this your I that showed up here.
So going to copy that in and I'm going to add that in as a redirect.
Your option.
So let's go back to our dashboard and add that in.
All right so here I am back on my dashboard Let me zoom in just a little bit and we're going to come
back here to credentials.
Go ahead and click on that and we should see now is the web client credential that we created earlier.
Go ahead and click on that one.
And then underneath authorized redirect your eyes.
The basic one is localhost 5000.
But because we're actually testing this locally we're going to add in this 1 2 7 0 0 5000 as well.
This and this are essentially the same thing except one is kind of more clarification when you're testing
this locally.
So click save and then that's added in.
So we can click Save again just to make sure that's saved then.
And now let's jump back and try to log in again with Google.
So going to minimize this and it come back to my office to air Shurmur we have this redirect your your
mismatch.
So let's come back and revisit our Web site.
So we're now back at the home page and then to click again log in here of Google.
And now you should see something that looks like this.
It says Choose an account or log in.
So are Mordy have my default fill them all click.
Choose an account pasand your password here.
Then click next and then it should take you back to the home page.
Menow it's really cool when you click on the welcome page here.
You should see welcome Google user and your e-mail.
OK.
So again that specific fix for the your eye.
We only really had to do that because we were testing things locally on a local computer.
The general local host you or I that should work when you actually deployer Web site and are using open
authorization.
OK.
That's really the basics.
Notice how this code is essentially just lifted straight off from the QuickStart guide.
I would really recommend that you always use the floss that's QuickStart guides and they have more extensive
guides for adding in things like logging management or multiple open authorisations.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.