Welcome back to this lecture on loop's We'll talk about for loops and while loops.
Let's start by talking about four loops.
First many objects in Python are what's known as iterable.
That means we can use for loops to execute a block of code for every iteration through these objects.
So that term iterable just means that you can iterate over the object.
For example you can iterate over every character in a string iterate over every item in a list or iterate
over every key in a dictionary.
So let's talk about the actual Python syntax for a for loop.
Let's imagine that my iterable object is a list.
So I created a variable called my iterable and I said equal to this list.
One two three.
So what happens here is I say for item name in my iterable print the item name.
So let's talk about the actual steps that's going on here.
First I'd define an iterable object.
In this case it's a list but this could be a string or a dictionary or a tuple or many other object
types.
So later on you've built an intuitive understanding of what's iterable and what's not.
But right now we'll focus on lists since they're basically the most straightforward.
So once you have your iterable defined then you're going to choose some sort of temporary variable name.
So you're going to say 4 and this item underscore name you can choose whatever you want to plaister.
So in this case I chose underscore name and then we say the in keyword and then we say my iterable basically
that variable.
So for every item in my iterable colon and then we're going to execute a block of code.
In this case I can print out every single item inside of the iterable.
So the output here would just be those numbers 1 2 and 3.
Basically for every item in that list go ahead and print out that item.
Now let's talk about while loops while loops will continue to execute a block of code while some condition
remains true.
For example while my pool is not fool keep filling my pool with water or while my dogs are still hungry
keep feeding my dogs.
So let's talk about the syntax of an actual wild.
Here we're going to say while some boolean condition and then we're going to execute a block of code
continually until that boolean condition is no longer true.
So often we're going to have some sort of way to effect that boolean condition inside the while loop
itself.
Now you can also combine a while and else if you want to show you could say while some boolean condition
do something else do something different although often you just see while loops by themselves ok let's
explore all these concepts by heading over to the Adam text editor and working through some examples.
Ok let's begin by showing some examples of a for loop.
I'm going to start by using a list so I created s e q as my variable name.
You can really choose any variable name you want and I'm going to create a list the numbers 1 2 3 4.
So let's imagine I wanted to perform some sort of action with each element.
I could say for item in CQ or sequence.
Go ahead and print that item and again notice how there's indentation here and this should be automatically
done for you in any ID.
If it's not then you should probably save this as a profile and check again.
So now I'm going to run this code and if I scroll up I get to see one two three four five.
So it went ahead and printed every single number in that list.
What I could do is say maybe print every number squared.
So I'll take the item square it and then print out the result.
So let's run those results and I see 1 4 9 16 25.
Now often beginners get confused they say well we're that this item come from I didn't see the find
anywhere.
Technically it's just a temporary variable name for the iteration through the sequence so you could
have this be anything and I like to make something weird here just to make that very clear so I could
say for jellyfish in the queue.
Go ahead and take jellyfish.
And maybe times it by 2.
So again it's totally up to you.
What term is going to be chosen for your sequence throughout that iteration.
Now often you're probably not going to want to use something like jellyfish.
Instead you should choose something pretty irrelevant.
Maybe nom would be a good one in this case because there numbers so this is how I would do this.
I would say for them sequence print name but keep in mind any variable name there is OK.
So something else you should know is when you're saying for some item in a sequence you don't necessarily
need to actually use that item in the sequence.
Let's say I just wanted to print Hello five times.
This case for every number in that sequence 1 2 3 4 5.
I'm going to perform the action.
Notice I'm not actually using numb instead I'm using almost this as some sort of counting device.
So now when I run this I get back.
Hello hello hello hello.
Just one hello for each item in this list.
OK so that's how a for loop works of a list.
Let's see how it works now with a string.
So I'll say hello is a string and I want to save for now I'm going to make this actually say C H A R
because it's more reflective what it's going to do with a string.
So I'm going to say my string is equal to hello and for C H R for character in my string.
Go ahead and print out that character.
So when you actually for loop through a string you basically loop through every single character in
that string.
So for a list every item or element in that list for strings.
It's every character in that string.
Then for dictionaries.
Let's go ahead to make a dictionary.
We'll say salary's again and we'll say John 10.
Let's have Sally B 20 and let's say Lisa is 30 I'm going to start this again for.
And when you loop through a dictionary what's going to happen is you get a loop through the keys of
the dictionary so you can say for key in salary's print the key.
So when I read this and I loop through a dictionary I see all the keys John Salley and Lisa.
So something to know here is you could technically call this whatever you want.
So maybe it makes more sense to call this four employee in salary's again to really taking advantage
of Python's clean syntax to make code very readable.
So here it's very clear what's happening.
I'm saying for employee in salary's Prince employ and there we go.
John Salley and Lisa.
Now let's imagine actually wanted the values associated with those keys.
Well all we need to do is take my salary's dictionary and then index it for that particular employee.
So I'm going to grab that employee and paste it in there.
And let's print out salary's for that employee.
So now when I run this piece of code I see 10 20 30 and if I want all the information I can just use
multiple print statements.
So Nel's prints employ here and let's do some more prints so I can say the let's say employ
has a salary of.
And then we'll print out that salary and I'm going to print out a blank line there.
So save that and zoom a little bit so we can see the whole picture here and collapse this little bit.
So have a salary's dictionary.
I'm saying for every employee in salaries.
Remember when you loop through a dictionary it's going to default through the Keys that dictionary.
So then in print that the employee has a salary of and they're going to grab that associate a key value
pair and then prints a blank line.
So when I run this I get back.
Lisa has a salary of 30.
Salary a salary of 20.
And John has a salary of ten.
So again just keep in mind when you loop through a dictionary it's going to loop through the Keys by
default.
Now the last special thing I want to mention is something called tuple unpacking.
As you begin to work a lot with Python you'll notice that often functions return a list of tuple pairs.
So you'll see something like this a one.
And then maybe C-3.
So notice what's happening here.
I have a list of tuples.
So if I were to print out the length of my pairs I would expect a length of three because there's three
tuples inside of this my pairs list.
So here you have these tuples.
There's three of them.
So what happens when actually loop through this I'll say for item in my pairs print the item will save
that and run it and I get back each particular tuple which is fine but because this sort of structure
is so common in Python having a list of tuples where you can do something called tuple and packing so
you could do is instead of saying for item and each item being a tuple you can actually have a little
tuple here and then say something like.
Item one item two.
And then you can print out item 1 and print out item 2.
So this is actually going to deconstruct or unpack the tuple as you are going through your for loop.
So now look what you see.
You see one you see a one BE2 and then see three because you're printing out first these letters and
then printing out these numbers.
So you're unpacking the tuple inside of your for loop.
Now you actually don't need these princes here.
Instead you could say Item one.
Item two and my pairs and this by itself will also work just fine.
To get that exact same result.
I just wanted to show you with the princes to make it clear.
The idea of what's happening.
And again we can choose whatever variable names we want for these particular items inside of this list.
So it might make more sense to do something like four letter numb in my pairs.
Prince
and again you don't have to use both of these.
Maybe I only want to print the letters inside of those pairs.
So after you save it you can run it and just get back the letters.
Or maybe you only want the numbers.
In that case just print out them save that.
Run it again and easy one two three.
Again this is called tuple unpacking and it's a pretty important topic because you see this sort of
structure a lot and some more advanced Python functions.
OK so that's the basics of for loops.
Now let's quickly discuss how we can use while loops and we'll also talk about a few other topics such
as the in keyword and the range function so let's say that so remember that while loops will continually
perform action until that condition becomes true.
So I will set a variable.
I equal to 1 and I will say while I is less than 5 go ahead and Prince I is currently and then I'll
go ahead and use an F string literal to Prince.
I so what was happening here him say is equal one.
And then while I was less than five I'll say I is currently in the current value of i.
Now if I were to just run this by itself right now it would go on forever because I'm not changing the
value of I one will always be less than five.
So this would constantly Forever print out eyes.
Currently one is currently one is currently one.
So in order to make sure that we don't get a forever while loop peer analysts a prince actually not
going to print anything I'll just say I is not going to be equal to I plus one.
So what does that mean.
It means I started off as one.
I'm saying while I less than 5 print out the current value of i and then take the current value of i
add 1 to it and reset that to be I.
So then that's going to become two then three.
Then it's four and eventually it'll be five.
And this while loop will no longer execute so it should stop by printing.
I's currently 4 and by the time I get added 1 and it's 5.
This while loop ceases to continue.
So let's run this and see what we get.
So we say eyes currently 1 2 3 4 and on that very last iteration of the while loop we said 4 plus 1
is 5 and 5 is no longer less than 5.
So this while loop terminates.
OK that's the very basic idea of a while loop.
You want to be really careful with this condition because if you do something like.
While one is equal to 1 then it doesn't matter what you put here.
This is always going to be true so it will go on forever and you want to use Control-C to stop permanent
while loops OK we just discussed for loops and while loops.
The last thing I want to do is discuss a few more useful operators.
One is the range function which can quickly generate a list of integers for you.
So if you use Range what you can do is signify a start a stop and a step size so you can say range from
0 to 5 and you can actually loop through this or iterate through it so I can say for x in range 0 to
5 print X and what range does it automatically generates integers for you.
So now I want to run this I get back.
0 1 2 3 4.
So it starts at 0 and then goes up to but not including 5.
So again you can kind of play around with this maybe do 11 so that will go all the way up to but not
including 11.
So we'll see.
0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 and something else to know is that you can add a third parameter.
That's a step size.
So hopefully this feels really really reminiscent of slicing a list or slicing a string.
So if you want to take jumps and two cause by default it just jumps one integer at a time.
When you run this you get back 0 2 4 6 8 10.
So again that's the step size.
So you have a start in exclusive stop.
So it goes up to and not including a stopping point and then a step size.
Now if you just want the list itself where you need to do is cast this into a list and then say something
like result is equal to that list and then if you aren't you can then print that result.
So if you don't intend on actually iterating through this range instead you actually want the raw result
as a list.
You can just cast it as a list and then get back to that list.
OK the last keyword I want to dive in a little more on is the in keyword.
We already saw as a keyword for 4 loops but I just want to clarify.
You can actually use it to test if something is in an iterable.
So let's say I want to check.
Let's say I have a really long string so I'm just going to type a bunch of code there and I want to
check is the letter S inside of that string.
All I can say s in this string and then I can actually print out the result of this.
So I just print s in right here and this should return back a boolean value.
And in this case it's true because S isn't here.
Now let's put Z.
I can tell that zees not in there.
So I run this they'll give me back false.
So this works both for strings and for a list.
So let's move this and I'll say one two three.
So I'm going to ask is the string Z an element inside of this list.
You run that you get false.
So let's change it to 1.
So now is 1 inside of this list.
Run that and that's true.
So that's the in keyword operator by itself.
Kind of outside of a for loop.
You can just check if an element is inside.
In other iterable element.
OK so we talked about range in the keyword and then while loops and for loops as well as tuple and packing.
Kind of a special condition for for loops.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.