Welcome back.
To finish off this HTL crash course we're going to have a quick second assessment of your skills.
So in order to test your skills your task is just going to be the same as the first assessment for each
team will essentially recreate the aged female first sight in your browser.
So just by viewing what's in the browser tray to recreate it in Tamil in order to do that.
Go ahead and double click open part 10.
H tim l assessment to that each time L and view it in your browser.
Again mission out to peek at the actual HTL code since that will essentially be showing you the solution.
Let's see what this looks like in the browser and then we'll set you off to actually try to recreate
it on your own.
All right.
So once you actually open this in your browser you'll notice you have a Heading 1 puppy adoption page
and then basically just the form asking you to fill in information in order to adopt a puppy you have
labels of a lot of these boxes.
So first name this is just a text box.
Notice how there's placeholders here for first name and last name and then notice that there's actually
a break in between this first name and last name to create a new line.
And you can do that either by adding in a brake tag that's the be our tag we saw one of the videos or
just by adding in an empty paragraph tag then we have email here as well as a password that it asks
you Are you over the age of 18.
A need provide yes or no.
Notice how these buttons are linked.
Meaning they share the same name and then we have a dropdown menu asking you if you have credit card
or Paypal and then you have submit feedback.
Now it's up to you what you want to do when you submit feedback.
Right now we don't have any actual redirect.
So when you submit your feedback the page has just refreshed along for your choices at the top.
OK.
Best of luck recreating this Web site.
Again just look at it in the browser.
Instead of looking at it in the text editor and the very next structure will show you how to go through
solutions.
We'll see if.