Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and go through the solutions for HTL assessment too.
All right here we have in each team file and right now it's link to the empty browser page.
So I'm going to start off just by typing.
H t m l and auto filling.
What we need here in most of our work.
Pretty much all our work is going to happen here in the body.
So let's start off by creating that heading one which we saw was the puppy adoption page and then I
believe there was another heading to just asking for more information.
So I'll just say Please enter information.
It's up to you how much detail you wanted to provide in those heading to.
Again we're not worried about matching the exact text just matching the ideas of creating a form.
Speaking of which let's go ahead and create that form so I'll type up form enter and we're not going
to worry about a class because that's for CSSA.
And in this case we don't really worry about having a redirect for the action.
Instead we'll just have the method B get.
That way we can make sure that we're actually grabbing information from the form and passing it through
to the URL.
Upon submission of the page the first thing we wanted to do was add inputs for first name last name
email and password and all those inputs also had labels.
So let's create a very generic label input pair so say label for and then input here and we'll give
it an ID tag as well.
And right now this will just be empty.
So I'm going to copy and paste these a couple of times.
We have one for first name and other for last name and other for the email and another for the password.
And then in between first and last e-mail password I'm going to insert a little break here.
That way we can start a new line and you can do this either by just inserting a paragraph tag with a
closing paragraph tag or by inserting a line breaker which is just a B tag.
All right.
Now that we've done that let's actually create these.
So we'll start at the level for first name and I will say this is.
First we'll give it an idea that matches first.
And this type is going to be a text type and we can go ahead and remove the value and instead replace
it with a placeholder.
So say placeholder is equal to first name we'll hit save and let's refresh just to make sure.
Right along the same path.
So first name and I have the first name placeholder.
And now I need to add the labels for these other boxes here that their inputs.
So we'll do that as well.
So we'll say last match that up with last ID and then will say last name colon and then we'll have that
have a placeholder as well.
So say placeholder is equal to last name.
Save that and let's fill that in for the email and password as well.
So we'll say for email connected with the ID and then we'll do the same here for the password we'll
say for pass.
Connect that with that.
Remember these are essentially just arbitrary string choices that just didn't match up with the four.
And the ID and then we'll say email for that label and will say password here.
And we also want to change the e-mail and password to reflect a specific input types.
So we'll say type is e-mail and we'll say type here is password and if you want it can have a placeholder
here as well as that lvalues will say placeholder for that placeholder.
I'll just say email at e-mailed dot com save that let's refresh see if it's working.
All right.
Looks good.
We have first name last name email and password.
Now we also want to ask the user if they're over the age of 18 so they can adopt this puppy so that
inside the form I'm going to create just that paragraph asking Are you over 18 and we want to actually
have a radio button and we want make sure they're connected.
So we'll have a label and we'll say this is for.
Yes.
So say yes this person is over 18 and that's going to be an input of type radio and I will say the name
here is over 18.
So this really matter what you call this name wise it just matters that when you create the next radio
button you make sure they connect to the same name.
So I will copy this label in this input
and have it here and let's make one for no
and then we still have the same name.
And then the values will go ahead and pass back something like Yes.
Over and over.
And remember when you actually hit submit.
This is the name value pair that's going to be connected with this actual choice on the radio button.
Let's make sure these are working to save this refresh.
So it says are you over 18.
If I select yes and then select No my radio button only allows one to be selected.
So they are successfully linked there.
Finally let's add in that dropdown menu.
So say do you have credit card or PayPal.
So I'll say do you have credit card GCC or PayPal.
And then for this we'll use the selected and we can not worry about the class for now since we won't
be adding style to it.
And for the name I'll just say something like payment and then let's add in an option.
So the option here will say the CC is the value we pass back and then we'll say credit card is the option
that dropdown menu will create one more option and I will say Peepy here for Pay-Pal.
There you go.
Save that.
Let's refresh make sure it's working.
So see yes or no credit card or PayPal.
And then finally let's add in a submit button.
So after this still inside the form I'll see input type submit.
And then let's add value here submit feedback or submit choice or just submit.
Doesn't really matter what you call it refresh.
And now I see all these options.
OK let's make sure this all works.
I'll just say Al is the first name and then we'll say Smith is the last name email we'll say e-mail.
E-mail dot com.
Just something really simple password.
I'll just pass over 18 and I'm using your credit card.
Hit submit and we should see this page refresh.
There we go.
And if you look at the top you should begin to see those name value pairs.
Now if you didn't define a name value pairs for some of these maybe then define a name value pair for
first name or last name then you won't see him here in the OR L if you want to see them.
All you need to do is come back here and then provide them.
So for example first name I didn't see that in the URL because it has no name value pair.
We just need to provide a name for this so we can say first last save that refresh here and then we'll
do this again.
Just say Al.
And then last name Smith So let's say at the dot com some letters there for the password.
Submit again and they should begin to see the first and last appear in the oral.
OK.
That's the very basics of HMO forms.
Again keep in mind later on in the future will really be using flasks his own built in a library to
automatically create the HTML here for us.
But it's important to understand what the real him code underneath would look like.
That flask is going to generate.
OK.
That ends your e-mail crash course.
Hopefully it should have been pretty straightforward.
Not a whole lot we need to cover in order to understand how to work with the basics of each T.M. with
flask.
Up next we'll discuss SS first styling our actual web sites.
Then after that we'll talk about bootstrap which has its own built in classes to make your websites
look nice.
Then we'll be ready for Python and flask.
We'll see you there.