Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to go through the solutions for the function tasks.
Let's get started.
OK.
Let's begin by taking a look at task one.
So the first one I wanted you to return a boolean to check if there's some of these two numbers was
equal to 10.
Often beginners will do something like this.
They'll say if and one plus and two is equal to 10 return TRUE else return false.
Now while this is a perfectly valid solution it's actually not the most efficient solution because remember
just like we showed in some previous lectures this itself is already the boolean true or false.
So instead of doing something like this you could just return there some if it's equal to 10 or not.
So you could take the sum first.
So we'll say OK and one plus and two and check if this sum is equal to the number 10 and I'll return
a boolean.
True or false.
Moving on to task 2 wanted to check 10 some.
So this one was a little different.
Now you are going to need some sort of if statement because I want you to first check if the sum is
equal to 10 return TRUE else return there are some so say if and one plus two is equal to 10 return
TRUE else will return their actual sum or turn and one plus and two OK.
So again now we actually do need that if statement.
Now let's return to task 3 and this one wanted you to create a function that takes in a string and returns
back the first character of that string in uppercase.
This is pretty straightforward.
All we need to do is say my string grab the first character which is going to be 0 and then perform
the upper on it and just return that result.
OK that's all you have to do for that one.
Just again grabbing the first character and then calling the upper.
You could technically separate this out into two steps but you can also do it all in one step OK.
Moving along to task for this one wanted you to create a function that takes in a string and returns
the last two characters.
Now there was a stack overflow alink that give you a pretty good answer on how to actually grab characters
from the end more than just one character from the end.
So let's walk through how we could do this.
First we should be checking at the length the string is less than two.
So I'll say if length of my string is less than 2 return error else and this is where you could use
that stack overflow alink we're going to return my string starting index position negative to essentially
two steps back from the end colon all the way to the end.
So if you take a look at the stack overfilling it would have given you this sort of syntax.
So this isn't something we exactly covered in our string lecture but it is something you would be able
to figure out if you used this link.
OK.
Again just going back from the very end to spaces and then colon go all the way to the end.
So our starting position here is necklet to task number five was given a list of integers return true
is the sequence 1 2 3 is somewhere in the list.
So this one probably has the most variety of ways you can tackle this problem.
Lots of different ways to do it.
I'll show you one simple way.
So one way to do this is we can iterate through the list all the way up to the last two.
So we're going to say for I in range length of Nom's minus two
numbs of I is equal to 1 and number of I plus 1 is equal to 2 and Nom's of E-plus to is equal to three
then return true otherwise otherwise we'll just return false.
So let me zoom out here just we can kind of see what's going on.
So again what I'm doing here is going to say for every i in range length of Nom's minus two.
So what this is doing and I'll probably make more sense if we look at this line first let's imagine
what it is just going to be the index positions themselves.
So this for loop right here.
That's going to start at zero than 1 One two three and it's go all the way until the length of the list.
Minus two.
And often beginners get confused Well why not.
All the way to the length list why minus two.
And that's because those what we're doing in this line we're saying if none of AI is equal to 1.
So if in that list of numbers in addition is equal to 1 and the very next index to an AI plus one is
equal to two and then next to this and after that I plus two is equal to three.
Well then you have your match.
You're going to return true.
Now the trick is we're saying I plus 1 and I plus 2.
That means we only need to go in this range up to and minus 2.
We don't need to go all the way to the end of that list.
Otherwise I plus one and I plus two would be reaching out beyond the length of the list.
So that's why we say length of numbers minus two because we have I plus two and I plus 1.
So we don't need to go all the way to the end of the list and said we need to go to up to the analyst
because I plus 1 I plus two themselves will reach the end of the list and then if this happens to be
the case 1 2 and 3.
Well then you can just return true.
Then if you've gone through this entire four loop and you never returned to true then I'm just going
to return false.
So notice how my for loop is now indented at the same as it's return false.
OK.
There's lots of other ways you get done this sequence check.
Maybe you could have just done this as a single slice.
So Gone slice by slice and then check it to be the list.
One two three but I think this is the most kind of fundamental way of doing it.
Yes go throughout the list and then check three at a time separately and return true.
They happened to be the case.
The trick here being you have to go all the way to the end of the list.
You just have to go to the length of the list minus two because of this I plus one and I plus two OK.
Let's move on to task number six which was given two strings create a function that returns a length.
The difference in length between them.
This it's actually pretty straightforward if were able to figure out how to do an absolute value in
Python which in this case was just abs.
So first we take the length of string 1 which here we called S1 and then we subtract the length of S
2.
So this right here this gives you the difference in length between S1 and S2.
However if one is smaller than as two then you'll get a negative number.
So you're going to want to return the absolute value of this difference.
So then you just pass it into abs absolute value and then you just return that and that is your solution.
So we turn the absolute value between the difference of length of these two strings finally task number
seven given a list of integers is the length but the list is an even number.
Return the sum of that list is the length of the list is odd return the max value in that list.
So how can we do that.
Well we can say length is equal to length of my list.
And then we'll say the following.
If the length mod to is equal to zero.
Return the sum of the list else return the max of my list.
So all we're doing here is we're checking the length of that list saying if the length Mattu is equal
to zero then return the sum.
Otherwise just return the max of the list and that's the sum or max function.
Ok that's it for this lecture.
I hope you found the section useful if you're a beginner to Python.
Coming up next we're going to begin to discuss more advanced Python topics in Python level 2.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you there.