Welcome back to this lecture on bootstrap basics and buttons and this lecture.
We're going to discuss how to actually link your H T.M. to bootstrap C Ss and javascript files as well
as containers jumbo trons and buttons of bootstrap.
Let's get started.
We're going to have our browser open as well as our text editor.
OK so here I have a basic H.T. mail file and it's empty right now.
And they also have the get bootstrap documentation on the home page and another tablet's linked to the
to him file.
So let's go ahead and fill this in of some skeleton code.
H team.
Save it.
And in the body I'll have a heading one that says Hello world.
EXCLAMATION POINT we'll save this.
Refresh our browser and now see.
Hello world there.
Now let's see what happens when we actually connect the stage to himself to bootstrap.
We can do this easily by coming back to the home page scrolling down and you'll notice there's a link
for the CSSA here.
So let's grab this and let's make sure we get that closing tag as well go all the way to the left.
Copy that and I'm going to paste in inside of this head in between the open closing head tags.
I'm going to paste in that link for the stylesheet.
So that's the stylesheet that's being hosted online that are each HTML file will automatically connect
to and we can also do is copy and paste these other script lines.
And this basically connects to the javascript and Jay query so we can copy that and place that as well.
Not every component needs these scripts right here are these links to javascript but some components
that have a little bit more interactivity will need them.
So we'll make note of that when we actually need them or not.
Typically you just copy and paste all of them.
So I will save that and let's refresh our page and see what happens.
So part of being refreshed noticed that there's a couple of changes here now.
Or Hello world is in a different font.
And also the margins and kind of buffers around hello world have changed as well.
So we're going to do now is explore various class calls we can make with bootstrap What are the most
common class calls we are going to make is putting things in a container.
So often you're going to start a div and for the class you report back a container class and here is
where we can have a Heading 1 and we'll say hello world exclamation point.
Save that and this hello world you'll notice is inside this container which is going to automatically
set some margins to the left and to the right and it's actually smart to be responsive.
So as you begin to move your browser size maybe reviewing on a mobile device it can automatically set
the text to where it needs to be.
So it actually senses the size of the browser that it's being looked at.
OK.
Now we can also add in some buttons and we can do this with an HMO button that so create a button tag
here and we'll have the Type-B button and the name be button.
And right now in between the open and closing button tags I'm just going to type button so I can save
that in if I hit refresh here.
Now I see this nice button and nothing happens when I click on it.
But if we take a look back at bootstrap and go to the documentation and then click on the components
and Button section you should notice a bunch of examples for different buttons.
So pretty much by default there is different colorings for buttons such as a warning button or a danger
button and all you need to do is copy the class call to this.
So for instance the primary button this blue we can add that in as a class call inside of the button.
So say class copy and paste between space between primary save that and then coming back to our basic
page to him.
We're refresh.
Now you notice it's stylized as a primary button and there's lots of preexisting bootstrap templates
that can't affect the colors of these and you could always override with your own color classes as well.
So you can come down here and check out the other button tags.
You can do kind of outline buttons different sizes so let's say we want a large secondary button like
the one shown there.
I can copy that code come back here we can create another button.
And this button will just say large and let's pass in that class call so will copy and paste that in
between BT and secondary tan large save that and when it come back to basic it's HTML refresh.
Now I see that larger secondary color button is the main idea behind our use cases for bootstrap.
We're just going to come to the documentation.
Scroll down until we find the components we like.
Check out the examples see which ones you liked and then you can copy and paste the classes.
So there's ways to kind of disable the state of the button.
So here I can clearly click on them here when they're disabled.
I can't so it can copy and paste that as well.
And you can scroll down here and see the other toggle States.
So you're able to toggle buttons on and off essentially changing the color.
See if a has been checked or not etc..
So here we can see just a bunch of buttons.
So if you ever want to copy and play around of these.
All you need to do is click here on the copy of the clipboard.
Come back to each T.M. and you can put this inside of a new div save those changes come back here refresh.
And I see that example.
So we have these kind of active radio buttons there and something you should get really comfortable
with.
It's just come into documentation and looking for those components and copy and pasting and playing
around with a lot of these class calls.
The last thing I want to mention is the Jumbotron class.
So if you scroll down you can see an example of a here jumbotron and it's a lightweight flexible component
that really is kind of like a showcase message for your web site.
So I'm going to remove all of this here including the hello world and I'll create a new div and give
it the class Jumbotron.
And inside this DiVall say H-1 and say hello and welcome.
We'll see if those changes come back to basics or a smell to a refresh.
Now I see this nice background in gray.
Hello and welcome.
And often if you want to censor this way you can do is put this whole div inside of another div with
a container class.
So then we can grab this div with the Jumbotron stick that inside some container save it and when refresh.
Now we see it being contained to the center and it will adjust as we kind of expand or contract or browser
size.
So Jumbotron is something we're going to be using a lot more throughout the course and you can always
copy and paste these examples here so we can copy that paste it here so now I see there's a jumbotron
with some display classes some late classes save that will come back here refresh and you get to see
that example.
So it's up to you whether you want to put it in a container or not depends on what you want your website
to look like.
Main idea being you can always come to the bootstrap documentation and copy and paste from the examples
here and then adjust to the way you see necessary.
So if you don't want to say hello world who's come find the heading one and have it say something like
puppies are awesome.
Save that.
Refresh our page.
And now we see puppies are awesome.
OK.
So that's the very basics of using boot strap.
Coming up next we're going to briefly discuss bootstrap forms.
And after that we'll talk about Neph bars.
I'll see you there.