Welcome back.
Let's get started with flasks.
By going through a very simple Hello World site example we're going create our first website flask and
this is essentially the simplest site possible with a flask web framework.
We're simply going to just return a single string Hello puppy onto a web page just in case you have
installed the app.
Make sure you've either done Condon's flask or pitmen small flask at your command line.
Let's go through the code and then we'll jump to the text editor and actually write it out ourselves.
Here we see the code that we're going to be using to create our simple web page.
Let's go line by line and discuss the details of all this and then we'll head over to the text editor
and type it out.
So first off for saying from that flask package import the flask class.
So notice here the capitalization is very easy to make a typo there.
That flask class has upper case f the package itself is lowercase f.
Then we have this line.
We're saying app is equal to flask.
And we're passing an underscore underscore name underscore underscore.
Essentially what this line is doing is it's creating an application object over on the left hand side
as an instance of the class flask imported from the Flast package from the first line and the name variable
that's being passed into that flask class call.
That's a python pre-define a variable.
As we've previously talked about which is then set to the name of the module in which it is used essentially
answering the question Are we running this script that correctly and flask is able to use the location
of the module that we pass in as a starting point when it needs to load other resources or other files.
Those are things such as template files which were going to be discussing later on.
So once you've created that application where we can do is add pages to it and in this case let's jump
over past that route function or route decorator and go down here to where we see Death Index return.
Hello puppy.
What this function is doing is defining a page index with the function and then it's going to return
the string later on we're going to return the ability to actually render an entire template of HTML
code.
But it's that all we're doing right now is just returning a single string and it actually has h tim
l code in it.
It's saying hello Papy as a header one which means when we actually call that index page we're going
to return that string.
The browser is going to read that in as h HTML code and we should see help Papy in strong large bold
text.
Now the decorator above that function directly links that page to whatever route on your web application.
It should be at for instance right now we're just saying a single forward slash which is essentially
the same thing as your home page or your domain.
So if you're launching this site at WW I love puppies dot com then if you went to AILA politico.com
that single home page you would see.
Hello puppy.
Later on we're going to show you how you can add multiple pages through routing.
But right now all this is saying is with our application route to this your L and in this case since
it's a single slash.
This is your home page and then return back that function which is the index page and it returns back.
Hello puppy.
At the very end we have this line which as we've already discussed in the Python section where we say
if name is equal to main essentially if you're running the script then run your application and later
on also see how he can set debug equal to true inside of this run call.
So we can debug our application in real time if we're ever actually serving this to the Web and other
people are going to be using it.
You want to make sure you set debug equal to false which is the default.
So that's all the code.
Let's go ahead and go back to our text editor and type this out and see if it works.
Lori here I am at my desktop.
I'm have a flask underscore examples folder and underneath the folder I'm going to create a new file.
And I'm just going to call it basic dot PI.
You can technically call it whatever you want just do not call it flasks that pi.
Otherwise Python's going to confuse.
When you try to import things from flask.
So call it essentially anything you want that's not flasks of Pi.
OK so basic that pie.
And what I want to do now is say from flask import flask that I will create my flask application by
saying grab an instance of this flask class and then pass in my predefined name variable then when I'm
going to do is grab my application and I'm going to set a route.
And the first route is just going to be to the home page or the domain name.
So I just have a single forward slash later on I'll be more clear what this line is doing when we actually
link it to other pages in our application.
But right now this is just a single page application and below this we're going to have the function
that defines what is actually shown.
When you go to that specific route on your application in this case the home page and we're going to
return the string to the browser that says Hello puppy or whatever we want.
And it's going to be a better one.
And then finally here at the bottom we're going to say if name is equal to Main take my application
and run it I'm going to say this and let's run now this python script at our command line will call
Python basic thought pie.
And when you run this expand this just a little bit you should notice now it says running at HTP 1 2
7 0 0 0 1 5000.
If you're running multiple flask examples for instance you have multiple tabs open.
You may see this last four digit number change a little bit.
We're going to do is we're going to highlight this and copy it.
Be careful not to use Control-C copy because that actually quits the server and let's type this or paste
this into our browser and check it out.
I'm going to drag over my browser now.
Here it is.
And it says hello puppy.
So you can zoom in here and check out.
Hello puppy.
You should see it as a header one.
And if I right click and say view page source I get to see the actual source that I returned back H-1.
Hello puppy.
And as I mentioned later on we're actually going to pasan for HTML files to our flask application.
But notice here it's just at the home page of this local Your L or IP address we have.
Hello puppy.
All right.
That's the very basics.
You've now successfully ran your first flask application.
Not so bad.
Later on we're going to see how we can expand off of this to have multiple pages sync up if a database
have interactivity with users and so on.
But with just 10 lines of code and you already have a full application working great We'll see you in
the next lecture.