Welcome back to the basics lecture where we're going to do here is learn just the absolute basics of
an HTL file and how it's structured will create probably the simplest HVM else skeleton could possible
see what it looks like in our browser.
And then the next lecture will go much deeper into the actual tags than HTL file holds.
Right now let's head over to our text editor and explore how to create a basic HVM file.
Ok here I am at my Adam text editor.
First thing we need to do is actually create a new file.
So I will say file new file and when you first create a new file it's just untitled and actually contains
no file type.
So let's save this as an h tim file.
I'll save file save as an on my desktop.
I have a folder called flask underscore examples so I'm going to save it here.
Feel free to save it wherever you prefer on your actual desktop or computer C-Drive downloads anywhere
is fine.
So I will call this basic and then dot T.M..
So it's important to have that extension.
Aist him all that way.
Adam knows that it's actually working with NHT metafile and can perform syntax highlighting and autocomplete
as necessary.
So I will say this now as basic thought T.M. And now that it's an H team l file Adam actually comes
with a built in autocomplete for basic things like HTL.
And if you begin typing HVM l you'll notice that you get this little pop up HTL.
Once that happens you can enter here and it will auto fill the actual doc Skelton for an HTML file.
Well we're going to do here now is actually describe the main components and then we'll see what it
looks like in the browser.
This very first line this doctype tag that basically tells your browser as it reads in the file hey
this is an HMO file.
You should read the tags in a certain way and all the modern browsers understand that one line this
first line to say that and this should always be the first line in the HTML file.
Next we basically have a series of tags and tags are denoted by these open and closing tags marks or
sometimes they're also called greater than or less than marks.
And we have an html tag and then we have an HMO closing tag.
Usually you have an open tag and a closing tag.
You'll notice that the closing tag starts with a forward slash.
Keep in mind not every single tag needs to be closed.
We'll discuss that in more detail later on.
Now we have two main components of an HDMI file.
We have this head component and this body component this head component mainly contains the meta data
and the meta data are going to be things like linking to your CSSA files later on linking to your javascript
files and things of that nature.
So not a whole lot of code is going to go in the head.
Instead most of your HTML code is going to go inside the body.
You'll notice when we actually called L we got this title open tag and title close tag this title tag
is what appears inside of the tab.
Inside your browser.
So let's go out and check it out.
I'm going to type out.
This is the title and I need to save this so control s or command us.
Adam usually has an indicator whether it's been saved or not.
And then what I'm going to do is open this file inside of my browser.
You'll notice as you hover over your actual file you should get a full file path there.
Alternatively you can do is open up the side panel and then find your actual file.
Here you can find that as basic thought is HTML right click on it and then select Copy full path and
then once you have that full path copied to your clipboard go ahead and provide it to your browser.
So I'm going to bring in my browser here.
So I notice in my browser right now I just copied and pasted the full path.
So I'm directly pointing my browser.
This is Krome Internet browser to my local H.T. mail file.
And notice what it says and the tab it says this is the title so that corresponds with the title that
was shown here inside of this HTL file.
OK.
And then later on we're going to discuss how we can add things to the body.
Let's just go ahead and do a very simple script or very simple phrase essentially just add some text.
So we're going to add some text here in the body.
Notice how it's not tagged in any way.
That's OK for now.
I'm going to save those changes and then back in my browser if I hit refresh I now get to see add some
text.
So that's the very basics of an HTML file.
Again it has a heading component and then a body component the head component that's going to contain
metadata and links.
We'll discuss that in more detail later on.
And then the body that's basically going to contain the actual elements you see on the page things like
forms headers styles et cetera.
OK.
So we have had body in our basic h mail.
And next up we're going to discuss basic h him all tags.
We'll see what the next lecture.