Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to start off by talking about scope and also nested statements in general scope is the concept
that determines where you can actually see or access a variable and if you're jumping straight into
Python level too by now you probably actually already have an intuitive understanding of this idea of
scope.
But we're going to do is have a more formal discussion of this topic and show you some things that maybe
you haven't thought about yet.
So let's get started.
We're going to head over to the text editor and we're just going to do a couple of experiments to show
you this idea of scope more formally.
All right let's begin with a quick thought experiment.
I'm going to set a variable x equal to the string outside then I'll create a function further down called
report and report doesn't accept any arguments.
What it does is it sets X equal to inside and then it says return x.
So now the question is if I were to say prints X what would you expect to see.
Would you expect to see outside or inside.
Well this is where the idea of scope comes in basically scope comes into play when Python is asked to
the termine what type of variable you're referencing.
In this case Python wants to know what X you're referencing when you call 7 here.
So let's actually run this and see what happens.
Notice that it says outside which basically means that it's referring to the x over here x is equal
to outside instead of the re-assignment that's happening inside report.
Now you may already have some intuition at that because technically you're not actually calling report
to execute anywhere you've just define this function.
I haven't actually called it.
Now sometimes what's confusing for beginners is let's imagine I do call report.
So I have Report be executed.
In fact I say print's report.
So I'm going to print out report which should return x in this case it's inside.
And then going it prints X again.
Now what do you expect.
Do you expect to see inside outside or inside inside.
Well let's say this and find out.
So in this case we see inside and outside.
So the result of running a report does give you this re-assignment x is equal to inside.
But notice how it doesn't affect this global scope appear of exegetical to outside.
When you say print X without any reference to this function you'll still say outside.
So the whole reason this sort of thing is happening is because of scope.
So let's say discuss this idea of scope.
And in simple terms.
Basically the idea of scope can be described in three general rules.
One is that name assignments will create or change local names by default.
Two is that name references search at most for scopes.
So let's talk about these for scopes.
They're known as the LGB l e G-B rule.
And that stands for local inclosing global and built in.
So what's going to happen is Python is going to search in this order of scopes to try to figure out
what you're actually referencing.
So if it can't find something locally they'll start looking in the inclosing function.
If it can't find the reference and inclosing function will start looking globally at the module level.
Basically your entire Python script if it still can't find it then will start looking at builtin keywords
with Python such as the Eliane length function.
Now in order to actually build the understanding of each of these scopes.
Actually work through some examples of them.
I'm going to clear out this code right here.
And we'll come back to it later on.
For now let me show you an example of local and that's actually basically what we just did inside of
that function.
So I'm going to say report X equal to local.
So this is a local assignment
and then if I say print x x is going to be searched for first locally.
So right here at the local scope
melts take a look at this next scope which is called inclosing.
So this is an example of an inclosing function local.
So this first one this is a local assignment.
Now I want to check out inclosing.
So this is going to occur when you have a function inside of another function.
We have actually seen an example of this so far.
So let's try it out.
I'm going to say x is equal to a string.
This is global level and it's global level because it has no indentation and it's not within another
function and to show this I'm going to comets out our entire previous function.
So now this is the only life code inside of this python script.
So I'm saying X is a global level parameter or variable then I will say the F inclosing colon and I'll
say x is equal to.
And here I'm going to assign it inclosing level.
Then inside of my inclosing function ongoings create another function.
So notice here how this function is actually inside the enclosing function.
Take a look at my indentation carefully and then I'm going to print x and then I'm going to call inside.
So again take very careful attention of the actual indentation.
All of this code right here is within this inclosing function.
So what's happening here is I'm defining inclosing function.
I'm setting this variable x equal to the inclosing level.
Then I say this other function inside is going to print out X and then I'm actually going to call the
inside function to execute.
Which means when I call the inclosing function to x Q It says X defines inside and then executes inside.
So now here X I have this global level.
So now the question arises if that is further down in my script.
Let me get a little bit of space here.
Maybe you can actually see the indentation very clearly but if further down in my script script hour
to execute inclosing What do I expect to see.
Do I expect to see this is a global level or inclosing level.
Well let's think of the L EJB rule.
So in this case we're going to follow L E G B.
So we first look for something local roomer something local looks like this.
When the uncomment this so we can review this is a local assignment.
So X just looks locally.
See if find something at the same indentation level and there it is local.
So that's what Python wants to look for first.
So here we're saying Prince X and pythons.
OK.
Let me see if I can find something where x is defined locally and it looks for the entire inside function
and it can't find it.
It says.
All right.
So L is done.
Now it's time for me to search inclosing.
So the inclosing function is this entire function.
And then it can find right here x is equal to inclosing level.
So that's what it goes with.
It stops right there.
It no longer needs to jump up further and start looking for a global variable.
So if I were to save this and run it to make sure everything else commented out.
Let's run the script and there we see inclosing level as expected.
So this is no longer local.
Instead it's inclosing.
OK.
Now let's talk about the global level.
So I'm going to comment out this assignment here.
I'm going to save this again.
And remember the order that pi is going to look for it's going to say let me try to find something locally.
In this case it won't be able to find it.
Let me try to find something within the inclosing function actually commented out.
So I don't find it there.
So the next step is hey let me start looking for something at the global level basically with zero and
then Station.
And there we do see this global level variable.
So I'm going to save that run it.
And now I get back.
This is global level so we can clearly see here how Python is taking the steps of local inclosing global
and built in.
And in fact let's go ahead and show them all right now.
So let me make sure that's been answered correctly.
I'm going to say local here so let's run this again and whips I make sure my indentation is correct.
There we go run this again.
And now I see local so I can see there's a local level and if I were to comment that I'll save it and
run it again.
Then I see the inclosing level up here if I'm to comment that I'll save it and run it again.
Then I see the global level.
So hopefully this is a really clear picture of how Python is going.
Local inclosing and global.
Now let's say you can't find something in global.
It's going to then look for built in namespace.
And in this case these are the type of functions and keywords that you're actually already familiar
with things like length or some books or some or max those kinds of things.
So if it can't find it as a built in variable then it's just going to give you an error and say hey
X isn't defined.
So if we run this I'll say hey sorry name x is not the find.
Well maybe it won't be so apologetic but you get the idea.
The last thing I want to cover here is just local variables versus global variables.
We already understand scope in general how we go local inclosing global and builtin basically the order
that Python is going to search for variable definitions in.
But let's go back to the original example of the report.
So remember I'm going to delete everything here.
Remember we had something that said X outside and then we say for Port x is equal to inside and we return
X
and then I say go ahead and print out report for me.
When our toes run this notice I get back inside because right now we understand that it's going to look
locally for that scope first.
Now there may be times where you actually do want to change this particular value that is global.
So the question is Well how do I do that.
I actually reach out and tell Python Hey when I'm doing this x is equal to inside I actually want to
change this global variable as well in order to do that.
Use the global keyword.
Keep in mind you should be very careful with this and most Python users don't use the global keyword
often.
In fact it should be avoided because of how powerful it is.
Basically you could really easily reassign everything within a function within a script and kind of
screw yourself up so that's where you want to do this with great caution.
I will show you how it works.
So the way this works is the following manner.
I'm going to say x is equal to outside and then within my report I'm going to say Global X and this
basically tells Python Hey grab the global level x variable and then once it's done that then it's going
to reassign the global x.
So this is no longer just a local assignment.
It's actually telling Python Hey keyword global.
That means this X is going to reference this outside Global X and then when you say x is equal to the
inside you're going to return x.
So when we actually run this we won't see anything different occur.
We will still see inside what will be different is if we were to ask for Python to Prince X.
After calling that report function knows what happens.
Now I get inside inside.
If I were to remove that global call here so I'm still having x is equal to outside.
And now I'm just re-assigning locally.
When I save and run this that I see inside outside it's only when I call that global keyword that Python
basically now has permission to go into the global namespace.
Grab the x variable and do the re-assignment globally.
Until then you won't actually be able to affect the scope of this x variable and this function.
OK so that's the very basics of scopes.
Again the global keyword in general if you're starting to learn at this level of Python you should just
pretty much avoid it entirely.
Instead you should pass it in.
If you ever want to work with it.
So what I mean by that is if for some reason you do want to work with this outside a variable where
you can do is you can just pass it in report X and then say x is equal to inside return x.
And so you can say X here and then play around with it that way.
So here you'll notice we get inside and then we still get outside.
So this is a much safer way of doing any sort of reassignments while still having access to the initial
global.
So for example I could still say print x here and so I should see outside inside outside and there it
is outside inside outside.
OK if you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums.
Hopefully you start to really get a fundamental foundation to your already intuitive understanding of
scope.
Just from your lectures on functions in the next lecture we'll start talking about object oriented programming.
We'll see if.