Welcome back and this lecture we're going to talk about forms with bootstrap.
So we're going to quickly review how bootstrap can help make your forms look really good.
And for this lecture we're really just going to walk through the code and discuss the various class
calls instead of manually typing things out because what we've essentially done here is just copy and
paste it different form elements from the documentation into a single file.
So go ahead and open up part 2 underscore forms.
T.M. from the bootstrap folder.
Let's check it out.
In the text editor and also see how it appears in the browser.
OK here we have the actual file open in my HTL text editor and in my browser I have the documentation
page open to the forms component as well as in other times that's actually linked to this ASTM l file.
So as quickly walk through how bootstrap can make your forms look really good.
First off there's basically a fully updated form class system with bootstrap 4 that makes his forms
look really nice and you'll notice that even as you click one of these you'll begin to see like the
highlighting around the box.
You also get information that can pop up like we'll never share email if anyone else and you can edit
those for the message to display whatever you want or we can just remove that message entirely.
You can put in passwords example select and then you can have multiple selects as well an example text
area that you can resize.
Notice how these corners are a little more rounded.
And notice how I can only now resize up and down.
So that way the page isn't go too crazy since a normal text area box by itself with no class adjustments
you can resize it both width and height.
And typically they're just a little nicer to only have it height wise.
You can also upload files so choose a file and there's a message here.
You can also have radio buttons that check out a check out button and then you know submit.
And essentially this will just refresh the form in our case.
And if you want.
You can also check out the forms bootstrap documentation for various examples on all these form controls.
So what we've done is just we created a simple reference document for yourself in case you ever want
to add in any of these classes to your own forms.
And there is going to be stuff that we haven't really put into that actual reference to himself because
they're not as common.
So you can't have a range input if you want.
You can have a read only input plain text and so on.
So basically what we have here inside of our east him file or links to the bootstrap C S and Javascript.
Let's quickly go down and basically explain what we were seeing before.
So for email submissions the main idea that you have to be aware of is you're going to have to specify
type email and then you can say classes such as form text and text muted as well as giving this an ID
of email help and that will adjust was actually displayed.
So that this little small tag that directly links to what was displayed below the e-mail so we'll never
share e-mail for anyone else.
You know we can change this.
The thanks for your e-mail save those changes and we check it out again in the actual forum page upon
a refresh then we see that change of.
Thanks for your e-mail right here.
So again just various buttons and tags and elements you can adjust to your liking.
That's really what you're using bootstrapped for your copy and paste from the documentation and then
adjusting manually.
However you see fit.
You'll set passwords again.
We want to see these classes such as form control an example input password one for the ID dropdown
select again if we come back here we had this dropdown select option the class for that would be form
control and we also have IDs for example select one multiple select options.
We can see here we have another form control class and this option right here just saying multiple that
allows you to select multiple options.
So if I come here and I can hold shift or control to select more or de-select the one that's allowing
me to do that is this multiple call inside that class then we have the text area.
This one again you're gonna want to say form control as your class and you can also give it a div for
forum group Lotus notice these other ones also have their own divs and that's really common.
You give a div for every single form component.
Then we also file upload and inputs as well as radio buttons.
You can check out the various classes.
A lot of these tend to be very similar things like form text and text meated and form check input.
Those are very similar classes you're going to see throughout many form input calls.
And then finally at the bottom we had those radio buttons as well.
Again form check input class and form check input class as well.
OK.
So that's just a very brief showing of what's possible.
Making these forms look really nice they look a lot better than what's available if bootstrap.
In fact we can always check what it would look like without bootstrap by scrolling all the way back
to the top.
We can just delete these save that change and if we refresh our page here this is what it would look
like without any bootstraps and notice all the formatting that Bitstrips actually taking care of for
you.
So it looks way worse then without bootstrap.
So if we undo this again save this refresh the page.
This is what it looks like with bootstrap a huge difference and it's going to save you a ton of time.
It is really important when you want the Web sites to look really good on mobile devices as well.
Again something to notice about bootstrap.
It's constantly going to readjust depending on what the browser size is.
So that means going to look good regardless of your monitor size or regardless of your actual phone
browser.
OK.
I hope you enjoyed that.
I hope you find that useful.
Again the main thing I really want you to take care of here is the fact that you can go to documentation
look at the components you want paste them into your T.M. see the class calls there and adjust as you
see necessary.
Coming up next we're going to learn about nav bars.
We're definitely going to be a little more hands on there because we're going to be using nav bars all
the time with our own Web sites.
We'll see you there.