Welcome back everyone.
We're going to continue working on our project by setting up some core views.
Those are the views for kind of the home page and also set up some basic templates including our base
HVM our file.
Let's head back over to our project text editor.
All right here we have the apple pie file we were setting up before.
We're going to now head over to our core page.
So remember we have this core with in it and views and we're going to set up those views and then link
them to some templates.
So to begin with we're going to do is start off by opening our views up py file.
So again to make it clear this is under core views not pie.
And what I'm going to be doing is saying from flask in poor render template request and we're going
to be setting up a blueprints and zoom out just a little bit here.
And I'm also going to import blueprints then we're going to say core is equal to blueprints and we'll
say core as the name of this blueprint and then will pass in the underscore underscore name underscore
underscore.
So if you want to review how blueprints work you can check out the structuring larger flask Applications
section of the course so we'll start setting up our routes will say core routes.
And this is just going to point to the main page.
So we'll call this our index view and here we're going to return render a template and we'll say indexed
each T.M..
Now later on we're going to be passing in a list of blog posts but we haven't set up our blog posts
models so we'll just pass an index h team L here.
So there's still more to come.
So keep that in mind because remember when we were first viewing that home page it has a list of all
the blog posts available right now just going to kind of be a very basic home page and then we'll see
at core route.
And let's go ahead and make an info page so this will just be general information about the company
and we'll call this view info than other info we're going to do is just say return render templates
and this will point to a template called info H.T. mail and then go ahead and save that.
So underneath templates what I'm going to do is I'm going to start off by creating a base HVM l file.
So this is our base h t m l file.
So I'm going to say T.M. enter for it to autocomplete.
Make sure it's save this nature html file in order to get that autocomplete and inside of the head.
I'm going to copy and paste the links from the bootstrap documentation that we've done many times before.
So right here inside the head and a copy and paste.
So my style sheets as well as the J query code and the bootstrap CD ends.
So we have these links from the bootstrap documentation and then in the body.
What are you going to do is set up my navigation bar.
So this navigation bar it's going to show up at the top of the web page.
And right now are just going to set it as an unordered list for the first thing and we'll say class
is equal to NAV so we can link it to a navigation bar.
And there's lots of different ways you can do this kind of the most basic way to set up a navigation
bar.
You can always check out the bootstrap documentation for like a dark navigation bar.
What's wider.
And so on but it's unordered lists.
We're not going to say ally and each list item will say class is now of that link and then inside of
this or are going to do is have an anchor that's going to link to another part of the page.
So for instance right now we can say A.F. And here we can say that home its breath is going to be your
L underscore 4 and here will just link it to core index.
So that's going to have a text saying home on the navigation bar that links back to the actual core
index page or over we say core because we're using that blueprint.
We don't just say index.
OK.
So this is essentially what every single navigationally item is going to look like.
So let's add one more for that info.
All say info here and then type in info or we can even say about.
So like about the company and then we're going to add in some more links that are actually not going
to be functional first but just go ahead and say the breath is a single hash tag.
So that basically means it's empty.
And these are going to be our log in log out views.
So we're going to create those right now but we're not actually going to use them yet.
So we'll say we're going to need of you to log out as a user and then we're also going to when a user
is locked in have them be able to view their own account and then we'll also want them to be able to
create a post again notice right now.
These traps are essentially blank.
So we're also be later on adding in some logic to check for users authenticated.
But we haven't really introduced those yet.
So we're kind of building this out slowly.
OK.
So we have our log out account and create post and then we'll go ahead and create the other links that
we want which is a log link.
So we'll say log in.
And another one if they're not logged in they may want to register as an user.
So I will say register.
There we go.
So there are an ordered list ready to go.
The last thing I want to do is set up a container division so I'll say class container and that kind
of fits everything center middle and then this is where we'll start off and create our block and will
color block content.
OK.
So we did quite a bit of stuff right here in our base HTL.
Let's zoom out so we can get the basic understanding of it all we did really was we did or bootstrap
imports.
And then inside the body was set up our navigation bar right now has a link for everything.
Typically we were actually running this Web site we're not going to want to show log out log in and
register all at once.
We'll only want to show certain things that pending If the user has been authenticated or not.
So later on we'll be adding in some logic when we actually create users.
But right now he created this navigation bar so it saved those changes and we're going to create two
more views.
One is the index page view and the other one is the information page.
So underneath the templates we're going to say a new file.
So let's say that in New File under these templates and we'll say indexed the HTL.
So here's our extended C.M..
We're going to say it extends from base the each T.M..
So now has that nice navigation bar and this one.
We say block contents.
And here I'm just going to create a jumbotron.
So that's a type of component from Bootstrap elysée H-1 puppy company blog.
So essentially the welcome page for that.
So that's all it's going to have for now.
Later on we'll see that we're going to add in logic to actually display the blog post but we'll need
to do some more views in order for that to work.
And after that we'll go ahead and set up our info that each team.
So I'll say new file info.
HMO and again for this we're going to extend from that baseline HTL file and then we're going to set
up our block content.
And here let's have this be a Jumbotron as well.
So say Jumbotron H-1 info about our company and then is going to create some Lorem Ipsum here instead
of a paragraph type so just type in the entry that paragraph tag.
And then if you start typing out Lorem you should be able to then enter lorem ipsum.
And this is just some kind of nonsense Latin characters are words in order to have us fill some space.
OK.
So let's go ahead and mix this all actually connected in order to do that we need to make sure we registered
that blueprint.
So remember back in core we have this blueprint for core what I need to do is now register that inside
my in it PI file in order for it to successfully connect.
So what I'm going to do is come to it by Rimmer's puppy company blog and at that pie.
And what I will be doing here is saying from puppy company blog that core views import core.
So now that important core because remember in views that pie here we have this core blueprint so I've
imported that here that's that blueprint.
Now you just need to register it.
So I'm going to say take the app and register the blueprint of Core.
OK.
So we're going to be doing this for the users the blog posts and the error pages.
But right now we're just registering one single blueprint.
So let's save that as well.
And now that should be able to link to our overall app thought pie.
So let's look at the main components again before we actually run this.
We have our views that we created we created a core blueprint and routed that using the index and info
pages and those views are now linked to these template files along with this base h team L.
And then we are in it PI registered that blueprint.
So let's run this and see how it works.
Well say Python app that PI enter to run it looks like it's running.
So let's bring in a browser so we can check it out and your web site should now look something like
this.
Let me zoom in just a little bit.
Notice we have this navigation bar we have a home about the log out account create post log in and register.
All of these are not going to be viewable at the end.
We'll only view some of them depending if they're locked in or not.
But right now if you click on any of the later ones you shouldn't see any links in the only ones that
will work or the home which will basically refresh this.
And then if you click on About It will take you to this info about our company.
OK.
So we've set up our core views.
We're still going to work a lot more on this home page in order to list out the blog post.
But so far we set up our core blueprint which is a big step forward as far as setting up the components
coming up next we're going to continue to build off this project by beginning to set up our users and
blog posts and seeing how those models will work for each other.
We'll see you at the next lecture.