Welcome back to this lecture on basic tagging with H T.M. the main components of any web site are defined
by him elements and every element is going to have a corresponding tag inside the actual h HTML file.
We're going to start learning about those basic tags that are available to us in the previous lecture.
We saw a title tag which is one of the most basic tags that already comes in that skeleton when typing
HTL.
Now discovered heading tags and how we can add in paragraph tags.
Let's head over to the text editor Henri here I have my text editor open to that basic HTL file from
the previous lecture as well as my browser open directly connected to this basic each team a file with
the file path.
I'm going to zoom into my browser a little bit so you can clearly see the changes that I'm going to
do my basic HTL file the first types of element tags I want to show you were actually going to put inside
the body.
Notice that if we just add some text will see some text appear inside of the browser but there are also
heading tags H-1.
And if you begin to type H-1 you'll be able to enter and they will auto complete both the opening tag
and the closing tag and any text in between these two heading one tags is going to be bold and larger.
So I can say this is heading one.
I will save this and then refresh my page over here.
And now you get to see this heading 1 font.
Keep in mind I'm very zoomed in to my browser so the effects in size are going to be a little distorted.
However when you're following along you see the effects quite clearly now just says we have a heading
1 we also have smaller sizes of headings.
So there's a heading to type that out save or changes refresh the browser.
And now I see a slightly smaller heading and as you may have guessed if I keep going down there's heading
three so H-3 we can have the autocomplete.
I have my heading three tag and then if I saved this and refreshed my changes.
Now I get to see a smaller heading and this actually goes all the way to heading 6 so we'll skip four
and five.
You can type in heading 6 save this and if you refresh you'll see a bold but smaller versus Heading
1 2 and 3.
OK.
So those are heading tags.
And most commonly we'll be using Heading 1 and heading 2 and those are for font that you want to appear
just large and bold on the page.
And later on in the CSSA section of course we'll also discuss how to add in your own custom fonts.
Now let's imagine we have just a bunch of untagged text that is actually tagged in between two tag elements.
So here are some text and then I'll add some more spaces more text.
Add a lot more spaces and say even more text save this.
Now a lot of times people will expect these sort of spaces to actually show up inside of our Web page.
The one to refresh this I see here is some text more text and even more text.
And in fact these spaces aren't going to actually register unless you use proper tags.
So the way you can actually create separation is through the use of what's known as a paragraph tag.
So I will delete these and the paragraph tag it's just a simple tag.
So if you begin to type P and then hit enter.
You'll get the paragraph tag.
So it can say here is some text and then inside of another paragraph tag I'll say even more text
save those changes.
And then when I refresh this you'll see now I actually have a break I say here are some text.
There's a break and then even more text.
If I didn't want to break then all I would have to do is grab even more text and put it all together
inside that same paragraph tag again.
This is known as a paragraph tag and it's just a simple P and then we refresh.
Now we get to see everything.
I'm really zoomed in here so you'll see the effects a lot more pronounced.
So if I Reesa here this is what it would normally look like on your browser as a quick note.
You'll often want to just generate a bunch of text as you're messing around for your test sites.
The way to do that is if you just start typing Lorem you'll get this Lorem Ipsum hit enter and then
select it and you'll get just a bunch of text that is known as Loar some text.
This is filler text that will quickly create a filler paragraph of just Latin text that it's meaningless.
So if you're fresh just now inside of our browser I can see what's known as larm if some text.
This is just a quick way of quickly filling out large bundles of text for you to test out your Web site.
Then finally I want to talk about inline tags.
So here we have tags that basically have a start.
All the information and then a stop or closing tag inline tags actually allows two tags inside of other
tags.
So let's create in paragraph 10.
And here will say new semantics and let's say strong and emphasis.
So if I saved this and refreshed my page I see new semantics strong and emphasis.
Sometimes you're going to want to make things appear bold or you want to make things appear in a tablet.
So in order to do this I'm going to wrap this strong text inside of a strong tag.
So I'm going to create some more space for myself and if I begin typing out strong you should see a
strong tag eventually form for yourself so you can select that and then we have these inline tags strong
and then closing strong.
Anything inside of this.
So just put the text inside will end up looking bold inside of your browser.
So if you refresh now I see bulled inside.
So let's go ahead and make that strong text strong.
So say inside strong Savir changes refresh and they should see how.
Inside strong is not bold.
And we can do the same thing for italics or emphasis.
The way we do that is we use the E and tags so emphasis and now automatically create open inclosing
E-M tags for us.
We will grab emphasis here and let's say inside emphasis.
Save it and now it does.
In-between these inline emphasize tags.
If I save and refresh notice now inside emphasis is now going to be in its hallux.
So these are inline tags because typically they're going to be in line with some other major component
like the paragraph.
All right.
That's really all we need to know about basic tagging.
As a quick note there there's actually really useful resources online for basic tagging.
One of them is the Mozilla Foundation's documentation for basic elements.
There's a link to it inside of this lecture file that corresponds with what we just did here in this
video but on screen over my browser right now it's a developer that Mozilla dot org and we have docs
for web h him l n elements and Lotusphere it is a full reference for all the HTML elements possible
so we have Area article buttons canvasses details and so on.
You can see here that there is a ton of elements on the site.
We definitely don't need to know all these.
We're just going to go through the basic ones in this H.T. mail crash course but if you ever have questions
on one you can always come here.
Search for the one you're looking for.
For example I can see that there's a paragraph here.
So if I click on that will take me to the paragraph element and begin to describe what it does.
So talk about taggle missions permitted parents the attributes.
It's really nice as it has several examples here and it shows you the actual result.
Here we can see how that paragraph is actually enabling the breaking of the text so we have the first
paragraph wrapped in between these two p times in the second paragraph wrap inside another set of p
tags.
So when you actually run this you see a first paragraph and a second paragraph.
And what's really cool is you can open this up in a site called Code pen which will basically allow
you to play around with this inside your browser.
So if you're just on a mobile device you can go ahead.
This right here save it and you'll see the changes being uploaded.
Sometimes asks you you can just say save is anonymous and then play around with the files.
Ok we'll discuss code Penda IO in more detail later on.
There's also G-S fiddle which is another Web site where you can write H-2 him all code inside your browser.
All right so that's it for this lecture.
Again we just covered basic tagging.
Up next we're going to cover some more topics such as lists.
We'll see either.