Welcome back everyone to this lecture on numbers.
As you previously mentioned there's two main number types in Python that we're going to be working with.
And those are integers which are whole numbers and floating point numbers which are numbers of a decimal
point.
Let's explore just basic math with Python how we can treat Python as a calculator.
And then after that for the second half of this lecture we're going to discuss and explore how we can
create variables and assign them values.
So let's head over to the text editor.
All right.
Open up Adam.
I have an untitled file here.
I need to say this as a PI file in order for Adam to understand it it's a python script so I can run
it.
So try this out in a say file then select Save As and underneath my desk top flask examples what I'm
going to do is just say this as my example.
Pi Pi is the extension for python files.
Ok so now I see my example that pi and I'm going to quickly write some code here prince which will actually
display the output of something if I don't have print.
That means when I run the dot PI file I mean that see the output.
So let's say it prints hello world.
So that's a string which you're going to get on later.
But for right now just go ahead and say print open print sees either single or double quotes and then
hello world.
Single or double quotes make sure they match and then print CS OK.
And then over here at the bottom I'm going to open up a new terminal.
If you don't have this ability to open up a new terminal go back and check out our installation lecture
and set up lecture.
We cover the installation of python and adding this terminal to Adam there.
OK.
So make sure you're in the same location right here at your command line as you originally were.
When you say the file so under-class examples my file is there in order to run this all I need to do
is say Python space and then the name of the file.
In my case it's called My example the PI I hit enter and now as the output I should see whatever it
was printing.
Hello world.
OK.
Perfect.
If you have any issues again not seeing this little plus button in the lower left hand corner or maybe
you haven't set up python yet go back to the very beginning check up our installation and setup lecture.
We cover all that stuff and we actually have a time set for you so you can head forward in that video
and check it all out.
OK.
With that being said and it's discussed now it's just very basic Python essentially how to do very basic
math.
So for example if we ever want to do addition and for this I'm actually going to zoom in a lot more.
There we go.
And let me clear my screen.
OK.
So if I ever want to do math such as Ed. I can say two plus one.
So if I run that I get back three.
If you ever want to do division that's going to be one forward slash to if you save that and you were
to run that you'd get back 0.5.
Notice how this is now a floating point even though these two were integers.
And then we can also do subtraction.
So one minus two that should give us a negative one.
And there it is negative 1 is the output multiplication is an asterix.
So we can say it 1 times 3.
Or let's say three times three.
So it's more obvious.
So we'll save that three times three and we get back 9 as a result.
So it makes sense.
Keep in mind that if I didn't have the print statement here and I just said three times three and I
tried to run this it would have no problem running it you just wouldn't see the output.
So again in order to see the output we should be printing things so Prince overprint sees whatever the
thing is and then enclose princes division we already went over.
If you ever want to do something to the power for instance if I want to do that power three it's just
to Asterix in a row.
So two to the power of three I save that I run that it's going to be two times two times two.
So in that case it's eight.
And the last thing I want to mention here is the order of operations actually followed by Python.
So I get to do that through an example.
I'll say two plus ten times ten plus three.
So Python is going to follow your standard order of operations which means multiplication here is going
to happen first before this addition.
So when I run this it's going to say OK ten times ten is one hundred.
And then it's going to add them all up.
So two plus 100 plus three which is 1 0 5.
But let's imagine.
I want to add this number first and then add these two numbers first and then multiply that result.
Well I use parentheses to actually dictate the order of operations I want so I can wrap these in parentheses
just like you would for normal math.
Let's wrap these guys in princes and then we were going to add one more set of princes because that's
outside that a prince is for Prince.
So now I'm going to say OK add two plus 10 first then add templates 3 and then multiply these guys for
the result.
So I say run it and I get back 156 this time.
OK.
That should have been a very straight for and pretty basic.
It's just how to do basic arithmetic with python.
A lot of it been pretty intuitive.
Now let's talk about variable assignments.
OK let's take a quick dive into variable assignments in Python.
So we just saw how to work with numbers but often we're asking ourselves well what do these numbers
actually represent.
I'm just writing two or three will to of one or three of what is actually a pretty nice if I could assign
these data types a variable name that I can easily reference them later on in our code.
For example instead of just having to I could say the variable my underscore dogs is equal to two.
And then I could reference that variable name.
My dogs throughout my script now there are a couple of rules for choosing a variable name variable names
that cannot start a number.
There can also be no spaces in the name.
Instead you should use an underscore and you can't use any of these special symbols such as an exclamation
mark or question mark or a dollar sign.
So none of those symbols are allowed.
Essentially you just be using lower case letters and then underscore and you can also use numbers as
long as they're not the first letter or character in the variable name.
Now there's also best practices for variable names and this is known as pep 8.
So in general it's considered best practice that the names are all lowercase.
It'll still work even if they're not lowercase.
It's just a convention so that when you're reading someone else's code or someone else is reading your
code it follows the same sort of basic convention or best practice.
You should also avoid using words that have a special meaning in Python such as list or as TR.
Often there are built in variables that are already used within Python and will be going through them
throughout the course but a very common on that beginners often mistake is using list.
So don't use that as a variable name because it's actually already built into Python.
The last thing I want to mention is that Python actually uses dynamic typing.
This means you can reassign variables to different data types and this makes Python very flexible in
assigning data types and it's actually different than other languages that are what is known as statically
typed.
So let me quickly show you the difference between statically typed and dynamic typed.
So let's imagine somewhere in my Python script maybe at the top I say my underscore dogs is equal to
two.
And then there's a bunch of code and then later at the end I say all right same variable name my underscore
dog is not equal to what is known as a list of Samie and Franki.
Python isn't going to complain that you suddenly change an integer into a list.
That's totally OK in Python.
You don't have to specify beforehand what my dogs was going to be.
You'd have to say OK this is going to be integer or this is going to be a list.
That's not always the case in other programming languages.
So this is known as they Nemec typing in Python.
It makes it really easy to code things really fast but it also leaves the potential for mistakes to
be done.
So just keep that in mind there is a tradeoff here.
So again that can produce an error in other languages.
So something that was statically typed for example to C++ you'd have to add the clear first integer.
My dog is equal to one semi-colon.
And then if you try to reassign my dog to something that wasn't an integer that would result in an error.
So that's called static typing.
However again Python doesn't use static typing Toney's dynamic typing which is why it's so popular for
beginners and it's easy to learn.
So again the pros of dynamic typing it's very easy to work with has faster development time.
The cons of dynamic typing.
It may result in bugs for unexpected data types.
They need to be aware of that type.
All you need to do is use that builtin type function which will go over in future lectures.
OK so let's get an idea of all of this together by jumping over back to the Adam text editor and going
through a couple of more examples.
Ok here I am again at my example that PI.
I'm going to delete this print statement save that change and when to clear out my terminal here.
OK so the first thing going to do is just do an assignment.
So say a is equal to the number 10 and then I can print out a.
Let's save that.
And when I run this I get back 10.
So now I have high.
I've assigned the variable a to the number 10.
Now it's really interesting as I can actually use a to read the fine.
So then later on in my code what I could say is OK now am going to be equal to a plus a.
So what does that actually mean.
It means a starts off as 10 and then you're going to reassign it to be equal to a plus a.
So then you would expect when you print out a after that to get 20 because 10 plus 10 is 20 which is
what happened exactly when and run it.
Now you get back 20 as the output.
OK let's show you a more realistic example because you won't just be using variable names like this.
Let's imagine that we just had a bunch of puppies born so let's say six puppies were born.
So we'll say puppies is equal to six.
And each of them weighs two pounds which I'm actually not sure if that's a lot or a little for a puppy
but hopefully bear with me here.
So two pounds per puppy.
Now the question is what's the total weight of all the puppies.
Well now I can use variable names to easily find this in a very readable way.
I'll just say something like total Ezekial to puppies times and then I'll just print out the totals
to report that.
So say that again.
All I'm doing here is variable assignments and then I'm working the variables of the same arithmetic
I was working with numbers when I run this.
Now I get back the result six times two which is 12.
So now my total is assigned to 12.
OK.
So we just learned some of the basics of numbers and arithmetic and also how we can create what are
essentially labels for all these data types through the use of variable assignments.
Hopefully this was pretty intuitive and pretty straightforward but if you have any questions feel free
to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.