Welcome back.
We just saw how we can connect our template to our flask Python script through the use of ginger templating
by actually inserting those Python variables into our HTL.
Now it's a template in the way we actually passed in those variables was using that double set of curly
braces syntax.
Read then just put the variable name inside of those double braces.
We also have access to is control flow syntax in our templates and those can be things.
So just for loops and if statements that actually take place in the template that is the same file.
And for those sort of more control flow like statements that are not just variables you use a slightly
different syntax.
It's a curly brace.
And then percent signs.
Let's quickly explain things samples so it's a little more clear.
Let's imagine that you passed an A list variable to the H team l using template variables like we just
did in the previous lecture.
So far we've just displayed the entire list including the commas and those square braces instead of
displaying that entire list at once.
We can actually do is use our knowledge table to display each item in the Python list as a bulleted
HVM elist and the code to do that on the template side would look something like this.
Let's walk through each of these major components.
First notice what we're doing here.
H T.M. we're creating an unordered list isn't that you Eltang.
And then we have an el Itek for an actual list item.
And what we're doing here is we're combining both the template variable syntax and the template control
flow syntax.
So we have a for loop at the very top and what we're doing is in the flask app that PI script or that
view function is where passing my list variable to the actual html template and then inside of the template
we get to create a for loop and we say for item in my list which is essentially saying for every variable
in that my list object passed into the HTL template then you get to make a list or NHT item point with
the item.
And so that's what this connection is for every item or variable and you could actually choose the name
of that variable in my list then make a bulleted point in each T.M..
Notice that we also have to do here we have to say and for which we didn't have to do a python.
But in this case we do have to do this with the template control flow syntax and also keep in mind the
differences between the actual syntax for a variable in your templates versus control flow logic and
your templates for the control flow logic statements.
We see that it's a Crilley brace of a percent sign for the variables we see it's two sets of curly braces
OK let's play around this with some more examples.
And I think this will begin to make the idea more clear to you.
Let's hop over toward a text editor a here am my text editor.
So far I just have a very basic Flash application connected to a very basic h m l file.
I've said from class import flask and run the template I set up my flask application.
I have my index or home page just saying Return basic HTL and then I run in debug mode.
If we take a look at this basic 30 S.M. underneath a folder called templates.
I had this HDMI file and all it really is if you ignore what's in the head here it's just a head or
one that says Web site.
Let's run this and make sure we see web site when we get this.
So we'll say Python is up PI.
Let me expand this a little bit.
Looks like it's running.
Let me bring that over and all you should see is this Web site in your actual browser.
What I'm going to do now is start by sending over a template variable into my web page what I will do
here is create a list so say my list is equal to.
And here we're going say one two three four or five then I'm going to save that and then I will pass
in a variable called my list and said equal to my list.
So I have this parameter my list and getting equal to my list over here.
And this is what you're going to do most often set this variable name same as parameter name.
Then back in our html file We're going to say instead of web site since we're dealing with a variable
we set two sets of curly braces there and then I pass in my list.
So this my list needs to match the parameter.
OK so I'm going say this and then let's go back to each HTML file.
Or excuse me our browser.
Once you refresh this you'd say you should see the entire list here.
One two three four five.
So this is returning that entire Python variable which is a python list.
So you see that square bracket and then the commas themselves.
What I want to do is take advantage of control flow to actually use HTL in combination with this python
variable that I'm sending over to the template.
So what it will do is the following.
I actually don't need to change anything in my py file.
Instead I want I'm going to do is come back to basic values T.M..
And here is where I'm going to introduce some control flow.
So let's delete this right now.
I have an empty body and I will do is the following.
I'm going to create an unordered list and then I will create 4.
And if you've downloaded that flask add on or plugin you should be able to say for and it will automatically
create something that looks like this for you for element in collection.
Right now I'm just going to manually type this out just so we can see it clearly.
I'm going to set my curly braces and then two sets percent science and say for item in my list.
I'm going to create a list item here.
And that's a variable Selsey item and then with every four you need to also say and for.
So that's what makes it a little different than just normal Python to declare and for.
So what I'm going to say here is for every item in my list object that I send back member that my list
object that's 1 2 3 4 5 then I'm going to make that into an HMO list in an unordered list.
So if I save this and then refresh my page and I bring it over.
Now you should see something that looks like this.
And look at them side by side.
I'm saying for every item in my list go ahead and create a new list item inside of the HTL an ordered
list and then end the for loop.
Notice also where I am ending the for loop and then the for loop inside of this an ordered list.
And in fact all of the control flow is going inside of this unordered list.
I want to make sure that because I don't want to terminate the unordered list before I'm done with my
for loop I also want to point out that technically this variable name of item that can be whatever you
want just like a normal Python for loop.
So I could say something like jelly.
So for jelly in my list say jelly.
Save that and that will give you the exact same result as before.
Usually what you want to do is choose a variable name that actually makes sense maybe number because
I had numbers on my list.
So it's a number in my list go ahead and create a list item of a number.
All right.
So we're going to do now is show you how you can add an if statement to this.
We'll go ahead and keep right now.
Just a basic list that we're sending back but let's make it a little more realistic.
We'll say puppies and let's create a list of puppy names I'll say fluffy capital F Rufus of capital
R and then Spike capital S.
So I'm going to send back puppies.
So we'll say puppies is equal to puppies.
Save that.
Come back to the basic h T.M..
And since my list doesn't exist anymore we'll do the following.
We'll say for let's say pup in puppies.
Make a list item pup and then I'm going to save that.
Then we'll refresh my browser.
Bring it back over and I could see Fluffy Rufus and Spike.
So I have all the names of my actual puppies.
Now I'll show you how you can use an if statement through template control flow.
What I will do is now outside of an ordered list I'm going to introduce a little bit of logic.
We're going to say
the string Rufus is and puppies.
All creates a paragraph element say songy rufous and notice here.
Specifically saying string in the puppy's list.
So this is much more pythonic.
And then I can also have an L statement which is just.
Else
then I'll say
rufous is not in this list.
And then just like we had to say and for we need to say and if so I'll say and if.
All right so notice the logic we have here was saying if rufous in that puppy's list say we found rufous
else we're going to have this HTL paragraph that roof Rufus not on this list.
And when I save this I should expect to see found your rufous because Rufus was in that list of puppy
names.
So going to bring back my browser.
Let me refresh it.
And then it says found you rufous.
OK.
So that's an example of an IF statement that's also taking into account that list variable that you
passed in.
So when will this be useful in real life.
Well let's show you a really common example.
When we come back to my flat out pi application and let's imagine there's a bunch of code that at the
end of all this we have something like user
logged in and we're going to set the sequel to true because somewhere in our code let's imagine we have
lots of code here.
Then we decided that the user was logged into the Web site.
So he said true.
So we can actually pass that in as a variable.
So say user logged in is equal to user log then save that and then back to each HTML file.
Let's go ahead and see all this in the body and do the following.
And this is a really common and really realistic showing of what you would use the sexual template control
flow will say if UPS suits me.
If user logged in Notice I'm not saying if user logged in equal to true because he's reluctant or expected
to be able insole say if this is true then I will say welcome back.
You are now locked in else that means that person's not logged in.
So I'll say something like Please log in.
So this is a very realistic example of the kind of logic you're going to be using with your template
flow thing.
Always remember if you're using control flow logic you need to end it.
So the last thing you need to put in here is and if it's always easy to forget these and ifs and fours
because we're used to Python where we don't have to do it when you come back to Jinja templating you
do have to say and if in and for.
Just keep that in mind.
It's also really easy to forget to save things that happens to me often I'll forget to hit save and
then I go to my browser and I'm wondering why is this not updating because everything is correct here.
So if ever in doubt just do a quick command or control ask to save it.
Let's come back to our Web site so kind of back to our Web site.
It should say welcome back.
You are now logged in because remember we sent over on our Alaska application user log in is equal to
true.
Let's not set this to false and then say this again and now refresh the page it says Please log in.
All right that's the very basics of using template control flow.
The main thing to remember is you have the ability to create a for loop and you have the ability to
do if statements and there's more complex it's happening that we're going to see later on.
There's also things like Aliff statements just like in normal Python.
So we can say something like Elif and maybe some other condition that we pasan and so on we can have
more templates and more stuff.
So we'll say something like paragraph use case number two or whatever.
All right.
So that's really all there is to it.
You have this control flow logic for loops and if statements later on we'll see some more examples of
this.
But right now you should not feel comfortable being able to pasan not just a template variable but also
then using basic control flow logic in your templates.
We'll see what the next lecture where we continue our discussion on templates with flask.