Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to talk up past word hashing.
When you say has user authentication capabilities you're going to need to store their usernames and
passwords for security purposes.
You're never going to want to store the raw text of the actual password because if your servers ever
become compromised that means whoever Perhaps you would have the ability to read a person's password
in the raw text format.
Instead you want to secure it using hashing.
So we can use a hash function to help us with this.
Basically in a very simple terms a hash function is an algorithm that can take in a document.
In our case it's just going to be the password and return back a secure hash.
Digest so it's secure because just given the hash a person cannot determine what the original password
was.
For example let's imagine a very simple and also insecure hash function.
So this is just to get the idea of how a hash function works.
This is a one way hash function ought to make it clear that this is a very simple hash function.
And we're not going to use something this simple.
For our example the hash function is just going to count the number of letters in a password and store
that as the hash.
For example if we provided the password my password as our string what we would do is pass through our
hash function.
In this case we just count the number of letters and that equals 10.
So then we store that hash.
Now if in some instance our systems became compromised the hacker would only see the number 10 stored
on our servers.
Given that number 10 you wouldn't be able to determine what the original password was.
Now this hash function has issues because the same password could come out with the same hash cryptographically
secure hash algorithms will give a unique hash code for any entry provided.
So there's already cryptographically secure hashing algorithms and libraries for us to use.
You should never really write your own unless you're a professor of mathematics and you already know
about this stuff.
So what we're going to do is when the user provides a password we can simply check it against this hash
form for a match with our safe hash on our servers.
So there's two useful libraries for this.
One is the crypt and the other one.
Excuse my pronunciation is Virk Zug.
And what we're going to do is show you how to use both of these libraries since we're both pretty popular
in the flask space.
And then you can decide which would you prefer.
Honestly they're both extremely similar.
So let's get started.
We're going to show you examples with both of them.
All right.
Here I am at my text editor.
I'm going to run this just in a simple example that PI file before we get started.
I'm going to show you how to use B Crit. And if you don't have it yet you can always install it by just
running Pipp install flask.
Dash B crypt.
That's b c r y p t.
Enter and let it install if it has an installer already.
So mine is collecting because I didn't have my environment activated.
If you have our environment activated it should already be there but you can run that just for good
measure.
And then we're going to say from flask underscore the crypt import secret.
Notice how important a capital B.
So the way this works is you create the hashing object so we can say lowercase b script is equal to
be croupe of an uppercase to have the instance of the hasher.
And then what we do is let's imagine I have a password so my password.
I'll say password is equal to super secret password.
So this is what the user is going to provide inside of the form.
This isn't something we want to save.
Instead we want to save the hash version.
So what we can do is I can call my hashing object B script and then call the generate password hash
function off of it and then just pass in my password.
So in this case the password is actually equal to the pastorate here.
So you can say password Zucco the password or we can actually just provide the string directly.
And then this will be the hashed password.
So then we can actually go ahead and print that.
So let's do that and I say print the hashed password and let's check it out.
So when I run this lips run my Python of my example up high there we go.
So here is the hashed version of the password.
You'll notice it's basically unreadable for a human which is exactly what we want.
This is the hash that we're going to store on our servers.
That means if we ever get hacked all the hackers are going to be able to see is this actual hash.
Instead of the super secret password code.
Now let's imagine that the user we already saved their hash version the password and now they're logging
in again and we want to be able to check if their password matches the hash.
Luckily the crypt can also do that for us all we need say is the crypt check password hash.
And then you provide the hashed version of the password.
So in this case the hash password and then whatever the news value is that you're trying to check it
against.
So let's say the user tries logging in of the wrong password.
So in this case we'll just say wrong password.
So let's go ahead and print the results of that check.
So say print that check I'm going to comment out the other line.
So again all I'm doing is check password hash hash password it goes in.
And then whatever you're trying to compare it to when you run this notice I get back false because wrong
password didn't match supersecret password.
Now let's put in supersecret password There we go let's save this and run it and then we get back.
True.
So the hash version of super secret password matches the hash version of what we say.
So that's how you use B crypt again.
Pretty straightforward.
There's really just two methods you need to know after importing it.
You just create that object and then call generate password hash or check password hash and VERCO Zug
is going to be extremely similar.
So let's show you how you can use that.
I'm going to delete all of this and you can always check the notes for the file in case you don't have
it yet.
You can always install Virk by saying Pipp install capital W E R K z e Yuji and in my case I've already
have it installed and it already comes a flask.
So you should already have it.
Then we're gonna say from Vicksburg security.
Whoops not that security that you were going to import generate password hash and check password hash.
That feels super familiar.
That's good because it should be.
It's basically the exact same process we just did.
So what we're going to say is hashed pass is equal to.
And in this case we just call these functions themselves no longer needed to create an object we just
import these functions directly.
So we say hash pass is equal to generate password hash so I can say my password and then I could print
out the hash pass and if ever I want to check it all I need to do is say check password hash and then
you provide the actual hashed version and check it against whatever you're looking for.
So go ahead and check it against the wrong password here.
And then we'll print the check.
So again extremely similar process except just your imports are different and you just import the functions
directly.
So now when I run this on my example the up-I I get back the hash and then I get to see that it's false.
Now the changes to actually match the password I provided.
So my password.
Save that.
Run it and now I get true.
The hash version does match the hash version of my password.
OK so that's basically it.
And since you are going to do is when a person first registers the Web site will generate their password
hash and save that generation on our server and then afterwards logging back in again.
We no longer need to generate as said we'll just checked her password hash using one of these functions
which in itself will generate it in the backend.
OK that's it.
Again it's just generation and checking.
The only differences is how we actually import and use those two libraries.
It's up to you which when you want to use.
So keep that in mind.
We'll see what the next lecture.