Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about navigation bars with bootstrap navigation bars
are present on almost all major Web sites.
They allow us to quickly links to other pages on our web applications through a convenient bar at the
top.
We can create a nav bar through the nav HVM tag bootstrap classes can then be added to the NF element
to add styling and functionality.
Bootstrap also allows us for the easy creation of collapsing nav bars.
This means if the nav bar is viewed on a different size monitor than maybe your desktop computer such
as a mobile device the smaller screen size will readjust the nav bar to produce a dropdown menu in order
to add on that functionality when you actually link in some query code.
In addition to the bootstrap.
So let's go ahead and learn about all of this by heading over to the text editor as well as our browser.
Look a here I am at my HMO.
Let's go ahead and start getting set up for the HMO.
I'm going to type the team L and notice that we have this head and body I need to grab an ad in the
bootstrap blinks for the time ahead as well as the Jake wheelings so I'll show you how to do that as
well.
Come back to the bootstrap home page get bootstrapped dot com.
Scroll down until you see the C S S only.
Go ahead and grab this link here to make sure we grab that tag as well.
Copy and paste it just as we've done before.
And then we're also going to grab.
Come down here.
This javascript links.
So copy all that come all the way forward.
Copy and then paste those in as well.
Now there's a small issue with the query that's shown here.
It's both slim and men.
Basically that means it's been slimmed down and minimized.
So it's a kind of Jake wearier javascript file that has gotten rid of a lot of spacing that sometimes
causes issues of certain browsers for the extra functionality.
So what we're going to do is we're going to add in the uncompressed version of this directly from the
actual Jay queery Web site.
So in order to do this we're going to come over here back to our browser and go to code that Jake queery
dot com that C O D E dot JQ e r y dot com.
And you'll notice we have Jay queery three point X..
This is the one we need the one on the bootstrap.
It's slim and modified and we only want the one that is magnified.
So we don't want any slim or slim in a find we either want uncompressed or minute fine.
So if you click on the manifold link we get the script right here.
You can go ahead and copy it sort of copy that.
OK.
And upon pasting it in.
Now I see this the source and notice now is just men.
So go ahead and save those changes.
This is going to allow us to have that collapse functionality.
There are sometimes issues in certain browsers when you're using the one from bootstraps since it's
slim and men.
We just wanted to be men OK.
So again go to Kodachi query and copy that path.
Let's now come back to bootstrap.
So we'll come to the documentation page click on components and then check out navs and nav bar.
So navs just gives you a basic instructions on how to use navigation components things like little links
at the top.
They can see all the various styles here available such as adjusting the vertical adjusting them to
the right aligning them to the middle et cetera and then for the basics on actual navigation bars and
there's also tabs available here.
If you come to nav bar right below navs This is where you actually get the main documentation of how
basic navigation bars work.
And there's really powerful support here for branding navigation and the collapse plug in in order for
that class plug in to work.
That's where we had to add in that Jake Query code.
So here we get this nav home link dropdown disabled search bar etc. all in an avocation bar and we can
see the code that supported with it here.
Let's go ahead and copy this code to our clipboard and let's put it in the body so going to zoom out
a little bit so we can see everything that's going on here.
All of this is in between.
This open nav tag and this closing tag.
So that's the very basic nav tag that each team already has.
And then the rest is really just adding classes and divisions.
So I noticed this big class call here nav bar.
Now Barbash expand.
LG now are like B.G. light etc..
Save all of that and just check it out.
Now in our Web site.
So going to refresh my page is linked to the HTML file.
And if I zoom in now I get to see this nice nav bar with Home link a link a dropdown menu.
This disabled link for the styling and then even a search bar.
So I don't even at forms here.
And then search something.
Obviously when I submit that nothing is actually going to occur because none of these links are actually
connected.
Let's break down what's actually happening here.
For the major components.
So typically if we zoom in here the very first component you're going to have in your navigation bar
is your brand and that's going to be some either larger font that matches up with the site name.
So here it's called nav bar but typically it's going to link kohm so we can say something like home
here save that change in between these two anchor tags.
And if I refresh now I see home notice how it's a little larger than this other home link.
That's because it has this nav bar brand.
OK.
So we have this home link.
And often people call it brand and you can go places with an image of your web site as well.
So I'll refresh this.
Now we see brand here and this is the nav bar dash brand class and it's typically the first thing that
goes in your nav bar.
And here we've also added this button with this haggler.
So what does this actually mean.
So if we keep scrolling down eventually you'll see a div that has collapse nav bar collapse and our
brand link is outside of that division.
Basically what this means for this device is that everything inside of this division is going to be
able to collapse upon changing the size of the browser.
So let's experiment with that a bit right now I can see the entirety of the nav bar but as I move this
down and begin to get less and less space suddenly they'll collapse into this hamburger icons have a
click on the MBR icon.
Now I get to see everything.
I begin to expand this again.
I get to see everything on the nav bar so collapsed with the expansion that I can close off or I get
to see the entirety of the nav bar.
This is basically detecting how big your browser screen size is and then showing the appropriate method
of the nav bar.
So for smaller screens we're going to want to be able to collapse here but for larger screens we're
going to want to show everything.
Now you may be wondering well why isn't brand collapsing into that actual hamburger icon.
So as it begins collapse this notice branch still stays there.
It doesn't go inside this hamburger icon.
Well that's because recall that this brand anchor tag is not inside the div which has this collapse
glass.
If I wanted it to collapse as well all I would need to do is grab everything relates to this brand cut
it out and then stick it inside that collapsed div..
Save those changes and then if I refreshed my site so I refreshed it and I'm going to begin to collapse
again.
Notice now everything goes to collapse.
However that can cause issues depending on how you do it.
Because now we've also collapsed the button onto itself.
So this button that's actually representing that hamburger icon all the way on the right.
So it's probably a good idea to have this one outside of the collapse itself.
Otherwise you'll be saying collapse into the collapse.
So save that change.
Refresh our Web site and now we get to see this hamburger icon.
That also includes the brand.
And since it's by itself now it just goes to the left.
So I get to see the entirety of the nav bar and as it begins to collapse everything including the brand
now goes into this button.
So again that button is right here in the HVM L.
That's something you're not going to want to have go into the collapse otherwise you won't see anything
in the nav bar when you collapse.
OK.
So again that's defined by this data toggle collapse right here.
So a lot of times we're going to want this brand to go outside of the collapse that we always see something.
So if I refreshed this now it gets to the brand including the collapse button and if I expand this I
could see everything else.
And as far as adding links to your navigation bar the way it works is essentially an unordered list
with class calls list items and then anchor tags for them.
So here we see this giant unordered list which is nav bar Barbash now of M are auto.
Here's a list item.
Again if a specific class call from Bootstrap.
These are things we're going to look up in the documentation.
You don't ever have to worry about memorizing these class calls.
Nobody does.
Everyone just always or first the documentation for them and then we have an anchor tag here.
So it's experiment by adding in a new link on our nav bar.
Right now we have home link dropdown and disabled when I'm going to do is inside of this an ordered
list or add list item we'll give it the class similar to the one that's right below it.
Nav. item space active and you'll notice that there's other classes you can do such as just that item
or drop down and then we can see the dropdown menus there as well.
But here's just my simple list item and I'm going to have just be new item.
So I'm saving that change of the list item coming back here doing a refresh and now I see that new item.
Notice how it looks a little off compared to these other ones.
And that's because we did an ad in this class of NAV link.
So let's add that in as well.
Save it refresh.
And now it's going to be lined up with the rest of them.
Now typically for nav links those are going to be inside Achor tags since you want this new item to
link to somewhere else on your page.
So instead of just having a list item like this or we're going to do is inside of that list provide
an anchor tag with some sort of reference we'll put the class call here.
So we'll say now have link dash link and then we can have this say something like brand new link.
Save those changes come back here.
I want to refresh this.
I get to see brand new link right next to home link and dropdown.
You'll notice that some of these look a little different.
Home looks a little darker linked looks a little lighter and that's just the different class style calls.
And we can even see here the sable looks even more faint.
So those are all defined by the class style calls so we see item drop down.
In the case they wanted to be a drop down and then inside of that dropdown you can see we have another
list item with a div with the class dropdown menu and then various tags there and we can also have dropdown
dividers.
So if you come here and take a look at the drop down I see action and other action some sort of divider
and then something else here that's being defined by this dropdown divider.
So we have action in other action the dropdown divider division there and then another dropdown item
and hopefully are able to link in your mind what you see in the browser versus what you're actually
seeing in the bootstrap example documentation.
So then here's another list item It's a nap item.
Notice the classes change slightly Navesink disabled and that's the styling call if you want it to appear
like it's disabled a little lighter.
We can also put in forms directly into this nav bar.
Again all this is going in between those nav tags and we can see here the various classes available
form in line form control and so on.
And typically you're going to use that to add a search bar to your actual navigation bar.
All right.
Now I know that seems like a ton of stuff but I really want to emphasize here you shouldn't have to
memorize any of this.
You should be skilled in being able to come to the documentation looking at the example that reflects
what you want in your web site.
For example if we just scroll down here maybe you want some sort of text of an inline element or you
like this nav bar.
So then you just copy the actual HTL code here and then realize what class calls you need to make and
adjust as necessary for your own web site.
So if it keeps scrolling down you can see there's different color schemes such as color navigation bars
or blue navigation bar light blue and so on and all you have to know is that you just change the actual
calls.
So a nav bar and then you just say nav Barbash dark B.G. dark or you say primary or you say style background
color and then add your own hex code for your background color.
It's all just class calls that you add in when you reference the documentation.
You can put everything inside of container to not have it stretch all the way out.
So lots and lots of different options here.
Again we want to become masters at looking up the information for the documentation not memorizing all
these bootstrap class calls.
OK.
So that's really it for bootstrap.
Again the whole idea of it is just referencing the documentation for bootstrap and then implementing
it in your own projects.
Well we're going to do next is we're going to have a quick bootstrap project so you can get comfortable
were referencing the bootstrap documentation and then building something new.
All right.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Kewney forums.
We'll see you there.