Welcome back and this lecture we're going to take a quick little detour to talk about how you can create
your own error handling pages.
That is if you have a four or four error instead of showing that default not found four or four page
that we saw earlier in the section we can show our own four or four HTL template so to set up the handlers
for that in the error pages directory and then link those using a blueprint.
Let's head back to our text editor and show you how it's done.
All right.
Here we are back at our text editor what I want to do is run our application as it is right now and
see what happens when we try to reach a page that isn't available to us.
So if we take a look here at our Web site we have the full navigation bar.
And if I go to forward slash info I see info about our company but let's go to forward slash information
of you that we know doesn't exist.
So if I hit enter I right now get this default for 0 for error saying not found the requests are always
not found that our server where we're always to do this play our own template file.
So you've definitely worked for other Web sites that show their own customized four or four page.
We're now going to show you how you can do that with flask in order to make that happen.
I'm going to stop serving this and come back.
Remember we have a directory called Air underscore pages underneath that directory by convention.
We call it handlers dot pi.
So we're going to create a new file which is essentially a view up high file.
But for the error handling.
So in order to distinguish it from just typical views we're going to call it handlers dot pi.
So again this file that I'm at right now is called handlers dot pi.
And what this is going to do is it's actually going to serve the views of those particular error pages
sort of say from flask import blueprints and also render template and then we'll say error underscore
pages is equal to a blueprint.
And then we're going to call this error pages and then passen the builtin name variable.
Now we're going to do is say at error pages.
So instead of saying dot route we're going to call dot app underscore error handler because this isn't
just a basic routing since we don't know what the user is going to provide for it for or for air.
Instead we're using the app underscore air handler to connect it to a general air and then we pass in
the error code that we want to connect it to.
So in this case we're going to connect to a 4 0 for air and you can google around for the various h
T.M. codes so forfour is just one type of air which is kind of a not found error.
And then we'll see if error underscore for 0 4 and then we pass in the error that was actually found.
So this is the view that's going to happen when you get a page that isn't found.
And we're going to return render a template and we're actually going to set this not underneath the
regular templates folder.
Instead we're going to have the error templates set apart in their own error pages directory.
So the template is going to come from error underscore pages forward slash 4 0 4 h m l and then I'm
going to say comma for 0 4.
So notice what's happening here.
I'm not just returning this render template function I'm actually returning a tuple where the first
part of it is the rendered template and then I say comma for 0 4.
So keep that in mind we haven't actually done something like this before because we haven't use that
app.
Underscore error handler before but this is the main approach for setting up your own templates to be
served for a particular errors happen.
So now we need to do is actually set up this error underscore pages directory within our original templates
directory.
So if I expand templates right now I see Base 8 team.
In this index page to melt info.
Tim L. I'm going to create a new folder here called error underscore pages and this will allow me to
separate my specific error templates from my other templates.
So now underneath error pages I'm going to create a new file called for 0 4 h T.M..
So this is for 0 for the H Tim L and it's underneath the error pages.
So directory of templates and what you can do is basically write out whatever you want to show up for
the four or four page.
What's nice about this is I can then extend from base H.T. mail that way even if a forward for error
occurs the user still has access to the navigation bar.
So say extends from base T.M. and then we'll set up our block called content and here I'm going to have
a Jumbotron that basically tells the user let's say four or four page not found
so if you ever want to add in more errors.
All you need to do is come back to the handlers thought py file.
So essentially the views file for errors and then you just add in whatever errors you want.
So for example if you're interested in a 403 error so that's the kind of error that occurs when something
is forbidden.
So maybe you're trying to update someone else's blog posts without having permission.
That's a 4.
0 3 error.
The way you would do that is pretty much exactly the same.
You just change the code.
You would say error underscore pages dot app underscore error handler passen that particular code.
So if 403 is forbidden access and then we say DPF error 0 3 you pass on the actual error and then will
we say here is return render template and then we would just set up another template for that.
So I'll say error pages 4 or 3 that each T.M. and then we say comma and we actually pass in the integer
code for that.
So that basically connects us to that actual air.
OK so since we're saying four or three H-2A l Let's go ahead and create one more template.
We'll say new file for over 3.
The H team L and this is actually actually going to look pretty much exactly like the Frot for.
So going to copy and paste this except I'll say it's sort of four or four page not found.
I will just type out for three forbidden access also access for bin and then the last thing for us to
do before we actually test this out is make sure we actually link this blueprint to our in it that PI
file.
So we have this blueprint called error pages and it's underneath this handlers that pile underneath
err pages underneath puppy company blog.
So I'll come over to it thought pie and we're going to do a very similar thing to what we did here.
We're going to say from puppy company blog dot and in this case it's called Air underscore pages will
say handlers import error underscore pages and then we're just going to register that will say take
the app and register that blueprint of error pages and save those changes.
So now that will link those two additional views 4 4 0 3 or 4 0 for errors.
So let's check it out.
We're going to be will check the 404 error right now because we don't have any logging permissions set
up.
But as long as that works we should be able to see the idea of it.
So I'm running my application.
Let's go ahead and go to the home page.
Let me bring in my browser.
So here's my browser Papy company blog about everything looks good.
Let's go ahead and go to a page that we know this exists.
I was going to type in some random letters here and now I get back my custom template for 0 4 page not
found.
OK.
So that's how you can perform error handling of your own custom templates.
Just to review what we did here is recreated underneath this error pages directory a handlers that pi
file.
So you could call those views up high but by convention people call it handlers up high.
We set up our blueprints connecting it and then we call error pages dots and then notice here that difference
and set of that route we say app underscore error handler pasand the actual HTML error you're looking
for then passen that error.
Connect it to a template and then also remember repassing 8 were returning a tuple really for this app
error handler to handle in the back and you'll say comma and then four or four or whatever the code
happens to be.
So here flask is actually performing a lot on the back end for you.
Essentially all you need to remember is to call app underscore air handler and to return the tuple including
the rendered template and the actual code beyond that flask is doing a lot more for you on the backend.
Then we just create our HTL templates here of whatever you want to display for any given error.
And then remember we wanted to link the actual blueprints.
All right.
That's it for handling errors.
I hope that was useful to you.
Coming up next we're continue on with the main part of the project we'll see at the next lecture.