Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going start talking about flask log in the flask clogging the library mix adding user authentication
to our web applications.
Very easy.
Basically it just has easily callable decorator's for adding user functionality.
Let's go ahead and begin exploring it in part 1 of our discussion on this library.
LAURA.
Here I am back in my text editor.
I'm going to start off and we're going to try to organize this a little bit similar to what we're doing
before when talk about larger flask applications.
Now technically this floss application is going to be too small to separate forms and models into their
own subcomponents.
But what I will do is I'm going to create a new folder called my project and at the same level of this
my project folder I'll create a file called app pi.
So this going to be a little similar to what we're just doing before in the previous section of the
Course now to begin with.
I'm going to create all the files and folders will be needed.
So inside of my project I'm going to create the underscore underscore in its underscore underscore the
py file and that will allow us to import from my project and then also create a form's thot py file
as well as a model that py file and then underneath my project I'll create a new folder to hold my templates.
So all those age html files and we're going to have a couple of different aist him all files available
to us.
So we should start creating them now will have a base 20:00 essentially to hold on and how far that
will have a home page.
So I'll say homemade T.M. and then we'll have a log in a page.
So once the users register they can log in in an order for them to log and they have to register.
So will create a new register each time I'll say register each time.
And then finally after someone's log then we'll go ahead and redirect them to a welcome user page just
so we can check that everything's working.
So we'll create a new file and call it welcome underscore user that HMO.
OK.
So we have all our files ready to go.
We have our templates and then all our forms and models.
Let's begin by setting up our underscore underscore and it underscore underscore that py file signatures
to make it clear.
Right now I'm editing the file underneath my project folder.
So I'm going to start off of a couple of imports as we've done in the past.
Import os from flask import flask will set up a database source say from flask underscore sequel alchemy
import sequel alchemy from flask underscore migrate import migrate and from flask underscore.
Lock in.
We're going to import loggin manager.
So if you haven't installed flask log in go ahead and do so.
Just a simple Pip install a flask log in and flash laga it comes with.
This really is full class basically that allows you to effectively automate all the management of your
logging systems.
So we'll start off by actually using that anoints say logging.
Underscore manager is equal to an instance of this logging in a manager object that it won't create
my application just as we've always done we'll see.
Underscore underscore name underscore underscore we'll do a couple of configurations here.
So I will say app config and let me get some more space here.
Will say app config for secret key
is equal to my secret key.
Or really whatever string you want at this point and then will set a base directory equal to OS path
absolute path and the here will say OS that path directory name or C underscore underscore file underscore
underscore just as we've always done and then we'll set up the configurations for our school like database
all say squawker me underscore database.
You are I said that equal to school like colon three forward slashes concatenated with O S path where
a base directory is and then we'll call it data thought sequel.
So we've actually already done all this before.
The only thing new here is that query that log in the manager object which we haven't used yet but we
will in just a little bit.
Last thing I want to set up is sequel alchemy underscore track modifications and set equal to false
OK.
Next step is to actually create our database by saying sequel alchemy passing in our application and
I want to be able to perform migrations on it.
So I'll say migrate past in the application and our new database.
And now I can pass on the application to our logon manager.
So the way this works is you've taken that logging manager object you created and you call the method
in underscore app method off of it.
And this is going to basically configure your application to have management of lock in users so you
pass in your app and then in order to tell users what view to go to when they log in will say log in
manager log in view is equal to log in.
So what that means is in our actual app the py file or setting up our views we're going to have a view
called log in and that will essentially link this up to our logging manager so that we can tell what
users view they need to go to to log in.
So everything else is pretty much the same.
I want to highlight the differences and that is from Flast log in import logging manager.
Create an instance of this logging manager object and then scrolling down here we initiate the app to
be able to have log in management and then we set our log in to view equal to logon and that will match
up with the view we create later on in our app.
Hi file.
So save those changes.
And up next we need to do is actually begin creating our model for a user.
So let's go over here to models not.
Right now I'm in models not pi and I'm going to set up everything we need to contain an actual user
in our database.
I'll say from my project import database and that log in a manager object that we created.
Again that's being imported from that in it py file.
So we were just in then I'll be using Virk search for my password and hashing and checking.
And you have to apologize for my pronunciation of that.
I don't really speak German so I'll say that security in poor generate password hash and then check
password hash.
I don't want it to collapse this sidebars.
We get a little bit of room here so I have the ability to generate the passwords and check the passwords.
And then finally also from a flask logon import user mixin.
So it's really cool is by inheriting from the user mixin class we're going to get access to a lot of
built in attributes which will then be able to call interactional views.
So that will come later or messing around for views in the app pie but I want you to keep that in mind.
Let's continue.
By starting off to create our user class this won't be too different from before.
We're again going to inherit from B model but now we're actually going to inherit from multiple classes.
And the other one we're going to inherit from is user mixin essentially user Mixon has all those management
features of logging in users and authorizing them.
So we don't have to take care of that ourselves.
So we inherit from DVH model and user Mixon.
Let's give this a table name parameter.
So I'll say wups table name and I'm going to set equal to users and let's have a have an ID column.
So say this is a D-B column
D-B integer.
So those here I'm not doing the actual imports from D-B.
Instead of saying D-B column D integer.
And this should be a primary key.
So every user should have a unique primary key so that we don't have overlapping primary keys then we'll
have e-mails for each user.
So we'll save their e-mails as well.
This will be a strain.
And if you want you can pass in a number into the string to limit how long the e-mail can be in case
you're worried about spam.
So we can go ahead and say 64 characters most often you'll probably want to set Unique equal to true
for this column because you don't want to have two different users with the same e-mail address because
if something happens where we want to reset their password by sending them an e-mail.
Our system will get confused.
So we should have unique e-mails and we can also say index to be true
and also that username equal to the B column.
And this will also be a string.
So we'll say string Well also said it's 64 characters their user name should probably also be unique.
So you don't have two people with the same username Otherwise you make it confusing trying to log in.
And also indexical to true.
And then finally we're going to save the hashed version of the password.
So say password hash is equal to D-B column D-B.
And this is also going to be a string.
However the hashes we're going to say are actually pretty long.
So we should have at least 128 space for that string.
OK.
Then in order to actually create an instance of a user object we'll say the F in it and this will take
in self email username and password so then we'll say self e-mail is equal the email it's passed in
for that user self username is equal to the user name that's passed and for that user and then self
password hash is equal to.
And this is where it's going to be actually a little different.
So when the user is being created they're going to provide their real password which will be a string
like my secret password one two three.
However we don't want to say that actual string.
We want to save the hashed version of that string.
So that's what we're going to use right here.
Generate password hash.
Get a copy that and put it down here so it's a general password hash.
From the password that's provided upon initializing a user.
So again we're saving the past rehash not the actual password and then in order to check when the users
log in that is to correct user We're going to have a method called check password and it's going to
be self and it's going to take any password.
And we're going to return the result of check password hash self password hash and password.
So all this is doing is it's using that check password hash function that we talked about earlier and
it's going to accept some passwords.
So this is when a user is logging in maybe a second time it's going to check their stream password hash
it and then check it against the self-taught password hash that was stored earlier for that particular
instance of the user.
OK.
So let me zoom out a little bit so you can see the whole picture here.
We have our user class table name these four columns ID email user name and password hash.
We accept email username and password but remember when you're accepting that password we generate the
password hash and then we have this method for checking it.
Finally what we need to do is add in a quick little function here called load user and the user loaded
that that we're using here.
This is basically going to allow flask log in to load the current user and grab their ID.
So once someone is logged in we'll be able to show them pages specific to their logon ID.
And this is actually quite simple.
We're going to zoom in a bit here so we can see it.
You say at loggin manager thought user underscore loader.
So again this is a built in decorator into our logging manager.
And then we say DPF load user you pass in the User ID and then we're going to return off of our user
database.
We're going to query and get that user ID.
So that means we have this ability to load whatever current user that we're looking at based off their
ID so we can query our user table based off that user ID and grab that specific user.
That way we can later show information specific to that user.
In our case we'll just be saying something like Hello username.
So that's how we're going to be using load user.
So save all those changes and that's it for this lecture.
So far what we've done is set up all the directories and files and then we set up our in a file here
essentially very similar to what we've done before except now we have this log in a manager object that
we're able to also initiate our app.
We set up our log in view and we have our models up by file here and we're using those generation and
checking a password hashes.
We have this load user function to check for the currently logged in user.
And we also have this user class and notice here we're using this user mixin that's going to come in
handy later on because it's going to allow us to call different attributes directly in our views like
is authenticated is active and get ID.
So we'll see that later on when we start messing with her app that py file and building out the views.
Before that we'll probably want to actually create some forms.
We're going to do all of this and more coming up in the next lecture.
We'll see if there.