Welcome back to part two of our discussion of object oriented programming.
Well we're going to talk about methods and inheritance.
Let's head back to text editor where we left off last time.
Last time we left off at creating this dog class that only had attributes.
And we also discussed class object attributes which are attributes which are going to be true for any
instance of the stock object.
So it doesn't matter what kind of breed or name the stock can have or it also doesn't matter if we create
a brand new dog.
So I can create a variable called new dog which is also an instance of the dog class.
This one may be a golden retriever so say Golden is the breed and the name will just have this dog.
Cindy and if I say Prince new dog species save I'll get back mammal as well.
So I get mammal mammal.
Doesn't matter what the breed instance or name of the dog is this class object attribute is going to
be the same for all of them.
So let's now talk about methods which are basically going to be actions you perform on the object.
So I'm going to delete all this code and let's start with something new.
We're going to create a circle class and we'll say DMF.
Let me zoom in here just a little bit.
We'll say T.F. and we create our own method.
Remember this is double underscores so underscore underscore and we'll say self and in this case we're
going to define an attribute as radius and we can also give a default value just like we could for a
normal function.
I'll say radious by default is equal to 1 in case the user doesn't provide it then we'll say sulf thought
radius is equal to radius OK.
So we have class circle.
And in this method when you create a new instance of the circle class you can provide a radius for it.
If you don't provide a radius then the default will just be radius equal to 1.
So let's create an instance of it will say My circle is equal to in its circle.
And then I'll print how my circles radius.
Let's run this.
And now I get back 1 as a radius that circle however I could provide in my own radius such as 10.
And when I run this again.
Now I get back 10 so I have this default radius which you can always overwrite when I'm creating a new
instance of my circle.
Now think of a class object attribute which is going to be true for any circle.
One of these could be pi.
So the value of pi or that ratio 3.1 for that's going to be pretty much true for any circle regardless
of the radius.
So it could set that as a class object attribute though the second house under that init method.
So far we've only discussed attributes now discuss methods.
So this init method is technically what's known as a special method.
Again it has that double set of underscores to show you that.
But you can create your own methods that performs some sort of action with or on the object.
So let's create a method for calculating area and by default every method should start first with self.
Basically that tells Python that you're referring to the instance of the object you create when applying
this particular method.
So area is just going to return the area of the circle which in this case is pi r squared.
So we're going to say self-taught radius times self-taught radius times self-taught pi.
So it saved that and I will say my circle radius and then we'll print out my circle area.
But notice what happens.
Area itself is a method which means if I just called that area it's actually not going to execute the
method.
Self-taught radius.
That's an attribute.
But this DPF area is going to be a method that you can tell.
It's a method because it has DPF in front of it very much like a function would.
So let's say this and run it and see what happens.
Right now I get 10 for the radius.
But when I call my circle the area I get this bound Methot Circle area of main circle object at this
location memory and very similar to what we are working on functions in order to execute a method.
You have to have the open and close princes and then you can see the syntax highlighting has even changed.
Now when I run this I'm able to see the actual area of the circle three fourteen point zero so are squared
times pi.
OK.
So again the method is going to perform an action and it can return or it can actually affect the object
itself without returning anything.
Just keep that in mind for future reference.
Let's try adding a new method which calculates the circumference of a circle will say the F will say
circumference.
We pass and self and then we'll say return and circumference of a circle is 2 times pi.
So we'll say self-taught pi times the radius which in this case is self-taught radius.
Notice here how I'm saying self-taught radius instead of just radius.
If I say just radius Pi does not understand what I'm referring to.
I need to tell it.
Hey I'm talking about self-taught radius the radius of the circle that it was assigned upon create in
the circle.
So a self-taught radius there.
Let's run this and whoops we actually forgot to execute it.
So let's come back here and say my circle circumference again remember those open close Princie so we
can actually run this method.
I run this and I see the circumference of the circle with some extra precision due to using floating
point numbers appear OK.
So we were able to create our own methods for area and circumference.
The next thing I want to talk about is inheritance.
So I'm going to clear these examples.
And let's create a class called animal it's going to be a very simple class it's going to have an in
it method.
With self it's not going to take any other parameters.
And in this case we're not even going to assign any attributes.
We're just going to say animal created then we're going to say T.F. report self and this will be a method
that just prints out animal then we're going to create one more method self that prints out eating.
OK so let's play around with this.
I'm going to create an instance of my animal object.
So say a is equal to an animal object and then we'll say a dot and let's have it eats and let's have
it report.
Notice tone after call print on eata report because those methods themselves already print out for me
and I'm going to zoom out a little bit so we can see the whole class on the screen.
So let's run this.
And notice I get back.
Eating an animal.
OK.
So pretty basic class right here.
Again it's just going to print's animal created upon creating an animal or animal created that happens
on line 12.
Then it says eating and that it's an animal.
Now maybe you want to create a new class such as a dog class and you start thinking to yourself Hey
I already did all this work with the Animal class maybe I could reduce some of this.
For example I would like dogs to have an eat method and have them say that they're eating.
So how can actually take advantage of all the prior work that I've done on the Animal class with my
dog class which you can do is you can inherit the Animal class and the way you do this is you just pass
an animal no princes as far as the end of the animal into the dog class and then inside of that class
you're going to say in its self and then here you can say Prince dog created save that and now down
here what I'm going to do is I'm going to create an instance of the class so I'll say D.
Is equal to dog.
But then what I'm going to do is inside this method for dog I'm going to initialize the animal method
I inherited Saussy animal dot underscore underscore that underscore underscore and then passen self
so what this says is upon creating an instance of dog I'm going to using my inheritance from animal
create an instance of the Animal class and then print that created.
So when I create dog here I should see animal created because I'm calling in it down here an animal.
And then I should see dog created.
Let's see if that happens.
So I scroll up and there we have it animal created and dog created.
Now the question arises there are these other useful methods on animal report and eat.
Let's see if now I have access to them from the dog class.
So I'm going to say D.
Eat notice here.
I never defined eat inside of my thought class.
It's only the inside of the Animal class.
I'm going to run this and I get back eating even though I never strictly defined it inside of the dog
class.
I was able to inherit that method of eat from the Animal class and this is what inheritance all about
being able to use methods or attributes that you already defined in another class with a new class.
So now I have access to eat and I should also have access to report.
So Saidy report run this and now I get to see dog created eating an animal.
However let's think about this.
Maybe I want to be more specific in my report than just animal.
Maybe they would like it to report dog.
Well that's no problem.
We can easily overwrite inherited methods.
All I need to say is the earth choose the same method name report say self.
And then it's going to print.
I am a dog so now when you call report even though you're inheriting from animal and animal typically
prints animal for its report.
Now Dog overwrote that and now it's going to print.
I am a dog.
So when I run this python in my example it's going to say dog created right above it.
Animal created.
That comes from this line and it Methot off animal.
Then it says Dog created that comes from this line print dog created and then when you call dog eats
that's actually calling the inheritance method here eating.
And then when you call I am a dog off report.
That's this report Prince.
I am a dog.
You were able to successfully overwrite this old report method that you inherited from and that's the
basic idea behind inheritance being able to use old methods from another class to find.
And then if you ever want to you can always overwrite those methods yourself.
Now something I'm often asked is What do you do if your animal init method actually took attributes.
So for example let's say the animals had a fur attribute so so me delete this print statement and say
self-taught for is equal to the fur provided in this case.
If I were to try to run this I would get back an error it would say hey this is missing one required
positional argument for and that's coming from this animal in itself line.
So right here it's saying hey animals you're required to say what kind of fur this animal has.
And when you created in the heritage from the instance of the class down here when you're saying D is
equal to dog.
You forgot to provide what fur.
Well that's no problem.
All you need to do is then accept a parameter for the init method of your dog class and then stick that
for parameter into the method of the animal call.
And I want to save this if I just read this right now still get an error because it saying hey you're
forgetting to provide for so on it to do inside the class is provided for.
So maybe I'll say this dog has fuzzy for an hour when you run it you don't get an error it just says
Dog created eating and I am a dog.
And if we delete all these I can always say d dot for and I can print out type notice again that first
an attribute in this case.
So I run this and you get back dog created fuzzy and notice it's no longer printing animal created because
I don't know.
No longer have that print statement there in the animal.
So instead I'm saying in it except for assigns that for and if I ever need to do that with my inherited
class I can just pasan in its own init method and then pass that into the inherited class method.
OK.
That's the very basics of methods and inheritance.
Remember methods are essentially functions defined inside the body of a class and they're used to perform
operations with the attributes of our objects inheritance is a way to form new classes using classes
that have already been defined and those newly formed classes are called derived classes and the classes
that we derive from are called base classes.
So in this case animals the base class in dogs the derived class if you have any questions feel free
to post to Cunanan forums.
We have one lecturer left in this O.P. series which is just special methods essentially methods that
allow us to interact with built in Python functions.
We'll see if they're.