Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about the debug mode option as we learn about flask.
We're definitely going to make some mistakes along the way.
We can set debug equal to true in our application to help us catch these errors.
Debug Mode also gives us access to a console in the browser.
Let's explore all of the debug options we have by jumping over to our text editor OK here and back in
my text editor.
Right now we just have three views.
There's the home page you for index.
There's this information view and then there's dynamic routeing view where we can take in a puppy name
and display right now in uppercase the puppy's name.
What I'm going to do right now is change this view for puppy and I'm going to have it return sort of
saying uppercase I'm going to have it returned the one hundredth letter of the name.
Keep in mind not every name is going to have 100 letters in it.
In fact most names won't.
And then here we're going to say Index 100.
So what's happening here is I'm basically asking for the index at one hundred and then I'm going to
try to return it.
So right now I'm just going to say APTA run here on line 19.
Let me save my changes.
Now let's run the file.
And let's go to the home page in our browser.
Here we go.
So I'm at the home page in the browser and if I do something like forward slash information it says
Puppies are cute.
Now let's try to visit puppy and I say puppy slash Rufus Now remember Rufus doesn't actually have 100
letters in it which means when I try to do this indexing of name 100 that's going to be an error inside
of this function.
So what Flast does by default is it says you have an internal server error the server encountered internal
error and was unable to complete your request which makes sense that function inside of a web application
has an internal error.
So instead of just breaking down the entire site it just reports back you have an internal server error.
That's not very helpful however.
We're trying to debug our code.
So instead what we can do is debug equal to true inside of our text editor.
So let's go back and do that and come back here.
I will set debug equal to true and then that save Let me restart my server and we're going to come back
here.
Let's check the home page again.
So home page looks good.
It says Hello puppy and what I'm going to say is could be.
And the Rufous again and now notice what happens if I'm going to expand this.
I get an index error.
Now I have a lot more information about what's happening within my application.
It says street index out of range.
So now we're already thinking the idea hey maybe I have an index problem with my actual function which
is exactly what was happening.
We pass that rufous Rufus's I have 100 letters so the index is an issue and it'll give you a full traceback
here and you notice as you go around it's say something like at the very bottom just what triggered
the index string index out of range 100 flooder format name.
Now what's really cool is as you hover over these particular errors with the traceback you'll get little
console icon.
And if you hit this you can open an interactive python shell inside of this very frame.
Now in order to do that.
Going to need to expand this as you scroll up here you should eventually see the full traceback error
in this command line.
And then if you also come back here you should see a debugger pin you're going to need that in order
to actually access the console.
So notice right when you set run Osei debug mode is equal to on will say debuggers active and it has
a debugger pin.
I'm going to highlight this debugger pin right click and then select Copy make sure don't do Control-C
that's going to quit your server if you do that.
But once I have that debugger pin let me go back to my browser here and back on my browser going to
expand this again.
I'm going to select the console and then it's going to ask me hey what was that pen.
I'm going to paste that in.
Click.
Confirm pin.
And then once you confirm it you'll be able to scroll back down here and now it says consolers ready.
So what is this useful for.
Well it's really nice here is I can then pass in whatever variables I want and essentially a debugger
counsel right where the traceback happen.
So if I type in name Ill say hey the string that was passed then was rufous and then if I type in name
of 100 ill say another traceback here.
Hey you have an error index string is out of range.
So here I can explore the various variables that are actually happening inside of this view function
and these are the two main aspects of debug.
The first one is this fool that traceback that it's going to issue you and a lot of times just from
this itself you'll be able to debug that if you need to play around whatever variables that are inside
the view function or really any other page that's going on you're able to open a python console within
a step of this traceback.
So those are the two main things to note here.
Remember you'll need the debugger pin in order to actually access this console which is a nice little
security feature that's built into flask.
One last thing.
Keep in mind is that you should never have debug equals true when you're deploying this to production.
Otherwise other people are going to see this debug page and be able to see your full traceback instead
of just getting that internal server error.
All right.
That's it for the debug mode.
From now on we'll be sending debug eagle to true for most of our projects to help us debug any issues
that may come along the way.
And I would definitely suggest to you as well as you're playing around a flask the debug equals the
true and only set it to False.
Once you're ready for production do you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
We'll see you in the next lecture.