Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about relationships and databases often for larger
projects you're going to want to have multiple models to represent different tables inside your database
and these models may have relationships to each other.
For example you could have a model for puppies and another model for their owners.
So there's a relationship there between an owner and it's puppy so to understand model relationships
we need to first review primary keys and foreign keys and tables a primary key is a unique identifier
column for every row inside of a table.
So something could be like a Social Security number or national ID card for a person a name is not unique
identifier because different people could have the same name.
So the primary key is going to be a column whose value is going to be unique for every single row a
foreign key is just the primary key from another table and that allows you to connect two tables together.
So let's show you an example let's imagine we have two models or two tables inside of our database.
We can have a puppy model where is an ID tag or a primary key for the puppy.
And then the puppies name the puppy's name is not a primary key because different puppies could have
the same name the owner table has three columns a national ID number such as a social security number
or a national ID card.
And that would be a primary key because every single owner has a unique national ID number.
Then we have the owner name and then we have the puppy ID for the owners puppy.
So the puppy ID inside of the owner table that's a foreign key because that's the column that directly
connects the owner table to the puppy because the puppy I.D. is the primary key inside of the puppy
table.
So that's a difference when a primary key any foreign key.
It's pretty simple.
The primary key is a unique identifier inside of the table and then a foreign key is just that same
column referenced inside of another model or table.
So later on we're going to discuss more complex relationships between two models.
For now let's work through a simple example of connecting two tables together by connecting their respective
models inside of the pie script.
We're going to get a little more practice so we're going to start completely from scratch so we can
review things like Flast migrate as well as importing D-B models.
Let's get started.
All right.
Here we are at a brand new Python script I've called this model's pie and it's actually going to contain
pretty much the whole application but it's really going to focus on just three models.
We'll have a puppy model a toy model and then an owner model.
Let's go ahead and get started.
I'm going say at the very top.
Import os.
And then also same from flask imports flask.
And then we'll say from flask underscore sequel whoops sequel alchemy import sequel alchemy.
And then finally from flask underscore migrate import migrate.
So we've already seen how to do all these commands and separate lectures but we're kind of just putting
them together first.
First step is to set up our school like database so we create our base directory based the IRA and we
do this by saying oh s path the absolute path of.
And then we're going to grab our current location.
So say oh estop half that character's name and then passen the builtin file variable.
Once you've done that will create our application by saying app equal to flask and the will passen the
builtin name variable.
And then we want to set up our configuration.
Say app config and we're going to do here is say sequel alchemy underscore database underscore you are.
And then we set that equal to sequel like colon three forward slashes and then we're just going to grab
a pass again O S path and we'll join our basestar victory.
With data dot sequel lights.
I'm going to collapse this left hand tab to get a lower room here.
OK.
So we've created our the victory for the sequel alchemy database.
Essentially just creating a new file data that sequel like where we're currently located and then also
set up the configuration for Sequel alchemy underscore track underscore modifications and anoints set
that equal to false.
Then finally I'll say D-B is equal to sequel alchemy and I'll pass in my application and then I will
connect them by calling migrate and saying app D-B.
All right.
Hopefully there was a nice review of how you actually set up your configuration when dealing with a
sequel like database.
Now let's move on and actually create a couple of classes or models.
So start off with a puppy class.
I'm going to say class puppy and we inherit from D-B that model and then you can supply a table name
here.
So what I will do is say that this table underscore underscore table name underscore underscore is equal
to puppies.
That also the ID equal to D-B column.
And I'll say D-B integer and then will say primary key equals true.
So notice I'm setting that this is a unique identifier for every single puppy so each pup is going to
have their own unique ID and then we're going to say name is equal to D-B the column d text.
So every puppy can have a name and there were ways to create a One to Many relationship.
So we're going to say that one puppy can have many toys.
So later on I'm going to make a model for toys.
So again this is a one to many relationship that the puppy is going to have.
So I will say toys is equal to D-B dot relationship.
And then I'm going to pass in the string toy and then we're going to say back ref to the back reference.
Is lower case puppy.
And then we'll say lazy is equal to dynamic.
And before we actually break this down I'm going to create the other two classes that we're going to
be working with.
We'll say a toy class that inherits from D-B model.
And right now I'll just say pass here and then I'll creates a class for the owner.
So say owner D-B model.
And here here I'm going to say pass as well.
So this is the other two tables in the database.
One for the toy and then one for the owner.
But right now let's focus on this relationship right here.
So again this is one too many.
And we're connecting a puppy to what may be many toys and then a little bit we'll see kind of a one
to one.
So here's one too many puppy too many toys.
And we have several parameters inside of this called D-B that relationship.
So what we have here are three main parameters.
The first one is just connecting it to the actual other model.
So we're saying that this column toys is a relationship with this toy model here.
Then we have a back ref reference variable and or parameter.
And that's basically just going to add a back reference.
And the other model in the relationship.
So it's going to add a reference to the toy model to remember that that's also related to but B through
this relationship column and then we have this lazy parameter.
And this is for people who are a little more advanced in databases but it essentially specifies how
the related items are to be loaded.
There's actually lots of possible values here he can provide select as a string immediate as a string
joined subquery and no load.
Often it's just easiest to use this string dynamic which basically means that instead of loading the
related items the query that can load them is given.
So that's usually best suited for general purpose.
And you can check out the documentation for the D-B relationship to see if you want to use other string
codes there.
But for pretty much all or use cases will just be setting in as dynamic.
All right so now let's move on and fill out a couple of more methods inside of this puppy model.
First we want to set our method and this will allow a sexy create new instances of a puppy essentially
adding new rows.
So say self name also a self-taught name is equal to name and then we also add a representation.
So say the representation of this actual puppy model and we're going to do here is something a little
different.
I'm going to add in one more relationship column inside puppie and this will be a one to one and this
will connect one puppy to one owner.
So we're going to assume that every puppy in the world only has one owner and vice versa.
Every owner can only have one puppy.
So here we're representing a one to many puppies too many toys and a one to one one a puppy to one owner.
And the way we're going to do that is just say owner is equal to.
Now I will say D-B relationship.
And then we're going to pasan owner to connect it to that actual model.
Well say the back reference is puppie again.
So that gives it the back reference.
And the other one and we can actually just leave the lazy parameter to be the default for this one to
one relationship.
But what I going to do is pass in a parameter called Use List instead of equal to false.
So the reason I'm doing that is because by default it's usually true which would make sense for a one
to many relationship because one puppy when you ask for its toys it would be a list of possible toys.
But here we just have one puppy to one owner.
So we don't need a list of voters because it's just going to be a single owner.
So we expect to be returned which is why we use this useless parameter and we set it equal to false
by default.
It's equal to true which is why we didn't actually play around it in the toys column.
So these are two relationship columns that get a one to many and they wouldn't put me to one owner.
Let's move on to this representation and we're going to do the following.
We'll see if self owner meaning if the actual puppy has an owner.
We're going to say return and it is going to use some of string literals will say puppy name is and
wants her back.
The puppies name Elsie and owner is I'll say say self the owner and then the owner is going to have
their own name.
So say Salta owner name.
So again that's just grabbing the attribute owner here.
And then from that owner object you'll see later on the owners are going to have their own name which
is why we're using this kind of double dot notation of Celta owner that name.
Now let's imagine that the puppy does not have an owner.
Then what we're going to do is say else return using string notation puppy name is self-taught name
and has no owner yet.
OK.
So that's going to be the representation when we print out a puppy.
Either return the name.
And if they have an owner return the name of their owners and then can say puppy name self-taught name
has no owner yet.
Now let's finally add one more method to this class in order to report back the number of toys that
the owner or that the puppy has.
So say if and I'm going to make a quick method here called Report toys will say self and what what it's
going to do it's going to print.
Here are my toys.
And as we just discussed with use list use list is set to true by default.
So that means when you actually ask for toys from a puppy meaning you safer self-taught toys that's
going to be A-list.
So that means I can do the following.
I can say for toy in self-taught toys because useless by default is true.
And then I'm going to say print grab that toys Item Name an item name is going to be an attribute that
we create inside of our toy model.
So we have this name attribute that we suddenly create owner as well as this item name that we still
need to create inside of our story class.
So let's quickly fill out class toy and class owner.
So we'll go ahead and manually give them table names.
Technically this isn't required but we'll do it.
So say toys for the table name and then create a primary key for our tables.
So this is going to be D-B column.
And then this will be an integer.
So it's going to be a unique identifier for each toy and they'll say primary key is equal to true and
then we'll say item name is equal to D-B column D-B text.
So the name of whatever toy or item it is.
And then we need to connect the toy to the puppy that owns it and we use puppies ID because the table
name we set up here if we come back up here it was puppies.
So Mishu what I mean by that.
So this is going to be the column that connects toys to puppies to say puppy ID is equal to D-B column
and it's an integer type column.
So say D-B integer.
But then we also clarify that it's actually a foreign key.
So we'll say foreign key and then we pass in the string puppies ID.
So where does puppies the ID comes from.
Well remember the table name here for puppy weeks clarify that it's puppies and the column that we're
seeking with the primary key a puppy is called ID.
So puppies that ID is what we're passing in as a string here which goes into the foreign key which remember
a foreign key is just a primary key of another table.
So that's why we're passing and Papy the in that manner.
Now finally let's give in in its statement so we can actually create toys later on we'll say self item
item name actually and then we'll take in the puppy.
So that basically says when you create a toy you have to assign it to a puppy will say self item name
is equal to the item name that's passed in and then we'll say self puppy ID is equal to the puppy ID
that's passed in save that and move on to owner We're going to do here say table name and set it equal
to.
Owners will create a primary key here will say D-B column and this will be an integer column very similar
to what we've just been doing before.
For the other unique IDs so D-B integer.
And then we'll also set this to be a primary key primary key is true.
And then every owner can have a name.
So this will be a column and then the type are going to pass and here it's just a normal text column
for the owner.
And then we're going to connect the owner to the puppy.
So remember the the one to one relationship we're going to say puppy underscore ID and said equal to
D-B column and it's an integer column and very similar we say D-B foreign key and we passen the string
puppies.
ID as we just mentioned earlier.
So now we have the owner connected to the puppy Id call him up here.
Last thing I want to do is set init method so we can actually create owners will say if underscore and
that underscore underscore then we'll say self name puppy ID.
So again this basically concludes that when we create an owner We're going to assign them a puppy a
self-taught name sequel to name and then soft top puppy ID is equal to puppy ID.
All right.
So we just went through a lot of code in the next lecture.
We're actually going to connect all of this together and perform the migrations as well as create some
puppies some toys and some owners and see how that all plays out.
Let's run a very quick review of what we just covered here.
We went through the basics of setting up your flask model as well as your sequel light database created
the base directories configure application and then creator D-B as well as migration capabilities that
we created.
Three main models our first model puppy we set the table name.
We have basic columns such as a primary key column for ID the name of the puppy that we have a one to
many relationship where a puppy can have many toys and then we have a one to one relationship where
one puppy can only have one owner.
So we say owner and then we set the back references to puppy and then here we say use listicle to false
because it's a one to one relationship.
Then we set the init method so we can quickly create a puppy with just their name and then we have the
representation of the puppy.
So it's going to be if the puppy has an owner they'll report back the name of the puppy and the owner
or if not I'll just report back the name and then each puppy has a method where they can report the
toys they have number self-taught toys a list of toy items that is connected to then we have the toy
class here.
Very similar structure except now we set the relationship Habi ID to be a foreign key or we say puppies
the ID.
And then here's our method to actually create a toy and essentially do the same thing for owner.
Set the table name create the relationship column.
Again if a foreign key and then set the method in order to create owners.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
We're going to continue on the part two and the very next lecture where we actually implement these
models implement the database do the migrations and then play around with the actual entries in the
table.
We'll see at the next lecture.