Welcome back so far we've created our about and home pages as well as our pages for handling errors.
Now let's move on to the main two components.
That is the user component and the blog post component.
Before we can really begin to work with views or forms for those components it's probably a good idea
to set up their basic models so let's create a models that py file and set up our blog post model as
well as our user model and then create the databases for them.
Let's head over and begin.
All right.
Let's begin by filling out our models that PI file in case you haven't already created it underneath
the puppy company blog directory or folder.
I have a empty models not file.
So this is my model's not pi and this is what we're going to be filling out right now.
So to begin with we want to do is set up our classes Sugoi to have a user model class and I can pass
here for now as well as a blog post model class SOORLEY say pass there for now.
Now remember typically what we end up doing is we say user and we inherit from D-B model.
So in order to make that work I need to actually set up my database using flasks sequel alchemy.
Now all of that is going to be handled on the in that PI file.
So let's begin to set that up first.
So I'll come back to my in it that PI file directly underneath.
Puppy company blog.
So this is where I have a flask flask and I set up my application and want to add in a couple of more
imports here all say from flask underscore sequel alchemy import sequel alchemy.
And after I have created my application what I know to do is set up my database and I would recommend
that you do as we did in the provided notes and kind of comments out the major components here.
So we'll say this is the database set.
All right.
So I have this new component inside my end at the PI file and I'm going to set up my base directory.
So I'll say and I'm going to use OS did this on an import os as well.
So we'll see.
Import os and the base directory especially stuff we've already seen before will say oh estopped path
take the absolute path and here grab OS paff directory name and then pasand file.
And then here we're going to get our app call configuration and we're going to configure the sequel
alchemy underscore database underscore.
You are I and I'm going to set that equal to sequel like colon forward slash 4 slash forward slash plus
and then we'll say OS that path dot join and we'll say base directory data sequel like.
So that essentially sets up the actual connection to the database.
And then we're going to say app config and then just as we've done before we'll say sequel alchemy underscore
track underscore modifications and set that equal to false.
Once you've done that we can create our database object saying D-B is equal to sequel.
Alchemy pasand the app and we'll probably want to be able to migrate this as well.
So at the top also say from Flast underscore migrate in poor migrate that allows us to conduct migrations
when we actually set up our databases.
So then after I created the database using secret alchemy I'll just say migrate connecting my application
to the database.
OK so nothing new here really.
We just have our basic database set up right now it's all going underneath this in a pie file because
we want the app that for it to be very clean.
So we'll come back to our models not pie and here.
So we set up our D.B in the init file.
I can do the following.
I can say from puppy company blog import D-B.
And then what I'm going to do is say D-B the model as well as the blog post that's going to inherit
from D-B model.
So again what I'm doing is importing D-B from the in it that py file that we just created here.
So that's why I can say from puppie company blog because I'm using that and it file.
Ok let's begin by setting up our user model later on we're going to need to add in one more thing which
is that user Mixon in order to have authentication but right now we'll begin by setting up the attributes
for the user model.
First I'm going to just set up the table name so I'll say table name underscore underscore and set that
equal to users.
And then I will say Id equal to D-B that column and this is going to be an integer essentially just
a unique identifier for each user.
So since it's a unique identifier we'll say that the primary key attribute here is equal to true.
And then the next one is give yourself a little more room here.
The next we're going to set up is a profile image.
So right now we're going to kind of leave this blank.
But later on you'll see what happens when we actually set up our image Chandler.
For now we'll just say D-B that column and this is going to be D-B string.
And the reason for that is this essentially is going to be a link to a particular image file that the
user later on uploads.
So I'll say nullable equals false.
So essentially you can't get rid of their profile image so will provide a default for them.
So it will say default is equal to.
And here also a default profile dot P and G.
And later on we're going to do is inside of our static folder we're going to put in a PMG file there
as a default profile image.
So moving along we have our ID we have our profile image still some more work we need to do in order
to make that work out.
And then we're going to add in an e-mail.
So it's definitely seen this before.
DB column D-B string up to you.
The limitation on the string you want to put in.
So we can just say 64 here.
And in fact let's make the profile image may be a little larger we'll go and say 64 there too as far
as how long of an image name it can have.
Well say D-B string is 64.
And here will say that unique needs speak to true.
So we can have multiple emails and or a multiple of the same emails I should say and then we'll say
Index true and then we'll say user name is equal to the B column
DB string also set that to some arbitrary limit let's say 64 and this one also needs to be unique.
True and I will say index is true as well.
Now if you're wondering what this index is equal to true means it basically just sets up an index.
And this has to do a little more sequel than it does with flask or sequel alchemy.
But if you're interested in learning more about this you can just come and check out docs on sequel
alchemy and so Dachs that sequel alchemy.
Or check out the constraints and they have a whole discussion on indexes.
Again this has a little more to do a sequel than with actual flask.
So kind of leave it up to you if you're more interested in it but certainly just allows you to make
that column into an index so you can then use sort and it come back to our discussion here on finishing
off this user model.
So you set up the idea let me collapse this left hand side.
We've set up our id our profile image our email our username and all we need to do is set up the password
for the user.
So for this we're going to be using password hashing.
So in order to make sure that all works are going to import all say from and here we're going to use
the works.
If I'm pronouncing that correctly security and here we're going to import the generate password hash
as well as the check password hash functionality so we're going to save that.
And then also now that we're up here say from flask underscore loggin in poor user Mixon.
So this will allow us to have functionality such as is authenticated is active et cetera.
Our actual model inside the templates.
So we want to pass in that mix in here.
And save that.
So this allows the flask logging functionality and then lets set up that password so say password underscore
hash is equal to D-B column.
And this usually hashes to 128 bits will give it 28 string and then finally we're going to want to connect
the blog posts to a user or author.
So I'll say pose is equal to.
And here we're going to set up the relationship will say D-B relationship and we'll say blog post.
The other model here in the same file and we can go ahead and give this a back reference.
So this is a string.
Essentially it's going to look like an attribute call or actually dealing with the templates but it's
what we actually want to call the relationship between a blog post and a user.
So we're going to go ahead and call this author so that the author of the blog post is a user model
so we're going to say that the back reference here is just author and later on we'll see how we can
directly call author into the templates.
And we can make this connection happen easily.
So say true.
Then finally let's create an app method so we can actually make an instance of a user.
So it's actually create an instance of a user.
We're just going to have them at the beginning provide their e-mail their username and password.
So notice in the very beginning they're not going to provide their profile image.
Instead we're going to do is we're going to send it to a default.
And then they can visit their account page and update their profile image like we saw in the very first
lecture of the section.
So there's our method.
Now we're going to set up or attribute assignments we'll say self-doubt.
Email is equal to email self-taught username equal to the username pass then and then self.
And in this case it's the password hash is equal to generate password hash of the provided password
and then we're going to have a method for a user called check password
which is going to take itself and the password provided and we're going to be using this method during
our log interview and essentially the way is going to work is we're just going to return whether or
not the password provided at logged in when hashed matched our currently hashed password.
So say say return check password hash of the user's current password hash versus the provided password.
So we're going again to be using this in our log in to view and we've definitely seen kind of all of
this before.
Now we're really putting it together.
And then finally it's go ahead and have some sort of representation we can print out of a user so we'll
say the string representation pasand self.
We're just going to return that user.
So we'll say return and we'll use extreme formatting here username self thoughts username.
All right.
So the last thing I want to set up as we begin to really finalize this user model is the ability to
have a lock in a manager for this.
Then in order to make sure that we have a logging manager function working correctly we need to actually
set up our logging manager and we need to do this back at our unit thought PI file.
So come back in at that PI file and we're going to do here is safe from flask underscore loggin in poor
log in manager.
And then let's set up our log and configurations.
So after your database setup we're going to do is set up our log in configurations.
So here we just create a log in the manager objects or say logging manager is equal to an instance of
logging manager then we're going to pass in or apt to the logging manager.
So say logging manager in an app pasand the app and then we want to tell users what viewed to go to
when they need to log in.
We haven't actually created this view or even registered as template but we'll go ahead and do it now.
We'll say loggin manager thought loggin view is equal to users loggin.
So later on we're going to register a blueprint for users and that users blueprint going to have a view
called loggin and that's going to be this connection here.
But the reason we created this now is because I actually want to come back to my models that apply an
import that logging manager.
So here what I'm going to say is from Papy company blog import D.B and the logging manager object.
So not imported that logging manager.
So what I can do is say at wups that hash tag atts at log in underscore manager DAW user loader say
the F load user taken the user id and then we're going to return user the query doc get based off the
user id provided.
And again this is the function that really allows us to do that.
If users authenticated sort of stuff in our templates Okay so we technically there really go over anything
new.
The only thing we still need to tackle really is this profile image but the rest of this should feel
very familiar based off of our loggin authorization and authentication lectures.
If this feels fuzzy at all to you I would definitely suggest that you go back and review those lectures.
OK.
So we set up our user which is the more complicated of our two models.
Now let's finish up by completing our blog post model which remember has a relationship to the user
OK.
Let's begin by actually setting up that relationship.
So we're going to have each blog posts be connected to the user by saying users is equal to D-B relationship
and then just pasand the user table and then later on we'll see how we can set up an actual for key
connection.
Now beyond that connection of the relationship we need to set up an individual ID for each blog post.
So we'll say D-B column and then here will say D-B.
And that's just going to be an integer and it's a primary key.
So I'll say true 60 unique identifier and then we're going to do here is set up a user ID and that's
going to be the attribute that actually connects the blog post to the user.
So here we're going to say the following D.B column and that also happens to be an integer.
And then I will say D-B foreign key so we'll call foreign key and then we pass in the string user's
ID.
So where this comes from is the table name users.
So remember we set up that table name here.
Users and then ideas the attributes off of that table.
So say users ID is the actual foreign key for our blog posts user id attribute.
So there are users ID and then we also make this noble is equal to false.
So every blog post must have a user ID associated with it.
After that it's just the basic one so will say date is equal to Debe column and there's actually a special
date time storage for say D-B date time and also set down will equal to false.
So every blog post must have the latest published day.
And then we'll set a default and the default will just be date time UTC now.
So the way that's going to work is we're basically going to say when someone publishes a post it will
automatically default the date that it currently got published that.
So in order to use this date time functionality import pythons builtin date time.
So at the very top we're just going to add in one more or less import will save us from date time import
date time.
And this basically allows Python to automatically grab the date time stamp so that will be the date
of the actual blog post.
So basically just asking when was this last published.
We provide that day.
And then each blog post is going to have a title.
So that's just the normal string column D-B string.
So to you for how long you want to be able to make titles let's just go ahead and say 140 characters.
How long the title can be.
And this will also be knowable false.
So we have to provide a title and then we should also have to provide text right.
So the actual body text of the blog post.
So this will be a column D text and this will be nullable as equal to false OK then we're going to create
our init method so we can actually make an instance of a blog post.
So when someone creates a blog post all they need to do is provide the title the text and the user id
of who's creating it.
Everything else will add in ourselves so will automatically set up the primary key identifier and it
will also automatically default the date.
So then we'll say.
So that title is equal to title self-taught text is is equal to text and then self-taught.
User ID is equal to the user id provided.
And this is essentially all going to be occurring when we actually set up those views.
Finally let's create a way to print this out.
So we'll say the representation of this.
So if I ever want to print out a blog post maybe I'm debugging or something I'm just going to return
a string literal post ID and then passen self-taught ID and you can do other things in here whatever
you really want to pasan for this string representation.
You can also do things like passing the date.
So say self-taught date this or you can also even do the title.
So I add that in as well.
Self-taught title kind of really up to you what you want the print representation.
We actually I don't think we'll be printing this out.
Hopefully not almost when you do some debugging.
OK so let's zoom out speaking at the whole idea of what we just did here.
So what we did is we connected our database in the logging manager in our in a PI file remember we added
in those lines here.
So the database set up the log in configurations and then we created two models here a user model that
has a relationship to the blog post.
So every blog post has this foreign key of the user id and then we also set up the ability for user
names and passwords with the user model as well as a logging manager.
OK.
So if you have any questions on that feel free to check out the notes.
I would highly recommend they do a quick review of the user authentication lectures in case you are
confused on anything regarding the user model.
All right.
Coming up next we're going continue to expand on this and begin to dive in a little more into views
and templates.
We'll see if they're.