Welcome back everyone in this lecture we're going to finish our discussion of object oriented programming
by talking about special methods.
These are also called Dunder methods because of their use of double underscores.
Let's head over to the text editor and finish off our discussion.
All right.
As we already know there's built in functions in Python.
For example there's the built in length function that can check the length of a list or there's the
built in print function that can print out a list.
But notice that Lenk can check the length of a list but it could also check the length of a string.
So how does it do this.
How does length as a built in method know what to return when you ask the length of the list or the
length of the string or the length of any other object.
And what if we want our own objects to be able to interact with built in functions such as Eliane and
Prince.
In that case we can use what's known as special methods.
So we're going to be creating special methods within our own classes or objects in order to be able
to interact with these built in length and print functionalities.
I'm going to create a class and we're going to call this class book and we're going to have an in it
method and our book is going to take in a tidal an author and the number of pages and then we'll say
self-taught title is equal to title self-taught author is equal to author and then self-taught pages
is equal to the pages.
OK so there's our book save this and then let's see what happens if I create an instance of the book
so I'll say my book is equal to an instance of the book and I need to pass in the attributes title author
pages.
So let's say the title is Jose.
Actually let's say the title is python rocks the author is Jose.
And then we'll say number of pages is there's 250 pages in this book so I'm going to save that.
So I've already created my book.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to print out my book.
Now what do you think is actually going to print out when I print my book.
Let's find out.
We'll say pass on my example that pi and Currently when you print out my book right now I'm just going
to say hey you have a book object at this location in memory.
Now you can actually decide what gets displayed when you print out my book and the way you can do that
is through the use of a special method and the special method for that.
There's actually two options.
One is underscore underscore SDR underscore underscore that the one we're going to be using since it's
used more often in the flash documentation is our R and that's basically going to ask for what's the
representation for this object when you want it to be printed out.
So I'll say self.
And then we can return whatever we want to be printed out when you print out a book object.
And notice here I'm saying return not print.
So we're going to say using string literal notation.
The title is self-taught title and the author is self-taught author save that.
OK so what I'm doing here is going to zoom out so you can see the whole picture.
I have the special method underscore underscore R E P R underscore underscore.
And what's going to happen is when you called print on my book print is going to ask hey do you have
a string representation of this book object I can use.
And then this special method is going to say yeah no problem here's the representation and it's going
to pasand the string and the string is using formatting to inject.
Self-taught title the title provided appear and self the author the author provided appear.
So now let's save this and try printing out our book again.
And now when I print out my book object I get title is python rocks author Jose.
So it's totally up to you what you want the actual representation of your object to be when you print
it out.
All you need to do is call this special method underscore underscore our EPR underscore underscore self
and then return whatever string you want to be printed out.
Again we're returning it not printing it here.
You print it out.
When you actually call that function just to make it very clear what's happening here I'll say print
out.
Yep actually returning.
So in saying F are EPR return up and I want to print out my book for with to run this again I'll just
say up and I'll see you up for any book no matter what title is what the author is and what the number
of pages are.
So it probably makes more sense to go for our original thing which was inject self-taught title and
author.
Again all we're doing here is when you print out the book object it's going to look down and say what's
the representation provided.
Now let's try another function that's built in.
Let's see if we can check the length of the book and we'll say Lankes book is equal to length of my
book.
And then at the very end I'll just print out the length of book.
Now let's see what happens if we actually try to run this.
You'll get an error and it says object of type book has no length.
And that actually makes sense.
What should Python use to represent the length of your book.
You haven't really told it so it can't just go in and guess because all it knows is that a book has
a title author and pages.
It's up to you to decide what the representation of the length should be.
In this case we can use a special method to do that.
We'll say the F and the method are related to the length function as underscore underscore.
L e n underscore underscore.
So this special length method is going to allow you to decide what you should return when you call length
on your actual object.
So this case let's go ahead and return the number of pages we'll say self-taught pages.
Save that and now when I run this again it's going to return back the length of the book is 250.
The number of pages I provided here.
Again these are the two special methods we're going to be using throughout the course for working class.
The string representation of an object.
So that's going to be really useful when you want to print things out to get an idea of what they are
and the length of an object that's going to be useful in order to interact with the length function.
And those are really the only two special methods we need to know.
Now you'll notice as you begin to type the F underscore underscore there's actually a ton of special
methods available for you here.
And if you have some sort of Python autocomplete you can get the whole list.
But in our case we really don't need to use all.
In fact mainly the one we're going to be using is this representation for a string to actually prints
out our own objects.
OK the last thing I want to mention is often in other Python courses including my own.
You've probably seen our EPR shown as as TR So this will bouffe work for our use cases but since the
Flast documentation tends to use our EPR for its actual string representation we're going to use that
method throughout the course.
Now if you're wondering what's the actual difference between SDR and our EPR.
You can do a simple Google search for that.
So say difference between underscore underscores TR and underscore underscore our EPR.
This discussion is kind of advanced and it's outside the scope of this particular course.
But you'll notice that there's actually lots and lots of posts because it's actually a really common
question.
But I would say for our level of discussion it's a to advance for us to really be able to see the differences
between them and our cases we can actually use both.
So you can check out the full discussion here.
It's kind of a long discussion and it's also a pretty advanced discussion so just keep that in mind.
If you're wondering what the differences for practical purposes there is none for our use cases.
OK so those are all the special methods we need to know just how to print out our own objects and how
to check the length of our own objects.
Coming up next we're ancestor new skills of object oriented programming through a project.
We'll see you there.