Welcome back in this lecture we're going to talk about your own links with templates.
Flast comes from a very convenient your URL for help function or helper function that allows us to easily
connect other template pages or files within our templates so far.
If we wanted to actually connect one HDMI file to another we would have had to have hard coded in that
path to the html file instead of the URL for function.
We're going to be able to easily just pass in the string name of that view and connect it.
Let's see how this works with both HTL templates as well as static files.
Let's head over to our text editor.
All right here we have opened the Web site we worked on last time we were talking about template inheritance
we remember back at the actual base studies team l file if we take a look at it it had a ref anchor
tag which right now just has a empty hash tag there basically meaning it's actually going to link to
anything.
All we can do is inside of this we set up two sets of curly braces and then use the function Yoro underscore
for and then imprint sees what you do is you actually pass in the view name that you want to link to.
So you come back here to basic that pie or and every happened to be calling your application that PI
file.
And you notice here we have function names index up name.
What you do is you choose one of these functions such as index and then you come back here and say x
4.
And as the string here you pass an index save.
And what that's going to do is now that is your link in this anchor tag and you can do a similar thing
using your L4 wherever you are able to pass that link in.
H tim L.
So we're going to do now is run our file.
Let's head over to the browser or just bring the browser in.
So right now I have puppies rock.
This is the home page.
If I go to like we did last time forward slash puppie slash rufous it says this is the page for rufous.
Now last time if I click puppies rock nothing would happen but this time I'm on another page and if
I click puppies rock it takes me back to the home page.
All right so it looks like that worked.
Notice again the syntax is just if we zoom in here is your URL underscore for then you're going to pass
in the name of the view function.
You want to connect to.
And then what's going to happen is automatically Jinja is going to say OK you want the URL for index.
I'm going to go over to your flossed file figure out where indexes and then render that template for
it.
Or just do whatever the index function actually does.
OK.
So that's how we can link to another template.
Let's not show you how we could link to a static file.
As a quick reminder.
I have another folder called static right above my templates folder and inside it that I have this nice
Papy underscore picked up peg what I going to do is now show you how you can use that.
Underscore for help function in order to actually link a static file such as the picture of this puppy.
We're going to do is let's go ahead and our puppy thought age Tim L file.
Right now we're just saying this is the page.
Let's add an encrypted that's going to reference that actual picture.
It's sort of say ref and again another little braces and we say your all four.
And then if you want to pasan a link for a file and set up a template what you do is you passen as a
stream the name of the actual folder that it's located in.
In most cases this will be static.
If it's a video or something you probably have it in a folder called media.
The free now we're just dealing of static files.
So I'll say it's static.
And then the second parameter pass in here is called file name.
And here you can pass in the name of the file.
In our case is called Puppy underscore.
Pick that up.
And then let's add in some text here so we can link it we'll just say here.
So then when a user clicks on here they should be able to see then the link to that puppy pic underneath
the static folder.
So let's go ahead and start our script non-basic the pie will bring in over our browser to the puppy
page.
Here we have it.
And so when I click here I now get to see I'm really zoomed in right now but this cute picture of the
pup.
OK.
And that's the main use cases for that you are L4 are going to be having a lot more practice with it
as our projects get larger.
It's going to be a really convenient one as a way to connect to your static files in another as a way
to link to your other views.
So this is the main way we're going to be using it for.
And in the name of that view function.
Thanks and we'll see at the next lecture.