Welcome back everyone for your O.P. project.
Exercise.
This is going to be a quick little project to make sure you've understood the very basics of object
oriented programming.
For this challenge you're going to create a bank account class that has two attributes an owner attributes
and a balance attribute.
It will also have two methods the withdrawal method and a deposit method as an added requirement.
Withdrawals may not exceed the available balance.
So if in your withdrawal method you'll have to add some logic that checks the actual balance on the
accounts.
Let's take a look at the finished class should be able to do.
I'm going to open up the project that py file.
Ok so this is what the actual file looks like for your project.
Again you need to create an account or bank account class that has an owner and balance attribute and
will be able to take deposits and also execute withdrawals and as the requirement the withdrawal can't
exceed the available balance so it should return some kind of error or warning message.
So he already set up a class account here and it's your job to fill it in with those two attributes
and those two methods.
Then you should be able to test the account by following along with these test steps.
So you should be able to instantiate the class.
So looks something like this.
Here we have an account where the owner's Jose and the balance is one hundred and they should be able
to print the account.
Remember those special methods were covered.
They should be able to show the account owner showed the account balance issue Bill to print out those
attributes then make a series of deposits and withdrawals.
So the posit $50 withdraw $75 and then at the end try to make a withdrawal that exceeds the available
balance which is 500 and that should return some sort of message saying sorry it can't be done.
OK.
Best of luck on this project.
We'll see you in the next lecture.
When we go over the solution.