Welcome back in this lecture we're going to show you an example of connecting an age female form to
your flask application.
In the H.M.S. of course we already learn how we can create in each team a forum for users to supply
information and then reroute them to other page after they submit the form.
Let's explore how we connect our flask application to these forms in one of the most basic manners.
Later on in the next section of the course called forms we're going to cover forms in a lot more detail
and show you much better ways of doing this before we head over to the text editor.
Let me show an example of what our actual Web site is going to look like.
All right.
This Twitter page is going to look like we have a navigation bar home page.
And when you click on this home page it'll take you back to the home page.
It says Welcome to puppy rock.
We're going to sign up for auditions to join this puppy band.
We'll click sign up for auditions.
OK welcome to the Sign-Up page.
And you can provide a name like Jose Portsea.
You submit the form and then say thanks for signing up.
I notice that it's actually going to grab that session information.
What I just provided my first and last name and report it back on the thank you page.
Keep in mind we still haven't learned how to save this to a database.
We're going to cover that in the future section of the course but we just have very basic functionality.
We also have this navigation bar again if I click home page will take me back to the home page.
Something else that we're going to add as far as functionality of the site is if someone goes the wrong
your.
For instance I just type in a bunch of jibberish Deryn it doesn't exist and enter we're going to show
them a custom four or four pages.
So this is our own custom four or four page we'll show you how to do that through app air handlers as
well.
OK.
We got a lot to cover so let's head over to text editor and get started.
Here I am at my text editor.
I have a very basic application skeleton set up in port flask Brender template and the Lessin going
to do is also import request from flask.
So it's going to be using that to actually grab information from the HMO form.
Now what I want to do is underneath my templates folder create a new file and I'm going to create a
base team l file and I'm going to create a couple of more HTML files.
So basically to tell us what we're going to extend from will say new here.
Let's create an index page for us.
Then it's basically going to be a sign up and think Page.
So we create two more files.
One is called Sign-Up h T.M. and then the last file is going to say new file will go ahead and say I
think you T.M. so after the user signs up we go ahead and say thank you.
OK so we have our basic thought PI what we're going to do is set up the views here and then connect
them to some templates.
Let's actually start off by editing the templates themselves.
Since there's more work to be done there.
First off we'll start with our base h T.M. first start off by just typing HTL and having that auto fill
in.
I'm going to copy and paste the links to the actual bootstrap code that we're going to be using.
We delete this title here and then I recommend that you're going to copy and paste a lot from our files
that we don't actually spend too much time worrying about getting everything correct.
But essentially I just linked a title called Puppy rock style sheet.
And the script from Bootstrap let me go ahead and it's close that so we get a little more room.
And in the body what I'm going to do is set up a navigation bar will say Nav..
And then let's give this Nev. a class that matches up with our bootstrap essentially.
It's very similar code to what we had before going to copy and paste that code right there.
Well let's put an anchor tag intern avocation bar will have the class of the sink or tag be equal to
nav bar Dasch brand and then Tref here.
We're going to be using that Yoro for function that we just talked about and we're going to link that
to an index page.
So this should just take you home.
So we'll have the actual XP Home Page So our navigation bar is going to have a little button.
Home page looks like a brand meaning it's a little larger when you click on it it takes it to your index
which you actually haven't defined yet and or that PI file.
We will do so at the end so we have a base H.A..
I'm going to save this in in order to extend it to the other HTL files.
What I need to do is create my block so I'll see block and then call this block content.
Let me save that.
Now we're going to move on to our index page.
So let's do that now.
So over here at our index page the essentially going to be the home page.
First I need to say extends and we're going to extend from baseline.
Each team will.
And then I will set the block the block was called content and then what I want to insert here I'll
say class is Jumbotron just so has a little bit of style to it.
And let's say welcome to puppie Iraq and let's imagine users want to sign up for this band.
It's a band full of puppies.
So we want to sign up for our puppy band and then we're going to say here is just create a little link
with an anchor tag and the anchor said will be your l4.
And this is where they will go to the sign up form so I'll make another view called sign up form that
directly links them to that Sign-Up page.
And technically you can call these you or whatever you want as long as the function that you later import
to your flask application matches that name.
So just keep an eye on these names and make sure that they match the functions you're going to be creating.
Since we have an anchor tag let's give it some text saying Sign up for auditions here.
So you're going to audition for a band and that's pretty much the end of it.
Simply the home page is just going to link to the sign up form page.
Now go to sign up each table and see what the puppies who want to join our band are going to have to
do so.
We're going to have a forum here.
But we first want to extend from that base team M-file will set up our block and this is going to be
content and let's have this whole thing be in a jumbotron and you can always copy and paste here in
case you're if I'm going a little too fast for you but hopefully you can keep up.
We're saying Welcome to the Sign-Up page and we're going to do is just say
fill out the form.
Notice we don't save any info.
That's something I want to make clear right now.
We haven't really learned how to connect a form to a database that's coming in a future section so don't
worry about that right now.
Essentially it's going to happen with someone who visit this web page.
They fill out the form.
We hit submit or they hit submit.
Then we take them to a thank you page but we're not actually going to store any of that information
permanently.
Now we're going to create our form in the sign up the H HTML page will save form and we won't go ahead.
We'll remove that class.
We also don't specify a method here because we're keeping things very simple and for the action.
That's basically what page should it go to after we actually call this I'm going to say your L for.
And we're going to take it to the think Page say think underscore you then we'll have a first and last
name and put all say label and this will say the label for first or last the person or puppy for their
first name and then we'll go ahead and connect it to an input.
Will be text and we'll just give it the name first.
No need to give it a value.
In this case and then we're going to copy and paste this for the last name of the user.
Well say last name and then call it last so that matches up with the sky right here last.
And then finally we need a way to submit we'll type out input type is submit and it doesn't need a name
we'll just give it a value like submit form.
All right so there's our sign up H team out page.
So now we're at the thank you page.
Let's go ahead and fill this out.
It's going to be pretty straightforward just something that says thank you to the user.
So we just want to say extends and then we'll say basically each team will will say block content and
we'll just have this be a Jumbotron that essentially says thank you so tough one.
Thanks for signing up.
Now what would be nice is if I was able to grab the first name and last name provided and then actually
send it to the page.
So what I'm going to do right now is just templating.
I will say first and last.
So now let's go back to our flask application and do kind of the heavy lifting here of connecting these
three views to some functions or just three templates of functions.
We'll start off with the first one which is the easiest.
It's just the home page.
So the home page is going to be essentially what we always do index.
And then we're going to return render a template for indexed H.
Then after that we want to set up the link for the Sign-Up form.
So the app thought route and we'll go ahead and have this your Elby sign up form and then we want to
call this function the same your all four though we chose earlier.
So recall from the index page we have a sign up form here.
So I want to copy this and make sure that my function name matches up that same way.
So I'll say sign up form and here we're going to render the template which is going to say make sure
I need to return this return rather template.
And here I'm just going to say Sign thought Timo
and then we'll say app thought route.
So after they sign up we want to take them to the thank you page.
So save forward slash.
Thank you.
And it can be thank you underscore.
Whatever you want.
Well you cannot change is whatever you had yourself for.
So on our sign the page we can see here that we're saying go to are L for think underscore you so we'll
go ahead and copy that and then we'll bring it back to our actual flask application.
So we'll come back to this and say the E-F think underscore you and it's quite common to make sure that
this function name matches up with your name.
It's not necessary but it's nice that we can directly relate the oral to the function.
So go ahead and match it up here we'll say thank you.
And then this is where we're actually using this request that we just imported.
We're going to say is once the user actually fills out that Sign-Up form we technically have a live
session with that user or we can grab information and the way we do this with an HMO form is the following.
We say request Dot's args so the arguments of the request get and then we're going to grab first because
the name if we take a look back at our Sign-Up HTL page notice we set the name for first in the name
here for last.
So that means we can actually grab those as the names of those requests objects that the user submits
when they actually submit the form.
We're going to grab that value for first that was provided in the HMO form will say first is equal to
that request and we'll do the same thing for last and this is how we can grab that request session information.
Now we're not going actually save this to a database that comes later in our studies.
But right now we're essentially just grabbing that first and last name provided and then we're going
to return render a template and say render a template for that thank you that HMO.
And we're going to pasan first equal to first and last equal to lips last because remember on our page
we take a look at it again.
We have this first and last there.
OK so there's our basic HTL Let's go out and make sure that we didn't make any mistakes.
So I'm going to run this python basic pie to enter.
Looks like I have no typos there.
If you are getting a typo at this stage go ahead and copy and paste the code.
Or just run our files directly.
We did a lot of code here.
It's really easy to make a typo so keep that in mind.
It's always best just to use our notes directly so we don't waste time.
But I'm going to come over here if my browser zoom in just a little bit.
Our home page is looking good.
Let's click on the home page.
Notice it keeps reloading the home page that looks right reading click sign up for additions here.
Click on that before we submit a first name or last name.
Let's double check that nav bar.
If I click on home page it should take me back to the home page so that nav bar is working out the URL
for.
That's good to know.
Sign up for auditions.
Let's sign up.
Will say Jose Portsea and then it says fill out the form.
Notice we don't save any info so that means we're not saving anything to our actual database.
And here we can see it says thanks for signing up Jose.
Portsea.
Now we want to do is add in our own custom for forthought h tim L..
So we need to do is create an html template file to actually hold our 4 or 4 error code.
So let's go ahead and add that in going to come back here under templates say new file and create one
called for 0 4 h T.M. and let's that up.
We need to do here are 4 or 4.
It's going to extend just like all the other files from the base HTL.
That way you can have the nav bar ticking them back to the home page.
So I'll say block content and then essentially just add whatever message you want to occur when a user
goes to the wrong page.
I'll just have a little Jumbotron here that says Sorry could not find the page will save that.
Now that we have our 4 or 4 h HTML file ready to go we need to connect it to a view so we'll come back
to basic that pie and this view is going to be a little special.
It's not going to be a normal app route.
It's going to be app dot error handler careful not to make a typo here and you're going to pass in the
4 0 4 error code and then we're going to do is save page underscore not underscore found and you get
a.
E.
Technically you can be anything but by convention it's E for air and then we're going to return render
underscored template and then whatever the name of your HTML file you want to show for a 4 0 for error.
In this case we'll call it 4 for that HTL.
Then you say comma for 0 4.
Let's save that and run our file so running our flask application looks like it's running just fine.
We're going to go back to the home page here.
So have my home page and my browser.
Sign up for auditions.
That's still all working.
But let's imagine that we spell a page wrong and we hit enter.
Now we get the connection.
Hey sorry page not found and we now have our navigation bar so they can go back to the home page instead
of just saying that the fault Yoro.
OK so that's the basics of connecting h HTML form to your flask application.
Notice here we're a bit limited because we don't know how to save all this information to a database.
It is there we're just grabbing the raw arguments from the request that the user gave.
Later on we're going to see a much better way of creating a sign up form using a flask form library
called WITF forms and that we can let Flast do most of the heavy lifting on the Python side instead
of having to manually type out A-stan out forms.
A lot of information is coming in the next section and then the session after that called databases.
We're going to show you how you can actually permanently save this information.
So step by step we're building more and more functionality interweb sites.
Though we have to make sure that we walk before we run.
So this is just the very basics of connecting a raw each time form to flask.
Later on we're going to cover a lot more capabilities and a lot more detail.
Thanks and we'll see at the next lecture.