Welcome back everyone.
Let's go ahead and work through the solutions for the object oriented programming exercise.
All right here we are at the exercise.
I want to scroll down until we get to our actual class account and let's start filling in.
So again it's up to you if it's optional if you open and close princes or no princes Python 3 won't
complain either way.
But first we're going to need to have our own method because remember we want two attributes we want
an owner attribute and a balance attribute.
So we always start with self and then we'll say owner and then balance and especially if you want.
You can set a default balance of zero and we'll say colon and they will assign those attributes so I'll
say self-taught owner is equal to the owner it's passed in and then self-taught balance is equal to
balance.
OK.
So we also want to be able to print our actual account owner and account balance.
So let's go ahead and set that up right now.
Since you already have everything we need for it will create either an S T or a method or if you want
a representation method.
It's kind of up to you when you want to choose in this case will work the exact same way and then we'll
say that the account owner is self-taught owner.
How I'm using string literals here and then we'll say a count let's just say balance balance is self-taught
balance.
So so far I've set up my attributes and they set up my printing capabilities.
All I need to do is set up to deposit and withdraw methods will start the deposit method pasand self
to make sure the positing to this instance of the account and then we'll create a variable called deposit
amount or DGP underscore amitie and then we'll take our current balance and we're going to set it equal
to the current balance plus the deposited amount and then we can also print out a message like deposit
was accepted.
It's up to you whether or not you want to print that but all we're doing here is when someone calls
deposit they pasan a deposit amount and then you take your current balance add that deposit and then
set that to be your current balance.
Notice here how I'm using self to reference the self balance.
And finally we're going to have a withdrawal method.
So say withdrawal very similar is going to pass and solve.
Except this time we'll say it's a WD amount or withdrawal amount they'll say if self-taught balance
is greater than or equal to the withdrawal amounts I'll take my current balance and I'll stick to my
current balance minus the withdrawal amount.
And then I will print something like withdrawal successful else.
That means I actually don't have enough money for this withdrawal yet.
So I will edit my balance and then I'll just say Prince funds not available.
All right.
So let's zoom out so you can see kind of everything that's going on here.
So all we did was we set up our method to set up the attributes the owner attribute and the balance
attribute.
Then we set up our representation for the string.
So if we want to print out our account we get the account owner and balance.
You could have had a lot of flexibility as far as what you actually want to be printing out.
Then we set a deposit.
So we take our current balance as a deposit amount and print deposit that and then for the withdrawal
we first want to check do we actually have enough balance is our balance greater than or equal to the
overall amount.
If so then we can remove that of Charle amount say withdrawal was successful else will print funds not
available.
So let's do all this will instantiate a class will print the object and then I'm going to print the
account owner or show the account balance as well.
So will print that out.
Then we'll make a deposit.
No need to print that out because it's just an action being performed.
Then I'll make a withdrawal.
So this should be withdrawal I believe.
Let me make sure we match that up.
Withdrawal and then also say withdrawal here so let's save this.
Open this up and run it.
So we'll say Python and I wrote this in my example the PI file saw hit enter and see.
So I have Jose 100 my deposit fifty was accepted.
That makes sense.
My withdrawal was successful.
Seventy five.
That makes sense.
However when I try to withdraw 500 funds were not available.
Which also makes sense.
OK.
That's all you had to do for this project.
Again if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A for us but hopefully once you're able to view
the solution you can see how everything connects together.
We'll see you at the next lecture where we'll talk about decorator's.