Welcome back everyone.
So we just learn about all the data types and data structures.
Now it's time to do a quick exercise review underneath your Paice on level 1 folder.
You should find a 0 5.
Exercise underscore reviewed that PI file.
Basically a Python script that has a bunch of common problems free to solve.
So just five quick problems for understanding it should be pretty straightforward.
We're now going to jump over to the Adam text editor and walk you through what these problems are expected
to do.
OK let's head over there now.
OK.
So this is what the file actually looks like basically just a bunch of comments and then you're given
a problem statement so there's five problems here.
So problem one says given this string aesthetical to a flask use indexing to print out the following
f s s k and Ls and k.
So for example for the first one it should just be something really simple like you're grabbing F which
should be the first letter in S which say s indexed at zero.
So that would be the answer for this first one.
So then you need to do it for these other letters and then bonus use indexing to reverse the string.
So we might have mentioned that during the lectures.
See if you can figure it out.
Again that's a bonus problem not a huge issue if you can't figure it out.
Problem 2 is given this nested list and Lotusphere there's a list inside of another list assigned to
L..
Or we could call this you know my list.
We want you to reassign hello this string hello to be goodbye.
How would you actually use that.
You should use two sets of indexing off of that object.
Problem 3 is using keys and indexing grab Hello from the following dictionaries.
So this one's really easy.
Just a simple key.
And then you have hello.
And then the next one notice you'll have a nested dictionary here.
So it's going to take two key calls and then here you have a list and dictionary.
So this was probably really tricky.
Keep that in mind.
This one's going to be one you want to break down piece by piece.
So first try K-1 see what you get back and keep building off of that.
Again this one's really tricky.
Problem for is using a set find the unique values inside the list.
We should a really similar example to this in the lecture so maybe review the lecture if you forgot
how to do that problem.
5 If you're given these two variables age sequel to four and name the Sami I want you to use print formatting
either the dot format method or the string literal method to pronounce the name hello or print out the
sentence.
Hello my dog's name is Sammy and he is four years old.
Again you've given two variables here.
Use print formatting like we discussed in the streams lecture to actually print out a string that looks
like this.
OK.
Best of luck in the next lecture.
We'll go over the solutions.