Hey guys this is adland a second instructor here.
Now it is my turn to welcome you into the computer vision.
It is of course and we're going to start with this page that we made for you which contains all the
resources of the course.
So not only contains the code templates but also as you will see some additional reading to accompany
your understanding of the theory explains in the course.
So this page you can find it at.
W w w that super data signs that come slash computer haif envision and now in this quilt is all I'm
going to walk you through this page and show you how you can get all these resources.
So as you can see it follows the exact same structure as in the course with our three modules and it
starts with this section.
Welcome to the course that contains the computer vision is that template folder which contains the whole
folder structure with three modules.
But don't be surprised if the folders inside are empty.
That is just for you to have the main folder of the course that I will use in the different tutorials
and then later on when you start the modules you will add the different codes and the different resources
you want.
So that's just for you to start with the right structure and then you have this second link here which
is the link to download the virtual platform the virtual platform is a special new tool.
In this course it contains all the pre-installed packages that you will need to execute the different
models who will implement.
And so basically once you install the virtual platform you will never have any installation to worry
about.
All right.
And then you have two different modules of the Course module one face detection with open Sivy module
two object detection with SSD and module 3 image creation with guns and for each of the three modules
you will find the same structure.
First we start with some additional reading so that after you watched intuition lectures by your real
Who then will recommend some papers to read.
Well these are these papers here that are in the additional reading section.
So I recommend to read them that will give you an even deeper understanding of the theory and then of
course you have the code template.
So that's where you download the codes and the data sets for you to execute the models.
So in the code you will see each time one commented version of the code where each line of code is commented
and one non-committed version of the code and that will be the code we will implement.
So these are just the same codes.
But you can choose to see the comments or not.
And after we implement the code together we will tackle the homework challenge of the section.
And as you can see for module one face detection with open city the challenge will be to build a happiness
detector and for this homework and the others you will find the homework challenge instructions and
the homework challenge solution containing the code of the solution.
And then of course new to me you will find a video lecture that explains the solution.
All right and then that's the same for the other modules in module too early detection with SSD will
find again some additional reading the code templates.
So here make sure to download the right code template for your system because as you can see the code
is different whether you have a Mac in Linux or a windows.
So make sure to download the right one.
But then in this module you will find a special element.
It's this one here training the SSD.
We wanted to separate this element in the structure because training SSD is really overwhelming with
a huge code.
So we wanted to put it separately and therefore by clicking on this link you will get the code that
you can use to train the SSD model and the other code the code here is just for the detection so only
for this module we separated the detection and the training.
And then again you'll find the homework challenge of module 2 which is by the way really exciting you
will see the video.
It is about detecting some epic horses galloping in Monument Valley.
So it's actually my favorite Homer challenge in the course and you'll see we're going to have a lot
of fun on this.
And so you will find again the homework challenge instructions and the homework challenge solution.
And then eventually in module 3 image creation with Gannes you will find your additional reading and
then you will find the code templates which contains not only the code to create some images with generative
as the social networks but also the code of the training.
And this time we do everything at the same time.
All right.
And no homework for this section because you will see that this is a pretty big section and that's because
we implement the whole training from scratch.
But a great and actually the most relevant homework would be to reproduce yourself.
The training that is recode from scratch the implementation of the Gannes including the training you're
going to see that this will already be huge an excellent practice.
All right so that's this page.
Make sure to always have it open with you.
It contains some really valuable resources that I highly recommend to check out regularly.
And now Rylands the virtual platform in the next story also make sure before to click on this link here
to download it.
And then once it's downloaded we will install it in the next Tauriel.
Until then enjoy computer vision.