Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
So here we are ready for the big first step of the training that is updating the weight of the neural
network of the discriminator.
This big first step we're going to tackle it in three subsets.
The first step is to train the discriminator with a real image of the data set.
The second step is to train the discriminator with this time a fake image generated by the generator.
And finally will back propagate the total error which will be the sum of the errors of these two previous
trainings.
So now I have a question for you.
Why do we have to do a training of the discriminator with both a real image of the dataset and a fake
image generated by the generator.
And the answer is that simply because we want to train the discriminator to see and understand what's
real and what's fake and therefore to make the discriminator understand that well we need to give him
the two different ground tricks we need to give him the ground truth of what's real and the ground truth
of what's fake.
So the ground truth of what's real is of course the real image and the ground truth of what's fake is
of course the fake image generated by the generator.
So if you understand that well it will be very easy these two subsets will appear very natural to you.
And so now if you're ready let's do these three steps.
But before we start with the first obstacle is training the discriminator with a real image of the data
set to train it to understand what's real.
Well we need to initialize the gradient of the discriminator with respect to the weight to zero and
to do this it's very simple we take the neural network of the discriminator which we called Nedney then
we added that and then we use the zero underscore grad function and that will automatically initialize
to zero the gradients with respect to the weights.
So that's done and now we can move on to the first subset that is training the discriminator with a
real image of the day set.
All right so the first thing we need to do is get the real images.
Why do I say real images.
That's because we're going to get in fact a mini batch of real images and that's because a neural network
actually accept as inputs some many batches of single inputs like single images and therefore we have
to work with many batches but that's perfect because we already iterated through some many batches that
we got with a loader.
So we already have these mini batches.
And therefore as you will see right now it will be very easy to get these in any batch of real images.
So this input many batch I'm going to call it real and it's actually going to be the first element of
our mini batch data.
Right now we're dealing with a specific mini batch which is data and data is composed of two elements.
The first elements are the real images themselves and the second element are the labels.
But we don't really care about the labels right now.
So I'm just getting the first elements and to do that to get the first element of technique is to add
a come here and then an underscore to specify We actually don't care about the second element and then
equals data.
All right so perfect.
We have our input but it is not yet an accepted input of a neural network in by torche by torche neural
networks only accept the input in Torch variables and I remind that a torch very well is a highly advanced
variable that contains both a sensor and a gradient.
Right now we have to sensor because real is actually a sensor of images.
But we need to wrap it into a torch very well to associate it with a gradient and to do this we're going
to introduce a new varry Walters we're going to call input because this will be the input of the neural
network and this input is going to be an object of the variable class which will take his arguments
are real input images in them in batch and now are input images are not only in too many Bache but also
in a torch variable.
So now we're allowed to feed the neural network with this input.
But before that we will get the target.
And now the line of good I'm going to type is very very important at this stage.
You're going to try to guess what the target is going to be.
We're going to have to target for the different training this training and the following training.
And so try to guess what exactly these targets are going to be.
So I'm going to introduce here a new target.
So now according to you what is this target going to be.
Well since we are training the discriminator with a real image of the data set to train him to under
one and see what's real what is a real image.
Well for each of the real image of the million batch Well we need to set the target to one white one.
That's because remember zero corresponds to rejection.
The image is rejected by the discriminator and one corresponds to acceptance.
The image is accepted by the discriminator and therefore we need to set the target to one because we
need to specify to the discriminator that the ground truth is actually one to ground truth is the image
is real.
So the image gets a 1.
And that's why right now we're going to create a torch sensor that is going to have the size of the
mini match.
And that is going to be composed of only once we will have a one for each of the input image of the
mini batch.
So there we go.
Let's do this.
We need to take the torch library and then very simply we have a great function that is called.
And that will create this sensor only once.
And as you might guess what we need input in this one function is actually the size of the sensor that
is how many ones do we want and we want as many ones as they are real images in the real input mini
batch.
So how can we get this size of the input batch.
Well we just need to take our input many batch and then add that and then add size with some parenthesis
input that size contains the size of the mini batch that is contains the number of real images of the
input many batch and therefore also the number of ones the target should contain.
But as you notice I said contains.
And to get the actual number we need to take the first index of this element in that size which is zero.
So input that size of index 0 will return you the size of the mean bitch.
Perfect.
And now question Are we allowed to move onto the next step.
No we're not.
The reason is we have to wrap the target in a torch viable.
Indeed we're going to compute some gradients of the target as well and therefore we need to attach this
target sensor to a gradient inside a torch variable.
So I'm going to take my variable class again and I'm going to put everything inside some parenthesis
so that target becomes an object of the variable class taking his argument this torch and sort of once
right.
And now we have the inputs and the target.
So we know what to do next.
We need to get the outputs.
So let's do this let's get the output well to get the output.
Actually pretty fun and very simple.
We'll first introduce a new variable for the output output and we are going to call our neural network
of the discriminator so needy and we are going to feed this neural network with of course the inputs
the input which is a torch Vrable of a mini batch of real images.
And so inside here I just need to input Well input.
All right.
So through the main metal module that forward propagates the real input images of the mini match inside
the neural network of the discriminator to get for each of these real inputs images the prediction of
the discriminator whether they should be accepted or not.
So I remind that for each of these real images the output that is a prediction is a number between 0
and 1 and a number close to zero means that the discriminator will reject the image and a number close
to 1 means that the discriminator will accept the image.
So that's the discriminating number and it's a number between 0 and 1.
All right perfect.
And now that we have target full of ones and the outputs.
Well guess what we're going to get.
Well of course we're going to get the error.
The first error coming from this first training of the discriminator with the real image ground troops.
And so this specific first arrow we're going to call it e r r d.
Because we're also going to have an area for the generator but much later that is in the second big
step of the training.
E r r d.
And since this area corresponds to the real ground truth.
Well I'm going to add here and underscore and real.
All right.
We are the real and now to get this error.
Well what should I take I should take my criterion.
We have a new object that will compute the last error for us.
It will compute the last area between the output and the target.
So that's perfect.
And as you might guess inside this concern we need two inputs.
First the output and second the target.
And there we go.
We have our first last error of the discriminator the one corresponding to the training of the discriminator
with the real images to train it to understand to recognize what's real real images perfect.
And now we're ready to move on to the second step of the training of the discriminator.
It is the training with this time a fake image generated by the generator.
So this time we're training the discriminator to see and understand what's fake.
That is to recognize fake images.
So we're going to do the same process as we did here.
We're going to get first the input then the target then the output then this will generate a loss which
will call our already underscore fake and we'll be done with this second step.
And then finally we'll get the all error as to some of these two errors are already real and are fake.
And then we'll do the big back propagation of this total error.
Back inside the neural network of the discriminator.
So let's do this let's tackle this second training with the ground truth of the vague images and let's
start right now by getting the inputs.
So it's actually not that direct according to you.
How are we going to get the input which this time should be a mini batch of fake images.
Well if you remember what we did here when defining the architecture of the generator.
Well remember that the first inverted convolution takes as input a random vector of size 100.
And that I remind is because the generator is like an inverted CNN.
And since CNN takes as input some images and returns a flattened vector of one dimension.
Well this inverted CNN of the generator will do exactly the opposite it will take as input a vector
one dimension and we'll return the images or return some fake images and since we specify here that
the input vector is of size 100.
Well right now we are exactly going to create a vector of size 100.
This will be a random vector and that will represent some noise and then we'll feed the neural network
of the generator with this random vector and it will return some fake images.
Of course at the beginning it will return some images that look like nothing but over the books we will
update the weights so that the images look like something that is look like some real images.
But before doing that that's actually what we'll be doing.
The second step before doing that we need to train the discriminator to recognize what's fake.
So let's do this let's make this random vector of size 100.
And as we just said we're going to call it noise it actually represents some noise being a random input
vector.
So to create with by toward a vector of random values of a specific size Well it's actually very simple
We have a function for this.
This function we get it from the torch library of course and the name of this function is round and
runs.
And now inside this runs and function we need to input several arguments.
The first one is going to be the batch size which I remind is 64.
So that's the first argument we to input here.
And therefore I'm going to copy this batch size which I got for my one function.
There we go.
Copy and paste.
So we need to input this first argument of the batch size because we're not only going to create one
random vector of size 100 we're going to create of course a mini batch of random vectors of size 100.
So that then we can get a mini batch of fake images.
So input size corresponds to the size of the batch and then the second argument will be well the number
of elements we want in this vector and that is 100 because we specify in the architecture of the generator
that the input vector should be of size 100 and then we're going to add to arguments which are going
to be one and one and that is just to give to these random vectors some vague dimensions that will correspond
to a future map that is in fact instead of having 100 values in the vector.
It's like we will have 100 feature maps of size one by one meaning each of the 100 feature maps will
be a matrix of size one by one.
Great.
So now we get our noise.
So are we ready to move on to the next step.
Well no no we're not.
Because always for the same reason we have to wrap this mini batch of random vectors inside a variable.
Why is that.
That's because this noise here is going to be the input of the new one that work of the generator and
neural networks and pite which only accept torch variables.
So let's do that quickly.
Let's get our variable class and put this torche tensor of random vectors inside the variable so that
now noise becomes an object of this variable class containing this tensor.
Right.
And now we are allowed to move on to the next step.
So now according to you what is the next step.
Well obviously the next step is to get what we want.
That is this new ground truth.
We're looking for which of the fake images and the fake images we can now get them because we have the
right inputs of the neural network of the generator.
So let's get them we're going to call them fake.
But keep in mind that this will represent a mini batch of fake images a fake is the name of the match
so fake equals.
Then very simply again we're going to take the neural network of the generator to which we're going
to feed.
Well this noise mini batch containing the random vectors and therefore will get a mini batch of the
same size containing some fake images.
Awesome.
So now it is important to understand that this is the new input compared to this one.
This was the input containing the ground truth of the real images.
And this is a new input containing the ground truth of the fake images and therefore very quickly will
get the new output.
That is the output we'll get after feeding our discriminator with these new inputs fake images.
But before we get this outputs we need to get the target.
And now that's crucial to understand that this time the target is going to be a new kind of target.
And so what is it going to be.
Well this time since we are training the discriminator with some fake images we want to train it to
recognize the fake images we want to train it to recognize what's fake and therefore the target should
be the rejection of the images and the rejection of the images correspond to 0 0 means that the image
is rejected by the generator and therefore the target should be this time a sensor full of zeroes.
And so what I'm going to do I'm going to take this again because it's the same we're going to wrap it
into a viable but instead of using the ones function to get sensor full of ones.
Well I'm going to replace it by guess what zeros we have these very practical functions intuitive to
remember and by torche this time we have the zero's function that will return a sensor full of zeros
and the number of zeroes will be the size of the batch and put that size of index zero.
Perfect.
We have our new target.
And so now let's get the outputs.
So I'm going to introduce the variable for this output which I'm going to call outputs again and to
get my new output.
Well I'm going to take the neural network of the discriminator because we're still training discriminator
and I'm going to feed this do all that work with of course the fake images and then for each of the
fake images of the fake mini batch Well you'll get a prediction which is a discriminating number between
0 and 1.
And again if it is close to zero the discriminator will reject the image and if it is close to one it
will accept it.
All right perfect.
But we can do something actually better here.
We can save up some memory.
Remember that fake is a total variable because the output of a PI torche neural network is also a torch
variable and therefore it contains not only the tensor of the predictions the discriminating numbers
between 0 and 1 but also the gradients.
But actually we're not going to use this gradient after back propagating the error back inside the neural
network and when applying stochastic great in the sense.
So what we can do now is actually detach the gradient of this fake torche viable that will save up some
memory and that will speed up the computations.
And trust me we want to do this because the training is going to take quite a while.
So want to savor as much memory as possible and get the fastest computations as possible.
So we're going to detach the gradient here of this toward horrible and to do this we are done here and
then detach and then some parenthesis we absolutely don't care of the gradient of the output with respect
to the weight of the generator.
It will not be part of the considerations in stochastic gradient descent.
All right so now we have the time yet we have the output.
So guess what we're ready to have we are ready to have the new error corresponding to the training of
the discriminator with the fake images.
So let's do this.
And actually it's very simple we just need to copy this line because it's almost going to be the same.
We will just need to change the name of this new error.
So this new error corresponds to the training of the discriminator with the fake image.
So instead of calling it we are the real we will call it R R D fake.
And there we go and then that's the same because we have the same variable names for the outputs and
the target.
Wonderful.
And so now congratulations you are done with the two trainings that we had to do with the discriminator.
We trained the discriminator to recognize real images and fake images.
So two subsets done one more to go and we'll do the last one about back propagating the total error
back into the new one that work of discriminator and the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy computer vision.