Welcome everyone to this section on creating databases and tables.
So far we've really only focused on querying and reading data from an existing database and an existing
table.
We are now going to shift our focus to creating our own databases and tables using sequel commands so
if this section Well first going to discuss a few theoretical concepts such as choosing a data type
primary and foreign key as well as constraints.
Then we're gonna move into actual SQL commands to perform the creation of a database or a table using
create INSERT UPDATE delete alter and drop so as I mentioned we're first going to focus learning a few
theoretical concepts such as choosing the correct data type first stored value and setting possible
constraints on it which means the first few lectures in the section are just going to be slide lectures.
Then we'll also learn about things like primary and foreign keys.
Once we learn these theoretical concepts we'll move on to actually learning the cycle commands to implement
them.
Okay with that being said let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.