Hello everyone and welcome to the
overview of challenges lecture.
Throughout this course,
you're going to be receiving challenges.
These challenges are gonna allow you
to test your understanding of Postgres
and basic and more advanced SQL commands
as you go throughout the course.
The basis of these challenge scenarios will be
that you've just been hired as a SQL consultant
for a DVD rental store.
That's gonna be the basic background
as we give you challenges throughout the course.
As far as solutions to the challenges,
challenges are gonna start off very simple
and basically be asking you to repeat what you just saw
in the previous lecture, so don't worry
if you are finding challenges to be very, very basic
at the beginning, because that's how they are.
Later on, you're gonna be provided with solutions,
or walkthrough video solutions, for the tougher challenges.
So at first, the challenges are gonna start off simple
and ask you just to repeat what you just saw
in the previous lecture, and there's not gonna be
a specific solution to that challenge,
because you can just reference the previous lecture.
Later on though as the challenges get harder,
you'll be able to be provided with the solutions
the next lecture after the challenge lecture,
or we'll have a whole walkthrough video
in case it's a very difficult challenge.
Keep in mind that challenges may show up unannounced,
so always be ready for them.
With all that being said, I hope you enjoy these challenges,
and I really hope you do them.
They're gonna be a great way for you to get a chance
to test your understanding and test out your SQL knowledge
on the example database as we go along through the course.
Okay with that all being said,
I will see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.