Welcome back everyone to this lecture on order by.
You may have noticed that post Chris sequel sometimes returns the same request query results in a different
order meaning you may have run the exact same query on your computer and saw the results in a slightly
different order than what I have on my computer.
So in order to alleviate this issue if we want the results in a certain order we can use the order by
to sort rows based on a column value in either ascending or descending order.
So that would be alphabetical for string based columns or numerical order for numeric columns the basis
syntax for an order by statement would be as follows.
We select whatever columns we want from the table and then we decide to order by a specific column and
then Optionally you can add an HSC or a DSE whether you want the ordering or sorting to be ascending
or descending noticed the order by towards the end of the query.
Since we want to do any selection and filtering first before finally sorting so that means order by
is going to be towards the bottom of a query and one of the very last things that sequel actually performs.
So we're going to do all our selection or filtering if we use a where statement that should come before
the order by.
And then right at the and we'll go ahead and do any sorting and you use HSC to sort an ascending order
the EFC to sort in descending order.
If you leave it blank order by just uses a sending by default.
Now what's also interesting is you can use order by on multiple columns.
So this makes sense when one column has duplicate entries.
Let's take a look at this example database or example table really we have three columns here company
name and the sales for the individual at that company.
Notice here that we have duplicate entries under company so if we were to actually order by two columns
here we could select the company column the name column and the sales column in that order from this
table and then we order by company and then order by sales.
What does that actually mean.
Well it means we saw everything first based off the company column.
So that as we have Apple coming in first now better order than Google and then Xerox and then the corresponding
names also get lined up.
However we can then also order by the sales.
So after you've done the sorting based off the company column which makes sense because there's duplicate
values there within that particular company we do a second ordering which is by the sales column.
So note the sales now is an ascending order for each individual within the same company.
So we see Andrew with one hundred and then Zach with three hundred and then for Google we see clear
of two hundred and then David with five hundred.
So if you have duplicate values in a particular column and you want to sort not just by that particular
column but another column as well it makes sense to do an order mine with multiple columns and it's
going to sort based off the order you provide.
So Ill order by company first and then by sales let's go ahead and explore some more examples and P.G.
Advent on the DVD rental database.
OK here I am inside of P.G. admin.
What I'm going to do is explore the customer table.
So we will say select and let's select just everything from the customer table so we can take a quick
look at what the results look like here.
So notice we have this custom I.D. and more or less it seems to be in order except for this first one
which is five to four and then we also have the first name and last name.
Let's see if we can order everything based off the first name of the user.
So that would be an alphabetical order based off first name.
So we do here is towards the bottom we'll say order by and then we decide on the column.
So say order by first name.
If I don't leave anything here and just run this it'll automatically order it here in ascending order
so starting at a all the way down.
So then if you start going more and more down you'll eventually see bees and then sees this is the same
as if I had clarified ascending order.
So you may be wondering why bother clarifying ascending order there.
Well it's nice because we come back to read this or someone else is reading your code.
You can realize that they specifically wanted it in ascending order.
We can do the same for descending order by adding and DSC towards the end of this order by statement
and now notice we're starting at Zachary then Yvonne Yolanda and going down so starting at Zee and then
going down all the way to a.
Now notice here that we have different store ideas and we also have duplicate store ideas.
So we have story the one story to end story these shows up multiple times so we have multiple entries
for store I.D. which basically means that this particular customer let's say Zachary height goes to
store I.D. number one and the second customer Yvonne Watkins goes to story the number two.
So there's Yolanda Wilma et cetera.
Well we could do is first order by the store I.D. to get all the results per store and then organize
it by first name.
So the way this will work is I would say first order by store I.D..
And if I just run this by itself notice now I get store I.D. one first and then if I were to continue
scrolling here maybe a couple thousand so might be hard to actually see this but then I eventually get
store I.D. number two and then within this you'll notice that we scroll back up here.
I'm actually just going to select store the first name and last name columns.
So let's reduce this a little bit.
We'll say select the store I.D. column select the first name column and select the last name column
run this.
So if we take a look at this the store I.D. is now sorted starting at 1 and then eventually you scroll
down you'll see you'll see store number two but the actual entries themselves are in no particular order
within store I.D..
So what I could do is say first order by store I.D. which makes sense because they're duplicate values
in that particular column and then go ahead and order by first name.
So after you order by the store i.e. go ahead and order by first name run that.
And here we cannot see store I.D. number one then everything starting in alphabetical order based off
the first name.
And then we scroll down here to eventually hit store I.D. number two and we can see within story the
number two all the first names are now in alphabetical order starting with a.
And if you want you can always add an ascending and descending to each particular order by statement.
So I could say order the store I.D. on descending while ordering based off first name on ascending.
And notice here it's semicolon is optional.
So we run this and now at the very top we're starting at story the number two and then seeing the alphabetical
order Aaron et cetera.
And then eventually if I scroll down far enough I would say store I.D. number one.
The other thing to note here is that if I select just first name and last name and run this it will
still work which means I can technically sort by columns that I do not actually request in my select
statement.
Now whether or not you actually want to do that in a real world setting is really up to you.
Typically it would make sense to actually select the column you're ordering by because that just logically
looks better as a result and it'll kind of continue the logic of your SQL query into your results and
you'll understand whatever the person was trying to explore from a business standpoint.
But I do want you to be aware of the fact that you can technically order by a column and not select
it in your SELECT statement.
If for some reason you want to do that.
OK.
That's it for the order by lecture.
Coming up next we're going to quickly discuss a limit function which allows us to actually limit the
amount of rows that are returned in a query and then we'll give you some challenges for the order by
statement in conjunction with the limited statement.
I'll see you at the next lecture.