Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the in operator in certain cases.
You want to check for multiple possible value options.
For example if a user's name shows up in a list of known names.
So instead of having to write a bunch of or statements such as name as equal to David or name is equal
declare or name is equal to Zach.
We could use the in operator to just create a condition that quickly checks to see if the value is included
in a list of multiple options.
So you can check something like We're name in Zach David and Claire.
So the general syntax would be something like this value in and then a bunch of options.
So for example an example query could be select the color column from table where color in red blue.
So note here that the options are in this little list in parentheses.
And then we use the in operator to basically specify that we're checking for the color condition that
happens to be either red or blue.
These are bunch of or statements so anything red and anything blue will be returned to us and we can
always expand this to more options quickly so we can say now where the color is red or blue or green.
So essentially there's a little or statement in between all these.
Keep in mind you can also combine this with the not operator to essentially do this excluding these
values.
So our color is not in red or blue.
So essentially every color that is not red or blue let's go ahead and quickly see some examples in P.G.
Adam here at the query Ed. I'm going to take a look at the payment column or a payment table.
Well it's just like everything from payments which limit this to zero so we can take a look at the result
here and notice we have an amount column.
Let's first figure out what are the actual distinct values that are available to me in the amount column.
So what are the unique amounts that we're charging so we can say distinct amounts from payment and I'm
not going to limit this.
I want everything back.
I run this and I can say I have 10 8 and 9 1 any 9 etc. and what I could also do just for clarity is
order this by amount as we've seen before and I can order amount 0 ninety nine et cetera so maybe I
want to figure out all the orders that happen to be ninety nine cents one ninety eight and one ninety
nine.
So how could I do that.
Well what I could do is I could select any columns I want or everything from payment and then we'll
say where the amount is in and here we'll go ahead and specify ninety nine cents one ninety eight one
ninety nine.
Note here that I'm not using strings or quotes because there's a numeric data type.
So if we go ahead and run this we get back a bunch of values where the amounts happen to be in one in
a nine ninety nine cents or later on one ninety eight.
And if I wanted to figure out how many payments actually occurred that happened to be one of these three
values I could run this and I'll get back that there are three thousand three hundred one payments.
Now let's imagine I wanted the actual opposite information.
I wanted to count out how many payments were not 99 cents one dollar 98 cents or one ninety nine.
Well there's a couple of things I have to do here.
First notice here I'm going to have the parentheses of that list of options if I just add not in front
of this and run this then I get back the amount that is not in 99 cents one ninety eight and one ninety
nine.
So there's eleven thousand two hundred ninety five payments that are not these three values and let's
go ahead and explore this on a string column to finish this off.
We'll just say select everything from customer.
Take a quick look at this.
I have the first name and last name.
So let's go ahead and select all the columns from customer where the first name is in and let's just
give some options like John Jake and Julie we'll go ahead and run this.
And here I can see there was no one named Jake in this particular table but we did have a Julie.
And we did have a John.
OK so that's the way the operator works.
Main things keep in mind is that you're using parentheses here and then commas to separate out your
options and your options should be matching the general syntax of the column.
So we want to make sure that for numeric we're providing numerical analyst for strings for providing
these string of single quote strings here and we can always say not in if we wanted to see essentially
the exact opposite.
All right.
That's it for this lecture.
I'll see you at the next one.