Welcome back everyone to this lecture on like and I like.
And really it's more than just these two key words.
This lecture is about using pattern matching with string data.
We've already been able to perform direct comparisons against strings such as where first name is equal
to John.
But what happens if we want to match against a general pattern in a string that enables us to answer
questions such as all e-mails ending in at gmail dot com or all names that begin with a capital A The
like operator allows us to perform pattern matching against string data with the use of special wild
card characters.
So there's two main wildcard characters we're gonna cover right now and that is the percent sign which
matches any sequence of characters.
So essentially any number of characters.
And then there's the underscore which matches any single character.
Essentially a wild card for just a single character inside of a string so let's see a couple of examples
of this.
We'll start off with the percent sign.
So the percent sign is a wild card character for any sequence of letters or characters.
So this basically specify something like all names that begin with a capital A.
So we would say where name like and then a string where we have the capital A and then the percent sign
essentially saying you'll match.
Anything that starts for capital A and then has any number of sequence of characters effort then we
could do something like all names that end with a lower case A.
So then we have where name like.
And then we start off with the percent sign and end for lowercase a.
Essentially saying that anything or any sequence characters can come before that lowercase a notice
I've been saying things like uppercase or lowercase and that's because like is case sensitive.
However you can always use I like which is going to be case insensitive now using the underscore allows
us to replace just a single character.
For example let's imagine we were storing the Mission Impossible films and they were titled something
like Mission Space and possible space.
And then one two three or four etc. so we could do something like where a title like and then Mission
Impossible space.
And then the underscore just leaves a single wild card place to fill in whatever number we're looking
for.
Now you can use multiple underscores.
So imagine we had a version string codes in the format something like version numerical or hash tag
a four and then version hash tag B 7 etc..
So that would be something like where value like version hash tag.
And then to underscores where those two underscores can be filled of any sort of characters you want.
So the essentially leaves open any two characters to fill in those specific underscore positions.
Now what's nice about this is then we can begin to combine powder matching operators to create more
complex patterns.
So take a look at this example where we say we're a name like and then underscore HCR percent sign.
So if we think about what this is actually asking for this is returning back and we've color coded it
here a single wild card space for the first letter and then after H.P. are any sequence or any number
of characters can occur.
So here we have Cheryl which starts off a single C then HCR and that has two characters after that or
Teresa which has a capital T ACR and then ESEA.
So notice here it has to be just one character before HCR but then any number of characters after it.
So this allows for a really powerful pattern matching code.
Now we're just focusing on like and I like and those two wildcards of an underscore and a percent sign.
But in case you're familiar with something called regular expression or regex in other languages such
as Python or C++ I want you to keep in mind that postcard sequel actually does support these full regular
expression capabilities and you can check out the link here or just go to the docs and look up functions
matching and not only is have information on like an I like but also goes to much more detail on regular
expressions.
We're not going to cover those for right now instead of we'll just focus on like and I like let's check
out some examples in admin on our own DVD rental database OK here we are at the query editor.
Let's imagine I wanted to figure out how many people actually have a name that starts with J.
Well I could say select and we'll start off by selecting everything from the customer table and we're
going to check where their first name is like and then notice here and going to say capital J.
And then percent sign.
And then if I run this I get back the results for every one that has a first name that starts with the
letter J.
And if I wanted to actually figure out how many of these there were I could simply just provide a count
on the number of rows returned and I get back there sixty five people who have the first name it starts
with the letter J.
Now I can't keep adding on to this.
So then I could say something like and last name like and let's go ahead and do something such as.
Starts with an S I'm not actually sure if there's someone like this but we can run this and check.
OK it looks like there's five people.
Let's go ahead and explore those names.
Just grab all those rows for those customers run them.
And here we can see there's Julie Sanchez Jeffrey Speer et cetera.
OK.
So that's how it worked for the.
Percent sign and notice here that I had to make sure to use capital J because I'm using like if I were
to lowercase one of these and run this again I get back nothing because this is case sensitive.
Alternatively if I don't want to worry about case I can use I like run this and it'll return back the
results Whip's excellent changes to J.
Go and change that back to s run that again.
OK so there we go.
I like is case insensitive which means it doesn't matter if I use the lowercase J here or a capital
J and a capital S. I run this again it's gonna be the same result either way.
So I like is case insensitive like is case sensitive just something to keep in mind.
And we can always add in more than just a single wild card character for example we could do something
like this.
I can say first name like and let's imagine I wanted to figure out people who have the sequence of characters
e are somewhere in their name.
So I could do something like percent sign e r percent sign I run that.
And basically what that's asking for is anyone who has e r somewhere in their first name.
Now notice they'll return something back like Jennifer.
So E R is at the end of Jennifer and this sequence of characters can also be nothing it can be zero.
So that means e are just that's a show up anywhere inside this name.
So Kimberly has the E.R. here in the middle.
Katherine does as well but something like Heather has it at the end and that's still is OK with this
sort of code.
So just because it has a percent sign doesn't mean it has to fill in something there.
It can be blank and we can keep doing this.
Maybe we want something like her somewhere in the name run that and I can see Katherine Heather etc.
Or we can do what we did in the slides which is replace one of these with a single underscore which
means only one character is now allowed in that space.
So now when I run this I only see back.
Cheryl Theresa Sherry and Sherry often I so note the difference here is now only one character is allowed
before this h e r something that's also important to note and we'll finish this off is to show you that
you can also add in the not operator to essentially get the opposite.
So I can say Kimberly everything that's not like this.
Essentially everyone that isn't these four people so I can just run this and here I see everyone that
wasn't in that list of four people and then can combine this with things like logical operators such
as and so I could do something like let's say we're first name like and let's say has to start with
funny.
So we go ahead and run this and we can see everyone who's first name starts off funny and let's go ahead
and order it by the last name so we can start kind of getting more complicated here ordered by last
name run this and I could see I'm Austin Angel Barclay Agnes Bishop et cetera but let's imagine for
some reason I didn't want any one whose last name start off would be so I wanted to remove Barclay Bishop.
Bradley burns and Butterfield here.
Well it can begin adding things so her first name is like a and then we can say something like and last
name not like and then we'll say starts of a B.
So we go ahead and run this and now I can see I got rid of those people had a last name started for
a b and yet retain everyone who has a first name starts funny so you begin to create really custom patterns
for whatever you're looking for just these wild cards.
So keep in mind you always have the percent sign and the underscore available 2 percent sign for a long
sequence of characters underscore just for a single replacement character.
All right.
Thanks and we'll see you at the next lecture.