Welcome back everyone.
Before we discuss grouped by operations we should understand aggregate functions in general sequel provides
a variety of aggregate functions and post gross equals no exception to that and all the functions we
see here are available in any major sequel engine.
The main idea behind an aggregate function is to take multiple inputs and return a single output.
Now postscript sequel overrides many many different types of aggregate functions and you can check out
the link in this slide in order to go to the official documentation page.
But we're just going to discuss the most common aggregation functions in this particular lecture.
The most common aggregate functions are average which returns the average value or mean value there
is count which will actually already familiar with returns the number of values or rows returned.
Then there's Max Inman which return maximum minimum respectively.
And then there are some which returns the sum of all the values.
So it adds everything up in that particular column.
Keep in mind the aggregate function calls happen only in the select clause or the having clause.
We don't know about the having clause quite yet but we're going to learn about it later on in this section
some special notes to keep in mind for certain particular aggregate functions is the average call returns
a floating point value.
Many decimal places long.
So for example could be something like two point 3 4 2 4 1 8 etc. and you can use the round function
on top of average to specify precision after the decimal.
So we'll see that in this particular lecture.
And keep in mind that count simply returns number of rows which means by convention we could just use
count asterisk in order to see the number of rows.
You can either pass in a specific column or just an asterisk since it's essentially the same thing but
we've already discussed that before.
Let's go ahead and see some examples of aggregate functions in our own database going to head over to
PGA admin now.
All right let's begin by exploring the film tables since we'll be using that.
So we'll say select everything from film.
And if we run this we can see we have a film by the title description and then release here language
I.D. And we also have this replacement cost those we have several values here.
Let's imagine right off the bat I wanted to know what the minimum replacement cost was.
Well what I could do is call my aggregate function and then I'm going to call parentheses since this
is a function call and I call it on that column.
Replacement cost.
And when I run this it's going to return back the minimum replacement cost.
So at a minimum we're going to have to spend nine ninety nine to replace a certain film.
Now that also means certain films are more expensive so maybe we have a budgeting question asking what's
the most we can expect to pay to replace a film.
In that case we can just call Max and figure out the max on a replacement cost.
So the max on replacement costs now report it back is twenty nine ninety nine.
So that is the men and max function pretty self-explanatory and you can call them just on any column
here.
Keep in mind if we were to try to call something else like let's say I also wanted to call a film might
be column for some reason that doesn't really make sense.
And the reason for that is we're just actually calling an aggregate function on a column which means
Max replacement cost just returns a single value so it doesn't really make sense to call another column
with this in order to call other columns.
We'll have to learn about the group by statement which is coming up next.
So keep that in mind we are doing just simple calls or queries like this where we want to figure out
the men or max it doesn't really make sense to call other columns there since we're aggregating a bunch
of values to just a single value which you could do something like Min replacement cost
from film now we run this and that works.
And the reason this works is because that function maximum and this function minimum are both returning
a singular value.
So this will be the max and min for your replacement costs.
So keep in mind because those rows happen to match up that sort of query makes sense.
OK let's explore the other aggregate functions we talked about.
We're already familiar with count which essentially is counting the number of rows returned so we can
say select count in asterisk run that never turns back.
How many roads we have so we have 1000 films.
And keep in mind this works on any column.
So we could also say fill my D and that's essentially the same thing since that's the case by convention.
We typically just write an asterisk there and we're already familiar with count.
Let's imagine we wanted to know the average replacement cost what I could do is say average
replacement cost run that and that's going to grab the mean or average from the film table.
However you probably notice it looks a little strange here in this because by default this average call
gives you a lot of significant digits.
So if we expand this column there's time stretching it out here we can see that it's actually nineteen
point nine eight four and then a bunch of zeros.
So realistically you probably don't want all these significant digits past the decimal point.
So we can do is wrap this around with a round function and the round function actually takes in two
parameters.
One is the value you actually want around and then we're gonna put a comma here.
And how many decimal places want to round it too.
So we'll say to two decimal places and it's essentially a mathematical call on this result.
So it's going to take this result and then round it to just two places pass a decimal.
And then when I run this notice I get back nineteen dollars and ninety eight cents as the average replacement
cost from the film.
And we can always edit this if for some reason we wanted three decimal places.
We can run that and it keeps going.
If I said for as you may have guessed we'll start including the zero.
So you can either stretch out this column to see all the results if you don't have that rounding call
or realistically you're probably going to want to round this to some degree.
Again notice how round uses parentheses in order to organize its parameters or its inputs.
Here we have the input that we're trying to round.
And then the second parameter is how many decimal places so we discuss average count Max and men.
And then we finally have some which is going to sum all the values in a column.
So what does that actually mean.
If we take a look at our table again select everything from film let's imagine for some reason we had
to replace every single film.
So we were opening a duplicate store and had to replace every single film.
So we needed to figure out the total sum of the replacement cost column what we can do is say some replacement
cost we run this and it would cost us nineteen thousand nine hundred eighty four dollars to replace
all those movies.
And if we think about this value for a second it actually makes perfect sense.
Recall that we were taking the average replacement cost it was nineteen point ninety eight four.
And here we're replacing 1000 movies with the average replacement costs.
So which means the sum of the replacement cost should equal the average times the actual amount of movies
we have.
So that's essentially nineteen point nine eight four times a thousand movies which means again the total
cost to replace all the films would be nineteen thousand nine hundred and eighty four dollars.
All right.
So those are the aggregate functions by themselves that's average count max min and some you can hit
the slides and check out the link for more complex aggregate functions.
Some of them which we will go over in later lectures.
Right now these are really the most common ones.
You should know right off the bat and coming up next we're going to see how we can use this in conjunction
with group buy to create very powerful queries.
I'll see you at the next lecture.