Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the case statement we can use the case statement to only execute
secret code when certain conditions are met.
This is very similar to if else statements you can find in other programming languages such as C++ Javascript
Python etc..
Now there are two main ways to use a case statement and that is to use a general case statement or a
case expression.
Now keep in mind in many situations both methods can actually retrieve and lead to the same results.
So I want to first show you the syntax for a general case statement here's the syntax for the general
case and the way it works is at the very beginning.
We have this little block of code that we're going to start off with the case keyword and then we have
one and then keywords.
So we start off by saying case and then when a certain condition is met then have some sort of result
returned.
And then if we want to check against another condition we can keep listening.
So when condition 2 occurs then return result 2.
And finally at the end we can have an else statement which basically says if none of the above conditions
are met then return some final other result and then we can end that.
So let's go out and see an actual example of this.
So it's a little more clear.
Let's imagine that we have a very very simple table and in fact this table is just the table here I've
seen on the bottom where there's a column called A and there's two entries in this table or column entry
one an entry two.
So these are a test table and if I say select everything from the test table this is what shows up.
Now let me show you what it looks like.
If we want to use a general case statement so I will say select the a column comma case and then I can
do the following.
I can say.
CASE WHEN A is equal to 1 then string 1.
So what that is saying is if the instance in column A for that row happens to be equal to 1 then go
ahead and return the string 1 and let's check for other cases or conditions when A is equal to 2 then
return the result string to else if that's not 1 or if it's not to return.
Other AND THEN I SAY N and then from whatever table I want.
So the way this works is we're basically inserting this general case statement inside of this select
call almost as if it was another column.
So notice here I'm saying select a comma and then I have this case statement inserted which is basically
going to return the results based off those conditions as another column.
So the column is by default called case but you can always use an alias to name it something else.
So you could say something like case when a is equal to 1 then 1 when a is equal to then 2 else other
as label and then that's going to relabel that return the column.
So basically the way I like to think about this is for the general case you're just essentially substituting
calling a column that already exists with your own general case statement that is going to return certain
results based off certain conditions within another column and then you just end the case letting sequel
note that you're going to continue on with the rest your query such as doing something like from test
and if you want you can add things like order by after that.
So the way I like to think about this is the general case is kind of this giant substitute for a column
call Rican define your own conditional logic.
As far as what you want returned now that was the general case statement let's explore the case expression
syntax and this is sometimes confusing to beginners because it looks very similar to the general case
statement.
The main difference is that the case expression syntax first evaluates an expression and then compares
the result with each value in the when clauses sequentially.
So this is the case expression syntax and the difference is pretty subtle but you'll see here that right
in front of the case we're actually going to evaluate an expression and then the when statements instead
of having actual conditions within them they're just going to have value so they're basically checking
for when this expression is equal to value 1 then return result 1 the case where this expression is
equal to value to then return result to else return some other result and then end that case expression
so let's go ahead and rewrite our previous example.
So the way this works is notice here.
I no longer have to actually have that condition after the one with the case expression syntax.
I'm now saying Case A.
So that's my expression just the column itself when it's equal to one then one when it's equal to two
then two else other.
So this is basically saving you the step of having to check those conditions yourself manually.
You can think of the case expression as something to use when you're just going to do a bunch of checks
for something being equal or equality.
The general case syntax that we saw earlier let me go back to it here we can see this is actually going
to be more flexible because the case expression syntax essentially just checks for equal or equality
to the provided expression which can be as simple as a single column provided.
The general case syntax allows us to do all kinds of conditional checks.
So can we can do things like when a is in between the values of five and 10.
Or when a is greater than 4 et cetera.
So case for the general syntax allows us to do a bunch of conditions individually and uniquely right
after those When Calls the case expression syntax is essentially just evaluating one expression and
then you're listing the possible values to be equal to that expression.
And often that expression is just a simple column call such as case a 1 1 then 1 when 2 then 2 and so
on okay.
So those are very simple examples but let's go ahead and look at some more realistic examples through
P.G. admin.
I'm going to open up PJ admin now OK here I am inside P.G. admin I'm going to go ahead and just explore
the customer table so let's grab everything from customer run that and I see I have a customer I.D.
story the first name and so on.
Let's go ahead and work under the assumption that the customer I.D. are assigned as serial primary keys.
So what I mean by that is if your customer I.D. is one then you were the first customer to ever purchase
something at our store or rent something from our DVD space.
And if your customer number two then you were the second customer and so on.
So let's go ahead and run a promotion for maybe a different tiers of customers.
Let's go ahead and set customers that are in the first 100 to be kind of a premium status and then customers
between 100 and 200 to be a plus status and then everyone else just to be a normal customer.
So this is a great situation for the case so I'm going to select customer I.D. from customer and run
that.
And so now we're essentially kind of simplifying this down so it matches more or less what we were doing
in our calls earlier in the slides.
No here it's actually not in order by exactly because 5 to 4 for some reason is just returned faster
and everything else.
So let's go ahead and make those categories with a case statement.
So what I like to do is I set up my kind of my normal query here and then I'm going to pretend this
is another column call.
So I would say comma and then this is where I'm going to insert my case statement and it's really quite
common to use spacing and indentation to help organize your case statement although keep in mind that
sequel itself doesn't really care about your spacing or indentation that much as long as your keywords
aren't touching each other essentially.
OK so here's our case statement.
So I'm going to say.
Case and then let's go ahead and write in our corresponding end.
So now that we have that kind of done I'm going to use the general syntax which means I'm going to have
my when calls.
So here I'm going to say when and let's go ahead and first check for when the customer these are less
than or equal to 100 going to put these inside parentheses.
So when the customer I.D. is less than or equal to one hundred then they have to decide what to return
when the actual case happens to be that the customer is less than or equal to 100.
So let's label these our premium customers since we want to reward them for being within the first 100
customers.
And now let's go ahead and have another condition to check against.
No here I don't put a comma between my conditions.
So now I'm going to say when Let's go ahead and type out where customer I.D..
And now let's do everyone.
That's between one hundred and two hundred.
So I will say between one hundred and 200 then let's call these customers plus.
So no.
Here.
Basically all I'm doing with this general case statement is after the when keyword I have some sort
of condition and I have a lot of flexibility over these sort of conditions.
And then I have to decide what do I return if this condition happens to be true.
And then you can keep listening.
When then lines or clauses for as many conditions as you want to check.
Then the last thing we're going to add in after you've decided you've checked all your wet conditions
is an L statement and the L statement basically says hey if you're not true for any of these conditions
meaning I didn't return a premium and I didn't return a plus then what should I return.
So go ahead and check for those conditions.
Else if none of that happened to be true go ahead and return something.
So let's go ahead and say that will be the string.
Normal so let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure we have no typos and I'm going to zoom out just a little bit so we can see this here but note
that I have my premium customers we can expand this column so all my premium customers and if I keep
scrolling down beyond 100 then I have my plus customers.
And then if I scroll down beyond that I should be able to see my normal customers over here beyond two
hundred.
Okay.
So again the syntax for a general case statement is you basically plug it in in lieu of a column here
and then you have your when keyword the condition you want to check then what should you return when
that condition happens to be true doesn't have to be a string could have been a number or a digit et
cetera.
Okay.
So last thing I want to point out is you often want to actually call this something not here just returns
the column name as case after the end statement.
I can use an alias saying something like as I could say like as customer class.
So what class is customers in.
And I run that and I'll rename the column for me.
Okay.
So we can see here that the general case statement is the one that's the most flexible because you can
check all kinds of conditions but often for case statements you're just going to be checking for equality.
So the simpler version of that is that case expression where right at the top you're going to check
for a case expression and then just check for equality off of that.
So let's imagine that we are running a raffle so let's go ahead and just come back to select customer
I.D. from customer run that and make sure we delete that comma here run that.
So here's my customer I.D. And I'm just selecting a customer different customer.
And now what I'm going to do is I'm going to hold a raffle and let's say I held the raffle separately
just kind of some random lotto tickets and I'm going to pick based off the customer I.D. number.
So based off kind of my random choice I decided.
Number two is the winner a customer I.D. number five is second place and everyone else is just normal.
They didn't win anything.
So how can I do this with a case expression the case expression is probably the better choice here because
I'm just going to check for equality.
I'm just checking that if the customer I.D. is equal to two then I want them labeled as a winner.
If the customer I.D. label let's say five that will be the second place in a raffle.
Everyone else is going to be just labeled as normal since I'm just checking for equality here and not
checking for things like between two values then a customer expression is or excuse me case expression
is probably the best case for this customer I.D. check.
So the way this works is same as before I'll say case and then I will say end except now right after
my case I'm going to provide my expression and the expression here is just a simple column call which
is the customer I.D..
So I'm just going to check for the customer I.D. be equal to something.
So here again my karma and this case and block is essentially the substitute for another column call.
So I'm saying case where the customer I.D. and then I'm going to say when and I no longer need to say
something like customer I.D. equal to two I can just type in two.
So this is nice.
And this is just going to check for equality against this expression.
So let's say when the customer I.D. to then that's the person that won the raffle will say
now I can't have another case.
So let's say when customer I.D. five let's go ahead and have that person be second place and then finally
everyone else will just list them as normal.
And I'm going to call this right after end as raffle results.
So again note the difference here is that I have this expression often just a single column call and
instead of checking for conditions within the when I'm just checking for equality.
So checking one customer I.D. when it's two customer I.D. when it's five.
So obviously this one is not as flexible as the general case statement but it's kind of faster to type
out.
Basically saves you from having to type out customer I.D. equal to this customer the equal to that and
say you just write customer at one time and then you just check for equality of the values themselves.
Let's go ahead and run this.
Make sure you didn't commit any typos and it looks like we're good.
So let's expand on the results and note here that looks like customer number two the raffle results
of this person is a winner and customer I.D. number five this person got second place.
Ok awesome.
Now the last thing I want to show you is you can actually begin to then perform operations on the results
of these case statements.
So let's take a look at our film table.
I'm going to say select everything from film run that so we have our film I.D. title et cetera.
And if we take a look at this we have the actual rental rate.
So we know there's different rental rates.
Let's go ahead and make some categories for rental rates and then let's also figure out how many we
have per category.
Keep in mind technically I could do this through some sort of group by call but this is really to drive
home the point that you can take these complicated case syntax statements and then perform operations
such as a sum on them.
I kind of want to walk through a little bit of logic here that may serve you well in the future but
keep in mind that you could have figured out this in other ways so you don't need to write back saying
could we have done this if a group buy you probably could have fewer creative enough.
So let me show you what I'm talking about first.
So we're gonna say select the rental rate from film since that's kind of all I'm interested in so I
have these different rental rates and I have a ninety nine cents rental rate.
I want to figure out how many of these do I actually have.
So let's go ahead and start categorizing things.
We're going to say select and I'm going to do the following.
We're actually just going to say select case and no we're going to check for the rental rates when it's
99 cents then label it or return 1 else 0 and then we have to have the end call associated with the
case.
So not what I'm doing here.
I'm basically just saying Select Case rental rate if it's ninety nine cents then return a 1 in this
new column.
Else return is zero.
And this.
So when I run this I have this nice little case here.
So case integer bunch of zeros.
And notice here it happens to be one if that rental rate was then ninety nine cents.
And to kind of drive this point further I could actually ask for the original rental rate column comma
run that and I can see the direct results next to each other.
So nothing too crazy right now certainly the exact same thing we did before except for returning zero.
If it's not 99 cents and a 1 if it is.
So now what I can do is I can actually take the sum of this case column to figure out exactly how many
ninety nine cents movies I have.
So the way we do that is just as if this was any other normal column I'm going to take this whole thing
and pass it into some
and then I'm going to delete rental rates since it doesn't make sense to call rental rate anymore since
I'm just taking the some of this and then I'm going to say as let's say a number of bargains so I'm
gonna say 99 cent films are a bargain.
So if I take the sum of this return column in the case then it's gonna give me a one for every time
there's a ninety nine cents essentially counting how many ninety nine cent movies I have so we run this
and we get back that the number of bargains I have or number of ninety nine cent movies I have are three
hundred and forty one.
So you're probably thinking right now.
Well this isn't super useful because I could have already done this with things I know about group buy
and count and where and having and all these other tools that we've learned so far.
But what if I want to now do this for different categories such as bargains and regular prices so I
can keep doing this as if there were more columns.
So after this let's go ahead and just call this bargains.
These are my bargain movies.
I'm also going to take the sum of let's say movies when they're two ninety nine so let's say some case
rental rate when two ninety nine.
Then one else zero.
And then finally end.
So basically the exact same thing I did up here except now checking for two ninety nine and let's go
ahead and call these let's say as regular.
So it's gonna be pretty nice about this and no here my karma.
Because I'm basically treating this whole sum as in other column call that when I run this I now I'm
able to format the results in this easy to read manner where I have the number of bargains being showed
at the exact same time of the number of two dollars and a nine cent films and so I can keep doing this
for the other cases go out and copy this again add in a comma I was going to copy and paste here the
exact same code except now I'm going to check for when it's four ninety nine and let's go ahead and
call these our premium movies because they're more expensive and now I'm going to run this and now at
the exact same time as separate columns I can see bargains regular and premium.
So this is something that is a lot more difficult to do given the other tools we know and it's almost
impossible to format it in this way where each of these counts has its own column and its own label
columns a number of bargains number of regular movies and then a number of so-called premium movies.
So this is really nice and it allows me again to call functions on the results of a case column and
it's super common to use case with a when statement and then you say then 1 else 0 as ways of summing
things up or counting the results.
OK so that's it for this particular lecture on the case syntax coming up next.
Going to have a challenge for you to make sure you've fully understood what we went over here.
Thanks and I'll see you at that challenge lecture.