Hello and welcome to the complete SQL bootcamp.
I am Jose Portilla
and I've taught thousands of students on Udemy
the most in-demand tech skills
such as Python, Data Science,
and Coding Interview preparation.
And now I'm excited to launch this new course
designed to teach you one of the most in-demand skills,
using SQL to interact with database and analyse your data.
I've designed this course
to take you from zero to hero of SQL
so no prior programming experience is necessary.
Whether you're a marketing or business analyst
looking to learn SQL, a data scientist,
or just someone who wants to improve
their data analysis capabilities,
this comprehensive course is right for you.
SQL is currently the most in-demand skill
for the tech sector and learning it
can dramatically change your career prospects.
Once you complete this course,
you'll feel comfortable putting SQL on your resume.
We'll be working with one of the most popular
and in-demand versions of SQL, PostgreSQL,
but the syntax and skills you'll learn in this course
can be applied to any other major database
or software that uses SQL.
This includes database systems such as Amazon Redshift,
MySQL, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle Database, and much more.
Throughout the course, you'll get video lectures
explaining concepts clearly
and you'll get challenges to complete
against a real database to test your new skills.
This course also includes comprehensive assessment tests
so you can review your SQL knowledge.
You'll also receive a certificate of completion
that you can post to your LinkedIn account
to show your new skills to potential employers.
Not only do you get great content,
but you get an effective learning experience.
And when you join this course,
you'll also get lifetime access
to our helpful community of students
and the discussion forums.
This course also comes with 30-day money back guarantee.
If you're not 100% satisfied with this course,
I'll refund you your money, no questions asked.
This course is designed to help you
achieve your career goals.
Whether you're looking to get more into data analytics,
increase your earning potential,
or just want a job with more freedom,
this is the right course for you.
Check out the next preview lecture
for a full curriculum overview.
So what are you waiting for?
Begin the next chapter in your career and enrol today.