Hello everyone,
and welcome to this lecture on using PostgreSQL with Python,
and with using the library psycopg2.
So I'm right now using the Jupyter Notebook system
in order to show you how all this syntax works.
You can feel free to use any editor
or IDE that you prefer for Python.
If you've already experienced one of my other
Python courses, you're probably already really familiar
with the Jupyter or iPython Notebook system.
If you're not and want to find out more,
you can go to www.jupyter.org and explore that website,
and I'll also give you a link on how to instal it,
and you can explore it more.
I really like it as far as for teaching and quick scripts.
But, you can also explore everything we're about to do
in your preferred IDE or development environment for Python.
So let's go ahead and start by just importing the library
that we downloaded from the previous lecture.
So again, go to the previous lecture for more notes
on how to actually download everything,
and for the dot py file
that has all the code that I'm gonna execute here.
Or the Notebook file that has, again, all the code
and some notes of what I'm gonna execute here
during the lecture.
So to get started, like I was saying,
we need to import psycopg2.
So psyco, let me make sure I spell that right.
Psycopg2.
So by convention we just import it as pg2.
And then the next thing you're gonna do
is connect to your database.
And by convention that's C-O-N-N.
And you're just gonna say pg2,
and then call the connect method.
And you're gonna pass in a couple of arguments here.
The first one is what database you're gonna connect to.
I'm gonna go ahead and connect to the dvdrental database
that we've been working with a lot.
And then you have to define the user.
So depending on how you actually set up your pg admin
account, you may have set up your own particular user name.
If you don't specify the username in this argument
of the connect method, it'll automatically by default
on a windows computer, and I believe on a mac as well,
default to the user profile name.
But if you've just been following along
with all the lectures, the default for pg admin
as far as the username, is just postgres.
So if you're having any trouble with your own username,
try just saying postgres, and if you set everything
to default, it should be postgres.
And then the last thing you have to input is your password.
Now I've already set up my password
as the variable called secret up here.
So if you want you can just set up a variable called secret,
and put in your password.
Obviously my password is not the string,
your password goes here.
So if you've done all this correctly,
you should be able to run this line of code
or put this line of code inside your dot ipy file,
and then you should have a connexion there.
So in this Jupyter Notebook system I'm basically just
running each of these cells as a separate block of code.
And that way I can run the cells
and show you the output at the same time.
So now that we've established the connexion to PostgreSQL,
the next step is to retrieve the cursor.
And the cursor is just a control structure
that enables traversal over the records in a database.
So you can basically think of it as some sort of iterator
or pointer for sequel data retrieval.
And the way we're gonna do that,
is we're gonna go ahead and create a variable called C-U-R.
And then we're gonna have a connexion object.
So that was this C-O-N-N.
And then we call the cursor method off of it.
And so now we have our cursor.
And that was essentially the last thing we needed to do
in order to execute sequel queries from Python.
So using that cursor object, I can say execute off of it,
and then you basically, inside the execute method,
you pass in a string of whatever you want to
actually ask the database, or query the database of.
So we can say something like this, select asterisks from,
let's go ahead and say, from payments.
So now this cursor has that execute statement.
And this cursor then has a couple of methods available.
It has fetchall, fetchmany and fetchone.
So what these do, is they basically return rows of data.
So if I just say fetchone,
it will return the first row of that data.
So these are the numbers that correspond with
that row of data, from select everything from payment.
I can also say fetchmany,
and then actually pass in how many rows I wanna fetch.
So I can fetch 10 rows.
And you'll notice that it returns it
as a list of tupel items, which is nice cause then you can
use tupel in packing later on.
And also note that depending on the data type,
it'll also specify like a datetime, data type,
if you have a time stamp information on it,
for that particular column in your database table.
So those are really the main features you're gonna be using
with psycopg2, and as far as using this all on Python,
it's gonna be kind of up to you how you use these
main three or four commands, in order to use
the power of Python and use the automation capabilities
of Python to query your database
or put things into your database.
So again let's just go over what we've done so far.
You had a import psycopg2 as pg2,
then you had a establish a connexion,
I set it as the variable C-O-N-N,
and you said pg2 dot connect,
you had a pass in the database name you were connecting to,
pass in the user you were connecting as.
The default user for any Postgres application is postgres.
And then you had a pass on the password you set up
when you're first installing pgAdmin and PostgreSQL.
Then, you had to get a cursor off of that connexion.
And with that cursor you could then
execute sequel queries off of it.
And then once you have that cursor execute that query,
you can actually fetch the rows that are returned,
you can fetch many rows, you can fetch just one row,
or the final option is actually to fetch all of them.
And notice here since there's quite a few rows
you may wanna use this carefully.
Otherwise you'll just end up with a tonne of rows returned.
So let's go in and change that back to fetchone.
So again, this is really nice
because you can use tupel and packing along with it.
So you can say something like,
if we just say, fetchmany such as 10.
Let me actually execute that query again.
Notice I had to execute the query
in order to fetch them off.
So let's go and execute that query one more time.
And we'll say this is equal to data,
and now if I take a look at data I have this list
and I can index off of it as you would expect,
tupel and pack it, keep indexing off of it,
just to get particular data points.
It's really up to you as far as
what you're gonna use this type of data for
and this sort of Python of psycopg format with.
But hopefully, basically these lines are
the most important ones and they can really be
your building blocks as far as
how you're gonna use PostgreSQL with Python.
That sort of application's really up to you,
and more likely than not it's just gonna be a smaller part
or back-end of your application Python
when you're communicating with your database.
Once you're done communicating and executing
off your database, you're gonna wanna close your connexion.
So you're gonna wanna say your connexion
and go ahead and close it.
And that's really all there is to it.
You can check out the dot ipy or Python file
from the previous lecture or the iPython Notebook file
from the previous lecture, to get a couple more useful hints
and tips for how to use psycopg2 with PostgreSQL and Python.
Other than that, that's really just the basics of it,
and that's kind of all you need to know
to start exploring how you can use PostgreSQL
with your own Python applications.
Again, the most important parts are just the import,
establishing that connexion, creating the cursor,
and then executing the sequel queries.
One thing I wanted to note, is to make sure
that you kind of avoid using Python's print formatting
or string formatting,
when you're executing these sequel queries.
And what I mean by that is imagine you have this situation,
where you want to say, execute,
and you input some command.
And let's say earlier in your code your command line
was something like, maybe it was select all from,
and then you were gonna add another string to it later on.
So maybe that string was another object.
And what I'm trying to say is you may wanna be careful
when you're doing this sort of thing with psycopg2
and PostgreSQL with Python, because it's kind of dangerous
if you accidentally call add something like,
drop table later on, this could kind of potentially
screw up your database.
So just keep that in mind.
It's always best practise to put in the entire sequel query
as just one single string and to verify
that it's a single string that you want.
There's a couple more notes on that in the Notebook,
but it's just something to be aware of.
Okay with that being said, that's really it,
as far as just a quick overview
of how you can use psycopg2 and PostgreSQL with Python.
Feel free to ask any questions
in the discussion section of the course.
And you can also feel free to refer to the resources
from the previous lecture for more hints and more tutorials
on how to use this, really this whole library.
Okay, thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.