Welcome back everyone to this quick lecture on mathematical functions.
We're gonna quickly explore some mathematical operations that we can perform with sequel.
And this is actually all just best shown through some examples and also by showing you where you can
find all the examples of mathematical functions in the documentation.
So to do this I'm gonna jump straight to PGA admin and my browser.
OK.
Here I am inside of P Jenman if my query Ed ready to go.
I first want to quickly show you the documentation for mathematical functions.
And if you come to the P.G. sequel documentation and then just go to functions dash math or just search
for mathematical functions and operators and Google along with G sequel it should bring you to this
page.
You can also check out the URL here at the top post for sequel talk slash Doc slash current slash functions
dash math that each team L and there's lots of different operations and functions but we're really going
to focus on throughout this course are mathematical operators because that's more common to use for
business SQL queries and the way this works is as you may expect it's just things like addition subtraction
and multiplication done between columns so you can add one column to another or subtract one column
from another etc. So it also gives you examples.
And then the expected results.
So pretty much any mathematical operator you can think of is available to you in post press equal.
So this is operator you type in its description and examples.
Now you can shift into doing more complex mathematical or there's also mathematical functions we're
already familiar with one of these which was round.
Remember that rounded off a number to a certain number of decimal points but there's things like absolute
value cube root exponential even logarithms are available to and lots of different options here.
So for our particular databases we don't need to be taking anything raised to some sort of power or
be converting degrees to radians but I want to let you know that this stuff is available to you in case
you need it.
And there's even trigonometric functions so there's random functions here and then there's trigonometric
functions as well as hyperbolic functions so lots and lots of different options.
So in case you find yourself needing to do some sort of complex mathematics within your circle query
go ahead and check out this documentation page and see if the function is already available for you.
Now I want to show you just a couple examples how you may actually use some of those mathematical operators
and functions from within PGE adamant in your queries.
First let's go in and select everything from the film table.
Go ahead and run that.
And I want to zoom out just a little bit so we can see the results here in a little more detail.
Looks like we have a film idea as we know title et cetera and we're going to focus on are things comparing
the rental rate versus the replacement cost.
Let's imagine I wanted to know the percentage that a rental rate versus a replacement cost happens to
be.
So what percentage of the replacement cost is a rental rate so the way I can do that is the following
I simply need to calculate rental rates divided by the replacement cost.
So if I run them notice we get back.
This results here.
And if you get it back like this kind of squeezed down a lot of numbers just remember you can always
expand this back out because it's keeping a lot of decimal places.
So I also wanted this in terms of percent which the first thing going to do is I'll go ahead and round
this off to just be two decimals.
So we'll say round this result to be two points past the decimal so far around that.
Now I get to see point three three point five etc..
And then what I can do is if I wanted to get it in terms of percent just times by a hundred so now I
can see 33 percent twenty five percent etc. and if I want more detail there I could say Q4 from the
original run that and I get to see thirty three point two nine percent twenty four point nine six percent
et cetera.
And you can only say an alias here as something like percent cost or whatever you happen to name this
column.
You can see here it's percent cost.
Okay.
So this is kind of typically what you would do.
Let's imagine for some reason you wanted to just put small deposits down of 10 percent of the replacement
cost.
You could easily calculate that you would just say something like zero point one times the replacement
And then you can name it something like as deposit from film run that and we can see here we have 10
percent other replacement costs for some sort of deposit program.
All right.
So really it's all pretty self-explanatory here.
You can always jump to the documentation and explore any mathematical operators that you see fit to
use.
Okay.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.