Welcome back everyone.
In this lecture we're going to give you some challenge tasks that focus on the having class as always
we have the challenge the expected result.
Some hints in case you need them.
And then the solution.
Let's get started.
We are launching a platinum service for our most loyal customers.
We will assign platinum status to customers that have had 40 or more transaction payments.
What customer I.D. are eligible for platinum status okay.
Here comes the expected result so the expected results are these three customer I.D. And if you want
You can also show how many transactions they had.
We can see here that there's three people that have had 40 or more transactions.
Here are some hints in case you need them so the hint is to use the payment table and to recall that
any column can be passed into account.
Call.
Coming up next there's a solution so the solution pretty straightforward here.
We're going to select the customer I.D. and then we're going to count and you can either pass in a column
here specific to the amount or just pass an asterisk.
And then we're gonna grab this from the payment table group by the customer I.D. and then we're going
to say having a count greater than or equal to 40 essentially answering a question that they've had
40 or more payment rows associated with that particular customer I.D. thus earning them that platinum
status.
All right your next challenge is to answer the following.
What are the customer I.D. of customers who have spent more than one hundred dollars in payment transactions
with our staff by the member number two.
Again that's customer I.D. of people who have spent more than one hundred dollars in payment transactions
but only with the payment transactions that occurred with the staff I.D. member.
Number two here comes the expected result so there should be only five customers that have done this.
And then here's the associated sum.
So they're all over a hundred dollars here upcoming or some hints so the hint is to use the payment
table and to remember to use the where statement to first filter based on the staff I.D. column and
then use the group by clause.
And then finally let's see the solution so a solution.
Here we select the customer I.D. and we take this sum of the amount in order to calculate who has more
than a hundred dollars from the payment table.
We first however filter where staff I.D. is equal to two that way when we do the group buy on the customer
I.D..
We're only considering people where the actual payment transaction occurred with the staff I.D. equal
to two.
And then we check for having a sum amount of greater than 100.
All right.
And that's it for your challenge tasks.
I'll see you at the next lecture.