Welcome everyone to this lecture on right joins a right join is essentially exact same thing as a left
join or LEFT OUTER JOIN except that the tables are switched and often beginners get confused when first
starting to learn sequel especially when they hit that left outer join which is the most difficult joint
to learn about because it's asymmetrical and then suddenly they're introduced to this concept of a right
join.
And students often get confused because it seems like the right join is a completely different thing.
But the reason I don't want to dwell on it too much is because a right join is essentially the exact
same thing as the Left Join except you just switch the tables around.
So this would be the exact same thing as switching the table order in a left outer join and in fact
you can pretty much go on just using a left join for two tables and just switching up the order of the
tables in order to satisfy whatever need you have.
So it really depends on how you think about the tables and what order they come in in your mind whether
table A is on the left.
Table B's on the right or if table B's on the left and table is on the right sort of quickly show you
some examples three Venn diagram so a right outer join.
Notice this looks a lot like a left out or join except it's just flipped along the axes.
So we're saying select everything from table A A RIGHT OUTER JOIN ON TABLE B where A table has a column
match equal to Table B.
So what this is saying is essentially the exact reverse of a left join.
And what they're saying is return back rows that can be found either exclusively in Table B or in both
table B and table a and do not return back rows that are exclusively only found in Table A.
Notice how this would have been the exact same thing as a left join.
Had we just switched around the table order.
OK.
So again this is pretty much the exact same thing as a left join except you're switching those tables
around and you can actually get back these same results by doing a left join and selecting first from
Table B with the left join on table a.
So keep in mind really the right outer join is just to help you keep the same tables in the same order
in your mind of tables on the left and table B's on the right.
But switching up the results you get and keep in mind you can do either right outer join or right join.
They both work fine and just like we could have a left outer join.
You can also add a clarifying where statement to say something like where table a that I.D. is null
in order to clarify they only want tables that can be found exclusively in Table B and are not found
in table a okay.
So it's really up to you and how you how the tables organize quote unquote in your mind when it comes
to choosing a left versus a right join since depending on the table order you specifying the join you
could perform duplicate joins with either method.
So if two tables can be joined and you can get results with a left outer join you should also be able
to get the exact same results if a right outer join or right join by switching the table order and playing
around with that table ordering or playing around of any table ordering in the where results depending
on the exact query you're doing so really take your time to understand the left outer join extremely
well and then if you want you can begin to use the right join if the moment calls for it or if you want
you can always just stick to left join and switch around the table order there.
OK so again hopefully if you understand left outer join well enough you can see how right outer join
IS REALLY THE BROTHER OR SISTER OF LEFT JOIN.
You're just kind of flipping that and just keeping the table or do the same in the query itself but
flipping the results around and if you wanted to you could just flip the tables in the query in order
to keep the left join call and I'll have to switch to a right join call so take your time with these
two slides.
This pretty much just answers the question of what a right join IS and if these slides are confusing
to you they need to go back and really take your time to review the left join a left outer join.
Because once you understand that really well then these two slides should be very clear in the fact
that it's just the left join with the tables flipped.
Okay thanks.
And I will see you at the next lecture.