Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the update keyword the update keyword allows for the changing
of values of the columns in the table the general syntax is as follows.
We say update then what table we want to update and then we can say set column equal to and then some
apparent value that we've chosen for that column and then we can also specify conditions for where the
update should occur.
So let's show you an example we can use that account table we created earlier to say something like
update the account table and then set last log in column equal to the current timestamp where the last
log in is NULL which basically says if there is a null value in the last log in go ahead and update
all those values to be the current timestamp.
You can also reset everything without any where condition.
So if I wanted to just overwrite and update all the last log and entries I could just say update account
set last log in equal to current timestamp I could also set everything based off in other column.
So we also have the created on column I could just say update account set all the values and last log
in equal to create it on I could then also add an A where condition on top of this we could also use
another tables values.
This is sometimes known as an update join even though it doesn't use the joint keyword.
So the way this works in general syntax is we choose the table we're updating such as table a and we
say update table a and set the original column which is part of table a equal to some new column part
of Table B from Table B or table A.
The I.D. is equal to Table B the I.D. which is essentially where that joining is taking place.
So we just figure out some key to match these two tables on and then we say set the original column
then table nine equal to Table B that new column we can also return the rows that are affected.
So if you just run one of these update commands you don't see any results but if you do want to see
particular columns that were affected you can set the command something like up the account table set
last log and column equal to the created on column and then you can say returning and choose the columns
you want return and it's going to return the rows that were actually affected and you can return all
the columns or a subset of columns it's really up to you.
Let's go ahead and explore this further in P.G. Ataman alright to begin with this I'm going to take
a look at the account table we set up earlier by saying select everything from account.
No notice I'm connected to that learning database and so far if you've been following along you should
just have one entry in this account table if you have more than one.
That's OK.
So we have this username password email created on and currently our last log in is no.
So let's go ahead and change that.
A couple of different ways using update so one thing we can do is set it to some sort of value just
all over.
So I can say update account and then say set last log in and I could set it to the current timestamp
so I could say something like set it to current timestamp.
I run that and notice it doesn't actually give you an output.
So we'll have to ask again to select everything from account to see the change run that.
And if I scroll over now I can see the last log in matches the current timestamp for when I ran that.
Let's go ahead and just have it match the created on column so to do this.
We're going to say update account and say set last log in equal to created on.
Run that.
So it looked like it worked.
Let's go ahead and check on that.
Select everything from accounts.
Go ahead and run this.
And now if you ran that you should see these two match exactly down to the sub second because it's directly
lifted off the created on.
And finally let's explore how we could do an update based off two tables.
So to do this we're going to explore that job table we created.
So again we have this job by the job name.
And then recall that not only do we have the job table but we also had to expand on this the account
job table.
So we're going to say account job run that as well.
And it looks like we have a hired date.
Let's go ahead and change the higher dates based off in other table.
Now the procedure here is really just for syntax purposes.
The actual logic behind this won't make too much sense as far as why anyone would want to change the
dates for this higher date based off in other tables so just keep that in mind this is really just for
syntax example.
OK.
So how we're gonna do this is I'm going to update from this account job table and I'm going to set the
higher date equal to and let's use the account table and let's use the created on date from that.
So we'll say update account job set higher they equal to account dot created on from the account tables.
We have to specify what's the other table.
And then we're gonna do the following.
Essentially this is where the join comes in.
We're gonna say where account job the user I.D. is equal to account that user I.D. So we run this.
It was successful which means if I were to select from account job notice here the actual timestamp
just go ahead and take a look at the sub seconds.
So 19 0 9.
Now let's take a look at the account and it should be the exact same 19 0 9.
So again that's the syntax for updating based off the results from another table.
Very very useful to know that in this particular example maybe that logic of the reasoning behind it
that didn't make too much sense on why you would want to do that.
However I was really just for the syntax example.
So again you update table a set which you actually want to update from table B and then show where you're
actually matching that up which is why this is known as an update join even though we're actually not
using the joint keyword.
And then finally I want to just show you the returning keyword.
Let's go ahead and go back and update our account table let's just set the last log in equal to again
current timestamp suddenly essentially just resetting it a little further into the future.
So we'll update account set last log in equal to current timestamp and then I can say returning and
I can return something.
Basically whatever columns I'm interested in such as email and let's say last log in and let's also
grab in the created on just so I can compare them.
We run this and that successfully ran.
And in addition to that it returns back whatever columns you're interested in that way you don't need
to do that select second step.
Just to clarify or double check that your results went through.
OK.
That's it for the update command.
I'll see you at the next lecture.