Hello everyone and welcome to the installation and setup lecture.
It's time to get set up for the course in this lecture.
We're mainly going to be installing two things.
One is post crest sequel which is a sequel engine that stores data and then reads in our query and returns
back information from the database.
The second thing you're going to install is P.G. ataman.
This is a graphical user interface that lies on top of post sequel that just makes it easier for us
to have a graphical interface in which to type our queries so it'll directly connect with post graphs
equal and just make things like restoring a database a lot easier.
Please know that we want to make sure you follow each step in order carefully.
There's two really common confusion points during the installation process.
One is we have a database file called DVD rental that TAR file as a resource.
In this lecture Do not open that file directly.
Often students get confused because it looks like a PDA or the computer recognizes it as a different
type of file.
You don't need to worry about any of that later on we'll just download it but do not open it directly.
The second really common confusion point is forgetting the password you set up for post stress sequel.
It's really important that you write down and remember that password.
When that step comes.
All right.
So to help avoid any missed steps we've gone ahead and numbered the steps so as we go through this you
should be able to follow along.
You'll see step one step two step three etc. So we'll present them in the correct order for you.
Let's go ahead and get started.
Step number one is to download and install post crest sequel.
Let's head over to an Internet browser.
All right go ahead in your browser go to Google dot com and then search for post gross sequel.
Hit enter and the very first link that isn't an advertisement should be WW that post gross equal dot
org.
So we'll go ahead and click on that.
This is the official site for post crest sequel and then this takes us to the official site and essentially
somewhere on this page you should see a download button.
Go ahead and either click up here or it says download or click the download button here.
The site page just changed from time to time so you may have to look around to see where the download
button is.
But overall we want to click to download and it's typically at post sequel to org slash download and
then as we come down here we'll see something called different binary packages for Linux.
Then there's Mac OS Solaris windows etc..
There's also the source code.
Right now I'm on a Windows computer so I will go ahead and click windows for the correct download and
then you'll notice that it says interactive installer but enterprise DP.
There's also different information on platform support you may have to choose a different version depending
on what version of Windows you're running.
If you're running an older version of Windows especially a 32 bit version of Windows you may need to
download a lower version of post egress equal so quickly make sure that the version of Windows you're
running is compatible with whatever Postgres sequel version you install.
OK come back up here and then hit download the installer.
Keep in mind this does change from time to time as far as the description it may say graphical installer
enterprise DP but overall we're getting the installer from Enterprise VB go ahead and click on that.
It will take you to enterprise D.B. dot com download etc and you're going to click the correct download
version for you.
So right now I'm running on a Windows computer.
I'll go ahead and just select the most recent version.
If you're running on an older Windows computer you may have to downgrade to a lower version.
So we're gonna go ahead and look at the windows column and then hit download OK so you download should
begin automatically.
Here you can see among Google Chrome.
And over here on the bottom left it's downloading that post equal executable file.
I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done downloading.
All right that's done downloading for me so I will go ahead and open up the executable file.
Upon launching the executable file you should see the setup wizard.
Pop up if for some reason you don't see the setup wizard.
Pop up.
Make sure that you don't have a firewall blocking this installer from opening.
Especially if you're on a work computer business internet connection.
OK.
So here we have set a postcard sequel.
We'll go ahead and click next.
Go ahead and please specify the directory I recommend just choosing the default installation directory.
Go ahead and click next and then it's gonna ask you to select what components you want to install.
Go ahead and just leave everything selected as is.
Notice that it's selected P.G. admin for for us anyways we'll go ahead and just leave everything as
a default click next and then go ahead and select the data directory of where to store the data.
Make sure you choose the default.
And this is the extremely important part.
It's asking us to please provide a password for the database super user.
So you have to absolutely make sure that you remember this password.
I highly recommend that you make it something extremely simple just like password and all lowercase.
This isn't really a security issue since since it's just a learning exercise will be will be just running
this locally on our computer.
So I'm not too concerned about someone hacking into my computer so I'll just say password and then password.
There's no way I can really help you if you forget what this password is.
So if you forget with this password is you're essentially going to have to uninstall everything and
reinstall all over again.
So please if you name your password something else that's difficult to remember.
Write it down somewhere.
I cannot help you if you forget this password.
OK so I set up my password is just lowercase password.
We will be asked for this later on.
Next is going to ask you to please select the port number the server should be listening on.
By default it should say the port number is 5 4 3 2.
If you get another number like 5 4 3 3 or 5 4 3 4 etc. that's OK too.
We can later on show you how to make sure you're connecting to the correct port number.
When we install PGE admin most likely by default you have 5 4 3 2 unless for some reason you may have
maybe an older version of Postgres sequel on your computer already existing and listening on a specific
port.
So we have it right now as default as 5 4 3 2.
So we'll keep it that way.
We'll go ahead and click next it's going to ask you to select the location to be used by the new database
cluster.
Go ahead and just leave it as the default location hit next.
And then it's going to tell you all the settings you just chose.
That's OK to hit next setup is ready to install hit next and let's go ahead and let it install.
And this essentially concludes.
Step number one on the fast forward in time until this is done installing.
All right.
This is done installing you'll notice at the very end asks you if you want to launch stack builder.
You don't need to launch that so I'm going to um click the launching of that and then just hit finish.
That's the end of Step 1.
It's time to move on the step number two is download and install PDC admin to start off.
Go ahead and go to your browser and then go to Google dot com and search for PGE admin.
I'm going to do that now.
OK here I am at Google dot com.
I search for PGI admin and the first thing that should pop up that is an advertisement is peachy Ataman
dot org.
Go ahead and select that link it'll take you to this Web site P.G. admin PGI admin is the graphical
user interface that we're going to be using tax you perform queries and connect to post graphs equal
during the course.
And what's interesting about PGI admin it actually uses your browser as the graphical user interface.
So after we install it we'll be able to open it up within our browser.
So somewhere along this page you should see a download button.
So it's either gonna be up here and download or there's quick links here for both an online demo if
you want to check it out.
You can open this up and try it out here in your browser start a situation and it set something up for
you and it has a little bit of a sandbox here you can check out.
They'll kind of play around officer and thing ask you for email address etc. But in our case we're going
to go to lead this and just click on Download since we're gonna be installing it anyways.
There's two versions of PGI admin PJ admin for and then PGE admin 3.
Keep in mind if you're running an older version of Windows you may need to use PD admin 3 instead of
PGI admin for.
And even though it says PJ admin 3 is no longer supported that just means that they're not updating
it anymore which makes sense if you're running an older version of Windows so if you're an older version
of Windows like Windows 7 or something you may need to actually use PGI admin 3 but if you're on the
latest version of any of these operating systems Mac OS Windows.
Some Linux distribution you should be good for.
PGI admin for I'm going to go ahead and click on Windows since I'm on a Windows computer.
You realize there's multiple versions of PGI admin for they keep releasing updates to it and I'm going
to hit on PJ admin for version 4 point 1 8 The latest version released so I'll click on that and it's
going to take me to something that looks like this and it's a little confusing at first but essentially
all we need to download is the actual executable file that's within this and if you take a look it should
be the largest file we're actually downloading.
So go ahead and download this executable file for PGE admin and you can see down here it's downloading.
It'll be done in a few seconds.
Once you've gone ahead and download the executable file go ahead and open it up and run it.
Keep in mind you may need to run it as an administrator so make sure you have admin permissions on your
computer and you can right click and run this as an admin so I'll click on that and now we have the
setup wizard for P.G. admin.
Most of this work is going to choose a default so we'll go ahead and click Next accept the agreement
hit next.
Select the default location that's going to be OK hit next.
It's going to ask you what you want to call the start menu option that's go ahead and click next and
then just hit install.
OK.
That's pretty much it for installing PGI I'm going to fast forward until this is done installing and
now it's finished installing.
We are not actually going to launch PGI item and yet we have step number 3 to move on here so you can
go ahead and unclip the launch PG&amp;E in 4 and then just hit finish.
It's now time for step 3 of our process where we're going to download but remember do not directly open
the DVD rental that TAR file the DVD rental dock tar file is a compressed version of the database we're
going to be using for this course.
You can download it as a resource in this lecture.
Keep in mind that we're only downloading it.
Do not attempt to unzip it or try to open it of any other program.
It may say that the file is damaged and the windows can't find a program to open it with.
That's okay.
This file is not meant to be opened by anything other than Keiji admin.
So please do not double click on this file after downloading it.
The only thing you're going to do is download the file.
Let's see how to do that.
If you check out the Udemy support page on downloading supplemental resources as you're watching this
particular video over on the right hand side you should see a little resources button pop up and then
you'll see the DVD rental that TAR file.
So what that's actually going to look like is you'll be watching the complete cycle bootcamp and then
over here on the actual lecture you'll hit resources and then select DVD rental that tar.
Go ahead and click on it and it should download and I'm going to open the file location recall.
Do not double click or open does not tar filed directly.
You can see here that I now have it underneath my downloads and DVD rental.
Dot tar things that are important to keep in mind is to not directly double click or open on this file
and the second thing to keep in mind is you must know the exact location of this file so I know that
it's underneath my downloads folder.
If you have any questions of where this file is actually located you can always right click and then
select properties and you'll see the full location right here of wherever it happens to be on your computer.
We're gonna need that when we actually restore the file.
Okay so that's all you need to do is download it as a resource from this lecture.
Do not open it and do not double click it.
All right.
Step number 4 is to go ahead and restart your computer to make sure all the actual changes due to Postgres
sequence PGI admin have taken place.
We need to restart the computer.
I'm going to go ahead and restart my computer and then move on to Step Number Five step number five
is to restore the database.
A quick note on this step is you can ignore the failed exit code that may appear during the restoration
depending on your exact version of your operating system and the exact version of the Postgres sequel
you installed.
There is sometimes a failed exit code that appears that basically indicates that the restoration accidentally
happened twice.
That's totally ok because what happens is it works the first time and then it doesn't do it a second
time because the first time worked.
So you'll be able to safely ignore that failed exit code.
If it does appear so let's go ahead and open P.G. admin to get started.
So on your computer go ahead and search for P.G. admin mix you're actually opening P.G. admin the application
and not the executable file.
Otherwise you'll just end up reinstalling it so don't click on this executable file but instead click
on the actual PGE adamant program this application so I'm going to open that up and what's going to
happen is you should see it eventually open up in the browser
OK and here it is in the browser.
Notice that right now it's running in the browser.
This doesn't actually mean it requires an Internet connection to run.
It's just using the actual browser as a graphical interface.
Then it asks you to set a master password.
I would highly recommend that you set this to something very simple and easy to remember since you're
going to need this later on I'm going to just set the password to password in all lowercase which actually
matches that Postgres SQL password setup earlier.
Then we'll go ahead and click OK.
And now it's time to restore the database.
If you click here on servers you may actually see various versions of Postgres sequel depending on which
one you've installed.
If you follow along with me most likely you'll just see post quests equal twelve.
I've actually installed different version the post crisis equal on this computer so I see all the options.
But in your case you're most likely just going to see Postgres sequel twelve we'll go ahead and click
on Postgres sequel twelve and you can double click on this and then it's going to ask you to enter the
password for the user post grass.
This is the exact same password we initially set up during the installation of post crest sequel so
I will say lowercase password and go ahead and save the password that we don't need to enter every time.
So again only that it was a double clicked on post stress equal to 12.
It's gonna connect to the server using a password that I set up earlier.
OK.
And now you should see it connected with this little elephant symbol.
So I've connected to my server and everything's good to go.
If you get an error there on the post yes you can try leaving the password blank but really most likely
you enter the password wrong and you may need to go back and look down to where you wrote that password.
Now it's time to actually restore the database so if connected to a server you'll notice that there
is that default post crest database or next you're going to right click on post critical 12.
After connecting to it and then we're going to say create a database and then the database we're going
to create is called DVD
rental and then we'll say save and then that creates what is essentially this little empty database
here.
So you can go ahead and click on it and we can see that that database is created.
But right now there's no tables or information in this database.
So we're going to restore the database and we do that by right clicking now on that database and going
down here and we're going to say restore click on restore and make sure that underneath format it says
custom or tar file and then we're going to do is we're going to grab that DVD rental that TAR file location
and pass it here as file name.
Now there's two ways of doing this.
One is to click on these three little dots and then search around for wherever you happen to save that
file.
And keep in mind you may need to show hidden files and folders and have all files as the format and
you can see here.
I have found DVD rental that tar and then I can select it.
And here now I have the full file path.
Now what sometimes occurs is when you click these three points you actually are in a weird location
on your computer and you can't actually find it.
You can try navigating uses using this home or using backup and sometimes you're in this kind of weird
location and you don't really know how to actually find that DVD rental that TAR file.
That's totally ok.
All you need to do is just manually type in the file name so how can we do that.
Well I can come back to where I actually saved that DVD rental that TAR file recall I can click on properties
here and then all I need to do is just copy and paste this location so I'll go ahead and copy that and
then I could manually paste it in here.
That's now the location and then just add in DVD rental dot tar file.
So you have two options.
One is to try to locate the file isn't it a little graphical user interface.
If you're doing that make sure you're showing hidden files and folders as well as showing all files
and you can navigate by going back home here or going back etc. Or you can just manually type out the
file name.
So if the street version doesn't work for you just go ahead and manually type it out then we're gonna
come to restore options and we're gonna make sure that we select pre data as yes data as yes and then
post data as yes.
OK those are actually the only sections that we need to worry about as far as these restore options
are concerned.
You can leave everything else as the default will come back to general and then we'll go ahead and select
restore click on restore.
They'll say restore job created.
Now depending on your actual version of post sequel you may see this little field executed pop up and
I'll say failed execute one you can go ahead and click on more details and if you read these details
it's essentially just saying hey it failed to create it twice.
So sometimes on certain systems it actually creates it twice.
That's totally ok.
We can safely ignore that.
So what we're gonna do here is our DVD rental that TAR file has been successfully restored.
You only thing we need to do now is refresh in order to actually see those changes.
So we're going to right click on DVD rental.
You'll notice it has this refresh.
Go ahead and refresh.
And now what's gonna happen is underneath the actual DVD rental database we should be able to perform
a sample query to make sure everything's running.
So I'm going to right click and then I'm going to select query tool query tool is essentially what we're
gonna be using for the rest of the course.
And this allows us to actually perform a query and then ask for information back.
So we're going to say select and then an asterix from film semicolon and then to run this you can go
ahead and click this little play button.
So it's the execute refresh.
Go ahead and run that and you should see now under data output some actual information here.
Okay.
And if you see this information then everything was successful.
If for some reason it says film does not exist which is sometimes a commoner.
Make sure you restart your computer if it still doesn't say that film does not exist.
Go ahead and try a lower voter version of post quest sequel because most likely what's happening is
your specific OS doesn't work with that specific version of progress equal.
So you can just repeat the steps for any previous version of Postgres sequel but we can see here that
everything is working and this is what we're gonna be using for the rest of the course.
So we can check out this query Ed anytime by clicking underneath the version of Postgres sequel underneath
databases DVD rental right click and then you would just hit query tool.
OK.
And that's it for how to perform a query with PGE admin and successfully restore the database.
If you have any questions please make sure to check out the Q and A forums.
We have hundreds of already answered questions there.
So I would highly recommend you check those out first before posting a new question in order to save
yourself some time.
Thank you so much and I'll see you at the next lecture.