Welcome everyone to this lecture on the account function the COUNT function returns the number of input
rows that match a specific condition of a query we can apply count on a specific column or just past
count and then an asterisk.
We will soon see the should return the same result because count is merely reporting back the number
of rows returned which is going to be the same regardless of the actual column you're looking at.
Let's see a simple example.
Here again we have that table with a couple of names and then their color choice let's imagine we called
SELECT COUNT name from table notice here count does need the parentheses because it's a function acting
on something so it won't work without the parentheses.
Keep that in mind if we were to count the number of names from table.
That's just asking for how many rows are there in the named column which is going to be four.
So the result will be count for.
So again it's simply returning the number of rows in the table.
In fact this should really be the same regardless of the column we call because each column has the
same number of rows since they're literally in the same table which is why.
Whether you call SELECT COUNT name from table select count choice from table or select count asterisk
which is just saying select the count of all the rows for all the columns in the table.
They should all return the same thing since the original table has four rows.
That means each column has four rows.
Which is why I usually just see an asterisk from the table.
Now keep in mind it's sometimes useful to use a column name instead of just providing an asterisk because
if you come back on your secret query some time later it may actually help kind of stir the memory of
what actual question you were trying to answer.
So again because of this count by itself simply returns back a count of the number of rows in a table
and count is usually much more useful when combined of other commands such as the distinct command that
we already learned about Imagine you wanted to know how many unique names are there in the table.
So to answer this question we need to first decide the distinct number of names then we'll provide count
on that result of the stink name from table.
So the logic that's going to happen is distinct is going to figure out what the distinct names are.
Here it seems that David is duplicated so it's just going to kind of remove that and now we have the
three unique names and then count is going to count the remaining rows here which in this case is going
to be three rows.
So the end result for a select count distinct name from table is three answering the question that there
are three unique names in the table.
It won't tell you what those names are.
That would just be a distinct call by itself and again notice the parentheses structure here.
It's informing us that we are calling.
Count on the result of distinct name if you want.
You can also provide parentheses for name on distinct although that's not necessary.
As we've previously discussed however some people find this result more readable let's go ahead and
explore some examples in P.G. admin okay.
Here I am at the query editor in PGA admin.
Let's select everything from the payment table just so we can take a look at it.
So say select everything from payment.
I can see there's a payment I.D. customary the staff I.D. etc..
There's also an amount and a payment date.
Let's imagine I just wanted to know the number of rows that are in this table now.
Luckily for us this table's pretty small.
Which means I could if I wanted to scroll all the way down and then check the actual here on the left
hand column.
It's just account so I could scroll all the way down and eventually I would see the correct answer.
However and this is actually quite a large table.
There's more than a thousand entries in a realistic database you're gonna have very very large tables
so you're not going to just scroll down just to see how many rows there are in this table.
So one easy way to do this is just say select count and then to make it easier to read I'll pass and
the princes.
And it just is asking count the number of rows and all the columns.
So this should all be the same which means it's going to be fourteen thousand five hundred and I need
six rows so much easier to do that than scroll down until you see fourteen thousand five hundred ninety
six and you could do this for essentially any column.
So if I pass in the let's say amount column again this is just asking how many rows are there and the
amount column.
Well it should be the same as the number of rows in the actual table.
So notice we get back the exact same result.
So when people are beginning to learn about sequel they sometimes get confused over what column we're
gonna pass on the count and in the end it really doesn't matter.
It's really probably most common to see an asterisk since.
Again it doesn't matter but sometimes it might be easier to use a column name in order to set your mind
set.
As far as what you were thinking when you're writing this query so if you come back later in time and
you would see this query you can see that you were probably thinking about the amount column because
somebody asked you a specific question of it.
So keep that in mind.
It might be easier for you to actually clarify with a column name.
Okay now let's go ahead and say just select the amount column from payments run this and I can see there's
different amounts that people are paying 7 9 9 1 8 9 2 9 9 5 9 9 etc..
Let's imagine I wanted to figure out the actual number of payment types.
What are the actual number of unique amounts or distinct amounts being paid.
If I were to just use distinct on the amount column I would run this and it shows me the distinct values
1 and I intend to write to ninety nine etc. essentially removing any duplicates.
So this answer is a question what are the unique payment amounts.
However my question is how many unique amounts are there.
Which means I should be counting the result of this.
So one way I could do that is scroll all the way down and realize there's 19 rows here or to do this
programmatically.
I would just say count distinct amount.
I run this.
And notice here when I'm using these two functions I will need to specify with princes so I'll say count
distinct amounts and then it actually ends up working.
So the reason in this case that I need to use parentheses is because if I don't post gross sequel is
going to think that I'm trying to call count on some distinct column which doesn't exist.
So this is why I need to call parentheses and specify that distinct the amount should happen first before
I call.
Count on whatever this result is.
And if you want you can add in another set of parentheses just to make it more readable for you.
It really depends on your personal style and we'll get back the same result.
OK so that's it for learning about count.
Coming up next we're going to learn about the select where statement which is really going to help us
out in a lot of different query types.
I'll see you there.