Hello everyone and welcome to the installation and set up lecture for Mac OS users so it's time to get
set up for the course in this lecture video.
We're going to be installing two main things.
One is Postgres sequel which is the actual sequel engine that stores the data has the database reads
in queries and returns back information from that database.
The second thing we're going to be installing and setting up is P.G. admin P.G. Ataman is the graphical
user interface that we will use in order to connect with the back end of post Cress equal.
Now there's a couple of things to note here.
First thing to note is please make sure to follow each step in order very carefully.
If you do these steps out of order or mess a certain part of each step up then you may have to go back
and restart from the very beginning.
There's two really common confusion points.
One is later on we're going to download a file called DVD rental that TAR file do not open that TAR
file directly.
We'll show you how to deal with it later on and also later on we're going to setup a password for both
progress equal FPGA admin.
Make sure you do not forget that password and sure you write it down somewhere.
OK so help avoid any missteps.
We've gone ahead and numbered the major steps and we'll present them right now in the correct order.
So let's get started with step number one which is to download and install post press equal for step
number one.
I'm going to head over to the Google Chrome browser and then go to Google dot com okay.
Here I am at Google dot com.
Go ahead and search for post crest sequel in Google just hit Google search.
And the first thing you should see after advertisements is the official Web site which is post gross
equal dot org.
And then click on this official site for post Postgres sequel.
And it should look something like this.
Keep in mind this page does get updated from time to time but this is we're going to be downloading
post Cress sequel and somewhere on this page you should see a download button.
Either just be really obvious here and download or appear at the top.
So go ahead and click download that will take it to the court distribution page and you'll see the different
packages.
There's the linux packages the windows packages et cetera.
But right now we're focusing on Mac OS since I'm on a Mac right now.
I'll click on Mac OS and then you'll see here there's different options for the Mac OS packages.
And then there's also different versions for platform support.
So depending on what version of the 64 bit Mac OS Platform you have you may actually need to download
a lower version of post sequel.
So make sure that you actually check that your Mac OS Platform is going to correspond to whatever version
of Postgres sequel you have.
So again older Max will need to go with older postgrad sequels.
OK.
So in general I'm just going to use the latest one since I'm on MAKO as Catalina and I'm going to click
right here where it says interactive installer enterprise D.B..
I'll click on download the installer and this will take me to the enterprise Debbie download page.
And here we can see for Mac OS.
Go ahead and choose the corresponding post grad sequel version.
You can check on the last page to see what version of Mac OS corresponds to which version of postcard
sequel supports.
I'm on the latest version of Mac OS.
So right now the latest version of Post classical supports that.
I'll go ahead and click download here under Mac OS 10 and then go ahead and let it download.
It should download this zip file somewhere onto your computer and then I'll go ahead and save it underneath
my downloads folder.
So go ahead and click save and then it's going to download that zip file for us.
OK I'm going to fast forward in time until this is done downloading.
OK.
This has now finished installing.
So what I'm going to do here is fish see it and finder.
We have this zip file.
I'm going to go ahead and just open it with the default archive utility that will unzip this right here
underneath downloads and you'll see here that I now have this postcard sequel OSX.
Go ahead and double click on that and then you may get this notification saying it's an app downloaded
from the Internet.
Are you sure you want to open it.
Go ahead and click open for some people.
They have their Mac OS settings that says it doesn't allow them to open.
UNIDENTIFIED developers or unidentified applications.
You'll have to go to your settings and change that.
And if you just google search the actual terms that Mac OS returns to you about opening stuff.
UNIDENTIFIED developers we'll show you how to open that very easily through a Google search.
But in my case it's just asking me if I want to open it Go ahead and select open it may ask you for
your password.
Go ahead and provide it.
And the installer should be in.
So here's the setup wizard.
I'm just gonna hit next here.
Go ahead and choose the default directory and you'll notice there's some components here that it's going
to install.
Go ahead and just select them all have all the default selected hit next.
Go ahead and select the default for the data directory of where it's going to save our data.
And this is the extremely important part.
There is a password here that you need to provide.
And if you ever forget this password you'll need to essentially uninstall everything and reinstall from
the beginning.
So I highly recommend that you put in a password here that you're no You're going to remember.
So what I like to do is I just like to just type in password and all lowercase.
So we'll say password since this is on our own computer we don't need to worry about any sort of security
issue if this.
So I'm just typing password and all lowercase again you must remember this password.
If you decide to do something more complicated make sure you write down this password somewhere else
because if you forget this password there's really nothing I can do for me for you on my end.
You'll need to uninstall and reinstall everything.
So this is a very important step but you must remember this password.
OK I'm going to go ahead and hit next.
All right the next thing you're going to do is select a port number the server should be listening on
depending if you've already installed post crest sequel before or not you may see a different port number
here than what I have currently I have five four three three.
It's really common that it shows up as five four three two.
But whatever the default value is here.
Go ahead and just leave it be.
So my default right now is on five four three three which essentially means that port is open and the
server can listen on it.
It's essentially going to be the connection of where Postgres sequel is going to live.
And keep in mind that if you have a corporate firewall you want to make sure it's not blocking this
sort of port.
So later on when you're running PGI admin if you see that their firewall is blocking that port go ahead
and allow your firewall to connect with Postgres sequel.
And this particular port number.
So it provided me a 5 4 3 3 4 provide you with a higher number or a lower number that's totally ok just
select the default hit next and then select the default location for the new database cluster hit next.
And then we'll say pre installation summary that's OK to hit next setup is now ready to begin hit next.
And let it install onto your computer.
I'm going to fast forward until this is done installing.
OK.
That has finished installing for me.
Keep in mind if you're running an older version of Mac OS or you have a much older mac book that you
updated to the latest version of Mac OS you sometimes get an error that says something like database
cluster initial initialization couldn't be done or could not be found etc. If you get an error at that
particular step between hitting install and then actually finishing the wizard it most likely means
they need to downgrade to alert lower version of Postgres sequel.
So if you get an error saying something about the database cluster initialization not being setup correctly.
Go ahead and try a much lower version of progress equal like nine point seven or something like 10.
So don't go for the latest one.
OK.
In my case it looks like everything went well.
It's an ask if you want to launch stack builder exit.
We don't need to do that.
So go ahead and unclip that and then just hit finish.
OK.
And now we've taken care of Step 1 which was installing post Cress sequel.
It's time to move on to Step Two.
Step two is the download and install P.G. admin P.G. Adam is the graphical user interface that we'll
be using to connect with post press equal.
And what's really interesting about the latest version of P.G. Ataman is that it actually opens up in
your browser.
Let's go ahead and show you how to download it.
To do this we'll go to our browser.
OK.
Here I am at the browser.
We're going to go ahead and do is just input PGI admin.
Go ahead and google search.
And after the advertisements the first thing you should see is WW that P.G. Adam and dot org.
So that's the official Web site for PGI admin.
Go ahead and click on it.
And this is an open source free.
And it's the most popular way to work with post press equal.
And what we're going to do here is somewhere here you should be able to see that there's a download
button.
There's also an interesting online demo if you want to check it out so you can kind of quickly see what's
going on online without downloading anything but go ahead and go to download.
We'll go to PGA admin and the latest version is PGA admin for if you're running a really old version
of MapQuest.
You may need to run PGA admin three it will warn you that it's actually no longer supported but that
basically means that they're not supporting PGA admin with the latest versions of post press equal.
That's OK if you're running a older version of Mac OS you can go ahead and just click on MacOS under
PGA item three.
I'm really the latest version of Mac OS so I will go ahead and select Mac OS under PGA admin for they
will take me to the downloads here you can see that there's various versions of peace on and for they
keep updating it with more features or better workings under the hood.
I'll go ahead and just select the newest version which in my case was four point one eight.
You'll see here that I'll take you to kind of this interesting file browser directory.
There's no files here.
Really what we're looking for is just the start DMV file which is the typical installer for any application
on a Mac OS.
You'll notice that it's by far the largest file so that's actually the only one we need here is the
largest file which is the dot the empty file.
Go ahead and click on it and upon clicking on it we're gonna do is we're gonna save this to our downloads
folder.
So I will save that to downloads and that's going to download that dot TMG file.
Going to fast forward in time until this is done downloading it and then we'll walk through the installation.
OK.
This DMV file has finished downloading it.
I'll go ahead and open it.
So this is essentially running the installer and we'll go ahead and agree to the terms and then it's
going to open the doors the AMG file it'll verify this may take a couple of seconds and then you should
see a little window that looks something like this.
PGI admin for and right now what this has done is it has PGI admin for ready to go.
But we need to do is to make sure that the saves on our computer and we don't accidentally start reinstalling
it every time to open it.
We need to save this and move this to our applications.
So we need to do is in your finder window.
Go ahead and look for your applications folder.
You can come here to applications click on that.
So here we have our applications folder that should actually be under favorites by default essentially
where all your applications live.
And if you notice here you start scrolling down to P. You have post Chris equal available for you but
you don't yet have PGI admin for.
So what we need to do is simply grab PGI admin for and drag it and move it to applications.
Okay.
And what that is going to do is that will finish the entire installation process.
Otherwise you would actually be reinstalling PGI admin each time you actually wanted to open it.
Okay.
So that's it for installing PJM and for is following through that that DMV procedure and then making
sure that you actually copy the PJM and 4 and move it over to your applications.
All right.
So once that has moved over to the applications you can go ahead and close this initial window.
It's quite a large file so keep that in mind going to fast for a timeout until this is done copying
over okay.
Now that has finished being transferred over to other applications.
If you don't see it under applications after you transfer over to it you may need to click on desktop
and then come back to applications in order to see the actual change occur inside of your a little finder
window.
So right here we see PGI admin for and if you go back to your desktop you now no longer have to worry
about this little temporary drive that's open.
You'll notice there's PGI admin for here on your desktop.
Go ahead and you can just check that and they'll remove from your computer.
However it's safe to say that it still exists on your computer now under applications.
All right.
And that concludes step number two.
Step three is to download but not directly open the DVD rental that TAR file as a resource in this installation
lecture you should see a DVD rental tar file as a resource to download or we're going to do is download
this file but do not attempt to unzip the file double click on the file or open the file or interact
with the file in any manner.
It's only meant to be interacted with directly through P.G. admin so please do not directly open or
interact with the file.
Sometimes computers think it's a PDA file or it's a zip file that needs to be unzip.
Do you do not need worry about any of that.
All we're doing for this step is downloading it.
So let's show you how to do that.
If you take a quick look at you to me support page on course taking there is an entire article lecture
devoted to downloading supplemental resources.
Keep in mind this may change in future versions of you to me but right now the current way you download
them is there's a little icon underneath the lecture called resources that you just click on and then
it'll have a drop down menu of the different resources to download.
So what's going to happen is as you're watching the actual installation lecture you'll be a complete
sequel bootcamp.
You'll come over here and then over here somewhere on the right of this particular lecture you'll hit
resources and then you'll see this DVD read told not tar file you'll go ahead and click on that and
you'll save it and make sure to save it underneath your downloads.
You must remember where this is saved so go ahead and save that to your downloads and that's all we're
gonna do for this step.
Do not attempt to double click on this file or open this file or unzip this file that will cause an
error for the rest of the installation process.
So once you download it that's it.
And that's all you need to do for that.
OK let's move on to the next step.
All right.
Step number four is to restart your computer in order to make sure your computer has attributed all
the changes necessary for Postgres sequel and P.G. admin.
It's common that we need to restart your computer.
So go ahead and just restart your computer and we'll move on to the next step.
All right.
Step number five is essentially the last step or we're going to be restoring that database.
Keep in mind there may be a failed exit code that appears and you can safely ignore it in some particular
versions of Postgres sequel along with some particular versions of Mac OS.
You get a failed exit code that pops up because the database attempts to restore itself twice.
Now what happens is it works fine on the first time and then it gets an error the second time because
it works successfully the first time.
So if you get the failed exit code it's totally safe to ignore it.
So we'll go ahead and try our best to show you how to ignore the exit code.
But again if you get a failed exit code one you can safely ignore that exit code in order to restore
the database.
We'll need to start startup P.G. admin.
So let's do that.
You started PGI admin.
All you need to do is search for PGE admin and it should autocomplete with PGI admin for underneath
your applications.
Go ahead and open that so we'll double click on that.
And what's going to happen is it's going to start up PGI admin for us.
They'll verify it.
You may get this warning saying it's downloaded from the Internet.
Are you sure you want to open it Go ahead and stay open.
If it does not allow you to open it from the internet go ahead and just change your settings to allow
you to open things from unidentified developers.
If you're not sure how to do that you can just google search the actual message that pops up and there's
pretty much tons of tutorials online that teach you how to just go to your settings and edit it so you
can open that up.
OK so I'll go ahead and open it you'll see this little icon up here PJM and management tools and this
may take a few minutes especially the first time it's ever opening it though it's going to happen is
eventually it's going to open up in your browser.
We'll go ahead and allow notifications from PGI admin.
So I'm going to forward in time until this is done up.
There we go.
So it's already running and it's going to open up in your browser and what it's going to ask you is
to set the master password for PGE admin.
Keep in mind this is technically a different password than the Postgres sequel user password.
This is just for PGI admin.
However I would highly recommend that you set this to something either the same as Post Chris or just
something you can really remember in my case.
I'll keep it simple and just set this as password and be careful when you're spelling this because there
is no confirmed password which is kind of a design flaw here.
But just go ahead and I'll going to choose lowercase password makes you write this down somewhere here.
OK.
And then you should see something that looks like this.
So we have PGI admin for it's running in our browser.
You can always copy and paste this your URL.
You want to use a different Internet browser.
It'll open up in your default one underneath servers if you expand on this.
Well you should see is post graphs equal to 12.
Now if you've already installed older older versions of Postgres sequel on your computer you may actually
see those pop up in my case I actually installed nine point five earlier.
So I see that pop up but you should see post Chris equal to 12 here.
If you don't see it make sure you've already restarted your computer and then expand this again.
And when you try to expand it it's going to ask you to enter the password for post Cress.
That's the same password that was set up during the first initial installation of post Cress equal.
That's why it's so important that you remember what that password is.
In my case I just kept it all lowercase password.
So that should be good to go.
Go ahead and select safe password again if you do not remember the postcard password.
There's really nothing I can do for you here.
You'll need to start over since the very beginning.
OK then.
OK.
That should work since that was the correct password.
And now we can see a bunch of information about the dashboard etc. What we're going to do here is just
restore our database.
So to do this I'm going to first create underneath databases a new database.
I can see there is one that already exists called Post press.
I'm going to right click here and hit create and then database.
Now we're going to call this database DVD rental so called the database DVD rental and then go ahead
and hit save.
The owner should be by default post Chris hit save and you'll see how this new DVD rental database that
we're not yet connected to.
If you click on it you should see it get colored in and now we're connected to it.
And now it's time to actually put the information into this database by restoring from that DVD rental
that TAR file.
So I'm going to right click here and I'm going to go down to where it says restore.
Click on restore.
So what we need to do is we need to tell PGI admin where our DVD rental that our file is actually located.
So we need to find the file name.
So most people are going to be able to click on these three points here and then actually search their
computer for it.
However for some users especially on MAKO as Catalina there's been some issues lately of just stuff
being locked or not being able to actually find the file itself.
So here maybe you can search on other applications.
A double click on that.
And then keep going forward.
But what I want to do is show you the failed Perth pathway which is just to manually provide the file
name.
And I prefer this way anyways.
So what we're going to do is we're gonna remember that we saved that DVD rental that TAR file underneath
downloads so open up your Downloads folder and you should see DVD rental that time.
So we know it's located under downloads.
All I want to do is grab the complete file path so I'll right click on DVD rental Avatar again.
That's a right click and then select get info and here I can see where it's going to tell me it's in
their Macintosh HD Users and in my particular user name is Marcy here and then downloads.
So what I'll do is I'll highlight that entirety of where right click hit copy then come back here to
restore and then select paste.
So notice now it gives me the file path users Marci downloads.
Then we'll complete this by saying forward slash DVD rental dot tar.
And that's gonna be the complete file path telling PGI admin go look at this location and look at this
file.
The next we need to do before we hit restore is go to restore options and select pre data data and post
data and then come back to general and then we're ready to go hit restore and it will attempt to restore
this.
They'll ask you Would you like to access your Downloads folder.
Go ahead and allow it to.
Once you hit ok here.
And that should actually complete the restoration process.
Keep in mind that you may actually see this failed exit code.
One pop up.
It's totally ok if you see that you can go ahead and ignore that.
It just means that it attempted to restore it twice which is totally ok.
So go ahead and exit this and then we're going to do here is we're going to say on TV the rental right
click and refresh in order to have those changes take place.
And now let's attempt our first query on this DVD rental database.
We're going to right click and select query tool and query tool is essentially where we spend the rest
of the course.
This is where we actually learn and type out sequel.
So I'm gonna type out select space Asterix space from space film semicolon and then we'll go ahead and
run this
and upon running that you should see here under a data output just some film.
These titles descriptions etc. And now you successfully restored the database and you queried it for
more information and we'll talk about what this actually means.
Later on in the course but this is just the general query Ed..
OK if you get some sort of error saying film not recognized or not found.
Make sure that you follow the steps.
Exactly.
So you may not have to go back and restart your computer or you could also do is try using a lower version
of Postgres sequel.
If that error keeps coming back because most likely what's happening is that your particular version
of Mac OS wasn't suitable for the most recent version of post sequel.
OK.
If you're able to run this query and see the results then you're ready to go.
I'll see you in the next lecture.