Welcome back everyone to this lecture on unions.
The union operator is used to combine the results set of two or more select statements.
The way I like to think about a union versus the joint we've already learned is that it basically just
serves to directly concatenate two results together essentially just pasting the results of two select
statements right on top of each other the syntax is simply the following You have your first select
statement and then you have a union with another SELECT statement something to keep in mind is that
these should be logical and they should match up in a way that you can stack the results right on top
of another.
Let's go through a simple example so let's imagine we have these two example tables and what we're doing
is we're organizing the sales per year per quarter.
So I have one table with my first quarter sales for the year 2021 where David sold one hundred amount
and Claire sold fifty then I have another table storing my results from the second quarter.
Again David now has sold two hundred and Claire has now sold one hundred if I actually want to put together
the information from these two tables in order to get kind of total results or see every single time
a amount was sold for the first half of the year.
I can't really use the typical joins now we're already familiar with.
Instead what I should be doing is just pasting one of these on top of the other.
And this is perfect for a union so all we need to do is say select everything from the first sales quarter
union with select everything from the second sales quarter and what it's gonna do is just grab the results
from the first query and then paste them right on top of the second query.
And as you can imagine if you wanted to you could have multiple union calls just pasting together these
different results and you can also do is for example if you wanted to be ordered or sorted by the name
you can just add an order by call after this to order it by the name.
OK.
So as far as the DVD rental database goes there is not really a good use case for the Union call.
So instead we'll explore union calls later on in the course with another database.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.