Welcome back everyone to this lecture on the altar cloth.
The altar clause allows for changes to an existing table structure.
It has lots of use cases such as adding dropping or renaming columns changing columns data type setting
default values for a column adding check constraints and even renaming a table.
Let's look at just a few examples for the general syntax for these cases the general syntax is altar
table table name and then some sort of action call.
For example if you wanted to add columns to a table you would say altar table table name.
Add a column the new column name and then specify a data type you can remove columns by saying altar
table table name drop column and then the column name you want to drop you can alter the constraints
of an existing column by again using altar table table name altar column the column name and then you
can do things like set a default value you can drop the default value you can remove or add in a not
null constraint such as setting I'm not more constrained to add one end you can drop and not no constraint
you can add just a general constraint by saying add a constraint and then the definition of the constraint
name like a check constraint etc. So let's cut and explore some examples since there is lots of things
we can do with this altar table command okay.
Here I am in I admin since we're going to be doing so much altering and editing to a table.
Let's go ahead and create a new table first we'll say create table and we'll have just this table be
called general information and let's go ahead and have just a couple of columns here we'll say an info
I.D. column which is going to be serial and based as a primary key let's have something else called
title.
This will just be like the title of some information say five hundred characters max and let's say for
now it cannot be no and we'll add in one more column.
Let's go ahead and have this be some person the information is related to again variable character.
We'll say 50 let's have it be not null as well as unique.
All right.
So a very basic table here we'll go ahead and run this okay.
So the tables created let's select everything from that table just we can see the columns so select
everything from the information table we have invitee title and person.
Let's do a couple of things first.
Let's go in and rename this table.
So the way we do this is by saying alter table we choose the current name which is information and then
we say rename to and this will change the table name to something else.
Let's go ahead and call this table new info.
We run this and we successfully alter the table which means if I were to try to select from the information
table I get information does not exist which means I need to use the new name which is new info.
And again we get back this empty table.
So that's how I can rename the table if I want to rename just a column.
I can do this.
I can say altar table new info renamed column.
Let's go ahead and rename the column.
So the way this works is we say rename column person to the new name.
Let's go in and say people run that and if we select everything from new info I see now.
Person is people.
So obviously a lot of things you can do here with this alter table command.
The next thing I want to do is show you how you can use the alter command in order to alter constraints
that already exist on certain columns.
But to do this first I want to show you how we could try to insert data into this table so I'm going
to say insert into new info and I want to insert let's say just a title recall that people was also
not know.
So I'm actually not going to provide people on purpose here.
We're going to say values and let's just have title be some new title.
And if I were to run this I get back an error saying no value in column people violates not no constraint.
OK so we have two options Either I can add in people and then add a value for it or I can try to remove
this not null constraint using altered table.
Obviously that affects it permanently for the table on a table level.
But this is just to show you the alter command.
So I'm going to say alter table new info alter column people and then we're going to drop the not null
constraint.
If I wanted to set a constraint then I would use set and that adds a constraint.
If you want to remove a constraint use drop and recall this not null can be anything could be dropping
the unique call that not no call any sort of constraint here.
OK so let's go ahead and run this.
OK so I successfully alter that table.
Now what I'm going to do is if I take a look at my query history I can actually grab that old query
of insert info.
So let's go ahead and copy this.
You can also I'm pretty zoomed in here.
I might look at make it look a little strange but in your eyes you should see insert into.
Go ahead and copy this.
You can even copy it directly into the query editor.
So I'll just click that.
So we're trying to now insert into new info title values some new title.
Go ahead and run this.
See if it works this time.
And notice that it was able to work because I had removed that not no constraint.
So if I select everything from new info run this we're able to add in some new title and keep people
as something no if you ever get confused or stuck or have trouble remembering what the actual calls
are for the altar table command.
You can always go to the documentation and look up altar table and it has a whole synopsis of the different
variants you can use such as rename to the table etc. We can also show you different actions that are
available dropping columns adding columns altering columns.
So lots and lots of different options here and examples.
And if you start scrolling down has even more detail on each of these commands such as ultra constraint
there's also things like dropping constraints et cetera.
So lots of different options here.
It's all for you.
It's all here for you in the documentation.
OK thanks.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.