Welcome everyone to this lecture on an overview of the graphical user interface we use for this course
which is P.G. Adelman version for so by now you should have gone through the installation lecture have
P.G. Ataman and post Chris equal installed and setup.
It should have been able to perform your first sequel query in the query editor or query tool.
What I want to do now is just quickly go over some of P.G. Adam features.
Keep in mind this is kind of an optional lecture.
We're going to be going over things like how to change font size how to choose a dark theme how to get
shortcuts from with NPC admin.
If that sort of stuff doesn't really interest you or if you're fine if the defaults or if you feel comfortable
enough they you can quickly just google search how to change these sort of things.
Feel free to continue on with the rest of the course since this particular lecture technically isn't
about sequel it's just a quick overview of the graphical interface.
If you are interested in those things go ahead and continue along by opening up P.G. Adumim.
So let's head over to PJ Adelman now.
OK here I am inside of P.G. admin when you open up P.G. atom and you'll see the servers here.
You'll see a dashboard as well.
And what's nice is it has some useful links such as adding a new server if that's necessary to go to
the documentation.
The PGA admin official Web site etc..
So if you expand on servers you should then see the Postgres sequel version you install and then if
you expand on that you'll see databases and you'll see your DVD rental database.
Note here I have a couple more databases later on in the course will actually be creating some of these
databases so don't worry about that yet but you should see the DVD rental database that you created
in the installation lecture.
So let's go ahead and show you a couple of useful things for PGE Adelman.
First I want to start off by how to edit your preferences visual preferences for PGE Ataman if you come
to file select preferences you'll see a wide variety of preferences.
A lot of these are geared towards advance users so you have things like what to display on the dashboard
what graphs to show in the refresh rate for them.
But probably the ones you guys are most interested in is if you come to miscellaneous and select themes.
There is currently a standard theme but the latest version of PGA admin for released right now as I'm
filming this has a beta dark version.
Now since this is technically in beta I didn't want my PGA admin to crash as I was filming.
So this course is filmed in the standard theme but if you were working on sequel in a dark room or it's
nighttime and you want to rest your eyes a bit you can always select the dark theme for your own P.G.
admin.
The other thing I want to point out is the query tool is really where we spend most of the time in this
course and the query Ed specifically is really what we're working with.
And if you ever want to change the font size for the query editor you can come here under query tool
editor go to font size and then you can change the font size here something to note is that the font
size is actually not something like twelve point font like you would have in a normal word processor.
It's actually a relative font size.
So if you want to double the current font size you would type in a two because it's a two to one ratio.
If you want to increase the font size by 20 percent you would type in one point too.
So up to a maximum of 10 so that's 10 x.
The default font size which is probably way too large but this is something you can play around.
You can see here I have one point four so we'll go ahead and just not have any changes set that cancel
and those are the main preferences for visual things you can edit.
The other thing I want to point out here is if I go ahead and click on DVD rental and select that object
I see this dashboard start to show up as give me information of things things like how many transactions
am I performing on this particular database per second.
You can see here that essentially I'm not really doing anything right now with it.
So it's kind of a flat line and you can always edit what's shown on the dashboard.
Again by going to your preferences dashboards display graphs and you can refresh this faster choose
things not the display etc..
Let's go ahead and cancel that.
And then the real thing that's pretty important to understand here is if you have your database selected
there's a variety of tabs here on properties sequel statistics dependencies dependents cetera.
And we're going to be understanding these particularly what this actually means here with sequel.
Later on in this course.
But really where we spend most of the time here is if you right click you see the query tool option.
That's where we spend most of the time.
And if you have an object selected you can also then go to object appear in the top toolbar and it will
give you the same abilities either on their object or under tools such as query tool and you can easily
get those again by right clicking on a database.
So essentially you can either get them here from the top toolbar or by right clicking and select the
toolbar here.
So let's go ahead and right click on this.
Open up an example query Ed..
So here I have my query Ed..
Something to note about the query Ed is you have this nice query history option.
So if we perform the same query we did at the beginning select from film and then I can either run this
with play or by refreshing with a five you'll see some results here and obviously we don't know sequel
quite yet to understand everything here but we see a data output which is the rows and then the columns
we see explain.
Sometimes you will have something to explain especially for inserting stuff into a table.
Right now we are not doing anything advanced enough to see an explanation.
There's messages you should always pretty much see a message indicating whether or not your query actually
worked.
Also how fast it was which is kind of nice if you want to compare queries and then any notifications
if necessary.
In this case this is simple enough that there are no notifications so beyond this data output what's
nice.
Also here available to us in the query editor is you can go to your query history.
So here I can see a variety of query histories.
I'm going to have a lot more history than you.
Because this is from filming other things for the course that you've seen here.
But what's nice about this is let's say I take a look at some historical query I can either just copy
that query or I can copy to query editor select that and it will automatically copy and paste something
from history directly to the query editor.
So I can run that as well and do worry about understanding this sequel could we actually cover this
later on in the course.
Another thing I want to show you is if you're actually selecting something from the data output and
you decided hey I want to share this with somebody else as a CSP file you can come over here to this
little download icon and it will download the current results as a CSP which is a comma separated variable
file and that's the kind of file that you can open easily with Excel or a wide variety of programs.
So that might be helpful to you if you're trying to build a report for someone else or just share with
them the results.
Now the other thing I want to point out here is because this is in the browser sometimes you'll accidently
quick on click on this query tool and drag it out and then you get this kind of weird separate window.
If that ever happens to you if anything you can always just grab it again and then snap it back as if
it was a tab.
So I'm going to grab this and note here it's kind of going to highlight that I'm putting it back in
there and I will snap it back to the main tab.
And the last thing I want to show you is how to quickly access online help.
So if you come over here to help there's both help on P.G. admin which is a graphical user interface
and help on post Cress equal.
So if you click on pediatric Web site it takes us to that official Web site.
It can click here on documentation.
Introduction four point one nine which is the latest version I installed and it has pretty much the
entire description of everything you see with Adelman.
So if for some reason you're super interested in the toolbar for instance click on toolbar here and
I will describe everything available to inside the toolbar.
So that is available to under help PGA and Web site.
And then underneath the PGA admin Web site you simply come to documentation and select the version that's
appropriate for you OK the other thing I want to show you is the postgrad sicko website is also available
to you underneath directly PGI admin.
So you got a post where a dot org.
Go to documentation choose the version we're using which is twelve and then you'll see the documentation
here.
So maybe your issue that in queries which is what we're going to cover click on that and I'll give you
an overview of table expressions such as the from clause.
Now the whole point of this course is for you not having to read through documentation for more advanced
equal commands.
We will reference the documentation for things like useful lookup tables or useful functions.
For example later on we'll cover mathematical functions and instead of listing them all in the video
we'll just reference that documentation fee to visit.
So you can always quite easily visit documentation by simply coming to help post go website and then
selecting documentation along with an online manual for your current release.
Okay.
So that it's pretty much all you need to know for now.
We'll cover some other useful features of PGA admin that are more specific to things like create table
commands much later on in the course.
All you really need to know for now is how to access that query tool which is the same thing we did
in the installation lecture.
Thanks.
And I will see you at the next lecture.