Welcome back everyone to this lecture on self join a self join is a query in which a table is joined
to itself self joins are useful for comparing values and a column of rows within the same table.
So the reason we talk about this as ADVANCE EQUAL commands instead of in the joint section is because
this sort of use case is more dependent on your table structure and the actual question and trying to
solve.
So it's not as common as just a normal inner join for example.
So let's discuss self join in a little more detail the self join can really be viewed as just the join
of two copies of the same table.
Keep in mind the tables are not actually copied internally but sequel performs the command as though
it were and the other thing keep in mind is there is no special keyword for a self join.
It looks just the same as a simple standard join in it carries the same syntax with the same table happen
to happening to be in both parts however when you are using a self join because you're using the same
table it is necessary to use an alias for the table.
Otherwise the table names would be ambiguous within the self join.
So let's see a syntax example of this in order to see what I'm talking about when I mean the same tables
being joined as well as those table aliases.
So here we can see the syntax for a self join I'm saying select table a thought column comma.
Table B that column from table as table a join table as table B on table a thought some column matching
to Table B that some other column.
So what's actually happening here.
Well the main thing to focus on are these table names.
Notice in green here we're saying from table as table a join table as table B which is me assigning
two different aliases to the same table.
This is what allows me to perform the self join.
The main thing to keep in mind is that even though you see representations of table a table B and just
table here all of these are actually referring to the same table.
We're just using the aliases in order to organize this okay.
So I think it's the best explained through an example.
So I want to show you a more realistic situation of when you would want to actually use this let's imagine
that we have a company and we have some employees in this company and employees have to send reports
to other employees.
So I have this table of employees with their primary key employee I.D. which is just a unique identifier
per employee than the name of that particular employee.
And then the I.D. of the person they need to send the report to so each employee sends reports to another
employee.
For example here I can see that.
Andrew.
Employee Number One sends a report to employee I.D. number three which happens to be Charlie.
So Andrew's sending reports that Charlie Bob's also sending reports to Charlie.
Charlie is sending reports to employee I.D. number four.
So that's David.
So Charlie reports.
David.
And then David sends reports to employee number one which is Andrew.
Now let's imagine I wanted to show the results of the employee name and their reports recipient name.
So I want to go from this employee's table to something that looks like this on the right where I have
the name and then the person they're reporting to instead of just the report I.D. which is the employee
I.D. of the person reporting to technically all this information is in this one singular table.
So I can use a self join to essentially make a copy join it together in order to match the employer
name or employee name with the report idea along with the employee I.D..
So let's break this down here again we have the generalized syntax and let's start swapping out the
components given but we want to accomplish here.
Going from this employees to just the name of the person they report to.
So what I'm going to do is first focus on the tables because that's really what we're doing here.
First things first is we have the main table.
So we already know the name of that table it's just employees.
So if I take a look at my employees table that's just the name of the table I'm working with.
So I'm going to replace that with employees and now it's time to select the first alias which is table
a.
So what I want for my first column is the employee name so I want to think of this as referring to the
employee name based off the employee I.D..
So I'm just gonna refer to that as ENP for employee then the second thing I want to do is focus on the
person they report to.
So for Table B alias I'll go ahead and label that thinking of it as based off the report I.D. so I'll
label that as report that I need to decide what column am I going to join this on or recall that the
employee underscore I.D. column corresponds with the report idea column the report I.D. column was just
representing the employee I.D. number and then the column we actually want to select happens to be the
name for both this theoretical employee's table and this theoretical report table and this is the final
syntax.
So this will take our singular employees table and return back the results of one column of employees
and then the second column of those same employees.
But the person they happen to be receiving reports from in in order to make sure you don't get two columns
with name.
We can always say that second column should be as Rep..
So essentially an alias for that second column that we would on C name name.
Instead we see name rep as shown here.
So we want results showing the employee name and the reports recipient name and again make sure you
kind of pause and make sure you understand the syntax and how we were essentially just swapping out
the tables and swapping out the aliases let's explore a quick example on our own DVD rental database
OK.
Here we are in P.G. admin.
Let's imagine that I wanted to answer the question find all the pairs of films that have the same length.
If we take a look at the film table so select everything from the film table we have the title of the
film and then if I scroll over I also have this length column so what I'm going to be doing is just
focusing on that title column and this length column and I essentially want to figure out what other
films happen to match up together as pairs that have the same length.
So if we take a look at chamber Italian for example which is the first one that I got notice here it's
one hundred seventeen minutes.
So if I say select title length from film where length is equal to a hundred and seventeen minutes and
run this.
Notice that there's besides chamber Italian for other movies a fair prejudice.
Graffiti love magic Moretz and resurrection Silverado that share the same length.
But my final result the way I wanted to look is to have two sets of titles and then their matching length.
So essentially I want to have these paired off chamber Italian for a fair prejudice then chamber Italian
again of graffiti love chamber Italian magic rats and then chamber Italian again finally with resurrection
resurrection Silverado.
So how can we actually do this.
Well to do this I would essentially need two copies at the same table.
So this is perfect for a self join.
So what we're gonna do here is forget about this where for a second and I'm just gonna run this.
So we have select title length from film First let's decide how we actually want to format this.
I'm going to pretend that I have two tables film one and film 2 or EF 1 EF 2 so I'll say F 1 title comma
f 2 title and then I decide to grab the length from one of the tables.
So we'll do it from f 1.
That way I can get something that looks like chamber Italian the mall rat 1 or whatever that film happened
to be called and then or a resurrection Silverado and then hundred and seventeen minutes.
So it's going to do this for all possible pairs of films that have the same length at least with the
ones that for the first instance it found it in the title of the column.
So then we're going to say from film as f 1 and then we're going to do an inner join on film as f 2
and this is where we have to decide what we're actually going to be joining on.
So I'm going to say join film as F two on and I'm going to say grab film I.D. from f 1 and I actually
don't want to set it equal to f to film my D.
Instead I want to say not equals 2 but in order for this to make sense of why we're doing and not equals
here.
And first actually going to do it incorrectly with an equal sign.
So if my f one film D is equal to my F two film I.D. And then I say and F one length is equal to F two
length.
Notice what I'm asking here for I'm basically just gonna match up for example chamber Italian with chamber
Italian again in the next table or its copy so far to run this I'm just basically matching each movie
with itself.
So what I actually want to do is make sure that for example chamber Italians film I d doesn't actually
match with any other film like these on the table but does happen to match with the same lengths.
So I'm gonna say not equal to here.
That's the kind of fundamental difference.
In order to answer this question.
So now when I run this that is what happens I get back.
Chamber Italians matched up with the other titles that happened to share the same length in runtime.
So what I'm doing is I select film 1 title film 2 title film 1 length from film as EF 1 inner join film
as EF 2.
So these are the aliases necessary in order to perform the self join and then on in his particular case
in order to answer the query I had to say not equals to the film D but I did want to make sure that
their lengths matched up and that's an example of a self join using that DVD rental database that we've
been playing around with.
OK thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.