Let's look at all the different services that fall
inside the Amazon Kinesis family.
Now, this is going to really help us answer the question, what is Amazon Kinesis?
You might've heard someone say the word Kinesis or read it in a
blog post somewhere, but what is Amazon Kinesis?
Well, Amazon Kinesis actually comprises several distinct AWS services,
each with their own purposes and capabilities.
Most commonly, when people talk about Kinesis,
they mean Kinesis Data Streams,
which are used to process large amounts of streaming data in near real time.
But there's also the Amazon Kinesis Data Firehose,
which is also used to process data in a more
hands‑off and managed by AWS kind of way.
You can also use Kinesis Data Analytics to analyze,
transform, and manipulate streaming data or leverage Kinesis Video Streams to
stream video data into AWS and make it viewable on websites,
leverage machine learning capabilities with it,
or simply store it and services like Amazon S3. With
these four different distinct services,
things can get pretty confusing pretty quickly, so let's
clarify some jargon around the word Kinesis.
When somebody says Kinesis all by itself or Kinesis Streams, they're
probably referring to Kinesis Data Streams, but technically, there
are Kinesis Firehose delivery streams, too.
If someone says Firehose or delivery streams,
they're talking about Kinesis Data Firehose and
Kinesis Data Firehose delivery streams.
And in later modules, we'll look at both of these services in more detail just to clarify things better and show you how each of them work.