Let's look at different destinations that we can
configure with Kinesis Data Firehose.
First, you can send your data along to Amazon S3. Now,
this would act as a long‑term object storage for any data that you have.
However,
if you wanted something a bit more flexible that you could
still interact with and maybe searched through,
you could send it to something like the Amazon Elasticsearch Service.
You could also send it to something like Amazon Redshift,
which would allow you to perform more data analytics‑style
queries rather than search‑based queries.
Another option for a destination is to send it along to Splunk,
another tool that might help you visualize and interact with your data.
Now, with all of these destinations,
there's some configuration that we can do to determine how
we're going to send the data along and a few different options
that we might want to take with it.
So let's look at each of these scenarios in more detail.
First, we'll look at sending data to Amazon S3 using Kinesis Firehose.
We'll start with just Kinesis Firehose and a destination bucket we want to
send the data to. As data comes in to Kinesis Firehose, either the buffer
interval or the buffer size will eventually be hit,
and at that point we would send our data over to a destination S3 bucket.
Now, there is also another option where we might process the data.
So, as it comes into the Kinesis Firehose delivery stream,
it would then be either the buffer interval or buffer size would then trigger
it to go over to Lambda. From there, Lambda would then process all this data
and either turn it into successfully processed data,
dropped records, or failed records.
Now, with this,
we would then send the failed records and the successfully
processed records to Kinesis Firehose to be then moved back
along to a destination S3 bucket,
and we could split up the successful and failed records to isolate
them a little bit better and review them later for more details
about why they failed the processing.
Another option with Amazon S3 is to do a pretty similar case,
except with a backup bucket where we store all of our original data.
So when data comes into the Kinesis Firehose and hits its
interval or buffer size limitations,
then it gets moved over to both Lambda for processing and the optional backup
bucket with an initial unprocessed copy of that data in case we want to keep
that around for the long term so we have another thing to replay if we need to
reprocess it or analyze it in a different way.
Now from there, of course,
Lambda then processes the data and does the exact
same thing it was doing earlier, where it takes the successful records,
the dropped records, and the failed records and treats
them differently. The dropped records it's going to leave
alone and not do anything to,
whereas with the successful and the failed records, it'll move over to
the destination bucket where we can then review it.
So these are some of the options we can configure with Kinesis Firehose when we're using the destination of Amazon S3.