So now that we've taken a closer look at Kinesis producers,
let's look over some of the ways we can read or consume
data from Kinesis using Kinesis consumers.
There are a few common consumers that we can use to read data from Kinesis.
We'll start by looking at the Kinesis Client
Libraries and when we might use them.
So what are the Kinesis Client Libraries?
As much as we love the AWS documentation,
there are not entire buildings filled with books on Amazon Kinesis.
The Kinesis Client Libraries, or KCLs for short,
are a tool designed to help consume and process data from Kinesis Streams.
It's also possible you hear them referred to as Kinesis Consumer Libraries.
The KCLs also support several different programming languages,
and you'll frequently see them used to help build
applications without having to write custom code to solve
common problems like handling failures.
The client libraries come with support for many different
programming languages like I mentioned.
These include Ruby, .NET, Node.js, Java, and Python.
One of the first major benefits of the Kinesis Client Libraries is that
they can be used seamlessly with Kinesis Producer Libraries in order to
handle the aggregated record data that we sent in a single collection of
records through to the Kinesis data stream.
Now as data is sent in from the Kinesis Producer Library
through to the Kinesis data stream,
and then it's actually processed inside of those shards
and retrieved by the client library,
the client library will then be able to take that aggregated
data and then de‑aggregate it into its constituent records
inside of the Kinesis data record.
So when the client library gets the data back from the stream,
it can then take it into each of these individual
records we stuffed into it earlier.
Before we move on, I want to make a quick note about throughput options.
When working with Kinesis Data Streams, there are two options for throughput.
The default of shared throughput is what we've been discussing up to this point.
All of the consumers can share throughput that is proportional to
the number of shards in the Kinesis data stream.
This scales linearly with 2 MB of reads per second
and 5 read transactions per second.
However, there's also another option called dedicated throughput,
also known as enhanced fan‑out.
This allows consumers to have the same capacity per shard,
dedicated explicitly just for that particular consumer.
So when you're using Kinesis and you want to use Kinesis Client Libraries,
there's an option to use the version 2 of the Kinesis
Client Libraries to get enhanced fan‑out,
and it's implemented by default.
You can use enhanced fan‑out when using the AWS SDKs and the APIs directly. However, using the Kinesis Client Libraries makes this much easier to do.