Now let's look at using the AWS SDKs to create consumers.
Why would we use the AWS SDKs in order to build our
consumers for Kinesis streams?
Well, to start, it'll give us complete control over the specific API actions,
which may be something we prefer if we're
customizing our application significantly.
We can also use the AWS SDK in any programming languages of our choice.
There's a variety of support for many, many different programming languages.
And because the underlying AWS HTTP requests are all set up as HTTP requests,
you can really use any language that could support that protocol.
Finally,
we can run our consumer application anywhere we
want in Amazon EC2 or AWS Lambda, in containers,
or really anywhere else, whereas for some of the other consumer options,
there might be more limitations on where we could use them.
In addition to the AWS SDKs,
we can also use other AWS services to act as consumers of a Kinesis data stream.
Some common AWS services that we might use as consumers of a Kinesis data
stream might be AWS Lambda or Kinesis Data Analytics,
which we talked about a little earlier.
We could also use Kinesis Delivery Firehose as a consumer,
and we'll talk about this service in more detail in later modules.
AWS Lambda is a serverless compute option.
This means that Lambda doesn't require the developer to have
persistent servers that they have to manage and maintain.
Instead, you upload your code,
and AWS handles running the code for you when needed.
The code usually runs in response to incoming events,
like API requests, file uploads, or, in this case,
when data is added to a Kinesis stream.
Now when new records enter the Kinesis stream,
they're going to be batched up and then sent over to AWS Lambda in
order so that that function can process them.
So let's look at how this works.
When we have a Kinesis data stream that has new records
coming into the Kinesis data stream,
we can configure a Lambda function to process this data.
You can write your function in a variety of different programming languages,
and as the Kinesis data stream is ingesting this data,
it will start to batch some of these records together into an event
that will then be sent over to the Lambda function.
This will then trigger the function to process the new incoming data.
At this point, the Lambda function can do a variety of things to the data.
It could process the data that comes in and then send
it over to a service like Amazon S3.
It could also take an action on the records coming in like
triggering an alert or sending out a notification through email
or maybe through SMS as a text message.
And there are lots of different options for what AWS Lambda
could do as it processes the data because,
essentially, you can write any code in here that you'd like,
take action on other AWS services or third‑party APIs.
So now let's look at the Kinesis Data Analytics option.
We already kind of peeked at this earlier.
You can stream data into Kinesis Data Analytics from a Kinesis data
stream. And then you can run things like SQL queries on top of that
streaming data to generate insights.
And, finally,
you can also review it live or send the output queries to other streams.
We'll look in much more detail at Kinesis Data Firehose later on.
But for now,
just keep in mind that you can have data from a
Kinesis data stream sent into Firehose.
Then Firehose can process and transform that data if
required by using AWS Lambda. And, finally,
Firehose can send that data along to another destination like Amazon S3,
ElasticSearch, and a variety of other configured destinations.
So now that we understand both the producer side and consumers of Kinesis Data Streams, let's take a look at a demo in the next video.