Hi, everyone.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey, and welcome to my
course, Collecting Data on AWS.
I'm a cloud architect at Stormlight Consulting, and I've worked
with dozens of AWS services over the years on projects ranging
from data pipelines to web applications.
AWS has one of the most robust public cloud platforms for data analytics,
and data engineers and other data professionals have some of the best
career prospects in the technology industry.
This course is a quick introduction to AWS data collection
services and other services that integrate with them. No prior
experience with AWS is required.
Some of the major topics that we will cover include collecting
real‑time streaming data with Kinesis Data Streams,
analyzing streaming data with Kinesis Analytics,
transforming and delivering data with Kinesis Firehose and AWS Lambda,
and use cases for the Amazon Snow Family of hardware appliances.
By the end of this course,
you'll know how to use different AWS data collection technologies
to get your data into AWS and how to analyze or apply
transformations to the data you're working with.
Before beginning this course,
you may want to have a general understanding of cloud
services and some programming experience,
but all code samples and demos will be provided,
and we'll walk through everything step by step.
From here,
you should feel comfortable diving into other AWS topics with
courses on Storing Data on AWS, An Introduction to AWS
Lambda, or AWS IoT: The Big Picture.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn about AWS data technologies with the Collecting Data on AWS course, here at Pluralsight.