It's important to know when we should use Snowball Edge versus Direct Connect,
not only for our purposes in our applications,
but also if we want to take any AWS certifications
because this will definitely come up.
One way to first establish which you might want to use is if your
situation has a consistent network connection.
If you're not able to establish a network connection at all,
then Snowball Edge might be a good fit for you because you can take it to a
location that can establish a network connection and have your local
devices interact with that Snowball Edge device.
And if you need to send any information back to the cloud,
you then ship that physical hardware back over to AWS.
With Direct Connect, on the other hand,
you're going to want to establish a direct network connection to AWS.
And it's not going to be an option if you can't do that at all or you have no
ability to connect into one of the Direct Connect partners.
Another example might be when we want to enhance the compute or storage
needs of our applications at the edge or in an environment that doesn't
have easy access to the internet and to the cloud.
Snowball Edge, as the name indicates,
is really designed for at‑the‑edge computing.
Direct Connect, on the other hand,
will enhance your on‑premises environment with dedicated bandwidth to
AWS and provide you a more reliable way of interacting with those AWS
services at a potentially reduced cost,
depending on the bandwidth that you're sending in over the
open internet versus over Direct Connect.
Finally, we also want to think about what our transfer needs are.
If we want to transfer large batches of data from distributed locations,
Snowball Edge or even Snowmobile might be a great option for us.
But if we want to transfer large amounts of data on an ongoing basis and we're
able to send that out over a network and that's feasible,
Direct Connect could be a better option.
So now let's look at a few examples of when we might want to use
different services between Direct Connect,
Snowball Edge, Snowball, and the Snowmobile service.
First,
let's imagine we have 225 PB of video and image data
that we need to transfer into AWS.
This might be a one‑time transfer.
Now you can pause the video here if you're wanting to
think about it a little more and rehash.
And the same goes for the next two examples that I'll show.
Do you think you have it?
Well, in this case,
we might want to use Snowmobile where we send an entire truck
full of storage out to our location on‑premises,
connect to that truck,
and upload all 225 PB of data into the truck before it gets
sent over to AWS and unloaded into the cloud.
For the next example,
let's imagine we're trying to connect to AWS services
inside of a virtual private cloud,
and we don't want to go through the public internet.
We could do this with Direct Connect,
where we could set up a colocation provider that has a partner
that works with AWS to get us a direct connection to AWS VPCs and
also to public API endpoints for AWS without having to go through
the entire public internet.
Finally,
let's imagine that we need to aggregate some factory
equipment data and then send it to AWS.
But there's a lot of data inside of all the equipment that we're working with.
We don't need all of it though.
So what sort of tool would we use for this?
In this case,
we might want to think about using Snowball Edge because we
could bring that device to our factory, have it interact with our equipment,
and then either process the data that comes in and aggregate
or summarize it or take action on it before we send any
information over to the AWS cloud.
Now we can also ship Snowball back and forth between the local edge computing locations and the AWS cloud if we need to.