If you recall the previous module,
Spring Boot configured both form and basic authentication.
When we accessed the demo site,
Spring Security redirected us to the default login page to authenticate.
If we inspect the source, it's a simple form,
submitting a POST request to the login endpoint.
In the body, it sends the username and password.
Now I have put a breakpoint in the username and password authentication filter,
and you can see it extracts the username and password from the request body,
creates an authentication token,
and then asks the authentication manager to authenticate the request.
That's form authentication in a nutshell, nice and simple.
It's a simple POST request to the login endpoint with
the username and password in the body.
Next is basic authentication.
This is simply the concatenation of the username and
password separated by a colon.
It can be transmitted in the header or the URL.
However, via the URL is now duplicated by RFC 3986.
But Spring still supports it. When transmitting in the
header, it's additionally Base64 encoded.
The intent of the encoding is to encode nonHTTP‑compatible
characters that may be in the username or password.
This can, however,
often be mistaken as being more secure than form
authentication as the credentials are not readable.
But don't be fooled by the Base64 encoding.
It does not offer any security benefits.
It's not encrypted and can easily be decoded.
There are sites on the web you can simply paste in the basic
token and convert it back to human‑readable text.
So essentially, it's transmitting the password plaintext,
just like form authentication only in the header
and not the body of the request.
Now to demonstrate basic, I'm going to switch to curl.
If I access the site, I get a 401 as expected.
Now if I include the basic header,
you can see I get access to the web application.
Next,
let's see how we can customize the authentication strategy to only support either form or basic, but not both.