If you look at a typical response that comes back from the web server,
you can see a number of headers with Spring Security included by default.
These instruct the browser on how to communicate
more securely with the application.
They are added by the header filter,
which can be conveniently altered using the headers builders
method on the HttpSecurity builder object.
If we use the disable method,
then this filter will no longer be added to the filter chain,
and hence none of the headers will be included.
Additionally, you can use the defaultDisabled,
which still adds the filter to the chain, but disables all the
default headers, and then you can add your own.
As you can see, it's very easy to disable these headers,
and I have seen many code samples online doing so. Now let's go through these filters and learn why they are important.