Throughout this course,
the demo application we will secure with Spring Security is a
Crypto Portfolio management application.
Users can register and create a portfolio of crypto currencies to keep track of
their value and brag about it to their friends and family,
of course.
Now let's say Victoria wants to access the application to view her portfolio.
The application will first need to identify who she is in
order to retrieve the direct portfolio.
It also needs to verify she is really who she claims to be.
This process is known as authentication,
the process or action of verifying the identity of a user or a process.
Spring Security has a class that encapsulates this,
and it's called the authentication class.
Now there are many ways to authenticate a user,
and, out of the box, Spring Security supports basic,
form, digest, certificates, and it's also very customizable,
so you can implement your own solutions.
If you look at the authentication object, you can see the principal field.
The principal in Spring Security is basically the logged‑in user and
hence often referred to as the authenticated principal.
Now when a user accesses a web server, generally,
it will create a session for them.
Now once Spring Security authenticates a user,
it will store the authentication object with the
authentication principal in the session. The web server will
then send a cookie to the user's browser,
which will be included in all subsequent requests to the server by the browser.
This way,
the user will not have to reauthenticate for the duration of the session.
Now the authenticated principal represents the user in the application,
but it could also represent a non‑human entity,
like maybe a service or a machine. And users can potentially have multiple
accounts with an application, hence multiple principals.
Maybe the user is an administrator in their day job and has an admin account,
but also has a personal account to track their portfolio.
Here, each principal has a different level of privilege and
potentially authentication checks as the admin principal might
require more scrutiny when authenticating.
Now once Spring Security identifies the principal a request
is for, it needs to determine what the principal can do and
what resources it can access.
Now this is known as authorization, the function of specifying
access rights and privileges to resources.
For example, Victoria is authorized to access her own portfolio,
but she's not authorized to access Joe's or any other users. Next, let's take a closer look at the Spring Security project.