Even for single‑page applications,
you would still need CSRF protection. If I tried to submit a
transaction, basically anything that is not a GET request,
like a PUT or a POST, you can see Spring Security returns a 403, as
we did not include the CSRF token in the request.
However, unlike with classic MVC applications,
because the views are not rendered server side, the CSRF token cannot be
included in the response HTML by Spring Security, hence it needs to be
included in a cookie sent to the user's browser.
To configure this, on the HttpSecurity object using the
CSRF builder, you can set the CsrfTokenRepository to be
the CookieCsrfTokenRepository.
You also need to set the HttpOnly to false.
Now the reason for this is our React application will need to
extract the CSRF token from this cookie.
In order to do so, you need permission to read the cookie.
But by default, browsers block any JavaScript accessing cookies in the browser.
This is to protect against cross‑site scripting attacks.
Now the browser will only allow JavaScript access to this cookie from
JavaScript that originates from the same domain.
If we submit our transaction again,
you can see the new cookie named XSRF‑TOKEN with the XSRF‑TOKEN inside it.
Now if you're using Angular or React,
the good news is they will automatically detect this cookie, and extract the token, and include it in any outgoing requests for you.