X‑Frame‑Options: DENY.
This instructs the browser not to embed your web application in frames.
This is to protect against clickjacking,
where your user is tricked into clicking something on your
website without being aware of that.
This is a popular attack in social media and even has its own name, likejacking,
where users are tricked into liking posts and pages
in their social media platform,
giving the malicious site access to their friend list.
Typically,
this is done by overlaying a malicious site over the top of the target site.
Hence, if a user is logged into the target site,
the malicious site can load the target site in the background.
Any actions on the malicious site are actually taking place on the target site.
The hacker can send another email apologizing to the user for technical
issues with the promotion and asking them to try a new link.
The page looks similar, but let's take a look at the source.
You can see it's embedding the portfolio site as a frame on top of
the form of the malicious page that submits itself.
Let's change the opacity of the frame to 30% and see what happens. You
can now see the portfolio site in the background.
The hack can simply align the buttons on the malicious
page over the top of the portfolio site.
Hence,
the user is actually selecting things on the portfolio
site without even knowing about it.
And if we look at the source off the embedded portfolio page,
the cross‑site request forgery token is on the form.
So if the user submits this, their litecoin position will now be removed.
The user has just been a victim of a clickjacking attack.
If we re‑enable the header filter and try this again,
you can see the browser prevents the malicious site
from embedding our portfolio page.
Now back to the drawing board for the hacker. You can get
access to his header via the header builder,
where it can also be disabled or configured to a less
restrictive option, such as same as origin, where only pages from the same domain can include the site in the frame.