Now until now, we have mainly focused on security filters.
But there is one other security component,
the HTTP firewall,
which is actually the first line of defense when a request hits the web server.
The FilterChainProxy will first run requests through the
HTTP firewall before any filter chains.
The HTTP firewall is an interface, and there are two flavors Spring provides,
strict and default.
Ironically, by default, Spring uses the strict version and not the default.
Go figure.
The HTTP firewall protects your application in a number of ways. It
enforces a whitelist of approved HTTP methods,
hence providing some protection against HTTP verb tampering and cross‑site
tracing attacks as HTTP methods such as connect and trace are blocked by
default. It also protects against many forms of URL tampering.
It blocks percentages or encoded percentages from requests, URL‑encoded periods,
semicolons, URL‑encoded forward slashes,
double forwards, and backslashes.
It also enforces that only principle ASCII
characters are allowed in request URLs.
This is to protect against injecting non‑ASCII characters
to look similar. Example, a unicode character that looks
like an a, but really is not.
Now the default version of the firewall is more
forgiving than the stricter version.
It tries to resolve some of the issues by sanitizing the URLs.
However, Spring recommends using the strict version,
which is why it's default. Again, these features are all customizable.
Just expose your own instance of the HTTP firewall, which will have many setter methods for you to override these settings.