So we created this admin layout.
So we have the admin navigation on the sidebar as well.
So it looks something like this in the light theme and dark theme.
By the way, if you want to change this navigation color in the light theme, let me show you that prior
monster, the one finished project so you can see on light more.
It looks a bit different it's a it has the dark never used to.
If you want something like that you can.
Easy to do.
It's good to talk now.
And on the menu you can pass past.
Team Doc.
So if you use that, we get something like that.
So that looks on duck as well as light.
All right, so let's keep it like that.
And the next thing you can see, this content, it's right up to the very end.
So let's add a bit of padding.
And there.
So that's here in the admin layout.
So we have the content, we're showing the children props, which is this one.
So here, let's add some padding here.
So start.
Adding, let's say ten picks.
So.
Elizabeth.
That's fair.
All right.
So the next thing we want to do is start walking in the signing and sign up basis, because as you can
see, we have this admin desk world which should be restricted for the logged in user and the users
should have the role of admin so that we will have many different users with different rules.
So one is the type of admin, another is a type of author, and the others will be subscribers by default.
All right, so let's focus on implementing the authentication.
So first, let's create the pages here.
So let's create the sign up in time basis.
We need a log in from here.
Once we have the log in form and then we can get to the user input or whatever name, email, password
or whatever they enter, we can grab that, send it to our backend, and that's how we can implement
logging and registration system.
All right.
And for that, we're going to use the end is an go from component.
So if you visit and then go to components here, you can search for form.
And you can see the exemplar here now.
And dissent from component is a little bit special because it has its own state.
So you don't have to have your separate state here in your react component.
All right.
So if you're using a form component from Envision, it will have its own built in state.
So you can easily grab the user input and you don't have to worry about storing in a in your own state.
It will you'll have access to that straightaway.
All right.
However, obviously later, when as we progress through the course, there will be many different pieces,
many different components where we will be.
Having our custom state.
All right.
So we'll use the use state hook and have our own state.
So that is something we would obviously cover.
But for this logging and registration we can use, the end is ends file, which has the built in state
and it has some error handling.
Either the search summation is very easy to use, right?
So you continue to have this kind of a warning central password you can.
So in hide the password, they pretty much ready to go.
They're really good.
So we can find the one that is very much suitable for us.
Obviously, we could use this one as well, but there is one that is really good.
So if you come down.
So you can see I want to use something like this.
This is something we can use in logging into register basis.
Right.
So let's have a look at the code here.
As you can see, they have the form component and they have input components.
Button checkbox is for this one.
And then basically there is a function that will execute when the form is submitted.
So you can see it's a fun component.
And on fairness, this function gets executed.
So on this function we would write some code that will send this user data to our backend.
All right.
So you can see this is a file from inside, from a you need the input filter you use from item and use
the input I all this code, you don't have to write the rules and keep it really simple.
You just have the form item and the input field.
However, with these rules, you can easily issue these error messages, which is pretty cool.
All right.
So most likely you want to use them as well.
So they got the rules, some rules here.
Another input for password.
So that's for email password.
And we have the button here.
Some text link for the puzzle page.
We're going to have that as well.
We will have that full password feature as well.
And finally, the button say it's pretty straightforward.
It looks a little bit bit too much code.
That's because of the rules.
If you take the rules out, it's really simple to have fun with the form item and then we have input
elements.
All right.
So nothing to get confused here.
So let's copy this code.
Let's copy this code.
And we can use this in
here in our basis.
Now, before we actually use this one, let's fix one more thing here.
Let's use some icons here so that they look nice.
So let's go to the top now.
Let's bring in the.
I can that we can use that one is called.
I had previously used that one.
That's.
Hmm.
I think I have to search here.
It's open.
Another friend is an agent.
We will be using quite a lot of them.
I got.
So for user.
Use it and.
That's for registries and I think we can use this for registration too, adding we can use that for
extrusion and we're going to use this for logging.
All right, so let's use these two components, user add outline and user outlined.
It's important.
Use outlined.
And another one is user outlined.
By the way, you must have noticed that it is my coded editor's theme.
I like to keep changing.
I don't like to always use the same car, but hopefully you don't mind the way I change it.
Hopefully I will use this for some time.
It looks pretty cool.
I should only use this.
I'll show you that simple.
Let me just use this item first.
So sign up.
So that one, let's replace that too with user and our client.
And on this one user outlined.
All right, so let's have a look.
Okay, so that's better.
That's for sign up.
That's for sign.
Beautiful.
And let me just show you the theme that I'm using if you're interested to use the same theme I want
to be.
And go to the color theme.
And you can see here, the one I'm currently using is called MCI.
Maureen And I say, if you want, if you're interested, just search, search for some name.
If you done, if it if it is not already installed, you click here and then right here.
So you can search MCI, the one I was using.
So in a naming and service.
And that will pop up.
Maureen and Art that runs.
It's not finding it will be as one or two using it.
Let me sit tight.
Okay.
So, you know, so you get to an end.
Sometimes it's a little bit slow, but you get all these different themes.
And then he can just use the up and down arrow keys to get a live preview.
These are pretty good.
I made actually some this I might use it with live it looks pretty nice.
All right.
Let me go back to the one I was using.
So we got so.
Bring my side were with command Swift E.
So let's work on the sign up component in the next election.