All right.
So now we are going to work on actual content management systems.
So when we think about content management system like WordPress, we think about this beautiful desk
world where admin can do a lot of things.
Admin can create categories, posts, manage media files, manage users, things like that, right?
So let's say in send and this users subscribe.
At the moment it's not even admin, but we'll work on that little bit later.
At the moment, let's go to the admin desk.
And as you can see here, we have a lot of these features that we're going to implement one by one.
And by the end of the course, everything will be working.
What do you see here?
All right.
So it's going to be awesome.
So at the moment, let's go ahead and create one piece.
Now, first, I wanted to start with the post.
I wanted to allow the admin to create a new post.
But before we do that, we have to implement the categories feature because when you create a post,
he want to assign some categories, right?
So that means we have to work on the categories so we will implement the categories.
Quote so called stands for create, read, update and delete.
So we would implement those features for core.
So four categories and then we're going to move on to other features.
Right.
And I was talking about it earlier that we're going to put it there out at the moment this user is not
even admin, right?
So anyone logs in, they have access to this desk.
Now that will change a bit later.
But at the moment, let's just focus on working on this space so that we know how to create categories,
how to work with forms.
That is something we already did in our sign in insider basis.
But Stuart, let's implement the categories feature through to the space and then we move to the back
end and we will see how we're going to protect that route so that only the user with the role of admin
will be able to create a category, create a re update, delete all those features in the back end.
Only our user with the role of admin will be able to do that.
So we will implement those role based restrictions a little bit later.
But first, we want to work on the space categories.
So let's go ahead now let's go to let's first tick if we click here.
So we have the the correct link.
So admins, less categories, we just have to create this space.
So let's go ahead.
Let's create that into basis.
Admin create a new folder.
It's called categories.
Categories.
And instead here we can do a file called index dances and it's going to use the admin layout and that
is something we have already used in the admin index, as you can see here.
So we can reuse this code and then go to categories index based here.
So basically we are using the admin layout, the admin layout.
When you said earlier that means this layout.
So this will have the menu on the sidebar and the content will be here.
All right.
So that's the add layout.
So we use that here in.
The Categories index, right?
Q Let me close out the taps,
and here since we are one step inside, then this one we have to go one step up
and let me just call it.
Categories.
Just leave it like that.
Listing the company name.
Let's call it categories.
It's a model not found.
So from here we going?
Okay.
Sorry.
So I supposed to.
I thought I was here, but I'm actually modifying this index fan, so let me copy all this code and
let me just undo a few times just so that we don't make any changes here.
All right, so this is how it was.
Live it good.
Two categories index and the space that hit I.
So we just added one more this line.
So we go one stick up and we change the name.
That's pretty much it.
And we change the heading.
All right, so let's give it a try.
It's good categories.
And you can see we have that base category, small country.
Right.
So we've got that.
That's great.
No.
Now we can continue working on the scale of the special.
We will basically allow to use it to create categories.
So the categories that are created and allow the admin to even update and delete all within the same
component because the just categories basically they just need one form field called the category name
or category title, whatever you like to call it.
It's going to be a nice little foam and we can pretty much do everything here.
Now, if you want to have a look at that, how we did in the finished product, you can try.
So let's send it.
All right.
So you go to the categories index and this is how we're going to implement it.
So at the end, this is how it will look.
You can create a category, you give a name, let's call it moral step, and you can create like that
as soon as you create it.
We saw the notification and that comes up here.
You can see immediately that comes up here and then if you want to delete it, it's clear another one.
If you want to delete, you can delete it.
That's gone to continue.
If you are updating and I'm dead, we allow the user to object in this model.
So it says the name, let's say all caps look monster and then immediately that will change here.
So nice, beautiful categories crud all within one component.
So this is what we trying to achieve, right?
So you can see here, the first thing we need to do is create a form, have a button so that we can
create a categories and then we will move on to affecting all the categories from the database, allowing
the user to edit and delete.