I we done with media and now let's move on to uses.
So we will allow the admin to create a new user.
So let's go ahead and clear the space.
So business admin, we create a new folder.
It's called to use this
list file called New.
You just knew.
All right, so first, let's import some folks who need so we need you state from New York.
We need the layout, admin layout, import
admin layout from one state to state, three state
components.
The layout had been layout.
Let's make sure components layout.
And now this makes one we need from end.
So we need x.
Let's move on that we need to draw, we need call, we need button, we need input.
And we also need to use the tick box component from end.
All right, next one excuse.
We need excuse to make a request later on.
Excuse.
And we also actually need one more component called Select so that we can select the user role in a
subscriber admin.
Awesome.
Next one toast.
When the user is created, we can send the notification to import toast form.
We are top toast.
And Roland, we need rather to read the reviews once the user is created.
Simple user review.
From the next round.
And to generate the food.
So we going to have that feature where you can click to randomly generate the password.
All right.
So for that, we're going to use a library that's called a generate password.
So you can have a look at that in the NPM as you.
Okay.
So that's how we use jet bass will generate and that will give us the password.
The randomly generated boss Rebecca absolute copy that.
And here we are at the front and it's in-store
and it's around the server again.
So that one is involved and generated from.
Generate possible, I guess.
I think that's all we need are the inputs we need.
Now let's create a component concept new user it to so cost.
So here first we want to create a state and then we just going to return the phone, right?
So yeah.
Let's work on the state first.
So we need a name.
That Konst name
said name to use the next one.
We want email.
So in a courier, in a new user, we need name.
Email, we need password.
Okay.
Now for Barcelona we're going to by default use this generate to order generate the bustle generated
don't generate.
That's the function that will give us the password.
And you can send the length.
It's how long you want the password to be.
I want just six.
Okay.
So that's the password.
By default, we will have some randomly generated password in the state.
Next run is rule.
I guess so.
User will have a role of either admin, subscriber or user.
Next one is a loading.
We can use the loading as well and we will also use the tick box.
So if the tick.
Then let me quickly show you the finished app.
So if the take, then we will send the email to this newly created user with all these login details
as well.
Owens ticked set to Miss Tuesday.
By default it will be false.
And you said that's all the state we need now.
We need a function to make a request to send all this information to the back end, to create a new
user.
For that we can call and suddenly.
So this one will be event.
Summit.
Event.
Prevent default.
So we will prevent the base reloading and then more code.
We will be writing there.
Let me just see.
Just try it.
Can't make it.
Really.
So if there's any air to my tongue's twisted toast error sign up fail try again let's have some This
is enteric and set loading to false When we are ready to make a ruckus and learning to poop and then
the more code will be added here.
Okay, so let's walk on the fun first.
Basically, we all have everything ready.
Let's walk on the farm so that we can show the farm to create and use it return.
So here.
So this is will be available for the admin.
So obviously we want to use this admin layout.
And inside and out.
We want to create a room inside.
We want to create a cool.
Call him.
So I want the column, the form, to be centered in the middle of the base.
So for that, we have the 24 column grid, so we can use 12 to the top and then offset we can use six.
Thank you.
And here, let me just even just write something just so that we can see how it looks so far.
Used to do is to find.
Used to.
Is it?
Is something wrong?
Okay.
That's for.
Beautiful.
Got the content centered on the base.
Okay, so let's continue creating the input fields.
So the first one.
Actually, it's give it a head.
It's full.
Let's add new uses.
Stuff.
Bit of a margin underneath, just the margin for the input filled.
So margin bottom is let's say minus.
Minus ten things.
Minus picks.
It so good.
The heading.
Let's use the end event input component.
All right.
So here we're going to use some stunts as stunts going to you to use margin.
So it will be clockwise.
So on top 20 pixel on right there pixel, bottom ten pixel.
And on the left there is.
Okay.
And then the end design input component.
You can pass the size for so size we want to use allows now as a placeholder.
Let's write the name, full name.
Venue name in the city to name.
And then on turns.
Obviously we want to update this state using certainly the Valley's name change event.
We give the event we give the event target value.
So that will give us the user input.
We put that in the state.
Awesome.
So let's have a look at this one.
Beautiful.
Assume that this beautiful.
Now we need to report this form.
Now a few decimal isolated copied input.
So we need one more.
That one will be a for email.
Full name just right.
Email
value email on ten sent email.
All right, let's email.
Next one.
In this first year.
Next one will be 4:04.
A full name actually passed from Cantor to generate the next round we can use for website.
So let's add one here.
Phones, websites.
It said it wants to use state.
We are the user to we are the use it to handle etc. so place for the website
so the value.
So it said on ten CET website.
Okay.
Name, email and website is done.
Next one, we want password.
So the next one will be password passwords.
We have to create a little differently because you can see here we have to have this order generate
your style password.
And then we have this dropdown and we have the checkbox.
So let's continue this in the next video.