All right.
So now we're going to.
I work on these categories feature.
So at the moment we can create a category but one security category.
We want to show the list of categories here and we want to allow the admin to update and delete as well.
Right.
I guess so.
What are you going to do is let's try creating.
I think we have to fix a few more things.
You.
Let's see.
If I create.
Okay.
So of course category get squared is successful.
However, the value still remains there.
So we have to reset the value.
And since we're using and design.
Let's go to Mrs..
I mean, can you give us index?
So using the end is in a form.
So.
And that gives us this.
The from hook that we can use and then we will be able to reset the values of the firm.
And that is something we used in a assigning I think.
Let me just say.
Yeah.
We use 500 reset fields to reset all the values of the film.
So to use that, we have to put the phone.
In the end is in form.
And this form you get from the youth from Hook.
It is right here.
I guess it is.
Are we going to use.
So let's go ahead and trace it is.
You can copy this code.
Go to categories index.
So here since we're using any designs from.
Folks.
Let's put put it here so we can distract a phone from the end event phone use phone hook and then we.
Use this form in the actual form.
It's right here and finished form equals to form.
And then we can reset the values.
In our case, the input field.
It has.
The name.
Name.
Right.
So we want to empty this field.
So we can do that here in unfinished console.log.
Let's go over that.
Now we show the successful success message.
Set, loading, default.
And then.
From that, Reese, it feels.
And we want to reset the field name.
I that's the name.
Actually, it would have to be inside a tree like that.
So that way, if you have more than one fields in your farm, then you can just do like this.
Oh, you could just use the let me just quickly go to Sandy or you could just use the recent fields.
Phone, don't reset fields and that will reset everything.
We could actually use this one.
But let's try this as well.
So this will give you the ability to individually target the elements.
So feel form has many feels and you want to keep some an empty sum.
Then you can just do it like this.
So let's give it a try.
Let's try what we try now.
Electronic.
Mm hmm.
So this one actually didn't want.
From the tourists, it feels.
From equities to fund or use from.
Maybe we just need to reload the phase.
That's right.
Part.
Okay.
So it research since you mean stuff.
So it works beautifully.
So we have been able to create categories.
I received this film.
Now let's go ahead and try to show the list of categories.
So for that, obviously we have to started out back in.
It's good to back end and create the endpoint that will give us all the categories.
So let's start from roots category.
Let's create a row with a method of get.
Categories then.
What do you call it?
Wait.
I like to use this card.
You know create rid of the delete so that naming convention to just call it read.
You.
So let's import this one from controllers category read.
Mm hmm.
Actually, the read I thing think it's a good idea, because read is something we could use for getting
the single category.
So I think we just call it by the same name categories.
I guess it is good that this controller function and work on this category is function.
So here.
Export contest categories include to.
Async request response try gets error
control.
I get requests usually goes pretty well without, you know, you don't really have to worry on the air.
So even if it doesn't find anything in the database, it will just return improve.
All right.
So we can use the category model, use the find function, which will give you the entire collection
and you can sort by the created that data.
If you don't have this code, you will still get all your categories.
But.
The most recently created ones.
They will come at the end and the old one comes on the top and that is probably not something you want.
So you might want to see the latest ones on top so you can use the search and survey.
They created a date.
I guess that will give you the list of categories and you can send those categories to your reactor
application in the front.
Right.
So it's that simple.
Let's.
And this endpoint is something you can see.
This is public.
There is no request, signing or anything.
And this is something you can access from the browser directly as well.
Sorry I missed the.
Ah, let's fix that.
Okay.
So this routing and try it directly from browser as well.
So let's go.
Give it a try.
Nicholas.
Our server is running an 8000.
SLAs API, SLAs categories.
If you try that, you see we get all the categories that we have created so far.
One, two, three, four, five, six categories we have.
So you can see you can get the array of categories.
I guess this beautiful decent data for the categories we can.
Get in our front end.
We can make a request to this end point using.
You defect and we get all this and we can render the categories just like we did in our finished application.
We take them freely.
So you.
According to the categories.
So this is how we want to display.
So all the categories will be here and then admin will be able to edit or delete.
I guess taken two immediately comes up here.
You can edit.
You can edit it or you can delete it.
So that's what we're trying to achieve.
So we have created the endpoint.
Now we have to make use of use effect hook to learn all those categories in our categories base for
the admin.
I mean, categories index.
So we can do that right here.