All right.
So now we're going to work on the comment system.
So it's post users should be able to post a comment.
So for example, we can click to view the the post.
All right, so here we got the post post content.
And here down here we want to have the comment section and then we show you the finished.
And how it's done.
So we go to.
Post.
It's visit post and then.
You can see down here, we have comment section two user can leave a comment.
And we saw the the existing comment.
All right.
So this is how we came to implement Common System.
So let's work on this one.
So first thing I want to do is work in the back end.
Create a comment more.
Create a right and controller function so that we can come back to our frontend, create a form so that
the user can post a comment, something about this like a simple form with a button.
So when user enter something here, we take that comment and send it to the back end so that we can
see in the database.
I guess that's the first step, creating a comment, saving in the database, and then later on we will
display the comments and then we will allow the admin to delete the comments because some point as an
admin you may need to delete all the user's comments.
Some sometimes they could be offensive.
Right.
So admin will be able to see all the comment and delete and at the same time the user, whoever posted
those comments, they should be able to view these comments in their dashboard and they should be able
to update and delete.
All right.
So let's start from the backend.
Let's create a more comment model, root and controller function so that we can send the comment from
the front end and start saving in the back end.
All right.
So let me just go to our backend.
So let's collapse this one.
It's good models with a new file and it's called comment dirties.
And here we create a schema.
Let's go to category and let's copy this so that we save some time.
Come here.
This that in and turn this to.
Let's call it a common schema.
So it's common to.
We'll have the content.
Okay.
So let's call it content.
So its content will be the type of string and it is required.
You can set the the maximum length.
All right.
So for example, let's say maximum is
20,000 characters.
I guess so we can send the max length as well.
And then.
We win.
We want to have the posted right feel so that we know who posted the comment and that is something we
have done in post as well before.
So something like this.
Let's copy that based here.
So I'm detecting.
We need to have the object ready.
That is something we can do.
Structure from memory schema.
So it's copying that.
There's to.
All right.
So we got the content, we got the poster by.
And we also want to know the post I.D. So each comment will not be the individual comment on its own.
They will always belong to a certain post.
Right.
So that means we need to know which comment belongs to which post.
So we need to have the post some kind of reference to the post so we can let's call it post 80.
Again, this one, we do the type of object I.D. and it will refer to the post model.
So it is time we save the comment.
We want to have some content.
We need to know who created the post.
So logged in users ID and the post date so which post this comment belongs to.
So that post idea to win it.
And that is all we want for the comment.
All that's so that's a whole comment scheme.
Now let's go to Roberts, create a comment.
Randazzo.
Well, actually, actually, we can put it all in the post because comments basically will be the part
of the Post.
All right.
So let's leave a comment in comment and then here, let's create a post wrote surrounded a dot post
to save the comment.
We can create a.
I wrote called Comments Less Bush Style so we can send the post at the request forums and to quit my
comment.
We need the logged in user, so we want that malware.
Can create, read and create compliance.
So quick comment again, creatively, let me just have a look at that mirror.
Actually, we don't need that email.
We can create read.
This familiar basic tactics if the users add mint are awesome, but in this case for the comment, anyone
any logged in user will be able to leave a comment.
It doesn't have to be admin also, so we don't need this maneuver.
All right.
So let's go with this quick comment control function.
And controllers forced.
It's right here.
Export accounts create comment equals to async.
So we can use try
quotes and.
So yeah, what we want is we want to create a comment.
So for that, let's make sure we have the comment module on top.
Comment from.
Comment
I just saw too great a comment.
What we can do is first, we need a couple of things.
We need the post and we need the comment comments content which should be coming in.
The request body to that is something we can access as requests more detailed content, right?
And then we create new comment using the new keyword and we give all these values that are necessary
to query comment.
For example, the content posted value should be the log to News Society and then the post, which will
be the added that is coming in the request params.
And then we save and we send it as it is in response.
Beautiful.
So that's how we can create a comment.
So we created the model row and the function that this event means we should be able to create a comment.
We just need to send it from the front.
Right.
So let's see.
We have some error.
Cannot override category model.
So looks like we have had some.
Cannot override.
Controllers post the swarm.
Controls post.
Let's go back to our model carnival.
So we still have to link category to this to comment.
Okay, so we got an error, so it should be good in our back.
And let's head over to our funding so that we can start creating the comment.