I actually have done quite a lot in this series for music and most of the features have already been
implemented.
The next few months we going to work on is and just sign out from this user.
Log in as admin.
So I want to now work on.
Oh, the contact phone.
Thanks to everyone who said need to have a contact form.
And since we're using SendGrid anyways, it's really easy to send emails.
So let's implement that so that you can always use this in your real life project as well.
But otherwise you can see a lot of this has been done.
All this is done.
Media comments.
User Now profile is also done properly.
You can see user can upload the images.
So that's done.
Now customize this one will work with LED.
We haven't stained the home base.
We can show the list of post latest post categories so full with images.
So it looks good.
Something like this you can see here.
The discounter condone.
So all these things we can do.
So the list of categories.
Latest blog posts.
Of customization.
So this is something you can do as an admin to customize.
Since the front images speak from the library, for example.
Let me try this one.
Use of text more.
Mushroom stir.
All right.
And you can see I changed and it's intuitive, beautiful.
So.
These are things we are going to implement.
We will also implement.
The resources here.
We will also show the list of categories and recent posts.
This can be reused because you can see the categories and recent posts are also displayed here in Homebase.
Or we can reuse that.
We include this nice little footer, so a really cool stuff's nice and easy for you to implement.
Now let's work on this contact form and then we will go on to do those things right.
So here, contact form, we will create a basic contact phone where you can enter the name, email message
and send it.
Now this information we will receive in the back in and then using SendGrid, we will be sending an
email to the admin user, the site owner, so he can receive the emails.
All right, so let's create this basic contact.
So let's first close all this.
Let's start from the navigation.
We want to add that link here in the now.
So here, now, top nav.
Let's go.
So sign and post after the post.
Let's you call it contact.
Let me find a nice item for contact.
Come on.
Okay.
So for argument's.
Review the items and find contacts I think we can use.
Mel outlined here that she just.
I mean, outline.
It's important.
Give it to reload.
For some reason, it's murder.
You.
Middle outline defined multiple times.
Okay.
So it was already there.
I think we were using that for something else.
Something that.
Mail is here contact.
So we got that.
We did have the basis for this quite quick based go to pages create a new a new fun contact or is.
And it's simple rule and call them form and
import.
Now, I want to import that contact form.
I want to put that in a component in import here.
The benefit of that is related to, for example, let's say now this contact form you want to see in
the footer here.
You can do that again, import the component, put it here, or maybe you want to put here on the single
piece anyway you can easily import and use.
So that's where I want to put it in separate component.
So import, we don't even have that for now.
Let's just continue at the moment.
Print contact will still.
Return.
Rule.
Come.
Now I want to center the film.
There's no point taking full with.
Four with four from our data center like this so I can use spend two strokes and then offset six.
So both said six.
So that'll be 12 in total that's two total 24.
That's a full width and bit of a Ben Stein
batting talk, let's say ten.
A 10%.
So here I'm going to show the content.
Okay.
So we got the contact phone.
Now, I want to use a component for that.
Two components create a new file.
Contact this.
And here, let's create a contextual context.
From ABC.
Here.
Let me just return.
And just just this for now.
That's important.
Let's make sure we're doing it right.
Import
content.
From.
So from here this will go one of getting set components.
I think we just need to go one step more.
And so the.
Complement.
One of the phone components contact phone.
So from here we go instead of getting set components contact.
So I call it contact.
Let me call this component contact form.
All right.
Beautiful.
So let's continue working on the contact form.
So what do we want to do here is you already saw we have to create something like this name, email
and this text area.
Now this looks very similar to our sign in.
A sign up is right, so maybe we can borrow the code from there just to make things little quicker.
So let me do that.
It's good to sign.
Sign in.
All right, sign in.
And you can see we're using the and designs form which has its own state.
It has its own rules for errors.
So it's it's quite straightforward.
So we don't even need to have our own state agency.
We just use the function.
We can access everything, the values from and the form component.
Let's try to reuse differences, copy everything, go to contact.
And in fact, literally just get this one pasted here, which will make it must first send this to contact
form.
Go and talk to and share contact phone.
So here, what we want is we don't.
Need the earth context.
So assume that.
Other things.
Let's leave it for now.
So context.
We don't need context.
We need a local state for.
Loading.
We can have that.
For the contact form we need.
Well, actually, we don't need to have our own stud because we using the end from component that gives
us the value straight away to our function.
So that looks pretty good.
So we don't need to use effect as.
On fitness, we can execute the function.
So let's.
All these columns remove for now.
Try.
Literally save it for now and just work on the phone first.
So let's call it contact and then the phone.
So from the contact phone will have.
Name and name.
First fill.
Okay.
So the initial Israelis who don't want that to move that.
So that's name from name, but it's a that fits in that name.
So the name is going to be name the user's name, whoever is sending us the contact form.
So name, E.M. name, email and Mrs..
Right.
So the time.
We don't need to review the rules here.
We can use the rules.
Rules make it required.
Quite true.
And then, if not, if he tries to submit without anything we can to the Mrs..
Please.
And to you and name.
All right.
So that's for the name Field.
It's rooms named rules.
Through the rules we can use has feedback by the little be to input prefix we can so the icon placeholder
it's the you name.
So we can work on this.
I can speak later.
So that's for the name.
Next one for email.
So name email for rules for this one required.
True Mrs..
Please input your.
Presenter you.
Email.
All right.
Has feedback.
Feedback.
By the way, all this information you can visit the and documentation.
Check out the fun form component.
Right.
So.
For Emile.
Internet password.
For email.
Also we use the prefix.
We can choose the icon bit later.
Give us a place for
your email type.
It's no dial.
Beautiful.
So good.
One photo for a name makes one for Emile.
And the next one we want for.
Text area for entering the message.
All right.
So let me just grab this name, phone and make some sense.
Forgot password lets you move it with an event.
So this one for the misses name misses.
This name is important because then we will be able to access this later when we are submitting year
80 on.
So Mrs..
Also we can use the rules require through writing Mrs. Year.
I require to please write to
Mrs. Input to text area.
Text area with capital.
Placeholder.
Write your message here.
You know.
Next one is the last raised button.
Do you call it Summit?
Okay.
We don't need this link.
We don't need line break.
All right, so we got the phone.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful to get the contact, phone, name, email and the text area.
Awesome.
That's extra line breaks.
We don't need that.
It's.
Awesome.