All right.
So the next thing we want to work on is should the number of post comments and uses that we have in
the in the application for the admin.
So this data will be showing in the admin desk for to let me show you.
So the one I want to implement is something like this so we can even display here in the homepage.
But first we will start from the admin, so let's log in as admin.
You can see when the admin leant in his Beth desk class admin.
We are showing this statistics.
You can see 17 post categories, comments, and the use of this number is the actual number of these
posts that we have in our database.
So this is the actual numbers to let us see how we can implement something like this.
All right.
So first of all, we need to create a road in our banking that will give us these data.
Number of post categories, comments and uses.
And then in the front end, we can use.
This and design component to display them nicely here.
Something like this.
All right.
So let's see how we can do this.
Let's go to our project.
So this one actually, let's start from the back end.
Let's bring it out so that we get all the data we need and then we can just walk in our admin desk,
work as the server, what's website?
Let's start, let's right here all the way side related to what we put here.
So this one, let's call it numbers dot get.
Number two, we want to get the numbers of all the all the the post and guys who have to use this so
require signing.
Requests.
Request.
I mean, actually, this one.
Let's put it in.
Let's remove here.
Let's put it in the post category.
The reason for that is to get all these the numbers for the post categories users.
We have to import all these models and they are already used in this post model.
So we create in a way do extra work trying to do it in the websites.
Let's do it here.
Well, it don't get so we call it numbers and we actually don't need to apply any middleware because
later we want to display this this value of the totals in the homepage as well.
So we don't want it to be.
That requires signing anything.
So just so I get the numbers next, let's write this one to the function.
So it's good to control this post here.
Export cost and get numbers.
It goes to async request response.
Try gets in error.
So here what we want is we want to give the total posts you just comments and categories who you actually
want for it.
That's should start from posts post equals 2.41..
Count documents.
So that's that'll give us the total cost.
Let me copy and paste three more times.
The next one will be for users.
So that would be you just use a model next one for comments.
That will be for from the comment model.
And finally, this one for categories.
Categories from category more.
All right.
Once you have that, we can.
He's for some reason it's highlighting.
Okay.
So once you on that, we can return the response station and we can return posts, posts, users, comments
and categories.
That is all we need to do.
I said that to give us all the tutorial.
We can even try it from the road.
If you curious, let's try it.
8000.
That's our server.
It's less EVA, it's less numbers.
And you can see we have 13 Boston users six and comet forgetting beautiful.
Now based on this data, we can display them nicely in our desk or something like this.