All right.
So you have built this absolutely amazing project, and now I'm pretty sure you are excited to deploy
this to the cloud, right?
So that you can use it for yourself, or maybe you are doing it for your client, or maybe you want
to put it on your regimen or whatever it is.
It is absolutely great project and you should to deploy it and show it to the whole world.
Right.
So the deployment section, in the next section, you'll see how you can deploy a react and next this
frontend and Node.js and MongoDB it back end both in the same droplet under the same domain, you will
be able to deploy it.
No, no, I have I'm pretty sure you already know.
I have many courses in Udemy, many full psychoses, and almost all of them have this deployment section,
just the very recent one, for example, this one, it's kind of like any of you, any type of project.
This is the e-learning marketplace and I build my site called continue dot com awesome based on the
same codebase.
All right.
So you can see here it is a marketplace anyone can become instructor I create courses students can enroll
on that similar to Udemy.
So this this product that I use the same course in that now this course has the deployment section so
all these videos I will make it available for you into this course as well.
The reason I'm not going to blow this is because it's exactly the same and it's exact the same.
The react in next year's front in Node.js and MongoDB be back in its exact descent.
So instead of doing the same thing over and over again, I'm going to share these videos, the deployment
six and these videos from this course to this course that you are doing.
So all these videos you will find in the next video, sort of next section, and it will guide you from
absolute express how to set up to these lows all the way to configuring your server, pushing your go
digital.
Everything, all the steps so that you will be able to deploy your project to the cloud.
All right.
So with that said, we have come to the very end of this course.
And once again, congratulations for making it so far.
And I hope you will be deploying your project and saying with everyone you can see with me as well,
you can always get in touch with me in Twitter.
You will find me at Twitter dot com.
Let's go around.
You can miss me if you have some issues related then of course related.
Then obviously you can ask the Q&amp;A section.
But anything other you can always misses me here and you can even tell you, you know, so this is feedback.
You can basically get in touch with me.
All right.
So I would be very happy to stay in touch with you guys.
So with that said, thank you and I hope you will.
Be able to deploy your project successfully in the next lesson.
If not, I will be always there to help you in Q and A six.