All right, sir.
Finally, we have arrived to a point where we can start building the application, learn the full stack.
So a skin development.
Right.
So, again, to set up our front end project.
So the first thing you want to do is decide where you want to put this project.
I have this folder in folder in my computer.
So here I'm going to create a new folder.
I'm going to right click and I'm going to call to see Ms..
Inside here.
We're going to have two separate projects.
One is the frontend.
One is the backend.
All right, so here, let me create a new folder and let me call it client.
And then later we will create another for Rufus server.
But at the moment, let's just leave it like this.
Client All right, now let me click this folder and drag to my editor via code.
I guess I'm going to put this second window so we can just go through the preview and the code editor
nice and easy like that.
Okay, so we have the project, but it's basically empty at the moment.
It's just a full so what do we do?
So the first thing we want to do is set up a project.
So we are setting up a JavaScript project here now.
Any JavaScript project you want to send on, you want to use NPM.
So NPM is NPM in sort form, stands for node packages manager NPM.
So basically any more than to applications you want to use.
You want to build it.
You want to use NPM because there are hundreds of thousands of packages available in NPM, which you
can easily within the one single line command line you can easily install in your project.
And then you can start using those libraries.
For example, React.
React is a library that you can download from NPM.
Next, this is another library you can download from NPM, even explicit test, which will be used to
build a server that is also available in NPM.
So as you can imagine, without NPM, it's, it's almost you can't build anything using more than Dallas.
I guess that's that's how important NPM is.
All right.
So that means we have to set up a project and brand new project using NPM and quite straightforward.
So what are we can do?
We can go to terminal.
By the way, if you're using voice code, the voice called has built in terminal.
So what you can do, you can just on my mat, I use control.
And the tilde character.
Tilde means the key.
Whatever you have underneath the escape key on the top left corner.
Okay.
Now you should be able to open from here.
You could go to the code terminal turn.
You can easily open from there as.
Now, during the discourse.
Through discourse, I will be using a separate terminal just so that you have a bit more space here
to see the code.
Right.
So if I open terminal here, have the sidebar here.
So we have very little space left for you to see, right?
So that's why I'm not going to use this one insert.
I'm going to use a separate one here.
To let me navigate through that directory.
We have a project which is, as you can see here, you didn't see.
So I need to give you that full right so I can go here sans directory.
That's what I did meant CD You did.
And I can restart the files using else.
You can see here we have two full step.
Okay.
So I want to get into it seems to change directory C, D, C, and now these LCD, these commands might
differ if you're in windows, but I'm sure you you know how to use run this command.
So these are.
Widely used come once, I'm pretty sure you know.
How do you work with your windows machine?
All right, so here, let me list out the files.
And inside seamless we have the client for so let's go into a client for city client.
I can now then if I have a look, there's nothing there.
Okay, let me clear the these previous comments.
Yes.
So we are inter client for here.
Now we want to set up our project with NPM.
Right.
So what you do is NPM in it means initialize this and you can pass dest y flag, which means to us.
So if you don't pass this way flag and hit enter, it will ask a couple of questions for you.
It you can type the project, name the entry, file, things like that.
However, to make things easier, you can just pass the white flag, which means to us npm in it.
That's what.
And that will initialize the project with NPM and that will automatically create this spec is consistent.
Have a look at here you can see previously it was empty.
Now it has the spec is a decent file and this content is what you see here in the terminal.
So you can see here that that command, NPM command created this basic information and put it in this
bag is a decent file.
So it has the project name, version and description.
You can write the main into file scripts.
We don't really have anything.
Who is going to change that very soon?
Okay, so all the information you can write to, pretty much the standard information is, you know,
any NPM packages you install, for example, React Nexus, any package you install, they will be listed
here, they will appear here.
All right.
So that means we want to set up our React project using Nexus.
Right.
So how do you do that?