All right, so we have this post ready.
We can create post.
All we have to do is execute this function, too, and the button is clicked.
We send this all this data to back in to save it in the database.
Right now, that's where we get the going to our banking to close all these.
That's for now.
Okay.
Now let's start from the roots.
By the way, if you're wondering where you can get all the images, obviously you can use any of the
images or you can go to pixabay dotcom.
You can use royalty free music in this download from then use in your project.
All right, so let's head over to our roots posts.
So we got images of Pluto to be used before.
Next one we need now is rather dark forces.
Oh, create.
Create port as the endpoint we used, you know.
Here in the admin post new.
And to probably create Bush.
I guess that's the end point to make sure you have the same name Kuwait Post and this one.
Also we'll have these mailers is admin and then create posts.
Okay.
So let's write this function in our controller controllers post.
So, yeah.
Export const create postings to async request for response.
Right.
Kept in control of the air.
So here for the moment, it's just gone to law to request.
Marty, just to make sure we're receiving the data that is sent from the client.
All right, so we have all this data.
Let's try to hit, publish, and nothing happens there.
But you can see here we have received the data beautifully.
You can see we have the total content and categories.
Okay.
So that's perfect.
So next thing, before we start saving in the database, obviously we have to create a model which we
don't have yet.
We don't have it's good to models.
Models.
We have categories of the user, but we don't have for post the screw the new one for start test.
And let me let me just copy design this to have this basic corner here.
So we improve MongoDB, we destructive schema, we export.
Now we have to create this schema.
Right.
So let me actually.
Just a second.
So we had to.
Let's leave it.
Let's just change the name from category schema to post schema and then this one we use here.
Let's send the model name and zoom from category to post.
So we have the post model which is based on this post schema right now.
What do we write in the schema?
Whatever fills to those fruits will be we will be able to save in the database.
So this for the category, of course what we can tends to understand we can leave it slugs, we can
leave it because we need to have a user friendly issue slot.
This drug will be generated based on the title, so leave this as well.
Just send this for me.
Change this to title the type of string required.
True.
Right.
So if you remember.
They're sending the total content and categories.
Okay.
So that was a good the title makes fun of content.
Content will also be the type of train.
Actually, it's going to be type, content, type.
We're just going to leave it empty.
Empty object.
So when you have empty objects, you can put any kind of data.
The reason I'm doing this is because there you can see this markdown editor.
It's sending all kinds of data.
So it's better to just leave it like.
Okay.
So that's content, not categories.
Two categories that will have the array of guests.
It will have the array.
Now, even though it is array, it will also have its own type.
Thank you, sir.
We will basically be saving the categories.
Reason for that is when you have the categories added later, you can query the categories model and
find all of the information related to the categories.
Right.
So you don't just have the name, but you have the created date of digit eight and anything else you
add later, all that will be accessible.
So we just refer to the categories highly.
So when we say the category for its model, we have to save the categories.
I not the name but the idea so that it's going to be.
Schema types don't object.
Right.
Oh.
If you want to make a certain destructor const
object id from.
Make sure there's no typo.
It's a capital idea.
I can show you a district that from mongoose dot schema capitals.
Okay.
So if a destructor like that, you don't have to take all this long and just do that.
So type object.
Adding it refers to the category model.
Okay.
So this is how we came to save the categories.
And that is all we need for now.
Later we might add some more.
So at the moment we have the title content categories.
Slug will be generated based on the title and the default timestamps.
Later we're going to add the feature limits.
We can also add.
In fact let's added now we're going to do it now featured in.
I relate to it because the images will be saved in the media model.
So we're going to create another model for media.
So let's wait for this one.
Instead, we can add two more properties published.
So by default we can add sorry.
Published can have the type of boolean.
Means it can have the value of either true or false.
So if published by default, we can.
We can send it to troop.
That means it's time.
A new post is created.
The it will have the status of published.
The default is true.
However, as an admin author, if you want to unpublished this one and continue, you know, adding
improving, I'm writing more content, you can do that.
So by default it's true, but you can always unpublished.
I guess the bedroom and another very important one we almost forgot that is posted by author or do we
like to call it a post and by also will be something like this.
The object.
It will be the time.
Object added and to refer to the user model.
I guess this is really important because it's time a new force is created.
We want to know who created the post.
All right.
So later, when we saw the post, we would saw the user information, whoever created the post.
So you can see this post was created by Mr. Edmund Sydney.
Okay, so for that reason we want to know who posted this.
Oh, the post.
So the user you decided will be required and this idea will basically be whoever is currently logged
in at the moment.
All right.
So we have in our route the request requesting that we give us the currently logged in use aid so that
users I.D. will be used in the post.
So that means we will know who created the post so that later, if somebody wants to update or delete
this post, we will make sure that the user, the posted by Addy and the logged in uses ID at that time.
Whenever they want to update or delete that, they're both met.
If the Mets, that means it is the same user who is trying to update or delete his own post and not
someone else's post.
All right.
So with all this, we pretty much done with our schema.
We have the post model.
Now we can go to our controller and start saving this post in the database.