So you can see here this is a learning base.
Now, obviously, you can go crazy with the styling.
I have focus on the features more than more than styling.
So I have just to use a photo with images and parallax theses full with images.
Here we have the counter.
They are representing the actual value, the what we have in the site.
We have three categories at the moment, 11 posts, a few comments for users.
We have the light and dark theme as well.
You can see here is the light theme.
You can choose to dark theme.
Now I'm already logged in as and I am going to log out and as soon as I log out landed on the space.
And now you can see here this application is already deployed to the live service.
Feel free to take it out.
I will provide this email and password.
You can log in as an admin.
Have a look at the application.
Have a look at the dashboard, which is the most exciting feature of this whole project.
All right.
And you can also check out as author and subscriber has.
Now let's go through the front.
Let's see how this looks, looks and feels in the fondant.
And then probably in the next lecture, we will discover the back in the ad, which is absolutely incredible.
So if you are familiar with WordPress, it's very, very similar to that seems.
All right.
So we have this we have the section we were showing the latest blog post.
We are showing all these categories that we have in our vacation.
So when you click on those categories, you land on a base symbol.
Let me click React.
You can see all these posts are in this category, React.
I saw quite a lot of post all these categories that we have.
You can browse them from here as well.
And we are showing the latest blog post, a few six of the most recent blog posts here.
So you can click here and visit the post as well.
Before we do that, let's come back to our friend Biz.
Yeah.
And by the way, this section you can control from the admin despot as well.
You can choose the image so you can see as the title subtitle.
You can do all that from the admin desk.
How good is that?
All right.
So this is the landing page.
Let's go to the post where you can choose the theme.
You can go to light mode.
Dark mode.
Now, this is text.
It is actually a dying dream come true.
You can see you'll be able to push the classroom.
You'll be able to write reduced list items, tables.
You can embed images.
There are so many features, so many text formatting options I will be showing you in the next video
when we discover the back end of this application.
So you can see here.
I have to keep it absolutely simple.
I'm just showing the post images and the title, but obviously there is so much information on each
and every post.
So if you want to get some more information here.
But I decided to keep it simple.
So when they click, we will obviously show more information about each post to you.
So you can see here we have we are showing currently six at the moment.
We can use it, can click and load more if there are more post.
They will be loaded here.
So we have so far 1142.
So let's take out one of them, I guess.
So you can tell when you click on the post.
We land on this single post with where we show the images.
We still using the sidebar.
Now this sidebar, we can be more creative.
You can shoot Google ads so you can show some kind of a promotional item to you on the sidebar.
All right.
You can just take the full width for the images.
It's totally up to you.
You can see here the is blog post, have all this information.
So when it was created, how many comments are there?
You can see the comment section is here.
How many comments?
You know, which categories to this post belong to all these categories.
They are here.
They're clickable and created.
By which user?
So all this meta information is here and you will be able to share on the social networks as well.
Faith, email, Facebook, Twitter, LinkedIn.
Now, at the moment it works because we have the we are using the actual domain name.
So you would be able to share to the social networks as well.
All right.
And then we have this absolutely beautiful, rich, fixed editor.
You can see here using the list items to render the content.
Now, some other post may have some other content.
Just try this one.
This one has certain some other information.
So we have the heads to some list items.
Now this restricts Ed, I will be showing you in the next video in the ad when desperate, it is absolutely
a dream come true.
Okay.
So user can leave a comment if they logged in.
If not, they have to log in to leave a comment.
So this is how we displaying the post.
Users will be able to send an email to the site owner as well.
So this is similar to the standard contact form that you find in many websites.
So it's one of those and it works.
If you can fill out a name, email, some misses hit submit and admin will receive the email.
All right.
So we have the lighting dark team as well.
Obviously, we have the signing and the sign up basis.
So let's explore the desperate by signing in as an admin.