So now we are going to create one more state, global state using context for post and categories so
we can put them both in the post context because category is basically used for post recruiting posts.
Right.
So you already understand the concept of context.
Let me quickly go to the one we already have.
That is called theme context.
So we had to have this theme context because this way we could access the current theme no matter where
we are.
We could be in any of those places, any of those components, wherever we are, we can easily access
the theme using the theme context.
So this one is not here.
So let me quickly go to.
So this is our theme, theme context.
And if you want to know the, the current theme and if you want to tense the theme, then you can just
access this context anywhere.
For example, we have access to that in our component called toggle theme that you can see to access
that theme.
For example, if I wanted to access here from this component, it was this easy.
So all I had to do was use the use context to give the context, and that would give me the the result.
And if I want, I could even update using set theme.
All right.
So that way, if you need some information, some data, not just in one component, but in the entire
application.
So you may need in some places, you may need in some component that time.
It is so easy to access them and object.
All right.
So we need to do that for push.
I guess so.
Again, so this is a finished project.
So post also when we want to edit, we take them to a separate base.
So on that basis we need to access the post now later.
Not only admin, the author also will be able to upgrade his post.
Right.
So we need the same functionality, pretty much the same code.
However, we need to have a different base for SLAs.
Author less post.
And that time also we need to show all the post we need to implement edit when they click edit we need
to take them to a different base.
So when we are doing like that, we need to access the current.
We need to access still array of post and categories in many different places, many different component,
because later we're going to move a lot of this code from the create base.
So you can see this place.
So all of this, we're going to move them to a component.
So that way we can just bring them into admin, post base and later author post base as well.
So we can pretty much put all this coordinate component in for our to reuse.
So for doing things like that, as you can imagine, we need to know the area of post array of categories
in many different phases in component.
So when there is a situation like that, when it needs certain data in more than one places, then it's
always a good idea to use the context so that you can easily access that and you can even update the
data in the context.
So for that reason, we're going to move our code from the local state to the new context we're going
to create.
That will be post context.
All right.
So once we have the post context, the first time we're going to use that is here in the admin post
index space.
So you can see here that is the limit.
So that base is right here.
Now you see you can see here we have the list of post.
So the first thing we're going to do is when we have the post context, we're going to put all of this
in the global post context.
So instead of putting them here, we put them in the global context.
That way we will be able to access all the post, not only here but any other places as well.
So we can easily access that from context.
So you will see how and when we have to access it in other places or components.
As we continue building the application, you will see the use case.
But for the moment, we're going to move them to the context.
All right.
So let's continue this.
In the next video, we can create a new context called post context, the same we did previously for
the theme.
All right.
And then we're going to just.
Continue building this.