All right.
So the next thing we want to do is work on the media component.
That's a media library.
So here, if you go to the library, you will be able to see all the media, all the images that users
have uploaded to our site.
And they maybe they're used in some post.
Maybe they are not used.
It doesn't matter.
So whatever has been uploaded or whatever has been uploaded to be used as a featured image.
That is the functionality we will be adding to our post.
So all the images will be here.
All right.
And then here they can go to add a new one, or they can just go to the library and see all the images.
And then also they can add more than one just one upload image.
Right.
So, so this will be inspired by WordPress if you have ever used WordPress.
WordPress has this beautiful media library section where you can upload the images and later use them.
When you are creating post, you can use them to put in your post as a featured image.
You can manage the photos in the media library by deleting them.
Yeah.
So they're going to have something like that too.
You can order more than one bulk upload as well.
So let me quickly show you how I did it in the finished form.
And so you can go add a new one to just upload one, or you can go to library and upload here from here
so you can of work from here, you can upload from here, you click, you can click and drag all to
work and you can see these are the images we currently have in the site.
Now you can delete as well.
Now delete is for admin.
They can delete any any images.
What for?
Also they will be able to delete only the once they're uploaded.
So they will also see only the ones they have uploaded.
So we have that security feature as well.
So the media, this is the one we're going to use and then this component will be used in other sections
as well.
For example, when you are trying to create a post, for example, let's go to.
If you try to create a post and you need a featured image, when you click that, you see we have these
two deps.
So the first one, basically this clip to upload is the same thing you saw here.
So that's the component I have used here.
And now in the glacier, that's another component.
That's a library component I show you.
So you can see how I'm using the reusing the same component in multiple phases, in multiple situations.
So when they want to upload a featured image, they can either upload one.
Now this is this component previously you can see that has one button and nothing else.
So that's that component.
We just saw that in this model.
So we use the end event model and we just so that we have the two devs on one tab, they will be able
to upload.
Basically we saw this component.
And on this tab we saw another component called library.
Now just notice, listen to this one and then the library component.
It's the exact same thing.
We just doing this in our model here.
So this will beautifully we will be able to use the media component in many basis, for example, here
when we are creating and then when we are updating the post.
So when we are doing that and also you can access that, you can see this post using the feature in
limits, you can access the same functionality here again.
So those components will be used in multiple, multiple places whenever we need to add this media feature,
which is pretty nice.
I guess this is one of the strengths of our first team is so we're going to replicate some similar feature
in our application.
All right.
So that was a bit of explanation.
Now let's move on.
Work on these media components.
So we.
Okay.
So we have created the base.
Actually, we don't.
So we need to create one for the new to operate a new media and another one do so on the media in the
library.
So maybe we don't have the base yet.
So let's go ahead with bases and work on those components.