All right.
So you can see we have only six comments here in the admin dashboard, even though we have more than
six.
That's because we are sending only six at a time.
We have implemented the pagination.
So if you want to load more, you have to click on the button, right?
And that button will increment the value from 1 to 2.
And then whenever this value changes, you want to run the code that will fit the comments.
So we can use use effect, we can create a function to fix the comments based on this value, right?
So whenever the value changes by button click, we will execute on the code.
So let's, let's create another user to use effect
and the dependency here is going to be B, so whenever the page changes, we want to run the code here.
However, at the very beginning, by default it is one.
So by default you don't want to run this function only when the value is bigger than one, then you
want to run.
Okay, so first we take if is a consequence equals one, which is two by default.
So when the piece gets gets loaded, you don't want to run this use effect.
So if base equals you can see this one return, don't do anything.
Otherwise we want to learn more.
If Page is not one that is between changes we want to.
Our normal post here, similar to how we did to the token.
If you have the token, then load more.
So that means we have to clear this function, load more that will load more comment to basically make
the same request but with a different value.
So what we can do.
You can read that he finds loads more.
Charlie, I just realized you may not even need another front, and maybe we can use the same face comments,
because you can see who it is taking the base value, wherever that is.
So we can use it.
We can use the Fed's comments.
The only thing we need to do here is instead of a sitcom and whatever you want to keep the previous
values if previous comments, if it was that.
Thank you.
So here, let's use away from it.
I guess a previous comment if it was there you can to leave it there and then.
You want to add the new array of comments which you will get here?
I said that would be just done.
All right.
So we should be able to do this when the base changes.
Anything other than one we face again, face additional data and then put in the commentary.
All right.
So let's use a button that will increment the base.
Thanks to this in comments more than one we run.
So let's try that.
Let's create that bond.
So we have this rule.
Let me create another rule at the very end.
Create a call to the school.
Spend 20 full time
on the center to text.
Text a line center.
Okay, so here we're going to set a button.
Toilet load?
No.
And when this button is on quick, we want to increment the base
set.
So whatever value it's under there, plus one.
Okay.
So this button we can give the size let's use last.
We want the last button type primary loading.
When it's loading, we want to disable this loading.
Okay.
Let's give it a try.
So this button is clipped.
We increment the best value when the base value increments.
We run this aggressive face comment function that will fix the comments, put in the commentary.
All right.
I guess something happened here, and it's good to kind.
I guess we have six posts and we have this launch button if I click here.
Nothing's happening.
All right, so let's have you send the best one.
So in tennis, we run.
This should be more than one.
Let me.
Let me just put you based in the survey and see the value we have.
So we have the base for five six suits.
X is enough for.
Okay.
So I just realized I forgot to exclude the function, which is a silly mistake.
You see here.
I forgot to have the parentheses.
So it was never executed.
All right, so maybe the students come here to reload.
So we have the normal one.
We have six post.
If I click here, this six is loaded, try again and over six and then there are normal post.
But we still showing this.
Now that's not how it should be working.
Now for this one, obviously we can use the one more request to back in to get the total comments that
we have, I guess if the total comments we have in the back end.
Is.
Less than what we have in the state.
Then we show the Lord Mountbatten.
Otherwise we don't saw.
All right.
So for that reason, we have already created that end point in the back end.
So let's go and execute that function.
So I can put that here to get the total counts of the government's crunched can total equals to.
All right.
So we can make a request to get the total comments slice.
I think we called comment comments, comment comment that will use the data which will have the numeric
value, how many comments we have in the backend.
And we can execute this function in our very first to use effect.
So we can execute that here.
Since we know that we have to two lines we can just wrapped in a corridor.
If we make a request.
All right.
So now we should have the total as well.
We should have the total.
Now, let's use that to conditionally.
So this button.
Not just the button we can at home.
We can put it, put the entire row, I guess here we take if the base
multiplied by six.
So each time we are sending six, we are receiving the six comments.
Right?
So this number should matter how many are returning from a back end.
So if you turn this 200, then you want to change this 200 new back in as it portrays value in our control
support base multiply by six if that is smaller than total.
Okay.
If that is true, then we saw this row which has this button.
Thank you.
So in that code, let's have a look.
Now you can see the bottom is not there.
Let me reload on my time.
Okay.
So Button is not here.
Let me just have a look at space and then.
Right.
So we have the page one total is zero.
So engineering the total.
Comet count for four.
Okay.
I think we made a typo here.
Count.
Oh, sorry.
That's got.
Okay.
No, no, no, no.
And then no more, because that's what we have.
Beautiful.
I guess that's one grade.
Let's.
Let's go back to comments.
So here, what I want to do is remove that.
Yeah.
Okay.
Now, the next thing we want to do is show the edit and delete.
I can see.
In fact, we just sort of delete icons, so admin will not be editing so we can destroy the data.
On Post by Ryan on post.