All right.
So we have come to the end of this course.
It was absolutely amazing.
It was a wonderful journey for me, and I hope you enjoyed it and learned a lot.
I'm sure you learned a lot if you have.
Finish this project up to this part.
And you you should be really proud of yourself.
Go ahead.
Build awesome projects for yourself, for clients.
Go get a job if that is your aim, you know, whatever it is, you know how to build full stack application
from back to back to front with all these incredible creativity and then, you know, problem solving,
trying so many different things.
Being kind of a one man band handling the back end.
Turn it all together.
You should be really proud of yourself for making it so far.
You can check out other courses here as well.
I usually publish courses that its course takes a couple of months to prepare.
So during that time I did those courses that already released, you know, like a pretty pre-release
phase in this course.
It has already been published here, so please feel free to check out the courses.
I'm pretty sure you excited to build such awesome projects with me.
They're very helpful articles you can find here and you can always find me in Twitter, sort of twitter.com.
Celeste COLLURA.
All right.
You can always find me here.
You can follow me.
We can have a chat, real time chat.
I share some useful content here, both free and paid.
So, you know, if you want to stay in touch with me, obviously, I would like you to connect in Twitter
as well.
All right.
So with all that said, thank you very much for being part of this.
It has been great.
So that that is it.
I will see you in future with some other great projects.
Thank you.