All right.
So the next thing we want to focus on is making it collapse when we are in a smoke screen.
So this is something you can control.
So we have this slider and we have the collapsed value in the stood by default.
It's false.
Now, let's try to using that in the sidebar collapse so we can use this collapse to be the true or
false.
Collapsed with teeth.
So you can see here at the moment it's collapsed this fall.
So we see it's open.
But if I turn this van into two.
Then you see it is collapsed.
I see you can see it's collapse.
I can't even open because it's the state said to to.
So what I want to do is.
When the browser with is smaller, then I want to automatically collapse.
Then I see that's what I want.
For that we can use a and vim baggers that will give us the value of the current browser with all right.
So that we can source with this package that's called or react windows sites.
React to Q&amp;A said.
I think that's the one we want.
Go back react who window size.
Still it's come to this come on.
And you can see the basic use case has.
So we can import and we can just.
Get the width should be fairly.
So all we need to do is this get the window, a window size.
You know, the one we're going to use is a window with the size, window with.
We just need to get the width.
All right, so let's insert this one.
Let me stop the server here on this.
And while it's happening let's go and input.
So we input that admin never seemed to limit input on the input.
The one function we want to use is to use a window width use window with and from.
And we asked who window size.
All right.
And to use that, we can invoke that hope.
So that's the they can see, folks.
So we can put that here.
It's a first only with we can put that in a very wanted to with equal C use window with.
So we just need to execute that function and that will give us the current window with you can have
a look at it you can sort of now.
Window with, only with.
All right, so let's have a look.
Giving you a quick refresher.
Okay.
So we don't have then that's because we haven't started the server.
Window with, I guess you can to 1280.
That's a window with my face.
Make it small.
You'll notice that we get this dynamic value of the current with.
That's pretty cool.
You can see here.
So you can use the value or whatever value like.
And then you decide if this screen size is smaller than that, then I want to auto collapse.
You can do that.
All right.
So let's use that value that we have to decide when we want to collapse.
All right, so I'm just gonna turn that out, actually.
Let's move that window with.
Now, let me use another user.
15.
So I will run this code whenever these values change.
So window with.
So to use effect, we have this function and then the dependency array.
I'm going to use only width.
So only width actually to as you make the browser small, it continues to grow.
So what I want to do is I want to check if window with is smaller than let's say 800.
So that's not too small enough to me.
So if window with is smaller than 800, then I want to collapse the saver.
Otherwise leave it open.
Obviously you want to do is if only with is smaller than 800.
Then I would like to set collapse the troops.
I want to collapse the object to the valley in the States.
It collapsed.
True.
Otherwise.
And if.
If window with is greater than 800, then don't do anything.
Leave it out.
Right.
So it collapsed.
False, just like it is in the default state.
So if it is bigger than 800, keep it open.
Set, collapse, false.
Otherwise make it too beautiful.
No discord runs whenever the window with becomes more than 800.
So that means we will have the dynamic collapsed valley so we can use that.
It's used it here, which we already did.
So let's give it a try.
Okay.
So let me make it small.
A small.
Small.
As soon as I hit 800, it is collapsing.
And automatically.
Beautiful.
No, you should make it open bigger.
Obviously it opens.
If it goes on by 800, it collapse.
Beautiful.
Now, one more thing.
We have to fish is it collapsed.
However, sometimes some user may still want to open.
Open up.
Even if it's a small swim.
Maybe they won't get a clear view.
But at the moment, it doesn't work.
So let's add one more functionality so that we can manually give the ability for the user to change
this, right?
So for that, we have a function that we can use with the site that is called On Collapse.
All this is in the document, isn't it?
And finally, the document isn't very quickly.
So how you can take out things like that.
So when you are here, for example, say the.
Now sometimes you want to know, for example, it's good to button hard.
It's a simple example.
So you have this one component.
Do you have a bunch of examples?
That's fine, but sometimes you need to go deeper.
What are the properties?
What are the options available?
Right?
So for Button, you can use the button button type primary.
Okay, so best is there.
So things like that, do you want to explore more?
So always go down all the way down and you can see here the API, the six and you can take out of whatever
options you could use.
The Freedom BLOCK Danger.
That's a title that would give it the red button so you can use loading if it is valid, true or false,
the you will get the little spinner spinning in the button.
We will explore this feature split lib so you can see all these things so you can use it.
Unplug function on the button so you can see these are the things you can use with button.
You can use the size of the venue, small, medium, large, you know, things like that.
So always check out these API six and if you want to get a deep understanding of the and components.
All right.
So we have the collapse function that we can use.
So let's use out of fancy here.
So on collapse when the collapse happens, if you want the user to be able to you know under the excel
down then since collapse and you can turn this to not collapse so whatever value is in the state to
collapse whether that's true or false, you just revert the value.
So if it is true and make it false, otherwise vice versa.
So you can use this one is let's try.
All right.
So we make it small.
It goes smart home.
You can still manually follow the user to change it thanks to this function.
Beautiful.