All right.
So let's continue working here.
We want to create something like this.
So we want to have the form and we use the sidebar for a preview images I see here, we got this column.
Let's create a column underneath column.
We actually need to column one will take the span of 18.
And then another one we need for the sidebar.
So said, but we can keep the remaining six.
So sidebar we're going to use to show the preview.
It means we can just continue working here.
So here I'm going to use input or actually before input I'm going to.
So the option for media, which is very easy, we just have to do that and then that will give us the
option.
Beautiful.
So we got that after the media input
stuff and we going by some style margin.
Trying to fix so big.
So this is a clockwise or top 20, right general bottom 20 pixel and then left the pixel.
Sides with and these are input into the size as well.
Let me pick last place holder.
Give it a time.
And then the value to the value.
We can use title.
So we have the state title and said title.
So that means we use the valid title and we have to use it in.
Put something on since event said title even target fit.
All right, so you two can enter the total.
Let me copy this and boost two more times.
The second one is for subtitle.
Give it a subtitle.
Value will be tightly set.
Sid.
So don't.
All right.
And then.
Um.
Actually, we just need food in this food and just need to fit the title and subtitle.
And it looks like I actually done nude style on this one.
I just moved it on the first one.
Okay, so total subtitle.
Let's create a button as well here.
So button and click.
We will execute that handle.
Save function some button.
We call it save.
And then here on plate handles save.
Type of the button, we can use the default
styling.
I think we need a bit of a margin on this one.
Margin.
Ten.
Pixel zero pixel two and pixel zero pixel.
In all its glory.
I want to disable the button.
Ensure the loading indicates a loading.
And then I want this to take the full width.
So we pass this block that will give us this big full width, but also.
So let's work on the previously.
So in that clip we now upload our set from the library.
We see the preview.
So for that we have this section here.
What do we need to do here?
I'm going to use the media context state and take if we have any selected images then.
Before that, let me use India.
Stein Morrison.
For the pixel jr pixel two pixel two and pixel.
And then here we take the media.
If we have selected media in the context, then.
We want to so that if not, then if you have already uploaded, then that would be here in our local
state full with image.
So if we have the full width image, we show that.
Full weight of women's.
If we have that, we show that.
Otherwise, we don't say anything.
So here may have to write something.
So if media is selected.
We saw the images.
And if we have the full with images, again, we saw the images.
So if the selective media is there, we use that as a source.
So with a to use 100% width of the sidebar and then source, that would be media selected.
You are.
Okay.
Now, if you have uploaded and if the image is in the local state we use, actually this one will be
true.
The next time user comes.
So you can see here, this is the finished project.
This is our application's title model.
And then this is the subtitle and this is the image used.
So you can see it is already there.
So that means once you create for the very first time that the hope is on this content, once you create.
Next time you come here, you will see that.
So it's basically like creating a post and then later updating the post, and it's going to be it's
going to be like that.
So the next time you come, we will pre populate the existing existing content.
So if you had the image previously uploaded that will be displayed here.
That would be in the state.
So that means we will use use effect to make a request to the back.
And then if the homepage exists, then we will display pre-populated this form.
So that would be like updating.
All right.
So image again with.
100%.
And then.
Source food with him is door to you.
Okay, let's have a look.
I wish you wouldn't see anything here.
Let's pick one Mimi's.
You can open a new one or select from.
Then it's immediately there.
Beautiful.
Now we give it a total subtitle and submit.
No, at the moment nothing happens because our handle save function is not doing anything.
All right.
So we can now work on this handle, submit function.
That function gets executed on button.
Click.
So.
Hand and.
We have to create the endpoint in the back end.
We don't have that yet, but we can still write the code here and then we can continue that in the following
lecture.
So what we want to do here is we're going to make a request to our banking accounts, data accounts
to await execution of post to make a post request to the end point is
I think we should call it home base because this is especially for the home base.
Considering his two week Axios post, we make a post request to home base and we have to give the data
that would be used to customize the home base and that would be titled Subtotal and then full within
limits.
Beautiful.
Now the full width image will actually be in the context of media.
If we have the media.
If we have the.
Selected.
Then we just grab the idea.
I guess it's just like before we just wanted to send the idea of the images that will refer to the media
more.
And that way we can of face the images information.
Okay.
So in the beginning, again, we said loading two false stories to true.
When we get the data, when you give the response, including to false and if there was any error,
including two false.
Now we have to create this endpoint so that we can save this information for the home base.
At the moment, if you try, this one doesn't exist.
So let's go ahead, work on this route.