All right.
So we worked on the edit post here in the front end.
We just need to create the endpoint so that we can save this object in the database.
So let's go to the back end and create this endpoint.
Thank you.
So let me go to so let's start from the right post.
Let's create a food truck without a dog food.
So the end point is it it?
At least this post started it be getting the post.
Only the question is admin.
Edit post.
So let's create this controller from and post I.D..
Edit post I saw him export concert edit posts.
It comes to a song request response.
Okay.
So yeah, what we want to do is first and get the data from the params this destructor so it's easy
to use post ID equals to request params so we can find the post based on the idea and then prompt it.
Now let's also destructor are the values so that it's easier to use later context we can destroy title
content, featured images and then categories.
From the request for.
All right.
So we're sending this sending all this value which should be received in the request form.
So we do structure all of them as well.
Then first we have to work on the categories because, you know, we are extending the category.
The categories, which basically is the array of names.
However, when you want to save in the database, we need to know these categories and not just the
name, but the idea, right?
So just like we did when we were creating the post.
New post create post.
So previously also we did the same thing.
We pushed the categories 80 so we followed we found the categories based on the name and then we.
Using this for a look.
We post these categories, add to this variable and we saved this array instead of the name.
So we can grab this.
Let's grab that.
And just put here.
So that will give us the categories.
Add in the salary.
So once you go the categories, we want to save the the possible object.
Now if you notice previously when we were creating that time also we used the set time because because
of this, the look that we have, it might take a few milliseconds.
So just to make sure we have all the categories before we save in the database, we use the set time
I and we delayed the saving by 1/2.
All right.
So we can do something like that again on the edit.
So, so yeah, we can use set timeout.
So a set timer takes a function.
We use our function you.
And we give the.
Time, the delay time and let's say 1000 milliseconds, which is 1/2, I guess, for here.
What we want to do is we want to find the post by 80.
So constant post it wants to wait post.
Post mortem fine by I.D. and update.
All right.
So here into this function.
Well, first, we have to give the post I.D. so that we can find the post based on I.D..
So post I.D. is post I.D., which we have already destructed from the params.
So that's positive.
So that's for argument's sake, an argument is the values that you want to update.
So in our case, that's the title content featured in this album.
So title content.
By the way, let's also make sure to slowly fade the title, because if you have changed the title,
if you have changed the title, then you may want to update the slogan as well.
All right.
So slogan will be title, whatever that is.
If that has been changed.
And then here's the slug effect function.
We give the title.
Thank you.
So we saved the update entitled Slug Content Categories, which will not be the requisite body categories.
Instead, that will be the array of category IDs sets categories that it is and then featured in is.
We'll be there thanks to family and update.
So we've got a table here somewhere.
When I'm when I save.
And if it doesn't format the predefined doesn't format, then I immediately know there's something wrong.
So I noticed that we using a way to unity, using async support.
And that's the reason.
I guess that's the reason.
Okay, so we've got the titles, log content categories, feature images, that's all we need.
So find the post variety, save this update.
The next argument we can use is new to so that we can give the this updated response here.
Now it's a new true.
And then finally we can send the response.
However, when we send the response, we want to populate everything we need.
So one is first we want the posted by, we want the categories and we want the featured images.
Right?
So.
Let's use that.
So you don't.
Populate post in both.
We just need the idea.
And then again populate categories, name and slug.
Actually, we don't have to populate it.
It's always there by default.
And then populate feature limits.
We want to select the URL.
All right.
So that's all now we can say in response to Jason Post so this has been updated post.
So that's our that's our post update.
Okay.
That's the post.
Let's give it a try.
So previously we had issue four for not fun, but hopefully this time it works.
Let me hit publish.
It's let me just write some updates.
I guess if we have no let's add one more then we've got a feature that means let's hit publish.
You can see it has been successfully uploaded.
That's beautiful.
You can see the updated title is.
Then if you go to update again, you can see everything is there.
How good is that?
Beautiful.
Just to make sure.
Let me just give it a reload.
And he continues, Everything's working beautifully.
So we have been able to update the post as well.
Now.
Let's try one more time.
I've done it.
Let's try another post.
Actually, let's go to all posts.
Let's try this one.
You said this also had the existing image.
It's the last post from Ryan and it's in the title.
Let's use this.
We have no more.
Featured image limiting the featured images to
something else.
Let's try this one.
Accident and this one.
This one, even this one.
Okay.
He told this.
Beautiful.
You can see the has been published.
It's called Visit the Post Office.
We have veteran updated post.
Beautiful.