So we have the title.
We can make this clearly relate to.
We can make this claim.
So you can visit the post if you want.
Okay, so that's cool.
So here the accents
delete.
So I was saying you can make this clickable or you can just have one click link, maybe call it a view.
All right, so let's do that.
So let's have two items.
So this one, let's call it delete.
And.
Only we want to execute Hindu function.
And you give the item, which is the comment so that we can send the comment.
I need to delete the comment.
All right.
To handle delete, we have that we are receiving the comment as an argument to work on this one.
So that is.
But is it?
Excellent.
So that's that's one item.
Another one we want to create to see the post.
So in the clip from the time, I think it's very attractive to do it here.
Makes more sense here.
But if we do it.
We have to use a function.
I think it's better to do it here and we just to use lead component from next.
I think it's duty to link.
Let's make sure we have link.
Yes, you do.
Perfect link.
Let's call it view we.
So if you the admin want to see the post to which this comment belongs to, we take them then to link.
We?
It's where victims post stress.
We need to give the slot.
So that would be.
I don't.
Post Ida dot slug.
Right.
And let's put it into get back.
Beautiful.
Now you can see here we can delete at the moment that function doesn't do anything.
Okay, that's fine.
Now, if you click view it to take us to that base.
So let me try a few.
You can see it Texas that beautiful add to that comments belongs to this post.
Both.
No.
What are you going to do?
Okay.
So all these comments.
Welcome to this post.
Let me try a different one.
So when you land in the space, maybe you want to take them to this comment section instead of just
directly landing on this space like this.
So that's a little trick you can do.
What you can do here is you can send.
Slug.
Right.
And then use less and then use some kind of identifier.
For example, let's use the net associated item.
Don't unscrew it.
Now you go to the space and then create a DB with the idea of create a dip and give the idea valid.
Just like you give the class name for sheer size.
Give the ID value with that comment i.
So let's go find this comment section and use the idea as a.
Adam idea has this added value that is in the post slug.
And let's go to the comment section.
Comment from is there.
I think we let's just quit div here.
Accident.
No.
We need to know that comment.
And that is here the list.
We have the list.
We can take the user to extract the comment ID.
Okay.
List item.
Item.
Agenda is item.
Give the idea value.
Hopefully this one takes the idea equals to.
So just like the class name we would use class name.
This one we use for I.D. and that would be item don't describe.
All right.
So this is going to be the comment I.D..
That's where we want to take the users when they click here.
If you do that, let's go back.
So you want to.
When you click, you want to take the user to exactly on this comment.
Right.
On Code Refactoring editor.
If I click here.
You can see I take them there.
So I'd go to defect.
And that was the post title.
And here that comment.
Ryan I've actually been issuing the commentary, just seeing the post title.
So maybe I think we've missed two.
So the comment description here, let's use that.
So we have the description item list, item meta.
We can use the title as well.
Description that ends here and then title item to content.
That content is the content.
Content will be there.
Okay.
That's the comment.
So, for example, let's say you click view.
When you click view, you want to land in this exact comment six.
Now we can leave comments.
Let me try.
Now we can leave.
Comments.
Beautiful.
I try.
And test this one in Troy.
You can see.
Yeah.
That's how it works.
Texas.
Exactly.
They're beautiful.
So that was an extra tip.
You could do something like that.
All right.
It looks beautiful.
Now, what we want is we want this to work.
Such.
All right.
So let's see how we can do that as well.
So we already have.
The input?
I guess so.
All we need to do is a filter.
So the data source comments instead of that.
Maybe we can write a variable.
You can't filter comments it goes to.
So you can see when it changes the value cured changes in the state.
So based on that, we can filter the comments, comments.
Dirt filter filter common.
So this filter function.
Takes function as an argument.
So we use our function here.
So that gives us the is comment from the commenter.
So is comment.
We want to check if that includes the keyword that is typed.
I guess a comment comment or to look is includes the keyword.
If that includes that item you want to filter out and this filtered comment you want to render here
I a by default you saw all the comments, but as soon as you start typing something based on that,
do you want to filter so copying that value and use that as.
Dr. Swisher All right.
No comment, lower case comment.
Also comment dark content.
Right.
So.
Point of content that contains that common dirt content.
All right.
So we got that.
No more.
Awesome.
Chris Cillizza, I want to feel that seamless.
He can do that filter's awesome, right?
You.