All right.
So we created our roots in the back end to save the base and also get the base.
Now, you can see we have functioned to save the base so we can give it a try.
Let's give it a try.
More, let's call it.
More steak is the best steak.
I guess we have that image as well.
Let's hit save.
I guess we did get in response.
Let's have a look.
We've said to create or save is not a function to get some issues in the control.
52 line 52 let's have a look created equal.
So if said dot okay it should be new create a new instance of website
created new instance of website based on the request wording and see.
So let's try again.
Um, and let me just take the data.
This.
You can see we have got the websites already.
Awesome.
We already have saved it in the database.
So you can see we have the base pairs name and subtitle images ID.
Awesome.
Let's.
So this one.
Okay.
So once it has been created, next time it will be updating, it will be creating again.
And you should not be creating into mean give it reload.
Now when next time Edwin comes here, I want to show the existing information about this homepage.
So the existing title subtitle, the preview image, everything that has been saved here.
I want to show you next next time they call me.
So that means we can use use effect.
Good customers.
Please bring the use effect to use effect.
And let me just right here use a fake when the component mounts immediately.
What we want to do here is phase the information.
So let me call it load home base.
No.
This will work.
This home base kit drought is also predicted.
I don't think we really need to protect this one because there's nothing there, right?
Nothing private.
It's it's the information you see in the home base.
So let's not worry about these roads, these Middle West.
We don't need that again.
But if you keep that there.
Actually, you shouldn't apply the militia because otherwise you cannot despaired in home base, because
home base should be available for everyone, doesn't have to be locked.
Right.
To make sure you don't have the Middle East then.
Because if you do, then you have to access the token.
And only when you have the token, you want to make a request.
Otherwise you get there.
All right, so let's clear this frozen ghost load home, basically still async.
Try.
Cats.
Yeah.
So here what we want to do is we want to make a metric $1 equals two.
Or wait excuse to get make a get to to base less.
We need to give the root for air and that is the name of our base that's home.
That's home base.
That's what we saved earlier.
Okay.
No.
Immediately.
You should consult your doctor.
You should be able to see the page, information, images.
Right click.
Have a look in the console.
You can see we get the information already.
You can see it.
It means you are told subtitled everything.
Absolutely beautiful.
So this information in sort of console.log.
I want to populate here.
All right.
So settle down to the title.
Said Subtitle data added Subtitle set.
Full of images that are just full with images.
That way you can see the information gets pre-populated.
The first time it was empty, but as soon as they create it is there.
Now anytime you have it sends you continues from here.
Now, before we turn here, let's try to see how this appears on the homepage.
So the main idea, whatever we do, we're doing all this because we want to dynamically change the home
based layout, virtual home base images, title and subtitle.
We want to change based on what we write here in this despot.
So let's see how we can do that here.
So basically what we need to do is we need to do the exact same things.
We need this function, we have to put it in the state.
And then based on that, we can change the values.
Right?
So includes all of the deps.
And let's go to.
The IS index.
So let me copy this.
Actually, this is something this is a good case where you could use it as a custom.
So we have already done great in many custom books.
So if you want, I encourage you to create a custom home.
Right?
So for the moment, let me just.
Copy this bit.
Go to places index.
And then here I'm going to just based here, I'm going to call it the for biz.
Customization, I mean, just based to you.
So that is the state.
Actually, I didn't even need learning.
And then use effect in this function.
Let me cut.
Let's put it just underneath this.
Beautiful.
So it's similar.
So I moved the.
I copied the state.
From MySpace to here, it's going to be Sam.
And then we need the user fix that will work exactly the same way.
So whenever you use a lantern, the hope is we make request, get the information about the home base
and then all that information we already have in the state.
Right.
So that means we can display this state information down here and make everything benami.
So what do we have in the home bed at the moment?
Is this full within this?
Actually, this is the one that is showing this information.
The title and subtitle.
So that means this component is responsible.
We can pass the title, subtitle and the image as props.
And it's a full with title equates to title subtitle and then featured image.
Sorry.
Fun with him is something that should be fun with.
All right, so we passed this data as well.
So that means we can now use that here to make it dynamic.
Now, before I do anything, let me just.
Use date is not defined.
This is our home base.
Let's make sure I have a use effect.
So you use data as well.
All right, so so far, there's no change.
Everything is as it is before.
But now we should be able to change the image to the text, to the subtitle.
Let's see how that works.
Let's go to full with images because we have already past the data as props.
Title, subtitle and full width.
So we go here and we do structure.
Title subtitle and then full of images.
No.
Following the we can give it a different value of this one.
So if we don't have the value, we can use this different value.
But otherwise the source will be now dynamic source will be full within.
And here the heading again we can always give the different value is give the different value for 30
missions of same subtitle learn stay.
Okay.
So here we can use the dynamic prop title and then here
subtitle.
Okay, now let's see what you can see here.
Actually, the image is number one.
That's because this one is full of images, dirty URL until we're doing it here, actually, we can
just pass it from here.
It's past the year.
Just a year.
And the object.
And looks like.
I think this is the one.
And so we have some styling issues.
We don't see anything, actually.
So we then have the total loss of totality.
Why is that?
So here.
Title subtitle.
Home base.
Let me just come to love the Donna.
Reference error excuse.
Sorry, I don't have access.
It's a really good idea to make it a custom move so that we can use here and in the customized as well.
Beautiful.
I can tell you this is the image we chose and this is the title and subtitle we write.
And you can see here it's here.
Awesome.
How good is that?
That is absolutely incredible.
Now, let me go, since, you know, you can tell us how the place looks from here.
Customize home based.
More months that the ultimate mom seems by right.
I didn't even go to emoji.
I feel like adding some images.
Let me just combine that.
I let's.
This is.
I really like it.
But let's send this to its peak.
Another aim is.
Let's pick this.
Save.
When we say I want to see some kind of a problem, it's good customers.
So when we save.
Central Falls.
Toast.
Success saved.
Okay.
All right, that's great.
Now let's go to homepage and let's see.
You can see it has been saved.
How good is that?
Now this this is just the beginning.
If you want, you can just customize so many other pieces.
Everything from the decimal.
And you can.
We have only control the sets and now you can control more sex and you can control here you get control
over sex and so other things as well.
You also.