All right.
So let's go to our client and try to load all the images from our server.
The components media media library see here.
Let's use Busey factor
and here let's.
Actually, we didn't need to create a state because we using the the context for media.
Right.
So we can use use effect to load all the images.
And then when we get the images, we can put them in the media context in which has the array of medias
and the selected one to.
Let me just quickly have a look at that.
So we have the array of images we can put to put the the response here.
Okay.
So let's try.
Use effect.
So let's create a function.
Let's call it fits.
Let's call it going for it.
Media equals to let's make it async function.
So you could put this function outside or you can just put intent on doesn't really matter, but you
need to make sure to execute this one.
All right, so here, let's try
to get all the media cats in here from long.
So we use ecstasy.
Let's import that first.
And let's use that too.
That gives us the data and we distribute from excuse to get request to make a request to media rights.
That's the end point.
That's media.
Okay.
So once we get all the media, we want to put in the state specific media.
So media has other properties as well, which we don't want to touch.
So let's use a function so we get previous, we let you verify so previous.
So whatever it is that you want, you don't want to do anything with that.
You just want to update the images here with this data, which is going to be the array of images,
right?
So that is all we need to do it.
And so now we should have the media has all the media files in the context.
So let's have a look at that so we can use a math function to map all the media's and so them right
underneath this drag and drop, I guess here, let me just to use a react fragment so we can put more
than one over here.
So let me just right here from the media, Don Lin.
Thank you.
So here we are accessing media context.
So from there, we can access the media.
Actually, actually media
images.
All right, let's hold.
So we don't see that.
So that obviously so you see we have 19 immediate beautiful.
So let's map through all those medias and display them nicely here, just like we have here in this
finished project like this.