All right, so let's so all the media files here, just like what we have here in our finished project,
something like that.
And we will show the icon for Delta as well.
All right.
So here we've got all these images.
So let's use map to map through all this media.
So let me put it into the div.
So here are media
images.
If we have them, then we use method.
So here on your map, through the images, we get the images, right?
So you get the images.
So here we want to show the images.
Now for that, I'm going to use the image component from InDesign.
So make sure you import that.
Then.
We can use that to him if we need to give it source.
So so it's going to be immense.
So each image will have the URL.
That's how it is saved in the database.
So now that's how we do it.
Okay.
So as you can see, now we have the images.
And you can see with image component from and event there by default they saw this preview and you click
you see the full, full view of the image as well.
Again, now that is something you maybe you you don't always want.
All right.
So when you accessing this library from this component, then maybe you want to preview.
But here when we are creating a post, when we are creating a post, maybe we just want to click on
the image and that will be selected here.
Okay.
So instead of serving the P, so to control that, we can use another property here called.
That one is called.
Preview and by default it is true.
But you can make it false instead of hardcoded false.
We can use a sorted variables, let's call it so preview and let's have the default value are false,
but in some situations you may want to turn it to true.
At least let's clear the state.
CET so media equals to use state.
What's.
Okay.
So by default, it's false.
Now, if I come here.
Use date is not defined.
Okay.
So we have to import.
Now, you can see we don't have the preview auction here.
Okay.
So by default, we don't enable that preview, but later, we may enable in some other components what
here we don't want.
Our next thing we want to do is we resize them because too big.
So preview schools to the size we can.
Let's try to start here.
Start.
So start adding don't keep betting on top betting until five betting right ten so that the images they
don't they're not attached to each other so betting right we give ten a game the height height that
we use 100 pixels that's not too big with we thought and it said 200 pixel.
Object fit.
Problem because when we said the width and height to be equal square some M is my.
So you know their streets.
So we use object fit cover that will nicely fit the image.
So yeah.
So that's how it looks.
Beautiful.
I guess the next thing we ought to do is let's center these images.
So let's put some styling here, this deep style.
We just want to center.
So let's use fixed aligned center.
And that centers this right in the middle.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So we get a bit of a gap here.
Here, too.
Everything looks good now.
And next thing we want to do is we want to show this cross icon to delete.
And when they click the image, we want to make this image selected and then selected image will be
displayed here as a preview.
A preview images for the feature.
Right.
So just.
I take you to this context now?
As you can see, they can have the selected images.
All right.
And then how we this model is to show in inside so selected when they click on the image, if they click
on any of these images, when they click, we want to update this property.
So that clicked images we want to put here.
All right.
So that way, if there is a senator in Missouri, immediately saw that as a preview for this post,
you know, to to be served as a featured image.
Okay.
So let's come back here.
So the misleading the use and plea function so unclear.
What you want to do is update the media.
Set media.
Leave the rest of the properties and selected.
You want to select?
Put this me.
Put this image as selected so that it emits.
I wanted to that.
So
I guess this way when it is clicked, the images will be.
In his will be selected and the selected images were showing as a preview immediately as a featured
image.
Let me quickly show you how you did that.
Let's go to Edwin.
Spaces admin new posts new.
So in.
We have the selected.
So we get the preview model.
Let me just frame.
I guess we are showing that's not the one.
So if we have the selected media, then we are showing that you.
Just above this publish button you can to just follow the person we're showing here.
So let's try.
And if we click and you can see immediately we have that this dark, beautiful.
And you said, that looks good.
Let's go back to media library.
And by the way, if you want to shoot this kind of for.
Like this.
The the Hannigan.
They clicked.
Then you can use some CSC on the image.
So the stud cursor pointer.
You can do the now see this hand.
So it gives the user the idea that it is something clickable.
Okay.
Now, the next thing you want to do is you want to shoot the cross open so that they can click to delete
the image as well.