All right.
So we are so close to finishing this project, but I just don't feel like going away because it's been
incredible and it is looking really, really good.
Now, I don't want to just finish it yet.
I want to do one more thing.
And that is you can see here in Customize and in the homepage we have the code repeated of the date
of this state and this use effect has been.
He reused Hugh in both files.
So I encourage you to create a custom hook.
Just give it a try.
But I will show you anyways.
So.
So that you don't get stuck.
Okay.
So what I'm going to do here is let me just copy everything and then we'll be just deleting everything
we've done it.
That is the easiest way to turn it into a custom one.
So copy everything.
The customize base for the component components.
Who?
What a hoax.
Okay.
It's not intel component.
It's outside component.
Okay, let's create a new hook.
We're going to call it.
Uh, use home currencies.
Yeah, that's one.
They tend to use.
He's home.
So here we won this state.
We actually don't need.
Context.
But we can live there and we can work with the state.
We didn't even know which title subtitle full width and this huge effect.
And we don't need this function.
We don't need the region cured of this whole block.
We don't need it.
So here all we want to do is return.
We want to return the title.
So total and said full with so full with limits.
So all we need to do is that.
So we just written this and then let's treasury of use this in our customers base.
So let me just comment them out for now.
So we don't need full width here.
Title subtitle.
We don't need that.
We don't need this huge effect here.
That lured home Bay's dysfunction dysfunctional it.
So this bit whatever I have commented out as you can see here they have been moved to use home.
Right so hopefully we can we use that to you know at the moment if you live like this and go to admin
you get an error go to customize of course does work.
Now let's try to use that import to use no use home from.
Hooks use home, and then we can destructor all those values we need.
Konst.
Writing the subtitle.
Full length images means we can districts often use home.
We execute that.
And I think that is all we need to do.
Wow.
That looks good.
Let me see.
Oh, sit down.
That's right.
Since we have moved the state altogether and we still have here.
Sit, idle.
Sit.
Subtitling This input sled means we need to return them as well.
Let's go.
Let's also return these functions to our bit.
Still set.
Don't set.
Subtitle and set full with images.
All right, so with that, we can just destructor them here and customize.
Okay.
Now that should work.
All right.
Okay.
Let me just make some changes.
Ryan Dingell.
It's big, different image.
Save.
All right.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful.
That works.
Okay.
So we moved out cause he could use it as a custom hook to simplify.
And now we can do the same thing in our home base.
Right.
So let me just open a home base here in this sidebar.
Here I have customers.
Here I have home.
I'm going to bring the hook just like it did, then bring the hook and then
destruct all that.
That means I don't need this anymore.
It just come in that out for now.
I don't need this.
Yeah.
Since you're using custom hold in that symbol as that nice and easy.
You just import.
We use that.
No.
Okay.
So the path is not right.
So from here, we just need to go one step up and then inside hooks.
All right, beautiful.
Awesome.
Let's do it one more time and we're done.
Let me change the media to this one.
That looks good.
Save.
Go have a look.
Beautiful.