So far so good.
It's so that.
Comment from this from this comment from requests, couple of arguments, comments at comment and submit
and loading.
This fosters values.
Pendal submits.
So now this function will execute.
And what it will do is it will send the venting that will have it in the state, the object value.
You can see here the content.
This valley will send to the back end to update the comment and his comment.
We are getting that information we can get from here, that comment idea we can get from this selective
comment.
All right, beautiful.
So let's make sure we have right that function we don't have at the moment to handle.
From me comment.
This one, I think we don't actually need the.
Arguments.
On Summit.
We'll come back to this right here.
Cartoon.
All right, so let's come down here.
So we need to send in some information.
We need to send the comment this.
In the state that will be content, I guess, to make sure it is content.
The comment venue, comment form, that's the content and set comment will be set content.
And do we have loading?
Let's make sure we have a floating.
We have.
We have looked like beautiful.
And Summit.
Now, we should work on this one.
Let's see how this looks so far.
Edit You can see the content.
Content is already there.
User can make some changes.
Hit submit and this should trigger this function.
Beautiful.
You can click anywhere to close that model.
You can click here.
This is looking good.
Try to edit.
Beautiful.
All right, so let's work on this handle summit.
On the handle summit.
We have already created the endpoint in the back end.
So handsome if one of the do I mean to make you put request concert
in concert or wait excuse don't put make a put request to the endpoint and that is less comment less
comment ID right now that comment I do we can access from the state selected comment on the click on
the comment to edit.
We need to put that in the state.
And that's the reason we did that because we needed to access the I think it's comments less comment
ID.
And we are sending the content as a request, Marty.
Now we can send like that that's at.
Then.
We get the response right.
So.
We can consult?
No.
Let's have a look at this.
David.
We have some type of here.
Koonce diagnosed or it just put.
I noticed we have some typos there because you can see the code is not formatting and there was no space
here.
So I immediately noticed something's not right.
That's because I have 48.
And as soon as I have as soon as I have that you can see performance.
That's beautiful.
Thanks to PGA rights.
That's a really useful plugin.
I hope you using that and submit.
So let's try.
Edit let me open inspect.
Council.
This comment is updated.
Let's post we got the response content.
Quentin hasn't endorsed Quentin, didn't update.
Okay.
So let's figure out why it's happening and we can continue working on this function.
So I tried it.
It didn't work.
Let's have a look at this.
Is the function responsible from that when we click and edit.
So let's end it.
All of these have been said, selected.
We have this visible.
We have just said content.
And here in the model we have the comment form handle submit that gets executed when the button is clicked.
I said, but honestly handsome it gets executed.
So that means I'll handle some it function is right here.
Make a request.
Put request comments.
Let's comment and.
We sent the Content Council for comment, updated, retain and then just try it one more time.
And it didn't open network dev.
Updated post.
We got the response.
We're getting the response, but it's it's not updated.
Okay.
So let's.
Put 200.
Let's have a look into our control.
Comptroller's post.
Let's have a look at the round first.
I would put comments less comment, add requests and can object delete object comment.
I will look at the object comment.
So we send the comment.
We get the icon comment.
Comment in the request for this limit.
Check that.
So the content content is being sent.
Okay.
So let's go to the content.
I think that's what we need to make tends to content.
And I think that that will update it.
Post.
You can see now it works beautifully.
So that was the issue you reload that has been sent to updated.
All right.
So it works.
But you can see here, when we see when we post, we're not doing anything at the moment, we just console.log.
So let's fix couple of things.
We want to close the model, hide the remove the selected item and update the list immediately.
Right.
So he came back to use a summit and a summit to hear after the meeting a lot.
So once we get the data, what I want to do here is the most important one is I want to update this.
So I have a list of comments.
I'll have to find that comment from the list of I have to find that common that has been just updated
and then replace the content with the.
The object writes for him.
First, let me put all the comments in a variable.
Let a good student comment.
So all the comments in the state are put in this variable and I'm going to use find index function on
this very nice sort of cost index.
So I have to find the index because you can see the.
So with the the comment that has been just updated.
I need to find the index and then only then I can just make make the changes here.
The cost index equals to R3.
Right which is the all the comments.
Don't find index we use the find index function and this function takes another function as an argument.
So this friend index function will run its time for is item in the array.
So we receive them as comment.
See.
Okay, so it's comments add if that met.
With this selected common daily.
So this is the selected one that that is the one being updated.
Right.
So if.
That comment met with the selective comments and then that is the comment we have to find and update
the content.
That's the one need to be updated.
All right.
So we can find that using a way.
So array means all the comments we have to have in the state and then index our items we can always
access my indexed, the first one always be zero and then one, two, three, four, five.
So that's how we can access the array based on the index so we can find that item from the very best
in the index, whatever we got.
And then that item's content I want to tends to
data content.
All right.
So that way we will be able to find that particular item of its content valued with this value that
we got from the back end.
And then.
CIT comments.
Are we?
And again, because we have made modified this way.
And finally we can send it back to the state said comment.
Now you said that's done that will immediately of did.
Yeah you can try edit updating works instantly.
I guess it's.
It's not working.
Okay.
It's for.
Host so model has to close when the model plus we see it happens.
I guess so let's do let's change the model sources for some.
Success.
Mrs..
Comment updated.
Now that is not so important.
So again, to the end said visible falls so we don't show the model anymore, said loading.
False.
In fact, we haven't used the learning hit till it's due, said loading first.
We said it's true.
Once we get the response, we set it to false.
Any error.
We said false.
I guess that visible said loading and then said selected comment.
Also the mate empty.
And that is it.
That should work.
Let's come here.
Try it.
Now, let's try this one.
I can now update my comment.
He.
Is it beautiful?
All right.
It walks awesome.
You know.
No, I'm sure it works for a subscriber.
So he has a meta comment.
He can filter out.
He can click.
I have made an update to this comment.
Beautiful.