All right.
So we created this control function that will give us all the data post user comments categories which
we get like this.
So based on this data, we can display them.
We will display that in the homepage as we will later.
But for the moment, let's just show it in the admin desk full.
So here is the landing page for the admin.
This is where I want to display that information.
Let's go to admin client pages.
Admin index.
See here, we don't have anything at the moment.
To hear.
What I want to do is.
I want to.
First make a request to back in to get all those numbers right so I can use you to fit booklets.
Import duty free.
Um.
Use a state.
We are.
Then for destroying the dollar.
We need to import rows and columns from and row column.
Actually, we're not using layouts.
Let's assume that.
So I mean, what is there?
We don't really need the context here since we have to use that link, we should be using link.
From the next link, that is to make it clickable.
So you take it to the finish project.
You can see here we have the postcard user and the admin clicks here we take them to our post feeds
and if the two categories we take them to category space.
I guess it's just a list to make things easier.
All right.
So we have the link as well now letting products use
it.
Now it's doing that and here and it's huge, huge effect.
And when we get the data we can put in the states first, actually we can start from the state step
concert numbers that numbers to use state.
Physical object and use effect.
We use this to make a request so we can write a function here called Get Numbers.
And we can borrow that from down here and get number sequence to it's a function.
Let's make this function async
tri
count error.
No, the error here we make a request using excuse punched dollar equals to wait excuse to get we make
a gift request to slice.
The numbers that we give us all the data and we put that in the state said numbers to symbolize that.
Okay.
Now we can return.
So let's use the go inside rule.
Let's use column.
Column.
Let's use.
So we have the four items.
We getting these four items so we can display them like this.
One, two, three, four.
So 12 column grid.
We can divide two.
Six.
It's six.
It's.
Actually not six is 12.
It's because we want 12 to 24.
And then I know the road to a trifle.
First, let's give a bit of a heading here.
So in this column, the first column, actually first row, we can use full width for the heading.
Give full width.
24 and then here.
We can use another component from and that is called divider.
I guess that looks something like some kind of horizontal line.
Divide it and we're going to use that here.
The further inside here.
It's right.
Let's give it a heading.
It's statistics that.
It's reload is.
You got some issued FS.
Why is that?
I mean.
Okay so sometimes fiscal tries to you know auto import so that's that's an right we shouldn't be importing
anything from so let's remove that.
Get no mercy, you.
Awesome.
All right.
So we have the heading now underneath that.
Let's create another rule.
And inside this room is critical.
Again, he's quoting, We used to spend spend two.
And we can get rid of hostile Israel style
Amazon.
Top 100 Text Alliance Center.
Font size with his trim.
Again in this column.
We want to show the numbers.
So, for example, to show the post numbers.
Numbers that post.
It will be posts with this.
Okay.
So we get the number 30 now.
What I want is I want some kind of the circle, something like that for that student.
Not just that we want this to calm down, start the countdown.
Because if you notice.
You land on that for the very first time, you see the numbers start going down from one to whatever
that is.
All right.
So for that, you can see.
For that, we can use this library, it's called.
Now this one is called Let's Google It.
Rendered progress.
I think this once and then we act render
progress.
Actually, it's not a bean bag, as I used a indigenous component.
And then they have this component called progress.
So I use them.
I guess this is the one I use.
So let's see how we can use this to make it something like this.
You can make it nice.
Give it a beautiful color, Israel.