All right.
So we have the author layout.
We have the the navigation for author.
Currently, we are in our author desk for peace.
So let's go ahead, start working on these basis.
So let's start from the post.
So let's clear this base so that author can create a new post.
So let's go pages for admin.
We had the folder structure like this and then.
These are the files to create a new post object post.
We want to have a similar structure for also.
So let's create a new folder posts.
Inside a new.
And here let's have a look at the admin posts new.
And you can see we applied the layout and then we have the new push component.
So this component should work for us as well.
So all you need to do is change the layout from admin to author.
All right.
So let me just copy this one and then go to also post new and paste you to this to
actually we can leave it we can leave the name and just change the name from admin layout.
So let me just copy.
And now command f.
Find Ed Miliband and replace with also left.
It can then be safe.
And that is all we need.
That's so ridiculous.
Come here.
You can see how the police knew.
We have the exact same base to create a new post right now.
There is one problem in the some sense in the client state it's all good.
So used to be able to quit a new post.
This post is by also.
So you can choose the image.
So we don't see the images here.
That's because he said, don't worry about this one.
This one.
I was running a different story with Sokoto.
So what's happening here is a let me quickly take you to the back end.
So basically, the media is not accessible for author, right?
So previously everything we did was accessible only for the admin because we have the is admin middleware
applied in all our out.
Right.
So to create a post also you must be able to load the media library.
You must be admin.
Let's have a look
server raut's post.
Media.
You can see the is admin middle middle where is upload.
So that's where this user currently logged in.
This is the author has the role of author so he have no access to media.
So we have to fix this the middleware because now not only admin will be able to create, update and
do post, but also will also be able to create the post update and delete his post.
Not everyone else's but his post and should have access to the media is really should be able to upload
media and delete the media if he uploaded that particular media.
Right.
So we need a flexible middleware here.
The is admin.
We cannot continue using here.
We'll be using his admin for some other things, but for the post categories in media, both admin and
author should have access, I guess.
So we're going to modify the middleware.
We're going to change this to something else so that it works.
So we'll work on that in the next video.
But here, as you can see, we didn't have access to media.
And if we try to create a post, let me just open the console.
If I try to publish.
You see, I get the air for three unauthorized.
This is a forbidden error.
If you go to the network and click here, you see.
Unauthorized because the user is not authorized to create a port, the user has to be awesome.
Quick boost and right.
So let's go ahead, create some flexible measures that will allow both admin and the user to create,
read, update and delete.
And then we can come back and just continue working on this basis.