A profile.
I built this user object.
It works, but there are few things we have to fix.
For example, I'm logged in as admin.
If I go to all users, I can update any user, including myself, which I did.
Let me try updating another user.
Ryan I didn't make it all.
Ryan The
two networks sling the images.
So we got to submit.
That works.
So that is good.
Admin can do it.
However, if you log in has all three years you wouldn't be able to update your profile.
That's because the endpoint you know back end.
All still am just keeping this file close.
Others.
So, you know, wrote us.
You're going to object.
We only have this endpoint and that request to use it to be added.
So if you try to update the profile and if you're not admin, you won't be able to access.
Now that's the easy fix.
What we need to do is maybe duplicate this controller, make a small change, because you can see here
we are basically this route takes for the admin user, nothing else.
But when they when you use it, they're trying to audit their own profile.
We want to make sure that user is currently locked in.
All right.
So we find the user from the database and if they are to use this address the logged in inside only
then we will allow him to update to make sure he's updating his own profile, not everyone else's.
So for that small extra tick, we can just duplicate this controller, maybe call it something different.
Call profile user.
Object user.
And use that in a different route.
So we create a new route, new controller.
How cold it will be pretty much similar in the back end and in the front end.
The only thing we have to do is somehow change this route.
So when admin is using this, we use that.
If.
Other users are using it, then we just use object user so we can use the we can pass this route, this
endpoint as a prop whenever we using this component.
That way it will be dynamic at least to let me just try and log in as Ryan the awesome.
Okay.
So I have access to profile.
I can go.
Actually, let's quickly fix that so we can give that a try.
Let's go.
Two components layout also.
And then in here in the.
Sorry, not lay out nerve on the neck.
And here, let's do what we did with Ed.
So we need to access the health context.
Give me a split screen.
So this at a minimum, this is.
What a nerve.
Let's import the context.
Let's import the use context.
Come down here.
Let's add this to.
It's you put it in context.
And then we can use that as.
All the way to the end profile.
We send used that.
So he's back in the.
All right.
So this should be after stress.
Back to stress.
Also stress logged near the side.
I said let's use sin.
Here is rule.
Something to note with
Kobe besting author Lance Armstrong's usual 90.
Okay.
Let's try.
Good to death for.
Profile.
No guests author profile.
No, we don't have that base for author.
So we can go ahead, create that base.
And see how the profile update will work.
So we will have some issues.
And to fix that, we can use the new endpoint in the back controller and route to fix that.
Now when I'm doing here, whatever I'm doing here, I need to do that for the subscriber as well.
Let's go to the subscriber.
Is.
Actually, it's here.
Subscriber layout.
Again, here.
I want to import the.
I actually better have the contacts on this one.
That's.
All right.
So profile this user will be able to use profiles profile.
They are forever now.
It's good to subscribe and have.
So we didn't have the context use context.
What context?
Put in turn the component and use that auth user ID here.
Subscriber is less of a user d.
I'm going to copy this one carefully.
Active name.
Let's put it into tactics.
Senator, what he has wants active name less.
So Cisco's less of a user.
I.
Let's try.
This is awesome.
He can go.
Well, actually, we just fixed the drought.
We haven't created the fund, so let's go ahead and fight as well.
Maybe close this.
Let's go to pieces.
After.
Here, we create a new file.
Do.
Right.
That's what we did for admin.
I'm going to just copy that.
Put in ten.
All tied to this.
Layout admin layer instead of admin left command f replace that with art layout.
All right.
So we still use the same component.
Now, you can see we have the author has access to.
This phase where he can update his profile.
Now, at the moment, if he's submitted, doesn't work because.
In the back end.
This is only for the opinion we have that mill works if I try.
You can see he's a fairly stern school for three unauthorized forbidden artists.
We'll fix that.
But let's quickly have a look at the subscriber advertising.
Subscriber out doubtless create a similar file subscriber could a new file.
I did space to change this.
To come on if.
Subscribe now save.
And that is all we need.
Beautiful.
All right.
So obviously subscriber and also they can't update at the moment different if they try they get the
error for three 4 billion error.
So let's fix this by going to the backend and creating a new route in a controller funds.