All right, let's continue working on this piece.
So we need to have a form like that.
All right.
So.
Let's change this to.
And a of you just don't take add new category and new category.
All right.
So we want to have fun now.
Form is something we have already used in our in inside of components.
If you want, you can have a quick look at it.
All right.
So anytime in future, you are building a project and you want to you know, you can always come back
to the finished project.
For example, this project you can have a look, you know, you can take out the code or you can always
reuse the code.
That's the beauty of when you build many projects, you can combine, you know, you can look at the
code in its copy the components copy the.
Functionalities and then you can quickly build up to for example, we have already the form here so
if you want and you know obviously have a look at it and maybe even copy some of these input fields
to make things easier.
All right.
So.
You can see from.
And the foam item.
So we use that one for the evil two.
Let's copy that.
Just to make things easier, go back to categories and firstly it's import import from strong and and
then we want to so that so from
an inside from that base, that form item name let's give it a name name.
So that's going to be the category name.
It's sort of like the roots, this one input prefix.
Input free fee.
So for this one we can use the icon called edit outlines.
So import from at and right.
So.
It did.
Outline so we can use this component.
So this item.
So we prefix with that icon and then we see this input field, full name, category name so we can call
it plus placeholder.
Give it a name that's relevant.
Input is not defined.
So let's make sure we import input as well from and.
Beautiful.
We've got that little foam.
Awesome.
Now, we don't want to make it full width.
Just like you can see here.
We used to have space for the foam and the rest for showing all the creative categories as to let's.
Use the rule.
So with and designer we can use columns and roots a row and column.
So we use the 24 column grid in a row.
So what we can do here is within the admin layout.
Let me quickly have a look at the finished project.
So all this sits in the first half and then the rest on the second half.
So that means everything that we have so far.
Let's cut and let's use through the squid route in.
So we want to split the colons into half hour.
So.
Call.
This column seemed to have the content so spend we give 12 so in end then we use the 24 column grid.
So we used 12 for the first column and then another 12 for this second half.
And so once you have this really spaced that the code that we got before heading in the form.
And then after this call and just leave a comment as well.
You can.
I meant using command and slash.
If you press, you get this one and here you can write comment in this deus ex.
Let's call it first column.
So this first call, this column, another 1/2 column.
Second column.
Also, we use column in here for the moment.
Let me just write something.
So categories list.
Let me just read that for the moment.
Okay.
So we're going to the categories list later.
Here.
Here we can now continue.
So we have the input file.
We can have a button as well.
So let's import the bottom.
Front end and then within the sprung after the item in button.
And Barton also, if you want to, you can make the windows split open.
The sun component here where we have already used all these buttons and forms and we can quickly have
a look at it and see how it's done.
Right.
So you can see that's how it was done.
So.
But.
We give the name here, let's call it submit.
And here button type.
There are a couple of types you can use.
One is primary.
Few other ones.
If you are.
Take out of the documentation.
Let's go and take it home.
But.
Thanks to this good component.
And Bodden is right here.
So that's important.
Let's come all the way down.
And then here you can see the type.
We can use all these types, we can use primary host dest linked text all this.
So we might try a few of this later, but basically primary is the one we will be using mostly.
So let's use that primary just like we did here.
Glass, then we're not actually using the glass.
And so we didn't invent.
And that looks like it's pretty measured.
That's a really.
His statement.
I guess we need this one.
His statement, I submit.
Yeah, right.
Beautiful.
No.
Just like the the form we had before in the sign.
And you can see here.
Unfinished.
You can execute a function.
All right, so let's do that.
From from this unfinished order.
We call it let's call it handle.
Let's call it unfinished.
Let's keep it simple.
But obviously you can call it anything.
So on finis almost unfinished equal to async.
We'll make a request to back end for the moment.
That means if we just use console.log the values right.
Console
values.
Valleys or the valleys would be will receiving as an argument to these funds.
So that's how the fund component in end is.
And also so you can use the on fitness and that will give us all the values from the input.
For example, we have at the moment, just this one.
Its name.
Name is email.
So here we have called.
Give it a name.
Just name.
All right.
So don't get confused with that.
No, you can give it another name, but let's just leave it like this.
Okay.
So we'll be receiving the venue name so we can take that out here on our front.
So let's see if we see this console.log.
So let's open.
Console.
And let's say Rihanna hit Summit.
And you can see we obviously get the name which has the value yet.
Beautiful.
Now, that's a great start.
Now all we need to do is send this name to our backing so that we can save the a category in the database.
All right.
So once you save, we will be getting the response and those responses we can put here to show the list
of categories.
So we'll come back to it later.
But at the moment, as you can see, let me close this one.
It's looking good.
We have the face and with the form, we are able to create a categories.
Now, obviously, we have to go to the back end and create a root and controller functions.
We need to create the category schema.
We're going to do all of that pretty much from scratch in the back end because even though we were generating
the authentication server that only has the authentication foetus, anything else we want to add?
Obviously we have to write ourself.
Now this way you will fully understand how the the backend development works, how you build the API
is, how you handle the roots and how you send out the restaurants using the control functions.
We already saw how they work, but now we're going to actually write our SO I guess it's going to be
awesome.
So let's go ahead and work on the back end for the categories to create routes, controller functions
and even schema for categories so that we can start saving in the database.