Also a good disputable form on submit.
You can see this form.
You need to make sure you have this content on submit.
We have the so unfinished.
We have the unfinished function.
We can call it anything else we like, but let's continue using this one on the finish.
So I'm finishing in here.
X is all the values that the user entered in this form using values.
So let's have a look at this from the let's see what we get.
So Ryan emailed Ryan and then we start getting some misses.
If I hit submit, I get name, email and miss it.
Beautiful.
So this information we want to send to the back end so that we can.
So we can send an email.
Right, beautiful.
So what we can do here is we can make a request.
We don't have the routing controller yet, but let's write it here and then we can go and work on this,
you know, make.
So I'm finished.
What I want to do is first the shoes dry.
We don't have dry.
Let's make a request using excuse that to use a good stoop and wait excuse to get so it gets pushed.
We're sending this information, this context.
We have to create this endpoint called contact.
And here we are giving the values or whatever we got from the phone that values re sending that could
be name email and Mrs..
All right and then we have to apply some validation as and say if not added error if we receive any
kind of error message we can show that those dots and Donna.
And otherwise, if there was not issues, then we can show the success message to success successfully.
Let's call it.
Your message has been sent.
Okay.
And then we want to reset the field says so in the form has been submitted all this information and
you don't want to just leave them there.
So you want to clear them.
So for that, we can use a form for that to work.
Of course, you need to have this this important file.
And this from where does it come from?
This comes from the hook called use.
So let's use that as well.
Context distracts from the array from equals to from component don't use from.
So this is how you access the fun in and event form you give that value.
Yeah.
From.
So from.
Okay.
That way you'll be able to access the form.
And then we have that.
And then we can use the reset fields to reset all the the fields of this.
That's fulfilling.
Now let's work on the loading as well.
So when the function executes first thing we do set lowering to true.
If we get an error such loading to false.
If we get the success message that also set loading to false because there's no point showing loading
anymore.
If we get the errors that set learned to false which were other to happen.
Beautiful.
So I think that's all we need to hear now.
At the moment if you try our mistake don't want.
We get the error messages.
Let's change that error, Mrs..
Give me a felt tray.
All right.
So.
Now let's have a look at the network dev contact headers.
We're making requests.
Less contact.
We sending the payload of email messages and name stats for food later, trying to access this in the
backend so that we can send an email.