Let's go ahead and work on this.
Base.
Looks like we don't have the base yet, so let's go ahead and create that one.
So here in the business, create a new file for good.
Fast forward to this.
And here we just need a basic, basic layout which we may be able to use from one of the signing and
signup.
So if you have a look, look around probably from the sign in place.
So basically, we can continue using the image field and just the overall layout.
All right.
So let's go ahead and copy the code from sign.
Just to make things a bit easier.
It's good.
Sign in.
And let's copy everything.
And then we're just going to remove whatever.
We don't need to copy everything we're signing.
Good for the password and pasted.
So the first thing you want to do is change the name
for a password.
It's fun and turns here as well.
Oh, that's a foreign password.
So what we need here is this function.
This function.
We can give it a different name as it's led me to remove this for now.
All right, so we'll come back to it.
So we have the form unfinished.
Just.
Let me remove this for now.
You should come back to this one.
So we call it.
Forget fast food.
Food.
We keep that title.
Let's not use initial values and assume that the bigger the form, we have the input field for email
so we can leave that and other fields we're going to use bit later.
The password field will be using bit later because user will be entering the new password.
But at the moment we will not use.
So let me just comment this out.
Password.
Leave it right.
Full of password.
Leave.
We can't remove that.
And then.
Oh register now said this link also we can remove and change the name from log in to.
Let's quickly have a look at a finished product.
We have it.
We just called to submit.
All right, so let's send this to submit.
I would say it's a very basic component.
As you can see, we have some inputs.
We can clear them and be clear.
Let's leave it for now.
So basically we have a phone with the input field for email and that's pretty much it.
And then there's a button here.
Simple answer.
Let's quickly have a look how it looks and it's cool.
Click on the phone password.
So on that page we have this component where a user can enter the image.
It's pretty good.
Let me make sure there's not so it's being kept.
So we have two breaks.
Let's move that.
Okay.
So that's good.
No.
So we need to create a function that functions to basically send this email to the back end to the forgot
password endpoint.
All right, so let's write that function.
So let's call that forgot password request.
Let's call that context forward.
Passwords request inputs to async
R2.
Here we use try.
Kit and Eric aren't so long to enter and we want to show some toast notification.
If there is something on toast, don't enter.
We call it.
For the past four fellows.
Try again.
That's all we can do.
So that generate misses.
And then we can ask for the loading, right?
So we have the loading state here.
So we said if there is an error, we said the loading.
Let's put it right after this one.
Start loading.
We said do false.
All right.
So at the beginning we it to true.
We said it's true.
And then we use excuse to make a request to a backing.
So that will give us the response we can destructor done.
Oh, wait.
Excuse.
Don't post.
We make a post request.
We're posting the email.
Right.
So the end ones are going to be forward password and we are sending the email.
And so that's the first argument.
The endpoint second argument is the actual data, which is email.
By the way, if the name key and value say we don't have to write like this, we can just leave it like
that.
All right.
It's beautiful.
You can see that we are sending the email in object format that.
Actually, we're not using the state here for storing the email.
We are using the antigens from component and this gives us the valleys directly because we already saw
how this works.
Right.
So we just have to use the unfinished function.
Actually, it's actually use that I'm finished.
We're going to execute that function.
And that function is from a password request.
All right.
So this function will exist to have access to the values of this form.
So we get access to the values and then that values will have the email.
Anything else?
Whatever is in the phone.
All right.
So we can just send that vanish like that.
Then.
We can take again.
We can take for the air.
If Donald Ducks enter, we can show that error message.
Those dart error we can.
So data dart error so whatever error message we get and we also said the cert loading defaults.
If there's an error we show the error and then setting send the loading to false otherwise.
Otherwise we can show the success misses because at this point, if we don't have the error, then obviously
it is a successful request.
So to start success, we can source some kind of success.
Message password reset link sent to your email.
All right.
So you can use it, can take the email.
And let's also let's write a password reset reset.
Add to this for take your email.
Password reset code is sent back so we can source some kind of message like that and then sync learning
to false.
So in the beginning it's true.
But whether we get error or success of anything we set to false because we saw learning for very brief
seconds.
All right.
So that's all you need to do here.
And actually, once we get the once we get the response, we want to show one more field where user
can enter the code which they will receive in the email.
So we need to show access to fields.
If this request is successful, we need to show so the two fields, one to enter the code and the other
one is to enter the new password, right?
So that means we need to have some kind of a state here which we can control.
So when it is successful we said maybe we can call it some kind of visible and sent visible so we can
use a state like venture.
Let's write that here.
Const visible sets visible equals to use state to give the value of false by default.
But if we get the successful response, we want to set it to true.
So based on this visible value, if it is true, then we want to show two more fields from fields.
One is for password ID and one is for entering the reset code to let me just write something for a map
and then later we going to implement so visible.
And if visible is true, let me just right here.
So
from fields to end to cold and new possible.
So let me describe this for now.
We'll come back to it and then this walk on the farm fields.
For now, let's leave it like this.
Okay.
So if the request is successful, we will show this one.
All right and we should toss notifications and I think use you can always cancel until Donna.
Let's also consider all of the values.
Let's make sure that we use return.
Just for trying.
Just to make sure we are receiving the email as values.
Say, let's give it a try.