All right.
So here we are showing the loading insert that let's create a component that will not only show the
loading, but redirect the user in few seconds.
All right, so let's create one file into a component.
Components and I'm going to just call it loading to redirect.
Or this might be this component you can use in all you react projects for other projects as well because
this concept is very useful and you might want to use it in your other projects as well.
So it's I find it quite useful.
I have used this code in many other projects as well and actually tried this one import.
We are actually would have to import, react, use effect and use state from React, import the use
user from next row and then let's throw the function loading to redirect it instead.
So here on which page you want to redirect, you can pass the path if you want to.
You can destructive path.
And I give a default value of home base.
But if you want anything else, you can always pass the path as props I suppose.
First in our state I want to have the sum count, something called count and set count equals to use
state.
And I give it a value of let's say a three, three, seven.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to use use effect and I'm going to use set interval in that one
and it will stub the count down from three, 3 to 1 as soon as it hits one, we redirect to the path
of Homebase.
So we want to to redirect.
And once you have that, we can use use effect.
See, use effect.
And we want to run this huge effect.
And the county in this county, in the state, and here we're going to create a set interval.
So I'm going to put in a function interval equals two set interval and we're going to do here you can
see since integral this is a function.
This function takes another function as an argument.
So that's another function.
And the second argument is the duration.
So that's 1000 means 1/2.
Okay.
So first argument, the function second argument is the duration.
So in the function, what we're doing is we basically dick decreasing the value from the state.
So set count whatever that is, minus one.
So every second it runs and every second it will minus one.
So it'll go from three to 2 to 1 every second.
So as soon as we hit zero 3 to 1 zero after 3 seconds, then we want to clear the interval and then
we reduce the user to path home base.
All right.
So that's that's all we need now.
After this huge effect, we can return.
We can slow the loading for 3 seconds and then we'll redirect.
All right, so here, it's good to deal with the class of stuff.
Let's use Display Flex so that we can center this in the the base horizontally and vertically.
So display, flex, justify content center, a line item center.
And then for this to work, we need to give it a height.
So height we can use 100 vertical height again then.
Here.
We can write something.
You don't have to write.
If you want, you can write.
Sorry.
Not there, but intended here
so I can write something.
Redirecting in.
You can use the account you can so that seconds.
All right.
So we can say something like that, too.
And this is a loading to redirect component to, again, default export.
Beautiful.
All right, now let's try to use this one instead of that lowering indicator we had so good to subscribe.
A import
loading to redirect from.
So we go one step.
We are already in two components.
So learning to redirect.
Okay.
So I'm going to use this in all other layers as well.
So learning to redirect.
And I'm going to just replace this.
All this.
With loading to redirect.
I guess if it is loading.
We saw that for a few seconds and in 3 seconds it will automatically redirect the user.
But if we get the data from the back end, then we saw the content.
Perfect.
Now let's give it a try.
Let's go.
3 to 1.
And then we get rid of it.
Absolutely beautiful.
Now you want to do the same in other layouts.
So let's import this from.
Let's copy that good auto layout based here.
And then use that.
Nothing to redirect.
And let's also use this in admin.
Since that, too.
Learning to redo.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So if we're not logged in, we get redirected.
But if you're logged in, you should be all right.
Beautiful.