So the next one we want to create here is going to be something like this general password.
So we need to have this button here and this input here.
So, you know, both in length.
So we can use Flex for that.
And then we have this.
Drop down and then we take books like I guess let's keep.
Up to the left side.
So let me create a deal.
Use the style display clips.
All right, so here, inside here, we are going to have a button and the input.
All right.
So button and didn't button, we can call it generate password.
And then the next one is going to be the input field for password.
All right, so input.
And if we're going to use this input for password, we can actually use it like this.
I said, this will give us this side feature by default, which is here you can see.
You can see and hide.
It's nice.
I can select.
We can use that with input dart password.
I see.
Here.
First, let's work on this button.
It's a button.
Let's use glee on the clip.
We want to generate the passion.
Right.
So by default, we'll have the ordinary password in the state.
But if we click again, then that will generate a new one.
So on click we use our function
ssid password.
And that could be generated or generate.
And you give the length.
Length six.
I get to that click type button type default.
We don't want any color.
We don't want it to be grimy.
Anything just different.
I say we use last.
So we're using input alternates and bottom.
So trying to zero zero ten zero.
So we can continue using that one filter to change that.
It actually looks a little bit to get, but if you don't like it, just turn the value.
All right.
So this one looks a little bit of.
So that's input passwords to little open the input password.
Actually, this one is a self-closing compartment, so it's heated like that.
First we use style surmising.
Just then, zero ten zero, I think we use ten zero.
Okay.
So that's how it looks a little bit too big as opposed to use ten bits and I use tiny,
tiny zero ten to.
All right.
So let me quickly find and replace ten days from 20 to 10 to command B command F find 20 become replaced
with ten weeks of this very list, click to change.
So you see things everywhere.
Command s to save.
I guess that that's we're actually on this one.
We may want to use 20, but for the rest we can use ten.
Let's go on the top on this one.
We can use training and the rest we use system.
Okay, nice.
Okay.
So generate passwords.
So we've got this input password and got the style sites.
Size loss.
Placeholder password, value, password and on chance.
So we give the event, the user input, and then we use that put in the state.
So we have the auto generated one, but if you want to manually type, then you can do that.
Okay.
So you can see what the general posture is.
They can change that.
Oh, they can.
Just type is awesome.
Name, email, website, password.
Next one will be the dropdown for the role.
So after this div, let's use the select component.
Select.
And default value.
So we're going to have three types of rules for the user, subscriber, admin and author.
So by default, users will be subscribers.
So when you create by default, you can use the value that's called.
Subscribe iTunes and stand here.
Some margin, 10 to 10.
Do we use that with?
We can use with 100%.
Next one on.
Since we get the value from the select options, we will have the option to do so, whether it's subscriber,
author, admin or whatever that is.
We put that in the role as a string.
Okay.
So.
That means we need to have the option for the user.
Right.
So.
Here, we give them the option to select an option value.
The first one we can use the value of subscribe.
Next one we can use the value of admin and next one we can use the value off offer instead of just copying.
It is to add to this to offer.
And so whatever option you choose that will be accessible here and that will be set as a rule in the
state.
And finally, we can show the box as well.
So we have the password.
We have this option.
Next one.
Let's.
Use the.
Tick box.
So.
Yeah.
Tick the box ticked.
So the did we use the value, whatever that is.
If that is to in true.
Otherwise it would, it would not detect.
I guess so.
On ten.
What do you want to do is you get the event and you want to turn it to.
Event dot target two.
Actually two.
That's a tick box.
Here we can show some text.
So send the new user an email about their comments.
And you see, if you do, then we're going to add a feature in our back in to if it is saved, we will
send the user the email with their account details.
Okay.
So that looks good.
So we've got that now.
So.
Let's add a burden and then we can work on that submit.
All right, so take the monks button and let's call it submit.
So only we want to execute the function called handle.
Submit, which you already have done.
It's a button type.
Let's make it simple.
It's default.
Has the demo type submit.
I guess so.
And have they had similar.
This is actually.
Actually, it's not important.
If we were using the phone, then sometimes when you finish the form, you hit enter that will submit.
So in that case, you could use that.
But in our case, we're not actually using phone, we just using bunch of individual inputs.
So the function will execute on button too.
So we don't actually have to have that style
magazine again, lets you send value and actually just copy that.
Loading so we can double the value of learning to true and false.
So while it's loading is true, you don't want the bottom to be clickable.
So we use the learning so button will be disabled.
Okay.
So next one is block.
So if he is block the button will take the full available with instead of just being in a tiny little
path.
So it's block and that is all we need to get the front.
All we have to do is work on this function.
And then, of course, we have to create the out in a controller in the back end so that we can create
a new user.
Right.
So now before I do anything in, let me just continue long console table.
So let me have a look at all these values that we have in the state.
Make sure we have access to all this value before we send it to them back.
Right.
So for I see the role of it.
It's not to use.
Let's see.
Why is that?
Sylvester.
All I can say to that can stay like that.
So let's try here table.
Let's try to print out all of these names and name, email, wayside.
Classroom rule.
So let's make sure we have all these people we work on excuse to send this debate.
Pull me
in a minute.
Let's try this one.
I guess it's leave the password of a new one.
Also, like I said, let's make this user author send an email to me and you can see who we are.
We have all this information name, email, website, password, role too.
So all this information we send to the back end and in the back end we will quit in the user.