All right.
So now we want to secure the space for the user with the role of admin, right?
So for that, we can do something in the layout.
So if you remember, we have the layout.
At the moment we just have the admin layout, but later we will have all the layouts for offline and
subscribe as well.
So admin layout.
As you can see here, admin layout has this admin navigation which is also here.
And so all the navigation menu we see on the side, this is the admin nav component.
So that that nav component is here, it just the navigation and that that is also been imported in the
layout, the admin layout, right.
So admin layout has been used on all the admin pages and the content is received as children and that
is rendered here.
Right here.
So this is the children props.
So that means any base that will be accessed by admin is going to use this layout.
Right.
So we can do some kind of a take in this component and that will be applied to all the admin bases because
all the admin bays here, this layout.
Just a quick, quick review.
If you go to pages admin, we have a couple of pages here.
So if you go to the index, you can see we are using the admin layout and inside we have this content
which is received as is children props and rendered.
Here are two admin indexes using the admin layout post.
Also using this layout categories also.
Using the layout so as you can tier if you apply something in this layout that will be applied on all
those pages that are using this layout.
So that means we can do some kind of a trick here.
For the user.
And if the user has the role of admin, we can we can allow the we can just go ahead with this written,
otherwise we can redirect the user to some other bits.
Right, so we can pull from the take here.
Now this is just going to be this is not the best solution, not the best not the most secure solution.
So I will see you in the next lecture.
The most my preferred solution, which is making request to back in and get the response from the back
end that will be fully secured.
But this is another quick and easy way of securing the routes based on the value we have in the local
stories.
Okay.
So if you remember, we have the author in the local stories, right?
So that value we have in the local stories and also in the context.
So we can take for this value.
So if this user zone that we have in saved in the local stories and also in the context, if that user
has the role of admin, then maybe we can continue this one can go ahead with this region, otherwise
maybe do some kind of a redirect.
So that is a quick and easy solution.
But like I said, this is not the most secure because anyone can come here and edit the value.
So you can go to the console and run the query.
Local stories don't get item doors and use decent pass to change it as I was to change it to JavaScript
object from decent data.
And then you can just object the value to that way.
You could play around with the value and menu retains the value in the local stories.
So that will not be the most secure way.
So let's give it a try anyways.
And then we're going to.
Take a different solution by making requests to back in.
All right.
So to give it a try first, let's access the earth from context.
So import
all context from.
We go one step, two step context.
Oh, all right.
To use this one, obviously, we need to use context to react to import.
Here's context from React.
We have the context as well.
So here we can take we can access the context and set us from.
The Earth context, and we give that as an argument to use context.
We get these values right.
By the way, if you're wondering how I'm getting all these autocomplete, that's because of the type
tab line.
Now, you see, you can always I think I've shown you before as well in still extensive search for tab
line.
It is absolutely amazing.
Plugin it is tab nine and tab and I think -- nine.
So this is AI powered autocomplete for I'm Screwed.
It's absolutely amazing.
All right, so we access the US now, then we can use the use context.
So use effect that will run when the component mounts.
So as soon as the component mounts, we want to take if.
This user has the role of admin.
That's a huge effect.
It takes function as an argument.
Second argument, the dependency area.
We leave it empty.
We could use us.
So whenever the value of fairly invested tens tenses, we want to run this as well.
So not only when the component mounts, but also when the value changes in the context.
I guess so here we want to take if we have the fourth object in the context.
And then if the author user and we also want to take for the arts user role.
A consequence equals add me.
Actually it's a remote event.
So if all its user control is not equal to admin.
So if user is not admin, then redirect them to some other bits.
Maybe redirect to homepage utopia on a redirect to sign in because the user might be logged in user
but not the admin user.
Right.
No.
Actually, we are going to use header if we're going to use the.
You used hook I guess let's import use of from an extra from.
And then we're going to use this.
I guess.
Hopefully I'm not going too fast.
Sometimes I use this autocomplete, so I recommend you to install that blog plug in tab nine instead
of using that one.
But otherwise, I think I'm not going too fast.
All right, so let's use that.
Fox controller, it could use user.
Ah, we use that hook and then we can use this to redraw the user.
All right, so here are the dot posts.
We want to push the user to home base if it is not admin.
Okay.
So with this take let's see how this works.
So at the moment we have the user.
This is not admin user, but let's say he tries to manually access the admin position, whatever.
Previously he could, but now he can't.
You can see you.
He has been redirected.
Now you might see the pace for brief second millisecond.
We can fix that as well.
Um, let me just it's it's really hard to notice, but you may see.
The admin desperate for brief milliseconds in before we get redirected.
Ah.
So we're going to fix that as.