All right.
So let's explore the dashboard of this application as well.
Of course, there are too many features here, so I might forget to throw quite a lot of them.
But let's go to the overview.
So here, feel free to visit Monster dot com and then log in as admin so that you can check out the
application where while we are building this application from scratch and I think that will really help
you because sometimes even when I'm trying to explain, it might be difficult for you to understand
because, you know, it's so much better when you can see it visually.
That way you can actually come and get the the overview of the application.
For example, when we set up the basic project, we will work on the sign in.
It's had a basis, so it's easier for you to come and visit to the base, have a look at it, how the
form items, icons, placeholder.
Everything has been built here.
So based on that, when we are recording, it makes perfect sense.
You know what we are doing, right?
So that I think will greatly help you to go through the application and the learning process will be
so straightforward.
All right, so let's try a log in as an admin and have a look at the desperate.
Now, you can see here, absolutely amazing.
Desperate similar to WordPress.
All right.
So admin has all these options.
Now, if you log in as author, author will have some less options.
And for subscribers they will be very few options.
For example, they can leave a comment, manage the comment, and that's pretty much it.
But for admin, we have a lot of these options here.
All right.
So you can see it's a collapsible, absolutely beautiful saver.
And if you are using it in a small browser, it will automatically collapse as well.
All right.
So this is the decimal we're showing the total number of posts and categories we have in our application
and the pit posts.
We have all this post.
So we have total 11 post.
At the moment.
When you have more post, you will be able to describe the name of the title and then you can filter
out.
For example, if I want to search the post with the title of boot camp, again, just search boot camp
and you can see it filters out.
So that will be much easier when you have too many posts later.
You can put a new post from here, you can click here, you can edit or delete.
The post has also moved edit as it's called here and this is absolutely amazing.
Text Editor Amazing because as you can see here, when I double click, it gives you this option to
format it could see you can embed link, you can even for faster writing in this use less and then type
something in for example if you want to type his his too and then you can just hit enter and write.
This is second page.
So you can do that.
You can quickly type for example, let's say you want to write them.
Just tap two and then it comes up here.
All right.
B and C I.D..
Name?
Email to things are so much easier.
Now there are so many options here.
As you can see, we have the heading.
We have a to do list order.
In order to list codes table, you can put code block and divider images.
You can emit images, links, and you even have this nice little notification bar said to have.
Make it right.
Make sure to
check out our post space facts and you can create something like that.
You can choose different type.
All right.
Now, if you hit save of debt, obviously a ton of debt.
We can try that later.
Now, you can see we have the categories and they're showing up here.
You can see the preview while you're writing this at the blog post.
You can have a look at the preview images.
You can change the image.
All right.
So this is an absolutely beautiful feature of this application as well.
So you can observe one image on multiple images and you have access to the application's media library
as well.
So its image has been uploaded.
They are available here, just like in a word, resumes.
So if you want, you can just choose issue and send the images.
Let's change that to this one.
Click here.
You can see this electric in preview category is really you can delete, you can have a SEO, you can
just type.
And it comes up here, which sounds absolutely beautiful.
And if I hit update.
All right, it has been updated.
Let's have a look.
That's the window.
You can see the image has been said.
And.
We have this other box as well.
All right.
And you can leave a comment as well.
This is incredible.
All right.
Absolutely beautiful.
Let's go back.
Let's continue to explosive.
That's how he can edit posts.
He can delete post.
You can fill the post, you can create a new post.
You can go from here.
You can go from here, create a new post.
So why don't we give it a try?
Creating a new post and let me go to my.
One of my calls so that I can copy some content.
Ryan Dingell.
All right.
So let me take out one.
My course, for example, let's see this one graphic you.
I guess so you can type the title.
Let's put title to this post and we're going to write some of the hint something here.
Now, obviously, you can write a list.
I'll give you to do it as well.
It's pretty cool.
I guess you can do something like that as well.
Now, obviously you can write a list.
One, two, like that.
Now, sometimes you might be copying text from other websites from Microsoft Word.
So it gets really easy here.
For example, you can see this is the list item here and I have a copy here.
It will detect the list item and it will auto format.
He absolutely amazed right now.
Let's leave it for now.
Let's upload.
Let's put some categories.
Let's see if I want to use a React craft, you know.
So you can easily source and choose the categories featured images.
I can upload.
The new images I can choose the existing one.
Let me to the existing one here.
I previously uploaded a few tools that I could.
Beautiful knowledge spot this.
Great.
Now, this post has been published.
We can have a look at that bit later.
So that's absolutely amazing part of this application.
Then post management, blog post the categories here.
As an admin, you will be able to put new categories.
You can update, delete, they are here and media, arts and media.
You can add a new image while you can go to the library, check out all the images that we have.
You can delete if you want to.
You can click on drag.
It gets a multiple upload, it will, it supports multiple upload.
You can click the drag.
We have the comment section so you can see all the comments
in the site.
And if you think some comments are not appropriate, you can just delete it.
You can view it will take you to that post where the comment has been posted.
All right.
So that's pretty cool.
That's okay.
So you can filter the comments as well here.
And then you have the user management section where you are able to create a new user.
All right.
So you can see this is your self or the user.
So you can edit, you can delete as well.
You can edit and make them give them a different URL, fake them, do this admin.
You can change that to something else as well.
I guess you can put some information there.
You can create a user or you can upgrade the existing user, you can delete them.
So you have full control over the user management here.
So if you add a new user, you put in an email, you can use this auto generated password or even just
enter your password manually.
You can give them the rule and you can build this set of the same books.
If you do and submit, then this new user will receive an email about the account.
So this new user will receive the email and email password so that they can log in to that.
Because I guess if everything works, the email will be sent as well.
It's pretty cool.
Now profile.
So user, the admin here will be able to update his profile him to his profile images.
And we also have this customize feature.
So again, see this is the image that is being used in the frontend.
So let me go to Monster.com.
So this is the images we have.
All right.
So if you want to, you can change here so you can control the home based how it looks from within your
desk.
How good is that?
Now, let me change that from one step to just more inclusive.
Come back here, give refresh and you can see that inside.
Now you want to use let me be a different one.
Maybe try this one.
Okay.
Let's itself come here and give a reference and you can see we have a brand new image is absolutely
beautiful.
Now let me put it back the way it was.
Okay.
So this is a basic overview of how the admin despot looks like.
Now you can try with the subscriber and author as well.
So if you only log in a subscriber, they will have bit less features.
So obviously you can just copy from me as well.
Now you see it also has bit less options.
They can create post minis the uploads but that's net.
So now as a subscriber they will be able to just leave the comment.
Not not much I guess if you copy.
And there's the password here.
So subscribers will have very limited hours and obviously.
All right.
So this is a production ready, complete content management system.
Here's your monster, which you will be building in this course.