Let's go and visit the next district.
Org.
It's always good habit to visit the documentation.
Sometimes it change over time.
So you know, you want to keep this habit of going to the documentation and take out the instructions
so you can see how to get started.
You want to have Node.js 12 or higher, which we have.
We have version 16.
And there are two ways of creating mixed this app.
One is by running this command and b create next app whether NP X is available as soon as you have Node.js,
insulin, a computer, you can use this command or you can just manually set up like this.
Yeah, you can use here or you can use NPM.
We just going to continue using and build the NPM.
Create next app.
You could use that or you can go with a manual set up, NPM, install and install these packages separately.
Next, react and react.
So we going to take this approach because this command will create a few files and folders, which is
not a big deal.
Very basic information.
However, I want to start from absolute clean still so that you understand isn't everything how everything
is what you know.
All right, so let's copy this one in women style.
Next.
React and react.
So we want to insert that and we need to update our prejudice and scripts, and that's pretty much it.
That's how you set up next this project.
So let's come here and go to the terminal and let's run this so that we give these libraries, these
packages from NPM to our application.
You can see here, as soon as you run that node modules, this folder gets created and you can see in
packages that this and now we have the dependencies next next react and react.
Now these packages are installed here, the code base is installed here and along with them there are
so many other things.
Now you might be thinking, how come we have so many of these packages?
I installed only three.
And that's because these three packages also depend on are the packages.
All right.
Okay.
So that's how you see quite a lot of them, because these three packages depend on all these other packages
as well, because each of them will have their own package, a decent file.
And based on that, yeah, we need to have all these files.
So all this code base is here thanks to NPM.
We have next react in React.
So that means we we're very close to set of this project.
Now the next thing you can see here, open package edition and add the following scripts.
So we have to add this to the scripts.
All right.
So let's copy that here and I'll explain to you what they do.
So in this starts the scripts here content and just based that here.
All right so these commands will allow you to run so for example, you can run in the terminal NPM run
div, you can do an NPM run build, you can run engine start.
So that's how you can use this commands.
All right.
So throughout the development, we will be using this and do so npm run dev.
So that is the command you will use to run the development server.
And later in production we will be running NPM, run, build as well, which we would obviously correlate.
So at the moment these are the scripts we have and we will be mainly using the NPM Run Dev Connect.
Okay.
Now before we do anything here, one more requirement there is for Nexus and that is you need to have
the basis folder.
I guess that that's the most of it because the installation is done now we just need to have at least
one base so that the application works.
Yeah.
So here in the client folder let's create a new for the basis of this name is important.
Okay.
All lowercase and the name is basis that is a requirement interfaces.
You want to have at least one file to give it a try.
Let's try in the expertise.
All right.
So indicators is.
So we had to write some code here.
And this code will appear in as soon as we run this application as a home base.
All right.
So let's go to function.
So in React, everything you write is treated as a component.
So you can call it a component.
Call it a function that's going to function.
Function.
Let's call it home.
I go to these fronts.
Now you want to return?
Return parentheses.
Inside parentheses.
You want to return?
Some has to remove its reg div.
And here, let's write H1, H1, and let's write home.
All right.
So this is a react component.
It's a this is the name of the component and this component is returning.
This has steam.
Now within react you don't actually call it has simply called D6.
That means JavaScript and has since the mixture.
So the beauty of react is you use this d6.
Don't get confused with the A6.
It's it's so it's has dimmer but with additional features so that you can mix JavaScript with your estimate.
That's how it is so much easier to build UI components in React.
All right so this is has similar looking for it is technically the A6 but you can do today has team
with very very little differences.
Okay so instead of class you call it clustering.
So that is one of the most common difference.
Otherwise, it's pretty much like hysteria.
And you will be able to write JavaScript because you hear, you know, which we will explore a bit later.
All right.
So we have this component now.
We want to export export the default home.
All of this is important.
If you don't have this, you will get some error.
So when you write a comment, you want to export.
I said, That's extremely important.
Now, once we have this much, we have done the setup.
We are ready to give it a try.
I say let's try.
Come here
into client folder.
Now we want to run our application and to run the application.
Have a look here in the package position and you have to run this command and development server.
NPM, run, dev.
You can see.
Started on localhost, 3000 to 3000.
You can visit and have a look at your beautiful application and it suits so home.
Let's give it a try.
Localhost, 3000.
And there is our beautiful head swan and where to listen you have said of you react project to using
next this.