All right.
So let's go ahead, create a global stage using the youth context.
So first thing you want to do is create a fuller intake client.
Let's create a new folder called Context.
We can have multiple contexts, so this can begin to just create one for the theme.
But later we may use create more contexts, right?
So themed today is an insight here to create a context.
First, let's import some hooks.
So use context.
We need we also need to use state hook and then use.
A create context function from React.
So we have these two hooks and this function that will help us create a context.
So let's create a context for second.
Let's call it theme for context equals.
To use this function, we just execute this function.
All right.
So that gives us the context here.
So we execute that function, the value we put in this variable, same context.
All right.
So next one, we use theme provider theme.
Right.
This is going to be a component.
Now, you could use.
Renal function here to create a component you could do like this.
Well, you can use our function or something.
We would use our phones in whichever way it works.
All right.
So we have the context now.
We create a provider, this component, and then we're going to.
Export and then wrap our entire application in averages.
So first here, we need to have a state, some kind of a state where we can save the current theme,
right?
So whether it's a light or duck const theme, that's the state name and the object that we use.
The function set name equals to use state and we give the default value to, let's say, light.
So the way it's going to work is and then gives us the two stating dark, dark styles and light states.
So it's really easy to implement this one.
So we're going to have those both pieces here in our directory and we're going to load depending on
this value.
So by default we load light theme.
But if the if you that turns to dark, then we load the dark theme.
And that's how the application layer changes, styling changes because of the theme.
All right.
So that's the state.
So once we have the state, we can return the value using the provider.
Now, before we do that, we want to make sure that if a user change the theme, when they reload the
peso and they come back to our application again, we want to make sure that we remember his preference,
right?
So we're going to always to light him by default every time he visits the site, even though the last
time he tends to do duck.
So if it turns that to duck, most likely he'll want to use that continuously, right?
So to provide better user experience, we can save the value not only in the context but also in the
applications local stories, which is here in the browsers.
They have the local stories right click and so.
So you can right click open view pay source a certain to business right click and click inspect.
You get this one.
So you go click on the producer and hear local stories.
We have this domain to them, that screen domain.
We have bunch of things I can remove, I guess, to let me reload so we don't have anything at the moment.
So I enable you to change the theme.
We can upgrade the context, but at the same time we can set that value in the local store is here with
the key in value.
So you can store values here.
So this will stay there unless you manually remove.
So that means when user reloads the base or maybe he come back to visit our site the next day.
This value will always be here.
So based on that, we can show his preference theme.
You know, we can load that theme.
All right.
So let's see this in the local stories as well.
So by default, we use the light theme and then.
To load it from the local stories.
We have another hook that's called use effect.
Now use effect.
Hope you will use whenever you want to run some code immediately when the component mounts immediately.
All right.
So use effect hook.
This is a function and this function takes another function as an argument.
Right.
So we give another function so we can use elephants in here at a function.
So that's argument, right?
So that's our argument.
And then second argument.
Also, we we can give this function.
So that's a first argument format.
Second argument uses past empty array.
So we will learn more about use effect later.
The reason we do this is you pass out of the entries here to indicate that you want to load this.
I run the code here when the component mounts.
So that's the different behavior.
But this is also known as.
The dependency.
All right.
So whenever you want to run this call, when certain thing turns is, for example, when the theme turns
is, then you will pass that here so that we can have this function here, whatever port you write that
will run whenever the value is here.
For example, if you give them over integers, this will run.
However, we don't need that.
We just need to run it when the component mounts for the very first time.
So we just leave it like that and we try to load it from the local stories.
So if local stories don't get high enough, so whenever you want, we want to access something from
local storage.
You can use this function get item whenever you want to save something in the local story you can use
CET item.
All right, so this time we want to use get item.
You want to get the item by the key so you can see here whenever you save something in the local story,
you with the key and the value.
So whenever you want to get something, you give use the key name.
So key we can use theme because we haven't received anything yet, which we will do very soon.
But at the moment, if we have anything in the local search, we want to get that and populate the state,
right?
So if we have the theme in the local stories, we want to update our local state here.
Our state said theme and the value will be whatever is in the local stories, so local stories don't
get item.
Again, it's the same code that we have that.
I'd say if they have that get that and pre-populated the state.
So the benefit of this one is if user had chose the dark theme last time, we would load that theme.
So whenever a user visits our site, next time he will see his preferred theme in that spirit.
All right.
So when we want to have that, we can now return to return the theme context.
Theme context and theme context gives us this provider to provide a property.
This would help us provide the value here.
What are we going to do?
Is we going to return the props?
Now, if you.
I'm not sure if you know or not.
So in react whenever you wrap a component with any other component.
So those values will be accessible at children props so you can access them as props.
And then here you can use proctored children.
All right, so this children means anything.
So when you export this component, import anywhere, for example, let's say here in the European application.
So all this entire application becomes children and is received here as the children.
Props.
All right.
Make it so you can use props to children or you can directly destruct so and so that you can just use
children as well.
It's nice and easy.
So that looks are good.
However, we shouldn't forget to provide the value.
So that's the whole point, right?
So this value we want to provide you so value.
Carney Bruce and then you best that here I it's this way.
We cannot export.
No, this time we're not going to use the default export because we have two things to export.
One is context.
One is provider.
All right.
So instead of different export, we are exporting like this one thing, context and.
Over.
All right.
And this is it.
This is our theme context.
Now we can.
Import this in our abilities and access the value anywhere in our application in any basis.
This value team in team will be able to access that.
And then from anywhere from any basis, we will be able to obtain this state.
Thank you.
So let's give it a try and let's go to introduce and try importing this one.
Input.
By the way, you can see here in visual is to record if some imports haven't been used.
You see there they look different.
They'll look Greece.
So you can to you use context haven't been used because it was needed.
Instead we had to use create context.
But I think I've been using the word use context all the time, even though I meant to say create context.
All right, let's remove that so we could hear.