All right.
Now let's go.
Continue working in this control function.
Previously, we wrote Our moral support model is here.
So first, let's import the sport model to our controller.
Import export with a capital T from.
We go one step of models or so we import from that and then.
We want to come to this house.
We are we are receiving the data so we can actually take these strokes of the data from request part
to make things easier so we can restructure title content and categories from request 40.
We don't have the published and forced I can now next one.
Oh, you want to make sure that this post that you're trying to create with this title, this title
has not been taken before.
All right.
So you can see here, this is my first post.
I guess it's slang will look something like this.
This is my first post.
I guess if I post with this title, this log is already served in the database, then you don't want
to allow another post to be credited with the same title similar to that.
That will.
Not work because, you know, it's each one of them must be unique.
All right.
So just to make sure it hasn't been the title hasn't been taken.
Just like you doing the sign up we take for the email.
If the email was already taken, we could integration of the user, the same image.
It's the same content.
So we can take our take if title is taken.
So for that, we have to try to find the block, find the post based on the category, based on the
title.
So contact, let's call it already exists.
It wants to avoid to use the post model dot.
Find one function.
Find one will find.
Try to find the post based on this title.
So whenever it finds the very first one from the collection, it will stop executing the code to find
one.
That's how it works.
So find one based on the title.
And one I think we can still use this in the town however we want to use.
This slow slug will be the lower case format and there will be no white spaces, you know, the slope.
So we we're going to be saving the portion is pushed will have the slope based on the title.
All right.
So we try to find.
The post based on the slot.
So instead of total, let's call it slow and the slow at the moment we can use this value for our function
to this token that will give us the slope rises slowly, very
slowly for this total and slowly fey actually doesn't make it lowercase so we have to manually do that
title dart to load case.
So this is a native JavaScript function that they can use to make it lowercase.
However, slowly, if we have to install from NPM and I think we already did that in category control,
it's I would say yes, we already use that.
So let's use the same sluggish fey here as well.
Awesome.
So.
When you lose trying to create a post the you receive the title, right?
So you make that title lowercase and use the solitaire function that basically gives you the slug.
So you use that as a value to this one.
So you try to find the post based on this slug.
All right.
So if that is fun, that means we have to send some kind of error message because it's totally taken.
So if already exist, a return response, Jason, we send the error message.
Title is taken.
I guess this is even though it's error, error, it's technically still a valid response.
So it's a decent response.
Okay.
So this is the reason why.
Let me quickly go to the client to go to the basis admin and post new.
You can see we have this data tick.
I guess that is for taking something like this and something like this.
1...0.
I guess.
So if title is taken.
User will be getting the total notification.
Okay.
So that's done.
I think there's one more thing we have to do.
And then.
Somehow getting the category IDs from the category name.
So if you remember, you can see we are actually receiving the category.
Nim not died.
Now we could send the idea from the client.
However, since we are using this and isn't this component previously used.
So when we use the idea, we couldn't actually type and do something like that.
And later, it will be problematic as well.
When we are trying to update the blogpost, you will be showing the idea and that will be very confusing
because you don't know which 80 which category.
Right.
So we have to use the name for the user experience purpose.
However, it's difficult in the back end because we don't have the ID.
We just have the name.
Now there's one solution that is we can still try to find the.
The category based on the name we can slug ify and then each category have this slug based on this name
so we can try to find the category based on this total slug, just like this one.
And then when we find that category, we use the categories IED and use that to save in the database.
I guess so let's see how we can do that.
So get category IDs based on category name.
Okay.
So let's create this variable.
It is a consumer interior.
So in this area I will be pushing the categories ID.
So categories can be one of many.
So we're going to push the arrows here.
And then finally we can save the posts altogether with the categories ID.
So whenever you saving the categories, you have to save the area for ideas.
Okay, so I'm going to use it for look.
So for loop, I'm pretty sure you have used it.
So for lit i equals to do so.
It starts with the value of zero.
Then if this is smaller then the category that we get.
Categories, categories, dirt length.
Then keep going up.
I plus plus.
So what's happening here is it will start with a value of zero.
And for example, if we are getting two categories, right, so levels will be two.
So I will be zero in the beginning.
So it is smaller than two.
So that that time it will run the loop, then it becomes one and then it becomes two.
It's time you can see it is incrementing.
Okay.
So until it is less than the length which is two, then you want to run this look.
So if you are sending two categories, this will run.
This loop will run two times.
I guess I'm doing that.
What are you going to do is we're going to query the database.
So find.
The category was to find one that's contained with most.
That would be category,
I guess, and we can't use a because we are into the fall of.
So let's remove that I guess a category don't find one you find by the name.
That would be the categories whatever that is.
And then.
He's of that will have either whatever name is used.
I guess that we try to find the category best in that and then.
We take categories to find the one and then we use execute.
We can use the execute function since we aren't using it to execute.
Function gives you the.
You can use a callback here.
So another function lets you add a function
to here.
What are you going to do is execute?
You get error.
Oh, you get the data.
I guess we also have to check for the error first.
So if if error you want to return.
Just use console.log.
Yeah.
Okay.
Otherwise.
So we got some typos here for let.
Okay.
I know who to comment.
Should be calling.
Okay.
So if any error, we return the console log error.
Otherwise we can push the.
Dollar, which means the category that is front.
So when we find the category, we want to get the 80 because that's the whole reason we're doing this
search and we get the data today.
Then we post that to this area.
You can post items to the array using the post function.
Okay.
So you can see here we have the for loop and we'll running this loop based on how many categories we
have.
Okay.
And then it's time.
This is what happened.
So we've tried to find the category based on that.
And then for each loop it's time to run.
And so the first one and then the second one, it'll run.
And then we take care.
So if.
We find, then we want to boost that to category aids to this it is a really.
Okay.
So that should be.
That's Holland and done him aggressive and it's good.
Next week and what are we going to do here is we can now find him saving the date of this because we
have got the title, we have got the content, we have got the categories.
Now we got only the name.
But with this code we have all the ideas based on the name as well.
All right.
So that means.
Yeah, save post.
Now, when we're saving the post, I want to delay the saving by at least 1/2 because we have a lot
of this code that I need to execute.
So I'm just going to use sit down, sit down, write to you.
This is a function so it takes.
Two elements.
First one is the function is to get to whatever you're trying to do.
You do that.
And then second argument is the duration of the time.
So what?
What is the time you want to use it?
In my case, it's 1000 milliseconds, which is 1/2.
So what do we write here in this function?
The first argument this call will drop after 1/2.
After 1/2.
Okay, so this is what I'm trying to do.
So I'm trying to create a post.
Okay.
Using the title content categories, which is the idea that tier and then posted values are going to
be required to use.
I did because we have used that request and in middleware that gives us the currently logged in user
side.
I mean, so this is profit.
And.
When we have everything ready to create a post, we can use the same function to finally submit in the
database.
Now you can see we are using this callback for some.
If you want you can actually use async await here.
So you can prefix with async if you do that.
Uh, in use.
Oh, wait.
So no need to remove that new.
You can use it.
I'll wait for the new post to be created.
And then instead of that, you can directly call that save here.
Okay.
And then he can return the saved post using response.
Jason Post Let me just don't see the already exist and the post here.
Thank you.
Not doing this.
If you want to, you can.
Maybe you should try and get Tesla to try all this.
Get there.
Come to the air.
Art.
Beautiful.
So this is how we can create a post.
We've got all the data you take.
If the title is taken, we extract all the ideas.
Best in the category name.
Then we save everything in the database delay by 1/2 using set time.
So to create a push, we have the title of content.
We have the categories, which is the eighties, and the push by which to be logged in userspace.
All right, so let's give it a try.