Ah.
So we have this server generated.
Now let's see how this works.
The first thing you can do is you can see here we have two obviously in the variables.
So the environment variables we have here, it's a database.
So you can update this database with the actual database here.
And for that, we can use Mongo Atlas in a mongo atlas is running in the cloud so you can get the MongoDB
URI from then you start using that.
Or if you have MongoDB installed locally in your computer, then you can use that differential as well,
which I will see you later I guess at the moon.
Let's leave it like that.
SendGrid We have decided to send it and put that key here so that we can send the public password.
Emails, right?
So email, you want to use your email address.
Okay.
So we'll come back to it.
Let's not worry about this one.
Let's try running the event.
So you can see here we have to run npm, install and then and being stuck NPM still.
Once all the libraries has been installed, based on what we see in Baghdad today.
All these files, all these dependencies, they will be installed in non magisk folder.
That's done now.
We can start a server and you can see here when you run NPM start.
Norman will execute indicator days, which is the end point of our survey and I will be showing that
file and explain all the code.
Um.
Just a second.
I just noticed that we may have to install Norman because it's not here.
I guess unless you have Norman installed globally, otherwise you have to install.
So let's make sure you install this.
Come on.
This NPM library as well as NPM install.
No.
By the way, in Bergson, we don't use Norman, we use some other library.
But when we are running locally, we do that.
And now we have Norman as awesome.
Okay, now let's run NPM Start command, which will execute index.html this fun and beam stuff.
You can see we have the MongoDB connection error because that is not a valid euro.
I will come back to that.
However, you can see our service 100 up and running and you can give them a try by going into visiting
a route.
For example, let's go to the roads for let's have a look what we have here.
So we have the sign of road sign in roads followed password and reset password.
So these are all post roads, so you can send request here.
To sign up, sign in and do all that stuff.
We'll take it out later at the moment just to give it a try that we can try making request to our son,
which is running in World 8000 now.
I'll be explaining this on the school, but you can see here this is the route we have forwards less.
So localhost, 8000.
That's where our biggest son is running.
So.
So let's make a request and see what we get.
We should be receiving this response.
I guess it is heavily
has to be local host.
Now it's not 3000.
It's 8000.
That's our service learning API.
So I just missed that.
If you get anything like that, that means your server is running it.
Just saying that there is no route with just focus less.
So in our case it is prefixed with SLAs, Apia.
If you visit that, you can see the response decent responsive data and it is saying hello world from
cholera, the host API and this data is coming as a response from here.
You can see here, whenever we get requests to SLAs, we send this decent response.
All right, beautiful.
Now, you might be wondering, we had the SLAs, but we made a request to SLAs.
APAC.
How is that?
That's because if you go to the index to this, which is the end to point of our server, EMC here.
The file has been imported as our throats and then it has been applied as a middleware and it has been
prefixed with SLAs API.
So prefixed means whenever you make request to sign up, sign in for a password, you will always prefix
with AP, less IBS, less sign up.
That's where you will be sending the user information from him.
That's where you will be sending in.
Then your server will process the user creation to use authentication.
All that beautiful, right?
So that's the route.
However, let's go go through the very beginning.
So what's happening here?
The indicator, this indicator, as you can see here, this is the to point of a server.
So whenever you run the server, this file gets executed.
So everything has been imported here.
Else has been imported here.
I guess the first thing we have the X first, then we have the course.
And one way as these packages have been imported and then we executed the express which gives us this
EP.
So to build our several, we're using Express.
So Express it gives us a lot of functionalities.
So to access all this functionalities, we exit with the, we execute this, this function and put all
its value in this variable EP.
So once you do that, next thing we have done is we have created a server.
So we have created heads, we have used the has to deep module.
This module is not something we have to install from NPM.
It comes with nauseous by default.
Okay.
So has to be is also not required.
But it is good to have him because later, if you want to use some real time with some video, then
it's it gets really easier.
All right.
So then what we have done here is we have set up a database connection.
We have used this mongoose library and it has this connect function.
You can see connect function.
And this function requires the database zero, which you are learning from the EMV file right now.
This is not valid at the moment.
That's where we have the error.
We will fix that up.
So that's the date of this connection.
So basically we import the extremist app, we put that in a variable and execute.
So we have all the functionalities available and then we have the power of this connection and then
this exists at request.
Some mirrors always are basically a piece of code, a function that executes in the middle, right?
So basically how the server works is from the client, you send some data, sometimes you want to save
some data, sometimes you want to get from the database unit sending anything you just getting it so
that calls get request.
This one is you sending something.
This is called push to request.
All right.
So we'll be going through all this.
They don't get overwhelmed.
No.
Right.
So so that's how sutra works.
We it communicates with client.
Sometimes we ask for data, sometimes we send data.
All right.
So in this case, we will be sending the data.
So those dollars will be received here.
So they will be received as decent data.
So we need to have this middleware to make sure we are able to receive the decent data.
Okay.
So this is one of those middleweight x, Mr. Jason, and you set the limit to maximum.
We always for the of data transfer you can retain that of the URL extended we send it to true we are
place of course, so that there is no conflict between a different client running in a different domain
because by default the servers, the broadcast, they do not allow these requests from one domain to
other for security reasons.
So technically we have the power 3000 and the server is port 8000.
So they are technically different domains.
So when different domains tried to communicate with each other, browsers strive to stop them by default
for security reasons.
To avoid that, we can use the course.
All right.
So that's that moment.
Now, let me quickly show you that so you can see here.
Actually, we don't have we we have got this error.
So you can see that.
But whenever you make a request, for example, to sign up or sign any rules that will you get printed
here with the method to get a post.
So that will it really makes it easier for you to understand what's happening on which we are getting
a request to us.
So I'll get to all that you will be able to see here.
This is something we will call later as we progress to basically you can see it's very simple this file
imports.
Excuse the excuse that connect to database apply some necessary middleware.
Even roots has been applied as middle way into our throats, and whenever you want to apply as middleware,
you use this use function.
You can see this app.
Basically, it's an extra server and it gives us a lot of functionalities.
For example, one of those functionalities use, so this is a function to this function is taken this
middleware, this piece of code that do certain things and same with the rules we wrote also has been
applied as a middleware which is use.
Thank you.
And then basically we need a port to run our project.
And so we are using the port 8000.
If you want to use some different body, you can put it as a value in the variable which is in the EMV
file.
But if you don't have by default, we use 8000 just using this our operator if we have to use that or
use this again, finally we listen on the spot and then this second argument is just a console.log to
this system.
So this text for us, you know.
Done.
All right.
So that's the end point, very basic.
We basically apply some malware's kind of to database and use the rote.
Simple as that.
Now let's go to the routs, which we already had a loop.
Now you can have more than one route and you can just always import like that in a as well with more
than one traditional form.
So you can see here.
We are using the express rota in Israel.
That gives us more functionalities.
For example, post requests, handle the postings, get requests to get requests.
We already tried in the barrage amid a get request and we've got that decent response.