All right.
So we have been able to resize the image in the grand total.
We have got the best 64 format of the image.
So let me just control over the name of that.
It's remove the written keyword.
So we going to send this base64 format and the image to the backend.
And.
Then that way it will be returned to the air and will be returned.
So we have to make sure it is dirty.
Yara.
I guess so.
Hopefully it will not.
And then so this year, all of the uploaded images will be saved along with the post.
Okay, so let's go to the back end and create this endpoint so that we can upload the images to ordinary.
So I'm not sure if we have already signed up to Cardano.
Let's go to EMV.
And we haven't.
So we.
Do have the key for SendGrid for uploading.
Sorry.
Sending email.
But we didn't have the one for cloud in every.
Okay.
So let me just read that here.
So we need to go and sign up to cloud an area.
And when we sign up to cloud native, we get the cloud name
cloud generally let's call it name.
Next one will be key.
And then the secrets.
That's a key.
It's good to sign up, get these values.
We can sign up for free.
Get these values so that we can start uploading to coordinate.
I do have the account, but I'm going to create a new account just for this cause.
Um, Claudia and Erin.
So I'm going to use that image that I used previously for.
Simply.
This might be a bit of a long process.
So if you have already signed up to Cloud Generic, you can skip to the next letter.
What I will be doing is I will be just putting my name key and secret by the end of this video.
So if you have already signed them to clarity, you can grab these values and put them here and continue
with the next lecture.
All right.
So let's go ahead all together.
Right.
So the email I'm using is mine.
See?
Seeing this.
I saw.
Oh.
Most content.
All right.
Hmm.
Oh.
Oh, thank God.
All right, I take the e-mail.
Also got the email.
Let's click on this one.
Sign in to validate the email address.
Okay.
So the cloud name is also here, but we can grab on that from.
The desperate township went too long in.
You should be landing on the dashboard.
So.
Okay.
So here.
You need to go to the decimal.
I go to the desperate and call me the cloud name put here to that cloud name.
Make sure don't have any special anything here.
Right.
Cloud name API key.
Copy that key.
Put it here and the API secret and need to copy that and put it here.
Now these values, of course, you don't want to show it to the public because they can use you according
to this.
But I'm showing you because I trust in you guys.
And I will be hopefully if I don't forget, I will be deleting the the key.
All right.
So try not to use this value.
Okay.
So good.
The name key and secret.
So that is all we need to start using.
Ordinary, which is awesome.
Now, one more thing we need that is we need to install new in our server.
So let's stop that and NBN to continue.
Make sure you don't have any typos.
You.
So what is happening?
Let's go and create a road.
All right.
And, yeah, so we need to make sure that we restart the server.
But as you can see, we have to start it anyway.
Start the server and let's go to route.
So we need to create a new road for posts, write blogs, blog, post, post, whatever we like to call
it.
If I use the name post, we will be using post name quite a lot, so please don't get confused.
Right
posts don't test
cylinders, just copy some of these file from category and put in the post just to make things a bit
easier.
So we got to import express x.
Sara we may need these middle words and leave them here.
Controller let me remove all that.
Controllers will be forced control.
Limit this common that out for now and we're just going to have one drought for now and that is going
to be upload is required sign in so it should be only for the logged in user and the user have to be
admin at the moment.
Later, we will allow the author as well, but at the moment just admin and let's call it upload.
Here is I guess we need to create this control function.
We can put that here and control us first.
Now we need to go ahead and create this file.
All right, so let's go controllers with new file post start to use.
Export combs.
Popular music comes from async.
Request response.
Try.
Cats are going to love the air.
Now, before we actually upload the image to Cloud Native, we need to configure clouds in areas so
that we can start using it, right?
So we going to configure using the values that we have in the and we find the name key and secret.
So first, let's import that baggage.
We.
Insert.
Found a new front go delivery and we're going to config load in every supply ordinary config.
So config this function we passed this value.
So cloud name.
All right.
A battle the process took in.
We don't count in every name.
All right.
So let me just copy this one more time based here and one more time.
So next one will be cloud and area.
Also API key.
Make sure you use the same name here.
So that's a code name.
That's API key and it's is here.
We called it key.
Next one is FBI secret.
And that is echoed in every secret.
That is all we need to start using plugged in every awesome.