All right.
So next feature we're going to work on is the list of uses for add ons.
So this is the finished product.
All right, so I'm here logged in as admin and when I go to users, all users here, I can see all the
users that I currently
have registered into this application.
So you can see here, here I am.
Here this is the.
Ed Neely.
So obviously I don't want to give my sources that is grayed out.
I can edit my profile or for any other user I can edit or delete their profile.
All right.
So we want to have a similar functionality into this app.
So let me just sign in as an.
So here at the moment, we don't even have the base.
So let's create a base.
Basically, what we want to do in that base is list out all the users.
All right.
So we show how many posts they have as well.
So we'll have to go back to our controller and make a small change so that we will be able to post the
post.
It is time the post is created.
So we're going to find the user and post that post, Heidi, to the user's post.
Something to add that feature so that we can show the number of post that belongs to the user.
Okay.
And then we'll have the.
So it fits as well.
Okay, so let's go first.
Let's quit that base.
So here, let's go into bases.
It is admin uses index.
So here we need some imports.
So let's import use this state used effect.
Use context to react.
Next one, we want to import the admin layer.
So import admin now from.
So we go.
One step up, two step.
Wants to do two, three step components and lay out next one.
We want to import some of these components from and really call them.
List.
And then Avatar.
So pretty soon we will be showing the avatar.
We will basically using just the you this name, the first character of the display.
You could display images as well.
So we use Avatar for the next film and next one excuse.
And we import toast as well just to sort of toast notification.
In bold.
He used it out a hook or two in need use rather from next strata so that we can read with the user.
We need the context of context as room and we also need link from next.
I guess in it's important that first impulse link from.
LIM And let's put the context in full
context from.
Context off.
I said, that's all the inputs we need.
Now let's create our component so we can pull that all uses, const all uses.
It's word function.
Exclude default function.
All uses this way.
I didn't have to write x for default underneath, so it's just a personal preference.
So here what we want to do is we want to first access the context, right?
So context, sorry, context.
Second set of set off from use.
Context of context.
Once we have the context, we can access.
We will need to access hoops later to redirect the user.
So we use that used article and then.
We are going to have a state, the local state, that wants a local state.
Where are we going to put all the youth?
So we're going to use you de facto to make a request to back in, get all the users and put them in
the state.
And then we're going to render the list of uses from the state and so uses state.
So once you have that, why didn't we use use effect?
Make a request to back into that we can get all the users.
Now, before I do that, let me just return something and let's return a layout and layout.
Had been loud in Ted Leo tweaking to use the rule instead rule to use an entire column.
Let's give it a heading has for all users gave me right before styling here style.
Mars in Barton.
Means to fix it just so that we don't have a lot of gap under the from the title and the list of uses
and we will see if we need to add this.
We can add Slater in here basically moving to a list of here this list of uses at the moment we don't
have any uses.
We can try the length.
Okay, so this is our component.
So obviously we're going to use use effect to get on the uses, but let's have a look how it looks so
far.
So this admin user.
Users write to that.
That is user syndicate.
So it should work.
All right.
So we got the input error model not found.
And we lay out that to be kept today.
Okay.
So looks like we have the path that is not quite so far from here.
Once they do step three step.
You go up and the components lay out.
And then left.
All right, perfect.
So we got a bit based on users at the moment.
We don't have any users to its do.