All right.
So we learned a little bit about one stack.
We had a look at this incredible application as well.
But what it takes to actually be able to build the application, not just that you will watch recording
and copy that, but also be able to understand.
Now, obviously, coding is not easy.
No, it's not like watching a movie, you know, it's watching movies pretty easy.
It's easy to understand the story.
You know, it it's straightforward how gaudi's not like that.
So even when you're watching me doing this, you might have to repeat ten times sometimes to get full
understanding of what I'm doing, right?
So it's different.
However, I'm sure you have the previous experience with JavaScript that's extremely important and the
basics of React.
This gets it.
This is the minimum requirement.
So when I say basics of React, if you know the basics, that means you know the basics of modern JavaScript
as it because React is basically a modern dance.
Could you use the modern JavaScript features, for example, instead of creating using VAR to create
a variable, you use LED icons, you use reference and quite a lot, right?
And so many other things like DE structuring.
And some of the new features that we will come across, for example, using map function to map through
the array elements, right?
So those basics that you use when writing react, could you need to have that understanding?
Because even though a month's tech will be earning from scratch, one stack stands for MongoDB Express
React in note.
So all these different technologies, different frameworks will learn to use all together to build the
robust full stack application.
So that process will be from scratch.
However, you need to have the understanding of modern JavaScript and react.
All right, now you don't have to know nodes first.
You didn't have to know MongoDB, Node.js and MongoDB.
It's going to be pretty straightforward and easy to understand.
I will be explaining is in every line of code, so I'm sure you'll be good in that six.
All right.
Now, of course, everything will be explained very clearly.
However, I have to emphasize that the knowledge of modern JavaScript and react is absolutely necessary
to take this course so that you fully understand.
And whatever I'm explaining to you, you understand, right?
So that's the minimum requirement if you have that.
Welcome to this.
Awesome journey.