All right.
Now that we have the context to make sure this is available for the entire application, let's input
in addresses.
All right.
So that's important.
We have to do structure use.
Sorry.
Theme.
Provider from the start up.
So we go one step up here in this level and then we go inside context and theme.
So that's how we get theme, provide it.
And then once we have that, we can to wrap.
So at the moment, we're just returning this default to all the component with the props.
So we just want to wrap it with.
In provider.
And we put that here beautiful.
And with this, we should be able to access the context values.
Theme and setting in our application.
All right.
So to give that a try, we could try in home the home base.
Oh, we could create a separate component and just import that here that we later we can easily import
that in our navigation and use that.
All right.
So let's create a component and we can call that toggle theme.
I guess so here, client, let's create a new fold called components inside here.
Let's create a file called toggle
double tin bridges.
By the way, you you will notice that whenever I'm creating any component, the name will start with
the capital letter.
But everything else will be using a locus.
All right.
It's only for the components.
Only for the components.
I would be using the uppercase name.
All right, so here we want to add that functionality to toggle the theme.
All right, so first, let me write a very simple component.
So import.
In fact, we may not even need to import React because I think with Nexis, you don't have to.
It is imported by default.
All right.
Let's create a component.
Let's call it
double theme equals two.
We return for the moment just to make sure that everything is working.
Let me just to use one and let's call it.
Double team component.
I just want to make sure that we can import it and have a look in the home base before we add that functionality.
All right.
So hue exposed and default toggle thing.
So let me just import this one in our home based.
Import double team from.
We go one step, one components.
Terrible thing.
All right.
And then let's put that here temporarily later.
We're going to put it in the navigation instead of home base.
But for the moment, since we don't have the navigation, we just put it here just so that we can give
it a try.
All right.
So let me put some land bridge here and then use that component double theme.
So we imported the theme and we put it here.
So this way, we can easily use the components here.
Okay.
So we can bring down to call if there is a lot of quarter we can bring down and put in a multiple component
and bring them all together here and build up a base.
I guess that's the beauty of React.
All right.
It's a double theme.
Let's see if we have and yes, we have that text is coming from that component.
So everything is working so far.
Beautiful.
So now let's go here.
Now, instead of here's one obviously we want we want to actually use the.
Icons.
We can use icons or we can use emoji, you know, like theme, dark theme for the moment.
And maybe we can even use a but simple, but why not before we actually implement the the emojis here?
By the way, it's really easy to use emojis in verse code and I think I should see, I say, let's go
install this plug in if you don't have it.
By the way, you could also copy the emoji from emoji.
Let me just write some email.
You can just copy paste from the website as well.
But obviously this takes a lot of work, so we're going to install that plug more difficult if you want.
You could just copy like that as well based here.
Okay.
So that doesn't work.
So they had this awesome copy.
Okay, then return.
Now let me use India and let me paste that here.
So this is how also you can use emoji.
I guess we've got that.
But obviously there's a better, easier way, which is using a plugin.
Let me show you that once that you can use circle command, command, sift beat or you can go
in.
So from here you can.
If you don't have the sidebar open, you can use command to to open and close and the school.
I didn't really use the menu.
I always use soccer.
But let's see if we can.
Find.
Come on, palette.
I guess that's.
Come on, Sophie.
So from here also, you can search for the plug in to the one we wanted.
Emoji.
Right.
So emoji.
And since I did have insulin, you can see it's already there.
But if you don't have it already installed, you can just use command to open the sidebar.
Click here and then search for emoji.
All right, so.
Extensions said click here.
Emoji.
And you can see this one I have already installed.
So this plugin will allow you to easily insert images in you could.
It's not very nice to install this plug in emoji and then once you have that installed command swift
e let me close this once you have that installed, let me remember that what I can do is command swift
feet again.
Same as you did before.
Good to.
What is that command palette?
Come back better.
All right.
So once you have it installed, you can type emoji and then click on into the music and then you can
just type, right?
So let me type something and you see, I get that.
So that is the full song.
All right.
So it's here.
So then you've got that food here.
Beautiful.
So that's how you can use Moses.
All right, so what we were doing is we wanted to add that functionality.
Now, before we do that, first we want to access the theme context, right?
That's the one we want.
So for that, we can use use context.
You can see we've been using a lot of these react hooks.
Use context from React.
And this hope will allow us to access the context.
All right.
So we have this hope.
And we need to actually import the context as well.
So if you remember, we have exported the context and provide the provider we import in averages and
left.
So that's all.
You don't have to import this provider anywhere else.
That's it.
It's done.
But in this context, you will be importing all the time whenever you need to use this context.
All right.
So let's import this one here.
Import in context from.
So we go one step of get inside context theme.
So we have this use context hope.
We have the actual thing context as well.
Before we start using it, we can
access the theme and then set team.
From use context and the give the venue theme context.
All right.
So this way we can use the global context state.
So let me quickly take you there.
So when we were creating this context, we have this local theme that's our local state for this component.
And for that, whenever you want to use local city, you use use state hook.
However, why do you want to access the the global context to use the use context and you pass the actual
context.
And that will give us the value here if you want to.
If you're curious, you can even try have a look at it.
So this is a disk so we can put those to port here.
So this way he can have a look into the value theme.
So let's see what we have here.
You can see current theme is light.
That's where you select.
So that means you have been able to access the global context.
All right.
So now if you turn this to dark, you can see send this to dark.
So that's absolutely beautiful.
You have been able to access the global state in your component here.
So awesome.
Now we can create a we use a button to.
Let's use a button.
Oh, we could make it clickable.
Right.
So let's actually make it clear.
I guess so.
Let me use.
Let's use fragments.
So this is something you're going to use and react to if you're going to react multiple elements here.
Then you can put them all together within these.
The syntax is called react fragment.
All right.
Because you cannot return to items.
Everything you want to return must be wrapped in this outside a wrapper, which should be just one.
But I'm going to inside this fragment so you can put your code.
So here we want to use this icon.
So let me use span tag for that span again, then another span.
And here I'm going to use that another half for the dog thing.
So command TV emoji inserting movie.
Let me use some.
This time I'm going to choose this half duct first for the moon symbol.
He is that.
All right.
So conditionally.
We would be sharing this one to end the click on this one.
We saw the light theme when they click.
And this one we saw the duct.