All right, so let's work on this handled summit function.
So here, when the button is clicked and the burden is click, we summit all that data which comes along
at the moment.
Let's it's coming down.
So here we use the axis.
So let's make request.
Oh, wait.
Excuse.
Let's make sure to make it a async function.
That's excuse.
Don't post.
So make a post request that the point is going to be we can call it create use.
And the data we are sending.
So all this sort of all consulates.
Email them.
Website passwords, role it.
So we're sending all that and using Axios.
And then you can console.log that if you're interested.
We check for the error if done a dodge error.
We want to serve that because we'll be sending the error message from the back end.
So tostart error we can certainly enter data and if we get an error set loading defaults now if there
is nowhere else.
So we can show the success.
Messi's toast success.
User created successfully.
We can show the misses and said lowering do false.
Okay.
So that is all we need to do.
No, you if you want to, you can read the user say here.
So once you create a user, you can redirect to all user space if you want to.
Yeah, I'm just going to leave it like this for now.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create the clear user endpoint in the backend and console.log request.
Wanted to make sure we got all this data and then if we get it, we can just save in the database.
So that's how we're going to create a new user.
All right.
So let's go to so.
The roots are.
So this could this endpoint create?
With youths surrounding how to boost.
Create user, so request and must the admin and we use this function quit user which we can import from
the school to the controller.
It's right as export concepts create user equals to async the request response.
So.
Yeah.
What do you want to do?
To clearly user first let's make sure we got under our control.
Law requires born.
It just doesn't seem.
So we got on the data.
That's great.
Now let's continue here with some of that.
So first, we want to make sure that we received all those fields to a name, email, password.
So we want to make sure we have received all of them so we can do some kind of for take here.
And then if we if if we didn't get those fields, then we can send the error message, right?
So if first of all, let's destock through these values from the request board is a name, email, password,
a rule to get from request party and then we take if there is no name.
If we didn't get the name, then we want to send the error message.
So response and Jason error name is required.
Okay, so that's for the name then just copy this one down here.
Now if there is no email, then we send this message.
Email is required.
Now, if you want to verify the email, there are some NPM packages you can use.
Let me quickly show you one NPM email validate.
So this one you can use.
You can even use it in the client side.
Okay.
So you import that and then you just use dot validated function and give the user inputs or whatever
email has been injured and it will take for the email from it.
And if it is very limited, you didn't.
This is optionally, if you interested, you can always take that out.
So we have the net take for the name, take for the email that's based one more time.
And then here we can take for a password.
Password first we make sure we have the password name.
If we have, we want to make sure it is at least six characters long.
So if password or password length is smaller than six, then we have to send our Mrs. password is required
and should be six characters long.
I guess we have the look for name, email and password.
Next one we want to take if use exists because you may want to create a new user flexibility a new user
with the email of Ryan at email dot com and but maybe that user.
Ryan at email dot com is already in your database.
You know, in that case you cannot duplicate user you know, so your email has to be always unique.
So we can take we can use the user model, find one to try to find the user based on the email from
the database.
And we put that value in this exist this variable.
So if it has value, so if exist, then we have to send some kind of error message to the user because
the email user with that email is under the existing right.
So in that case, we can send the error message.
Yeah, that's it.
Email is taken.
Now if.
So far so good.
If all the ticks have been passed, then that means we can clearly use it right now when we try to what
we need to.
We're going to save all this information, name, e-mail, password, everything.
Now, when we said the password, we need to has the password, right.
So we don't set the password.
So to has the password we can use the has password function which we import from the helpers and we
already used in the.
Sign in and sign a process you can see has password it has been imported from.
To help us find here if you want to help out here.
So this function will has the password and this one compared the bus.
Okay, so let's continue down here.
That's possible that if so that's possible we used that function to has the password
contest password host equals to.
Has password, we use that function and then we pass the blend password that we're getting in the request
body and that will give us the result which will be asked.
And that is what we get here in this variable.
All right.
So once it has the password, we can finally go ahead and recruit a user.
We try to create a.
So here what we want to do is we want to clear the users.
So we to new user create a new instance of user and actually we can use that saved to save the user.
Now here we have to give all the values that we are going to use while saving the user.
So we have to use limit the use.
You mean we're going to use password?
A password is going to be best password.
Last, but certainly to guard here.
Are we going to use the rule?
No ticket is not for saving in the database.
This is to take if it doesn't click so if the text is true, then we need to send the email as well.
Right.
So we going to work on this a bit later.
It's legal, so we save the role.
And we also have one more field called website.
Right.
It's a website I think we don't have in our schema.
So let's fix that.
And it's a good model.
So user name and password, tool or image, so we don't have the website if we want to save again and
site type of street.
All right.
So once you add that, you'll be able to save in the database.
So if there's a website, we said, that's.
Awesome.
Now, once we save the user, if the.
Then you want to send send email with login details, right?
So if text is true then you want to send the email to redeem to send the emails here will come back
to that.
Right.
So let me just write here for my if said.
We'll send an email to we'll come back to this one.
But otherwise, we can send the response now because the user has been created.
Right.
So when you send the response, you don't want to send the password, but you can send everything else.
So let's use the rest of the console password and then the rest of it destructor password and the rest
of the values from user don't on script go.
All right.
So in this case, we send the response, Jason, and that's going to be rest.
So the user has been created.
We are sending that created user as a response except possibly, I guess be sending the rest and that
is it.
So this is a function that Will said the user acquired a user with all this validation and only thing
left here is to send the email.
Now we will take that out.
We can give that a try.
But before we do that, let's actually give it a try.
Let's try creating a new user.
First, really try creating a user that already exists.
Let's see how we get there.
Mrs..
Passport.
It's.
If we just keep playing baseball.
Let's not worry about this one.
Let's make this also and let's submit images taken so you can see we have the validation.
So let's run the fourth.
I actually want to use a valid email address so that we can.
I can.
See how the email is sent to Ryan.
Let's use ma'am.
See Ms..
Okay.
To me, make him author and submit.
Oh, really?
That was a stigma.
Let me just try one then.
I think in the front end we still haven't.
Actually we have.
Controllers.
Let's console.log.
Let's see what we got.
This website is no different out of this thing.
So we can destock to offset as earlier.
Okay.
And let's try.
Let's try again.
He's a creative, successful, beautiful.
I think once users do we may want to redo it all you.
So I think that makes more sense.
But anyways, let's have a look here in the database.
Let's say I'm going to use.
We have to go to the very end and begin to Mancini this one.
So the user has been created as the website.
The root is also beautiful.
Awesome.
Now in the next video we can try sending an email as well.
So we'll see how that works.