Alright.
So let's use the Indigenous card component to display the post like this.
Thank you.
So let's in full card.
And from God we can destroy matter as well that will be used for additional information.
Meter equals to car.
Now you could use cardboard meter, but I'm struggling just to make things a little bit easier.
All right.
So here, since you want to make this position friendly, we want to have the basics.
And as soon it's important, six from next tend to have sex.
And if you knew to have sex and that is something like.
You can see the recent blog post on the tab.
Now, when you go here, you see a different attitude that controlled by the mirror information and
that will be read by search engine, says Watson.
If I show you The View based source, you can see this page has let me just find command f title.
So you can see the metadata.
That's the title and that's the description.
We had a description, this description.
This is really good for search engine optimization.
So we're going to use head section to have that information.
All right.
So here, let's start from the head.
So let's put that.
So he good to return the roll.
Let me just put it in the fragment
and let's put it here.
So inside here we want to have the most visible mirror information you can have is the title and description.
So let's call it recent blog posts I get to.
Let's go and then meta.
It's a matter of description.
We want to have a description and a let's call it a blog post about with web development, programming,
etc..
I you.
That's I have six.
And if you write Kivu episodes, you will immediately see that
I'm f title.
You can see recent blog post, the style and description.
We wrote that.
Okay, beautiful.
Now let's map through all the ports and destroy them in this nice card from any design.
So let's remove the pre and insert and I'm going to map through the posts
posts dot map.
I get it post.
So to use our function here so we return card
card component from and.
And inside guard we are showing the medal
and a title.
We can show
that we use postcards.
Now you can see here we have these beautiful cards.
They have the turtle.
Awesome.
Now, of course, we want to show the images.
So let's use we have multiple options here we can use.
The image's component of we can use Avatar component to display the images.
I'm going to use the Avatar component because that gives you really it's really easy to use and especially
it fits the the width and height, this killing of the U.S. So let's use amateur.
So inside this calling card, you can see here.
Here we can use all that information.
So here, hovering, we can make the card hover over.
So as soon as you do that, by default, that is true.
You can see there's a hover effect when you go into quality in this.
Thank you.
Next one.
We use code so we only for the cover images.
So here in Tacoma, you could use images.
You could use Avatar.
We using Avatar.
So Avatar will have this stick.
He's square.
We can use circle.
So seven square stone height.
You can give the height and based on height, the image will scale automatically.
So height 200 pixel source of the image is a source that's going to be post dot so you can see we're
getting it's supposed to dot featured image.
So if we have the featured image because some post may not have.
So we need to take that.
If we have the featured image, then we want to access the URL, otherwise you can to some kind of a
default.
The different images.
Maybe you can have one.
You know what?
Somewhere.
Let's see if we have any.
We don't have so we can have some image, then we can just float from there.
Oh, you can use some.
Now you are from the cloud.
So let me just leave it like this for now.
And then alternative day for the image so that it will be found by search engine.
So old it can be post type.
And that is pretty much all we need is come here.
Now, you can see here, beautiful.
We got these cards.
Now, the ones without the images, they are broken.
So obviously we can fix that by using.
The default are, but otherwise this one has the image looks skewed.
Now this one.
Let's fix that.
It's full with.
Okay.
So I actually noticed that we amendment through the post and the column actually should be inside,
not outside.
So let me just take that bit.
So we map before the card, we put that here and we also need to close
this map just right here after the closing card to put that here.
And once you have that column that you can remove from here, top.
Remove from the top.
Remove from here.
All right.
Now you can see it is taking the 16th.
Actually, it was my wrong calculation because I was planning this for the for the single post image.
But here it.
I was planning for this one, but obviously we're not on that phase with this on the post phase where
we're showing on the post.
So each of them must have, you know, like three columns.
So 83 is a 24, so it should be eight.
So let's send this to eight.
And if you want to, you're going to actually go for extra layers and extra.
So that will work for pretty much all the screen size.
All right.
So we don't actually need sidebar because we're not.
We're not going to sidebar here.
We just showing the Boston.
Okay.
Now you can see.
It's nice.
Beautiful.
This looks exactly the same as this one.
No.
The only thing we want to fix here is the images.
So if the car doesn't have the Mr. Bush doesn't have the image, then we want to do some kind of a different
images.
So let's quickly find a nice images here.
Let's go to Pixelmator.
We can get royalty free images here.
Two different one.
Then this was technology related.
Some kind of image for suitable for blog series.
Maybe we can use that.
Content management system.
Let's use this software developer
freedom.
Its choose this size download let's download directly to the project folder inside public so we can
go.
Udemy theme is client public.
So let's create a new folder images and inside here and just call it default.
Okay, now this is a good time for me to show you the there are the use case of public funds to anything
you put in type of default of for example, CCS images to many images.
So if it is intact public folder, you don't have to leave whenever you want to load that image.
So that's only in your basis.
You don't have to go like this.
One step, two, step up, three, step over.
You didn't have to do that.
If it is in, say, public folder, you can directly default to, for example, images less default
dot
unzipping or so.
You can directly refer to your images if it is inside public folder.
For example, my one is less images, less the name, so I can directly use that I don't have to go,
you know, like one step after step you don't have to write the path.
So that's the beauty of.
Using the public for you.
So the default URL, if the post doesn't have the featured image, then we want to show this default
one.
So that phone will be just that images default or two.
Okay.
Now, you can see here we've got this default image for all the posts that doesn't have its own image,
but this one has.
So we show the default.
We show that image.
Nice.
One more thing I want to fix that is you can see here we have a bit of a gap on top.
Let's quickly fix that up and we're pretty much done here.
On the top and bottom.
So it's kind.
Column.
I think we should.
Unpleasant study.
Go.
Monsanto.
Five.
Marlon Brando five.
Okay.
So that that gives us a bit of a gap.
You.
Okay.
So the next step is making it clickable.
When we click, we open this post in a new place where we can see all the information about the post,
just like you saw when we would take them to the single post base.
So we have the person who would have the Post slogan based on the title that was generated, right?
So we saw the images and we saw the post content on this matter information and we will later use this
sidebar to display some other information.
Okay.
So let's make them clickable so that we can show them our individual face.