So what are we going to do is we're going to use a state called Lori.
So use state.
I guess we create a learning state.
Loading said loading the used state by default will leave the value of false.
All right.
Actually, this time what we're going to do is we're going to have the default value of so by default.
But the learning will be true and we will not show any of this content if the learning is true.
You because you saw this from pure milliseconds, because when the component mounts, only then this
function runs.
So as a result, you get that quick glimpse.
So we don't want that.
So by default, we show some kind of a loading.
You could show empty space as well if you want.
But I think it's good to show some kind of a loading spinner or something like that.
And then we.
Do the stick and if the user is not admin, we redirect them to some other place.
Otherwise we send the learning to France.
I guess so when the loading is false.
We will sort this one when the loading is true.
By default it is true.
So when it's true, we just for the loading spinner, we don't show any content, but when it becomes
false, we saw this content.
So here we can do that as.
If it is not admin we redirect.
If it is admin then we sit loading to false.
I can now we can do some conditional rendering here and we can have the return before this return as
well, using some kind of a function.
For example, here we can take if loading.
I guess if the lowering event lowering value in the state, if that is true, we can show some kind
of we can return anything.
Maybe let's a hedge one, we can show a nice loading spinner.
But for now, let's just keep it at four.
All right.
So by default, it is always true.
So we don't show any content like before for quick milliseconds.
At that time we also loading you would show empty, empty bays as well.
So you just return empty.
You can do that.
But we showing returning the loading text.
But as soon as the set learning becomes false, we are showing the content.
So let's keep them track of issues.
Is not admin.
He tries to go to admin.
You can see we saw that loading and then immediately we are back.
So that meant we didn't show any content from the admin which which includes the the sidebar a bit.
So anything we are not showing, we just showing the load, we could just leave it empty as well.
I guess if you try by the way, let me use the white more be a bit easier.
And.
It's really fast.
It's hard to see.
Oh, actually, we're not slowing the loading, so we just saw the empty space and then we redo it.
So that way we avoid that issue of the swing, the content for a brief second, maybe slowly.
Loading and then home beauty.
So far so good.
Now, like I said earlier, this is not the most secure way of taking the value from the context or
the local stories.
So we're going to have another solution by making request to back in.
So we need to create the endpoint in the back end where we can to make a request to make to get the
currently logged and use it.
And if the currently logged in user is admin, then based on that response, we will do all this.
So if it is admin, then we set the learning defaults, we saw the content, otherwise we take them
to some other bits.
Okay, now before I finish this video, I want to show a loading indicator instead of this text.
And I can do that using the end design component.
So import loading.
Let me actually.
Have a look at the and ducks to make sure I'm using the right icon.
By the way when you here you phone just quickly source the site command key.
Then this up so I can.
Click here.
Also you can see we have the load loading spinner.
Maybe we can use this one floating out land.
All right, let's.
Loading our land till we can return then instead of floating.
Floating out land.
And if you want to make it bigger, better, maybe center in the base, you can do all that.
Let's use a CSO stone.
Let's say display, flex, justify content center, a line items
center.
And then we give this a height, height.
We give 100 feet vertical height.
And just so that we can see the loading.
We can said this two points just so that we can see that and go here and try to go to admin.
Oh.
Guess we've been redirected.
Um, let's come and escort out.
We just want to show if luring is true.
We want to show this one.
I guess we should.
Something.
We did something here instead of post.
Let's keep it true and keep it true.
Nothing's changed.
Only thing you have to do is comment this out just while we are taking this loading icon.
All right, so we give some CSIS.
And we commented this out so we don't get redirected so that we can see how this looks.
It's coming in.
Okay.
So you can see that loading.
Beautiful.
Now only problem.
It is a little bit small, but otherwise you can see it's a nice the center.
Horizontally and vertically.
It's quite nice.
Let's see if we can make that bigger font size.
Let's, um.
Let's say 50 bits.
Let's try.
Okay.
That's.
That's not bad.
Nice.
You can give it a different color if you want.
Maybe and maybe read this better because it's loading.
Awesome.
All right.
So let's turn this back to let's bring back the use effect.
All right, beautiful.