All right.
So we have the comment from that here.
So let's clear the state for comment and we can put put that in our post slug.
See him, let's add a step for comments.
So we need to have comments started as well.
So later the Post will have more than one comments.
All right.
So to put all those comments, we will need this state comment.
And while we are creating a new comment right here, whenever we creating a new comment to put that
user input for recruiting comment, we can have a comment, his comments.
So that's a single comment.
And this is plural to put all the comments.
You all right.
So comment, comment and
loading.
Comments loading.
We give the default value of false.
No.
We need a function to submit the comment.
So it's called comment as a contest post.
It's called handle submit.
Let's make it async.
So we tried to make a request to our backend.
Let's make sure we have x use.
Then here we make a post request
excuse don't post and we are sending making requests to comments less comment or comment.
I think it's comment we need to send the post 80.
Right.
So we have the single post.
We have the post so we can grab that idea from this post.
Don't underscore it.
So that's the URL.
And second argument is the content, right.
So we can send.
The comment.
Comment.
I can.
Let me make sure I'm accessing this correctly because I think I used content instead sort of comments
that in me quickly go to our server controllers post.
Content.
No, we're not creating content.
We're getting comment.
We're getting the comment in the request body.
All right.
So that means, I guarantee you the same name list that's calling new content.
And then we send this as a response.
I guess if we get the comment in the request body and then when you want to say a new comment, you
need the content that that content would be in our case, comment, request body comment would be the
content to make the sense and come back to our slug here.
I guess we send this comment in there, of course, Marty, and then we get the response data.
You can console.log if you want to.
And then once you get that newly created comment, we need to push that to the existing list of comments.
Who are we?
Right.
So said comment.
Existing comments can stay there.
And then we put that post that this newly created comment.
Now, if you want to put it in the front, I think that's definitely you want to put before the rest
of the comments.
I said that we will you'll be able to update the additional comments.
Then said Comment empty.
Once the comment has been successfully created, you want to empty the value from the step.
Then
you cancel the total messes.
Comment posted successfully.
Like you said at this point, he understood the certain loading to France.
So that means when we started, we could send it to Drew.
When we get the recipient who sent it to France and if there's an error that then also we said defaults.
So that's a hands on function we can use to boost the economy.
So let's make sure we pass these as props to comment form.
So comment the loading and handle summit.
We can pass them as props.
So you.
Comment.
And also Mitt.
And loading.
All right.
Now, there's one more thing we need here, and that is.
Making sure this is visible and for the long term user.
But actually we have the context here so we can do that.
Great comment from the input excuse.
Okay.
Looks like we only had one.
So on had one or two it.
You state to have.
Let's make sure we have.
All right.
So we didn't see anything at the moment, obviously, but.
We soon have.
Now we can always put some.
This industry first.
So first let's make sure we receive them first comment and and submit and then loading.
I can just.
Just for how?
Just so that we can view while we are developing let's do some street fight.
The comment.
We remove this layer, I guess, at the moment, and there's nothing there.
Okay.
So it's not operating the state.
That's because we don't have the the said comment, comment, all that here.
So we need to have that.
So let's make sure we have in fact, we need the set comment as well.
So let's go to this parent component.
So yeah, let's make sure we set comment as well so that we can.
Said common in the state.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
Common sense comment.
All right.
So here now a Texas area value is going to be coming in on terms.
We get the event.
So until we get the event we use at a function set on Monday in the state with the very event don't
target don't value.
All right.
That's right.
So we have that now.
We can try
AT&amp;T.
Now we are able to complete this state.
If we don't have the logged in user, then we don't want this form to be.
This wouldn't be able to type it in here.
Right.
So let me just open in a new window controls it.
You you can just do it from view and file new incognito window.
So you open that and go to localhost.
We visit one of the posts.
I can tell you, even when we don't have the London news, are they still able to enter something here?
So that's not something we want.
So what we can do here is we can disable this disabled.
And if I put true here, you can see it's disabled.
And I want that to be true only if we don't have the long term user.
So we can take our direct user and we have the authenticated user.
And that is not.
No.
That means we have to use it.
Right.
And we can have additional take off token is also that token is not didn't make it.
So if if token is not empty if we if the user is not not that means we have the logged in user.
Disabled.
It will be disabled when the user is not and when the token is empty.
Okay.
So off.
So we have the context.
We have an actual use.
That's an issue that.
Don't pass that off.
Use context.
Context.
Okay now you see we don't have the logged near the to disable.
However, here we have the logged in user.
So it is entertainment.
All right, so that's good.
Next one, we can work.
Actually, we can send the max as you.
In our back end, we have said the cactus to 2200, 200.
So we continue to send the max length.
For example, if we want it to be a length, no more than 200, then you can do that.
And with that, let me just try and copy this.
Now, you can see I cannot type anymore because it is 200 characters.
I said that's one way of putting some kind of edit is near to max length and then let's work on the
button as well.
So when the button is clicked, we want to submit this form.
So we want to execute the handle, submit fast and then button when it's a loading we want to show disabled
loading and so the loading indicator.
So we can use that.
On a page.
Handle Summit.
All right, beautiful.
So this is a common form.
Now, let's try
to submit the commandant and see what we get.
So in the parent compound where we are using this comment from, you can see.
We have the comment from in the when we submit the form, we are sending the post idea as well.
We have the comment as well.
So it should be good to let me open, inspect and let's try.
First comment.
Have a look at the network to hit post.
Okay comment says the post 80.
Payload.
So I guess we send the comment as a payload response.
As a response, we got the response.
You can see the auto auto generated I.D. content created dead posted by this user.
Beautiful.
Post.
Most ideas should be here for state.
I suppose you.
Both sides have beautiful.
Let's make sure we remove this dysentery fight.
So this is good.
We have been able to create a post, but there are a few things we need to fix.
For example, you can see when we get the response, we don't get the now the post by users hold the
information, we just have the I.D. so we need to use the populate when we create a new command comment
and we need to populate the user's entire information and then.
We need to get all the comments off the post as well.
So you can see, you know, when we are showing the Post, the Post doesn't have any comments.
All right.
So the existing comments also we need to have so that when the new one is created all together, we
can render all of them here.
So let's work on that in the following.