So let's go all the way down.
By the way, you told him that it's made dark, too good for hose.
I guess this is the example we want to use.
So let me click here, she recalled.
We had had a look at the consulate's copy.
Actually, instead of copying the everything, let me just copy the form again.
Because we already have the.
Component virtual it's the new swiftly it's Kobe the only good back kid in space that I guess you want
to save.
We need to make sure we have these imports.
So we need to import the form and.
Input and a button as well.
So let me go back to and let's see all the inputs.
So they this is where they have their input to make and to this copy.
This input to copy then.
I guess Alumina actually caught this as well.
Put all here.
Awesome.
Let's have a look.
Unfinished.
We need to have that function as well.
Let's write that const on finish equals two.
Oh, so.
And font.
This font gives us the value.
All right, so that's how we get the user input sorted with the type here in the form email password
that we will be receiving as values.
So that's what I was talking about it earlier.
We don't need to have our own state with and for we get the vendors like that.
So there's no need to have our own state.
I guess if we look into this, we can even try console long values.
We can have a look at these values.
Okay.
So you can see that we have this beautiful form out of the box.
Username.
Password.
Remember me?
Peter may know to use that to me a little bit.
We just want the sign up.
Oh, a link to log.
Right to.
We have the button and then a log and link.
So let me remove that.
Remember me a bit.
It's not a bad forward pass version of this.
We will have this feature, but not here on this basis.
We will have it in the log base, log in.
Oh, which I won't actually have a land break here.
Everything goes down.
Beautiful.
So we got the name password.
Okay, so let's try to understand this form first so we can see from it as the name, class name.
Initial values.
So you can give initial values.
So by default it is empty, right?
But you going to give some initial values.
For example, we have the user name listed as to just name, I guess the name.
And you can see there are rules as well.
It's not mandatory, but if you have it, then you can show the error message.
If they try to submit form without entering the values, which is pretty cool.
So please enter, you know, let's see.
I guess if it is.
M.D. We saw this Mrs. and this field input field.
That's what you see here.
That's the input field.
And this field has the ICAM.
Right?
And the placeholder is in there so that.
Coming from here, sir.
The prefix with this item is outlined.
And the placeholder is the username.
All right.
Now send me the password.
We have the password.
The item.
And when you use the type password, it will automatically hide the inputs to you if you want to see
again.
So that in if you don't have any values, it'll get that error.
Mrs..
Same with the username if you make it empty so it will show you this warning.
It's pretty cool.
Now, we used to see the item here that we could allow the user to see the password that was.
I saw that in some of the examples and we just go all the way to the top.
So this one you can see the using this one.
So let's take it out how they did.
So the password.
The used input dart pass for you so that you can access this proper password.
So let's try using that.
So we've got the input dots.
Let's try using this.
I guess if you do that, you get that.
Beautiful.
So that's cool.
So you got the name password.
Let's add one more fill for email.
One more fill for email and let me think the documentation.
They might have the email specific input, which will look for the valid email format to be taken out.
They might have.
Name to who triggered this example?
Four.
So you've got the e-mail label, e-mail rules type email.
I guess if they didn't have.
Anything specific.
However, we can apply this to rituals.
Let's grab that rule.
I guess.
Let's go back.
So we got the name from Ida.
So we have to copy that.
So let me just paste this rule that it copied just so I can use it later.
From item to limit.
Copy this.
And just put it on.
I think I want to write a bit of commentary.
It's easy to read.
So this one's for the name, but this one's for Emile, which I'm going to paste here, and this one's
for posterity.
Just to make it a bit more easy to read.
Also, the email name will be email rules.
So the rules and I want to apply this rule for email.
That email server room we put here.
It's removed that and replaced with the one we copied.
Email soon.
User outlined placeholder email.
So this item for the email we can use, we can use this envelop.
Outline.
I think we have that.
I can tell it's important here.
Envelop
envelope outlined for me.
Copy that.
And for the E.M., it's a place that with this.
Looks like that one doesn't exist.
So it's always good to just search in.
Red envelop.
Okay.
So it's not even late.
It's called, I think, Messi's not Messi's.
This should be this should have.
Let's quickly have a look.
This should have some kind of four male.
Mail box type if I can.
This should have let me see what I used.
I guess that is the one.
Let me search you, Mel.
Okay, so that's the Mel outline.
So it's men and.
Thank you.
Thanks to the two men outlined.
Copy.
It's called the on top.
Replaced this one.
Beautiful.
All right.
So we got the phone name, email, password limit in place for this one for using name.
Send to name
the name.
All right, beautiful.
Let's see.
Let's have a look at the console.
Since this is and is an forms you can see on finished.
This function executes, it gets the values, and we can just access that without having our own state,
which is pretty cool.
Let's give it a try.
Let's try the name Brian.
Brian.
And okay, so we have the email format as well.
So if it is not email format, it will show that error message also.
All right.
So let's try and log in so you can see I'm console.log in the valley.
See, everything is coming up here.
If I come to Atari and click the button, you see, we have that form.
Guns along the valleys.
You can see we have access to the other info.
You have the name, email and password.
Beautiful.
This is good.
Now we can have the similar form, pretty much the similar form in the sand in bays as well.
So this will be for registration and another one will be for logging.
I guess that means I think we have to change this to register and this one, we make it look nice and
let's make it clickable as this when they click, we take them to sign in base.
All right.
So let's come here.
By the way, then once we have the sign in base as well, and then we'll come back and work on this
function.
So basically we can use X's to make a request to back in to send this data to the backend.
But before we even do that, we have to set up our own back in the API.
Otherwise, you know, we don't have any API server to send this data right now.
Building API from scratch is a lot of work, but there's a quick and easy solution, which I will be
showing you, which is very exciting.
All right.
So let's since this takes button takes to register and if they have already registered, they might
want to go log in.
So it is to log in now and make it a clickable link to swiftly remove that since we are using and next
this was got we use the link component from next and paste this and get that.
So history will be here.
Simon.
Logan.
We take them to signing.
Now, let's not forget to import the link component as well.
Empowered Link from next.
I guess I did one mistake here that is I destructor.
If you're coming from the react rather if you have been using react with react by default, you might
destructor.
If you do that it will not work with this and you get some weird errors which can give you quite a lot
of headache.
I always make sure to just import like this because this a default export.
All right, so everything looks good.
We'll come back to this space once we have our service set up.
But at the moment, we're pretty much done with our sign up.
If you want to go to sign in, we have that same sign.
Let's work on the sign in as well.