All right.
So we got this.
Ed, let's try to fix a few things.
For example, you can see this icon is pushing out.
So let's fix that.
So I think what we need to do is we need to give it a certain width.
All right.
And then on the sidebar, we will have a few other things.
For example, preview button, publish button option for uploading the image, things like this.
We will put on the the small column.
And then here we will have this editor.
All right, so let's come here.
So now we have the editor instead.
I'm going to.
Clear the rows and columns.
It's got and it's used to rule
in set rules.
It's used call and put that content back here in the column.
Let's make sure we have the rows and columns from end.
So this column I want to divide.
So let's use this spend 16 I guess a total of 24 column groups.
So we give this column 16 and for the sidebar we can give it a span of eight, two, eight and six,
and all together it will be 24.
So let me just write this sidebar for now.
It's going to have a look.
Okay.
So we got decide where we got that one.
We should have a bit of a gotcha quarter or whatever we called it previously.
That base we were working, that was categories, right?
So here if you have a look we have built for gap.
So that's that's how we want to.
Wanted to look here in the great new year as well.
So let's quickly have a look at how we did the categories.
So the column we have the Rose column.
So this is how we did it.
So on the small screen, we give it a full width and.
It's very small and small.
In the last one, we split, so we give it.
We give it a.
Ten offset to altogether 12.
So we split into half.
So what we want to do is we want to use offset.
And if you care about the very small screen, then obviously you can use these values as well.
So offset.
So that's what I want to use you.
Spent.
So let me go back to Categories Index.
I guess they sold us offset.
So let's use this article and forward it and then we will have offset one on both sides.
So altogether six.
And same here.
Let's give it to any of six and offset one.
Okay.
So let's see how this looks.
So we got this beautiful space that looks good.
The next one we want is the size 30.
It's too small.
So let's make it kind of big.
Something like this one.
So let's make it look something like that.
And we should have this icon also inside this box.
So the editor we have here, first of all, let's fix the theme.
So when we go dark, let's make it dark.
When in light it is light.
All right.
So for that, we have to access the theme context, its existence, import
theme of context from one sentence, 232 context theme to use context, let's import use context to
import use context from react are then we can use that hook, you know, context, context.
So we want to do structure theme.
So theme set theme from use context and we give the context that is theme context.
Awesome.
Now we should be able to access the theme.
If I have a look at it gone to long theme, we should be able to see the theme in the console is created
to give that a try.
So you can see it's currently light.
It's light.
If I turn this, it becomes dark.
It becomes light, I guess, if that's how it works.
So we get the value from the context, which is great.
So let me remove that consumer.
So we're going to use that value to dynamically change the background of this editor.
So previously we so it takes this box dark and then if we give it a value of true, it becomes dark.
If the value is false, it becomes flat.
Okay, so let's try to turn this dynamically.
So what are we going to do?
Here is the one we have in the context, if that is equals, equals equals light.
So we have the two themes, light and dark.
All right.
So if it is light, we want to set value to false.
Okay.
So we need to use the donor.
So if it is light, we set it to false.
So if you give the value false to dark, then you see the light integer, right?
So if we have the light thing, then we want to use the light editor.
So we give it the value false.
Otherwise we should.
That suit dynamic the tensely dry he can too in a good dark dark it becomes dark.
When I go to light, it is light.
Beautiful.
Now let's add some padding.
You can see it is the content is up to the very is.
Let's add some styling.
So here editor, let's use some style.
By the way, actually, it's not going to work in.
You can't apply the styling here.
Instead, we have to find out the see if this class name this editor is using and we have to apply some
here.
So let me open the inspect,
go to element.
He's just here.
And let me right click on this one, this particular element, and click inspect.
That takes me to this element you can see here.
So I'm trying to figure out the wrapping.
Do you?
So this you can see this is using the class name of Bruce Miller.
So this do we want to target this?
So let's take this class now and we can apply some see assists to discuss them.
Now I have this plug in the addon in in my Google Chrome.
So it's not mandatory.
You don't have to have, but it is helpful for trying out some live cases.
For example, to this class name I can write some C assume that you will see applied immediately here,
which can be very helpful.
So if you want to install this ad into your Google Chrome, you can go to Chrome Extensions Chrome Web
store and you can use the one that is called Live C.
S as editor.
Life, she said.
Which one is the a lot?
That's the one I'm using.
I think the this is the one.
So you see, I have this option removed.
So this is the one.
If you want, you can use.
It's nice and easy to use and it's very helpful.
Ah, so I'm going to target this deep with a class named macros pros.
Let's try.
So let's say height.
We want to give it a bit of a bigger height, let's say 200 pixel.
I guess you can see you mean deletions change barely padding top and bottom.
Let's say we want 15 pixel and right and left
for this icon to be inside the body.
Let's say 25 picks.
All right.
So that looks
awesome.
Okay.
And what else we can do here?
So this is the editor and let me try border radius.
I think that will do for the moment to discuss this studying and copy and go to your thesis for other
studies or to assist in this.
But that here I come, here you may need to restart sometimes.
Okay, so we've got this beautiful now, atria.
We can die.
We have this thing inside.
Okay, now, if I told the theme, I guess that looks good as well.
Beautiful.
There are few more things we want to do.
For example, this valley we want to put in the state.
All right.
So this time, we are going to use the, um, the desert form component.
We could, but we're just going to use the input field for the title and then we have the series editor.
So all these valleys we want to control and for that going to have our own state.
And so we need to use the user state hook put all the value from this end is for whatever user types
and we take that value put in the state.
And for that we can import use the state hook and here let's write
the screw in our state so we can call that const.
We can call that content said content.
You can still use state.
All right.
So when the value changes, we can put that value here that we later when we have all the information,
for example, the content, the featured images, the post title, all that, all together we can send
to the backend and we can save that in the database.
So we put in the state.
Previously, if you remember in the categories and sign in and sign a basis we were using the end isn't
from component and that had its own state and that would give us the values on finish function.
Right.
But this one I said will work a little differently because we're going to have our own state.
So let's come down here.
So this editor, whenever you get user input, the value changes on terms we can do the error function.
It's on change, you get the value and then you can control of the value just so that you can see or
to get.
Before we try to put it in the state.
So let's have a look at terms.
Now let's console.log.
One
thing you actually return valid only the function we get in control.
Okay.
So that's that's the tricky part on this one.
You can see we get only the function in reality.
We have to execute this function.
So the way it works is this value you see on until you get the value.
That value actually is a function.
So you have to execute that and that will give you the actual value.
I guess it's a little bit tricky.
You can see you.
To do that.
And this time it comes in.
Beautiful.
So instead of canceling now we want to put in the state now to put in the state.
All you have to do is sit content.
That's all you need to do, right?
Now, once you do that, if you're curious, you can file for a temporary use.
We can just have a look at it.
Pre session street fi content.
No.
Four.
Let's have a look at what we have in this state.
You can see I see the time and the line breaks are then a swarm in.
Make it bigger.
You don't see it when you don't see the actual heads table because this is a markdown markdown editor
but it will render.
Has Tim went on the base?
I guess that's beautiful.
So we cut the content.
What do we type in that is put in the state?