All right, so let's log in as this hates the root and we need the IP address, which you must have
answered.
This is the one to copy that.
Based here.
So we're going to log in by using our services.
Or so it will ask you, Are you sure you want to continue continuing?
You just say yes.
Hit enter.
Okay.
Now you need to give the password.
I'm pretty sure you have.
You remember your password you used earlier in this global.
Again.
That's from.
Okay.
So you can see I'm logged in as a root.
So the first thing you want to do is you don't want to continue using the root.
This is not recommended for security reasons.
So you're going to create a new user, you're going to create a new admin user.
First, you going to just go to user and then give him a role of admin and then you will every time
you log in, next time you will log in as that user instead of root user again.
So follow these steps line by line and be very careful with this.
And if you miss one step, things can go wrong, right?
So this is the first step we did that logging basis is now add new user because you don't want to continue
using root user.
So add user and you can give this user any name.
Here.
I have given the name FSA admin.
Probably here.
I want to give the name.
Let's.
Let's use the same name, so it's much easier.
All right, so we added this new user, FSM, right?
So given password, you can continue using the same password that you created earlier if you want to
do so that it's easy to remember.
So retype that one more time.
Okay.
Now, these questions you don't have to answer so you can just hit.
Enter, enter, enter.
Enter.
Enter and hit type Y and hit enter.
Perfect.
Now this new user has been added by the name of Eva's admin.
Now just adding the new user doesn't make any difference to this user.
We need to give him the admin ability.
Right?
So make this new user admin, make him admin.
And this is the command to make admin to user mode.
There's a D.
Studio if as Ed.
So this user has become the admin user.
So not yet added admin to the sudo users list.
So sudo basically means superuser.
So added to the sudo users list.
So sudo as u f is admin.
Okay.
Now, this admin, this user is the admin user now.
I guess that means we can nix them from next time.
We can log in as this user and not a root user.
Instead, we should disable the log in ability for this user for security reasons.
All right.
So here you can see try exit and log in as FZ to see if it works.
So first you want to make sure it works.
Then if it works, then you want to remove this root user and log in as the.
FSA admin this new user for from now on from every time you try logging again.
All right.
So let's try first.
Let's try to control C one more time
controlled C, I think I have to try it.
Okay.
One more time.
I did.
I guess I'm out.
He can see I'm out.
Clear.
Everything all right?
So let's try again one more time.
Now, this time, instead of a route, we want to log in as if as admin the new user with admin draw
that we created.
I could give the password.
Okay.
So that's crude.
You can see you can log in as this user that squared.
Now the next thing you want to do is remove the root user.
So root user cannot log in.
That's recommended to remove root user.
So we have to go to this file and make some changes so you can do sudo vim espace and then s+ etc..
SS hates ss hates d config.
So we have to go to this file and we need to give the password.
Okay.
Now this file you can see to edit this file, you can press a, press a, then you see this, insert
word and then you can use up and down, right and left arrow keys to navigate around.
So go all the way down until you find the line that says Permit root, logon and turn that from yes
to not.
So let's go all the way down and you can see permit route logging it is currently.
Yes let's change that to no.
No, no.
Once you make any changes into this file to save and exit, you can use the escape.
You can person that escape tab in a keyboard and then colon.
W.
Q This is really important to you.
You want to remember that again?
I have written that here as well.
Thank you.
Now, to make sure the all your changes were successfully applied, you can try this, I guess.
Let's try a pseudo service.
SS heads restart.
I guess it has been restarted.
That means the.
What the changes you've made that is applied.
No.
So now if you tried to log in as a root user, you shouldn't be shouldn't be able to log in.
So you might want to give that a try.
Let's try that exit again.
Now, let me try again.
Just use I've been known Iraqis to go to the previous commands and let me try log in as root user.
Let's see if I can still logging.
Okay.
You can seek permission denied.
So that meant with root user, I cannot log in anymore, which is great.
Now let's try and log in as the the admin user episode.
And we can log in.
That is perfect.
Now, next thing you want to do is push your local projects.
You have two projects.
One is the server.
One is the client of both projects.
You want to push to GitHub.
That way we push from our local to our local computer.
We push this code to GitHub.
And from GitHub we will pull that code to digital also.
Okay.
And this is what you will be doing every time later when you make some changes, when you make some
updates to your code.
You will do the same thing.
You will post, make the comment, the changes to GitHub, post the changes to GitHub, and then you
will pull that changes from this license over here.
Okay.
So that means we need to create git repository for client and server.