All right.
So let's continue working here.
So we want to show some content.
So we've got these images here.
So right after the emails and it's great to know that did.
And here in David is right.
Let's use H1.
Let's call, it seems.
Let's use paragraph and here let's call it content management system.
And then we also use a button to the let's import button from and
import button form and and then let's import I can handle to use with the button import send outlined.
I come from and icons and then let's import link as well from next link.
I.
So here, let's put that burden.
It's okay to be a burden.
Let's go explore here.
We just make it a link.
So let's actually cut this one.
Put it into a link.
Put into a.
Based that here in the link requires.
So history of.
Lisa Sylvester.
So any user who loves him, they will get this decimal subscriber, right?
So we take them there.
But if the user is not logged in, then obviously they will get redirected to log in base automatically.
Right.
So go this button.
Now let's have a look.
Now you can see we have this content.
Now what we want to do is we want to put some apply some styling and put it right here on top of the.
So for that, this day we do our best and stuff.
Here we use we want to send to the contents of text line center.
Let's add a bit of a margin margin to,
let's say -400 for 20 pixel.
Foreign sites.
One says, let me use 75 big so and then they just said, oh, I want to use a bit of a tech, so to
speak.
So.
To be so.
So horizontally and vertically.
We applied the saddle and then the blur for pixel.
And then the color.
We just use black.
All right.
As you can see, it's already there.
We have applied some margin.
Don't send to the text.
Apply some CC into.
So that looks pretty good.
Now, this content, this gap, we don't need that big.
And then this content.
We want it to be mid small.
So had to run.
What are we going to do here is apply.
Actually, we don't need to apply any thing on this one.
That's fine.
The paragraph stuck.
I want to make it smaller.
Font size.
So font size.
It's a 18 pixel.
Margin talk.
I want it -150 picks and probably that should be a right color.
I think is fine just by default.
And.
Okay.
But that's a bit too much.
-150.
-200.
It looks good.
And we've got the button here.
Let's give it a type primary.
Size.
Last.
And then.
What we can do here is we can use the icon and one icon.
Send our plan, we use that icon and then this link that we have.
Yeah.
I think we need to really do anything in this.
Good.
If you don't like this most space, you can use margin dope, negative value.
But I think it looks pretty good.
My family here, we take them to the subscriber base because the user is logged in.
But if not.
And if they click here, they will get redirected to.
Log in page.
This should be redirected logging.
Let me.
Let me see.
Why is that happening?
Let's go to.
So that would be insert components layout, subscriber layout.
So if we have the authenticated using token, we run this code.
And if we get the data, we set the loading defaults.
Otherwise we take we reader to home base.
Okay.
So I realized that we have to do some kind of redirect.
Maybe we can use said interval.
So start the countdown, maybe a couple of seconds, and then we redirect the user to our home page,
the log in page, whichever piece we want.
Okay.
Because it is very secure.
You know, we do we're not showing the content, we showing the loading.
But obviously that doesn't help because we can just show loading.
We have to redirect the user after showing loading for a few seconds.
We want to redirect the user.
Right.
So we can create a component.
In the next video, I'll show you how we can create a component that will show the loading for a few
seconds and then redirect the user to any page you want.
All right.
So instead of this icon, we can use that loading to redirect component so that we saw the loading for
a few seconds and then we'd redo it.
So we welcome that.
But otherwise, you can see so far we have already started working in the home.
Looks pretty good.
RC Let's see how we can fix this issue.
Let's see how we can redirect after showing learning for a few seconds.