So we've been able to simply using the date this now let's do some work here so that we can show some
error messages so some trust notification and do some redirect.
Right.
So here you saw we give the response data.
So instead of accessing always like this, you can always destruct done and that way you can just use
the value sort of we got to use it.
And the token as a data you can use it.
All right.
So destructor data strategy, you can console.log if you want to.
We already saw the console, so let's do that instead.
Now we want to show the some kind of a notification, whether it's a success or error message.
Now, you can see here.
If we don't get the name email password, a password is less than six out as we are sending all these
error messages.
How do we display this to the user?
That is something you can take you to if data.
So there is one standard error.
If we getting some error, we can show the error message you because you can see you.
In the back end, we are sending the decent response with the key error.
Every time there's error, we sending the key error and it has this different value.
So we can always access this error if there is any, and we can show this error message to the user.
Right.
So that's what we are doing here in the client.
If that added error.
I get the data?
What are you going to use the syntax as well?
Sometimes when you try to access error, you might get, you know, the error message saying that error
cannot you cannot access error properly from undefined, something like that.
So you can only take if data and if it if data has the error properly, only then do you try to access
this.
And this could also be written like written like data and tangible data.
If you could do this as this way also you could check, but this one is better.
Build this server nice and easy to write.
So the syntax.
So if we have downloaded error, we can.
So the error message, for example, you can use the trust.
React to this toast photo and you can display the error misses which will be data don't enter right.
I guess so.
That's forever.
Not if it wasn't, there was no area else.
Then we get to the Starbucks, dismiss it, and it's a toaster success.
Da da da.
In fact, if it is successful, we in this harcourts from something like successfully signed up.
All right.
And then what else we can do here?
We can.
Redirect the use it to another base.
For example, log in, please, if we can do that right.
So we can immediately redirect the user or we can delay using the set timeline.
In our case, I think it's better to just redirect straight away.
All right.
So if you on redirect.
We can use the link component from.
Next year.
In fact, link is not the right one.
We have to use the road so we can use the user hook from next year to navigate to a different route.
Now, before we do that, let's just give it a try.
It's how this toaster works.
Now, Victoria, how are you?
This will not work unless you have this push component in your written, written block here.
All right, so you can put that anywhere.
It doesn't matter, but you have to have.
So let's put that just on inside the column.
Just.
I want to make sure you have this component and then you should be able to foresee the success Mrs.
or Mrs. Smith scheme to try.
Now one user name is Ryan.
Ryan and continuing to.
But this user has already been created, which means if we try to register another user with the same
details, we should get the error message right.
So let's see how that works and try a district and you see email taken.
Now that beautiful touch misses is because of this react tortoise.
All right.
So we are showing that standard error.
So we saw that email is taken message that is coming from our server here.
And if you do exist, then we sending that error message.
I guess that's how we saw the errors.
Now, if we tried to create a new user then it's we should see this success misses.
So let's try trying to do.
It's true.
And this time successfully signed up because it has been.
It is such as?
I see.
That's beautiful.
You saw how you could show the notifications.
Now, one more thing we can improve here, and that is you see this toaster?
Now, this toaster is not something you want to just import and use an essential component writing sign
in and later doing the push to create push delete everywhere.
You would need this just notification, but you may not want to just import Ethan every time and just
put in your render written block, right?
So that's a bit of a hassle.
Now there is a shortcut, there's a solution to avoid doing this and that is bringing this into emergences
like you already know, after this gets initialized, before any basis in there in this next application.
So that means we can import that to send put here.
That means whenever we use the toast function it would work.
We didn't have to just have on it's an every components the written book so let's remove this one.
Let's remove this one.
Let's remove this one as well and instead put that in underscore app.
Okay, now before I.
Write it here.
Let's see how this works.
How this makes a difference.
So you can see.
Let me try.
Ryan.
By the way, if you don't like to keep writing this while we are testing the application, you have
to do that all the time.
So in that case, you can just hardcoded the default value as well.
I so.
I would say that in the next component, when we go for the signing, it's Ryan and the team input.
Okay.
So we got the MREs for that.
You can take the network that always I showed you earlier.
And here you can see response payload of the has where the request was made.
All of that now in the response, you see we got the images taken out of MREs.
However, we're not showing here.
That's because we don't have the torso component most of its go to AB and just equal to that hint in
both those two from pre and post and then we can put anyway so let's put underneath the now.
You may need to restart your averages.
In some cases hopefully shouldn't be required.
But in case you don't see your toes to make sure to restart.
Yeah.
Because otherwise it's a good excuse to try.
Ryan, Ryan and Tim Duncan.
Okay.
Now you can see it works.
You don't have to now import the torture component anyway.
You just import toast and just to use in your functions.
That's easy.
Now, if you give the password only just two characters less than 6 hours, then you get this in a message.
So all these messages coming from our banking.
No, that's nice.
I guess we did that as well.
The next thing we can do is show some kind of a lowering, right?
So when it's happening, when read, maybe you want to show some kind of a lowering, it will take maybe
less than a second, but still, it's a good to use a good UI.
And so you might want to show some kind of a learning window, especially with and design some button.
It's really easy to show the learning.
All you have to do is use this learning property.
All right.
So here.
That's the burden we're using.
So if you use loading too true.
We can use the value.
True or false if you used.
See, you can show the loading spin.
So that's beautiful.
And that time button is not clickable, as we can see.
It's not clear.
So we can, instead of hard calling the value, we can use the loading state from our.
Component here so we can create a state here.
And for that, we can use the use effect to.
So let's import that use.
So you state to try and react and then we can create a state followed const learning set learning which
to use state and we give the default value of false.
So by default it is false.
But when we make a request to our back end, we send it to true until we get the response.
Now that response could be error and a response.
So custom response doesn't matter.
When we get the response, we set it to false.
But until we get the response, when the function executes, when the user clicks.
But we haven't received the response yet.
So doing the so we want to set the loading right so we can do that here.
First thing you do, sit loading to too.
As soon as this function executes, which is when the form is submitted right on finished when the button
is clicked, this function executes and immediately we set the loading to true and then wait for the
response.
All right, so if we get the error response.
Set learning difference.
Right.
And if we get successful restaurants, then also we set forth.
We saw the success.
Mrs..
And who said it to us.
Now, if we catch the network error, any other time you want to send it to Fox.
And I did so in the beginning.
True.
As soon as we get any response, we send it to Fox.
Now, with this, they're lowering the value in the state will dynamically change.
So when it is true for those brief milliseconds, you'll see the spinner.
Otherwise, it will just work as normal.
So we can try that.
Ryan, Ryan and Jimmy the gun.
This made me very quick to have a look here.
That's so quickly.
We don't we barely see anything.
Okay.
So just to show you, it works.
I guess it works in production.
It may be a little bit slow, so you can see that.
But just to give it a try, let me go to the network Dev and let me.
Make man speed, slow throttling.
I can make it fast 3G.
So it's currently, I think 4G 5G.
So let's make let's make it with sleep.
By the way, you didn't have to do it.
I'm just doing this to show you so you could try.
Now you can see it took a little bit of time to you doing that time because the network were slow.
You saw this finish and then it's so beautiful.
Now, if you create a new word, let's use right through right three.
Beautiful.
So we did a couple of things here.
We so we learn how to use the toaster to throw the toast notifications we would the toaster component
in our everyday so we didn't have to import an essential component.
We also learned to implement loading.
Now we're pretty much done here in the same.
Later we might come here once we have the global context so that when we get this kind of response,
the successful response.
Yeah.
Maybe we want to use that, but in the global state.
Right.
So that is something we can do a little later.
But at the moment it's fine.
It's all good.
Now we can move on to signing component and implement something similar.
And doing the signing.
Once the signing is successfully completed, then we have to think about what are we going to serve
that the user and the token that we got from the back end to that recipient.
Where do we put right so that we can create a global context, just like we had a previous context for
theme, something similar we can use to store the user value globally, right.
So that we put in attend the base reload sees a comeback in our application after closing it.
We will always be able to saw that user in for Ms. and we should be currently logged in.
Right.
So let's move on to signing.