All right, let's go to the back end.
And you can see we are making a to object to by admin.
Let's create another one.
Another out called object user by.
By anyone, you know, object user by user, we can call them.
So let's go to server.
Wrote us a copy, then placed him a bill to use it by user if we are signing.
This is the one we need to remove.
That's the issue of the user by user.
Okay, let's write this function.
Okay, let's go to this controller.
Now, that will be very similar to abilities of admin so we can copy this function properly.
We've done here and the difference is going to be obviously it sends the name to by user and here what
do you going to do?
Is we going to check if.
This user use user from DV.
So if this user and the logged in user is simply because we want to make sure only the users are updating
their profile, not everyone else's profile.
So here.
I think if you do it himself or herself.
Right.
So of course.
So you're not going to take if you are from DB
if you are from DB and we compare the I.D. I.D. to string equals equals equals.
This use not equals.
So if you use it from database, that user side does not mess the currently logged in use society.
Then this user is trying to do something wrong, right?
So in that case, we can send we can send response status.
Well, actually we are showing the JSON response we could send there.
Mrs. Response Status 403.
Don't send your content.
Well, you can.
You, Jason.
You're not allowed to use it.
We can send something like that.
So that will prevent the user from doing anything extra, anything that I get.
But otherwise, everything else can say, Listen, I guess we have the validation, we have the profile
update.
Everything is fine.
You just have to do that.
Beautiful.
All right.
So that means now back to our page here.
Now, you can see if this profile page is being accessed by user other than admin, then this turns
to user.
Otherwise we it should be admin.
So let's try to pass this value here.
Let's try to pass this value either admin or user edition that we can make this dynamic.
All right.
So let's go to this profile of dead first and here.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to destroy the base.
And by default, we use and so by default, we will assume that the profile update component will be
used for admin, right?
So by default assignment, that's fine to use this base variable.
And you know wrote admin this part just the end product we replace with basis I guess so by default
or bridge user by admin it will be because the is different values admin.
However, whenever this component is being used in.
Here.
You can see not in the ad, but in the author and subscribers.
We will give the different value so that the request will be sent to different abilities and by user.
So that's how we are going to make it dynamic.
So I mean also add here we can fast the dynamic properties and this time we give user sort of a value
give that where the request will be sent.
And we want to do the same for a subscriber.
All right, beautiful.
Now, if you are a subscriber, also, when you submit this form, it will be sent to.
Update user by user.
In that way, it should work.
All right, so let's try this.
Use software to run the images and then.
Let's say I want to give them a name like that website.
Ryan Genuine Dotcom Subscribe now.
Okay, so there are a few things we have to do very soon.
Allow the user to change the rules from here.
Again, they should submit.
It works again.
It works.
And if you take here helps you can see the request has been sent to.
Update user by user.
All right, so that's good.
It works.
Now let's fix a few things.
This rule option shouldn't be here.
And for subscribing, we should show this media as well.
So subscriber will not have this functionality because they cannot upload the file.
They're going to speak from the media library.
If you want, you can leave it, but we will not allow them to update.
So let's come here
just for a security reason.
You can see this.
Even though we disable this field, users could be sending their rules using some other tools.
And that's not something we want.
We want to make sure that this cannot be compromised because if they can become admin, they can do
a lot of things.
So let's remove that functionality from our controller too.
So you can to update user by user here, let's remove this rule.
So rule will be updating using this function.
Okay.
So back to profile updates.
So here we want to hide the role.
Actually, we should hide the role role input all together for author and subscribe I see here role.
So we get the base.
So based on that, we can do some conditional rendering.
Is equals equals equals admin and we so, so only for the admin.
We are showing these options.
So it's not that beautiful now since we have removed that role functionality from the control.
So even though somehow they were able to send it, it won't be operating in the back end.
All right.
That's good for our road.
Next one for media.
Media is here.
Again.
See here, what I'm going to do is.
It would signal a cause and mean.
Actually, we can do this because we want to show this to author as well and we passing on it is working
on it.
So that's an easy way to fix this.
So we have access to the currently logged in user.
So if the currently logged in users have all these subscriber, then we don't want to show this one.
Right.
So us user or not equals equals.
Subscribe then only then we social media.
If it is not subscribed, then only then we show media.
All right.
Now, you can see here the subscriber can update on the name, you mean.
Only name, email, website and password.
All right.
So that was beautiful.
Sign out that sign.
And as also.
Profile.
Okay.
So you can see here he can update.
He has the options for media.
If he has the existing media, then we should show that.
I'm dead so we can go on to the best food.
Come here.
We should add existing media on.
Please reload.
We saw that sweater looks good.
Perfect.
And obviously for it wouldn't work for Edmund as well.
Beautiful.
He can again continue using it.
You can just go from here as well.
It's the same thing and same with the other uses.
One, two.
This is a subscriber.
Also this autumn round three subscriber lists.
Let me try changing the rules to offer.
Beautiful scumbag.
Ryan.
Three other beautiful.
I guess I had a look around why I see this disabled and I figured out the reason is when we upgrade
the user.
If you come back to the update profile here, so we have this function when we upgrade the user, we
get the response.
When we get the response, we update the local stories based on the response we've got.
So as an admin, when admin objects, he's not updating one of his profiles, he's upgrading other people's
profiles.
But with and thing is a really good idea, to be honest, we shouldn't be updating our this profile,
but it can be useful to change the the role.
But you know the use case is turned really doesn't really make sense.
What anyways we have that functionality.
So what happens is when it is updated we get the response to at that time user if he's not updating
his profile, but instead of building someone else's profile, then that person's response is received.
And whatever response we get, we update the local stories and context, which means the currently logged
in user has been replaced by this response user, whoever that is.
Now that works for in every other case except t admin is trying to update some other user.
Right?
So we have to be careful here.
So what we can do is we can do some kind of take to make sure this doesn't happen.
So what we can do here is we want to update the context and local stories only if.
The current user updated his own profile.
Now, how do we know that?
We can know that by taking the IP.
So the currently logged in you decide.
We know that.
So if the current trend of the news society, which is in the context, if that I had met with this
response IED so whichever user has been updated, the IED never changes.
So if that IED and the currently logged is added Metz only then we do our bit.
Otherwise we don't have to update the logged in user status in the context in local stories.
All right, so let me just got everything here and take here.
If posts the user I.D. equals, equals, equals.
This response data don't underscore, Andy.
Yeah.
Then.
Only then.
We update the context and local stories.
Update and local stories.
For current use only.
All right, so let's do this and let's see how this works.
So this is me.
Maybe I'm it myself.
One, two, three.
Summit.
Okay, it works.
So good to all uses so you can see it stays there.
The last time it was there too.
It's this too.
So sign out.
It's free stuff again.
So when you implement things like this one admin will be able to object, delete, do a lot of things
for the users.
Then all this complexity comes in.
But if you think about it, it's, it's, it's not hard to understand, but sometimes it can be quite
a lot.
So if it is, if you're feeling like it's quite a lot, just take some rest, take some time and then
start first, you know, let's go ahead here so you can see I can do it myself.
So if everything looks perfect, returns this.
Let me remove that.
Submit.
That works.
Let's go back.
Let's try someone else.
One year
it's changed it subscriber.
They may even make him an author.
Also, Tintin subscribed to us.
Okay, so it's come back here now.
You can see he is there as it is.
No problem.
And I'm still there.
Okay, that's perfect.
Okay.
So it was quite a lot and it might have been very complicated and a bit confusing, but when you're
building bigger application, things like this comes in.
I recommend you to repeat this User Management six and to updated it one more time.
If you're feeling a bit confused, don't trust this repeating because once you understand this thing,
it will be used useful for you, for the entire life, for many different applications that you'll be
building in future.
All right.
So hopefully you made so far.
Now, moving forward, we're going to just focus on other things.
Now, most of the hard look, we wanted it done.
Now there's maybe one more.
Saxon, which is not super complicated.
It's actually quite easy.
That is adding the functionality to add a comment in our posts.
So we'll do that and then basically know many other small cool things we'll be implementing in this
application.
But most of the core features have been already already built except that common six.
And we look good so far.