All right, so let's create the endpoint in the back end so that we can get on the users and then we
going to make a request from here using use effect.
All right.
So let's go to server routes of.
Let's create a new.
Quit using it, assuming that Rona don't get users.
Require a signing then is added to this throughout will be only for added to the admin and then we can
call it uses.
Okay.
So it's go this uses control function uses Google controls auth.
It's come all the way down.
It's right here.
So we have this control function, really.
So what we want to do here is we want to query the database of the users, right?
That is straightforward.
We use a user model that will give us all the users.
What do we want to do here is we don't want to select the users password or secret the reset code,
those properties.
We don't want to sleep, right?
So what we can do is we can use dot select and we can deselect so into the string minus password, minus
secret note communist.
All right, so this the names that you want.
So if you don't choose minus, that will be selected.
But in our case we want to disallow it.
So minus secret and then minus the reset code.
That's why we find all the users dislike these properties.
And then.
Jason Yes.
Let's give it a different name because these there might be conflicts or expression.
Oh, oh.
All right.
So this will give us all the uses, and it's cool to our route.
And I sort of it's good to have the index and how tactful I mean use this index and then here, let's
try using use 15.
Secure its use.
It's called a function, let's call it load uses.
And then we're going to execute that in huge effect.
All right.
A load here.
Now, this road requires the user to be admin, so that means we need to make sure we have the authenticate
to user and that the user's token is sent.
So you want to add the US in the dependency, also the token.
Sometimes immediately you may not have access to the context.
So at that time, if you make a request, you may not get any data or you may get some error.
So we want to make sure we have the token before we send a request to if of token, if we have the token
in the state only then send this request.
So let's work this function on load users.
Async request response.
So here we want to do and we want to use the excuse cons dollar act is still a great excuse to get make
a gift request to use this.
That should give us the uses we put in, put them in the states it uses.
That can be done.
All right, so now we should have got all the uses.
Let's have a look.
You can see we have the users total count 12.
Beautiful.
That's great.
Now let's come here and try to render.
The list of uses.
Now, let me also write one on the phones.
And just quickly, because we're going to implement, edit and delete.
Okay.
So let me read this.
Did Fox open up handedly try cats air?
Control of the air.
So what are we going to do?
We need to try
to come back to this function.
We can drive here if.
We should be receiving the user and then we can take this word for this transaction.
Let's just render the list of users, then we'll.
What about this one.
So we got the heading.
Yeah, it's.
And then our users looks like we don't need this.
Maybe we can have a line break.
And here we want to list all the users.
So we have the list component from end.
So let's use that to render the list of users.
So list.
It requires the to lay out what original wording we are using a horizontal data source that's uses in
the state the array of uses as the data source and render item that we were going to render.
That is.
Yeah.
So we get each user.
Granger.
We can use list item.
So here inside list item.
We can.
So it's you.
So we know we have to decide.
What are the properties you want to display for each user?
We want obviously to edit into the icons.
We want to show the user name.
So let me use list.
I had a mirror here I can sort of name.
So title that's going to be item user.
It's called user.
List item.
So that closes here.
Brendan Ryan So we're using one quarter this year.
And to you, we have got to use this to.
Perfect.
Looks like we have a break from camp there.
Looks like we don't actually need even angry.
Okay.
That looks good.
I guess we got the name of fuses.
Let's work on the other properties.
So here you can see we want to show the avatar with the this first character of the name, email, the
role, how many posts they have and then do.
All right.
So let's walk them that.
So you list item list.
So the editor did it.
I can tweet.
Is we going to just put them here?
They said that would be X and it seemed to be a way to here we can have array of x and so we wouldn't
have to edit and delete.
So in this array.
Let's go right at it so we can put it in a linked component.
So when they click through, take them to a different base where they will be able to edit these increases
to limit cookies to the finished ones.
So you can see when you click, we take them to a separate place where we can you can see we have the
admin uses the user ID is the.
And then this in the writing we send request back and get that user pre-populated in the phone so that
we can edit.
That's it.
That's for edit.
Then it will be straightforward.
You can see it is gone.
Delete.
All right, so let's come back here.
It's use link.
To Interlink, we use anchor tag.
And here we call it got it.
To link heads for history.
If it's going to be let's use back to less advanced less uses less user aid.
Right.
So that could be huge.
I'm just quite.
So that's for edit now comma because we are in the into the array so comma and then another value that
to be for delete.
For Dillard.
We don't need link.
So we can just use an attack like that.
Can't do it.
And to do it, we're going to execute a function.
So on click.
So we can execute a function which we already wrote here and then delete.
And we want to pass the user as an argument.
So give the user.
Anchor stay on click.
So we have obviously we've got one expert caught Bruce thank you.
So editing dude we have to when dude is clicked, we give this user object as an argument to this function
so we can access that user.
And then for the moment, I think we have to quit the delete to use endpoint in the backend.
Let's wait for that for the moment.
We can just try it if the user don't underscore it.
Equals equals equals of Dart's user to underscore.
Then I learned you can not do need to yourself and return.
All right.
So we're not going to allow the user to dilute themselves because usually editing required deleting
a user will have some consequences because the user may have created some posts.
Yeah.
So the posts posted by a user will not be there.
So there are consequences.
It shouldn't break the application because we can.
If the user the post posted by user is not there, then we just know I will assume the name is false.
That's about right.
But defending a user is not something we actually do in real life.
Maybe we hired the visibility to, you know, unpublished or something like that, but usually we don't
delete the user.
But as an admin you can delete, but we don't allow them to delete themself.
So if the user I.D., the user that they're trying to delete is the currently log to use it I that same
then we should dismisses otherwise we can to make a request back and we will come back to this bit later.
All right.
So let's give it a try as well.
Let's see.
You can do it yourself.
Okay.
Edit If we click, we will be taken to a different base, which doesn't exist at the moment.
That is also fine.
Let's just continue here.
Let's make it look like this.
So we show the avatar email roll and the number of host and then we're going to move on.
Editor and delete.
So we got that access.
We got to use the name next one to be for the use there.
Also the avatar.
So avatar source.
So the source is going to be.
If the user have images so we can show that image.
Otherwise, we just take the first character.
From the neck.
All right.
So for the profile, we'll be working on the profile six and later.
So when the when we walk in the profile, they will be able to upload the image.
So at that time, we can show the image.
But for the moment, let's just.
So the the character and it's a source user.
What does he most want?
Dirty URL.
So if the user has the image then we will try to access the URL from the.
Okay.
Now.
If not, that's fine.
What are you going to do?
Is he going to do so beautifully?
So you just don't make.
Can we just grab the first gauge using this syntax?
You know, you can see we have the easiest name as well.
Beautiful.
Our next one, the username we're showing.
I think we need a bit of a gap here, so let's use some style style margin lifters.
This used ten.
I guess that's that's better.
So that's done.
Next one, we want to show you this enlargement.
So after the mirror, let to use.
List.
Dot, item, dot.
Mr..
And here we want to show the e-mail.
So the description I can use user email.
Again, we use the margin.
And it's actually to work literally cut loose.
Yeah, it's just an amazing lift.
I think what we need here is we need to it somehow.
It's.
It's all consistent.
I think what we need here is the column with the span of full width that's available 24.
All right, that's fair enough.
Beautiful.
The entire island is looking pretty close to the sun.
Right.
So you got the name, email
and the delete.
Role in the number of posts.
Those two things have left.