Now it's here.
First, let's make sure we are receiving the inmates counsel long request, Marty.
So we should be receiving a request in body image because you can quickly go to the client post new.
As you can see when you make push to request using access, we are sending the images.
Okay.
So this should be accessible as requested board.
So let's make sure we have this one before we continue further.
So let's go.
So let me.
Let me leave this and just continue here.
Let me give you.
Just reload.
So let's try uploading the image.
Let's show the same image.
Okay.
So we don't see anything here, but let's have a look into the server console.
So we got four.
Four.
For forming space in our phones api upload images.
Let's take our out.
Upload images.
Okay.
So what happened?
This happens quite a lot of time.
Luckily, I found it right in time.
So anytime we create new file in the we have to bring them to index days and apply as a middleware.
I guess that's important.
Don't forget that.
So let's put let's call it post.
Postcards from the road.
All right, so we need play there.
That's really where it's coming, then.
Pushups.
Okay, now let's try.
I guess we don't see anything here.
But here in this borough council, we have got the image data base 64.
Beautiful.
So request borrow.
Don't miss.
We give you this data so we can send this to Claudia for uploading.
So let me comment that.
So I'm going to use this feature.
Let's put this result in a variable called result equals to a weight we use go generic dot uploader,
dot upload.
So this is the function we used to upload.
All right.
So upload and we just have to give the data that is request volunteered.
And then that will give us the result so you can control of the result.
So this result will contain.
The U, r, l and the public.
So you get to your one with just his two DP and another with his two tips.
Thank you.
So let's have a look at this in the concept before we actually send this as this in response.
All right.
So let me just give a refresh one more time.
Now you can see here the image has been successfully uploaded and we got this response.
Beautiful.
Now, here we have all this information, but the only thing, the most important one is the earth.
Sorry.
In fact.
Oh, yeah, that's right.
So we go to the URL and secure your.
So this one is only has to be this one.
It has to be is so always used.
This has to be this.
When I say always it means I mean, if you'll you will be hosting your website with his tips, then
you need to use this year.
Otherwise you know to use history if your website doesn't have the his two tips but then.
So if you.
Um.
Yeah.
If you would've said it just has to be without censorship, it not secure.
Then if you make a request to the security, you might get some issues.
If you, you know, from heads to heads to debate and then heads to heads to base, if you make it cross
communication, I think you get some kind of error.
But.
Yeah.
Feel free to use one, but I'm going to use one, I guess.
In Ferguson, obviously, you'll be using the security area, obviously, and you can even get a free
SSL certificate.
And most of these must have the hosting visitors and this application will be really hosting the installation.
And there you can use list.
Let's encrypt that free SSL aspect.
Also, if you buy a domain, you'll be use able to use the free has to be as secure assistant certificate.
All right.
So we're going to use the security guard and we're going to.
I think that's a in.
You can use the public radio really conserving the database if you later want to remove this image.
But since this will be all embedded in the post, we're not actually going to use that.
So we can just use the security URL to console.log result.
It's coming, get out and instead send the response.
A response.
Don't Jason know if you sent like this one?
If you send the response like this, the resultant CQ, you are ill.
If you do this, then you have to access this here.
You do not have to access dirty coal.
You'll do.
I'm very sorry if you do.
This, then you have to access the gear and like this one downloaded here.
But if you don't use the URL and just send it like this one.
Just send it like that one.
Then there is no need to use data tied to the data itself, just the earth.
So let's keep it like this.
Keep it simple, because we don't need any other properties to send, so we can just directly send the.
All right.
So this is all we need.
We are sending the euro and that euro is received here and that is returning to this year will be put
all together with the post content whenever we are creating this post.
You see, it's grayed out for a while now and it is finally uploaded.
You can see the actual images here.
He can align the position.
Beautiful.
I'll give you continued.
If you want to, you can download.
All right.
Absolutely amazing.
Now we can write some surface to make sure the the image content within the.
Within the content body.
But otherwise, as you can see, the image has been saved successfully and if you reload this time,
it will stay here because the URL is saved along with this one in the local stories.
So let me quickly have a new application post content.
You can see the images there.
If I reload.
Still here.
All right, beautiful.
Let me quickly remove the station string of five in a row using animal.
Oh, good.
Beautiful.
Okay, so you can see the content is overflowing.
So let's actually put this content, the editor into the deep so that we can put some styling.
We can use overflow scroll so we can make it scrollable.
So just copy that and then we use Div and put it into the do so in this.
Do I want to write some CAC source style?
In fact, it's totally in this t the class name.
Let's call it editor scroll.
All right.
So we're going to talk to this classmen now.
Ed, I think we already have some courses applied, so let's go to the cease fire stance to see this
is supposed minister that is the editor.
So if you're right, click inspect.
You can see this div.
This class name is first mirror so we can give it a height.
Bigger than 200, maybe.
Let's use 500.
Okay, Murray.
Still, we have to make sure it is soluble.
So at the moment, it overflows.
So what he can do.
Is due to a flaw.
Scroll.
I guess with that you can see the overflowing content you can scrub.
So that's good.
Now next thing, you can also hide this school sign.
But if you'll notice in my finished project you can see we can scroll, but you don't see the scrollbar.
So that's just for stylised styling purpose.
It's fine as it is, but if you want to remove that and still be able to scroll, then we can target
this div.
Now this is this content is entitled this div editor scrum.
We give the class name just now.
Write this one so we can target this one.
So come here and let's just write some thesis.
So we have to target the browsers, the Internet Explorer and Safari four on Mac Mac as well.
Right.
So here what you can do is to fix this in the web, get safari browser.
We can use sort of not like this.
So here.
Space.
Double calling with kid.
Scrollbar here.
What we can do is displaying none.
So hard the scrollbar in the safari.
And for Firefox and Internet Explorer added to scroll.
Mix of old style none and scrollbar with no.
So with this thesis, we should be able to hide the scrollbar while this to be able to scroll.
Yes, let's try.
You can see here, you don't see the scrollbar, but you can still scroll.
Beautiful.
After we got the title, we got the content.
We are able to upload the images as well and resized images embed here.
So even when you upload a bigger image, you don't have to worry because we are resizing to 720 pixels
with.
As you can see here.
All right.
So that's awesome.
So your content is not too bloated.
It will not be too heavy.
And so the post will load quickly.
All right.
So that's that's important.
So that is done here.
And we are able to pick the categories as well.
So far, so good.
The next thing we want to work on is the single upload for featured images.
So it is here.
So not just inside the editor, but also the individual images we can upload on each post so that we
can destroy them nicely when we are showing the post like this one.
So you can see this is the featured image.
Of course, if you want to, you can make it fun with and make it look really nice.
And this is the embedded image.