So we created few mirrors here can create read, can undo delete and can delete media.
So let's apply this minimalist goal to post rounds.
And here.
Immediately where's its imports
so we want to import can create read malware, can update, delete post malware and then can delete
media anywhere.
Again, you may want to copy the name is from here just to avoid any typos.
All right.
So we are still going to use it is admin for few routes, but for most of these routes for post and
media, we are going to use these routes.
All right.
So let's come down here.
So the first one is for uploading images.
So for uploading images should be.
For.
I guess I'm learning in me.
I think we should all of that.
Also to also applaud because you know that he will be creating posts.
Obviously he need images so let's send this to let's remove this malware and replace with can create
read it and create update create upload images right.
So replace is admin with can create these that's first row, second root.
Upload images file.
That's.
That's for.
The image that goes in the content of the post and this is the actual the featured image I guess of
this one also for both had been altered.
So to replace that we can create read for creating post against.
Can't quit read.
It's for everyone.
Oh.
Deleting now this one delete will be.
Oh, and this one is can.
I did delete post.
I should replace that with an updated post it will take for the boosted by ID and the logged in.
He decided to make sure he can delete only his post, not everyone else's, except if he's adamant so
he cannot deleted it.
Post.
Same here and media.
Rather to get.
I want to get media is I mean this will soon be a tweet read
and delete this delete this amount can delete media.
All right.
No.
Let's go and quickly have a look.
Previously, this user couldn't access the featured images.
All right, so now let's try.
Leaving just few reload.
Now you can see here this officer is able to access media library because obviously we have the middleware.
We have removed the A-Z middleware and we have replaced with nuance also, so to speak, this one.
All right, so let's try creating a post, and I'm pretty sure it works.
Let's open inspect.
But please.
Bush created successfully.
So we didn't have the.
For some reason we were redirected to home base, probably because we don't have the outposts for awesome.
Oh, actually what happened is when we created a post, we tried to redirect to probably less admin
and since this is also how this user was redirected to home base so that it's an easy fix to let's go
to our front end now you can see new post component has been used for both admin and other, but after
creating the post we want to redirect then different base.
If it is admin will go to class admin.
If it is over, we go to slash.
All right.
So it's going to have an.
Let's look at the handle submit handle populace.
Around 2% means less post.
So this has to be dynamic.
So this is something maybe we can pass as props.
From here.
Right.
So this new post component let's pass a value based equals to the value author.
So this is used in the author based space.
Author.
And.
This is also used in admin posts, but we didn't have to make any changes there.
So just here we passed this prop base equals to awesome.
And then let's go to this component, new post component and here it's going to relate to receive that.
So this structure
is all right.
So the value is coming from there as author.
But what you want to do is by default you want to give some different value.
So let's say default value is admin.
So by default the base will always be this string admin.
But if we receive some value like this one, then obviously this will be used against a base we sending
off to.
By default it'll be admin, but if we receive authored then that will be used.
So let's use this value down here on the root house.
So instead of targeting the admin, we can use that variable base like let solution just put it back
ticks.
Malibu tends to
bass.
So by default bass is equals to admin.
That's the default value.
So it will be less admin, less boost by default.
But whenever this component is used in auto layout, the base will be awesome.
So in that case it will render it to authors less posts.
Okay, so let's try it.
Let's try creating one more.
Also optional often gets
redirected.
All right, let's.
It's fabulous.
And this time.
You can see I'm redirected to less offers, less post.
So I listed this phase doesn't exist, but at the moment you can see it's working perfectly with.
We were not redirected to home base like before.
Awesome.