So we are almost ready to start building monastic applications.
Now, before we do that.
First we have to.
Set up our development environment and we do not really need a lot.
And since I think I'm pretty sure, you know, the basics of react, that means you have already used
NPM to install a react locally in a computer and tried a few times.
Right.
So that means you may already have Node.js installed.
If not, you want to make sure you have that right so you can use terminal command prompt.
Let me clear all this out.
I get so here I have my right here and I'm going to show you my note versus currently which version
I'm using.
So no deaths.
V, I'm using version six, which is latest.
All right.
So if you don't have if you want to upgrade to the latest version of Node.js on this visit, no, it's
just an old download, the latest version.
In fact, they already have seven in here.
All right.
So once we have Node.js install, next thing you want to do is decide.
I'll make sure you have the text editor, which I'm sure you have as well.
So I'm going to use voice code for this one.
Visual Studio code.
If you don't have that, you can download it for free.
And this is the one I recommend.
It's very easy to use and there are a lot of plugins that will make your development process so much
easier.
All right.
So here are some of the blog that I'd recommend you have is a preview and some React plugins.
So if you want to install, I'm on my Mac.
So on Mac, you can try Command Swift B and that will open up this window here.
You can choose to.
Install extensions.
You can choose themes.
Themes are basically for.
Oh.
The visual purpose is not super important, but obviously you want to have your favorite theme so that
you feel more motivated to code.
Right now, let me show you some of the plugins that I have.
Thanks to the blog list so you can see how I have these themes.
They're not super important.
The most important one I want to show you is truly.
All right.
So you can see I have already installed Superior Court format if you want to use this.
The beauty of this is whenever you type something, some code in your editor know and only hit save
comment is that tool.
Well, as soon as you do that that will or the format of court.
All right so this is a very useful plug you want to use that some react plugins which will be extremely
helpful.
So this is quite popular 187 React Redux.
You can do so to react and install that.
So any other plugins that I might use during the course I will be showing as well.
Amongst Sift e in the explorer window.
I usually have the side row using command to.
You can do that from here as well.
View Sidebar Explorer will show you the files here.
At the moment we don't have any.
Obviously we will create set above project and bring them here.
At the moment there's nothing there so you can hide the sidebar if you want to come on to do trauma
command.
Appearance.
So sidebar you can just control.
Among one and two will hide that.
Come on two will had then.
All right.
So the basics of this could.
It's close, this one.
And let's also quickly have a look at the applications.
This is the application we're going to build.
And this is already live on the Web.
So you can always come here, have a look at this application, log in and then just walk with me altogether.