All right.
So now we're going to make some improvement here.
So instead of taking the valley from the local stories, we're going to make a request to our back in.
So we're going to create a endpoint where we can get the currently logged in, use this information
from the database and we send that here and then we're going to take if we get the user then we can,
you know, set loading defaults to show the content.
Otherwise we show this loading spinner.
And then later just saying loading spinner is actually not enough.
Because if you have a look, we don't want to keep circularly, we want to throw them out of that base,
take them to a logging phase or something like that.
All right.
So, for example, if you have a look at the finished application.
So if a user is not logged in and if they try to go to admin pays, for example, then we have something
like this redirecting in 3 to 1 and then we redo it.
So we need to implement something like that just so that we don't the people don't just sit there looking
at the loading screen, which is okay, but we could do something like this.
All right.
So we're going to do that.
And at the moment, let's go to the back end and create the endpoint so we can make a request from here.
Now, if you're new to building a full stack application, you might be feeling like maybe some of you
might be feeling like there's just so much work in terms of authentication and protecting without protecting
your backend front end, things like that.
Whether it is because it's security is really important for any application.
However, all these things you have to do only once in the beginning of the application.
So when you're building an application, you always have to go through this authentication process back
in front end, securing the bases, all that things you do once and once it is done, then you don't
have to worry about that again and you just focus on building the actual application.
All right.
So we are almost done here.
Just add this.
We are towards the end of this whole authentication, protecting roots, spaces, all of it.
So very soon we will be done and then we'll be able to just do these amazing things like creating post
updating, deleting categories, media, library comments, users profile and just all this cool stuff.
So if you want to post personal feel a bit too much, you feel like it is a bit too much about the authentication
and protection and all that we all done.
All right.
So with that said.
But I personally enjoyed it.
It's so much fun.
But it's maybe it's not for everyone, you know, just just so that I wanted to share this with you.
You do it just once in the beginning of the application, and that is pretty much it.
All right.
So.
You defect, we're going to use the use effect, however discovered that is taking the value from the
context to ensure that we want to rely this data to come from our SARA.
So now it is fully secure.
So let's go to our server roads of let's create a endpoint and we can call that current user Aurora
dot get we make a get request and this will be very useful as well.
So anytime you want to know the logged in user who is the currently logged in, use it.
Then you can always make a request to this endpoint even though you have the data in the context and
local.
So is just for the security reason.
You can make a request to your back end and this will give you the currently logged in user based on
the the token, right?
So that response is something you can totally trust.
So rather than get we can call it, let's call it current to use.
Actually, let's call it current.
Add to what?
What I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a function in the controller that will have returned
the current user.
However, the endpoint we can change it to, we can call it current admin, current also current subscriber.
We can change it.
However, the function we will execute in the controller will be always same and that is going to be
current to use.
Basically what we want to do is get the current user.
Now how I'm going to make this dynamic for the author and subscribers to that by applying a middleware
here.
So I'm going to upload the admin middleware that will.
Make sure that this current user is admin.
So I will see you also how we are going to do that.
But for the moment, let's just focus on creating this.
Control function, and we also need to make sure to apply that middleware.
If we go to the category, we have applied the request handling middleware.
So we need that one has.
Because we need to know the.
We need to know the.
And to govern the society, we need to verify the token.
And then that would give us the ID in the request to use it.
All right.
So we're going to update this, request it right here.
So current user current add an endpoint, you can send a request from your React application.
And this route has this middleware approach it will take for the token.
If it is valid, the code here will execute and this code will try to get the user from the database
and return to the React application.
So current user, let's create this function that our control controls ask.
This from Tony, an
export concert.
Current user account stood.
Async requests.
Response
try.
Cut the error.
Cancel out the error.
So here, what we want to do is we want to get the current user.
So to give the current user, first of all, we need to make sure we have the user model, which obviously
we have.
So here we can use we can put this result in the variable user equal weight use the user model, the
find by ID function, and we give the idea and that is going to be a request to use a dot underscore
I.D. We can we we get access to this because we applied the request and in middleware in our route.
All right.
So we try to find the user based on the idea.
And once we get that, all we want to do is return.
Simple as that.
We just want to return to use it.
But.
But we actually don't need this user object in our client in React because we already have the logged
in user.
We're doing all this just to make sure that.
The.
So for the security reason, right?
So just so that someone is not messing around with the value in the level stories, right?
So that is the only reason.
Otherwise we could you know, we can we don't actually have to send the user to the client.
We can just send some kind of a value face and bullet response edition.
Okay to use something simple as this, because the data we're sending here is not really important with
a.
Whether the current user was there, whether the user's admin or not.
That is the important as to here.
We can just send the.
No response.
Okay.
True or false?
We don't really have to do anything.
Instead, what we're going to do here is applied the EAS admin middleware here.
That is something we have already created and we even apply it here in the category.
So let's go to middleware index.
So we have the is ADM.
Basically here we are finding the user.
If the user has the role of admin, we are.
Returning.
Executing this callback function.
Right.
So this a middleware we can use in our root you.
The current admin group.
That will make sure that we have the.
Currently logged in user which is who is also an answer here and its input is an.
Okay.
Now.
You can see here.
Previously we made we use the huge effect hook that take the value from the context.
Now we're going to change that and make a request to this endpoint.
Okay.
And this end point will have all these tick ticks for the validity of the token tick.
If the user has the role of admin and if everything is good, we can send the response.
Okay.
True.
Right.
So if the response.
Okay.
True.
Has been received in the.
The client said, then we can just render the contract.
So that means let's go to the current user.
And I just realized that we don't actually have to even make this query to find the user from the database
we don't have.
You know, we can just send the response or get to.
That's that's that's so simple and amazing.
So we can do this because we have already done all the tech necessary here in the is admin, right?
So if you want, you can even keep it simple like this one.
I'm just going to leave it like this.
I'm just gonna send this out.
We may use later, some time, but I don't really think this.
Leave it like this.
So we just send the response.
Okay.
So let's go now.
And try to make a request to this end point and let's see how we can use this.
So response to determine whether we want to show the content or not.
So let me close all this.
Let me close the server.
Go back to client and let's go to admin layout here.
Now.
I'm just going to comment discordant instead of working to make a request to back in I guess let me
input excuse.
And then here.
And let me execute a function here and get.
Current admin.
And then let's try this once again.
One of the reason is that we can't use async here.
I guess you can't do that.
Instead use effect.
You could write a function like this.
You just execute here like that.
You can do that, or you can just leave it outside just to make things make your core a little bit cleaner.
I So this are what I'm going to do.
So get current admin we use excuse excuse will give us the response data we do structure data equals
to await excuse.
Don't make a get request to
current admin.
All right.
And then when we do this, we may get the response or get to the point.
So here's what you need to do is you can punch a lot of the big into the Donna.
Before we do anything here.
Now, this function executes here in the U.S..
If it were here.
Oh, I, too, have to do one more thing here because.
The table the current admin to give the current admin in our back and we need to make sure the health
token has been sent to our back so you can do not want done token.
Because it might take few milliseconds to access this value from the context.
So you want to make sure you have access to token before you make a request.
So you can put this as a dependency here and then come here and give it a try.
Let's open.
Let's try to go to.
Actually, we can just go from here.
Localhost, 3000 subscribers, not phono.
So obviously we don't have the software.
Let's log in and add.
And you can see immediately we got that okay too.
We still have the loading, but.
Okay.
True.
That's beautiful.
You can see the request has been made to our backend.
Awesome.
So what we can do now is.
The same thing.
Yeah.
Said Learning difference.
If we got the response it removed the console.log done and let's put that here set lowering defaults
if we've got the data.
If there was an error, we can just redirect the use it to some other base.
Okay.
So we can do that.
And this all this good executing him.
So we don't need this code anymore.
I'm going to actually leave it here just for the reference for you.
So this way you could just use your context to take.
But now we're using.
This would be a request and the response based on their response.
We are.
Changing the value of loading.
And when the loading is true, we show the alluring spinner.
Otherwise, we saw the content.
Okay.
So you saw how we changed from this to this nicely.
So now you first.
Let's try.
We can try one more time.
Um, localhost, 3000.
If you try to go to admin.
You get redirect.
All right.
If you sign in.
But not as an item, but like someone is.
And if you try to go to any.
We get redirected to companies, so we have been able to secure the admin base.
Based on the response we got from our server.