And if you go to the plant, you can see at the moment we just gone to logging and showing the total
notification.
We're not redirecting our emptying it from the local stores.
All right.
So let me try.
So we got this post.
Okay.
So let's try saving it from this.
I guess it looks like we didn't get any response.
Let me double check.
Getting used in a different arc.
Obviously, I think we didn't import the categories model in the first controller, so it's important
that.
Model category.
All right.
So that's good.
Now, maybe one more thing we can do here that is showing some kind of for our learning, because it
might take a while.
It will take definitely 1/2, more than 1/2, because we have others delayed by 1/2.
So maybe we would show some kind of a learning, which is something we can work.
So let's try.
Most creative, successful, beautiful.
Okay, so that's good.
Let's have a look in the console and you can see her post published response and see the post has been
published.
It has been saved in the database.
We have got the unique ID categories array, the content created, posted.
Everything is yeah, beautiful.
Okay.
I want to have this one.
What do you want to do is you want to redirect the user to the old post office.
Okay.
And then in that page, we will make another request to our back in so that we can show the list of
posts, whatever.
How many has been created so far?
All that we can sort in this space.
I guess so.
Let's quickly redirect.
Let's undo that and let's try it now.
I think this time we will get an error because if I don't do anything and try to again create, that
will be a duplicate title.
So let's see how that works.
Now, if there is error, obviously the content will not be deleted from normal search, which is a
good thing.
So let's try.
So we didn't get any response.
So we got the error here.
Duplicate air we have, but for some reason we are error handling.
Supposed to work here if I don't exist.
All right, so I tried the console.log.
As you can see, I tried until all other exists and see what I get.
And I saw that we get not.
So that means true.
Already exist.
Not.
That means.
So if I try with this call, I'd get the oldest, not let me see it saying that it doesn't.
It's not there.
I think what happened here is that when I'm saving the posting in to here, I, I'm not giving slow.
So that is I think that's in the issue, which I forgot definite.
So let me use that slow, slow fire.
Stanley I that so we didn't have to make it look this big a slog will always be low cost based on our
money.
Okay, so with this slot, I think in this time it works.
Let me just.
Try it one more time.
So let me remove that control of her hat.
Return.
Here, give a refresh.
Let's try.
Let's try to create this same post with the same token.
Post created successfully.
I think what happened is for the first time we didn't have the slug.
So probably that is the reason, though.
Let me try again.
Let's try a second first.
Okay.
What happened here?
Content for the second post was.
Thank you.
To pick some categories, let's try to save this and I'm going to create another one with the same name
just to give that a try from this.
Okay.
It has been created.
Now, let me go ahead and try creating the post with the same title.
It doesn't really mirror the categories and it's try to at least take now this time it looks like.
So what happened is for the very first time, because I didn't.
Use the slow.
There were some issues on the very first post, but now you can see this area is working and so that's
great.
And now when we create if I correct this by Ryan, let's have a look at this one more time.
So then the error, what if I get my ten at the time it works.
Now you noticed in one or 2/2 we have a bit of a pause now for better user experience.
Let's see.
So the lowering here so that when it is saving, we show some kind of a loading spinner so that the
user knows what's happening, right?
So at the moment everything else is looking good.
So let's close the files from this.
So here in the front end one more time, let's have one more state for learning.
Front loading said loading it would see use state funds.
Since we are redirected, we don't have to worry about setting it.
To false once again to when we handle it.
The first thing we do said learning.
True.
And then if there is error, then that time you want to set learning to false.
If there's error.
Now, but if it is successful, you don't have to do it because we are redirecting anyways.
Right.
Let me just come to love that one comment that up.
But if there is error again you are right so that learning to fox is beautiful.
Now we have this dynamic loading state.
We can put that in our boarding component, thankfully.
And that's part and component works.
Based on the learning.
So you didn't have to do anything extra.
Sit here and we do loading across the loading van from the state.
So if it is learning, it will serve the learning spinner and it will also disable the button.
Let's try the
second post.
From this title is taken.
Thank you.
And let's dig in now.
You didn't really see that.
But if I create three or three.
Let's focus.
You can see the lorry for a while and then we get redirected.
Beautiful.
So it's great to.
You have been able to.
Create a new post, save it in the database if you want to, you can take on the date of the sensor.
And so you logged in as this user.
Among the TV.
So the next thing we have to work on is probably.
The media fiction, which is very exciting.
It's similar to how it works with WordPress.
All right, so let's browse collections.
Posts.
You can see we have covered a post and just created what categories are is there.
Okay.
So.
Once we create, we are redirecting the user to the open space.
So in the open space we want to show a list of posts so that the admin can edit or delete.
Right.
And then obviously later we will be showing the post in the home for the post office.
We can put on the homepage as well if we want to.
And that's when you will see how this.
The categories are, how are you doing to actually show the category name instead of just tired?
So you basically you can use dot populate function in your back and that will give you all the information
based on this idea.
So we'll we'll check that out later.
I guess I didn't finally create one nice post and then we done for creating posts.
So.
Modern home interior.
I just found one image that is really nice.
I'm just going to
post that it is.
Let me put some code.
Let's try posting some code.
Using these code, we can create a post, send request to turn back
and base then.
All right.
And at the moment, it may actually put that image in the veterans images.
Okay.
So that image actually is not here.
Unfortunately I will say that.
Nice it is a bit later, but for now, let's work with this.
Okay.
So you can give it a caption as well.
Peace.
It's a slippery line that.
React.
Note Awesome.
Let's publish beautiful.
It has been created.
Now obviously we don't see it at the moment.
It's a very beautiful post with a very beautiful image, but obviously that that's coming in future
lessons.