All right, so let's work on this field so that we can assume the code field and the new password field
for the user to the end of the values.
All right.
So here, let's first what we can do here is set this visible value to true just temporarily while we
are working it, so that even if you refresh the base, it is always there.
Otherwise every time you have to send a chill email to see this one.
So if you tended to fuss, you won't see them.
So just so that we we can continue working.
Create these two forms.
Let's make it true.
All right?
And then come down here and edit me.
Remove that instead
if feasible.
It is true we can to choose fragment.
So here we're going to put the funnel.
So this is the form that we already had, we copied from Solon.
So let me just cut and put it here.
So that is for the user to enter the password answer here we can call please input.
Please enter your new password.
That's it.
That's for the password.
And we want to.
So one input for.
Entering the code.
Let me just copy one of the, the previous one that we used for email and put that here and change this
from email to.
To reset the code.
You said rules.
Let's remove that rule.
Thank you, sir.
Input.
We can sense that.
I can.
Placeholder.
Let's call it.
We said court.
It's called Enter.
We said.
So let's have a look.
All right.
So once the visible becomes true, we so these two filters will one to enter the reset cooler and another
one is for passwords.
This make it a new password name.
That is the place holder.
New boss.
Perfect.
All right.
Now.
That is actually that is all we need to do.
All right.
So let's come here and write another function, because this function was used to submit the image.
But now now we are showing two more fields.
And when they submit here, this time it has to submit to a different function because it is submitting
to a different endpoint.
So we have to do a bit of a trick just so that it is the same button, but we are now using a different
function, so that's going to be pretty easy.
But first, let's write the function as to this function, we can call it reset password, request,
I guess, just like we call it for password request, we call it reset password request.
And if you like, you can even copy this code.
We could pretty much use a lot of food.
It's based here and it sends this to the reset password request.
All right.
So again, we get all the values of the phone.
We send the loading to.
True.
This time, the endpoint is going to be reset.
Fast forward, are we sending on the values?
If there is an error, we show the error.
Otherwise we show the success message to this time.
Password.
Since successfully.
Please log in with you with your new password.
All right.
Said Flooring falls visible.
It would be false.
No, there's no need to continue showing these two films.
So we send it back to the way it was.
Just the email.
Yes.
We sent it to France.
Okay.
So that is pretty much it.
Now, there is one more thing we can do that is empty the the fears.
So empty the values.
So you could reduce the use it to other ways.
But I think it's it's a good idea to just empty it and just so that no notification in that you can
log in the new password.
Right.
So in that case, we have to empty the fields.
Now to empty the fields I showed you in the previous lectures how you can do that with and isn't fun.
So basically we had to access that from.
Okay.
Thankfully I commented that commented out Tania.
So it's nice and easy to use that's a
wee destructive from from the end isn't fun.
A useful function said gives us the form and this form we have to use in the actual form here.
Let's uncover that one.
All right.
And then we can use this from that reset to reset the values back to empty.
Because when the user suddenly they have a lot of these fields, you don't want to.
Leave them here.
Right.
So you want to make them empty?
So visible will not be true anymore.
It will be false.
So we don't have to worry about these fields.
But this image we have to reset.
Okay.
So that one.
And so if everything goes well, we can show the toast notification.
And then from that we set fields and you can choose the foods you want to empty.
So in our case, we want just email, email.
All right.
So this name should mess the farm's actual name.
So as Smiths.
My guess is that we should be able to empty the fields as well.
This one.
Let's send this forward to reset.
So everything should work.
Let's give it a try.
But actually, before we try, how do we actually execute this function?
Right.
So we still have the same submit button.
You can see here the form has the unfitness.
That function executes this one.
How do we execute this one?
So what we can do here is we can take the status of visible.
Right.
So these two fields are only visible when this value here.
It becomes true.
Somebody can win.
We've made it false.
Let's bring it back to false.
And you don't see those false?
No.
Okay.
So by default, visible is false.
When the end of the email, then if the response was successful, then we said it's true.
Now, when the visible becomes true, we are showing.
The new password and the reset code feels right.
Okay, so that's good.
So at this point, if we are showing these two films, that means visible is true art, so we can use
the same.
Same conditional here.
He has full on fitness.
We can conditionally exclude different functions if visible then you want to execute this function.
Otherwise just continue using the previous form for password.
So if visible is true, execute the reset password function otherwise.
Firefox.
Nice new.
All right, so let's give it a try.
And now before we try, let's also go to our back end and have a look at the reset posture.
Let's see how this works.
So that's a forward pass.
Well, we already tried that.
Now reset password.
What happens is this time we are accessing these three fruits, email password and reset core.
So for everything to make sure you do not change these values when you sending from the client, make
sure it is called reset code.
It's called password.
Just like we have done here.
So the form name reset.
Don't give it a different name.
Password.
Don't call it new password or anything.
Just leave it like this.
Because if you change here, you have to change here as well.
All right.
So we access these values from request, Marty.
That leading into stability again.
All right.
So we are getting the values.
We are sending the values that will be received here.
Then again, we tried to find the user best in the email and reset core.
Now this time we're not just trying to find by the email, but also using the request core.
So this time both values should met.
So if we find the user based on this email and this reset goal, which was previously saved when the
user requested to reset the password.
If we find the user, then we can do all that.
Otherwise we are sending the error.
Mrs. email or reset code is invalid.
Okay.
But if you find the user and if you the new password is at least six characters long, then okay, otherwise
we are sending the error.
Mrs. Caswell, password must be six characters long.
I guess after this, before validation, we basically saving the user's new password in the database
so that he can log in with the new password.
Right.
So before we save, obviously we have to test the password.
So we use this function to test the password and then the user user from the database to this user,
we update this user's password to the host version based on this new password and reset going back to
empty strings of previously we saved that code intended to do the immunization, but this one we now
reset it back to empty string because that has been used here already.
Right.
And then finally, we send this user with all the senders and that is it.
Then we can send this successful response.
Beautiful.
And when this response is sent, we are showing the success message password to successfully.
Please log in within your password.
Beautiful.
Let's give it a try.