So now we're going to focus on creating a layout for admin.
Right.
So the first thing we want to do is focus on building the admin despot.
Because since it seems we merely see a miss, we want to focus on the admin section where admin can
create categories, create posts, quit users.
That's how we get the content for the entire application.
Right.
So let's quickly have a look at the finished products, added Fozzie.
So the next thing we want to focus is create layout for the dashboard.
All right.
So you can see here we have this layout which has the sidebar on the left, and then we have the area
here to show the content.
Right.
So if you go to the all posts, you see all the pushed here.
So that's the content and that's the sidebar that you could add new you get on the component here.
You go to the users, you get the users.
So we have to create this sidebar, put it on the side, and then the rest of the area we use for showing
the content.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create a similar layout.
And for that, since we're using and design and design has this layout component, so we're going to
use that so you can search for layout.
So here they're basically explaining the design concept, but we want to take out the actual code.
So let's go to components and you type here in the components, you have this sidebar.
And we want to check out the layout.
All right.
Layout.
You have, you can see some examples.
You have to have the content and footer.
You can have the sidebar like that.
We can have sidebar on the right or left.
All right.
So you can see some examples here.
The one we want to use is something like this.
So it will have the sidebar and it will have the content.
Six or so you can take out the code here.
Just let's click here so you can see first the import layout component and then they can destructor
these elements from layout.
So header content insider.
So that is used for the sidebar.
So you can destructed these components and then you can build you layout.
You can see here you have this wrapping layout.
It is wrapping the entire thing in inside layout.
You can have all the layout as really intuitive multiple layout.
So what are we going to do is first we import layout, we destructed these components and then we build
our layout.
So the layout we pulled, say the sidebar to show the menu like this one.
And then we use the content.
Content to show the content here as content like this.
All right.
So let's go ahead and take this out.
Let's try.
So we want to implement that in the admin.
Please.
I'd say the moon is just empty.
So let's go ahead and start working on that one.
Now we want to.
I created a separate component for the sidebar so that we can easily input just so that we don't end
up with a lot of code in the same file.
All right.
So we're going to create a separate component for the layer sidebar and another base for the layout.
So the layout is going to be just right here.
So base is admin indexed.
So we have this one.
So let's go ahead and import the layout component first.
So import layout, front end and then we want to be structure.
So we wanted to structure content out from now.
We don't need to disturb the sailor because surgery's going to be in another component.
All right.
So once we have the content, we can send our deep with layout.
I thought we have the layout once we have the layout, whatever content we want.
So we put into the content component content.
And then let's put this back.
Now, if you have a look, you don't see any change at the moment.
What we want to do is we want to actually.
Let's put it inside layout.
Because it has to be inside out because we're going to have the cider as well.
All right.
So we have the layout and internal layout.
We have a content.
You could have header as well.
If you want to.
You can check out the documentation here.
So they have the head as well.
But we just want a simple layout with.
Ah, the content.
All right, so we have the content.
So we have the layout, we have the content and we have the the page one.
That's the content at the moment.
And we want to have the sidebar as well.
All right.
So CIDR also let's let's bring here just so that we can see how it works then.
Then we're going to move them to a separate component.
So one to destructor so you can put them here.
That's within the first layout.
All right.
Then you have the sidebar and then you have another layout with the content.
So remember this structure.
So now let's have a look.
Now, you can see here we have the size of your we have the sidebar and we have the content.
So you get the idea of how it's going to look.
All right.
So that's good.
However, we don't want to actually put everything here because later we need to protect so many bases
for the admin only.
So only the user with the role of admin will have access to these bases.
You can see here to create a post media comments users, some of them, we will make it available for
the author as well, but most of them will be for the admin.
All right.
So we need to protect to make sure only the user with the role of admin will have access to these spaces.
And one way of doing that is create using a layout.
Right.
So that's actually that's what we're trying to do here.
So we want to create some kind of four admin layout and then we're going to wrap each and every place
that will be only for the admin.
And then in that admin layout component, we can make a request to backend to verify that this user
is added to protect the the bases.
Right.
So we're going to implement all that bit later.
But for the moment, just let's focus on the layout.
So basically it's on it's in every place because as you can see, admin will have many pieces.
So on, it's an empty place.
You don't want to repeat this code over and over again.
And you can imagine this sidebar is going to be quite big as well to make this big.
So you don't want to write that big meaning on each and every page.
Right.
So.
All these places, you don't want to repeat the call.
So obviously the solution here is to put all this code in a a component we can call that and layout,
and then we can just import that and wrap our content.
That way we can reuse that.
All right.
So that's what we're going to do.
So let me just copy this one.
Let's go to component and then let's build a new for call layouts.
And then to make it singular they out.
And then in turn here, let's create an admin layout.
All right.
So for the moment, you copied all that.
Could just paste that here and change this to admin layout.
Copy that.
Based here.
So this is the admin layout.
Now.
This admin layer.
Do you want to?
Use him in this space and then later you will create mini based.
So on all those mini pieces, you want to import that billion.
All right, so let's input admin admin layout from.
So we go one step.
Got something in my hair.
Admin layout.
So one step up, two step up and then go inside.
Components.
Different components add main layout.
Alright, so we've got the admin layer and now all this code is already in the ad now so we don't need
that, right.
So we don't need that.
Get rid of that and instead use the admin layout.
Sorry.
Admin layout.
Perfect.
Now, the way we're going to make it work is we're going to pass the content here.
So we can, you know, we can pass a whole lot of content here and that content we need to show in the
admin layout.
So at the moment we're just hard coding admin based.
That's not something we want.
Right.
So at the moment, if I save it like this, go here, take out.
Okay.
So it looks like the path is wrong.
That in and we can't resolve.
All right.
So we're here.
It's one step up to step up.
Go into components.
Lay out.
I guess we missed that clear.
So at the moment, if you use that admin layer computer, that's all you see, that's, you know.
However, what we want to do is we want to be able to pass the content as props so that we can reuse
this component.
Right?
So we can do that.
So you can see here, inside here, we can put whatever we like.
For example, let's say H1, H1.
This is.
I mean, is Trump's property sort of properties.
But for the moment, it just just dummy takes to be distant how this works.
So this is the content, right?
So this is the content we want to show using the admin layer.
So in the admin layer, what you can do is instead of this content, let's remove that.
And so that props what we got this content we will be able to receive in admin layout as children props.
All right.
So you could do props and then you could do props.
The children.
So that's that's how it works in React.
So anything you pass they will be received their children props.
Okay so you could pass the data to your component like this.
And he could receive that, too.
So let's have a look here.
Let me give you a quick refresher.
Sometimes she had to.
In fact, we're not showing anything there.
So that's the profit we're sending.
Add me loud.
Okay, so we have this bit of a typo here.
Let me quickly fix that.
Rename small a.
The foster children.
Okay.
So you can see it foster children at school and probably it wasn't working because of the there was
a lot of the letters kept kept the letter was used to you can hear from now if you try something else.
Paragraph.
More content.
You can see that works.
Okay, so that's beautiful.
Now this way we will be able to use admin layout as many times as we like.
Right.
So that's great.
Now, the next thing we want to do is work on the sidebar, right?
So we're going to decide where we have to build the entire mini like you can see here.
So we're going to use end is end mini component to create this menu.
And that way every place that uses the admin layout will have the beautiful sidebar menu on the right.
Now, before I finish this lesson, one more thing.
You don't have to access it using this dot notation.
You can just destructor if you'd like.
Instead of props to children, you can just directly destructor hits you.
I see that it's a bit more clear than.
Okay.
The.