All right.
So a bit of a change in our plan.
So previously I was saying that we're going to have.
This featured in the section so that each post can have its own featured images.
But we're going to wait for that.
That's because, as you can see, this featured image is basically going to display the library and
add new media.
So it's a big six and we have quite a lot of things to cover in this section.
So all the media that the entire application will have, you will be able to access all of them in the
library and then you will be able to upload one or multiple images abroad.
Drag and drop support.
I will say it will look something like this.
So this is one component, the add new component we will display like this one and then the media library.
We will show all the files that are currently uploaded.
Into our application.
Right.
So when you want to add a featured image, you could choose from here, the existing one, you don't
have to always upload.
You could choose existing one or before time.
You could go to the library and click and drag multiple images uploads and save it for later so you
could use the later as well.
I guess it's a similar concept used by WordPress to begin to implement such a feature.
And those images can be used here.
Click and selected as featured image so we can do that.
Or you could just upload individual images as well.
No problem.
All right.
So we'll come back to it later for looking at the featured image.
But for now, we are almost ready to.
Save this in the database.
Right.
So we have the post starting with the first content we can embed images.
We have the categories.
So let's have a button here so that we can send it to the back end to save in the database.
Now, before we did that.
We can actually do one more thing, which is not the most important thing, but we can work on this
preview six.
And basically, we just saw the title content and that's pretty much it.
So basically you learn to use this model more of the component of it, which will pop up like this one.
So let's quickly go through this one and then we're going to work on the button, make a request to
back in so that we can start saving this in the of this.
So we're going to import the model component from end, right?
And this model will be visible and not visible.
So true and false.
So when it's visible, we will show the model.
Otherwise it will be hidden.
Right.
So that means we need to have a state state here.
All right, so let's add one more step.
Const visible set visible equals to use state by default, it will be false.
Before I continue, I want to move these two functions to a separate file just so that we have a bit
more space as well.
This is getting quite long, so let's create one folder in this client plan directories.
So here the new folder, I'm just going to call it functions.
All right.
So here.
It's called a new file.
Let's call it upload notice.
All right, so here from here, let's copy these two functions and put them here, got from here and
just based here.
And then we need some inputs as well, so resulting in an excuse.
So let's go.
Let's compare that.
It's cool to upload.
Let's put it on top and let's input exercise to.
I guess we got the resizing, we resize the image, the upload image that is using X use, we've got
all that.
So this function gets the file as an argument.
So all we have to do is put export on this one.
We're exporting this file.
So we can now import this one.
We can import this in our new.
Import the structure of load from regions to work boosted of three stack of functions.
Folks in South Florida, and that is it.
We didn't have to do anything here because we have the.
We have the function.
And that function is used here again.
And that function knows everything, whatever it was doing before, we just put them in a separate file.
I guess that's a good double thing just to make sure.
So immense.
Let's upload this one.
Okay.
Now, if you're curious, you can even take the size, I guess.
At the moment this is to me, that's 2100 KB right now when you upload, it has been resized.
So it is uploaded now if I downloaded this one just for a testing.
Okay.
Now, let me show you this image.
You can see it has been reduced to only 260 foot Kimmy.
Originally it was 2.1 and mid that means 2100 Kiwi from that to this size.
So it's like ten x reduce the size and you still have this pretty good quality image.
All right.
So that's the beauty of image resizing.
Now let's continue.
Walking.
And is we going to work on the model so that we can serve it pretty right?
So we created the context of the state
so we can use that visible value to show and hide the.
So we came to we can put that anywhere that's put that we have decided versus let's put that here.
We can put that on the photo.
So we can put a button.
All right, so let's create a button.
I mean, the burden is clear.
You want to show the model.
So we change the value from visible false to true.
Some button click.
We use this to add a function said visible.
We make it true.
All right.
Let's keep this a button and.
Pretty few.
Okay.
So let's make sure we have the button component.
So let's make it full with and maybe a bit of a pairing, but let's come down.
Preview.
Bottom line is that this year
we can use margin on top.
Let's use ten pixel, right?
Zero pixel on bottom, ten pixel on left to pixel.
It's a clockwise value.
With.
With what we use for ways.
Okay.
So we got a preview.
Now on click, the visible becomes true.
So when it's true, we want to saw the model, right?
So we have this column.
The model can stay in here, doesn't have to be inside the column.
So we can use model here.
Okay.
So here in this model, we give this model a title.
Preview.
You want to center it on the base of centered and give that value visible.
So this is the most important one.
So based on the value we have in the statement, it's true it will display.
Otherwise it would be hidden on.
Okay, also.
So this model will have the.
We will slow the buttons on.
Okay.
And on cancer.
Cancer saying in both case we want to say it's a visibility to false.
Thank you.
So when user type something on the label, say this one.
So when you type something, something on the body.
When they type, yeah.
When they click here.
Right.
So in that when they do that, we closed the monitor.
And then you can serve the custom with as well.
So let me actually save this like this as it is.
And then so you can see the model looks like that.
Now you don't want to show this, okay?
In general, you just want this to work.
So at the moment it works.
You can see beautiful.
Now, one thing I want to fix is I want to hide these buttons.
So for that, you can use which are no.
So that will hide them.
And you can see the width is here this big with no.
If you want to make it bigger, probably it's a good idea to make it bigger and bigger.
So it's a preview of the post.
So let's make it bigger by passing a custom size.
So with again, person seven 2900 just use 17.
Now that looks bigger and it's a bit wider.
Now we don't have any content on it.
So the content here.
So in the model, we want to show the title.
Right.
So that's it.
Page one title.
And then you want to show the feature they miss.
Later at the moon, we don't have.
We want to show the editor and it's the content.
Now, this one again.
Let me just go back to my editor here.
And let me just copy everything here.
I guess I am in control of that.
Replace that.
So we need to use the team so that we leave.
That default value will be content.
And we didn't need to upload and content because this is only for sharing.
So we'd only make it true.
If you don't do, then it will be editorial content, which is not something you want to read.
Only true.
All right.
So let's have a look.
That's how we can show the preview in this monologue until we have the content heading into the editor.
You could show the categories as well if you want to him.
Now let's try.
You can see the previous year we get the title.
We got the quantum.
Awesome.
Now if you ask for the categories or again the same this select component.
All you have to do is copy that and put it here.
But I think that's not necessary.
It's clearly here.
So we just saw the total country also.
Okay.
And so we are ready to send the store back in.
So let's work on the a function that works, that gets executed.
When the department is clean.
Now we don't even have the buttons.
Let's create a button that is called something like this, called published.
And then we make a request to a back end with the title content categories, and then we send it so
that we can start saving in the database.