Let's go ahead, create the Get Tibet story.
And here you can see I have deployed only the backing.
But you can do backing in front in both.
Get.
So that is one thing you can do in addition to this one.
This one I did only for backing.
But let's do it for both.
Back in.
Turned it.
So did.
So I have all these projects, so let me create a new repository.
Let me call this a Demi Eden me server.
And you can make it private.
You can make it private.
You pledge to recreate the monetary.
All right, so we just need to follow these commands to get in it.
We have to initialize our project with and get our local project here.
And that is it's open here.
You can see I'm inside subfolder and here I'm inside.
Client four So let's deploy server now.
So here, first thing I can do is get in it.
Thank you.
So now it is initialize with git repository.
Then let me just make it small so you can see here.
Next command is git and
get and everything get.
And indeed, to get started, let's have a look at the status.
All of them have been added.
Make a comment to give you give your comment a name.
It commits and it's ready to deploy.
And then.
Get runs, men.
Let's try that.
It's the command you have to to get remote and everything followed by the euro and then finally get
push DSU origin main.
Great.
Know, your code base must have been deployed from your local computer to GitHub and I'm pretty sure
you had the git ignore files.
I guess so.
Let me just double check.
Ian ve get ignore to make sure you have the git ignore file and there you should have these two folders,
this folder and this file.
You don't want to commit to GitHub because this file will contain sensitive information.
So I supposed to show you this one early before we make a commit, but I'm pretty sure you had this
one.
If not, maybe you want to go to the folder
folder here and you should be able to see the hidden files.
Maybe just tried to just delete this, did fine, and then go through the steps again.
So if you by mistake didn't have those this get ignore file, but otherwise everything is perfect.
Okay, so that's for certain.
It has been pushed to GitHub.
Let's give a reference in C and you can see, you know, code base here.
Beautiful too.
That's for server.
And now let's create one more for client.
If we go ahead, create another repo.
This one is for client.
Did me client make it private?
Create.
All right, now let's go through the same step.
This time we want to go inside clean fuel.
You can get in and get and get committees and
ready to deploy.
By the way, this is the same steps you'll follow next time when you make some changes to your project.
After you do get Ed, get comment and then get push to pursue changes to GitHub.
And then from this lesson, you will get pull to pull the changes.
All right.
So this is the first time, so we have to follow this one as well.
So let's try that.
Detriment and origin that euro jet pose and origin may.
Perfect.
No, give refresh.
We should have the fondant as well.
Beautiful.
All right, that's perfect.
Now, let's continue here and let's see what we have to do next.
So we have.
So we had the getting file that was also written here, which is good.
All right.
And then we.
In this tutorial, I used Bitbucket, but it works for both.
I guess that means we have our project in GitHub.
That's perfect.
Our next step is to install Node and NPM in this lesson.
Right.
So that is the next.