So we want to show the list of comments here.
And also I want to get the response.
We want the user information and not just diety.
So let's go go to our back end.
It's going to be the control function we created to create form.
So once we create a new new comment, we're sending that as a response.
Now, before we do that, let's use broccoli.
Okay.
So new comments.
So we're going to make changes to this variable and let's change that from concept to let me comment
dot.
I me commit equals two weeks
away.
So this new comment, it's it's the mongoose model.
You know, you can see this is this entire the model is pulling this variable.
So we can actually use this as a model.
So our new comment, don't build to the end.
Use it like this to populate.
And in our case, we want to populate.
Posted my.
So we want to populate the user's name I.D. We don't have to it will automatically include so just that.
All right.
And then we send this new comment.
But this time, the information has populate.
All right, so let's try one more time.
It's cool.
Now the user info is returned.
Most.
Let's see this time you can see now this post and why it's not just data but we have their user information
name and then 80.
Beautiful.
All right.
So that's good.
When we create a new comment, we immediately give that comment.
So obviously we are putting that in.
The comments are safe.
All right.
So you can see, oh, here we going to put that we are putting that in the commentary each time a new
comment is created.
However, when we load the space for the very first time that this post may already have comments,
right?
So we need to be showing that.
So at the moment we don't have that yet because if you go to your controller one more time, let's go
to post.
Let's see what End Point is giving us this single post.
So for that again, let's go here.
Let's go all the way down.
So this is how we getting the single post so you can see posts less slow.
All right.
So let's have a look at that.
We can start from the root.
So to get out to get the post posts, let's look.
So this is the one single post.
All right, let's have a look in the single post.
Control of once single post.
In a single post.
It's not sending the comments.
And then you just take the moral.
We need to make sure we have.
Comments in the model.
Oh yeah.
Unfortunately we don't have because when I was building this app, even in the beginning, I didn't
think about adding comments.
But that's fine.
What we can do is we can add, No.
Actually, I just realized that we don't need to have the comments over here.
That's because a comment is a a new document, the economic model.
We have the common model already.
You can see.
So.
We can query the comment comment model and try to find all the comments for any post.
You know, we just need the post daily so we can find all the comments based on the Post A.D. and we
written all the comments that belongs to this post.
Okay, this is better.
Actually, this is much better.
So that's great.
That means let's go back here to single post.
So whenever we are sending the single post.
So we have the single post now, not just the post.
We want to send the comment as well.
All right.
So let's see how we can find all the comments that belongs to this post.
So what we can do here is we can use the comment model find.
Now only differences we can find based on the post side.
Right.
So we have the post idea property in the comments model.
So we find both post idea and the value we give is this one single most beautiful.
So this will give us all the comment because you can find the comments based on the post 80, which
is at this post 80 right here we giving the value.
So now, now that we have that, when we send the JSON response, we can send post and.
Dick comments.
Now let's use the object posts.
Post comments.
Okay.
So now that we have made this change, we have to slightly change how getting the data in the front
end.
But now that.
Great.
Now we can actually do one more thing here.
Dot populate again the comments that don't actually populate the user's information.
They just have the posted by ID.
So each comment when we are sending we want to show the user net who created the comment.
Right.
To limit clearly so the finished happy.
You can see whenever we shrink the list of comment we need to show the user's name.
The user should be different.
Right.
So that means we need to populate.
Dot, populate.
And we just need to populate the name.
All right.
So we we're sending the comments instead of ideally sending the actual user information.
And then so let's sort the comments based on the newly created ones.
We want to be them on the top.
So created and mentioned.
All right.
And we sending both post and comment now.
Now with this tens.
If it come here, give it reload.
It will probably it will not work again.
You can see it.
We have issues.
That's because now you.
We're not getting the post.
This data has data Deutsche Post and data documents.
All right.
So what you need to do is data Deutsche Post.
So that's what you need to do because that's how you're sending the object.
Okay.
Now, with this change, it will work.
I can see how that works.
Now, that also means that we should be getting the comments as well.
So let's return the post comment as well, which should be done in the comments.
Thank you.
So these comments we can.
Access that you.
And then we can render all the comments so we can render the comments right after this comment form.
Right.
So we can.
Let me just use preprint on.
Comments.
Let's have a look at it.
We have material in.
Give it a reload.
Comment has already been declared.
So we looks like we have some naming conflict.
Okay.
That's right.
Because we call it comments.
And then we are receiving the common sense.
So there's a naming conflict.
Let's not change the state in selecting this.
So instead of calling comments, let's call it post comment.
Let's come down here.
Let's give this as props post comments again.
Now we can access post comments,
post comments, and then that value will be the comments that here.
Right.
So instead of away we use post comments.
Beautiful.
All right, let's keep it a reload.
All right.
We have the comment form and then.
Empty area of comment so something's not worked.
So let's have a look, you know.
Control us.
Single post comments.
It's continual love.
Let's see what we get here.
Reload.
Go here.
We have the MTA.
We?
Post IED.
Let's have a look how we saved the comment.
Quick comment.
Content posted.
So that's that's the issue.
So we've saved it as posted.
Should we post D right soon before stating.
That is request body request for arms for say.
So that's the reason.
Now, now that we are saving the post idea, I think this time once we know start saving it should work.
Single post we finding on the post.
Based on the post only.
So this time it's a dog.
Let's give it a try.
Let's read a few comments.
And comment.
You can see immediately we have this new comment.
Second comment.
So this happens whenever we create a new comment, we push that.
So right here.
We put that to the comments in the state, but now we need to make sure we give them when the beast
loads for the first time.
Let's try for.
It's really slow in the development mode.
Can it populate?
Because it is not in your schema.
That is less a single.
So it's glued to the controller single post.
Cannot populate.
Making silly mistakes.
It's not popular.
It should be posted.
But
hopefully you you notice that.
Awesome.
I can see.
When we load the pope the bush for the very first time, we give them an A whenever we create that time,
once we give them there's one more thing I need to show you.
And that is if you go to the dashboard, go to all post trying to edit the post, you will not get the
post.
That's because we have changed how the post is sent.
Right?
So let's go.
Let's fix them.
That one is basis.
So that's that's in the components that's posts and post.
So here we're making requests to give that post.
And this time here we are getting data don't post, don't title.
So since we have, we're returning to object post and comment.
So here we need post.
So dot, dot, dot post.
I guess so let's make sure we add then data dot post and same here.
Doesn't.
Don't.
Postcode categories are used to hear and then hear everything we are accessing.
Previous stats data we need to make tends to Dr. Dawson to know it walks into.
It.