All right.
So the next thing we want to implement here is add the social sphere feature.
So we have the post and let me take you to the finished version.
So if it's good post, so if you visit any site, you see that we have the options to share on social
networks.
For example, if I click on Facebook, that will grab this link and share on Facebook, I know you can
see here.
So for that, what we can do is we can use this package from NPM and boom let's search for react there
shows.
Answer.
This is the one of you to use.
Check out the demo.
I guess that's the term.
All right, so let's insert this one.
In our current project.
Let's run this.
And while it's happening, that's cool.
So we want to show those social sphere options in our base.
We were showing the single poster good places post slow and we want to show them and let's show them
just under the heading.
So we have the heading matter content and here we can sort.
Thanks to right here.
So let's go.
So we have the written block.
We have the the heading, we have the meta information, we have the content just before the content.
We can do so here.
Okay.
Let's import
import here.
So?
So from the act, sir.
So soon.
And it's come down here.
So here we want to let screw to do a screw to div let's have a bit of a margin on top margin top if
you have a big gap.
I guess.
So let me just and during a piece of this how I did it earlier turn a big sell and margin bottom.
15.
We can only change these venues.
Let's see how this looks so here, says Shorten.
Do we want to use this in here?
The first thing we want to do is give the URL.
So when you want to sit on any of the social networks, we have to give them the URL.
Now the yellow should be the current URL, right?
So at the moment when we try to share local host, obviously it doesn't work.
Because localhost runs in our computer locally, it's not on the Internet, it's not available on the
web.
But it's later when you deploy this application and have a real domain, then obviously you can share
this.
Okay.
Otherwise, at the moment, if you said obviously people want the big they don't get anywhere.
So we need to grab the quarantine URL, right?
So we can do that using window that looks and it has to work.
Now before we try to access that, let's make sure we are in the client environment since we're using
Nexis so we can take processed start.
Brazil and.
Persistent rise and windowed dark location, dark highchair.
I said that will give us the current year.
Next one is so-so types, so we can choose on what platforms you want to share.
So for example, if you want on Facebook, you can just leave Facebook.
You can just leave it like that.
But we want to share other platforms like Twitter already and LinkedIn.
All right.
So that's social types and that is all we need.
We just need the euro.
And so sometimes if you come here, let's run the south.
And we may need to adjust some styling the height and width, but otherwise should work.
Okay.
So we have modern, not found causes.
Let's make sure we improve the right way.
First result from React shows.
I could not find a declaration.
Five Amodu.
Kind of friend of mine.
You.
Not sure why it's happening.
Maybe we have to into causes to try to ensure that.
Beautiful.
You can see we have the icons now since we're using the dark theme.
Because they have this by default.
And so we should change that.
But otherwise you can see you can copy the current euro beautiful code refactoring editor to this the
slow.
If you visit another post.
Let's try this one.
You can see the other changes.
So that's perfect.
We can copy and here or we can just click here and there.
Right now, it doesn't work at the moment because the local hosts you can't use.
So we getting the invalid here but when you have the real domain in proximity to block no we don't want
to show this field.
Right.
So if you want to include maybe Aston Martin and top two, you can leave it like this.
But I want to just so that I can type.
Don't worry about all this.
So let me a right.
I'm saying you.
That worm is here and it's at a at some style.
So style.
Height.
Let's set it to 100 pixel.
We don't want the all the heights of this city.
200 overflow
hidden in background.
No.
All right.
Let's have a look.
You can see background is none.
How do we set it to online and offline?
So we have this beautiful social seer icons.
Beautiful.