All right.
So now we're going to work on the signing phase, which will also require a similar form, but with
this form of support.
So the dark thing, it's pretty nice here, you can see.
All right, let's go to Santa.
We can pretty much reuse the same code.
All right.
So to make things easier, let's just copy this code.
Copy the entire component.
We could even try to reuse this and we could.
However, you can see, it's pretty straightforward.
All we have is the form component and the the input files.
There's not much happening.
So there's there's no harm in reusing the similar code for displays as well.
Just to keep things simple.
But obviously later, if you feel like you're not just doing some extra work and making reuse of the
same foam in both components, obviously you can do that.
All right.
So we have a sign.
A sign?
And conversely, let's send this to sign in.
By the way, I will show you how you can reuse components.
There will be many situations I this course where you will be reusing components, especially for images
upload.
You know that time we will be using reusing the same component multiple times.
So that is also covered, obviously.
All right.
So we got decided.
Now let's change the heading.
From sign up to sign in.
Then we want to turn this button from register to log in and.
If they want to.
If they haven't registered it, then we can ask them to sign up so we can take them to sign a petition
here.
Let me see what I have written here.
No, it was good to sign up.
You can see our register now and we have the followed password link as it was looking to use as well.
So.
Words to know.
And let me answer this competition and put right under the button.
You can see just like that for bustle, because believe it or not, we will have that feature as well,
something that you always need in a real world application.
So you learn how to do that.
So I just.
So this one's for for what
most of this place we don't have at the moment, but we will have soon.
So let's just leave it like this.
Let's have a look.
It's good logging in.
Now we have this space logging.
So we want to put that on top and then the bottom.
All right, so let's fix that up.
Otherwise, looks good so we can go to sign up or signing.
So here is this link cut from here we put on top of the button.
Probably on top of the form item.
Okay.
See that?
Let's have a bit of a line as you.
Sometimes you need to have to lambrecht.
All right.
Perfect.
Okay.
It's a similar form we used in the sign up and side in every log in.
If you try it, you get the same result.
We can have a look and then on the sign.
And we also don't need a name.
We just need the user's email and password to log in.
All right, so let's remove that first.
From.
I don't have the name.
Awesome.
So we just need email password obviously to the world.
Let's try one at the gym from some password.
Log in.
You can see we get the value.
Beautiful.
Now all we need is our backing.
So we need a backing so that we can send this information.
So that our end can save in the database.
You know, that's how we create a user.
And then we will apply the authentication, you know, when the log in.
Basically, when they log in, we will take the user's email.
We try to find the user based on the email and take the password that is already saved in the database,
which will be assessed in the hashed version.
So we take this split password, has it, and then compare this one with the one that is already saved
in the database.
And if the match that means we have the right to use it, we can allow the user to log in.
All right.
So that's how we going to implement all this.
So let's take a rest.
And in the next lecture, we're going to generate our backing.
Now, that might sound too good to be true, but that's what we're going to do.