All right.
So let's try this e-mail feature as well.
So in a tick and when I send a valid email so it's important you need to send the used a valid email
so that the email can be delivered, right?
So first of all, let me go to the database and delete this user because this user, it's already created.
Morency to Linda in that.
Okay.
Now, before I try submit, let me just come back here in my control.
And here, let me just go to the top first.
Make sure we have seen.
All right, so we have that.
So we're going to use SendGrid to send to email.
So if we're going to send an email, so first we can prepare the email.
So when we prepare the email, it should have the, the, from, from where it's sending to who is receiving
those email addresses and then the subject and the body of the email.
So I can put that in a variable email, Don.
So I can't.
Do we need do we need from.
We need a subject.
And then we need his team, his body, so we can send them.
Also to that will be this user, the user's email, the one we have.
So we're going to queer this user.
So that email, that's why I said make sure to use the valid email because that's where it will be sent.
So it should be valid now from now.
This from is really important.
Okay.
So from if you remember in the very beginning when we sign up to send SendGrid, we had a verified email,
right?
So that when we put in our N refer manasi a message symbol dot com.
So we used the similar just to sign up to send and send it ask us to verify the email address.
Right.
So, and we use that email to verify it.
So they send us the link.
We Clinton the league email us verify.
So only this discounts an email.
Okay so this email from here from it will always be processed or invited email from okay so make sure
we have that verified email that you used previously.
Now when you sign up for SendGrid and verify the email, use that here.
I guess that's important subject.
Let's call it account
create.
Right so when admin many liquid user then we send them the email account created and his team an email
going to compose you could use basic you could just send a text like this as well but we can use has
time, so let's use back text and here in the back text we want to we can put some page one has to write
some standard his email email.
So on his one we can write hi.
And we can use the user's name.
So in practice we can put all these variables using the syntax here.
I'm going to use.
So we have the users.
His name.
Let me just use a Peter.
And he lets the youth see him as a comment been.
Created it successfully.
I was calling this one, put it on me and I can show the log in details as you see your log in details.
That didn't make it through this one.
Slogan details.
I can certainly use this email and the use as possible.
All right.
So email that that will be the email, right.
So that's fun and password.
Again, we send the password now if you want you can create some of as well.
So start equal to email.
Make it let's make it call.
Wait and let me do the same for password.
That's a start.
For which.
All right.
And we didn't see one thing here.
It's it's it's often but what we can say is since we are many of a generation, the password may be
user 1 to 2 in the password.
So let's say we do recommend you to change your password after you log.
Let's make it smart.
All right.
So this is the email we want to send to the user.
So if we create this email data and we want to send this in Mendonca, and for that we can use SendGrid.
Right.
So let's try.
Get in there.
Console.log.
And so what are we going to try here?
Is we going to
use a we send we need mail.
$0.01 and we give this in.
No funding cuts and low.
All right.
So that's all you need to send the email now.
Let's give it a try to make sure the email is sent.
Now, of course, for the email to be sent to you, use the valid email address.
You use the verified email in the from field and you need to make sure that you haven't exposed the
send secret key anywhere in GitHub repository or anything like that.
Otherwise that would be invalid.
I guess in that case you can again generate another one, go to the SendGrid and then just generate
a new key.
So let me try.
This looks like we've got some issues.
I just cannot access password before initialization.
Line two.
One, two.
Basil.
Okay.
Passports.
Thanks to the password it actually has phosphor but we're not saying it has burst.
Was obviously passed for.
I think what we need to do here is put this block.
Cut it out and we put on top before we actually use here to grow to use it.
So let's just move here.
All right, so he has the password.
If we send the e-mail as well.
And then we're going to save.
Because at this point, we can save the user because we will detect if the user exists.
I guess in that case we can send the email and then continue saving the user in the database.
The reason we have that issue is because we distribute password like this.
So unless we could, we could actually, instead of using rest, we could just manually sent the response
like response system like for example, user
email user don't in.
So we could send like that, right?
So the name is the name.
So we could send the response like this.
So this user has been created and we send the created you this information.
We can send it like this.
What if we do it like this?
Then the password is already here.
The variable so that conflicts here.
So within this block, if we can put it here, so we can just put it on top like this.
Okay, so let's give it a try and it's try submit images taken.
So looks like.
Yeah, even though we had the issue, it was actually created, the user was created telling me this
difference.
Let's delay it from here and try one more time just so that we can see if the email will be sent.
I said that has been deleted.
Let's try.
User created successfully.
That's good.
Let's take the email.
I guess if we got this email account created for some reason, if you don't see it here, make sure
to go to your.
Spam folder and ticket.
All right.
So we got that.
Looks safe.
Hi, Ryan.
The author does her name.
You see, this account has been successfully created.
Logon deduces even.
That's password.
Beautiful.
All right.
So with this information, the user can log into the application.
All right, let's give it a try.
So this user, the admin created manually, right?
So let's say this user got the email, he tried to log in.
He should be able to.
U.S.A. and he's author.
So we redirect him to author page.
But obviously that doesn't exist for D.A. This works beautifully.