All right.
So we had some lengthy explanation about our server.
If their medical fees don't work, once we start making requests and analyze are calling our back and
it makes perfect sense.
And later we will be creating our own models for out of control assessments.
So once you do it a few times, you'll get fully comfortable.
All right, so before we do anything, we actually are almost ready to send a request to back in and
start saving the user in the database.
But before we do that, we want to make sure we have the correct values here.
So if we have MongoDB installed locally in your computer, you could do something like this.
MongoDB equals less less localhost 270176 less.
The name of your project.
It can be anything.
All right, so if you have the MongoDB, it's locally.
This is something you could do, and that's all you set with the data.
However, if you don't have it, you can always use Mongo Atlas, which is not of us as a service in
the cloud.
Let me quickly.
So first, I'm going to show you how to install.
TV.
In case you are interested, I recommend you to install locally.
It's much easier.
You don't have to keep signing up for Mongo Atlas every time you want to create a new project because
you get only one free connection.
So you can always go to the official docs and they have the instruction, whether it's for Windows or
Mac.
All right.
So if it is for Windows, you take it on.
If it's a mac, you take the link.
So it's for windows.
You can download the community edition, you can download using this link and go to all this instructions
step by step.
If you run into some issues, you can Google it and most likely you will find your solution in the Stack
Overflow or some ghetto issues too.
It should be good to go following this guide and if you're a mac you can use homebrew to install.
MongoDB.
Right.
So you can install boot and run this.
Come on to install it in your computer.
All right.
So that's if you want to install locally, but if you don't want to go through all that hassle, which
is a one time hassle and it's always easy, but you can always check out the Mongo Atlas.
Right?
Similar atlas.
And it's don't always click on the ad because it takes you to some random pages that's makes you lost.
So click here.
MongoDB Dirt comes at the start of this week.
You.
And you can sign in.
You see, you can sign in if you already have an account.
If not, sign them.
So I'm going to just use one of my existing icon to sign up.
You can log in with Google, which is the easiest option.
However, I'm going to.
I actually am going to log in with a little.
It's so much easier if you don't have a fresh account that you want to use.
Maybe just quickly create one email account just for the purpose of this course and just use this so
much easy.
So let me log in with Google and I'll get back to you.
All right.
So I have logged in using a new email I just created for this project.
And when you sign up for the first time and you get a little bit of different screen, you see something
like that and that's I saved and submit the privacy policy.
But once you have already created, I can't do it will look a little bit different.
So you'll learn directly to your dashboard based on what we need sending up.
For the first time, you might see some extra windows.
Like, for example, do this window, you know, celebrate extra because it's a first time.
All right.
So what is your goal today?
Build a new application.
What type of application?
It's content management.
That's the or is it preferred language, languages, JavaScript finishes.
So we want to use the free one.
So let's hear it.
Yeah.
So you get this option so you don't really have to do anything.
It's anyways chosen by default.
The free plan we're using.
I believe in Australia.
So Sydney's chosen.
But if you're living in some other countries it might Senate or the Senate.
So it basically means there's several will be near your location so you can have better performance
at a level like that.
You don't have to do anything.
The only thing you might want to do here is give your classroom a name.
Let's call it modern in this.
All right, so let's all create a cluster.
We get 512 and we're free, rather.
All right.
How would you like to authenticate your connection to on a MongoDB connection to your shrink?
So that is the one you get which you can just put in your Ian Macfarlane, start to connecting a database.
And for that you need to create a username and password.
Now don't get confused that username and password with your actual account.
That's a different the username and password you used to log in.
That's different.
This is different.
I did this just for the connection.
So let's call it.
Let me just keep it simple.
Ryan and password.
What happened to the bus?
Lead me out to dinner at the password.
Copy the password.
Come back here and let me just based here.
Just so that I didn't forget.
Because it's really important.
You don't lose it.
All right, so we got the username and password created.
A user.
This user is we'll be used to using the Mongo TV connection history.
Okay, so it's done.
Next one.
Where would you like to connect my local environment?
All right, I'll even link that IP address.
You can add your current IP or you can choose all from anywhere, I guess.
This 10.0.00.
Honestly, we like that.
I get to later, I'm going to added a different IP so that we are allowed to get it from anywhere.
Okay, so let's finish and close.
I can go to the desk for now.
This is the desk.
Where do you see when you log in the next time?
Only the first time we had to go through all that question answers.
So it takes about 3 minutes to provision.
So let me take a break.
I'll be back once it's done.
Okay.
Surprisingly, it didn't take even 10 seconds, which is something new, because before I had to wait
like 10 minutes.
So MongoDB is doing good.
They didn't read it.
Okay, so you can see now you get this these options to connect, we need a connection trying to click
here and I should click here and then we want to choose this option connected application and you get
these connections.
ST This is what we need.
I said, let's copy that, copy that and close.
Beautiful.
Now let's put that here.
So that is the connection strings.
That is the one we need.
And this will give us access to MongoDB in the cloud, which is pretty amazing.
Now write this the name in the password that we created earlier, if you remember.
So this is the password we had.
So let me take this password and put here instead of password.
All this bit, including the brackets.
Delete that and base to use a password.
Beautiful.
That's how you got the username and password that you've created before.
Here.
Just for this note, I was going to say thanks.
That is all you need.
Name, password.
And.
You can leave everything like this.
Beautiful.
That's all we need for database connection.
Now those colleagues.
And once you start saving something in your database, once we start saving users, then you'll be able
to see all the data here by going to that.
Browse collection as what I get.
And then here you can see the collection.
At the moment we don't have anything.
It's empty now.
You might still have some issues and if you have some collection issues or let's come here and have
a look into the Security Network.
Access six.
You may need to enter your IP includes current ABC.
Let me.
Click on this one.
And what I want to do is you could use our current IP.
But I'm going to.
Enter IP address ops.
And this is.
Previously, they had one option that would allow you to connect from anywhere.
Looks like they a that probably you can try using this option which will detect your IP address and
put it here and you can just save.
All right.
So they will leave it like this.
I think this will work.
Let's have a look.
If not, just try that.
Just enter.
Click this button that will pre-populated your IP and this thing.
All right.
And next time when you logon, you probably land.
And this is always good here to browse the collections.
And if you want to get the connection string again, you go here, connect, get it from there again,
the same thing.
And if you want to update the the password, you can go to on down to this axis.
This is the user we created you can edit iTunes is password is all right beautiful excluded database
browse collections who did have anything at the moment now with that since anytime you make any changes
to any file, make sure to restart your server.
I guess that's really important.
So let me go.
It's a running pygmy store and let me start.
And hopefully this time we don't get this connection there.
How good is that?
I can see here that it is connected.
This text is coming from.
This one is coming from here.
The end to point here we connect.
If there is any issues we control of the error or those we print out these sticks to be connected.
So in our case, it has been connected successfully, which is absolutely amazing.
That's what we've done with our set up for MongoDB on the next legs on the next and let's sign up to
send route so that we can send the immune cells over and then we're going full speed with our project.
We're going to send requests from here.
Start signing up, signing in and all that amazing stuff ahead.