All right.
So now we have this fight, we have these tabs, we have these companies.
Next thing we do is actually work on the implementation of invisible reversal.
We're going to use one endpoint in the back end that will expect the images data.
So from data we will be sending emails as a form data.
So we need to create the routes and the control function, but we just need one in the back end.
But in the front end, we're going to have these two, two components.
One will have the single route, one will have multiple routes, and it will alter so all the the media
libraries.
All right.
So here we I think we have to change the name of route files to just file.
I'm sorry about that.
I was expecting that to be multiple upload, but instead we're going to have the multiple library in
the library and it'll support the drag and drop as well.
So we just got a singular single number file and media flow.
All right.
So let me quickly take it to the end events, official documentation, and we're going to use the upload
component for uploading single images, which you can see here.
That's for uploading single single file and this one for multiple files you can click or drag.
But for both of them, we just need one endpoint in the back in two that makes things easier.
And we basically upload to cloud an area and that will give us the you are right.
So let me just search you upload.
You can see so this is the button, this is the functionality you can turn on to call.
So we're going to use that one for single upload and for multiple upload.
We'll be using this one and not that one.
So this one to click and drag.
So let's quickly have a look at this one.
So single upload, it can take out the code.
This one looks a little bit different.
So how it works is they have this component of and it receives the props.
You you pass props.
So props.
This is where this is the props.
Okay.
So this is the props.
This is basically an object.
Now it has all these file properties, the name X and two X and basically will be the endpoint of your
server, which will upload the image and give you the response, the uploaded image, you know, and
have this you can turn the token in the house and whenever a user uploads on iTunes, the file is received
like this one.
I can.
So you can track the status if it is uploading, if it is done.
So that happens on tens.
But the most important one here is you have the X and this is the endpoint that that's where the file
will be sent.
All right.
And if you want to send the token, you have the header.
So this is how we are going to upload the image using this component.
All right.
So let's give it a try.
So it's good to upload a file sampler file.
So first thing you want to do is import that from and
import upload form and and along with that you want to import button as well.
I need that.
And let me just quickly down to here.
Looks like we need to import the messages as well from and that will be used to.
So the message to the user when it is uploaded, it is uploaded to that message to so that we can import
messages which is which comes with.
And so that's important as well.
So here what we want is we want to have the access to the authentication as well.
So we need to import context.
The reason for that is the upload route in the back end will be secured.
So we need to send the token, right?
So otherwise anyone can upload so we can leave the road open like that.
So it must be for the logged in use only.
So that means to send the token in the heritage just like you can in the example.
To do that we need to have access to the context.
Let's import
our context from
this context.
So we go one step, two step of.
Context of.
And let's also make sure we empower youth context to.
Okay.
And we also want to approve import the icon of your icon from Aunt
Metro in this called upload outline.
I did so with that.
Let's.
First access to the context so that we can give the token context of CET Article six, context or context
and give us the oath.
We can grab the token from that.
Then we can return.
So let's return the upload component to upload.
So here, just like you saw in the documentation process, we have to use that so we can describe that
second process.
So we'll come back to it.
So the first and then this one actually you can use for multiple upload as well.
See, we're going to just limit to one, but you can.
Yeah.
Do multiple upload as well.
So mix count to make it just one.
We can give it one.
The reason we're doing this is we're going to have the media library where we're going to have the drag
and drop multiple approach.
So we want to make it just for one upload, single upload, SIMEX second one.
And then here basically we just need a button that says something, right?
So button and we can call it click to upload.
Okay.
And then Barton, he can give the I can do the Barton that one upload our client.
I guess we need to work on the props, but otherwise we should have this component visible with the
button.
Let's try.
Objects are not valid and signed.
Okay.
So then that was a bit confusing.
So what happened is it's the issues in the botnet.
When I click, we get that of the child.
If you meant to render a collection of children are using a reinstall.
The problem is it's in the button.
So I took the button and I realized that you can see the icon.
It's actually be a component to it.
I can is treated as a component, so we have to use it like that.
So that was the problem.
So things like this can be a little confusing, but hopefully you don't run into issues like this a
lot.
Okay.
So I just had to use it as a component with that.
You know, it works out.
We have this button when we click it to open up this the file browser so we can find the images and
upload.
All right.
So that means for this to work, obviously we have to work on this process, just like we saw in the
official documentation.
We have to.
Make a request to the backhand in the accent to that's going to be the API endpoint and then we can
send the token, we can handle the on tens as well.