All right, so let's work on showing the user role and the number of posts.
So we've got that description.
After the description, we can again use the meter.
So let me just copy that.
Here we use here to turn from.
And that seems to use a room.
Now I want to do one more thing and that is you can see I'm currently.
Logged in, and that's.
That's me.
So I don't want to.
Delude myself.
I said it doesn't even work.
But I also want to.
Excited to kick another year.
So I want to disable this delete and delete a link here so that it's here.
Currently disabled, so disabled if the user turned on the school I.D., the consequence equals odds.
Don't you jumped in the sky.
So if it is the same user, then I want to disable that.
So that looks great.
All right.
So finally, we're going to show the number of post that a user have created.
Now, this is something we didn't plan earlier, so the user model doesn't actually have the posts properly.
So we have to quickly go and fix that.
But let's see how we can show that first and then we can do fix that.
So let's copy that based here.
So user
posts.
So we take here because this project doesn't exist.
If we have user dots posts, then don't let we try to access the length.
And let me put everything and said back to.
Post.
All right.
So we trying to slow the number of posts the user had.
Now you can see here undefined post.
So because we don't have the post properly on the user hit.
So if we don't have the length, then maybe we just should zero here in the upper.
All right.
So let's go and try to fix this one.
So what happens is whenever the new post is created, we are saving the date of this, but we're not
assigning that to the user.
So each post heavy user, his post has the posted device.
So we know the post has been created by which user we know that.
However, when we try to find all the post of any user, then it gets tricky because as you can imagine,
how do we find all the posts that belongs to a particular user?
For example, if I have created five post.
How do they now query that?
Because.
There's no post array in the user schema.
Right.
So it gets really difficult.
So what are you going to do?
Is we going to add the stop code in our back?
So it's cool controls post, go to create post.
So whenever we are creating the post at that time, we want to post this newly created post ID to the
user's array of posts.
So before we actually even work on this one, it's good in the model, user model and add the post array.
So as you can see here, we previously didn't think about this one, so we don't have that.
But that's all right.
So let's add hosts array and this array will have the array of posts, right?
So each object will have the will be the type of object.
And so whenever we are saving anything here into the user's post array, we are just saving the post
ID.
That's all we need because later we can populate to get the entire post if we want.
All right, so add this so that we can start saving the post 80 to the user's post.
So we are used to make this change and then go back to your control.
And go to that create post function.
We post a sort of note on the off control screw to post control create post.
So here it's called we don't.
In this set I am not here.
We are creating a new post.
We saved the post and then we send the response before we send the response to the post.
IED to users posts read.
Okay.
So here's what we can do.
First, we find the user of each user find by D and update.
Or we get the logged in new society.
So we friend the user by adding because this push create function.
Let me just quickly go to the world.
Post.
Create boost to.
We have the requests and so obviously we get the user idea.
So we find the user vicinity and we want to use this newly created post IED to this user's posts.
So for that, we can use this property.
We could use PWS.
This is a special property.
We could use that bot post.
We'll
post the duplicate IDs as well, which use it, which is not something we have to worry here.
However, let's use another property called ADD to set out.
The beauty of this special function is that it will not save any duplicate IDs.
All right.
So let's use add to set instead of post.
So here we want to post to the posts array.
And what we want to use is the idea of the post that is just created.
Okay, so that's on the net.
Now it's time a new post is created that will be also pushed to the user's post re in the database.
So that means we can easily get on the post of that user.
We will know how many post the users have.
All right.
So that's this view.
I guess with that tense.
Let's go back to our index space here and here.
We should be able to show the list of just how many ports for use this has now.
But that do work, obviously, we have to start creating from now on because previously we didn't have
this record.
All right, so let me.
We sign on.
Counterfeit properties of known and many uses index 58.
I mean, uses index 58.
Okay.
So what do we need to do here?
If it's always good to use this syntax, if we have auth, then we execute it.
If we have a user, then we say.
Okay.
All right.
So let me ask Logan.
That's awesome.
Juan Gonzalez I think we have this year or maybe two capture later on not.
Okay.
So I just had a look at my server console and noticed that there is an error.
So let's fix this one object that is not defined in the user model.
So let's go.
Oh.
Can't really see what he's.
Using modern object I.D. so we have to distract something to seconds object 80 from schema dot types.
Okay.
Beautiful.
Now let's try.
These hues actually exist.
Beautiful.
Now, this user doesn't have any post.
Let's create a few posts.
I mean, just copy some dummy text from here and just copy that.
Turkey taken?
No.
So we've got issues here.
Users are different now.
So users learn to find.
That must be in our control.
All right.
It's important that.
Beautiful.
Let's try.
Title is taken.
All right.
So we got bigger issues as three posts.
Let me sign out.
Let me sign in as an admin.
Admins will also create one to create one.
All right.
I can see here.
Go to our users.
And you see here I have created one since we have made the to do list.
Previously I created many, but here you can tell I created one.
And that user, Ryan Arthur, created one.
All right.
So we had some issues in the the database at that time.
I think it wasn't executed.
So you can see one and one.
So let's try one more time.
Let's see one more and create one and let's make sure it works.
So I have credit to push so far this year and heavily.
You can see I had to post before.
So this is how you have been able to saw the users, the email there, all the post number posts.
And you can begin to implement, edit and delete in the coming video.