All right.
So also concrete boost.
And once the bush is created, we redirect them to cesspools that business and exist.
Let's go ahead and clear that one.
So that begins with the list of posts that belongs to that author.
And then we will allow him to update and delete that post just like we had four admin isolates.
Who didn't disclose on these?
We did have that base for our mentalist crew to have a look at that.
So bases and boosts index.
So you can see here.
So we have user fit that fits all the posts.
For admin, obviously we can phase on the posts, so that's fine.
But for other we have to create another route because we want to fit the post that belongs to the office.
So we have to create a new round that will give us the.
Currently logged in users on the post.
Instead of getting the entire database on the post from the database for admin.
Right.
So far though it's going to be different.
Edit again we can take them to edit this just like we use the create page so we can just use that.
Basically just import the component and that's how we're going to implement that delayed.
We have this delay as well.
So this one has can.
Update middleware has been applied to to work like that.
And finally, we just rendering in the layout, we are rendering the list of posts.
So this component shows all the posts in a list.
And actually we have the edit here.
That takes to the edit pace.
All right.
So let's go.
Let's try to use this quote from admin index, admin post index who's and good and good to also post
the scrutiny file called index.
In space study.
Okay.
So let's save and let's have a look what we get here.
So obviously this is Arthur.
So we have been redirected back because that is protected for admin only.
So we can change that.
It seems that from admin to also.
So.
I mean.
Copy and paste so off allowed.
Let's come down here.
Come back to the written block since then.
All the way down to.
No.
I should be able to access.
I'll post anything to you.
We go to the post now.
This user created just, I think two or three posts.
The rest of the post doesn't belong to this user.
So if it tries to enter delete, I'm sure I'll get an error because we have the middleware in our server.
So let's give it a try.
Let's let's see what happens.
Actually, you know, when we edit, we take them to the base and that base.
We haven't created that for Awesome.
That took them, took us to the admin base and we got redirected.
Okay, so that's fine.
We'll work on that.
Welcome to edit.
Let's try delete.
Obviously if I try, I'm sure I'd get an error.
In error.
Forbidden.
Except that forbidden in their training.
Obviously we've got to form it in there.
But if I tried to do it on my own, I should be able to.
Let me just try that.
And that's gone.
Beautiful.
So we've got ten books left.
Finding this one, we got nine posters so I can do on.
But without making any changes here, because you can see here this function is here and then we have
the middleware in the back end.
To delete is pretty good.
Reading the files, reading and getting the list of the posts.
So we want to create a new round in the back.
Into that we get only the post that belongs to this user.
Let's go quickly more than that one.
And then we'll come back and and, you know, implement.
The edit.
All right.
Still, it's good to see some.
Around sports.
Let's create a new post you wrote.
Walter, don't get.
We can call that this.
Call that.
Posts by awesome.
Right.
This will be for the love to new this require signing
posts by all.
So here with this meal we get the load in this society.
Now we're going to find the other post based on the the user side.
Because each post had the posted by property.
So we're going to find the post based on that property, get all the posts of this logged in user and
send as a response.
Now, this is really important from the control.
And this could use control.
You explore comments posts by also.
I.
Kit and Eric.
To hear.
What have you to do is be asking to query the posts of contest posts.
It could soon await post mortem find.
We are going to find out what are the institutions we going to find based on the posted birth posted
by and the values the logged in user site.
All right.
And then you want to populate.
So you want to populate.
Posted by.
You want to get the name?
I will automatically include some popular name for one of the categories.
By the way, all this.
We're not going to use here
but might be useful in doing the edit.
So.
Actually John Edwards also is not actually using.
Let's.
Let's do it anyways.
You can always just remove them to donate.
To
populate.
Featured image.
Just two year will be enough.
You want to start so that you get the new newly created ones on top.
So serve by created date and that is all that is over the next.
Now let's send return response to Jason posts.
All right, now we can make a request to this endpoint to get only the selected post that belongs to
this user instead of everything here.
All right.
Because this was originally intended for the end.
So let's go try and make my request to post by authorize.
To this front.
Okay, close.
Close.
Back to pieces author post index and here Facebook post that gets executed in a huge effect.
It seems that two posts by author.
Now you can see here I think this user had created to post we deleted so there's none.
Let's go ahead and try creating one and let's see if that holds.
Best move.
I.
Okay.
So this is still taking us to admin, so we have to fix that as well.
Let's quickly fix that.
So herein the return and new listings that do.
Seem to want to put some dummy text.
Right.
So you can just put anything.
Yeah, just write it.
Listen to what he wrote in his.
This creates some dummy posters for drawing nudes.
Right?
Some of this and you can see it.
This post is here because this user created this post.
Now, if he wants to delete this, he can do it.
Awesome.
So let me create.
Every great few points and then we're going to work on the edit.
Six of let's have some few.
She paused here so that we can work them.
By the way, here, Siemens should work abroad.
Let's try this one as well.
I feel it's probably.
Okay.
So I forgot to add the categories.
So that is something we can do in the edit section.
All right.
So let's work on that next.
So delayed.
Already works.
We saw that.
Now edit outside of work we just have to pass the pro just like we did before during the the decrease
in of the new post.
If you remember, you can see here we had to pass the basic props also.
So we have to pass something like that for edit as well.
Now that is happening.
Let's go back to index.
So also post index.
You can see all the posts we are showing in the post list component.
And that's where it is.
It's post has these links.
Edit in delete.
This did function is also executed.
Because we pass them as props and sing with the handle added.
We bussed them from here?
Oh, actually, we passed employment, so we didn't even have to pass the props because we actually
using the phosphate.
So that's even easier.
It says this off all you and that should work.
Right.
That's it.
Well, when the edit is clicked, we take them to SLAs.
Also less post posts, less the edit, which should be a base that is similar to what we have here.
And MinnPost Slaughter.
This way we can grab this slow, right?
So it's going to have a look.
Indeed.
Okay.
So we haven't actually refactored the code for edit.
So what?
We can do it just like we did before for creating a post on this code that we have for updating the
post, we can put it to a different component and try to reuse like reference and that would be much
easier.
All right.
So but now so far, we should be able to at least take the user to less authors, less post less the
slow pace whenever they click on edit.
So let's give it a try.
So if previously we were taken to the admin tool, we were automatically redirected.
But now you see we are in the author's last post less this slow.
So we are on the right place.
So let's implement the edit as well.
Now before we do that, we're going to refactored the code here in the admin.
All right, so let's go to admin busy admin post.
We have this post and it pays for admin.
So we're going to use this code refactor so that we can use it for authors as well.