Oh.
And so the next thing we're going to work on is a bit of a code refactoring.
That's because you can see here this dashboard is for user with the role of admins or admin can click
post categories media now and we can create users as well.
So now what do you want to do now is we want to make sure the user with the role of author he also has
access to the certain features.
For example, the author should be able to create a new post.
They should be able to see all his post.
He should be able to update or did his post not everyone else's, but just his post and the library.
Also, authors should be able to upload emails and delete the emails if that image has been deleted
by himself.
Right.
So not anyone else's, but just himself.
Yeah.
So on you just we don't need for authors are basically for post first categories and media.
These features will should be accessible for the user with the role of author as well.
All right.
So so far the way we have built the application, it is only focused for the one admin.
But now we have this concept of role based authorization.
So user with the role of author should have access to these bits as well.
So what are we going to do is we try to reuse these the code that we already have.
Right.
So instead of duplicating which would be which would not be a good idea to, you know, duplicate all
the features all over again for other what we can do is we can simply put our code in on a component
and then bring that component and put in the admin decimal places and also for other decimal places.
So basically all we have to do is move the code to a component and then just bring them.
And I saw in the user desperate that we just have to create two extra basis for author author and then
that's pretty much that's how it's going to work.
It's going to be very straightforward.
All right.
So let me show you what we're going to do here.
First, we have to refactor our code.
All right.
So we're going to start from post.
So it's good to pages.
Admin post.
Now at the moment we have the admin posts.
Right.
So you can see here.
What are you going to do?
Is we going to start from district to new?
So here admin is able to create a new post.
All right, so all this code we have in this space now, instead of keeping it in this space, we're
going to move it to a component and then just simply bring them here and then admin will be able to
create post.
The page will be authenticated only for the admin because all we need to do is wrap this component with
admin layout.
So all of this roll all the way from top.
The bottom of this quote, we can move to a component.
Okay.
And the same with the inputs in this function.
So we can move to a.
So let's see how this works.
Let's go to the components.
And it's called a new folder.
And let's call it the scrutiny for the four posts and then tell you it's good enough.
Let's call it new post component.
All right.
So here, basically, we pretty much want all the score to be there so we can copy all the code from
post new go to the new post component and paste here.
All right.
So let's start by changing the component name new post.
New post from former.
New post-Communist Soviet is the name.
The next thing we let's come down here and we have the layout, right?
So this layout we are going to put here instead we're going to put the layout in in here.
All right.
So that way it can be used for admin using admin layout and later it can be used for auto using auto
layout.
All right, so that's the idea.
So let's remove that and it's got all the way down removed from here.
Well, so we are returning this row and we just removed the layout and this layout had the authentication.
So if you have forgotten, let me quickly show you that just the components layout, admin layout.
So you can see here we basically returning the children props.
And before we do that, we have the tick.
We have the set loading.
We have the use effect.
It makes a request to back in to give the current admin that makes use this user have the role of admin
right.
So otherwise learning will be.
Otherwise we redirect them to the homepage.
So if loading we are showing the loading item.
And immediately we redirect to Homebase.
Otherwise we saw the content.
All right.
So we removed that layout.
We keep the row, and then from here.
So we can just remove that.
Thank you.
So now that we have moved our core to a new push component, let's go back to admin post new.
And here you want to let's start from the top.
You don't want any of this imported because all this has been moved there, right?
You don't want all that.
You don't want all these functions as well.
So this is our component name from there to.
All the way to return.
Yes.
On that code.
All those functions.
Some of that.
And then the admin laird.
We have the room.
We're going to remove all this row.
We have already moved this code here, so we just keep it clean like that again.
So what do you want to do now is we want to import the layout.
So import
admin layout from one step of custom.
All these two components.
Layout, admin lounge.
So we import layout and then we want to now import this component.
All right, so import new post component from components posts, new post component.
And then we put it here.
Simple as that.
Now let's give it a try.
Let's see if this works.
It's good to add new.
Okay.
So we may have to fix some of the path.
Components Boost New Push to theme context.
To this Footloose convert.
Let's try to fix some of this.
So probably the path.
So one step up.
One sip of.
To step up.
So just remember back to.
Sam.
You want to stick?
And component is right here.
So we go one step and then it's here.
So it's removed.
Both.
Component.
We are already in intel components.
Context.
Just to step up.
I think that so.
Let's have a look.
Give it.
Reload.
Media.
Okay.
So we already had two components.
We didn't need the components to just go on step.
Okay.
How good is that?
All right.
You can see we have avenue based just like we had before, but we simplified it by moving into this
component and this and bring them here.
Beautiful.
Let's try.
Let's try to create one and make sure it works.
Go to factory.
Just put some placeholder text.
Okay.
Featured image.
Let me pick one existing image.
And this one.
Categories react.
Note.
Okay, let's promise.
And you can see everything works the way it was work before.
Beautiful.