All right.
So we have the list of users now.
Next, we're going to work on the edit and delete.
So let's work on the delete first, then we'll move on to edit.
So for now, for delete, we need to go to our backing group, the endpoint to do the user.
So let me just close everything.
Go to.
So I wrote.
Also as crude and delayed trucks brought in dirt too late to deliver, the user began to make a request
to use it less.
We can send the IED.
We can call it users, Lance.
Call I.D. or let's call to use I.D. just to make things a bit more easier to understand.
So that's the endpoint.
Obviously, the question is needed and it should be admin.
Only admin should be able to deliver the user.
All right.
So did it.
User.
Let's create that function and import.
Yeah.
Screwed the controller off and it.
Just read that here.
Export controls delete user equals two async request response try.
Get in there.
Frontal lobe.
So here we're going to try to find the user subconscious and its structure.
Actually, it's not really important
concepts.
Actually it's destructive just to make things easier.
So we call it user I.D..
All right.
So let's let's now let's get to it.
So user I.D., we distracted from request forums and then.
We can take if the user I.D. that we are getting in the request for EMS, if that matches with the currently
logged in user.
Then.
We don't want.
To execute that because we don't want the user to do it themselves.
All right.
So if, by the way, you can already see.
But it's only for the admin.
I guess this service take is already there.
But despite having that, we also want to make sure that people are moderating themselves, including
including admin.
Sometimes you might get emotional.
They want to do it himself.
We don't want that.
I guess if user I.D. equals equals equals request to user and to underscore I.D., then we immediately
return it.
We don't want any code to execute, otherwise we can just find the user and delete.
So user equals two of each user find biden delete that started that ready and do it and then response
to this and use delete the user.
We can send this in response.
That's all we need to delete the user to get the root we get the controller.
Let's move on to our end.
And we already wrote the.
Function.
So admin uses index.
We have to delete this text on click we execute handle delete which is right here.
Handle Delete.
If they don't do them self, we stop them from doing that.
Okay.
Otherwise, try.
Getting into.
So here what we can do is we can make requests to back in.
So cast data equals to old excuse to delete.
We make a delete request to less users just to use it less uses less the user ID which is here user.
We getting as a program from that?
And a text from you would give the user as a carrier.
So we use that the time we send to use it and then.
We're not actually sending any error messages.
I guess that's a bit so we can.
So to start.
To start.
Success.
Even though it's a success.
I want to show in the red red color because it's it's a deleted message.
So I want to use that toaster better.
And we just have called the misses user deleted.
Okay.
Now, once the user is deleted, what we need to do is we want to immediately update this list.
We want to immediately remove that to use it from the list.
All right.
So.
We can use it.
Uses so we have a list of uses a re-enlisted said to use this previous.
So what are you going to do?
Is we going to return previous list of uses and we're going to apply filter.
Looking to apply filter filter fonts and runs on each of these users.
So each user we checking for the user ID if that doesn't met with these just deleted you decide then
that list we want to.
Extract and sit in this state.
Using the printer photo, we filter out the due to user input, put the rest of the users back to the
state and that's it.
So actually, let's put this to Mrs. after this, because this is more important.
No data.
We could use data today since we are sending the user ID of user object from the backend.
All you can is continue using.
This doesn't really matter.
All right, so let's give it a try.
So let me just try some random music around seven.
Delete.
You can see that's gone.
Beautiful.
All you just maybe you want to if you want.
Against a number of you decide.
Hmm.
So let's cool all uses.
Going just for the list of number of uses you just want.
Don't let.
So we've got 11 years at the moment.
Limit delete this, Ryan.
Six.
We have ten left.
Beautiful.
All right.
So the admin has the list of uses we did on that.
We implemented Jasmine.
Now, moving on, we came to implement edit for edit.
We're going to have we going to take the user to a separate page, which is going to look similar to
what we had before doing the.
Adding when admin created a new user using this form the exact form we need so we use the same exact
form.
Pre-populated is the updating.
Use this information and then make some changes and hit submit to update the user as well.
So that's next.