All right, now let's work on that button.
So we want to show that button underneath the categories.
One of the characters we could that preview button.
Let me just copy that.
And put it underneath this select.
So this button.
I will execute suited me use type primary and on click we can execute a function.
Let's call it handle.
And Summit helicopters and turns the port name to focus.
Okay, so let's create this function.
Let's put it right in the top of region const and of this async.
I'm guessing that Barton looks like that.
Beautiful.
Okay, so here, what you want to do is we want to make a request to beg, and we don't have the root
and control function, and we don't even have to push the schema.
But that's all easy.
We have already done.
The difficult part of that is authentication.
Now, everything that's going to be pretty straightforward.
It's not easy, but it will be straightforward.
Accounts error.
Control of the air.
Obviously, we control the dust notification rules.
And it's true that dust and let's suppose we fail and try again.
Let's make sure we have the toasts important.
We are not toast, so we import toast.
And it's school bag.
So in this function, what we want to do is we want to make a request.
Using Axios 90 seconds data equals two point excuse to post.
We make a post request to the endpoint.
To create a post we can call it.
Let's call it just create post.
Okay.
And then that's the first I went to this post function.
Second argument is the actual download that we have to post, right?
So in this case we want to send the title content and categories.
Beautiful.
I guess the lesson that we're sending now and we will be sending the error message.
So this is a generic error, but we want to show the agony.
So send the actual error to use it.
All right.
So if something if the title is empty, if there is no content in the body or if there is no category,
things like that, we can sin.
So we can only take for the date of that error because even though that error will you sending as a
response decent data.
Right.
So we have to take if data error dorst error dotted an error.
Again.
Let's just use this operative, because sometimes you might get an error saying that error cannot be
accessed from undefined because if the data is not there and we try to access error, then you might
get some weird error message.
So let's take that.
Otherwise I think otherwise what we can do is we can set the dose notification and then once we saw
that push notification, we can empty the fields in listed the total set empty content to empty our
categories again and to be empty every.
All right, so we do that and we also want to make sure that we empty them from the local stories.
Right.
So that's also important.
Now if you are redirecting the user to another base, for example.
This is the bush create base.
So once the admin create the post, if you want to redirect him to all the posts here in this place,
then in that case he doesn't actually have to empty leave out empty because he can just open that.
And in our case, that's what we're going to do.
We're going to redirect them to the all post office.
All right.
So I'm not going to use this.
Instead, I'm going to remove the title and content from local stories because if remember, we have
been we have been saving this in the local stories.
So if it is successfully saved in the database, then obviously we don't have to keep it in the local
storage.
So so we can remove.
Right.
So.
Local stories don't remove item by the name or title, and then local stories as a move item by the
name of post content.
All right.
Letting everybody vote and being the state, local state here, because we're going to redirect
redirect so that redirect and is now function like that.
Rather don't post.
We will post them to admins class posts.
It's.
Okay.
Now let me comment them for the moment.
At the moment until we I can confirm that everything has been successfully in the back council.
Long
post.
We postponed this.
Response, I guess.
Let me have a look at the response before I do anything here, Donna.
Now, since we're using robbery, let's make sure we have the aurora, okay?
So we don't have.
And sometimes Vsco tries to automatically import and you can see it is importing from the server which
is not for.
So sometimes you might get some weird errors because of things like this one.
And same with the reader.
If I by mistake or trade raven it tried to import from somewhere.
Like you said it's in the wild that import use the Aurora hook from next.
Then we're going to use that
from Strada to use and run.
We just execute that.
That gives us this freedom and we can use to push to redirect the user.
I could have common them out for now, just one to have a at the console.
Now, of course we don't even have this end point.
So our next task is to go to the back and create the root, create the control function.
And before we do anything in the controller function, we have to make sure we have the push the schema
as well.
All right.
So we'll be doing that in the next.
Let me just make sure.
So far so good.
Here, use wrong.
That's a bit weird.
Oh, kiss and mix this.
Right.
That's me.
Okay.
Perfect.