So we got the title, we got the content.
Next thing we want to create a post is a list of categories.
So when you create a post, you want to select few categories for your post, right?
So for that, first we have to get all the categories from our back in and hopefully we have the end
point slimmed down to several roads category categories.
So this should be our guest.
So you can see here we are getting all the categories from this control function.
So that means
we can make a request to select categories and that will give us all the categories to exclude here.
So here in the new new post, let's use a use effect to use effect.
So in the component amount, we want to make a request to get all the categories.
So let's create a state.
So we get all the categories we can put them here.
Categories said categories equals to use state.
So it the array of categories.
Okay.
So we have that.
And then actually we will have two types of categories in the state.
One is all the categories from our backends or whatever we already have created.
And online the list of categories will be the ones that will be sent along with the total content to
serve in the database.
So any create a new post.
You want the categories as well.
And this is the whole category.
So that means let's to make it less confusing, let's create another state for.
To put all the characters that we get from the database, we can call them loaded.
Loaded categories that loaded
new secular categories equals to use state.
All right.
So this way, when we make a request, you define all the categories that we get, we put here in this
state, and then during the push create or whatever, the user selects the categories for this post,
those categories that we put them here.
All right so let's use this use effect took it takes a function and now the second argument dependency
would leave it empty.
So here we want to use axis to load all the categories.
So I want to put that in a separate function here.
So I'm just going to execute that function load
load categories.
All right.
So here, let me write that function load categories that we import X use.
So here I try.
So we destroyed it and data.
From.
Oh, wait.
Excuse.
Let's make sure this is async.
Are we to excuse?
Don't get to make it get to the end point.
That is.
C-class categories.
All right.
So that is all we need when we get the rest of that stuff.
You can console.log the data if you curious.
I'm just going to say directly in the state, I'm pretty sure we have got the data, so it should be
here in the state.
That's all.
So this function will fit all of the categories, populate the state, and this function is executed
on the component mounts.
All right, so if you want, let's have a look at these loaded categories in the state.
So we got this.
Ed, let's put it right after the break.
Break them just to use JSON string in front.
Loaded categories.
Okay.
Now, you can see here we have got the categories.
Beautiful.
Now these categories, I want to show them in a multiple selection element.
So we continue to use and designs select component.
So let me quickly sue.
So that one will be something like this one.
I guess they're going to more than one.
They will be able to type if 15 hit enter 17 should enter to their concerts and then when they select
the it will be popular here they can delete from their oh they can just click as well and we will be
able to, although they use it to select multiple categories.