All right, so let's work in the front end.
Let's add that load more feature.
So here in the bases.
Pay this post to hear of first request, we continued make using the gift service approach so that our
building society rendered so we can leave it like that.
But when we get our post for the very first time, then we can put this post away in a variable in the
state, and then any new post that comes up.
Using that Lord moment, we just going to add to that state and render here.
So here.
First, let's create a state.
So.
KONST Let's make sure we have some deep the hooks to use the state we're going to need in food to use
state and then use effect.
So yeah, grants, let's call it all posts because the post name is already used here.
So let's just all post and then set our posts in which to use state.
Here by the front.
We give this valley post which will be ready before the component even starts.
So this base will not be rendered unless this function runs.
So that means when we are ready to display anything, we would already have that.
So we can show that to you.
I'll post and then we're going to have the total as well.
So we're going to have the loading as well.
We can use that cost total set total, it goes to use state and we give the default value of two.
Now this total will be coming from the back end.
So how many posts we have in talking?
So we wrote that throughout our control function in the previous lecture.
That will give us the total total post that we have in the database to make a request to get this value
using you state.
So to use effect.
Okay, so we put that here and then if the total in the database, if that is higher than what we have
in the state, that means we can share the load more.
But I guess that's for total.
And then we are sending the base number on each request.
So we use Bayes, said Bayes are listed and we give the default value of one.
Okay.
So with all of that, let's use the music fit.
So first shrink is to me to give the total.
So you get it's quite gift token and we execute that function.
Let's put that function down here.
Wants to get totally.
Could we try.
So to get the total, let's make sure we have access.
Okay.
So we have.
So we get the data.
From excuse a sweet excuse to get to make a get request to post count definitely give us the data and
we use that data to put in the states using set total.
And that would be data.
They will not be processed because it will just give us the number because we use that.
The government can't function.
We used.
Oh, little miss.
So you think that's at the very end?
Yeah, it's a common document.
This gives us the exact number, too.
That's the one we had written.
Okay, said total data.
Now at this point we should have the total in the state.
You can even have a look quickly.
Let's try.
Let me just put it right here.
You can see we have total football.
So you can see that for.
That should be more than that total.
That should be 40, not four.
We made a request before and we support it.
So that must be one must be missing somewhere.
Let me just put it in a by the way, you know, you could be getting anything, so it's always good
to have independent control lol.
Toby Well, let's have a look at the console.
We got the total for him.
All right, so that's good.
So we got the total.
Next, we make a request.
I guess.
So.
We need to have the the button.
Actually, let's create a button here.
So we have this one rule.
Let's create another rule and enter this through.
We do have a button right in the center so we can use column.
Column columns span 12.
And then we use this style to center the text style.
Text a line.
Center.
Thank you.
So here we show the button.
Let's make sure we import button.
And we put that burden on him.
And we discarded loads more.
And then here on this bottom comb, we give the size loss to one last button type primary that will
give us that nice blue button.
Loading.
While it's loading, we want to set this to loading so it is disabled.
They can click and on clicks.
So this is the important one and click when it's clicked.
We want to execute a function that will make a request to back backend on the same yard but with a different
value.
All right, so on click.
We want to make that request.
Not to make that request.
We can just increase the pace in the state.
So whenever that Bayes value changes, we can execute a function in a use effect to use effect to,
you know, it runs whenever the dependent value changes here.
So what I'm going to do is we're going to use create another use effect and use this space as a dependency
here.
So in that bed tenders so one click on click when we change the value of base from 1 to 2 to the three
like that, whenever that tends, we want to execute a function that will load more post by making a
request to this end point with the whatever base number we have in the state.
All right.
So all we need to do here is increment the base state and so on, click.
We use our function here, set base.
So whatever base we already have with that plus one.
Okay.
So that's what we do.
On click, we increment the value of base in the state.
All right, so let's have a look.
So we've got that lawnmower button.
That is not sentence.
Let's see.
Start.
Okay.
So that's good.
Maybe we can have beautiful batting.
That's it.
Batting 10th.
It's a bit of a gap, maybe even 20.
Okay, so at the moment when we click, the base number increases.
So we want to create another user effect.
Let's put that you use effect.
And interdependence is going to be base.
So whenever the base changes, we make a request.
We make a request to load more posts so we can call that.
Let's call that load more.
We said that we need to read that function, so let's read that function here and load more.
So here first thing we do said learning to troop.
All right.
And then if we get in here, sit loading falls here what are you going to do is will make a request
using excuse that only give us the data so it excuse to get we make a get request to get on the post
slash post and we also sending the business right to that space.
That could be that would be too.
So by default is one.
But when the button is click, it would be true.
If they click again, then it'll be three.
So, all right, so that's the value we send and then we'll get the value we'll get on the post.
So what we want to do at that point is whatever we already have in the step.
So as you can see you.
The post that we get from this gets those same props from the very first request.
When the page loads we get, we get all this post that's already here that is already being rendered.
Now, in addition to that, we want to add more.
All right.
So we want to add more to this.
All posts, so said all posts.
So whatever we already have.
So this is the array, all posts, whatever we have, we spread out and then we add these new posts.
So we just spread the array a post again, spread the earlier post that we just got and just set the
values to set our posts.
All right.
So that will keep the previous ones and post the new ones.
Okay.
And then send loading to Fox.
We set it false.
All right, perfect.
So this is all we need to do.
We get the total count, and I click up the normal button, we increment the base.
So whenever the base increment, we execute this loading of false that will learn more posts and Morris
with the existing ones.
And now let's the all posts.
As you can see, we are.
We are not we are not returning that.
So instead of post, let's use all posts.
Let's send it.
Okay.
Let's hope.
So let me give a base load.
Okay.
So we're getting all the posts.
So I noticed one small issue that is you can see we have the same force.
Same six force has been requested twice.
The reason for that is because of the use effect it runs with the component mod, it runs automatically
and then whenever this well it's in that time also orange.
So that means it already ran.
But we don't want to run this on the very first time, right?
So we want to run only when the base increments.
So what we can do is we can use this one if statements are if base equals sequence equals one, we don't
want to do anything.
So we just use written keyword.
So the code will just return here.
It will not execute any any court here.
So if base is one return, don't do it.
Because by default we have the base one.
So by default when the page loads don't do anything because that time we already have the post from
this function and that is here.
So we are rendering this one.
So on the very first time we did have to do this, so return.
But if the page is not one, that means when the button is clicked it becomes two and three and four.
So at those times we want to run.
Okay, so with this, let's come here.
So let's give a reload.
And you can see here we have six force or we have six force as expected.
Now, if I click here, we load another six.
Code refactoring.
Like it looks like this same.
And it's the same.
I mean, like you say, it's all learning simple.
So let's see how we can fix that.
Okay.
So I realized one typo we made in our controller and it's a request query.
We're not actually sending queries.
We are getting the parents who are limiting that to programs.
All right, so let's change that and give it a try.
I guess we could six post effective lord more.
Now this time we're getting the current post so they're not repeated again.
They're different.
Okay, so now that's all that's on the post we have.
We finished, we have some total foreign, but we still have this load mode button visible.
So let's fix this one.
So if all post, it's all posts that we have in the state.
If that is smaller, then the total that is coming from the database.
If that is true only then.
So the but now here what we can do.
We can just put in our entire row actually.
So let's cut and let's use here
all first.
If all posts don't live, if they're all posts total we have is smaller than total.
Total we have in our database.
Then we want to show this row with the normal path.
All right, so here.
Is that cool?
Okay, so we aim for the bottom the entire row.
Only if the outpost is smaller than the total we have.
All right.
Now you can see it's immediately gone.
Let's try again one more time.
Okay.
We got six lot more.
We got more on the season.
That's altogether 12 and then load more for 40.
That's on the post 12 bearded.