Also, we were able to send the category from our React app to our server and we could see the category
that is sent.
We could access that in our control.
So that is right here.
Right.
So it's all good.
But now we want to focus on securing the roots because we want to make sure not everyone can create
a category.
So first of all, the user have to be logged in, right?
So we have to perform a check that to make sure the user is logged in.
And another tick is the user should have the role of admin by default.
Any user that sign up to an application, they get the role of subscribe by default.
As you can see, a default really subscriber.
So for creating a category, a user had to be admin use, right?
So for that we can create a few middle layers.
The middle was basically a function that.
I run out in the middle, too.
Before you do something, for example, before you allow the user to create a category saved, you sent
the category in the database.
You want to perform some tic so those checks can be done in middleware functions.
Right.
So Miller is basically equal right here.
Yeah.
Just a quick example.
For example, let's use Arrow.
Right.
So these are Franzen and then this comma, this is a control font.
So here in the middle, if you execute some code, that is a middleware.
All right.
So here in express roles, obviously we have access to requests to response.
And next as well.
Next time, call next week.
You can call it a callback function.
You can give it an A name.
All right.
So request response, mixed and error.
So these objects you can access in express at any time you building explicit.
Now, we've done this for the moment.
So next, whenever you want to create a middleware, you can use this callback function here.
Right.
So if you do this next, that means the code here will execute because you basically you allow this
callback function to execute.
So everything will continue the way it is.
However, before you execute this function, you can perform some takes effectively.
Let me just right here
perform a check to make sure the user is adamant.
It's very simple.
You have a function that will do something.
At the moment we just console.log just so we get the idea of how middleware works.
Right?
So you can see this function is a middleware function.
Now, when I send when I make a request to this category out with the method of post, I should see
this in the console as well because this middleware function will execute and then the callback function
will execute.
Then this will execute.
That's a lot of excuse.
I saw him try to react.
Let's try another one.
Note.
I think if in office we don't get any we don't expect any response at the moment.
But if you go here in the back end, you see.
We got this concerned look.
So that is this middleware function that is gone to logging here.
So you can see if we do something here, if we don't execute next and send some kind of error, then
the code here will not execute.
So let's try that.
So here, let's send some kind of error message.
So response is send, let's send the status for the error.
So there are different status code in has to be friends in which 200 means okay 400 means error 444
means is not found so that there are different types of status code you will send, you will send and
receive.
When we are making a request and we will go to of more details later when we expect some errors, then
we will come across many different errors.
For one is unauthorized error.
Right.
So we could use for one as well.
So send this Tedesco to 401.
And then he can send.
A summary of four error messages, for example, unauthorized.
I say we can do that.
Issues return keyword.
All right.
So if we do some kind of a take here and if we find out that the user is not logged in, then maybe
we could return some kind of error message like this.
So let's try.
Let's try.
What happens if we do that?
So come here.
Let's.
Let's try.
Right.
Great category is straight away with God that let me click in the netbook tab and you can see here because
we send the full one unauthorized.
Message we got as a response against you unauthorized.
That's because our middleware send this error message.
So the code here the console.log.
We didn't even see that we started.
We got that response.
As you can see, we didn't even get that control.
Look, I said, that's how we can protect our roads, our server, our out of control function from
unauthorized to users.
I said that was a basic overview of how middleware works.
Now let's remove this one instead.
Instead of variety here like this, we're going to put those functions in a different file, just like
we did here for control of nonsense.
This is something we could write here, but we decided to put in this file to organize our code in a
similar way.
We're going to create a different folder from middleware.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create a middleware that will take if the user is locked.