All right, so there's one more thing we can do.
Give the Senate keys so that we can start sending the forward pass through e-mails as well.
And then we're pretty much ready to go.
Let's do that.
Send it.
So if you don't have an account, you can sign up or you can use your existing account.
I'm actually going to sign up.
That's for the noggin.
They have very strict requirements.
You have to have 16 character parts or something like that.
It's really a difficult assignment and didn't have the social login option, says the.
I was smiling because I was going to say that I'm going to sign with Google, but I'm physically, you
know, anyways, use the name.
So I'm using Monster.
Ms..
I mean, let me take this alone with a single sign.
And what is this the administration
used to mean more serious.
So I can do that.
Anyways, let's create a sign up for the new account.
Sign up.
It's a free plan to take a trip plan.
I guess the email address, ma'am.
Siemens and G.M. come.
I'm not a robot on my own.
It's $0.60.
It's crazy hours, crude accounts.
Okay.
Lots to do in Dingle Company name, let's say, Carlos said.
Actually I had my own.
All I'm doing in Turkey is a no.
That's not right.
It's straight into phone number.
Hopefully it doesn't.
It's not required.
What's a real developer?
How many emails there?
10 to 100000.
How many employers?
That one.
Let's get started.
We sign up with MongoDB and this single, this is something you could probably do, but many times the
new users they're used to is those get confused on steam.
All right.
So this is a brand new account, low key.
So any time before you start sending emails, you have to create a single sender.
I This is this one way to do SQL.
You are required to include your contact information.
Ma'am seeing.
And Jim in reply to attempting to send.
I guess.
So what do you want to do is you want to use the same email from and to.
So when you're sending email to some other users, even at that time, you'll be using the same.
For example, if you have a contact form and someone contacts fill out the form and suddenly you want
to receive that even, right?
So from Intuit it's going to be sent company after us.
I got 100 sin in New South Wales.
See the man on the Sydney Street doesn't actually exist.
I think that's why we're doing it for the wrong proposition.
From Denmark on the street in Estonia.
Okay, let's choose the country first.
Australia zipcode 2000.
Nickname is the Quiet Kid.
This is.
This is crazy.
More serious.
Center has been created to very, very similar.
Take your mailbox.
All right.
Let's take it to the mail.
Okay.
That's perfect.
We got an email from Alison.
Great.
Please verify your address.
All right, let's click.
Now, I am logged into a different window.
This approach.
Private window, sir.
I'm going to do what I'm going to do.
I'm going to copy the link address in this open in this process.
You could just click on that button.
It's no problem.
I'm doing a show that I don't have to log in again in a private window.
Okay.
Return to Congress.
Listen to you, Senator.
And it has been successfully verified.
Beautiful.
I guess so.
Once you have verified owners use this verified email address to send emails from your application and
you should be good to go.
All right.
So that's perfect.
Next one, we want to get the API kids right.
So let's go here.
Click here.
API keys generate API key.
By the way, make sure to not expose this API key anywhere.
I guess in the moment it is expose it will not work.
And you might they might put some restriction to your account as well.
They're really strict.
So if you pushing your code to GitHub, make sure.
We have the ignore file and your EMV is ignored so that in we file is not uploaded to GitHub because
if it gets public view you won't be able to send emails anymore.
This key will not work.
You have to generate another key.
They might put some restriction as system.
Don't do that.
Full access.
Alright, that's good.
Maybe a key name.
So moon see?
Misleading comment.
I could say Becky has been quiet to let me just copy this one.
Beautiful.
Done.
Once it's done, you can copy that again.
I guess that's that's gonna have to create a new one if you want it to.
Anyways, let's put that here.
Send key and then email from the students.
Now, ma'am, seeing this beautiful.
That's everything we need now.
Now did a beauty secret.
Obviously, you can just put anything in a such random characters, and that's it.
We're done.
So from the following lecture, we can start sending requests, name, email, password.
Send that to our sign route.
Sign up right here.
You can see whenever you get a push to request this function, we'll handle that so you can take out
the sign of function in the it's coming from the control center.
Right.
So we'll go through this code one more time.
Don't worry.
When we made a request, first we have a look at the controller.
Console.log and then we'll just go through all the code so that you understand how everything's worked.