So previously I requested from a password.
Let's do it one more time.
So that user was.
So let's go through one more time, see if you followed the password.
We want to log in.
You come here to San Base, click on this link.
Forgot password.
Enter your email.
Ma'am.
Him as this to.
Take your email password.
Wisconsin.
Now, when it was happening, it took maybe a minute, 1/2, something like that.
So that time you could show the loading indicator.
So it is a bit more interactive, right?
So let's quickly do that as well.
So we have the button button and we have the loading property as fluid changes dynamically here.
So we're going to use that value.
And thankfully with end is end and isn't button component has the loading.
Also.
So if she passed Hillary based on true and false, it will show the spinner.
All right.
So let me do a quick refresh and try one more time just so that we can see the loading Mancini is doing
and.
Now you can see that slurring we saw and then we got the success.
Mrs. Enter the reset code.
So user will go to his email.
All right, so we got this few emails.
Let's use the latest one.
This is the cordless.
Copy that.
And come here.
Paste that code, and then the new password.
Now let's try and use new password.
Let's call it password.
Okay.
It's for a summit.
Password change successfully.
Please log in with a new password and we reset the filter as well.
Beautiful.
All right, so let's go try logging with the new password, Szymanski admits.
I didn't try the previous password, which was just this character that.
Okay.
Well.
We got the error message.
Wrong password.
But wish to redirect the user.
So there's a bit of a fix to doing the signing, I guess.
But.
We saw that for the password to reset, password works.
Let's quickly fix this one as well.
Let's have a look.
Let's go fix this issue in signing.
So we have to try.
Okay.
So we didn't take for the data error.
That's the issue here.
So let me quickly go to our backing off.
Let me take the sign in.
Sign it.
So there are error messages we are sending.
All right.
So we should check for the error messages and then we should display their message.
So we made a request.
We give the data now we take for the data error.
All right, so let me just got all this cold and ticked.
If data does not want you to do something, so some portion notification and whatever, otherwise,
otherwise else, we based that code back into it.
I guess you've done an error do stuff.
Yeah.
And here we can sort out the dirt and sort of the error message we got.
Six loading two.
False.
Beautiful.
Let's give it a try.
So all we did is move that court in the L block and we take for the air using the if statement.
All right.
Let me also go to sign up and let's make sure we have that.
Okay so on sign of we did but I think we missed understanding anyways we have this one now let's executed.
So sign in, Ms..
And try using the new boss all password log.
Now, this time it doesn't work, obviously.
Now let me try using the new password.
I just reset the new password.
Right.
So let's try this one.
And beautifully it works.
How cool is that?
I asked this.
How you learn to implement a password into an application as well.
Something that is very important in a real world application.
Now we did we pretty much done with authentication.
It's a full authentication with sign up signing for password, reset password, sending emails, everything
is done.
Let's now focus on creating the admin restricted basis so that we can all of the admins to do more serious
stuff like creating categories, post things like that.