All right, so we have the orthodontics.
Now, let's try to make use of this one, right?
So when we sign up, we know that we give the user information.
And talking to that information, we want to see the context.
All right.
So that and also we want to in the local stories.
So let me come.
Let's open the inspect, click on the inspect, open this console and then if you go to application.
You'll see.
We have the local stories section in there.
You will see the current domain, too, that level of 3000.
And we have bunch of things saved.
Now, this one is the Chrome plugin, so you can do that.
Tim we said, well, we use light and dark.
It you can see here it is we are saving the.
Local stories.
So whenever user come back again, we always assume the users.
So a preferred theme, right?
You can see changes from light to dark.
We already know that.
So anything else, Liam?
Just remove.
You can manually remove like this one.
So you can manually remove one by one by clicking on some members.
If you want to just clear out the entire level smoothing, click here.
So you can click here in the applications stories.
Come down here and then you can select on that.
And then you can click here to side.
I guess it'll clear everything out.
If you come back here again, you'll see there's nothing there.
Now, if I give relooked, then obviously the thing will be saved here.
As soon as you ten you can see.
Beautiful.
All right.
So we will also look at a lot of stories and we also look into the context.
All right, let's go to.
Santa.
So on faith we are getting the.
The response.
And at the moment we're just showing this stuff notification how now we're going to send that information
in.
The context and the local story.
So console.log data.
Let's call the response.
Sign of response.
Let's have a look at it one more time.
Right.
Let's have a look at that.
Let's try Santa.
Run!
It's a five.
I think I used all the other ones.
To register successfully sign up if you have looking to your console.
We got that kind of response and you can see we have got the token and use it.
So that is the information we want to save in the local stories and the context.
So let's do that.
So let me come in there.
So little comment, save in context.
So in local stories, so local, it's easy to say in the context.
First we have to access the context.
So let's import use context to use context from React.
We also need the host context to import context from.
You want to get into context?
Oh.
All right, so we got the hook.
We got the context.
Let's try to use them.
Context, state.
This local state.
Let's leave a comment and hear
us and set up those values we of the structure from the context, using the use context.
All right.
So once we have that, we can use the set of function to update the context state.
Right.
So let's use that.
So said.
And all we have to do is give the data because this data basically has.
The.
Token and use.
Good.
See, that's all we had.
However, know actually that that's not who you had to do that.
But when we say in the local stories, we have to save as a decent data so we can use this JSON string
file so local stories don't set item.
We save these data, we use the JSON strings for a function so that it is saved as decent data and we
save that as a value off so you can see it.
This said item function has the two arguments.
First one is the key, the name for the data that we are saving.
So that's we called it off.
And the second argument you can see here is the actual data we got as a response.
We just had string for it and saved.
It's pretty simple to get item.
You get item to save you select.
Okay, so this way we can we populate the context, populate the local stories.
All right.
Now, for the moment, I'm just going to comment this out, all right.
Just so that we can see why there was a need to saving the local stories.
And so let's try to understand that.
So let's just save in the context now and if you go here.
And if something happened, let's try one more time.
Ryan six By the way, we can delete all these dummy users later.
That's horrible.
Let me put this.
This console on the right side of the answer.
Let me register.
Okay.
Successfully signed up.
Let's quickly have a look at our context and there is user information and the token is that that's
beautiful, right?
So based on this we can so the currently logged in use this name based on the user's role and we can
allow him to click on the despot and then based on his role so we can redirect him to a different piece.
If it is admin, we can take him to a less.
Decimal SLAs admin if it is auto, maybe some other place.
You know, we can do a whole lot of things.
The that's the power of authentication.
All right.
And then later in our server, if we have certain routes that we want to protect only for the admin
user, then that time until we can use the token to verify that the user is logged in and also extract
the user ID from the token with only our server can do it because only our server knows the secret that
is used to generate a disturbance.
Right.
So we can extract the user's ID which was used to generate the token based on the you know, along with
the secret.
And then using that idea we can query the database and find out who the who this user actually is if
it is admin or not.
Right.
So for the admin then we can allow him to do certain things.
Now you could also send the role from the front in this client to the back end, but that will not be
safe because anyone can turn the role and make a request.
So we cannot depend on the data that is sent from the client to server.
So we just to use the idea that is embedded in this token, which is also only now so we can decode.
And then based on that we find the user from the database and then, you know, allow him to do certain
things.
Now of course we will be going through all this domestic, so you'll get full understanding of that.
All right.
So it looks good.
However, the problem is if user come back to this application after closing it, somehow the paste
gets reload.
Unfortunately, Darryl Cohen, this did become empty again.
Right.
So that is the reason why we had to also see it in something like local stories.
So that way when something like this happens, when the user gets the base reloaded or something like
that happens, you can see it in a context.
We are we have this huge effect that runs on the component months and it takes for the oath in local
suits.
And if there is, then we want to grab that value.
Hopefully it states that we we will to use this information and the token will not be lost.
All right.
So that's the reason why we sitting in the local stores and grabbing the venue like this.
Now, at the moment, if we go to application.
We don't have we haven't saved this information in the local stories, but this time, let's do it.
RYAN 717.
Jim In fact.
This pride this time, by the way, we can redirect as well at the moment we stood here.
Then if you go here, we have it in the context.
And we also saved here in the local stories.
You can see.
We'll just send it in the local stories.
Now if you really go to the base.
Previously, we lost this.
Nada.
However, since we are using this effect in our context to take if we have the art in the local stories
and if there is, we want to grab that and put in the state.
Because of that, even on page reload, we still have that information.
I guess that's the beauty.
Okay.
So that's great.
And then finally, let's finish up on the sign up.
So we want to redirect the user to some other page when they log, right?
So at the moment we only have one admin desperate.
We do.
So let's not worry about the other user roles the author and subscriber will know.
You know, make some changes in our code later, but for the moment let us directly redirect them to
admin desk and that will be just less.
And I guess for here to redirect again we have to use a hook from next steps and it's important that
it's called use throughout from next to this one.
You have to restructure like this one and then let me just write.
Yeah, this one is hook const are equal.
So you can put it in a variable order and we use this function and we simply execute this, execute
this one that will use this.
The functionalities we put that in our variable ruler and this gives us the functionality like redirecting
the user to a certain place.
For example, if you want to take the user to a less admin based on signup, then you can use something
like row to do it puts.
If you're curious, you can even come to love.
And stick around.
Let's see what we what you can access.
This one.
I think it's better to sleep slayer like that.
If you go to sign up.
Now you can see him here.
The senator has.
All this information so you know the path nim using the road you can use back to go back to the previous
base, you can use PWS to redirect the user to some other base.
You know, it has a lot of this functionality.
So the one we're going to use now is this puts.
I just lost track.
So, Laura.
Once we see the user.
Instead of slowing the toast notification, which is not really important for.
No, but let's leave it anyways.
We do it.
So don't lose.
We use the push function and where do we want to push?
We want to push to every segment is okay.
Now next time we sign on the very first time when the sign of is successful, the user will be taken
to the admin base.
And since we have this log in loading thing.
Are we using that in the bottle?
Okay.
So we all adhere to the buffet.
Let's try one more time.
It's clear in the views of Ryan seven, Ryan seven and immediate.
Let's try this.
Three.
Who in ministry seven is undertaking.
Let's try it.
You can see here.
We have the information here right in it in the local stores, soda.
We have it in the context as well.
And then we were also redirected to this list and this beautiful.