I guess I will also be referring to this application all the time during this course, and you can also
come and have a look at the application and every part, whichever we are going to be working in the
Lexis.
You know, you can see that here as well.
So that really saved me from writing a lot of diagrams and showing you the diagrams and extending,
I guess, are we doing this now?
We're going to do that.
We can do that.
You know, that takes quite a lot of time for you, for me as well.
Now, when we have the actual application already there, that eliminates the need for the for the diagram.
So I guess that is another reason why I decided to deploy this application.
So instead of drawing the mockups, I have the actual thing already there.
All right.
So let's let's say we are now ready to build our application.
So what is the first thing you will do?
Okay, so you have two options.
One, you can set you back in or you can set of your it.
Now, I usually prefer to set up in the the front end because front end, to be honest, front end requires
a lot of code worth writing in.
It's a little bit gets complicated as well as backing once you understand it is really straightforward
because back in you have the kind of a straight map, you create the routes, you create the control
functions, and that's pretty much it.
And then the controller will communicate with the database.
You have some database models, schemas, but that's pretty much it always the standard thing.
Whereas in the front end you have to do so many different thing.
For example, sign in is an app is have different things on the home page.
You do something different on the post page, you display the post and then in the back in the desk
where there is a whole lot of things to do, creating categories, creating post, uploading images.
There are so many things now when it comes to the back end, it's easy.
You send the blog, title, content, image, everything to the back end.
Begging will save in the server and give you the response.
You know it's straightforward, whereas front end, it has a lot of moving pieces here and there.
So what are we going to do is we can just start with the funding that will make things so much easier
to understand as well.
All right.
So when you think of the application, when you think of building a full stack application, we should
have the back end funding.
Whereas the first thing you think is obviously set of the project at the moment, we don't have anything
with right away empty, sitting empty.
So we create in next year's project we'll be using next year, which is the most popular framework used
for products and applications to build React applications, right?
So it's a framework, React framework.
So we set up the project and we set up using NPM.
So I'll be showing you how you can set Node this project from absolute scratch.
Now don't get confused with Node.js and the react actually even react to use notice.
They also require a server.
All right.
So we'll be setting up React in next this project.
Once you have the project, we create a few basis, right?
So we create home and then maybe we create some sign in base and sign up base.
Once you have those phases, then we can think of actually creating the content for those phase.
All right.
So first we try creating new phases, maybe create a navigation, we add some links so that we can just
navigate around, go to Homebase, good design and basically design a base, you know, just have the
very basic framework for the application.
Few bases, epicenter shape is there and then we're going to focus on creating such forms, right?
Same in forms and of forms.
And then we need to send all this information that a user enters name, email, password, everything
we need to send to the backend so that we can save the user when they sign them.
Right?
And that's when we're going to go to the backend and set up our back end.
So that's how we go with the flow.
Okay.
Even though it's a bigger application, you don't need to stress we go with the flow.
So in the next section we set up the client application with React and next year we'll start creating
spaces for comparison and that's how we're going to start this beautiful journey.