All right, so we have the post, we have the normal working.
However, there is a problem.
If you go to your desperate outpost, you don't see any post.
That's because we have to end our end point in the back end.
Previously it was ebooks who wrote posts.
Previously we had.
This right pose didn't have zero tolerance, but now we do, so it's no longer work.
Now what you can do is obviously we can we can send the best number and implement business in here for
the admin as well.
That is one way, but I'll show you how to do that.
So into that, I'm going to take a different tweet and that is showing all the posts.
Now, that's not necessarily bad.
If you send just the post post title and then the post log this the basic information because here on
the post you can see we are sending a lot of data, we are sending the emails, we are sending the users
information.
Quite a lot of data is sent.
So that can be a bit slow when you are sending them in thousands and thousands of posts.
However, for admin we can just send the title in because that's what we are showing.
This is a finished product.
Quickly sign in and have a look.
So here you can see all we need to do is send the post title and the slug so they can disagree.
All right.
So let's let's work on this one and then the next we are going to work on is this sorting and filtering.
So admin will be able to see the post.
For example, let's say you want to find out this one with the total bootcamp.
So going through all of this one by one can take a lot of time, so you can just source bootcamp and
then that would field from a similar mark where you can filter out all this post that are marked.
Okay, graph.
Q All right.
So that's how we're going to we can easily sort and filter the, the result.
Okay.
So we're going to open that next.
And before we do that, let's fix this so that we can show the list of post for the admin.
So for that, we just going to create a separate front thanks to let me copy this one and then just
put it here.
I'm going to call it post four and.
Most fine.
Yes, that's fine because we already have the post by other.
So post for our admin we can create this one post for an admin.
Let's import this function and go to this controller and let's run that here.
So basically that's going to be similar to what we had before.
But and for I've done it in export post post for admin, it goes to async request response try.
Just and error.
Also explore costs.
So you can't post equals to avoid post.
Find another post.
And here we want.
We can select only the fields we need.
So we need.
Don't
slow
dieting.
Just don't take the model post-mortem.
Yes.
The title and the slogan.
So I get to that.
So since 19.
And then don't select targets.
So that's all you need to respond to.
Jason Post.
Okay.
So now that we have this end point that will send us all the posts, we can go to our admin posts.
Page's admin posts index and here.
We are making requests to post before, but now let's send this to post for ADD.
All right.
So with that, it's come here.
Give it a reload.
You didn't see post four and then only just opened.
I think I didn't go to almost I, I went to Desmond.
They continue.
We have the other posts I so we can click edit.
Post less on o k.
So we need.
We should.
Probably we were using the ID here.
Let's go back to Control.
Let me move that and I want to get you.
We may need to select.
Okay, so that's still undefined.
That one is fine.
So something happened in this one?
They're fine.
Okay.
So let me bring back that left.
We're back.
Click here.
So it's more than that just on this one on undefined.
So probably we know, but we still have.
That's a bit weird.
So this is the first post.
Supposedly that time we did have this slug implemented as something must have been, something must
have been done.
So let's delete that post.
Yeah.
So everything's working.
It's cool.
Let's try some more.
Our posts, by the way, we can do one more thing here, and that is restrict the access to this endpoint
only for the admin because you can see at the moment.
It's open for anyone.
If you want to restrict it, you can do it.
Is adamant.
Make sure to use request sign first require
signing is admin and then post that.
No, I think we we get the get an error because that will make sure we send the token and even though
we do on the very first time it might not be available.
So we need to have a bit of a tick.
So let's go ahead face post.
It's Axis V of context.
Context.
Also, let's use that context.
Context, Konst said they could try to use state.
I sort of returned to use to use context or context.
Okay.
And then now we can use that as.
Token.
And we make requests only if of token.
If only if we have the right token.
Only then we make a request.
So that will guarantee we get we give the post I get now.
This time you can see it's a little awkward.
Beautiful.
Awesome.
Now, like I showed you in my finished product, we can implement this certain filtering so that this
is really cool no matter how be done.
But you see in this.
Filter out, is it in this is something you can reuse in many other components as well.
All right.
So let's see how we can implement that here.