Let's continue with our code refactoring so there's more to do.
So it's good to test.
So we worked on the created new push.
Now let's work on the all posts.
So we're showing on the post here.
So what I want to do is this list of post.
I want to move to a different component.
All right.
So let's close this this post admin post index.
So we have the huge effect fitting of the post from the back end.
We have the edit and delete functions.
And then here we are returning the list of post to a list of posts we have using the list component
we're using.
And basically, we have the main button, we have the title which is here you have the bottom row,
the title, and then all this is a list of post.
All right.
So this list, I want to move to a separate component, which should be very easy.
So let's go inside components.
First, let's file let's call it post list.
All right.
So here, let's import list component.
Let's import link from the next link and then we write a component.
We return to list.
We return the list list.
It's going to be a self-closing component.
So we just leave it like this for the.
Okay.
So it's closed.
So here we will be receiving the props.
So the props will be at least a post.
So we leave it like that and we can also
receive a prompt to delete the posts to delete the post.
Actually it's called handle to Take.
All right.
So basically we want to render out of the post.
So let's go to the index admin index.
We can actually copy this component to list all of it down here.
Okay.
So this list, let's cut from here and put here and replace this with whatever we copied.
So you can see this list item needs the data source, which is post and it's item we rendering.
We are showing these items edit and delete on edit.
We execute the handle, edit and on delete.
We execute, handle, delete.
So hand ended.
Let me just turn to for edit we are taking the user to a separate base.
Right.
So and to end.
Yeah.
So this is something we could use a link component.
Do it all in line.
Or we can use this function.
I can actually.
Let's use this.
It's not difficult.
It's easy.
So let's use it.
And it.
I guess we and getting them as props to these functions for delayed edit as well as we're getting on
the post and we just render here.
So we don't need to make any changes here often.
So let's make sure we export this component.
Export default posts?
Yes.
Okay.
So all we need to do now is import this one and use here.
So it's gone all the way down.
So previously we had the disk component, you know, we just saw this component.
Now we need to make sure we pass the process, post and to edit.
And then.
And then delete.
All right.
So now anytime you want to show the list of Bush friends and later, let's say for Arthur, we just
have to import this component and give the post as props and these functions.
And that way we will be able to reuse this component.
All right.
So let's go and have a look.
Let's make sure everything is there.
Post list is not defined.
64.
Posts list.
I think we have an important book import posts list from.
Okay.
Great.
Refactored.
Here we refactored the list of posts.
They are here.
You can edit because we see using the same functionality we are passing them as props.
The same function is still working.
Right, so we just pass them as books.
So edit let's try to ring it.
I guess you can see it.
It works.
It will also work.
It's.
Try it.
So we have 10% now.
Now we have nine.
Beautiful.