All right.
Now we need to create in the file and add this environment variables.
So let's do it here.
Now let's see here.
Let's start with server.
City server.
And we need to create the Wi-Fi so sudo
don't dirty and V inside the subfolder.
I guess now we have the Ian Buffet.
You don't see the the hidden file with L.
So if you want to see in France you can do l l.
As you can see, we have the.
Dirty envy.
All right, so let's open that and edit using him.
So sudo vim dart envy.
I'm sorry, suni sudo.
Okay, so let's hit.
Right.
To insert the code.
So now we can go to our project.
Project where we start here.
And let's go to the server and let's go to the end file.
So this is the environment variable we have locally.
We've been using locally.
Now let's copy paste in this different file here and let's see what else we need to change here.
So we can leave that database.
So we need to install MongoDB.
Let's forget that.
Let's do that very soon.
Did a pretty secret we can continue using same or maybe just try different.
Doesn't really matter.
The Adobe's keys in secret.
They will stay the same.
Email from that will stay the same strip.
Now in the production, if you want to start taking real money or real credit card payments, then you
will go to the strip desperate and get the live APIs right.
So at the moment we're using the test API.
So I will continue using this one.
But when you are ready, when you deploy, you give, give, give it a try, make sure everything is
working.
And once you start receiving real money, then you can obviously get the live keys from Stripe and replace
this one with the lived keys.
But for now, we can just leave it as it is.
So redirect here.
That will not be localhost 3000.
That will be our API.
So until we add the domain, which is really easy to add to domain.
In this lesson you can easily shows how to add domain, how to add domain.
In this lesson, I suggest that you created a property.
You can add a domain and follow a couple of steps and it's really easy, so you can easily do that later
on.
But for now, let's not worry about adding a domain.
Let's just make sure we can up and run.
We get up and running with the IP address.
All right.
So here instead of Legolas, it will be your IP address, slash the URL name.
But later when you have the domain name, it will be the domain name.
Slash the these zeros.
All right.
So let's change that to a domain name.
So not the domain name, the IP address, it's copying that and just replace that localhost 3000 with
the IP address.
All right.
And that is all we need to do.
Now this file we can use in the production.
Ian Lee, I guess just copy the code here.
Based everything.
Okay.
And then we can just use hit a skip colon w to hit enter.
All right.
That's our server in front.
Now, we can do the same with the client as well.
But before we do that, why don't we install MongoDB as well?
That way server side is done and then we can just focus on the client side.
Right.
Now let's go to let's follow here.
Let's follow this.
So we can copy that to install MongoDB scoping that.
Come here.
Let's go to the root and let's run that.
Then sudo apt update.
Sudo apt install das y mongodb.
You should see the active running stats when you run this.
So let's grab that called.
Once it's done, we can give that a try and we should see the active running status.
Let's try that.
You can see MongoDB.
It's active up and running.
Perfect.
Now you can also try to run to Mongo comments.
For example, let's try Mongo.
Again.
Now we are in the mongo self.
It's the SO DBS.
So by default you get this database.
But we didn't have any other database, so we can create one.
So let's create use EDV here.
I have used not API.
Now this one we're going to use this name.
Use Udemy like it is to Udemy.
There isn't this one.
Make sure you have the same name that you have in the the EMV file.
That's the database name to make sure you have the same name here.
Okay.
So once that is done, updated the EMV, which we already have.
Will it have that?
You can use 127.2.1 or you can just use legalese.
Either way, it works.
Okay.
Now we pretty much done we have into MongoDB it's controlled X and it.
I did get inside.
Before we actually get inside, we're going to run our boats back in the front end.
Using PMD to use a beam to is built for production use unlike not one, not one.
As soon as you close the tunnel, it will stop.
Right.
So.
You want to use NPR PM too so you can insert that globally in beam i this DPM to.
So Beam two will make sure your server is always running.
Okay.
So we have to use sudo sudo npm ie death and z beam to.
So once you have the PIN two installed, we can start running our server.
So let's get inside.
So before we run, we need to make sure we run NPM installed because we don't have the node modules
folder.
All right.
So NPM install and you have to use sudo.
Okay.
And women still had been successful if you missed out.
Now you see not modules as previously we had get ignored, not modules.
So it wasn't there.
But now we are running in women.
Some say it is based on whatever peg is was here in the bag in today's market.
So let's try running the server PM to start NPM.
Oh, actually our server that is server or that's the end to point.
Right.
So you can use PM two to start this.
Perfect.
No.
If you go.
And try your IP address, which is here.
Now this is what you see because we haven't running we haven't been running the.
But if you go to less API.
Okay.
So we got five or two bad get away now.
When you have things like that, things are not going the way you want it to.
You can always try running NPM start just like you do that locally.
That way if there is an error, you can see in the server console.
Right.
So let me run this.
Actually, let me stop this beam to kill.
Kill all the Iranians process and then npm start.
Let's do this.
This is just for debugging purposes, right?
Obviously you want to use PM too, but now things are not working.
Right.
So let's see what's wrong.
Let's try.
Cannot get API.
Okay.
So then whenever you see anything like this, that means APIs are running.
Now, I'm not sure why it wasn't running previously.
You can see it is running it's try courses.
I guess we have an entry.
So seems like it is working.
We might have some other issues.
Think I know what is the issue.
The issue is.
Let me stop that.
The issue is you can see in server sorry, in package.
Jason, we have been using the import export index which is not supported by Node.js just by default.
That's why we use this beggars to help us write import export.
Right.
So this is how we started our server.
So that means you have to do the same thing in the production as well.
Maybe you could write a different command.
You could do that as well.
You can just use this does our yes and so so let's try that PM to start.
Well, actually, it's not being Brewster.
From the m to start desk.
Our ears and shoulders decided this.
This is the right way.
Okay.
Let's make a small change in our project here so that it's much easier.
So you can see here, we can leave it as it is this way you can always run Pim to start subjects.
It's okay.
So what do you want to do?
Is in the server this instead of writing everything, let's move all this code in a separate file and
then here we just going to import ESM and then we're going to serve this, this file.
That way you can easily use that in products in Israel.
Actually, let me change this file name to index for this.
All right.
And then here in the directory me create another file conservatorships.
So what what I'm going to do here is I'm going to require
require equals to
require ESM.
Module and then module two exports equals to acquire.
Index is because we all the code that we had in the server to this we move that to index.
So now here we are in the server to this file.
We are just inputting this index or this.
And the difference is this required is equal to the ESM module.
All right.
So this way.
Okay.
Let me make sure this is in the server folder.
Again, this is important to me.
Drag it and just make sure it isn't the server folder buffet.
Now we can give this a try locally before we push to the alive server.
And this way you'll also see how to make changes and push to the disclosed.
Right.
So let me go back to my server engine start.
There has been no changes and you can see everything is perfect.
You can go.
Local host Let me just try accessing api eight thousands less api so you can see everything is working
beautiful.
I guess that means we made that changes now.
We need to commit that to GitHub and then pull that changes in the digital logs.
I think it gives status.
You can see one file has been changed modified git and get commit death and.
Tinged soldier juice.
And let's get puss.
I guess the code has been pushed to GitHub.
Now we can pull that tinges into the disclose.
So it's good to disclose and make sure your intentions touch over full and you can pull the changes
using sudo get pulled.
Okay.
So we have pulled the changes.
Now you can see we have the index address and we have the server.
This says.
Now let's try to start server duties.
You.
Now, this time, let's see if this works.
And beautiful.
It works.
Now you can see a pin.
Anytime you get anything like this.
Dead in service running.
We just don't have anything served on this endpoint.
But if you go to courses, you see we have m-theory.
Perfect.
So I was able is up and running.
Now let's make sure our server at the front end is running as well.