All right, so let's go and create a media model so that we can save the images in the database.
Some models let's create new file media entities.
It's all lowercase media.
This to make things easier, let's copy one of the schema, this post schema pasted down here.
So we have all these inputs now this one we call it media.
Media skim copy come down here, media schema and this name will be media.
Okay, so leave the timestamp and everything else.
Let's just get rid of that.
We're going to write.
Um.
I just don't see what happened here.
Yeah, it's.
It's a slow slog and all that.
It's okay to scheme a little, right?
So what are you going to save when we save the is so going to save the earth.
That's the most important one this year will be receiving from cloud in every uploaded air and that
when we save in the database.
So the URL will be the type of string
public it will be the type of string so close never gives us the URL in public and so that public ideal.
So we going to save here because later when we want to remove this image from media library, we can
remove it.
So when we remove, we remove from the database and also from the cloud in area.
All right.
So this photo guide will be used for that.
And we also want to save the posted by posted by whoever uploaded the same is the reason for that is
later.
The authors will also have access to the media library.
However, they cannot.
Delete other people's the image that is uploaded by other users.
Right.
So that this will be useful at that time because if they were trying to delete someone else's image,
we will know based on the posted variety I suppose by the type object I didn't refer to the user more.
Okay, so that's pretty much it.
And the time since.
So that's something you need to see that you are obligated and the posted by user.
Okay.
So that's how media schema, once you have the media schema, we can go to a control function and start
saving the the images in the database.
So it's good to post control, it's cool on top and it's important model.
Media from models media.
Okay, let's come on down.
And here now we can upload to Cloud Canary.
We get the URL and probably already we can save that in the database.
And then we finally send the response.
The uploaded image responds to the front end here.
All right, so constant vigilance equals to avoid coding every dot uploader, dot upload and to upload
we need to give the images path.
So that's going to be requests to find the file to path.
I can says you can see the files give us previous to you so we got that request files give us this one.
So we also have to go and access the path.
So that means requested files don't file that path.
So this is what this is what we need to give to do.
Okay.
So that will give us the result which will contain the URL and public IP.
Now let's save in the database first.
Konst Media equals to new media.
No need to create a new media based on the URL.
That's going to be the result.
Dot security.
Earth, public I.D..
That's going to be results.
Dark, complicated, and then pushed to.
Right.
That's going to be the request door to user today.
Right now for this to work.
You need to make sure you have applied the request hand in middleware in your out.
Any question.
All right.
So that's all the data we need to create a new media saving the data we see in this to use save.
So once it is saved, you can send the response, no response to this and you can send media.
So this is the object you got here that is already saved in the database so that this will contain.
You are probably already posted, right.
As well as the the unique idea that you get when you save anything in the MongoDB.
Okay, beautiful.
Let's have a look at it.
Let's see how this response is received in the client.
So basically this when the image has been uploaded, we want to put that image.
In the context, in the context and from the context we can access to the posts that we are creating.
So if we want to send the photo featured image, we just upload and that will be automatically selected
so we can just create a post with that.
And then later, when you have the media library from here, if you want to choose any of the media,
you can just click in.
That will be selected and that will be again sent to the back end when we're creating a new post.
So we'll come back to that.
But so far we have almost we are pretty much done here.
So let's have a look.
Let's see how we received the response.
Once we receive the response, we're going to save in the context of that message.
We need to create the media context very soon.
So let me try and it's just separate.
This one, it's uploading.
Okay.
So you can see we've got a success message very successfully uploaded.
We got the response.
Let me just go to.
Upload file.
The response, Mrs..
We didn't to the response.
Network.
So the upload image.
Thank you, sir.
We.
I didn't see the response.
Okay.
So not just the success in Ms., but we actually have to use this response.
So when we get the successful response, we get the URL of the emails, right?
So that information we want to put in the context so that we can later use that to create a new post.
So that means not just the message that, but we also want to have a look at that.
Let me just console.log for now.
We don't have the context yet, so let's just come to log in for that file.
The tour begins in front of five.
I said, let's try one.
As it's uprooting.
Okay.
So you can see once it is uploaded we got the response info dot file in for the find it responses here.
So we're supposed to receive the response here, but it's empty.
And so I realized that here in our control.
I forgot to use a weight.
And that's the reason I think we're not getting the best one.
So let's make sure we have a weight here so that we get the response.
So let's try one more time.
I guess the end for that file this time we have the responses.
As you can see, this response has the information of all the media that is saved in the database.
So it has created a built in data public ID posted by users ID in the URL.
Beautiful.
This information we're going to save in the context.
By the way, if you want to try, you can try.
The image has been uploaded beautifully.
So this information.
Now all this files we will be able to show in the library later.
But as the upload is done, if you use a one to.
Use that images in the post.
He should be able to.
So we will put it in the context and.
Later when recruiting a post we can clear from the context.
So in the context we will have the media's and we will also have a property called selected.
I guess as soon as any image has been uploaded the the latest images response we will always save in
the context as a selected one.
Right.
So when the post is created we will always have that as a featured images.
Okay, so you'll see how that works.
But so far so good.
We have been able to upload the images.
Awesome.
Now this delete feature here, we are not going to actually implement this one.
Instead, we will show all the media library here and let me show you how I did in the finished product.
So here we will allow them to do it.
All right.
So we are going to.
Use this one.
So you saw one whenever you uploaded.
You see that?
So you can remove that by using CCS if you don't want to.
So that.
So that one to write.
Clean, inspect.
And Burton.
And upload a list items of this class, then we can target veterans.
Copy that.
And if you use that.
Let me just quickly try here.
Displayed.
No.
If you do that, you can see the.
You don't see that.
So let's use this.
See us.
Put it in our thesis frame.
All right.
Now, you come here.
You don't see that.
It's beautiful.