Okay.
So to upgrade the category, we need to.
Create a new state.
So let me just put that here.
It's opted to just so that we don't get confused.
So the concept of Dating Girl, we sit on the dating category.
It wants to use state.
So we're going to have the updating category.
So whenever that one is clicked, we use that handle and it function to put that item the click category
in the state just so that we know each category we're going to update.
Okay.
To make sure you don't make any typos, you.
And then we also going to have the visible state sections.
Visible set visible to use state and would give the deferred value of force.
This visible state will be used to display the model.
Okay.
So motta on list, the user is clicking on the edit.
We don't want to show the model so that will be hidden.
But when they clicked we saw that.
So that hidden and so and hidden that will be controlled by this valley.
So very different.
It will be hidden.
When they click, we will show them.
Okay.
So for this one, obviously we need the model as well.
So let's input the model component from and model.
Awesome.
Now first, let's make sure we are able to put the updating category in this state.
So let's come down to that function handle.
Edit We get access to the item, the category here.
So said updating category.
You said that to item and then
set visible.
All right now.
Just to make sure everything's working.
I want to.
Just come down here and just.
Have a look at that.
I'm dating category decent string a fine.
I'm dating category no for.
So when we click, we should see the auditing category here.
When I click, you can see the flipped categories node.
When I clicked here, it's broken and so beautiful.
All right, so that looks good.
Let me remove that.
So we got the updated category.
We have the set visible.
When it is clicked, it becomes true.
So let's bring in the model from InDesign.
So.
You can put that model anywhere.
Let's put it doesn't have to be inside column.
It can just stay outside.
You can.
A model.
Let's quickly have a look at the official docs.
It's always a good idea to have a look just so that you can always stay updated, even if it changes
in future.
So you can see the basic model example is here.
Let's click and let's see how it is used.
You can see they have the visible state.
And look it and cancel.
This is something you can do in L.A. because this is the one line of code.
And basically, this is how you use the model.
So use the model, put some content in.
Okay.
So you're going to use the object form.
Yeah.
And then you give the title and the visible.
You knew the value of the state and on and on canceling in years.
I guess the title visible on okay.
On guns.
Let's use that.
Let's
update category.
Title next one wants.
Visible.
If I do it to the Senate, I can sue you.
Let me sue.
You can see if you send it to Drew, it stays it.
It's open.
Of course, they don't do anything at the moment, but it stays open.
You know, you don't want to send it to Drew.
Instead, you want to send it to Visible.
By default, the visual is false.
So you don't see the.
Let me let me come back to this one.
Okay.
What do you want to do is close the motor?
I guess so.
Whether it's on.
Okay.
In fact, let me just wait for that on.
Let me show you visible.
Let me give you a base refresh.
I guess you wouldn't see the model when you click.
You see the model ANC now at the moment.
Nothing works.
But actually, we don't want the canceling buttons.
We don't want to use them.
We just want this item.
Let me show you how we did in the finished product.
You can see here this is the form and this is the button of that phone.
So we don't have any a default or can cancel buttons.
We just have this one.
So let's hide them to hide them.
What you can do is for.
Do not.
When you do that, you can see the food is gone.
Now you want to be able to close it, click here or click anywhere on the PC for that you can use.
On cancel and on cancel.
You want to double the visibility, right?
So on council, we didn't have to use another fence and we can just write everything in line because
it's going to be very simple, said visible.
You set it to false.
All right.
So when Ed was clicked
on, canceled.
Let me just turn to.
On.
Okay.
On cancel.
Yeah.
Okay.
On cancer.
Let's use.
Okay.
As you.
SEAL.
Okay, see, I did.
So maybe that's from SEAL.
I think we do need to be honest.
Let's.
It's funny.
Thanks to networks.
Now you can see when you click.
By default, visibility is false.
So we don't see that when you click, visible becomes true.
So you see that the model and then when you click it, it's gone and you don't have to click.
You can click anywhere here when you click.
That also goes the model to Beautiful.
That's good.
So it's looking good so far.
The next thing you want to do is.
Have a form that is similar to the one that we have here for creating categories.
So we need a similar phone.
So that we can.
Popular this ability category here in the form field.
All right.
So that you can see this is the form, right so this similar from we can use now we could just copy
and put it down here.
I'll put in Taylor Moore.
I like this one.
And it's a mortar we can close like this as well.
So you can show some content as well.
So you can see now into that we want to show the form now instead of writing everything here to make
this file really begin how to manage, we can create a separate component.
Okay, so let's create a separate component where we're going to.
So the phone for updating the category.