All right, so before we work on this for control function, I realize we need one more.
You can see here to get all the comments.
At the moment, only admin can get on the comments, but we will also need to get all the comments of
the user right.
So any user, any comments delivered could be in one post, could be in many posts.
Doesn't matter all the comments that they have left.
We want to wait for users as well so we can we can do use this because this will return all the comment.
This is only for the admin.
So let's it's another out for the user comments.
So what does it get?
Let's call it user comments.
Require a signing and then the user comment.
Make sure to include this control function.
And it's pretty.
So no need to credit this five functions.
Here's a comment.
Let's make sure we have that.
Let me just copy that.
Extend this to user comments.
Beautiful.
All right, now let's start working.
So let's first swerve in the comments which will return all the comments.
Now we need to make sure we have the pagination because we own.
Have implemented this business concept for the admin because the admin will be receiving all the.
All the comments, that can be quite a lot.
All right.
So we are we will be receiving the base as a root for arms.
And you see here first, just like we did earlier for the post, if you remember, Bob Baselitz said
it to our little G six.
Of course you can set it to 50, 100, let's set it to six because we don't have many comments at the
moment because we should be receiving from the request, perhaps a request from base.
If we have, we use that value.
Otherwise, by default, we use the value one.
All right, now let's find the comments.
Comments.
Let's use our comment Eagles to await
comment model user defined function and then we keep is minus one multiply or base.
Then we populate.
Posted by you this information we want just to name.
Then we want to also populate post forestieri so that we can get the post information title struck.
So no comma.
This can be useful because when you send all the comment for admin or the user, it would be useful
to know this comment was left on which post?
Right.
So we should be able to show the post title.
For each comment.
Otherwise it can be very confusing.
We saw all the comments, but I use this done.
Not on which post the comment belongs to.
Right.
So we need to send the post information as well.
We can do that like this.
Now let's start by the latest one at the limit parties.
So that's six and that's pretty much it.
No written response.
All comments.
Beautiful.
So that's how we can send out the comment with the pagination two is time can be hitting six.
Okay.
And then as the BS goes up to three four, that will.
We have this minus, so that will be deducted.
So if it is to do minus base.
So if the baby's due to management, there will be one that will be skipped party so that six posts
will be skipped when it is three.
Then that time poo poo poo comment will be skipped and so on.
All right, so we've already done this similar thing for the Post as well before, I guess.
So that's four comments now for user comments.
So now this time we want to find all the comment that belongs to that user.
And so this time, what you can do is go and count.
Sorry.
Not that one can't.
Let's put it in a variable comments.
It looks to avoid comment front.
So we find all the comments based on this posted by information.
So posted by the logged in, you decided I guess, to find all these comments and then Richard.
Actually, let's use some probability, just like we did before for the admin.
So we're going to populate.
Published.
Posted by.
We want to get the users name.
Then again, we want to populate the post information as well.
So post it.
We can send the title in slot.
We can search.
Based on the created date, the latest ones, and that is it.
So that's how we can get all the comments of to use it and we can return the response station comments.
So we return all the comments for the admin, we return all the comments that is found based on the
posted way for user comments.
Next one, we want to get the total of the comments so that we can use this in the pagination.
All right.
So count equals of it.
Comment on documents.
We can use that.
That would give us all the count.
So if we have nine comments that will give us the number nine.
Yep.
Like that.
That would be the response we send that like this.
Now.
Next one, let's work on.
Update and remove.
All right.
So to update the comment, all we can do is we can find the comment, find writing update pretty straightforward.
So first we can find we need to know which comment to update.
This comment ID is something we will be receiving in the request frames.
Right.
So we can grab that destructor from request params then.
Now we should also be sending the comment.
In the request body.
In fact, that will be content will be sending the content from in the request body.
And then once we have this information, we can finally update the content.
So fine by adding an update.
So fine by the, based on this idea.
And then what you want to update is we want to update the content, right?
So content.
Um, I'm not sure how we, I think before we had it common.
So if we are receiving the comment, then we could just leave it like this.
Content.
Slim into some of that.
I'm pretty sure we can send the content.
Let me quickly go up.
Previously we had.
Create comments or when we accredit, we sending the comment.
Okay.
And then the content value would be comment.
So that means we want to do something simple.
Copy that.
And then instead of content, actually we are receiving the comment like it's use comment.
So content will be comment.
Perfect new truth and we return the updated comment immediately.
No.
Next one is to remove the comment.
So here again, we can use the similar fonts and find bad idea and they move.
We can use that to const comment comment fine by adding delete, remove or dig.
Both works the same way and have that valid ID we will be getting in their request frames commentating
so you can destructor like this all you can do it it like this.
Okay.
And then he sent the response okay too because we don't really need to send the due date comment in
the front it beautiful.
You can see here we have all these functions to remove, update, get the count, get all the users
comment and the entire comments collection for ADD Beautiful.
Now that we have this one, let's head over to our client and start working in the decimal.
The youths, desperate admin and other users desperate for the comment and allow them to update intimate.