All right, so we could buy Alex Parallax images that looks like this is pretty cool.
Now, if you want some kind of a separate which looks something like this, so you're going to have
this horizontal line with this I can centered right here.
So if you want something like that, we can easily do that using a divider or two.
Let's import divider from end.
And then let's try to use that.
Let's come on with down.
We have the heading heads do.
Then here we put divider.
And then into divider.
And the children we can use the item.
So that item is called thunderbolt.
So we can import that from and.
Some on this from.
Thunder Bolt Portland.
All right.
And let's try to use that.
And you can see here we have got this beautiful horizontal line.
It depends on the background image.
If you have a bit darker image, then it will look more vibrant.
But you can see it's there.
Right.
Beautiful.
All right.
So that is all it's done.
So next thing we want is the categories, list of categories, which is something we can just import
our hopes and easily display the categories and then we are going to create the future.
Okay.
So after this one, let's work on that two categories.
Let's also create a separate rule for that.
So rule.
So we got the divider.
Integral, critical.
I'll give it a full width, of course.
Spent 24.
And then here, let's also write some thesis on this school.
I want to center the list of categories here.
So text line center and bit of a margin on top and bottom.
So we have a bit of a gap margin total.
Let's give it a D margin bottom eight.
All right.
So here I want to map through.
The categories are just like we did before for posts like let's actually copy this deep.
It's easy to use space here and we just want to send this from let us post to categories we already
have.
The categories he really do use from the hooks.
All right.
So we've got that.
So that one, when we click, when you use a click, we tell them to.
Category Sloths and sloth.
See.
Let me just call her.
See this to me just for the sake of simplicity.
See?
Category slug.
Category name.
Now, we don't want to destroy history.
Instead, we want the button.
Right.
So let me change that to button.
Button.
And then we can just give it.
If you actually try to use tape, let's leave it like that.
And you don't want them to be attached to it.
It's over.
So let's give it some margin.
In to.
All right.
And since this is a map function, we should use a key that we can trigger that underscore.
And let's use this key in here.
I think I forgot.
Post-op endoscopy.
Perfect.
All right.
So we got this rule.
We were showing all these categories, name in the button, and they clickable.
Let's.
Button.
Let's make sure we import that.
Beautiful.
We've got only four categories, so they are here.
If I click.
Land on the right base.
So we have a lot of post for react categories.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So the next step is the footer.
But before we do that, Fred, let's actually not forget to give it a heading as well for the categories.
So right on top of the category, just like before we had the heading.
We can have similar heading in the divided world.
So if you want to let me just copy that along with the heading.
And then who do you see in this two categories.
Oh, I.
I.
So you've got the categories now that looks too big.
Let's make something like this small.
And this time, instead of using this as I can, we actually put the category itself in the middle.
So let's let's do that.
So that means categories.
Actually, we don't need all this heading.
Let's remove the heading.
And instead of thunderbolt, we use categories text simply like.
Beautiful.
That looks good.
All right.
Now let's work on the future as well.
So we basically showing some icons and some text in the footer with the background image.
It's quite simple.