So we're going to implement, edit and do it first.
Let's implement it because that's that's pretty easy.
So let's do that first.
Let's head over to our server.
Account.
First, let's create that delete from the router.
Don't delete.
So we need to begin to create around, let's call it force class.
On the score.
I did it.
Just calling posterity just to make things easier.
Host Ali, we can call anything we like and require.
Signing is admin and the.
Control function name.
We can call this post.
Okay.
And it's clear this under a false name or post.
So yeah, export comes in first.
So again, what we want to do is we want to find the ports that it depicts.
I suppose equal weight or small fine but added dilute and we give the eyelid that we get from the params
a request for we call that post trading post.
And so once you delete we can just send a response or get to, you know, we generally need to send
this post, so let's go make a request to this endpoint.
So let me fix the type of interrupt.
I can now include two client.
So we go to admin posts index and then we have the handle delete function here.
That's the link.
So let's to this.
Let's try.
Captain Error.
So here we want to send a request using excuse.
So let's make sure we have access.
We do here.
The first, we want to show some kind of alert.
So sometimes by mistake, they might click.
So we don't want to immediately delete the post so we can show some kind of alert.
We can use a native browser feature that's called window control.
So let's put it in a variable, let's call it.
And so it would suit window dart going from just like under that alert we can use confirm as well.
And here we can say, are you sure you want to delete?
And the answer will be either yes.
True or false.
So if we click, okay, that will be yes.
Otherwise it will be false as to if we give the answer.
So if it if we get the answer, that means it will be true.
So if it is true, then we want to send the request.
Otherwise.
We want to.
We don't want to send a request, I guess.
So what are we going to do here is actually we can take you.
If no answer, then just return immediately.
Don't do anything else.
Otherwise.
What we can do is we can send a request to in to cast down to a good soup or sweet excuse to delete,
make a request.
So the endpoint is going to be less forced.
Less.
Most I guess would make a request to that.
And we give the response.
Okay.
To, to, if.
Okay, if.
Okay.
Data Okay.
Then what do you want to do is you want to remove this item, whichever item has been deleted.
Okay.
So you want to delete that from the list so we can use said post.
So we have we have the context, said Bush.
That's where we are.
We have all the force so set forth.
So in this post we have the post and categories.
So we we can use our function in previous values, whatever we have.
We spread out the previous values.
And this.
This will contain the categories.
So we don't want to touch that.
Just post.
We want to update the post.
We want to filter out the deleted one so we can use filter function for that.
So previous dot posts don't filter.
The filter takes a function to use out of function here.
So previous post we filter out till we get it post on the filter from the post and we want to filter
out the one that doesn't match with this IED.
I used to post dirt on disquieted not equals equals post dirt in this fight.
So we're going through all the posts.
So if that doesn't match the this 80.
So.
All of them.
We want to filter out so that value, the filter value will be indistinct.
Okay.
So we missed the parenthesis.
So let me just.
Wrap all this in a parenthesis.
And again.
So that should immediately remove the post from the list.
Yeah.
So let's give it a try.
So if I try this Friday editing this third post, we have nine posts at a moment in front.
Want to delete?
We get this window window dart confront.
So if I can't and nothing happens.
But if I go ahead and click.
Okay.
That is due to the third posted video.
And we have eight posts so far and I'm sure that is due date from the database as well.
And as you can see, we got on the edge left.
All right.
So that's deleting the post.
Now, next one, we want to work on it.