Okay.
So previously we were able to upload the image, a single image, which is awesome.
It's working.
When it is successfully uploaded, we got the response and we're not doing anything with that response
for a moment.
We just console.log, but very soon we'll put that in the media context, I guess.
So let's wait for this one because let's also work on the media library.
So we have both components ready.
All right.
So let's work on the the media library.
Now here we're going to have the multiple upload with drag and drop.
So let's roll that and then we can just work on this response.
So we will put in the context.
Okay.
So let me close this test for now.
And media libraries.
Let's go.
In fact, the North, there would be a lot of similarities, so maybe we can just split window.
Let's keep a profile here in media library here, just so that we can save some time by copying the
inputs.
So pretty much all all that we need here familiar library as well.
So we have the upload, we have the misses.
We didn't need the button.
This time we're using the drag and drop.
Upload outlines instead of Rhode Island.
We need another one that's called inbox outlined.
All right, then.
What are you going to do?
Is this props we might be able to use?
Pretty much as it is.
So let me just copy that.
Call me the props.
But yeah.
And let's also access the.
Context so that we can use the token.
All right.
So so far, you can see it's pretty much similar up to here.
The only difference we're going to have is the upload.
Now, instead of upload, we're going to use drag.
A drag is also something and destructor from the upload.
Let me quickly show you the other example.
So this is the one we're going to use drag and drop multiple upload.
You can see the code looks pretty much similar.
We just have to change, make some small changes to our props.
And here we just saw the drag instead of upload, we saw the dragon and then we have some text, we
have the icon.
So this is the text divide into you can see it's pretty similar.
The only thing we want to change is make it multiple so that it supports multiple upload.
Okay.
So let's use the drag so we can destructor drag from upload, which we already have.
We already have the upload, so let's destruction that and then let's use the drag.
So to return, we want to then that with Dracula.
And here again, just like abroad, we use props.
And I think this driver is mindful of its multiple.
So we don't have to probably use multiple yet the paragraph.
Mm hmm.
What he can do here is.
They give you the class?
Well, in fact, we may not need class name in books.
I would mainly just use this item for now.
And another Peter.
And here we can right click and drag.
Click and drag find to.
This area had two problems.
All right, so let's see how this looks.
Beautiful.
All right.
That's looking good.
Now, obviously, you can write some cheeses to make it look nice and big if you want.
Probably.
Actually, we can use the default class name they used here and upload drag icons.
Let's try using that.
Let's have a look.
Yeah.
So that makes a difference.
So we can use the different class names from the and documentation as well.
James and Blue Text.
Okay.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful.
All right, so we've got that drag and drop.
And now let me close this and just keep one window.
One window.
And let's go on the.
And this one, Brooks.
So we still are going to use the same endpoint.
So this endpoint will receive the images as a form data and upload the cloud in every save in the database.
Give us the rest once it will continue to work with.
It's one file of many files.
Doesn't matter.
So that's that's fine
here.
Okay.
So here we have to use multiple.
I can.
So, multiple truth.
That's the accent.
Let's put it on top.
Name one.
And then that one gets a multiple drew.
We got X and we get the token on the ten's everything as it is.
Happening with the upload.
Fine.
It's the same thing when it is done.
We saw the success.
Mrs..
We console.log the infra file.
There's one more thing you'll notice in the document doesn't on drop until we have this function.
All right.
So let's just make sure we have that function as well.
So.
So that's on tens and on drop.
They basically console.log.
But this probably will work behind the scenes.
Whether you are drag and drop or you just click in select multiple operative will work.
All right.
So into a fun drag draw.
So at the moment we just want a logging here and console.log here, here in both components.
I guess it will work on this response.
We will put in this context state.
But so far let's try and let's make sure media libraries also working for multiple upload answer it's
here and we have the console and then try this time I'm going to try to upload it so you can upload
as many as you want.
Okay.
Now you can see here.
We got both of these players.
Both of them are successful.
We got the response.
Both of them have been assembling the database.
All right.
So that's awesome.
You can have a look at the database if you go to media.
You can see all these images have been uploaded so we can grab from this.
So in the library.
One more thing I noticed then too when we.
When we are abroad, we should see some kind of uploading files name and this upload status just like
we saw in the of France.
So we should see that here as well.
But for some reason, I didn't see that.
Let me just try one more time.
Featured image.
Click and drag.
Now, another problem with this one is it will probably select all kinds of files.
All right.
So you want to limit this to only the immune state.
So let's fix that.
Dragon.
So what you can do here is.
You can use that property concept.
I sit and you are searched.
All kinds of images.
Images, less everything.
Now you could do imagery being or something like that.
But when you do this one wild card still in Mr. Debate PNC, all of the file types with images you would
be able to upload obviously with that tens if I come here and select something different, for example,
this file, TNT, you can select.
So let me try them.
Try these two friends.
I just want to see.
I can see.
Looks like there's something there, but you can see this height increase.
But for some reason we don't see that.
So the size has increased, but we don't see that it's inspect.
And upload drag.
So we just used it.
And I think it's the height issue.
So height, let's say 150 feet.
So.
Okay.
So that's reason.
So we have the France but it was somehow it was just marking these files for the reason so we need to
and this year is I guess this so that we can see the uploaded files.
So let's go and put inside probably.
Stents or C assistance.
Put them here.
Okay.
Now, let me just try some more.
Let me just try three and even two while they're happening.
We see that and they're absolutely beautiful.
Okay.
So we have been able to upload single images as well as multiple images along with the drag and drop.
All right.
So all this response we receive in our approach to this function.
So let's go ahead, create a context so that we can put all this uploaded media France to have context.
So I've been saying drag and drop, but I haven't actually shown you the dragon drops.
William Quigley show you how that works as well.
So let's go to desktop.
Let's go to images and let me just address this three image limit.
Just click and drag and you can see the drag and drop works.
Awesome.