All right.
So we did some refactoring.
Now we're going to move on to the admin route just like we have the author out.
We going to quit admin, right?
That will be protected for the user with the role of end.
And we will have a different layout as well of admin layout that will have that will look similar but
will have less features.
So admin author will be able to create host libraries and and profile.
So for that, obviously, first we have to work in our back in that we need to create a route that will
take if the user has the role of author.
Just like previously we had one for admin, so didn't close all this.
Let's quickly have a look at our layout admin layout.
So here you can see we are sending requests to current admin wrote in our back in and in this draft
we have applied the is admin mid-year.
So let's have a look.
Meanwhile, where's index?
Actually, it's good to get out first post.
We have the easy and middle way.
So if I click here, you can see.
We find the user by adding the logged in use idea and we check for the rule.
If it is admin then if it is not admin then we send the error, otherwise we execute it next.
So this is a middleware.
So we're going to create a similar middleware that will take if the user's role is also I guess if the
role is alpha, then we, we execute this function.
Otherwise we send the error response.
Okay.
So we did that first.
Let's go to.
Actually, we converted this middle works index from a threat that you.
Probably we can actually even copy this one to make things easier scoping them.
Is something it's called.
Obviously we try to find the use of by the lovely news A.D. and then we take if the users role is not
awesome,
then we send this at a response.
Otherwise we execute next.
Awesome.
Okay, now that we have this middleware, let's go to the post and then here and let's create the function
as well.
Actually, let's go to the author and we can import that here is awesome.
And we have the take him for admin current current user.
Actually, we can just use the current user function.
You can see current user.
So that's not quite as clear to the current user, to the current admin wrote When the request comes
in, we have this middle way that makes sure users logged in.
We have this middleware that makes sure that the user has the role of admin and if it is all good,
this function executes.
This function doesn't really have anything.
It just say or get true.
Richard This is just to give the okay response.
So that means we can do the same thing for current affairs so far.
And also
only thing we need to do here it turns this middleware instead of is admin middleware we use now is
also I guess that's something to do now from our client.
When we make a request from our callout, we make a request to current item and we will receive the
response.
Okay.
If the user is actually after.
Right, simple, simple as before, it works the same way it worked for admin.
Okay, so we've got the current off the root, we have the middleware.
So that means we can now go to a client and create a layout.
We create a layout and we create the navigation as well for auto, just like we did earlier for admin.
So we created the admin now before.
This is the navigation on the side where this is.
This is admin then.
So we need something similar for author and then we create a layout for our third.
So using the user effect to make a request to current author.