So we created the category post by category that gives us all the boost that belongs to a certain category.
Now let's create that piece.
We have the back in done.
So let's clear the space so that we can show the list of posts for any given categories.
So that means we need to have the space categories less notice.
So here in our Clean Spaces folder, we need to create one for all call categories.
I see that category.
Have you said let's make it singular?
We name
called category and enter here.
Let's create a file called Slow that would receive the dynamic slug and version that we show the the
result.
All right, so first, we need some basic inputs.
So first excuse from excuse, then we want a couple of components from and import.
So we need cart.
So we're going to use card to show its force card row and column four layout button and then divider.
We may use divider and then have it for and we use Avatar to show the the post image's import head component
from next because we will make this issue friendly place because this is one of the actually the most
important piece if your focus issue.
Actually we wanted it done that we have the single push.
These are the most important bits.
We have already worked on that.
But this is also pretty good for issue four is category.
If we are showing a lot of this post relevant post, then obviously that helps one issue.
So this is quite important as well.
I guess we import head component and then next one we want link as well link from next link then to
formatted the date.
We need pages in both pages from basis.
Then for this to work, we need to import the related time plugin for to work with this.
And then here also just like we did before, we showed the categories and we'll just post on the sidebar.
We can do the same thing here if you want to.
That's not really important, right?
You can sort it like that if you want to.
Let's let's do.
We did so already.
It's really easy just to just need to import these hooks.
Use category from
use category.
I'm sorry he's carrying you from.
So we are here.
So we need to go to hooks in the use category.
Copy and paste.
Here.
Change this to use.
Latest posts.
All right.
And that's on, Renee.
Now, let's extend this period of time to these years, and then let's try the function component.
Single category equals to
no, because we want this space to be some server interface issue.
We are not going to use use effect.
Instead, we're going to use the get some side props, okay, to export the default
single category.
And then just before that, we use this gift service as props export async function, get server side
props.
Now we need to access the slugs which we can access from params.
So here we use const data inputs to are we excuse don't get we make a get request, let's use bektic.
So that would be the the API so process stored in v dot API.
We have this variable in our eon bid because when we're using it in the server side mode in gives some
said proves the emu variable API will be accessible.
All right.
So SLAs API, SLAs post by category.
And then we need to send a strong so we use less foreign slack.
All right.
So we make a request.
We have some issues.
Excuse.
Oh, yes, it was.
My type of head should be input.
All right.
See, that's the X yes request.
And then you give us the data.
And now that data, we can return the return.
Okay.
So here I think we have to.
So when we return, we always have to return props.
So instead, props posts.
Tara, let me quickly go to Sarah because here I'm not just I want to show the post, I want to also
show this category in which every category has been collected.
You can see a post in Node.
So we are showing the category name as.
So that means we need to not only show the the post that belongs to this category, we want to actually
have some information about the category as was just about to.
We so here for that let me go to my server control category and here I'm returning post only instead
of just return post, let me return category as well.
So that way I can throw the category title on the heading.
So post and category.
If I do this, we will not only get the post but also get this category.
By the way, let's have a look.
You can see we're getting the posts and categories.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So that means let's go back here and now we are returning data don't host and we are returning categories
which that would be donna dog category beautiful.
So this way we will have access to both posts and categories.
Now to render that we can just destroy through the what has been written as props will be accessible
here post category and we can just show them.
Now before we do that, actually, yeah, we can do that to return.
Let me use fragment here.
First I want to use the head six and there's room for a superb was head here let me give the title.
We can show the category name.
And matter description we can use.
Let's use category name.
Let's let's use that text.
And let me just right here read latest post.
Category name.
Sorry.
That should be.
The Baptist.
Okay.
All right.
So we have the health and now let's work on the content, showing the content.
So we want to show the content in a room room column.
Grow can have the culture as girls.
Let's use Twitter and then call them.
Small.
We can make a dress.
One, two, three.
In a small screen.
We want to take the full width, so make it tougher for a small screen.
Lars use 18 and the remaining.
We can show the categories in the sidebar.
Make it just margin bottom 12 bit of margin on the bottom.
I want to have a bit of a gap here on the very top, so let me use it for that.
In that one stone margin, top six big.
So I guess just for the sole purpose of having this margin now in this quarter, let's try to show the
information about this category and how many post it heads I get.
Let me start from page one.
And let me just right here post in the category name category don't name let's make it give it a bit
of a storm.
Text Ally and center.
Yeah.
I just want to make it sound.
You can see here we have the heading post in the category.
Name.
Is that beautiful?
Let me remove the star sign.
Awesome.
No, it's not centered and unfortunately this one looks like it's not required objects.
Maybe just a little bit.
I think we can put that here.
Yeah, we can.
But then we will have the sidebar.
So I think it's better.
It's just undo.
Send this to me in between.
And that's that's fair.
Okay, so we got this one.
Let's continue working on this one list.
So all the posts that belongs to this category.