All right.
So let's go ahead and use that NPM library that I was talking about and being exposed to the integrity.
This will help us verify the token.
This is the package we're going to use.
So this is the way we're going to use.
So you can see here they have the root this function.
This middleware is here.
And then the function which in our case control a function that will do something, some kind of a send
some kind of responsive in the database, whatever that is.
So you can see here in between and this is the this is the library that is used to verify the token
actually did the.
Method we didn't use until it's installed this one.
In our service.
Let's stop that.
That in.
Let's start it back here and let's use that now to put that middle where we could actually put in a
control or we could create a different.
For.
Let's put it in a different folder because we will be creating a few more middle words later.
So here in this server, let's create a new folder.
Middleware.
And inside here we just need one find.
So let's just call it index service.
And here we can write our function to export const.
Let's call it that requires signing.
This is the name we are giving to our middleware.
And here, obviously we could write our own function.
However, since we're going to use that, the library that we're going to use that string and the input
of that first input expressed the view t from expressed to the ready to double take.
The ecologist did everything you could.
You know, you could call it anything you like.
And this is the way they have used it.
So you can even copy that.
So here.
Expressed the dignity to decide the library we import.
We use that.
We use that as a function.
And here we are going to pass the the object, which is right here as well to.
This.
The beauty is already here, our exhausted of some of that and more of that.
And then we have the curly brace as well setting up that, some of that.
So as you can see here, we just need these two properties here inside this object.
One is secret.
Another is the algorithm.
So algorithm is just a standard.
So we can continue using this algorithm secret.
And now the secret has to be the biggest secret, which is hearing the Ian Lee file by the name of did
a beauty secret.
So this is the same secret we used to generate token.
Right.
So that means to verify.
So we need the same secret.
So let's replace this with.
That that one we have.
In the end, we saw that Chinese forces stood in the dirt to the sacred.
All right.
So this is how you going to use this library?
Nice and simple request.
Sign it.
All right, so now you can import this in apply in any routes that you want to protect for the logged
in user only answer.
This is all you have to do.
So let's copy that and import in our routes because we want to protect this road.
Right.
So you.
So we have continuously sold the right one for.
MG Now it's so important.
Requires signing.
From Midwest.
All right.
And then we can apply it as a middleware.
So instead of.
The one we wrote before replaced that with a request.
Sign it.
Our set is how we can use a middleware.
Now, this will make sure that we have the logged in user.
By verifying the token it gets, it will also take for the expiry as well.
And if the token is valid, then it will add.
The property in the request object by the name of the user.
That is a default behavior in that what it does automatically.
So if the token is valid, then we know that when we generate that token, we use the user's ID, right?
So if you have a look here one more time when we generate that token.
We use the X Factor, we use the Secret, but we also use this data, the payload, which is the user
side.
All right.
So that means this ID we will be able to access from the request object because of this middleware.
This will automatically add.
If the token is valid, it will add the user property in the request object automatically by default.
And then from there, you will be able to access this user site.
All right.
So that's the beauty of this, Neal, because when we apply this bill will not only that, we know that
we have the logged in user.
We know who is the user because we have the user's ID, right?
So based on that I.D., we can query the database and find that uses other information, for example,
user name, email and so on.
All right, so let's let's give it a try.
So we have a plan that means we know.
The Square gondola function.
Let's have a look at that.
So creative control from.
So we should be able to see the request body.
We will also be able to see the heavies, but that is something we already saw.
So let's let's just leave it like this and give it a try.
Let's see if this time, if we can see this console.log and we should be able to see because we have
the token we're sending in the head.
So if you try.
Category cleared, failed.
Oh.
Secrets would be set.
Hmm.
Let's go to our middleware.
We have the secret.
It's a bit weird why we are seeing that.
Because we have the secret there.
So that means for some reason we're not able to access this in WI if it will soon be happening because
we have the required 30 individual conflicts that we have here in the server indication of this.
So that means we should be able to access the new files anywhere, anywhere in our app.
But for some reason it's not working.
So if we're having the same issues, just try to use the required here.
So let's see.
You could try that.
You can see it works.
So basically the problem was even though we using it correctly, somehow in this file, we were not
able to read the EMV variable.
So our.
Every update later on as we progress, if we have to keep doing it or not, you know, if there is a
solution to that.
We did have to keep importing.
I will obviously show you.
But at the moment, let's continue with this one.
So just require this envy.
We don't envy in this file as well so that we can use this variable.
Okay, so it looks good.
Now let's give it a try.
It's good to plant and let's send a category one.
And you can see, obviously, this one works because we have the largest user we have send the dog in
which is valid.
So.
We applied this middleware to our route and still we were able to create you know, we could execute
the code here.
So, so far, so good now since we have applied that middleware.
Like I told you, this gives us the requester to user by default.
So let's see how that should come to log request or user by default.
We get that.
Let's have a look.
So here we should be able to see the idea that we used while generating that hope.
Let's try that.
Let's submit one more time.
Come here.
And you can see here.
Thanks to that Express JWT middleware that has now given us this data and the request to use it because
our token was verified.
So once the token is verified, you can see you are able to access the currently logged in users IED,
which is great.
Now, based on this idea, we can find this user from the date of this and do many other things which
you will see how we use this information as we progress with the course and we have some other information
as well.
So this is issued did.
In this format and this is the expiry date of this stoke issue date and exfoliate.
So that's great.
We were able to use that library to apply a middleware to make sure we have been able to use it and
we will be able to access the ideas.
Now, the next thing we want to do is create one more middleware that will take if the user is admin.
All right.
Now, before we actually do that, let me show you.
What kind of errors you will get if you are sending expired to quickly go to the context.
And let's.
Let's just.
Put some extra characters.
You.
These are the one we're using in the clean one.
So let's.
Send some extra characters just to make sure make sure that our token is not valid, just to see how
this works.
If you do something like that, if you have invalid token and you make a request.
Okay.
So.
Let's try this one.
Okay.
And let's give a refresher.
I guess.
Let's try.
And you can see we got the error message through a category filled in the network tab.
You can see unauthorized because we have the send the invalid token and you can see here on unauthorized
token on a first error format is the format is wrong like you see for one unauthorized.
Beautiful.
Okay, so let's undo that.
Let's remove those characters.
Perfect.
All right.
So.
We were able to use that library to make sure the users logged in now.
In the next lecture we can try creating a category, saving the database.
But then we also want to make sure that it is only accessible for the admin user.
That means we're going to create one or middle middleware to take if the user is added.