Next.
Let's go back inside, blindfolded and in the ground for let's see what we have get ignored declined
to get ignored used to next and non-Muslims who didn't have to worry about that Ian with that local.
This is the file we have to manually create just like in the several we had Ian V in next we have invited
look at the city grind pseudo dot dot Ian we don't local.
All right.
Now let's get inside this fun pseudo v dirty invader, local place II.
And let's insert the gold we need for Ian before it's limp.
Copy that and put in a new file.
Let's see if we need to make some changes.
So the API now API because it's running in the same droplet, same domain.
We don't have to have the full party.
You can just leave it.
So I think you can still use the IP address.
But let me just get to that.
Let's see if there's an issue.
We will come back to this one.
So public, maybe this runs in the grand set, so that's fine.
However, this API we are using in the server side in the get server side prompts, so this one requires
the full path.
All right.
So here we need to use the the IP address which you have here is that is the domain name at the moment.
We don't have domain to just use IP.
I guess a lot of us is that.
With the IP.
This one will be used by the server side props.
However, for the client side we can just use less API.
And then the strobe key.
Obviously when you have the real payment you will get different keys, but for now you can just continue
with this instead of Mid-Continent.
So that's what we need in the products and at the end of it are locally based and a skip call and WQ
hit enter.
So that's how in V for the client as well.
No.
We just have to run npm install sudo npm install.
Once it is done, we will build using NPM brand build and then we should be able to serve our app.
Let's have a.
Don't let me build and run.
Build.
Make sure to use certain.
This may take awhile, depending on your.
Actually, it doesn't really matter.
You enter into and it is all running in the digital ocean.
So hopefully.
They're the droplet size you picked.
I think you picked the the one that cost about 12 down.
Hopefully, that should have enough memory to build.
I've had some issues earlier when the application is slightly bigger and you tried to build using NPM,
burn, build.
It would run out of memory, would run out of RAM, but hopefully it works.
So that's great.
We have.
Got this build process done.
You can see next year automatically optimize all the bases to anything with this symbol that is completely
services rendered.
These are instead again, these are these are automatically generated as static as HTML plus.
Jason So we got.
There's different kinds of build you can see here.
All right.
So let's run the front end as well.
We're going to use PM to start and PM test, test, start.
Perfect.
No.
Let's have a look at our beautiful applications running live in the server.
And there it is.
How good is that?
Obviously we didn't see anything, so we didn't have any coaches yet.
But this is beautiful.
You deployed the application to the lives of it.