Okay.
So we want to show the form.
Put in a central component and just put it here.
So the updating category in a morra.
But to be honest, we can actually move the whole model to the components itself.
All right.
So let's do that.
That's got this model from here.
We'll come back to this file.
Let me close on this.
So we'll come back to this one.
So let's go two components in here, then create new, more new forms called model.
Again, we might be using a few other models as well.
So here in a new file, let's call it
category of date model.
Don't tell us to contest.
A reunion of moral equals to.
We created this component which you and just based whatever you got from the other file.
The model and export
export deferral category on model.
Okay.
So here we need to make sure we have this model component from and
import the model from and.
Okay.
Now let's try importing this one here and this push.
All right, so let's go and talk.
Let's remove the moral.
We don't need that here.
Import that component in students in both categories of moral.
From one step to step three.
Step of getting to a component model.
Category update tomorrow.
So we import that component from there.
Now, the exact same code we had there, but now we moved here.
That's pretty much it.
Now we will get an error if we leave it like this.
As you can see, I guess this component requires all the fields, for example, visible, which is not
available here.
So instead, visible results are not available in here.
So we will get the error message.
You can see here visible is not defined.
So what we can do is we can pass these values, these values, these functions we can pass from here
as props properties.
Right.
Visible.
Invisible.
Soot, invisible.
Said Visit.
I guess we can pass the props from there and then we can access them here.
We can disrupt the visual set visual.
If we don't destructor and use just props, then you can access it as props.
Start visual.
You can do that.
But this structuring makes things easier.
All right.
So now it should be good.
You can see used to get that model to having to close.
Beautiful.
All right, so this way we can pass that process down to other components and make make them work.
And sometimes you can even make them reusable.
Reuse it's components in many other files.
Something like that we will be implementing in other.
Of other parts of this course as well.
Infuser.
All right.
So so far, so good.
We got this model, we move there, but now we want to show the front, right?
So let's import.
All right.
That we can put everything in.
From from and.
And just to save some time, let's go here in the next booth.
And we all have this phone.
So let's just try to make use of that, I guess.
Let's use that phone.
Copy that.
Come here.
And instead of that name to that phone, now you can see this request input and the button component
as well.
So let's make sure we have them.
We have we should have input and button as well.
All right.
Now, the input from Burton, we all have.
We don't have the edit outline, so let's input that I can as well.
Let's have a look at this from.
So we got the form.
We need the unfinished functions on finis.
This is something we.
We can pass this function from this parent component.
So unfairness.
Um, so.
So that unfinished is already used on this form to create.
So we can give that a different name.
We can call that handle.
It lets us handle entities already used.
So let's call it update handle.
Loved it and update.
Okay.
So we passing handle update function as props.
So let's write that here and update.
So in this handle object function, what we can do is obviously we're going to make a request to back
in, send the updating category to update.
But for the moment, let me just use maybe alerts, make update requests, and let's leave it like this
for now.
We'll come back to it.
All right.
So we got that function as well.
So that handle update unfitness, we can use that function handle object so we can distribute the handle
update
and then we can use that here.
Handle update.
So we can use this format as well.
So an object is done.
We can receive the value we.
I do not need this one because this is Abbate.
So the updating category will always be there, so let's not do it on that one.
We don't need that.
Let's.
Let's have a look.
Saluting.
Saluting is something we can pass from the parent component as props.
I guess the learning will be true when we are creating a category.
So that time.
This actually is not necessary.
So we have the loading only doing the create so we could have one during update.
But unless we have that, we don't need that.
So let me actually remove.
The lowering from the bottom.
All right.
So you can see we have got the foam.
We have the summit button.
When I submit make object request to that function handle object executes.
So so far, so good.
Everything looks good.
Now, what we need to do is populate the value.
So whichever is clicked, this clicked category is in this state as an updating category.
So we need to pass that as props to this component.
All right.
And then we will be able to access that very nice update of did updating category.
Okay.
We need to pass that and this value we can access in the in this component.
And we need to.
And let's try this.
So I'm dating category.
Also, it's been passed as props.
We destruct that and then we can pre-populated the value of this phone.
Now, since we're using end designed for this one, you can use the initial values for it in this year.
Initial value.
Actually, instead of seeing initial value, we can also use fields.
So let me use fields and here.
In this object, we can have an array and in this area we can write the name that is near.
You can see we are trying to target this input with the form item and the name name.
Right.
So that is here.
Okay.
It also must be inside the object within this array.
All right.
You can see first we use object in object.
We have the array.
Now, you could target more than one fields here, but we have only one field in this category that
is called name.
So we leave it like that.
And then.
Value.
Right.
So value for that fund is going to be I'm dating category dot net.
All right.
So with this, let's give it a try.
Let's make sure when we click.
So if I click on Python, you see we have the updating category name that it's frightened.
If I click on ma'am, we see ma'am, she.
If you don't see the change for some reason, just reload once.
And it should look like a beautiful.
So we have been able to target the particular field by the name and said the value.
As you know, it would be done a little differently if we were using.
The rule of thumb.
Oh, if we were using our local state to control the fun of even the designs, forms and design inputs
we could control using the local state using React uses state hook and that is something we will explore
a bit later as well.
But at the moment we just using end is end forms to this.
This has its own way of doing things.
Very simply, you can see that's how we can populate the values and when the form is submitted, we
get the form values in this function.
All right, so handle object.
Let me quickly go here and update here in the parent component for handle object, we get the values
right.
So let me.
Remove that and take control.
Console.log.
Send it to back and for the.
Values.
Okay.
And then let me also console.log the updating category.
Just to give it a try.
I mean, inspect console.
Let me try.
Ma'am.
Ma'am?
List says that he'd submit and begin to send it back in.
So we have got the new name for this category and the updated category is this one.
So when you make a request to back in, what we can do is we can send this updating name and then we
can send this slug.
And that way we will be able to find this category in the back end and update the name.
All right.
So that's what we have already done in our back in earlier, which we can have a quick look again when
we make a request to using excuse.