All right, so we tried the request hand in mirror.
It works.
Now, the next thing we want to do is protect for the admin user only.
Right?
Now, before we do that, let's go to our controller and try to create that category.
Because we can always dilute the categories anyway.
Let's close everything.
It's too many fights over.
Close the client to go to the controls category.
So here, let me just remove both of them.
Now, we want to save the category.
Right.
So that import category, model import category from.
So one step up.
Go to models.
Edit You also want to have that category.
We can create a new category.
Second category equals to we use a IT category that create.
Now this is one way of doing it.
Also the other way going category.
It was to avoid new category so you can create a new instance of category and then to create a new category,
we need some data, right?
So that data we get in the request body.
So we get to name in the request body.
So request body name equals to whatever that is.
That name will be used to create a new category.
So you can see here.
Category model.
You can save the name and the slot.
So we have to generate the slogan as well based on the name.
Okay.
So we can access the name for instead of just doing it with this body.
We can.
These districts of the valley of seconds name include student request board.
This would make make it a bit more easier to use.
All right, because request body is not enough to create a new user because we need to add a slug as
well.
Right.
So you create a new category.
Now we won't name.
You didn't have to do this.
It's the naming of value.
17 is clearly like this.
So the new category would need a name and it would need to slow.
Now slow is going to be the name.
But we have to make it a lower case.
Actually, we did have to make a lower case because our schemes will do it.
By itself, thanks to this, probably wouldn't have to make a lower case, but we have to make sure
that any bright spots are remote.
All right.
So this is something we could do using some simple regular expression.
But there is a buried library that we can use from NPR.
So that one is called slug fight.
So we can use this one.
We just give the name of our category, and that was Lightfoot.
So if the name is something like this.
Node space.
This, if you give that, then it will address.
All right, so simple.
Let's use this.
Stop that insult.
This one started.
So, again, bring that slug.
Fight you.
And then we can use that here.
Stratify.
We give the category a name that will remove any white spaces, and when it is saved, obviously it
will be saved in all lowercase.
So that's pretty much all we need to do.
All right.
So we create a new category and we use dot save immediately there.
Otherwise, if you didn't do that, you could also use Category dot C, you could do this as well.
But if we can do it all inline, why not?
Right.
So let's do it all in line and then that's all we need to do.
The category has been saved.
If you want to have a look, you can do it once a lot.
Let's have a look.
And then you want to send the response as well.
Right.
So response dart Jason kind of give.
I guess this way the newly created category will be received here in our client as well.
And then when it is received, you can just put in the list and display immediately.
Not sure you can do that.
Now, when you do this, make sure not to use coronavirus like this.
If you do this in the reactor application, you will be able to access this using da da da da da da
da.
You have to go.
So you have to go.
One step down.
I don't use the card address.
Just send like this license.
Jason, thank you.
And then that will give us the excuse.
We'll be able to receive it as a response to data.
And obviously you can destruct the data from access use in the client said it to do this I guess so
send the response like this and let's give it a try.
All right.
So let's create our first category.
And once it is created, we should be able to take out in the database.
All right, so let's try to react.
Perfect category created successfully.
That's great.
Okay.
You see this controller?
We did.
Let me just confirm that.
So that controller gives us this newly created category.
So this is how it is saved in the database.
You can see we give the name, we generate this log based on the name.
So it is all lowercase, it is the slot.
And in anything that is saved in the database, we get this unique ID and because we use the timestamps,
we have the created, added and updated and it is beautiful.
This is something you can also take out in the database if you go here.
Collections, you may have to refresh this.
Again.
Now you can see we have the categories and we have the very first category.
We just create beautiful.
Okay.
So the category has been saved.
But like I was saying, we want to.
Allow the users to create the category only if the user is admin.
All right.
So let's go ahead and create one more middleware that will take if the user actually has the role of
an.