All right, so we got a short list of posts that belongs to this category.
So let's continue working on that one.
So we show the heading, the category name.
After that, we can map through the posts directly into the column.
Poster map to map to the post.
So is Bush.
We want to display card.
Card component from and and then since we're using each item we keep the unique key that would be pushed
front and scope and here in the card.
We can use a deep dive to dive.
Let's use Flex so that we can show the limits.
Let me see the finished product.
So we want to show the images on the left and then the title and meta information like this one, horizontal
using flex.
This is Flexbox.
All right.
So here div style.
Display fakes.
And then in this debriefing had two elements one would be immense.
Another one would be the post voice.
I guess so.
For images I can use avatar component.
Same circle.
You can use squid.
I have used.
I like to use circle in this one so you can give the size.
I'm going to use 60 style margin right with Martin so that it doesn't.
Get to close with the post title to content.
So margin write
margin dried would be 15.
We can use 15 in the source of the index.
That would be.
Post featured in this post.
Don't.
Featured image.
If we have that, then we want to access the Yahoo!
Otherwise we use some default images.
So, for example, the default image we can access from our local directory public images default.
Thank you, sir.
Otherwise, by default, we use slurs in this class, and people don't do things.
Tipping in that script.
So we have posts, man.
Something's not right.
I just caught that bit, man.
Play through the post.
I think we need one more parenthesis here.
Yes.
So let me push them back again.
Beautiful.
So we are showing the avatar.
If not so, the different images come back here.
You can see we have the images.
These don't have the feature dismissal.
We saw the default image.
Otherwise, they're beautiful.
Now let's display the content here.
The title and the meta information.
So this avatar let's use all ties to it would be helpful for search engines post statements we use that.
And after that in Ms. is still inside this live flex with the flex here we use another div.
And here we should title page two.
We can use has to.
And here we saw postcard tourism.
And then I guess we got the title.
Now let's display the the meta information that created did something like this saying to you something
like.
Now you might notice that it looks foreign, looks a little different if you want to make it like that
that is using the typography from and.
I guess if you can use that, you can use import typography.
And then you can.
Use, for example, title capture detail from the structure, from typography.
And you can use that type of typography gives you other things as well.
For heads to history, there are other things you can destructor, you can tell the documentation.
So let's try to use that.
Title of that.
That looks big.
Okay.
So to make it like his two and has three actually we can use the level the level three that to look
like his three.
Beautiful.
Okay.
And not just that.
I think we want to make it clearly realized, but we have to make it clear.
So that means.
Let me put it into a link and get tag based here to link heads through.
SLAs, post SLAs or slow.
Okay.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful.
That works.
So we can click on the categories, visit all the posts, click on them to view absolutely beautiful
isolates and display the better information as well here.
So that one we can put under the link.
And let me use paragraph dag.
And then here.
First, I'm going to serve the dead daisies.
Don't.
So daisies.
And then we use the give the dead posts dirt created and dead to give that and we won't ferment that
comment that in this.
Let's try a different this time.
Let's format by the month day and the year and then the our minute and PM on that extended date for
once a month, day, comma, year and then our minutes and then am PM.
So we want to use this format that gives us this beautiful time.
Next one lit.
So it's less lit.
So the post created by the name you just name whoever created it gets a post dot posted by dot name.
Let's make sure we have this to.
Post.
So post posted by.
Looks like we don't have that.
Probably because we haven't populated toilets.
Google.
This one is the single.
And this one is the post.
My career is less critical to our server controls category populate feature images and let's also.
Use
posted by.
All right, so let's give it a base.
Reload.
Beautiful.
All right, so we have the time.
We have the author name.
That's right.
Let's go back here and let's see here.
And it's right by the user name.
Beautiful.
All right.
Now, finally, let's also show the
categories and latest post from the hooks.
Now, that is something we have already done in our single post views.
Let's quickly go to this post slug and we can actually copy that code.
And so the divider.
Including the column.
I think it's it's better to just copy the column as you can make here.
So we have this column on the small screen.
We take full width, but on the large screen we take only the 18.
That means after this column, we can put this so 818 that remaining six.
Okay.
And for a small screen, this again, it can take full width 24.
Okay, so we have one offset.
So let's leave it trying to.
Now let's make sure we have the hooks imported too.
Let's go here.
Let's go and talk.
Just like we did earlier.
Let's import.
Oh, actually, we already did.
That means we just have to execute them just like this.
All right, let's give it a try.
Okay.
Some some reason it is down here.
Let's fix that.
I think we don't need the opposite one.
That's not really important.
Then we can just leave it to 24.
Beautiful.
Now we can see we are showing the categories and latest post here.
Awesome.