All right, so now we're going to work on the post edit.
I saw post edit we already worked on the delete so to edit basically we have to take the users to a
separate base where they can update the existing post.
So it's going to be similar to what we already had in our new post base here.
So we have the post input field of input field for the post titled Post Content.
Oh, the featured image categories.
All these fields, it's going to look exactly similar.
The only differences are based on the the post that we're going to edit.
We have to make a request to our server, can get that post and then populate the values here.
All right.
So pre-populated the categories.
So the existing images.
So the existing content and the title here.
Otherwise, the the farm and the base going to look exactly the same.
So let me quickly show you the finished one, how we did it.
So it's good to it's good to talk more.
Let's go to admin outposts.
I guess so.
Let's say we want to update this one, so let's clean.
Edit Ah, you notice this is the post titled So Graphical From Scratch.
It's all this text you will notice in the slope as soon as we land on the end.
It is you can see the post slug is there.
So when you click before you land in this land, in the space, you will be able to access this slug.
So you will use this slug to make requests to your backing to get this particular post.
All right.
If you can use use effect for that based on the slug, you will load this post from the back in and
then.
You will have the data of this post in the States.
So you can put that in the state, local, state, and then you will pre-populated the values here.
All right.
So the values are already there.
The content is there, the title is there.
Now, you will make some changes or whatever you want to do.
Thank you.
So when you do that, you will again hit object button and that will update the post.
So that's how it's going to work.
Okay, so we've got the concept now.
Let's go actually work on this.
So the first thing you want to do is you want to create a piece for edit, so that will be admin posts.
We can create a new file this time we will be accessing the slug.
So let's call it slug that is.
Okay.
So here we can write everything from scratch.
But to make things easier, let's grab this code from this new to create new displays, because everything
is going to be almost exactly same.
And then obviously we have to make some changes.
But as you can see, this is the layout.
So we have the input for title content categories, feature images, all these things.
We need an update as well.
So let's copy everything and go to the slogan based here.
Obviously we will make the changes here so we can start by the name.
So change the name to new post it sends to edit post.
Let's go on top.
First we start from the name, so change the name and actually if you go you might actually see the
the create the base that that will look like the Asian celebrities the title first create new post.
So let's go to the return section create new post.
Let's turn this to edit post and let's visit displays first.
So we've got our posts when you click on this.
Edit, Nothing happened, so we haven't probably done anything on fleek, so let's go ahead and fix
that first.
So that is in the admin post index, we got the edit and delete.
So we have the function edit handle edit.
But that doesn't do anything.
What are we going to do is we can just redirect the user, take the user to that place.
So we could use link component.
Oh, you can do a programmatically like this.
So let's first make sure we have properly done so.
Let's input the hook we use row from next row.
And then to start using that hook, we can just put it in a variable, let's called a row that equals
to use row row.
So we execute that and then using roto we can push the user to that base.
So let's use that and to edit around and dark force,
we want to use it to slice.
Richard.
But Dick's slippers had means less post.
Post.
With s scarce.
We need the.
Post slow.
All right, so that's all we need.
We need to make sure we return.
Let's give it a try.
O'KEEFE It's imperative.
I miss the neutron.
I guess if I click, you get that takes us to that place.
Beautiful.
We got the post slot and we have everything there and it post like.
So the first thing you want to do is access this post, right?
So grab this year and make a request to the back end so that you can give that post.
And once you get the response, pull in the state and then from the state you will be able to show the
values you.
And we already have the endpoint because we have already.
Let me just open in a new tab.
We only have used the endpoint to get the single point.
For the single most viewed effectively.
Actually, you can see we are making requests to that the back end with this slug to get this post so
we can make a request to the same endpoint.
Give this give the post and then pre populate you in these fears much less growth.
So that's fence posts.
We have that one.
So that's a different base.
Let's close this file.
So this is the one we were working on and this is the one we copied on the quarter.
Let's close that as well.
So we are in this log.
This is our delete also edit post with.
So let me use use effects.
So we're loading categories as well.
So that's good.
Simply titled and saved content.
So we were learning from the local stories.
But we don't actually need this now because we already get the post from our backends.
So let's remove these two functions.
And then let's remove them from here as well.
And then just to use industry.
Because we are no longer getting the saving into the local sewers and getting from the local storage.
So we just remove that.
Okay.
So first, let's load use the fake.
Let's you do the.
We want to load the post.
All right, so let's create a function called load posts.
We execute that and looks for that here.
Post load post equals to async.
So here we want to lower the posting of posts.
So.
Contact Donna.
You can see.
Oh, wait.
Excuse.
Don't gift.
We get to use big tech's SLAs.
Boost SLAs slow now slug we are getting from around the region.
That query did slow.
I guess a disrupter gives us the slug as well.
So that's another beauty of this one.
So rather query.
Just slow.
We give this log, I'll make a request to back in to get that post.
And once we get that post, every first comes a log before we try to put in the step sequential log.
That's right.
Got post for its.
Okay.
Let's make sure we have got the post before we do anything that's open.
Set includes a defense arrangement that.
Rudy, let me just give you the reference.
We may have to have a dependency because we have to make a request only when we access the slope before
we access the slope.
If we make a request, obviously that will fail.
Right.
So in the dependency, let's make sure we use.
Of the dependency here.
Relevant relevant query.
Slow.
All right, let's try it.
Now we going to post unit.
So in our case, we needed the dependency because when the component mounts, immediately, the request
is made.
So at that time, maybe we haven't got the slug yet.
So that might take a few milliseconds.
So we have to wait for that.
Okay.
So you can see here we have got the post, we have got the categories, content, visual images, everything
is there.
Beautiful.
Now, let's pre-populated those values put in the these forms.
Now, let's quickly have a look at these fonts.
Now you can see.
The phone was that so screwed to the written block?
So we get the input for a title.
Now you can see the values.
They're already using the stead value title for this one stead value content.
And for previews we have the loaded categories.
Instead of law that goes categories.
We want to alert the post categories.
So we need to make a bit of a change here.
So let's start from the title and content.
So let's have a look at the steps.
So you can see we have the title content categories.
Now this time these categories will be posts categories, the existing categories of the post, if there
is any.
So we will use this state for the post existing areas.
And then loaded categories, we will.
So the loaded, you know, whatever categories we have available in our back end, we will load all
that so that the user can pick, you know, from the existing one.
They might, might want to add more, read more, more, so they will be able to select more from the
available categories list.
And okay, so that looks good.
Let's come back to the load post for instance, are here instead of just console.log, let's populate
the state.
All right, so you
can hear what I'm going to do is.
Said.
So that would be the data set down to the total set content that would be downloaded content that featured
images.
That would be data.
Featured image linked to the state.
We don't have these featured images in the state.
That means we want to add that current.
So let's put that right here.
Concert
Featured images that featured Indians includes two youths, the state and the empty object.
Because this is going to be the object said featured image.
We've got that as well.
Next one, we will actually need the post I.D..
I mean, we can update the post by slowly as we look.
We can find the post based on the slogan object.
Later, when we actually supplement this phone using the handle summit function, which is your handle
probably instead of using Slack, I like to use it because it's really easy to find valid an object
because that is the function we can use with mongoose in a find by the end.
Update.
So for that reason, let's also add one more state in that one more value in the state for the ID post
I.D. I just said I.D. and let's call it said post time and that would be data underscore.
So that means we need to have this state as well.
Let's add that that's added on top.
Post said post, I need post I.D. It was in use state.
Awesome.
So we've got that.
We added this one.
We had this one.
All right.
So we populate all those fields.
So we also have to set the categories.
But that's a little bit tricky because we have to extract the name from the categories, because categories
is going to be the array of objects.
It has the ID name and slug, but we just need the name.
That's how the we'll be able to.
So in the end design this dropdown.
Okay, so actually let's see.
So we already have the title and content, so let's see if we table.
So we got the title, but we don't see the content.
All right.
So this is probably because when the component is loaded at that time, the content is not ready.
So loading state, if we use the learning state, then it would be true that when the post has been
received using the use effect here, when it has been received using this excuse that time, it may
have been few milliseconds.
So when that happens, we put the response in the state.
How about this component?
Some of these components they have is their own state.
So sometimes they don't actually read render.
Okay.
So let's let's see how we can fix this one.