All right.
So before we move on to the different sections of the different sections, it's going to be obviously
a signing and signup.
So we want the users to be able to register and log in.
Only then we will give them access to these dashboards.
Right.
So at the moment, we're just working on the layout.
So before we move on to the authentication section, log in and log out.
I want to do two more things here.
One.
One is so the active link.
Now for that, we have to create one or two pages so that we can see how this works.
So why don't we go ahead and create a base for creating a new post?
Let's create a base and begin to work on when we navigate between bases, how the active link works.
So that's one thing.
And then the next thing is I would really like to ah, to collapse this sidebar when we are in smaller
screen size.
All right.
When we are in a bigger screen size I want it to automatically expand like that.
And when it is a small screen size, maybe people are using in a web mobile that does not I want it
to automatically collapse.
So we're going to open those two things and then we're going to move on to the authentication six.
So let me create one page, at least one page here.
So that we can give it a try for active links.
All right so that's going to be into business admin to and should be able to add a new post.
All right.
So let's call it.
Admin posts.
But it should be a folder that made you move there.
That's fine.
So into admin folder, we had to create a new folder called Post and Insert Post.
Let's create a new products called New Jersey.
So here we're going to share the admin layout that is already.
Here.
That's index.
Let me just copy that.
Good post.
New and tasty.
Let's call it new post.
Copy.
This two.
All right, so we came one step down here.
So we need to go once to go to step or three step.
So one more step and then let me just.
Right here.
Create new post.
Let's leave it like that.
No, it's at this place.
You can see this place will be accessible, adds less admin less posts this new.
Hopefully that is the you are and we used in the admin navigation and double check admin posts new.
All right.
So that shouldn't be post.
That's a single post.
So let's fix that and then let's give it a try.
Now add new me if I click here.
You can see I landed on this component and it turns it see the previously we were here and now we add
new thank.
Now when I click on Add New.
I expect the link to be active.
All right.
It is active now.
If I reload the page.
It's not right.
So that is something I want to fix because we have many components.
Yes.
I want to give the users the admin, the ability to easily understand where they are currently.
All right.
So we want to highlight whichever link we should be there visiting.
I want to highlight it as an act and offer that.
Are we going to access this?
The route I took, that's the domain.
And then there's the road.
So we're going to access that and then we're going to compare that with.
The history.
Right.
So if the current path, the other path in the history, if you can see here, if the Met, then we're
going to said that as an active link.
Right.
So that means you're going to use some thesis to make it look like acting.
So that's the logic, right?
So we compared the history with the Parthenon.
All right.
So to get the bathroom, we're going to use the use effect.
To actually use effect.
Hook is something that runs immediately when the component mounts.
So in the React component, once it is rendered on the screen, that's when it would run automatically
when the component mounts.
All right.
So we're going to use that to use effect to.
So you faked.
We put that here too.
Let's stay.
So comment.
You used a fake?
No, this is a function, and it takes another function as an argument so we can use our friends in
here.
You.
So this is another function.
I guess it is.
So that's the first argument.
Do you defend takes a function as an argument.
That's a first.
And second argument is the defendant.
So here you can pass anything.
So if you want to run the court here, whenever this value changes the variable value, then you can
put that as a dependency array here.
So we're going to use that.
Now, one of the things you need to understand in next, this is the next.
This runs in both client mode and so more.
All right.
So you want to make sure that you are in the client set environment first and that one you can do using
process dot because there are two two properties you can access in next.
This one is persistent browser that will make sure you are in a browser environment.
So if we are in a persistent browser, you can do something here.
Now another one is process dirt.
So.
So you can take it are in a settlement by using processed do so.
So in our case we use browser supported browser.
If we are browser environment then.
And so any query right here will execute only if this value's true.
So if we're in a browser environment, we want to set the current value.
So we get the Parthenon from the URL and put in a state, and then we're going to compare that with
the header.
So that means we need a value in this data.
We can call that something called, let's say, current account, current length.
So current set current equals to use state.
Leave the default value to empty string.
All right, so if we are in a browser environment, I want to set current.
And I want to set here the value.
Of the path here and you can see you all saw the deadline is helping me type here so window dot location
don't but name so that way you'll be able to access the path name whatever is currently at the moment
you can access them I think curious you can also control love which I'm sure you just can't.
So don't log window to location.
Don't let me comment that out for now and let's have a look at the bottom there.
If that gives us the actual path name, let's have a look.
Let's go right click click on the inspect.
Student athlete that would be considered.
Yes.
Well, we got quite a lot of warning here.
Looks like we have been.
We have some duplicate keys in the menu.
We can fix them.
That's fine.
And we give her a face.
Okay.
So window is not defined.
So you can see we get that kind of issue because the next year it runs in both environments.
So in play.
So we can do that kind of thing.
All right.
So it looks like it's better to just try this inside here.
So the fact I want to do that and I want to.
Actually, I could do it here as well.
You can add posers, Donna Brazile And if only if that is true, then you try to control the window,
location, Parthenon.
No, no.
When you do that.
Let me give a quick refresh.
No.
You can see we got Parnham, that is less Edmunds, less post, less new, beautiful.
So that's the one we need now.
We get the current value to whichever means we are at the moment.
If we go to the decimal, you see decimal.
All these apps we interface that you can see recorded.
And so whichever page you are, you can see that.
So that value we put in the state.
So we put here.
And then we're going to compare that with the history to determine which one is the the actively.
Now, by the way, a different select case.
I don't want to use that.
Remember that.
Because we don't need that.
Since we are, we have this code that will detect on which we currently at the moment so we don't have
to sin differently.
So let me just remove that and continue him.
So if forces, Rosen said to the current, now you want to run this call when we are in the client environment,
right?
And then when we have the patterning available so we can pass that value, add the dependencies.
Well, here, of course, is dog browser.
So whenever we're in Brazilian better do you want to run this call?
So you pass it here as a dependent theory and window to location dog.
When that is available, then you want to run this code and that will put the current partner in the
state with that code.
Let's make sure we don't have an errors.
Okay, so that's looking good.
Let me quickly fix try to fix this and then we're going to.
Work on making them active.
Since we have the value already here, it's going to be straightforward.
Let me have a look.
So we have the same keys for the navigation menu.
From the ended answer.
Let me quickly take that, Edwin, there.
One, two.
I think we don't have any duplicate here.
Seven, five, six.
Seven, eight, nine, ten, 11, two.
Okay.
So we have.
So.
So we've got 12 to 12 and then 30.
40.
Okay.
So that's.
Bearer inland collapse not controlled.
Many under suits.
It collapsed on the side.
Man still.
All right.
So collapsed on the side.
But we're going to work on this one.
We're going to dynamically collapse when we are in the smaller screen as well.
That's next.
So that's right.
Let's do one that.