All right.
So at this point, you might want to give it a try so you can try creating a few users.
Let's create one user, the instructor, and one student later so we can see how everything works.
All right, so register.
I still have this placeholder, which is something you might want to remove.
Let me just register as one stripe seller.
Let me log in as the seller.
The instructor create some closest, and then we will try as a student, try to enroll into that and
see how it works.
So one stripe seller run stripe seller very stressed and successfully logging rights for a set of perfect.
All right.
So nothing here.
But he can become instructors.
Let's try that said about.
All right.
So I completed the onboarding process, and I have my reader back and I have my instructor dashboard.
I can go and create course.
Beautiful.
I have zero balance at the moment.
Create course and create has the middle course for beginners.
I'm just going to.
Oh yeah.
Just copy.
I have one course by the way you can take out some free course you in good dot com.
So let me copy some text from here.
And let me just add some information.
Pain free.
Let's make it free first.
Let's create a free class
category.
Has to improve upload images.
Let's just try this.
Let me just.
Let's just use some emails.
I guess I still have that in me if you want to remove that.
This is free fire and save and continue.
Okay.
So you have this course instructor instead of adding lessons
learned uploaded on video.
Let's go to desktop.
Let me just grab one video from here.
Let me open the inspector.
You might come across one issue here.
If the file is too big, you might get an error.
For that, you just have to add one line of code in your engine.
So let's see.
Sometimes you might get max max file size.
If you get if you get that kind of fare, you can always get a profit.
That's good.
Because I wanted to show that when.
Our request entered two lots.
So if you get this error.
You have to do two things.
One, you can set the file size in the affirmative in rounds, and then you can also do something in
your next in the next config file.