All right.
So we make the request to the end point.
So that means we have to no go ahead and create this new endpoint to update the user.
So let's go to server.
Or else let's quit the endpoint product or put make a poetry quiz to update the user.
And this should be the use should be logged into require assigning either admin.
We are not going to use on this one.
Um.
I think I think we need to create to control the foxes.
They should be quite similar, but one will have the tick if the user, whoever is being updated, that
user is logged in user.
Right.
So we need that tick and we need another one that is that would take if the user is added, if it is
admin, he would be able to update other users profile as well.
But if it is not admin then they can object themselves only.
So at the moment we are working for the admin, so let's continue using admin.
But later for other users we may duplicate the road user would come back to it.
So let's call it update user by admin.
Listen to this function.
Actually I think it's better to use different drugs or reduce it.
By Edmondson.
It's called.
Let's go to react and let's send this to the user by admin.
All right.
So we'll conditionally change this one.
So later when we use this.
We will try to reuse this component for both also and admin and other users.
So we'll just try to change the the endpoint by passing some kind of port.
All right.
So let's continue here.
Object user by admin to integrate this function.
So let's put that here.
Bring from the controllers of.
Export context update user async request response Troy.
Now before you try to object to use it.
So we have to apply some takes.
So we need to make sure that when they're trying to object, we have got the name, we have got the
email, but the password is there and if it is there, then we want to make sure it is up to six characters
long.
So things like that we have to take.
So first of all, let's it's this one we're going to use for the admins object to use of admin.
So first let's destructor the values from request barley.
So we are getting the ID then just don't say kill.
We are sending that IED.
Um, I think we have to send they did because we have to find the user from the database personality
and Shintaro doesn't have.
That type of approach to road programs we have to send the ideas to.
Let's quickly go back here.
Let's add one more field here.
Set.
I d so let's start from here.
I'd say that indeed it was to you the state.
Can a tree declare?
Okay, sir.
So we have the right to query I.D..
So let me remove this one.
And just to use directly here.
I guess, you know, you use it in the state and then when we get the response sent, added, da da
da da, underscore it.
Beautiful.
Now we can send this I.D. when we make this request I.D. and the rest of the world is male, we will
access that here.
So I.D..
Name.
Email.
Password.
Website.
Role and emails we can distribute from request boarding.
I guess so, yeah.
First, let's try to find the user from the database based on this I.D. so user ID can so each user
find by using that I.D..
We can call it.
Let's call it to use a form from DB.
Thank you.
So here we're going to take a couple of things.
For example, let's take two valid email.
Now, this is something I think vanity means there are different ways of making sure the email is a
valid email.
But we can we cannot be 100% that it is a valid email.
That is what library we can give you.
Try and PM email validate.
We can try using this one.
So you can see that's a valid image.
That's true.
True.
But if it is not in the full format, then it will be false.
So it's a it's a basic to edit it so we can use that.
Let's copy that.
And it's so.
I guess once that is installed, we can input that in our control.
Import a email.
Validator from.
Even validates.
Now, you know we can use this.
So check for the van and even we'll take.
If not email validated or validate email.
So you can see this email validity gives us this function called validate and did that function?
We give our email and it will.
If it is true, it's region two.
Otherwise it's only false.
If it is not true, then we want to send some kind of error message to return Response Edition.
We send error and that will be invalid email.
Next one we take for take email is taken because when they're trying to update the profile, they may
want to update the email that belongs to someone else.
So in that case, we have to stop that from happening and see if Emily is taken next one to ask for
length.
So if they're trying to object the password, we to make sure it is long enough and then we can go ahead
and start saving.
So if there's password, we have to has the password as well.
I guess to give the email is taken down existing ones to use a friend via email, try to find the user
by that email.
And if we find if exist exist and exist dot underscore already don't do.
String equals equals sequence user from db dot and industry.
So if the if we find the user.
Mm hmm.
By email.
We don't object.
However, there is one exception.
If this user is this user, then obviously we have to update.
Sort of what's happening here?
Not.
So I think if the image is taken now, this image would be taken.
For this currently logged news, obviously.
So if exist and exist, it is not allowed to currently logged inside.
Then only then we send this error.
Mrs..
Don't respond to this animalistic thinking.
And then for password.
If password and password length is smaller than six.
The reason we have this one is first we make sure that we have the password.
Sometimes we use a may not be sending the password.
Maybe they just updating of all the information.
That time we didn't have to worry about password.
Right?
So that time we don't have to object anything.
But if we have received the password only then we want to make sure it is long enough.
I can then return response, duration and password is required and should be six characters long so
we can send that error message.
I guess.
So if all this validation pass, then we can go ahead and save the user.
All right, so before we save the user, we want to has the password.
So if there is password, so const has it has the password equals to again, we take if we had the password
if we have, then it has password.
So we have that function.
So we use that and give the plain password.
Password.
It's otherwise undefined.
So.
We don't have to make any changes for the users password.
And so if you have the password, then we has that.
And then.
We're going to object to user.
Oh let's put that result in the variable of did it enhance to avoid user
fine by I d and do it so we we find out
find valid that is the idea.
And then why do you do an object is here.
So what do you an update is?
Name that would be.
First we have to take.
So whenever we want to object, we have to make sure that that value is there.
For example, user might not want to update certain fields.
Maybe they want to update only one or two fields.
So in that case, we always have to be careful here.
So if name before we find bad idea an update we take.
So if name is this in the request morning.
If we have requested word in name, use that.
Otherwise the user's existing name.
Which is.
I use it from DVDs to whatever is his name.
We just continue using that, he said.
Email.
Also we use request border email if it is there.
If not.
User from database email.
Existing next one is password.
If it is password, we use the has Verizon has the password.
Otherwise the existing password.
Um.
The wolf said.
We do the same thing.
The rules.
Emails.
Also.
We do the same thing.
Okay.
So that's how we update.
Now, when we update, we want to send this updated information as a response.
So we use new tool and then finally we can send this response.
Now, before we do that, let me just use dot populate and I want to populate the images.
Also, when we send this response, the response should contain the images and then response to this
and updated.
So we send.
All right, so this is how the admins should be able to update the user's profile.
Now we can go and give it a try.
And let's see.
Let's see how we get the object to use a response.
Let's come here.
Let's change this user.
We go to all users.
Firstly, we try to update myself, Ryan the admin.
We've signed.
Now a little bit.
We're not getting any response.
But let me have a look into the net.
What?
I guess it looks like it is successful.
You can see
200.
Okay.
We got the response.
Beautiful.
We got the image idea as well.
Console the images.
This should have been populated, but otherwise everything looks good.
So we have the updated response.
I think we have issued the images.
You can see we're getting the I.D. we supposedly in depopulated images.
And I think that's because we did one mistake here.
In our model, user model, we have the images, but we have specified these two fields from the Guardian
URL.
Instead, what we need to do is we need to refer this to the media model because all the images will
eventually be coming from the media, right?
So they will be saved in the database.
So let me go to media.
Post.
So this is how that should be.
So just like we used featured themes for the post, it's going to be similar.
So let's go to Model C user elements, try to update that one to image.
Give me just Scott based here.
Sorry.
Let me just got this part based here.
So this will be the type of object wherein it will refer to media model.
All right, so let's make this change and give it a try.
This time, it should work.
Let me pick one existing image and try that.
All right.
So we've got the response this time.
You can see the images has all this information, including the euro Beaufort.