Let's create another middleware to make sure we have the user with the role of and right so let's call
it is admin to export and is admin equals to async let's make it async.
Folsom requests the response and since we're creating a middle way, we need the next call back from
scenario to ship.
And we try.
And if we get in here, we come to love.
So here when we try.
We want to make sure we have the admin user.
Now for this one.
First, let's go to the category drought.
I wrote categories.
So you can see here before we are the easy to create.
First we have to take for the logged in user and the the importance of this one is because this will
give us the you decide in the request to use.
Right.
So that's really important because based on that idea, we're going to find that user from the database
and then take if that to you this role is admin or not.
All right.
So later, we're going to apply the is admin middle way.
First, we need to have this one.
This is important.
Okay.
This will make sure we have the logged in user and we give the user ID.
So this has dollars come first and then we will use this middleware to check if that user is admin and
then if it is true, only then he will be able to create.
So let's remove this from now.
It's good to millrose.
And here we try to find the user based on the Andy since we have this metal world that will give us
the request to use it right to request user and the ID that was extracted from the token, which I showed
you in the previous lecture.
All right, so let's try to find the user content.
User equals to await.
Now, for this to work, we need to make sure we have the user model for its input that
input user from.
Models.
User.
And then this middleware gives us the request user and the we can access the I.D. from the token.
So that means, yeah, when we try to find the user from the database or we use a modern user defined
by a function.
Now there are quite a lot of useful functions like this we can use with mongoose model, which you will
see throughout the course.
I guess.
So I will be showing you one by one.
So this one is quite a popular one, finding the vicinity.
So we use the user model and use this function, find variety and this function requires the user side
and that one we can access from requester to user dot underscore.
Right.
I guess now for this to work, you always need to make sure you have applied this middle well first
and only then you apply.
That is admin nil.
And I guess it is really important.
This has to always come first, otherwise you cannot access this value.
All right.
So this will give us the user if you want to log in control loggerhead.
So always console.log until you fully understand what's happening and you can even have a look at the
code.
You know something?
And if something's not right, then the others want to make sure you've gone too long and things are
going as expected.
All right, so we find the user and then let me remove this for now if we need to do some console.log
also.
So here I want to take for the users groups.
All right.
So if a user does role, it's not equal to I guess, and not equals to admin, because we know by default
all the users role will be subscriber.
So if the users role is not, admin always tried to take for the error first.
Okay.
So that's one principle in Node.js you always want to take for the errors first.
So it is also called error driven development.
Not that we trying to create errors, but we want to resolve the errors before we do anything else,
just so that our server don't cross.
All right.
So if users role is not admin, then we want to send some kind of error response, right?
So response
return the response to the status of 403.
By the way, let me quickly show you what these discord means, for example, has to be four or three.
And so it is forbidden error.
So it is protected for the authorized user only if the user is not authorized.
We send this escort to this call.
The browsers understand and they that's why this is the standard.
So sometimes if the business is not found, you see four for error.
If it is unauthorized for three error of the normal errors, you get 400 errors.
You know it's like that.
So we send the rest funds for industry and we send the decent response as well.
Now instead of this in response, because since we're not actually going to display this Mrs. in the
reactive instead of that.
We can just use the sand as well.
So if you do this, then it won't be accessed as a decent error message.
But it is just going to appear in the.
The network depth so that he can have a look.
And so we will try the Jason era as we lead.
But for this middle way, we just need to send some plain error messages so that unauthorized.
The unauthorized, just so that if there's some issues we can debug by looking at the network to see
if user is not admin, we send the unauthorised error else.
It was, we can give you the access.
So all we need to do is execute this callback function.
So.
The code and execute.
That means then the create control function can run, right?
So if there's error, so it will.
Stop here and then the code in the controller will not even execute it.
It will not reach there.
It stops immediately.
In the returning the response.
But if everything is good, then obviously it will continue.
So this is how we can create the admin middleware.
Now we can give this a try.
So let's import this one.
Request sign in and then is admin middleware.
And then we can try applying here.
After this require assigning metal work.
Now we know that our users, they all subscribe.
There is no user that is admin.
No user has the role of admin.
So this time we may see the error message.
Let's give it a try.
All right, so if I try creating this term, let's try creating five.
Submit.
You can see we immediately get the error.
Let's see what is the error?
Follow through and forward an error because that's what we send.
And because we send this unauthorized message that should be accessible here.
Previously, you can see we got unauthorized.
I didn't send the decent response because this is, as you can see, it's a middle way.
So obviously we don't have to throw a nice message to the users because if someone is trying to do something
fishy like this one, then obviously we don't have to be very nice.
We just need to figure out what's going on so we can just send it like this.
Okay, so that's good.
It is now protected only for the user that has the role of admin, otherwise you cannot create it.
So that is awesome.
Our server is protected.
Now to give it a try, let's make our user admin.
So this user, the currently logged in user that is, I think run.
At G.M. Dotcom.
I think that's the one.
So let's make that user admin and see if he can prove to you the categories which he should.
So that's the very first use.
And we created many other users with these.
Fake email addresses.
So this is the one I'm currently logged in at.
So let me add this one.
Let me turn this to Ed.
All right.
I think something.
Something over there.
Later we will also be updates.
Just click on the update mode segment to later.
Obviously one admin will be able to either create either you just send the admin, you will be able
to give different roles.
For example, alter or even make another user admin.
I will show you how you can do all that from the dashboard, but for the very first time you want to
make one user admin which you can do something like this and this is something you can run the MongoDB
query ROC queries in the.
In the console as well.
So when we deploy our application in the cloud later, the very first user, we can update his role
by accessing the terminal like this as well.
So no problem there.
All right.
So it has been admin.
So let's try.
Let's sign out and sign in and.
This user is not admin.
Okay.
You can see they're only there.
So let's go here.
By the way, the front end is still not protected.
Our back end is protected for the admin only.
So let's go to categories.
Create.
No, it says category and it is created not because this uses admin.
All right, so our back end is protected.
Our road is protected.
But our fountain is not protected.
I guess a few any other user will have access to this one, even though they cannot create, they cannot
save in the database.
It's not good to show our fountain to anyone.
Obviously, we want to protect it.
Right.
So let's try the different user.
I guess this uses a subscriber, but he can still access this dashboard.
He can still access this category, create ways.
This is something we have to fix, and we will do it in the coming lectures.
All right.
So this user cannot create.
Awesome.