So we noticed that we have the title, but we don't have the content to fix this one.
We can use the loading state, so by default we can keep the loading stated to two saluting the value
instead of false.
Let's make it true.
I guess if by default it's true.
That means we're still loading the post.
We don't have the post yet.
But when we got the post, we changed this to false.
And when it is false, that means alerting is done.
Now we can show the content because we have already received the total content, everything we need.
So with with that issue, we will be able to serve the content in absolute post.
So by default, what we're going to do is said, Oh, actually we don't have to do that by default.
Loading is true in our state, unlike false, which we have been using a lot of the time.
This time we said it.
Okay, so.
Once we received the data, we said that the force said loading.
We said that to false.
So as you can see, by default, the loading will be true.
Until we receive the data.
When we receive the data, then it will be false.
Based on that conditional, we can do the rendering of this content in this edit.
So here.
Let me put that into entire div in the conditional.
All right.
So let me cut.
And you.
They've got.
You know, if if we have the loading state using the 2D stoner operator, if we if we are in the loading
state, then we can do something.
Otherwise we can show that.
So that's that's a proof based what we got.
I guess if we are in the loading state, then we should be loading text.
Otherwise we should the entity with the content.
Okay.
So the loading actually.
Yeah.
We can do like that.
We have the different value content now.
I think he was quick.
Reload.
Okay.
Now you can see for a brief few milliseconds we saw loading, but then when the loading became false,
then we got the content.
And then only then we render this at the editor.
So that works now.
Let's try one more time.
Listen.
Let's see.
We want to edit this one.
You can see networks.
Beautiful.
I also got the title.
We got the content, the categories.
Now you can see these are the loaded categories.
These are not specific to this post.
These categories are the list of categories that we have in our database.
Now, instead that what we want is we want to fill these post categories and we have to show them,
as people put it, pre-selected here.
Actually.
What we need to do is we have to continue pursuing these options, but we have to show the existing
categories of this forced, if there is any.
We have to see Olympia as preselected because just like.
Just like this one.
Me?
This is the finished project, madam.
It's.
Come here.
Let's find a post that has some categories.
And this one might have to.
I've said this one doesn't have.
Okay.
So none of them have to let me actually go and edit this quickly so that I can see.
Let's edit this graphic you.
It doesn't have react?
No.
So let's say this post has these two categories.
Let's update.
I'll get done.
Now, if I go to edit this one, you can see these categories are preselected.
Beautiful, right?
So these are preselected.
That means when you're upgrading, you know which category is already there.
If you want a chance, obviously, you know, you can now choose more.
And the selected ones are already there.
You know, they they are identical.
You can see these are already selected.
So you can click to on select, select or you can get beautiful.
So that's what you want to do.
So for that, first of all, it's good.
It's load first.
What do you want to do here?
We want to
map through the categories because if you remember, let me just continue on the post categories that
is object that just not the category name.
They have the slug.
They have the idea as well.
So.
So here you can see categories.
We basically need just a name for this and is and component.
However what we get is this the entire object.
Now it has the name ID and slot.
Now what we need to do is we need to map through the categories every and just extract the name so that
we can show them here along with the other options.
Right.
So.
What we can do here is we can do before and create a loop to get all the names in common, plus category
names.
So let's create a variable called array equals to the value.
Add the empty object, also empty array.
And we're going to map through the categories data dot categories, dark map.
So we move through the category and each category we get, we want to push to this area so we can use
a red dot whose.
See me.
Because all you want is puts the name into the story.
I So with that we get all the categories names in this area.
Now we can use that value to populate the categories states or set categories.
Or we.
Okay.
So.
That.
Let's come here.
And did.
Okay.
So when we created this post properly, we didn't have any categories, so we don't see any of them.
So let's.
Let's go ahead and create a new one.
Screwed a new one.
And it's what?
Content.
Let's pick one featured image.
Let's pick one of the existing one.
Let's be.
This.
Thank you to my competitors running really slow the processor struggling because I'm recording at the
same time.
Okay.
So we've got twos that feature image categories.
Let's choose to react and note and publish.
I guess it has been published.
You can see it's there.
Let me try.
Edit.
When I come to edit, I don't see them pre-populated here.
So that's fine.
But at least we know that this post now has two categories, so let's see why it's populating here.
That's probably because if you come down.
So we've got a select.
So on terms we had but two so the the default the existing one so we can use another box called value.
So the value.
So the VAT is going to be the array of categories, right?
So that you can spread out the risk to the arrays.
The categories are the array and they have the.
Just in name.
That's what we need.
So if we didn't.
Didn't do that.
Look, are you just to give the name?
Then you'd be just looking at the objects.
I guess that's why we had to just extract the name, push, push in the array and use that to upgrade
the state.
So as a result, we should be able to see the category names here with this value.
Why do we set the value to the select with the array of names?
Beautiful.
Now you can see we have them there.
And then since the loaded categories and this these selected categories, they share the exact same
name.
You can see the list there selected here.
Now you can add more.
You can delete more.
Beautiful.
All right.
So we've got the name.
We get the content.
We can choose the featured image.
We can upload a new one, or we can choose the existing one.
It doesn't really matter this component.
He's sitting there and it works whenever you.
I use on anywhere else.
Right.
So it has the context whenever you select the selected images will be available in the context.
So when you update the post, you just have to grab it from the state and say all together so that you
have the updated images.
All right.
So let's say we did this one.
So this one.
And finally we can publish.
Now, at the moment it will not work because we have to create the endpoint in the backend to handle
the post update.
And here also we may need to make some changes here.
So obviously we have to change this.
So let's, let's do it send this to edit post and we want to send the post slow post.
I have already saved the idea in the state, so let's send that.
So that would be post I'd.
So good.
The title content featured images.
The film is actually what we need to do here is first we have to take if this post.
Well, actually, first we have to check if the media in the state, if we pick a images from the library
like that.
So when we have that, whether we upload a new one or pick from the library.
So whatever that is, so we can show that which we are already doing here.
So if the media selected it.
So if we have that, then obviously we want to send that to the back end so that we can serve as a featured
image.
So in that case, we do.
Media
selected this Friday.
Otherwise.
We may actually have the featured image of this post already, I guess.
Already?
Not always.
You want to update a him as if the image was already there.
And you okay with that then obviously you can continue using that.
So that means and the the post might have the existing featured image which is you can see here when
you load the post said featured image.
We have this state here local state and we put the value here.
So featured image we can access from the state.
So if it is there, then we can use that.
You know, if it is selected then we grab that.
If not, we may already have in the state, then we can grab that featured images.
Otherwise it's going to be a nested ternary.
I guess that's the the first expression.
If that is true, we use that.
Otherwise, again, we take for future limits.
So if we have the featured image, let's take four on the slide.
So if we have the featured image I.D., then again, we're going to continue using that.
Right?
So featured image, don't underscore it.
Now, if it is not there, which means you can see nothing was selected and it didn't have the existing
featured images as well.
So in that case, this post doesn't have the implicit image.
So in that case we can just send undefined.
So when you send undefined, the nothing will be saved in the database.
So it looks like we have some syntax error.
So that's the funnest first time.
If it is true, we use that.
Otherwise we use that.
Otherwise.
Again, it's a nifty toner.
So we use question mark here.
If that is true, we used that otherwise.
Finally, if nothing is undefined, I guess it's a big finish to time to get the featured images.
We're going to send it to the back end.
Now there's one more thing we have to do here before we actually worry about this request, and that
is suing the featured image.
So at the moment we are suing it only if they pick one.
What if this post already had the featured image?
All right.
So we had to work on that.
So we know when we created the created this post just before we build the image.
So we are sure we have this post as the featured image.
So let's see how we can show that featured image here.
If I reload now, you don't see that.
So let's see how we can show the existing featured images.
And then finally we're going to give it a try.