All right, so let's.
So the featured image preview here.
So if the image has been uploaded and there is a selected one, it will always be there when the image
has been uploaded.
All right.
So using this model.
So at that time, we want to show the preview.
So let's do that and close this so that in the ad menu.
So right here, we can show that maybe underneath the categories just before the publish button.
So all the way down.
All the way down here.
So we're going to publish button.
Let's put it on top.
So here we can use the the images component from and so landfill 153.
Let me just want to.
So we don't have them.
It's important.
Must go to 953.
Let's come back.
I think it's a yeah, we can think we have the access to media contacts so we can take media and if
we have selected property in the media, so by default it would be empty.
But if the user have uploaded, then they will be selected.
So if we have this image, that means we want to show that as a preview, right?
So yeah, if we have that.
What do you want to do is you want to use the image component said the with 200 person so it takes the
available within the sidebar and source for the screen to be media
selected or to you are right.
I guess from the response you get from the database that will contain the URL.
So we want to use that.
So that's all we need.
Let's have a look.
Beautiful to now you can see here we have the preview images as well.
Awesome.
And let's add beautiful margin and talk.
The Taliban break.
I considered this trial.
Okay.
So one doesn't want to do.
That's it looks a little bit more jeopardy if you don't like that.
What he can do is just create a div.
And let's let me just put it inside fragments.
And it that's.
I can use a dip into a fragment.
Let's it and.
Here's some.
Murdoch.
My top 15.
Thank you.
Beautiful.
Okay.
So we have been able to show the selected one as well.
Now let's close the model.
All right.
So when we have the images, we have uploaded the images with it's singular multiple.
We want to automatically close this model.
All right.
And then let's also remove this one.
So it's foundation string.
If I were to have that.
That is.
Oh.
Key that says.
Find the return.
I guess that's assuming that.
So when the open road is done, we want to close the model.
So that means we have to treat the the value instead of using our own from the state which we created
earlier only visible media.
Let's don't use that.
Instead, we can use what we have in the media context.
We have media.
We have.
Context.
We have this social media model by different folks, so let's use that.
So instead of that, we go down all the way to that model.
We have the model for featured images on click set visible media truly things that do.
Said Media.
Media, straight out the media.
So whatever we have or have images selected, whatever it is, they leave it like that.
We just spread out.
We just want to toggle the property.
So media model, we make that to click to I guess on click to be true.
And when the upload is done here in the upward file, you can see it becomes false.
All right, let's try.
Yes, of course.
Wherever or wherever we're using the previous value, we have to change that as well.
So to model.
That one will be no media tart.
So the media model.
All right, let's try.
Beautiful.
You can see it has been uploaded.
It has been said as featured images and that is closed.
Amazing.
Let's try and monitor the long route.
Now do the multiple of or maybe you don't want to close because.
Normally you wouldn't do one day, but I'm not from here.
You would just do one.
But for whatever reason, if you do, that's fine.
It'll stay in the library anyways.
So when you do multiple, then what we can do is we can actually show the, the, the actual images
from the library including this recently uploaded once and then we can ask the user to click on those
images.
So when they click on the images, that will be the selected one.
So we can, we can of them there.
That's fine.
But so far so good.
It's been working fine and on click.
Yeah.
And closer to that it's in this it's fixed.
That said visual model now into that that would be we have to change that.
Said Media.
Media.
So sorry.
Send me some model fonts.
I guess you just copy that.
Put it down here, doc.
Beautiful.