Okay.
So if there is media that has been selected so we can show the previous, that is something we can do.
Good.
So let's work on that.
Let's try to show the preview.
So we're going to use the Avatar component from and let's make sure we have that.
It's come down.
So we have this written block.
We have media.
Let's put it underneath the media.
Probably we should have a line break and here we can to show the users immense.
So here first we took.
Actually, instead of using brake, let's just use a dip and do some use some scissors cluster.
All right, so div class name or even class news guys, start, start margin bottom.
Let's use 20.
And then text a line center here.
We check if we have the media in the context of media
selectors.
If we have the select media, then we want to show
the selected media.
Otherwise we want to show the other media for the images.
So here, what are we can do here?
If we have the selected media, we can use the to use fragment.
And here we show the avatar.
And we give the source the source of the image that's going to be media or selected, don't you?
And then we can give the size to this avatar and let's gives the size.
Of 100.
I say if we have the media, we use that
we want to have a bit of a lambrechts in the media, use MTV, not Glenn Beck.
So it's a bit of a space.
So let me use the empty div with some style, style margin bottom.
I'm going to use just 50.
I guess if we have the selected media, we display that.
Otherwise, if you don't have the media, then we have to check if we have the image.
So if you don't have the media in the context, but if the user didn't select from the library or didn't
approve the new one, then this user may already have the images.
So if that is true, then we have to take those rules.
Now we can take the images in the state.
So if images this is a nested ternary, we do something that otherwise we just don't see anything.
So if we have the images, then again, let me just copy then paste you.
That immense hero we saw.
Otherwise, we don't see.
All right.
So this bit of good will.
So the preview is come here.
You can see we have the images.
Now, if I pick another one.
If I pick this one.
I guess that has been selected.
Now, once that is selected, this stays here.
So you would have to just go to toggle the tap.
Now, if you don't want to do that, you can pass some kind of a prop that will toggle.
All right.
I think what we can do here is when you select the media library, it just comes up and that blocks
the view.
Let's move these images on top of this one so that then it makes sense when they select their kids,
then they can see the preview in real time and then they can just continue in the form.
So let's just change the order.
By the way, I was trying this props.
Let's not use that scooter only.
I was trying to pass the process, insert doing that.
Let's just reorder some media.
We put underneath this preview images.
Maybe so that makes sense because now when they select the media, they can see the black preview in
real time and they can discontinue don't oh, they can just toggle and just go gone with the phone.
All right.
So we got the update.
Let me open.
Let's make sure everything work.
So for example, try updating without income with only a race or password.
So we are getting this error message, but we're not showing that.
So let's see how we can do that as well.
Back here,
let's just handed the errors here so they are misses.
So if.
If Dona error.
So if you got the time to do it and then to stare into the error so the misses otherwise.
Otherwise what we can do here is we have to update the user right to use our builder successfully.
So when it happens we also need to make sure we ordered the user in the context and we also ordered
the user end of stories.
So let me just note we have the other context we have like.
So in that case, what we can do here is we can.
I'm doing the context.
St Paul's spelled out the rest of the venues and we went on to submit to the user.
We did have to object the token to leave it like that.
Just the user with the data that's already we got.
So that's how we opted.
The context and local stories also is there, said Adam.
Before we actually do that.
First let's get because again, in the local stories, we have to only update the user.
We didn't have time to talk.
So let's grab the van from local stories and put in a variable first to lift from the local stories
it can.
So we have to pass the value to Jason because the local stories to ticket item by then keep us.
So we grab that that is in the decent format so we use decent bars so that that is ready to use here
then.
So we get the object here using decent bars.
So we want to update the user.
So look at this variable, that value dot user.
So it has a user token, right?
So we just want to object the user.
So don't use a construct data.
And then finally.
In Syria.
Back to the level stories set out on us listeners far from large stories.
When you serve it back, the data for the user has been changed.
Okay.
And then we to the toast notification and that is it.
All right.
All right, let's try and just put it on actually better.
Let's try with the three on this short password, we give that notification.
If I give long enough, that works beautifully.
Um.
What else we can take.
So if we don't turn the vanity mirror format, inverted image to that works.
In real world.
Most likely you may not want to share this email as editable, free, maybe just make it disabled or
don't use the input as well.
Because when they.
If the.
I'll do the email then.
Yeah, there might be some consequences.
Just think about that, because most of the sites you visit to, you know, they don't allow you to
update the email.
But it's technically okay, but it's up to you.
So I can change the rule, but I don't want to make myself authors.
Let's leave it like that.
So it looks good.
Let me just give it a refresh and make sure the dialogue is there.
And you use it.
And new mobile just ended.
Submit your back to all users.
Reload.
You see, it has, you know.
Beautiful.