Disclaimer for example Picciola Ltd ABN 29 6 0 9 8 5 5 4 1 4 is a corporate authorized representative.
Our numbers are 0 1 2 3 8 9 5 1 of HL K. Group B 2 Ltd AC and once X want to three four five hundred
which holds and the Australian Financial Services license a EFIS cell number 4 3 5 7 4 6 any information
or advice contained in this course is general in nature only and does not constitute personal or investment
advice.
We will not accept liability for any loss or damage including without limitation to any loss of profit
which may arise directly or indirectly from the use of or reliance on such information.
You should seek financial advice prior to acquiring a financial product or securities and financial
products or instruments.
Transactions involve risks.
Please remember that past performance results are not necessarily indicative of future results.