Hello this is Carol from Foxborough dot com.
And this is the 11th tutorial in our series of kill for tutorials for beginners and today we're going
to talk about the switch operator just before we move on I wanted to say that today's topic is not really
essential for you to progress further down further in the course and feel free to skip today's tutorial
and move on to more on number 12.
You can always come back and listen about the switch OPERATOR When you feel that you need to use it
in your code.
All right so moving on as you can see here I've prepared a little bit of code already.
And here we're introducing a new variable called today which is an integer variable and we're assigning
it a value.
Now I know that we have not talked about functions yet.
And that's definitely a topic that will visit further down the track in this course.
But we're going to need to use one today and I'll just give a quick overview of what this specific function
does.
So this function is called day of week and this is how we call it or execute it.
We type in its name and then just a pair of normal brackets afterwards.
And so what it will do is it will look at the chart and will tell us what day of the week it is today.
And then for every day of the week it will return a value and integer value which will then be which
will then or will be substituted here and it will be assigned to the today variable and the values that
this function can return are as follows.
0 means Sunday 1 means Monday to means Tuesday 3 is Wednesday for Friday 5 is Saturday.
US Thursday 5 6 is Saturday.
So now what we want to do with this today variable we want to branch out our code and execute certain
certain different operations on different days of the week.
So let's imagine for for example that we have a trading strategy that tells us that we can only buy
on Mondays by a certain currency pair on Mondays and then we can only sell that currency pair on Tuesdays
and on any other day of the week we should not perform any actions at all.
So that's what we're going to try to do.
We're going to try to split our code to do different things on different days of the week.
So for that we'll use a switch operator.
And the way to use a switch is typing this keyword which is followed by normal brackets and within these
brackets you need to put the expression or variable that you are evaluating.
And then in the switches followed by curly brackets within which you need to put several case statements.
So the switch operator has a very unique
structure and it looks as follows.
So case one colon and then alert.
This is the operation we want to reform and break.
So here we want to say today is Monday
and then what you say is by on Monday.
So basically what the switch does is it compares this value that you have or this variable that you
have in the normal brackets.
That compares to each of the cases that you have in the body of the switch.
And in case in the condition that this variable equals or this value equals to this value so if today
equals to 1 then this block of code will be executed.
Otherwise the next case will be checked.
Case 2 we wanted to say Alert.
Today is Tuesday and on Tuesdays our strategy tells us to sell then we put a break.
So basically if today is one then we'll see this message.
And then the switch will stop working because all finalize its work because the break operator will
tell it to stop.
Otherwise if today is a two then we'll see this message and which will tell us to sell.
And then the break operator will tell the switch stop again.
And in the final case of any other day we need to use the default operator or the default keyword and
we want to say other day to not
create orders them for a
so let's compile that and have a quick look at what we've seen.
A trader for Scripps tutorial Lemmon run.
And there we can see today is Monday by and that is correct because today is Monday.
And so what happened is that today was assign a value of one by this function then this value was checked
by switch and it turned out to be equal to this value which is 1 and therefore we saw this message.
So this block of code was executed.
And so this message is Monday by and then break stop the switch and the script finished at its exit
its execution.
So one so that basically switch allows you to branch out your code similarly to how if LCF and statements
did.
There are two main disadvantages of switch.
And the first one is that you cannot use any dummy variables of the type double here for example.
So you can only use integer variables or logical expressions and that kind of limits you from doing
things like we did last time with the prices because prices are actually doubles and also switch and
them call for is implemented a bit differently to other programming languages and meaning that you have
to have this break at every k at the end of every case statement because if you don't have this break
what'll happen is the switch will continue moving on through your blocks of code.
So for example if I comment that out and I compile that what you will see is that it says Today is Monday
and then says today's Choose the which is obviously not correct.
This is useful in some circumstances but most of the time you do need to put this break so that every
case is separate does not get executed with the cases above it.
So that's basically it.
You might find a switch a useful operator especially if you're working with integers such as day of
week.
And hopefully that will help you branch out your code even more.
And that's all for today.
Hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you on the next one more editorials and
information or parable on phonics but com come until next time.
Decoding.