Hello this is Carol from for example dot com.
And welcome to the 14th tutorial in our series of tutorials on algorithmic trading for complete beginners
and the previous tutorial we discussed basic algorithmic trading system design.
And we had a look at a couple of approaches to constructing your automated trading systems.
In this tutorial we're going to understand how we can incorporate trader input into our algorithmic
trading systems.
By that I mean how we can structure our trading approach training programs in such a way that the trader
can actually input certain parameters into them and adapt them to the market conditions in which he
wants to utilize these programs.
What are we going to do is we're going to take this trading strategy that we discussed in the previous
Tauriel and we're going to start a script in which we will allow the trader to put these two parameters
the 10 pips take profit and the 10 pips Stop-Loss and then in the future Charles will build upon this
script and actually add trading functionality to it and turn it into a proper algorithmic trading system.
But for now we'll just focus on the trader input because it is a crucial part of the strategy.
So I'm just going to switch to marriage here and as usual we're going to create a new script using the
kill for Wizard.
I'm going to give it a name
called Tauriel 14.
And so as we usually do we will we're going to code the body of the script and here in the on start
function.
However we first need to add a property to the script which will allow the script to show the inputs
when it is launched and I will explain this when we start testing it.
But for now it was just to add a line here which is property scriptural input.
All right.
So here we know that we are going to be using Ask price the bid price and then to calculate the stop
loss and take profit.
We're going to need these external parameters of 10 pips to actually get these values.
So it will start creating
an internal parameter which we'll call double take profit level and another one which we will call double
stop loss level.
And these two variables are going to represent this blue line this red line.
So now we know from previous lessons that the ask price.
So we will need the bit price the bid prices kept and be bearable.
So we are going to use that we're going to use that to calculate out take profit take profit level equals
to bid plus 10 multiplied by point and point is a variable which is stores number of decimals.
On this given financial instruments or in our case point is 0.00 1.
So 4 digits after the decimal point as we can see here 1 2 3 4.
So that will give us a take profit and hopefully we'll put it over there.
And the Stop-Loss
is you can see em kill for is already prompting us for the existing variable stop loss level.
Stop-Loss will be bid more.
So we did minus 10 multiplied by point
and we can compile that no errors or warnings.
And of course we have to add an alert statement which will actually tell us these values profit level
equals and we'll do another one for the Stop-Loss level
just that we can check that the values are correct.
We'll compile that nor's or warnings or go back to the trading terminal.
We will find our script sort of 14.
Drag it to the chart.
And as you can see here this this is different to what we use.
What we would expect.
We have this window which is the parameter window for the script usually the scripts start working right
away as you can remember.
But in this particular case because because we did add that line at the top show script show inputs
it's first showing us this window which will learn to use in a minute and I'll just click OK.
And as you can see here take profit level is 1.3 6 1 6 as expected and Stop-Loss level is one point
3 5 9 6 x expected.
So the script is taking the bid price.
It's adding 10 points to get the take profit and it's subtracting 10 points to get the stop loss going.
We're going to click OK here and now we'll go back to the script.
And now what we want to do is we want to change this 10 to a user user defined variable and to do that
we need to introduce this variable so we'll call it Xorn.
And because it's an integer variable and we'll call it take profit.
Get a value of 10 and extend it.
Stop loss on the value of 10 as well.
Compile that.
Oh that's right.
This is has to go outside of the stock function.
All external variables have to go outside the main function and they just sit up here.
So it's simple act quickly no errors or warnings and will just take take profit and put it four instead
of 10 for the take profit level and stop loss and put a stop loss.
Compile that.
And if we go back to the terminal the results should be identical to what we just saw.
OK.
And 1 3 6 1 6 same thing 1 3 5 9 6.
So I was just luncher again and here you can see a new tablet here which is called inputs.
And here we have take profit and stop loss and we can actually now change them right here in this window
without having to go into the code.
So say for example if I want to change my take profit to 20 I will just put 20 here and if I want to
change my stop loss to say 15 pips for example put 15 then I'll just click OK.
Now when the script launches you can see that the take profit level is now 3 6 2 6.
So it's not 10 Pip's it's 20 pips away and the Stop-Loss level is 1 3 5 9 1.
So it's not 10 Pip's it's actually 15 peep's away.
And in that way you can you now have control over your program.
Let's try this again for example.
So if I want take profit of 100 pips and I want to conservative stop loss of 25 pips click OK.
And what we can see here the Stop-Loss level is take profit there was 1 3 7 06 So it's a hundred pips
higher than the bid price and the stop loss level was 1 3 5 8 1.
So it's 25 Pip's below and that is exactly what we're looking for.
So this these externe parameters allow us to give the user the trader control of the program so therefore
he doesn't actually need to know how to code to be able to adapt his program or the program that you
have created to market conditions.
And also just to fast away instead of opening the code and compiling a program every time you can actually
now you can actually just drag and drop and then change the parameters that you need.
So that is a very convenient and efficient way of structuring your algorithmic trading systems.
I think that's enough for this time and I hope you have fun with that.
And I really hope that you join me again for the next tutorial.
And don't forget to check check me out on forewings bomb dot com.
Until then happy coding.