Hello this is Carol from Fargo dot com and welcome to the 15th tutorial on algorithmic trading in kill
four for complete beginners.
And today's going to be a very exciting tutorial.
We're actually going to send our very first order through and algorithmic trading system.
Yep that's exactly it.
You heard it.
We're sending our first order today.
And that's jump straight into it.
So in front of me I have the code which we created in a previous tutorial I'm just going to go quickly
and say it as tutorial 15.
So we have a new file save that compile as you can see it's compiling a works where you have all the
necessary information in here.
We're letting the trader in the take profit level which is set at default 10 Pip's Stop-Loss level also
set a default 10 Pip's.
But because this is an xterm variable the trader can change it.
Once you launches the script on start function creates two new variables take profit level and stop
the stop loss level.
These two variables are calculated using the bid price through the take profit supplied by the trader
and the stop loss supplied by the charter.
As you remember point is just an indicator or basically a internal variable of the terminal which tells
us that the basically the amount of decimal points of the current symbol.
And finally at the well we stopped on the last toile was we just printed out onto the trader's screen
the calculate levels Volstead we're going to take one more step further and we're actually going to
send an order and to send an order we have to use a function is called Order send function.
Don't get too concerned about the word function right now we're going to look at functions in the next
tutorial for knowledge.
Just use it.
And as I like to say let's learn by doing.
Let's actually send the order and see how it all works.
And in the next tutorial will actually understand in more depth what functions are and how how to use
them properly.
So we're going to type in order send.
I hope you're following open a standard bracket.
And here we have a problem.
So are in these brackets we're going to have to supply a list of parameters.
So we're going to click f highlight or center and click one.
This brings up this call for reference.
Here you will see the list of parameters we need to supply for this function and it's a symbol name
the command in our case we're going to send a buy order volume number of lottes price at which price
we want to buy or sell slippage.
Basically that's up by how much the price can deviate.
Stop Loss level take profit level and I comment if we want to and some other parameters we should.
We're not going to worry about at this stage because we don't really need them.
They have default values.
Once again we will study this in more detail in the next tutorial.
For now let's just write the function.
So once again we type in the symbol name for us is going to be your dollar command.
We want to buy and the command for buys you O.P. underscored by you so you can see the prompt came up
Colma volume.
We're going to buy one lot.
Price at which price do we buy orders.
If you look back a couple of tutorials you can recall that we buy order.
We buy currencies at the ask price which is the dear price slippage.
We're going to send a set at ten pips Stop-Loss.
We already have the calculated Stop-Loss in here it's asking us not for the stop loss not for the amount
of Pip's but actually the Stop-Loss level which we have calculated here so I'll just copy that and put
it in and take profit.
We've also calculated that to take profit in anything else.
Yes it's asking us for a comment and a comment company we will say my first order exclamation mark.
And we're not going to put in any of these parameters because we don't actually need to alter them we'll
just leave the defaults and semi-colon at the end.
We'll compile this as you can see here.
It's returning a warning the return value of this function should be checked.
We're not going to worry about that.
Now we'll look at that in next to Tauriel.
For now that's fine for us as just a warning it's not an error.
So we've compiled that compiles go to the terminal OK.
So we're in the terminal.
And before we do anything that will basically of course you have to open the char will open your adult
chart and I'll quickly pretty this up to get rid of the grid.
Zoom in a little bit so we can see the action.
And now before we do anything we have to remember that for our algorithmic trading systems to work in
meditative for they have to be switched on.
So there's no way here you can see order trading is going to Redburn right now.
That means that all algorithmic trading systems are switched off and even if you try to pull them onto
the chart or launch them Thuram from the navigator they won't work.
Nothing will happen.
So now we're just going to press the button it's turned green.
That means all algorithmic trading systems are now allowed to trade.
And now we're going to find our script script a tutorial 15.
I'll just switch here to the trade view and here you can see that my balance is $5000.
Of course this is a demo account and I don't have any open orders at the moment.
I have just one county history transaction which is a deposit on the demo account so back to the trade
view.
Ok now I'm going to pull this tutorial 15 script onto the your adult chart.
As you can see right away we have these three tabs.
Last one is inputs and inputs we can choose take profit and Stop-Loss levels so we'll leave them at
default for now and we'll click OK.
So you can see he's brought up the alert statement and of course our orders have.
Order has opened.
So let's go here to the bottom.
We can see your adult all Order has opened.
The buy it's a buy order.
It's a total of one law that has been bought.
The price is 1 3 6 3 3 which was ask ask price when the order is open stop loss levels 1.3 6 to 1 which
is the same as in our message 1.3 six for one is a take profit.
Same as in our message which means everything is work correctly and we'll just close as a message for
now and we'll open up.
We'll add a section called the Commons section and in the Commons it's probably very small on your screen
but you can see here it says my first order exclamation mark.
So basically there you go.
Congratulations you've actually just opened your first order.
And that's that's a very big step and you should be proud of yourself that you've made it this far.
And yes so in the next tutorial we're going to look at how functions work and have a play Orangi can
open as many or as you want you can change this to 20 30 and it will open another order and you can
see now we have two orders.
So basically play around with that next fall and next to Tauriel we'll go in more depth on functions.
Hope you enjoyed the Tauriel don't forget to look on for ex-beau dotcom where you can find the source
code and more comments and more free tutorials.
And until next time happy coding.