Hello this is Carol from Fargus dot com.
And welcome to this Twenty-Third tutorial on algorithmic training for beginners and I really hope that
you're as excited about today's tutorial as I am.
Because today is the day that we're finally going to start working on our very own algorithmic trading
system.
So what does any algorithmic trading system start with any algorithmic trading system starts with an
idea an idea that we can put in the core of our trading strategy an idea that we will build all of our
rules around.
And that idea can be anything.
And most most of the time it will be a dependency that we observe on the market some sort of pattern
or something that we can expect we can.
We think that we can exploit.
So how do you come up with an idea like that.
Well I recommend using recalling what we talked about in the previous tutorial when we discussed rule
based decisions in algorithmic trading.
And I'll just bring up the slide from there and that time we talked about three types of rules that
we will be trying.
We'll be looking to incorporate in our system and those are price rules timebase rules and indicator
based rules.
So we can use this diagram as a guideline.
We look at price time and indicators to try to find some sort of pattern in the market.
So here you see the British pound dollar chart and some highlights that are very dismayed and they might
not make sense right away.
But watch how this changes in less than a minute as I just said just the chatter a little bit.
So first of all we are going to change the chart to a line graph and then I'm going to go into properties
and I'm going to add the period separate just like we did in the previous Toral.
So now as you can see it's starting to make a bit more sense.
The lines are always connecting the open price of the day with a price somewhere in the market which
we'll talk about just now and then some other arrows show which way the traders should and the market
blue means by Red means sell.
So what am I doing here.
I I looked at the British pound dollar.
And well actually let's rewind a little bit.
What I was trying to do was I wanted to come up with a trading system that we that we would program
in these in this series of tutorials.
But I didn't want to be just a generic indicator based system or something that we would code just for
the sake of training and practicing and picking up our programming skills I wanted to actually make
it interesting by actually finding a pattern in the market and something that we can exploit and something
that will give our system a chance so that it can actually be profitable and it can bring us money in
the end and that way it'll be more interesting and more fun to create the code for the system.
So what I was doing I was looking at the British pound dollar chart and I noticed the dependency is
something we actually spoke a little bit about in the previous tutorial that usually the day here starts
pretty flat and then it and then there's a big movement at the Miss somewhere in the middle of the day
and upon further investigation this is what I found.
I found that often the British pound will at the start of they will move in one direction and then around
9:00 or maybe eight nine ten eleven o'clock it will actually jump in the opposite direction.
So as you can see here the red line showing that the British pound was going down from the start of
the day from 0 0 to here it's 13 oclock and then it jumped back up here again it's going down from 0
0 and going all the way to 12 and then jumping back up here.
We can see the opposite happening.
The British pound dollar started at 1.7 8:59 went up to 1.7 136 and then it jump or it tumbled all the
way back down.
Here's another one.
It started somewhere around 1.7 1 2 0 0 went up and then at 9:00 it tumbled down.
And so this dependency can be observed quite often.
Sometimes you can observe it like for example here on the 16th of July 2014.
It's just going flat.
Pretty much no.
No movements and the biggest span here is about 20 pips courage you make a profit of that on British
pound dollar H-1 chart on our chart here which you can see is that is just going down just plain down
and that's why there's no bounce back up and that's why I put the x's here meaning that Conry tray if
we try we won't make a profit on these days if we try to trade this pattern that we've noticed over
here yesterday on the 18th of July 2014 what happened was it went up and then the British pound dollar
went up and around 10:00 and tumbled all the way down.
And so that's that's the dependency on notice and that's what we're going to put to try to put at the
core of our system and build a whole trading strategy around.
And of course automated in the process.
Let's have a look let's go back a bit and have a look if we can observe the same relation relationship
back in stock at the start of the year meaning just to make sure that it's not a recent trend.
It's not a recent thing that's happening that we it's actually pretty consistent because any trading
strategy can survive for forever.
But we would prefer it to be viable for at least two three four months and until we have to maybe adjust
it.
So looking back at February this year what we can see is that
we can actually observe this pattern as well here on the 24th of February.
The British pound dollar started low went up and then tumbled down.
And what time did that happen happened at 10 o'clock on this day I put across here because it did happen
but it happened around 3:00 which is pretty late me like we have to choose a time we have to choose
a time when we're going to be expecting this to happen.
And from what we've seen so far it's probably going to be nine or ten o'clock.
So I hear we probably wouldn't have made money on this one on the 26 of February.
You can see it started low went up and tumbled down at nine o'clock here.
It started high went down and then jumped up at 10:00.
Here it's kind of generally going up.
However Well there is a there is a jump down at 10:00.
And just I just didn't highlight everything around here just a few here.
You can also see it started low went high tumbled down at 9:00.
So this whole pattern or this whole behavior in the market is happening around 9:00.
And what does that mean.
Well it means that 9:00 on this server time is actually when the European session starts or somewhere
around there.
So during the Asian session this British pound dollar it's pretty is pretty calm or it's going in one
direction and then like here it's calm of course but it's going in one direction.
But then when the euro the European session starts it makes a rapid movement in the opposite direction.
And so that's how it can be explained from a market point of view.
Why why it could be happening.
And as you can see we're not observing this you know pattern every time.
There are exceptions and sometimes it happens later sometimes happens earlier.
But a lot of the time it does happen at 9:00 or 10:00 so and that's the beauty of Forex you don't have
to actually observe something or find something on a parody that happens every single time even if it
happens in 60 or 70 percent percent of the time.
Then you can still make a profit out of it by putting the right decision based rules around it and putting
good trading generally good trading strategy around.
So generally speaking this is a good looks like a good pattern for us to trade.
So let's bring up this presentation again and what what have we discussed so far we've ticked the price
because we can't the star of the day price and price at 9:00 or 10:00 and we take the time and because
we're looking at a fixed time we're expecting this pattern to happen at exactly 9:00.
So we are looking at time.
We haven't looked at indicators yet so how'd we do that.
How would we see if we can improve the system a little bit by using an indicator.
So we'll quickly add a moving average it's a 100 periods simple I reach by using the close price and
generally what you would do is a movie you tread a moving average is a moving average as a filter.
And if you're above the moving average if your price is above the moving average like here then you
trade you Jews you Dubai or as you trade upwards because it's that indicates that it's an upward trend.
If your price is below the moving average like over here you would generally sell because that indicates
the price being below the moving average indicates that it's a downward trend.
And obviously you had your druthers Sallon downward trend.
However let's see what's happening in our particular situation.
So in this system in this system that we're outlining here what we can see is that these blue arrows
are below the moving average and the red ones for this one are either very close to the moving average
or above.
And what does that mean to us.
That means that we're actually doing the opposite of what was prescribed.
So the price here is generally below the moving average but we are buying.
And that means that we are tré it we're actually going against the trade and looks like it by the looks
of it.
If we look back here we can see that the price is going down generally but at every one of these blue
Iris's the retracement.
And so to me that says that probably during the European session the British pound dollar currency pair
experience at the open of that session experiences a retracement within the trade within the trend and
not even knowing that what we've come up with this trading strategy we've come up with is actually based
on trading that retracement.
So it is legitimate that we are trading by orders we're creating by or below them moving our age because
we want to catch this retracement movement that we've observed.
And so that's basically it.
That's that's how strategies played out.
And it's picked all all three of these boxes price time and indicators and that's exactly what we're
going to be working on in the future in the next couple of tutorials and in the next one we're going
to create a blueprint for the system just so that our coding is then much simpler and then in the toilet
after that we're actually going to start coding it and you'll see how because we've done all of this
groundwork already and our system is shaping up pretty nicely and it's pretty straightforward and quite
simple.
You'll see how that our coding efforts will be very little and it will be very easy to program the system.
So that's that for today and hope you found this tutorial interesting and I hope to see on the next
tutorial.
Until then happy coding.