Hello this is Carol from Foxborough dot com and welcome to our kill for tutorial on algorithmic training
for beginners.
In the previous two trials we looked at how to open orders how to close orders how to modify them etc.
but now we have a question what do we do if we already have an order in the market and we want to find
out information about it.
So we don't necessarily want to do anything yet but we just want to understand is this order what the
stop losses for this are or what the profit is.
What instrument this order has been executed on what the volume is and all this other information which
is related to order how do we find that out.
And that's exactly what we're going to be looking at today.
So let's proceed to meet Ed. And we're going to take our Tauriel 19 over here which we worked on previously
and we're going to save it as Tauriel 20 as we often do and change this up here comp. that that compiles
perfectly fine.
So we're going to leave this first part which you are by now very familiar with the part where we send
the order and then we have a failsafe mechanism to check everything was done correctly and then we will
even leave this part where we tell the trader about our order and then we delay execution for this is
five seconds.
To be precise.
Now we're going to get rid of these two bits just to save some space so we had the closing of the order
here.
Get rid of that.
That was commented out anyway and then the modifying the order that previous tural will also get rid
of that.
And today we're going to be looking at just getting information.
So the situation is we've sent the order to the market.
Here it is we have the ticket number.
We know the unique identifier so we know what the order is but we will.
Now we want to get more information on this order.
So we want to hear.
We want to find out information like stop loss level or take profit level or the instrument and other
information like the direction of the order and it might seem trivial at this stage because we do already
have this information program.
Let's imagine for a second that we don't that we we were just our program was able to pick up this ticket
number now but it doesn't know all of this other information that we need to retrieve it.
Or you could imagine it in this way that after the order was sent sufficient time has passed for things
to change for example.
Or it could have been closed.
And we still have the ticket and we need to find out if the order is closed or still open and this is
probably the most crucial part because all of the other things like stop loss take profit and other
like the parameters of the order we won't be focusing on that as much in this beginner's course but
what we will need when we're coding our
standalone algorithmic trading system down the track we will need to be able to find out if the order
has been closed or not.
So I'll point that out when we get to.
But let's just start writing the code now.
So we we've told our program to wait for 5 seconds and now we're going to select the order and to do
that we need to use the order select function.
And here where it says index.
We put in the ticket number and then a second parameter I'm just going to tell you what it is it's like
buy a ticket don't worry about the other one at this stage.
So just four or de-select This tells your program or your script.
In this case to select this order that we have the ticket number four and remember the selection.
So once again order select returns returns a boolean values telling us if the selection was successful
or not.
So we have to implement a failsafe mechanism.
A result is orders select and then we have to check our results as we did previously.
If a result is false then we have to tell the truth to something like Error selecting order.
So he knows that we weren't able to select the order and we won't be proceeding with the next step otherwise
else if everything was all right we're going to tell the trader that the order selected successfully.
Very similar to what we've done we did before and for ourselves we'll just write a column on here that
now we can all work with this selected order.
And what that means is basically that the terminal has saved this election.
You will understand what this means in a second.
The timing of this election has been saved us by the terminal.
All right and now we're going to tell the trader more information about this or are we going to extract
this information through this selection.
So we did the selection here and now that selection will last is checked.
Extract information mention about order and hash tag for number.
And then we want to put in the ticket number.
Usually I just want to make this clear because I'm not sure if I was clear enough about this before
what would usually do is or we can do is we will take the ticket number.
But in order to actually convert it to searching we'll type conversion here string.
Take it as you recall and then.
So this becomes a string and then we concatenated with the rest.
But the statement by itself this function allows you to actually put parameters or call like separate
them just by calmer.
And then you don't have to do this part.
You can just put an integer and it will automatically churn into strings so I don't think I was clear
enough about that.
Both ways a fine so you can concatenated with a plus sign but then you have to turn into a string.
Or you can just use a comma and we'll use a column today and that will put another column when that
and we'll just put the like call on so we know that the parameters come afterwards or the information
comes afterwards.
So the trader knows that and then we're going to just have a series of alerts statements telling us
more about this or and will extract everything we can or everything we need at this stage.
So what instrument.
What financial instrument is has this order been created on the this is how it is done.
So this is the important bit.
So instrument.
That's OK but where do we get the instrument.
We hold the order symbol function a function as you can see doesn't take any void here.
Void means that doesn't take any parameters and it returns a string here on the left that says string.
That means this is how you call the function just empty brackets name function empty brackets and return
a string which we will add to the alert by means of this comma and what it will return is the financial
instrument where this order was opened so or where this order is opened.
So by selecting the order here we are now working with that order.
Why this function.
OK so let's do a couple more and that will make more sense or the like it more easy to understand.
So what about type of water meaning is it a buy or a sell order order type.
There you go.
So that will tell us the type of the order which was selected by the order select from function.
That's why I wrote here that selection has been saved by the terminals so he knows which was selected
so whenever we call these functions he knows the terminal knows which order to go to extract those values.
All right.
Is going to be quite a few open time.
Order open time is when the order was opened.
Open price is when the order
was what what.
At what price the order was opened.
Alert Hubei the volume now that will be Homi a lots.
So the function is order lots here.
So the volume or the order next will do stop loss.
So here we will be able to pull out the current stop loss and that will be it can change if we've modified
the order of order modify as you remember in the previous examples and then it will always tell us the
most recent stop loss the one that's currently set for the Order order take profit similar to crowd
comment.
Remember that comment that we put my first order exclamation mark.
So that's be the Calment or any other comment.
If you said a different comment how blocked What else do we have order.
I guess it's an important one order close time.
So I'm I'd stop here for a second.
Because this is what I mentioned at the beginning that this is going to be how we find out if the order
has been closed or not.
So here if closed then great then this will be a greater than zero value not closed then it will be
less then only equals zero.
So that's how this works.
If if the order has been closed and we still have this ticket we're still holding on to this ticket
number but because sufficient time has passed and the market conditions have either hit the stop loss
or take profit or we could have closed that or our selves freezing or reclose function.
In any case the order has been closed and the best way to find that out and this is my recommended way
and probably a lot of traders do it this way.
Check the order close time function.
So if the order close time is greater than zero that means that order has been closed.
It does have a closed time if it has not yet been closed the order closed time will always be zero.
So it's a very safe way to check if the order has been closed or not.
All right.
Order or close price.
So here for the close price very similar.
So if the order close price it's a bit tricky oil.
Basically if the order has been close in this case then it will have the price at which it was close.
So will will type in something similar if closed then close price or price at close if not closed.
Then a hug or possible
price to close.
So I'll just
put this on your line so you can see.
So this one is interesting in the way that if the order has been closed which you can check why this
function as the prescribed method.
So if the order has been closed then this value will be the closed prized and that's it that's done.
But if the order is still open instead of returning nothing or a zero or something useless and kill
for actually does a very useful thing and it returns the Kalat price at which you can close the Order
By.
If you are going to close it right now by the market.
And so that's very useful in the sense that because say buy order would always be closed at the bid
price.
So the cheaper price and sell order would always be called Closer and ask price at the dear price.
It's always usually you'd have to run a check so if you orders a buy order close it at that bid if you
order a sell order close to the ask.
However because you have this order Crooke close price it basically already incorporates that.
So if you're orders of order or close price will be your current bid price if your orders sell order
order clause price who'll be asked price current the current price so and kill for makes it very easy
for you to quickly understand at which price to close your order regardless of whether it's a buy or
sell.
You just have to use or close price.
So it's kind of a sneaky sneaky cheat code in and kill for don't have to use it.
If you if you don't want to but I find it quite handy sometimes.
So profit one more is the profit which will tell you either the profit of a closed order or the current
running profit of an open order.
So I'm just khush of time here.
This is becoming one of the long term deals and we'll just go and quickly see how this works will compile
that no errors or warnings which is great.
Go to the terminal scripts.
That's fine.
Our structural 20.
So I'm going to drag this input's for now I'm going to change anything.
OK.
Sorry my bad.
The training wasn't on.
So trading is on now.
That's because I changed the account to have a fresh balance here.
Every time you change your card you go to change that as well.
Or you have to apply the urelements settings.
Anyway back to tural drag.
OK.
And there we go.
So starting from here don't worry about that on our ticket and waited five seconds and then then this
is the information we've brought up.
So I was just going to quickly bring up the windows magnifier so it's easier to see so it's over here
on the right this window and I'm just going to go through this so this was our first message for this
launch of the script.
That's the order.
If you if we look down here that's the word tonight for on the end tonight.
For now we've selected.
So we launched it then we waited five seconds between here you can see the time for 15:30 420 So we
waited five seconds and then we have information about or soon nine that's that order.
So instruments used dollar.
That's correct.
That's true in recent scented with Type 0.
Don't get afraid that this is zero in kill for zero means by one means sell.
That's just historically how it has developed open time one for this very long number.
It is actually a code and that's how state tie dates and times date times basically are stored and am
kill for this is the number of seconds that has passed since 1970 from January 1970 until the time and
date when the order was actually opened.
So we can convert this into a proper date time but we won't bother about it.
We'll just believe that this is the correct date and time.
All right.
More importantly open price 1 3 5 1.3 5:27 Let's go down here and check if it is the correct open price
one point thirty five twenty seven.
That is correct.
All right.
Volume it was one lot that that is how many That's how big an order we requested.
That's good.
Stop Loss 135 15 and take profit 135 thirty five.
Let's check that quickly going down here.
Stop-Loss 135 15 take profit 135 235.
So the information has been extracted correctly.
Comment My first order exclamation mark.
That is our comment.
All right.
And to the very important bit order clothes time the order clothes time is zero.
That means that order is still active which you can see over here it is still in the market and order
close price 130 525 that is the price at which we could have closed the order at the time when we launched
the script.
And as we discussed this for the for this order because by order this represents the bid price at that
time.
And finally profit minus 20 is just basically means that that's what the profit was profit.
The order had when we launched the script.
So that's that's also correct dreadnoughts minus 30 but it's one pip lower than it was when we launched
the script.
So that's basically how you get all the information from an existing order.
If you have the ticket number on it is going to close this doesn't bother us anymore and I hope that
will make sense.
We will be using some of this information very like we'll be relying very heavily especially this order
clothes time where we develop power algorithmic trading system.
I hope to see you on the next tutorial and until then happy coding.