Hello this is curial from Fargo dot com.
Welcome back to the series of tutorials on arithmetic training for beginners.
In today's Tauriel we're going to recap on the system design and trading functions section of our course
which we have just completed.
So as you can see here I'm on the forex Board website and this is where I upload all the totals and
supporting materials to them.
So if you go to w dot for dot com and then click courses in the ribbon up here you should end up on
this page where the courses are listed.
And then if you scroll down and find three of our current course you'll get a list of tutorials that
we will discuss briefly each day.
So we started off this section by talking about basic algorithmic trading system design.
And we had a look at two specific examples and one we used a fixed distance to said stop losses and
take profits and then we used price levels on the market to find out where to put those stop losses
and take profits and also looked at a way of maximizing the safety of our system in the next tutorial
we talked about how we can incorporate trader inputs and we learned the externe keywords in them kill
for which allows us to do that.
And then we jumped straight into sending orders on the forex market and we had we looked at an example
of using the order send function and we actually send our very first order with phenolic through an
algorithmic trading system which was very exciting.
Then we had to take a step back and talk about functions because functions are a very big part of all
four and as you can see here there's quite a lot of functions involved in sending orders and doing other
stuff with them.
And so here we compared functions to a blender and there was quite a fun tutorial.
Next we talked about Fail-Safe programming techniques which are an integral part of a good programmer's
arsenal and allow you to cater to any thing that can happen on the forex market and make sure that the
traders are always aware of what's going on.
And after that we talked about two more functions which relate to sending and modifying orders on the
4 X market.
So the order close function allows you to close existing orders and order modify function allows you
to modify orders and change their stop loss take profit and other parameters.
And finally at the end of the section we talked about the order select function which helps you pick
out orders by if you only know their ticket number and then get more information about them such as
where whether they've been closed or not.
What was Stop-Loss is currently set for that order what tech profits and other things and that will
come in very handy in our next section where we'll be talking it will be will be actually creating our
very first big trading system from scratch.
So that's this section 3 in a very brief summary.
I just would like to say that the next section is going to be full of very interesting and exciting
stuff.
But at the same time it's going to be we're actually going to be programming our system so pleased to
make sure that you're very comfortable with what we've discussed here and that will help you move through
this course very quickly.
Also if there are any questions or you'd like to clarify something please feel free to leave me a message
forms like this.
You can see on most of the pages of the four expert website and you can just you can just leave any
comments or feedback or questions in these forums and I will respond to you very shortly after you leave
the message.
So what else.
Well the site is full of supporting materials to the lectures you can also appear you can also click
on the About Me page which will take you to this small summary which I did for why I started this website
just me over here I had some fun with that picture and there you can just read about why I started this
website what my background is and maybe connect with me on Linked In Google Plus or Twitter if you like.
And always happy to hear from you.
Maybe send me a message and we can we can chat and yeah that's basically this website that I'm running
at the moment.
If you if you if you're interested if you like it feel free to also subscribe to the newsletter over
here which will allow you to.
Which will basically help you stay up to date with all the stuff that I post and any more free courses
that I come up with.
So hopefully this was a helpful summary and I look forward to seeing you in the next section of of course.
And until then happy coding.