[MUSIC]
Next up,
we're gonna be getting funky with Unity.
We're gonna start off nice and gentle,
looking at the Unity layout, and
the windows, and the different components
of Unity that are most important for us.
And then we're going to be creating
something that is called a scriptable
object, or
specifically many scriptable objects,
in order to contain the data for
the game that we're gonna be working on.
And that game is going to
be simple text adventure.
And so by creating a text adventure,
we'll be understanding more about state
machines, and how different
states can lead to other states.
And how our state machine can only be in
this one state at a certain point in time.
So we're gonna be looking
at Unity specifically, but
also continuing to emphasize our coding,
and our scripting, and our C#.
I wanna mention something at this point,
just very briefly,
that as you'll go through this course,
you might have different things
that you're interested in.
You might be saying, well,
I really wanna become a programmer, so
just show me the programming stuff.
Or you might be the sort of person
who's saying, you know what?
I'd like to know a little bit
more about game design and
how I make a really cool game,
that's why I'm here.
So the course has been broken
down into roughly 50% of
the course is focusing on let's do
programming, let's talk C#, coding.
So about 50%, and
only about 40% is focusing on Unity.
How to use the Unity engine,
how to get the most out of it,
how the different components work,
new aspects in Unity.
And then you might be
sitting there saying, 50,
40 hopefully there's another
10% floating around.
There is, the other 10% is where
we'll talk about game design, and
game production, and how to make
a compelling player experience.
Cuz we assume that in addition to
wanting to be good at programming, and
learn programming, and
to understand Unity,
that you also have an interest
in learning about video games.
And how to create interesting video games
that might just be for yourself, or
might be something you
give to other people, or
maybe one day you would like to make
a career out of making video games.
We're not gonna go that big.
For now, we're just looking at the
fundamentals, and we're starting to have
that conversation about,
how do you something that's not just,
yay, I did a thing, but doing something
that could be interesting to the player.
So we'll be scattering through some
of those game design conversations
throughout this section and
throughout the sections following this.
Just wanted to give you a heads up.
If it's not your cup of tea, if it's not
the sort of thing you're interested in,
then go through a little
bit more quickly and
don't put as much time
into the challenges.
But if it's something you're excited about
and something maybe you haven't done a lot
of before,
then it's really good to dig into it.
And take the opportunity to really flex
your creative muscles when it comes to
the game production,
game design aspects of the course.
And of course continue working on
the challenges for the coding and for
the programming.
That's the way that you learn, that's how
you get better is by doing the challenges.
So let's dive in and
make ourselves a text adventure game.