[MUSIC]
Welcome to the next section of the course,
this section's called Glitch Garden,
it's based upon an old well-known game
called Plants vs Zombies which is a lane
based tower defense game.
I wanna show you a little bit of my
prototype that I've been working on and
tidying up and
putting a little bit more love into, so
that you can see what
we're working towards.
Here's our prototype, and if I click on
Play, I'll show you the core gameplay.
We have attackers that are coming in from
the right in their particular lanes.
We can place down defenders, like these
cactuses, they shoot, they also block.
This grave stone blocks
attackers when they come in.
We've got foxes and we've got the lizards.
We can also place down our, what is this,
the Star thing that generate stars and
increases our amount of
resources that we have.
I can see I've got an error, so
my prototype's not quite finished here,
ignore the error for now, if you will.
I'm wanna show you a couple of
things that we'll be digging into.
We'll be spending a bunch
of time in the animator,
getting you familiarized
with how the animator works.
We'll be looking at animations,
let me find an animation to show you.
So from the fox, the fox has say,
a walk animation.
And what is very interesting that's
gonna be a little different is within
the animation itself, we're gonna
be adding these animation events.
And that is where when we get to this
particular frame in the animation,
it will call particular function.
This function has no name.
The first one's probably
a bit more relevant.
Set speed, so at that point at
the start of this animation,
it's gonna call set speed.
So that's really cool.
That's a very interesting
different way for artists or
specifically for animators,
to be controlling things within the game.
Specifically, if you
had a fighting game and
you wanted to say that at the moment the
player goes just there, that's where we
wanna trigger the particle effects should
trigger the damage should appear, etc.
So rather than just saying the very
moment of starting the swing,
all those things happen.
We wanna say the precise moment, so this
will be interesting for those of you that
wanna dig a little bit deeper into how
that specific timing of things could work.
Okay, what else have we got in
here that I wanna show you?
So I've got my spawners, the spawners
we can choose how many different things
to spawn, so we can spawn just the fox,
we can change this array to two, and
then we can spawn foxes and lizards,
for example, from, where is my lizard?
There it is, from that particular lane.
So there's some changes we can do there,
and on my error down at the bottom there,
that's just me still working
on my prototype, not having it
exactly buttoned up just yet, but
look at that, the error has been fixed.
[LAUGH] Okay, so no,
the error hasn't been fixed.
I just cleared it.
That was just me cheating, but I promise
you when we go through the course,
we'll fix up all those particular things,
little things that pop up.
And this section is gonna be a little bit
more challenging, a little bit deeper.
It is building upon our spiral syllabus,
so
a lot of the things that we've covered
before, we'll be covering again, and
getting a little bit more complexity to
them, and getting you to be getting a bit
more hands on with how we create it,
but I wanna focus on animation.
I wanna focus on the core things that make
2D games really amazing, so let's jump in,
talk a little bit more about
the design in the next video, and
then get our hands dirty making this game.