[MUSIC]
Hello again, in this video, we're
organizing our folder structure, adding
all of our states and all of our dialogue,
all of our next state conditions.
And creating a game that we can play the
full way through with a start, a middle,
and an end, let's jump in and get started.
So here is your challenge, it's also
what were covering in this video.
We're going to add an introduction state
with some instructions to the player,
we'll add a Game Over state
with some sort of Play Again.
We'll create all our story states, we'll
copy in our text, we'll hook up our next
states, and we'll make sure we have
our folder structure nicely organized.
So let's start with our folder structure,
actually, we're doing things a little bit
from back to front from were I had
my Challenge slide just there.
Give myself some space on the window,
just to know if you hold down control,
and you roll your mouse wheel.
You can move in and out, or
you can grab the little, do that,
down the bottom down here and
slide around like that,
if you prefer this sort of structure
to be looking at your folders.
First thing I do is right-click Create
Folder, and I will call this scripts.
So we can grab out two script files and
plot them in there so
they're out of the way nicely organized,
there we go.
Next up, I will right-click
Create Folder and I'll call the states.
If it wants to order the complete,
there we go, not what I complete,
but just general complete.
It was thinking about something and
we will, let's see,
we don't need room one anymore,
I'm gonna delete that.
That was just placeholder and we,
likewise, don't need room two,
I will delete that as well.
StartingState, well that was actually
if I have a look at my flow diagram,
that was actually State A1.
So I'll rename now, just click
on that once or when you're when
you clicked on your file you can hit F2,
we can call this A1.
Now it's up to you if you wanna
get a little more detailed,
a little bit more professional we'll say,
when you could use the name of it, A1,
outside Hanger in here.
So A1.Outside.Hanger so
then it's super clear.
Not only can you order your files cuz
they'll be alphanumerically ordered,
but you can also read on it and
see, that's exactly what the state is
to make sure that there's no confusion.
Now, we will drag this state
file into the states directory,
I need a couple of other folders in here.
Actually, I'm going to Give myself a bit
more structure create a folder, so
I'm inside the States folder.
Creating a new folder which
will be called Intro, and
then another folder lots of folders
in this video, what did you do today?
Made a lot of folders, okay,
this is gonna be called Game Over.
And then I'll create another folder,
which I will call Hanger cuz in my game,
the player in this particular section of
my game's running around in the Hanger, so
it gives me some sort of structure.
If I have say seven different major
sections of my game, then I can
have them grouped and organized into
these particular sections of the game.
Makes it easier to find things, you don't
wanna just have a huge long list of state
files, it gets a little
bit tricky to find them.
So I'll drag outside,
hanger into Hanger, there we go,
now it's no longer outside Hanger.
Look at that for inception meta point,
accidental meta point there,
so I have my one State file in here.
Let's come into intro,
right-click, create a state, and
we'll call this State Introduction, and I
better give it a number, we'll call it A0.
So in the introduction we're just saying
something like, welcome to this game.
It's a choose your own adventure,
be careful what you wish for
or something [LAUGH] clever like that.
At each stage, you'll be asked
to push a key on the keyboard,
for example, 1 or 2 or 3.
And we could write in here
if we wanna add something,
in terms of quitting the game for
in the future,
we might say at any point in time,
push q to quit.
We don't have that have
that hooked up yet, but
that could be a thing to give people
that ability to get out quick, okay.
So we've got our introduction in up there,
that would be our starting state, so
remember we need to find on game,
need to find what is our startingState.
Now it's this A0 introduction,
drag that in, so
that'll be the very first state
that game plays when we hit Play.
And that will be from there, we can
then say go to, we'll put this in now,
we will go to in states in here we
need to make one that will give
us the selection option and we'll say go
to outside Hangout, there we go, okay.
So we've just got our introduction flow,
really important to get the game flow so
people can start,
have the game and then finish and
then know how to restart the game.
Speaking of finishing, we go to Game Over,
we'll create ourselves a state in here and
we'll call this.
Now let me have a look at what I called
it on my flow diagram X1 Game Over.
Okay, so this is X1 Game Over,
okay and then I did have some
information in here,
I'll just go in here and copy that.
Copy, copy, copy, great, and then click
and I was just copying with Ctrl + C,
I assume you know how to do a copy and
paste, Ctrl + C, Ctrl + V, or Cmd + C,
Cmd + V on the Mac, okay,
and that is in there.
I've just put in my
little bit of story text,
and then it's saying,
what do you wanna do?
Yes, play again, so if someone does
want to play again, I think so
we've got two states in here,
I'll just add in two.
If they don't want to play again, I think
they would go straight to the Hangar.
If they don't want to play again,
then I think we would take them back to
the introduction screen,
which gives them instructions.
It's kinda like a main menu instructions
on how to quit if they want.
Okay, so we've hooked up that flow for
the intro, for the game over,
and now to put in all of our states.
I'm gonna bomb in a whole
bunch of them in here, so
Create&gt; State, and
I'll call this A2 and then click on A2.
Ctrl + D to duplicate and then we will
call it A3, wonderful, duplicate,
duplicate, so I'm doing Ctrl + D or
Cmd + D that duplicates the file.
And because there is nothing in these
files, it's okay to duplicate it.
I've gone up to A12, did I need to
go up to A12 on my diagram here?
I go up to A11, okay, that's cool so
now we can start with the Bs,
so, A12, we can make this B1,
click on that, duplicate.
B2, B3, B4, B5 I think we're up to B6,
and B6, that's where we went up to okay,
so now I've got all of my states in there,
they're all sitting in Hangar.
What I need to do is copy in
all of the story text and
then hook up what is the next state that
we go to, making sure, being super careful
that the instructions of click one to go
somewhere and click two to go somewhere.
Making sure that I put the state that is
being described in one in element zero and
the state that is being described
in two in element one and
if I've got a third state then
that would be an element two.
Just to make sure that the button
is corresponding to the state.
So what I'm gonna do is pause the video
now and put in all my story text,
if you wanna do the same, if you're
following along and doing this, and
putting in a whole bunch of your
own story then please do that now.
Add in all of your states, and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
I'm pretty sure you don't want to watch me
copying and pasting for ten minutes, so
I'll pause the video and I'll be back
here in a moment when I've done that.
Welcome back,
I've added all of my states here, and
as I was going through that process,
I found it really easy to see which
of my states have I definitely
hooked up the next states for.
Cuz you can see as you cycle through,
just with the left and
right arrows on your keyboard as you cycle
through, you can see, yep, yes, yes,
yes, yes, and then I notice,
no, there's nothing in there.
And then I'd look at my diagram again and
see for state B5, B5,
what do we need to do here?
B5 needs to head off up to B6,
makes sense, so
then I would drag B6 over to
where it says Next States and
that automatically says and
drops B6 in there which is cool.
Okay one thing I'll show you is,
when you play your game if you click on
this button up here maximize play you can
toggle that on when it's light
whitish color that means it's on.
Clicking Play it means that your game
window will take up the entire screen.
So you see here welcome to the game bad
mistake in here it doesn't say one to
continue.
So, as you play through you'll find bugs,
and you'll find issues,
then pause the game, find that state that
is in our intro state, click on there,
we need to say, push, 1 to continue.
Okay, cool, found that, I'm gonna save
this, I haven't saved for a while,
onwards and upwards.
The other thing I'll point out while I'm
showing you stuff that I've done just now.
I had two success states I've put them
as well in addition to the game over
state that I had,
I didn't show you that before.
I started putting in all my work these two
green guys in here I put those in game
over cuz at the moment,
they represent game over for the game.
So I need to Loop back to the start
of the game when I do this, okay, so
let's click Play just to
make sure it's all working.
I'm gonna do push one,
read it a little bit,
kind of do a little of random button
pushing, make sure I don't get stuck.
Should hit to some sort of dent
at some point klunk, okay cool.
And one thing you might see as
you're doing this, you get an error,
this is our first kind of significant
error that we're coming across.
That for now we're going to ignore
cuz it's not breaking our game, but
it's in nearly every circumstance we
should be paying close attention.
Any time you see this red icon here,
the red icon down the bottom,
that means danger, danger Will Robinson
something has gone wrong.
For now all that means is we've
set up in our script that
the player can push 1, 2 or 3.
But some of our states only have,
for example,
one option that they can push, so
one state that they can go onto next.
So, from here if I was to push key 2,
then it would throw this error saying,
hang on a minute, you pushed 2,
that's outside of our range.
For now we're gonna leave that, there is
ways, there are ways to sort that out and
resolve that, but for now it's cool,
we're not gonna worry about that,
that's not the purpose of this
particular exercise for the moment.
And it's something that place not gonna
see and it's not breaking out game so
that's called but usually we would
jump on any sort of error that we get
this super important to take notice of.
Okay, so we've got a full game
that we can loop through,
great work,
I'll see you in the next video.