[SOUND] Hello again.
In this video we're going to be
using a script to push our character
across the screen with a tunable
walk speed variable so
we can change just how
fast the character goes.
So let's jump in and
make our character move.
What to do first?
Well we need to create a script.
Let's double script in double script.
Double script in our click folder,
that doesn't make sense, Rick.
Double click in our script folder,
that sounds better.
Right click and create C# script.
We will call this attacker.
It becomes attacker CS.
Double click to open up visual studio.
And here we go.
And you know what, while I remember,
I'm gonna jump back over into Unity and
attach that to our lizard.
So lizard, we can add component and
look for attacker this way, or
we can drag the attacker script on over,
but I'll just do it this way.
There we go.
We now have our component.
Which is the attacker
script on the lizard.
Now what do we wanna do in here?
First of all, we need the concept of
moving from right to left on the screen.
So within update we wanna say move,
move, move, move every frame for update.
And I'm gonna show you how to do
that using transform.Translate.
Transform.Translate and
the way we use this is in brackets to
say which direction we wanna move in.
So vector two,
we can do this as vector three.
But I'm gonna do it as a vector two,
which is basically just the same as vector
three, but without the Zed information,
it just makes it as a vector two.
Vector two dot.
Now what are our options here?
Interestingly the Unity
makes it a bit easier for
us to just say what we want our
character to go from right to left.
So we just want it to move left,
and there actually is, and
here if we go dot we can
see it's got a left option.
If you scroll around you can also
see there is a right option,
there's an up option.
Let's see and there's a down option.
So we'll type in left,
that's gonna move our character,
just move to the left which is cool.
We need to do what so
that it's frame rate independent.
We need to multiply it by, you got it,
Time.deltaTime and semicolon.
We also need to do one more thing in
here so that we can alter the speed, but
let's just see that this works okay.
Save, jump back over,
we have our lizard, click on play.
So it should be saying every
frame move to the left,
which is the negative
X I've moved to the left.
It's on the negative X.
So we'll click play.
See what happens here.
Jumps out and walk, walk, walk.
Excellent.
So we do need to do a little bit more
magic when it comes to the movement so
that it's not sliding as it jumps out.
So there'll be a little bit trickery there
and we'll get deeper into our animation
system, and triggering things, and
the relationship between that later on.
But for now we just wanna
get our character moving and
play around with that.
I'm gonna do one more thing cuz I wanna
be able to tune my movement speeds.
So I will multiply this
by concept of walkSpeed.
So walkSpeed multiplied.
WalkSpeed is not created yet so at the top
of our script we will say serialized field
float walkSpeed and
we will initialize that at 1f.
Okay, now to give ourselves
a little bit of constraint,
so we don't go in there and
accidentally do it too fast or too slow.
We can give ourselves a slider if you're
working with a designer or an animator or
an artist, to make life easier.
Let's give it a range.
So above or on the same line, before our
variable our serializedField float here,
we'll type in range and then parentheses.
The lowest we want our
character to go is 0.
You can't really go any slower than 0.
Maybe you could walk backwards, but
we're not really going for that.
And then up to a maximum of, I don't know,
I'm just guessing 5f, and
we can change that later on if need be.
Sorry, there's no semicolon
at the end of that.
So, like I say, you could write it like
that on two different lines to make it
a little bit easier to read.
Or we could do it on the same line.
So then it's all recognizable.
Up to you, I'm gonna do it on different
lines, just so I can have it nice and
clean and not going too far to the right.
So we'll Save, jump back on over,
click on our Lizard game object.
Let's see,
the script should take a moment.
And then blink,
we have our walk speed from zero to five.
So if I put it at zero, click on Play.
Should see that the character
stays there in the one spot.
Which is good for the jump but
then the moment it starts to
walk we'll need to change that.
So, like I said there's some trickery
we'll do later on in this section.
But if I move it up,
at what speed does it look good?
Five seems a bit too fast indeed.
Get back here buddy.
And I think the one we had it
at is looking pretty good.
What we want to do is make sure
there's a good relationship between
how fast it's walking and
where the feet are on the screen.
So, if the character is moving,
if the animation's moving really fast but
the character's not moving at all that
looks like he's doing the moonwalk.
He's kind of sliding on the spot.
So what we can do there
is look at how fast.
First of all from a game play point of
view if we're like okay that's the sort of
speed I want him to go.
But it looks like he's walking a little
bit too quickly with his animation.
So the way we can address that is
to play around within his animation
of the samples to change
how fast the animation go.
So that's gonna be a little bit of
a challenge I give to you now is tune your
walk speed, tune the movement of
the attacker across the screen so
you're happy with it.
Remember, this guy is a little
bit of a slower, heavier guy.
We'll implement some faster
guys as well in a little bit.
And then to tune the animation speed
of the walk so the actual arms and
legs speed, movement looks pretty good.
So take a moment to do that,
don't finesse it super, super long.
Just get something that
you're happy with for now.
Okay so let's change the walk speed,
now you might have come up against this.
I deliberately left this as one of those
gotchas for you to figure out, but
I can only see the lizard jump if I change
the samples here then it's the jump
that's changing.
If you click on lizard jump
you should see lizard walk,
which is the other animations
that's attached to the lizard.
And we can say well let's
make the walk speed say 18.
So when he's actually trundling
along we move at this 18 speed.
And I'm gonna change it to scene view so
I can follow it and not have to
keep coming backwards and forwards.
So that seems to be a plodding,
bloop, bloop, bloop.
Okay, and when we go to our speed
here we'll move the walk speed up to,
we'll say if it's one [SOUND]
that looks pretty good.
I'm gonna leave it that, 18 and 1.
And then follow him off the screen.
That looks like his feet
aren't really sliding.
Good, okay, so pretty happy with that.
We've created ourselves
our first attacker.
Got him moving from right to left.
And in the next video, I think what we're
gonna do is start spawning some attackers.
Yeah, let's do that.
Okay, so let's jump in in the next video,
and start spawning some attackers.