[MUSIC]
Hello, and welcome to another
instructor hangout with Rick and Ben.
Hello, Ben, how are you today?
&gt;&gt; Awesome, Rick, how are you doing buddy?
&gt;&gt; I am very excellent as well, thank you.
A couple of things we wanted
to go through first, and
then we've got our big topic we're
gonna be talking about namespaces.
First couple of things, I've seen
a lot of people in the Q&amp;A section
recently helping other people
answer their technical challenges.
And I forget where I saw it, but
someone was saying this is
a really great way to learn.
They're very active in there,
cuz they like to help other people but
learn as well.
Just a tip, if you want to really
enhance your skills, jump into the Q&amp;A.
See if you can figure out what's
going on with other people's code.
That's a really good way for
you to learn and
cement those things that you've
been learning in the course.
Just a little tip for
you on that one there.
&gt;&gt; Absolutely, you really have to think
about it from a different perspective when
you're trying to help somebody else out,
so good tip, Rick.
&gt;&gt; Totally, thank you, Ben.
And I can't take full credit.
I stole that from somebody in
the community raised that as a tip.
Also, I had a very direct question for
you watching right now in
terms of the challenges.
I haven't had a lot of feedback on
the challenges up until this point.
In terms of, are they too easy,
too hard, or just right,
do you understand what's
going on with them?
So against this video, as with all
the videos, there's a button, or
a link,
that will lead you to our community site.
If you can go into there,
or in the Q&amp;A section,
just let us know what you
think about the challenges.
Are they okay?
Are they too easy?
Are they too hard?
In particular, if you have a challenge so
far that you thought was perfect, and
we know what you think is
the current sort of challenge.
That would make a huge difference to us,
that would be very excellent.
And I think, next topic, that's banging
through these topics, that's two topics.
Here we go, Ben,
your chance to say some words.
If you have on your screen, I believe,
showing some of the screenshots that
people have been sharing
from number wizard UI.
Not as many as the text 101.
You guys were super,
duper active with text 101.
Lots of great sharing.
Coming up with some great screens and
looking things.
&gt;&gt; It's awesome variety here.
Thank you, Rick, for
including me with a wizard hat on.
I look fantastic there, of course.
&gt;&gt; Excellent, I can't see what
you're sharing at the moment-
&gt;&gt; I'm just scrolling through them, Rick,
that's all.
&gt;&gt; Yep, there's a handful in there.
So I know sometimes you think,
well, I won't bother to share.
But it really helps I think, for your
own flow and your own progress, to put
something out there and have people look
at it and not be too precious about it.
That's how you get better
at these things as well.
&gt;&gt; Absolutely.
&gt;&gt; Is a little bit of theme
of this conversation.
And now for
the big thing I wanna talk about.
Yeah, [LAUGH] sorry to interrupt, Ben.
The big thing I wanna talk about
has to do with namespaces.
We haven't talked about it a lot.
We've touched on it a little bit.
You need to use this namespace cuz it
gives you access to particular classes or
methods.
I'm gonna throw it over to you Ben,
just to give us a deeper understanding of
namespaces, to demystify it a little bit.
In terms of-
&gt;&gt; What's going on, yeah, okay.
So it's just including
other people's code.
It's as easy as that.
So where you say using Namespace Unity
Engine, that gives you access to all sorts
of things like the concept of a mono
behavior, the concept of a game object, or
the concept of most of the stuff you type.
If you just comment out that
line using Unity Engine,
you'll soon see Visual Studio will show
you all the things it doesn't understand
if it doesn't have access
to that namespace.
So a namespace is a collection of classes.
It's a collection of things like your
rigid bodies and your sprites and
all the other stuff you've
been messing around with.
You can think of using namespace as a bit
like Dropbox and selective sync, for
instance.
So they're folders is one
way of looking at it.
It's like why do you use
folders on your computer?
Well, we have all our courses,
RPG and then Unity and then Unreal.
And in there we might
have the images folder.
Images, images, images again and again,
and we don't get a clash between Unity
images and Unreal images because
they're in different folders.
They are still images, but
they are in different folders.
So it let's you have two methods like
on collision enter in both the Unity
namespace and maybe somewhere else,
or Ran for Random.
It could be Unity's to random,
it would be Matheft.rand or
it could be unity.engine.random,
for example.
So it allows you to use the same name
in multiple places like folders do.
It also allows you to selective
sync in Dropbox terms.
Which is to say I only want
this library available.
This Unity engine library,
this maths library, this whatever,
I don't need the rest of it.
And the third thing it does is segregate,
conceptually, these different things.
So in the RPG course,
a more advanced Unity course that we have,
we focus on using namespaces ourselves.
We create our own name spaces like
combat and weapons and stuff like that.
So the one piece of our code cannot
accidentally talk to another bit without
us talking about it carefully first.
We can't just have a player talking to
the camera, for example, or talking to
some other part of the game unless we say
using namespace RBG.camera or RBG.player.
So three things in recap.
Number one, we actually rename
class names, and method names.
It allows you to selectively choose what
you're gonna import and what you're not,
import other people's libraries.
And number three, as I just said,
it allows you to purposefully
segregate your code.
&gt;&gt; So [COUGH] most of the namespaces
we're using in Unity or
most of the content from those
extra namespaces we go to.
Every now and again we'll go to
the scene management namespace or
the UI namespace, that was all created
by the good folks at Unity, yes?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; That's the Unity namespace,
their particular classes and methods.
That's not C#.
So if we're out of Unity and
we're into just working straight up in C#,
in another area or not in an engine,
how do we know then what it is that
we'll still be able to use that's not-
&gt;&gt; We'll just comment out using anything
that starts using Unity Engine or
using Unity Engine dot,
by the way dot is just a sub-folder.
So using Unity Engine
gives you the top level,
the root of the Unity Engine folder,
if you like.
Using unityengine.ui uses stuff
in the UI folder and so on.
it doesn't recurse down.
So using Unity Engine doesn't
pick up UI that's underneath it,
you have to explicitly use each one.
If you do a double forward slash,
a comment in front of everything
that starts using unityengine,
then the code that won't run is the stuff
that's using Unity Engine stuff.
Using system.collections or
system that you'll see at the top as well,
that is C# stuff, so.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and within the namespaces,
would you say that it's classes and
methods and parameters like this is what
is contained within those namespaces?
&gt;&gt; Yeah so-
&gt;&gt; Is there anything that we haven't,
any kind of magical tools in a namespace,
that we haven't seen?
&gt;&gt; I'm gonna grab a book,
give me a second we might cut this,
we can cut this bit out-
&gt;&gt; I don't think we will cut this.
I think we'll leave it in and people
will be wondering, where's Ben going?
Well, he's saw a squirrel.
He's off having a look at it,
there's a pretty squirrel.
&gt;&gt; Wandered off, I've actually
got the answer right here just to
be slightly more complete with it.
About what else can be in a namespace.
I think we are gonna need
to cut this down, Rick.
&gt;&gt; Okay, can do.
&gt;&gt; It's basically all
just type declarations.
So have they done enums and
structs and stuff yet?
Not structs, enums?
&gt;&gt; No.
&gt;&gt; Haven't even done enums.
&gt;&gt; No, not in Techs 101,
I guess they haven't.
Okay, so we're just going to this.
So, the other things that can be in
namespaces, it's mainly classes.
You could also have in there
things like enums and structs, but
we haven't met those yet in the course.
So for these purposes, for
this stage, it's a way of grouping
classes together and-
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; The thing that you need to
think about is if for instance,
you get to a point in the course where you
wanna access a text element, like text or
type Text with at capital T.
That is in the unityengine.ui namespace,
for example.
So you need to have that
namespace imported for
you to even be able to
recognize the type text.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, and what I've seen a lot
of is that it avoids us having conflict.
And you said this in the point
that you were saying before.
If we say we're only able to
use these particular things,
then we know those things
work well together.
And we're not accidentally using something
else or conflicting with something else.
So it's flicking the switch.
And there's I don't know how many
namespaces, I haven't looked into this.
Would there be dozens,
hundreds of namespaces in Unity?
Like, lots and lots of them?
&gt;&gt; Of the order of 100,
yeah, more than dozens.
&gt;&gt; Okay, more than dozens,
in the order of 100.
And within each of those, there's
anywhere from a handful to dozens and
dozens of classes and
methods within each of those namespaces.
So there's a lot of content,
and it'll be a little bit of
drinking from the firehose, I think, if
we can access all of those straightaway.
&gt;&gt; Absolutely.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Awesome.
&gt;&gt; Cool, cool, all right, excellent.
Just one last one on that,
you mentioned the word libraries.
I've seen online people talking about
what's the difference between a namespace
and library?
Conceptually, they seem pretty similar.
Is there anything we need to know at this
stage about namespaces versus libraries,
or is that not really important?
&gt;&gt; Not really at this stage, no,
I wouldn't get confused about it.
A library is something where you're
using somebody else's code and
you're calling out to that code.
They're often namespace,
they're independent concepts really.
But you can namespace within a library.
You can have multiple
namespaces in one library.
You could potentially have multiple
libraries all under the same namespace or
sharing a namespace.
So they're not necessarily related.
Namespacing is about folders and
libraries going in, but
getting a whole new program installed on
your machine that you could get access to.
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; Yeah, we're just using built-in
libraries in Unity for the moment.
&gt;&gt; Fantastic, cool, thanks for that Ben,
thanks for your expert wisdom insights,
appreciate it.
&gt;&gt; No worries.
&gt;&gt; And that's good, I think,
for this instructor hangout.
Anything else from you?
&gt;&gt; Nope, that's it, enjoy the course guys,
hope you're enjoying Rick's instruction,
and I'll see you in the next one.