[MUSIC]
Hey, hey in this video, we're gonna be
creating a simple defender that has some
animation and
maybe changes color a little bit.
And an animation event that says,
this is the point where we want it to
shoot out some sort of projectile.
So that in upcoming videos, we can have
our defenders actually do defending.
So let's jump in and
set up a simple defender prefab.
A quick tidy up,
I'm gonna creat a empty game object.
An empty game object to use better
grammar and I'll call this Sporners.
Reset the transform of that and then just
place my five Sporners underneath that.
So just tidy it up a little bit,
there we go.
Lovely and my trophy.
Have we prefabbed the trophy?
Yes, we have.
So I just removed the trophy
from the scene for now.
Well, actually, nope,
I'm going to leave it there.
So we keep it tidy and we don't
have things getting in the way, but
it's sometimes good to have a visual
representation in a point of comparison.
So let's leave it in there, okay?
So what we need to do is start
off with a big old challenge,
cuz I think you're ready to
take on all these aspects.
That's creating a defender,
the animations and animated controller.
So slice up the sprite sheet,
what I'm gonna do is choose.
Let me see, so
we do this together from my not in use.
I'm gonna create cactus.
So let me just create a new folder here.
Cache, cache does.
Okay and then from my not in use,
I'm gonna grab cactus distitle and
cactus dislooping and
drag this in to cache this.
Okay, so slice u your sprite sheet,
the one that I was selecting they are not
the ones and create an idle animation
from the idle animation sprite sheet and
create an attack animation from
the attack animation sprite sheet.
And then to add an animation event when
you feel that the defender should shoot
a projectile at that to the attack
animation, an animation event and
then to create an animated controller
where we start off in idle animation and
then just go straight into attack.
So at the moment we won't have any sort of
trigger to say to go from idle to attack,
but we'll have our shape set up,
so we're ready for that.
So it's a pretty meaty challenge, jump in.
Take that on, I'll see you back
here when you've got that done or
you can do it at the same time.
I'm doing it just now,
if you'd like to do that.
Okay, let's see.
So we've got our idle and
I'm going to slice it up.
Change my sprite mode to multiple,
click on Apply.
Now let's have a look at this.
Cactus Idle and
take note it's 924 by 1008.
Get out my calculator, Calculator,
cuz I'm gonna slice by grid.
This will be not, how many have we got?
One, two, three, four, five, six.
So 942 divided by 6 equals 157.
I'm gonna write that down
on my bit of paper here and
then 108 divided by 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
7, 8, 1008 divided by 8 is 126.
Now, we go into sprite editor.
Go up to slice,
change this to grid by cell size and
we'll change this to 157 by 126.
I've done this before, so
it should be pretty familiar.
That's all looking pretty good with
just a little bit of a cycle through.
Yeah, that looks good.
Okay, it's all looking pretty good.
Nothing's been chopped off
at all looks in a good spot.
Okay, then click on Apply.
Nice, close that out for now.
We have our sprite sheet sliced up.
I'll go and slice up the other one for
now while I'm here.
The cactus looping,
otherwise known as the Cactus Attack.
Sounds like a bad movie, doesn't it?
Multiple, [LAUGH] click Apply.
Click on the sprite editor.
This is different again, okay.
Let me find the cactus looping,
the dimensions here.
So left to right, we've got one,
two, three, four, five, six.
This has got a lot of images on it,
hasn't it?
So this is 942 that I'm getting from
down here in the dimensions divided by 6.
That's 157 again.
Okay, that makes it easy and
then it is 1638.
I think this is gonna be exactly the same.
1638 divided by 1, 2, 3, 4, 5,
6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 126.
Yes, it is exactly the same.
Okay, great.
157, 126, slice that up.
It all looks pretty good.
Click on Apply and job is done, fantastic.
Did you play the old Warcraft
games way back in the day?
Warcraft II, job's done.
That's how the peasant used to say
that they'd finished their job.
That's what I thought of just now and
I'm saying job done.
Okay, Cactus Idle,
highlight all of the Idle frames,
right-click, create animation.
There it is.
Animation, we'll call this Cactus Idle.
Drag my Cactus Idle animation
to my animation folder.
Now we will create our next animation
which will be cactus looping,
highlight all of these frames.
There's ton of them, 63 and
then create animation and
we'll call this Cactus Attack,
Cactus Attack.
There we go, drop that into
the animation folder as well.
Soon, we'll need to organize this.
Actually, it's getting pretty close.
I'm gonna organize this into attackers and
defenders, so create a new folder.
Attackers and
then another folder, defenders.
And then the cactus
goes into attackers and
the lizard goes into, sorry attacks.
God, I've got everything wrong here.
It's attackers.
Rick, you dingbat and then we need to,
did I just put them in there?
Okay, so the cactus is a defender.
Thank you for
those of you yelling at the screen.
Rick, what are you doing?
And then we have the trophy,
which technically is a defender.
It's one of the goodies.
Okay, here we go.
Now that we've done that,
let's while we're here,
let's just quickly create
our animated controller.
So right-click,
Create &gt; Animator Controller that
we'll call cactus and
then click on the animator window.
This should be the animator controller for
the cactus.
Yes, it looks like it indeed.
Excellent, what do we need to do next?
Well, we need to create a game object.
I didn't have that on my list, hopefully
you figured that out and found it.
So right-click,
create empty this will be called cactus.
Reset the transform back down to zero,
zero.
We need to give this a sprite render, so
we can see what it looks like and
see where it is in the game.
Now pick one of our frames, so
go to cactus for the sprites.
Which one do we wanna have represent
just how the cactus looks normally?
Cactus one just fine and dandy, and
we will drag Cactus Looping_1over
onto our sprite.
There we go.
Now change the border to five,
that's all the same.
Great, that looks pretty good.
Moving on to the thing might be a tiny bit
too big, but I'll leave it big for now.
You can have a little bit of overlap,
perhaps and see how that goes.
You can change that pretty easily later on
just by changing out pixels per unit in
our spreadsheet.
So here we go.
We've got a cactus on the screen.
We've got some animations.
Let's go back to our animated
controller in defenders.
Okay, got cactus here.
Cactus dragging, our cactus first of all,
dragging the idle, Cactus Idle.
Blink, that creates that as it's
first step and then Cactus Attack.
We'll do the same as we did before where
we say, right-click from Cactus Idle,
make transition into Cactus Attack.
At the moment there's no condition for
when it should go into there,
it'll just go straight in there after
it finishes doing its Cactus Idle.
Have a look at the transition and
just clean that up a little bit.
I like to have a 0 transition for
these 2D assets.
Get that out of the way, that's pretty
good and then the exit time of one.
Great, great stuff.
Okay, Cactus Idle, let's make sure
it is not looping in our animation.
Yep, that's correct and
then cactus attack.
We'll leave that looping,
I think and loop that.
Okay, that should be all pretty good.
Last bit here is we need to say that
we need an animator on our cactus.
Animator and
then what's our animator controller?
Click on selector, it will be the cactus.
Now all going to plan, that should animate
our cactus that goes from idle And
the idle and
the attack are pretty similar.
Well, that's very slow.
And then [SOUND] okay, so again,
I wanna speed that up a whole bunch.
Let's go and have a look at that.
Cactus Idle for the moment for
animation is 12 frames per second and
we've got tons, and tons of frames.
Okay, so let us change that to,
make it 24 like our other ones and
then the cactus attack.
We'll make that 24 as well
just have a look at that.
Make sure it's all looking nice and
neat, and tidy.
So bounce, bounce, a little bit of bounce.
And then now I'm gonna shoot.
Okay, that's looking pretty good and
then it loops around.
What I'll do in here just add one
little bit of flair into our attack,
if I can get this happening is if I click
on the cactus attack animation which I am.
I'm gonna click on Record.
It's not letting me do that,
because I need to click on my cactus, and
now it should let me record.
Yes, click on Record.
Move it to where I think it should shoot.
Sorry, I'm on idle at the moment just
change the selection here to attack.
Now, click on Record and
move it up to, maybe it's gonna go.
[SOUND] Okay, [SOUND] so
the animation's not really made for
shooting bullets, but maybe just as
it opens its mouth wide up there.
So what I'll do is I'll add
an animation even in a moment.
Actually, I'll do that right now
just click my animation event.
We'll come back to that in a moment.
What I'm gonna do in here is just change
the color of my sprite renderer on
the cactus.
So we will have it build up
to some sort of bright color.
Watch we have it build up to a red.
It's gonna be a little bit ugly,
my friends, but that's okay.
Maybe build up to a bright green and then
I'm going to move back a little bit here.
So we've got a key frame and then move
back to here a little bit on my selection,
and put that back to normal white.
So then, turn off my record mode.
It should go normal, normal, normal and
then bright green and then blunk.
Okay, it stayed on bright green.
So I wanna have it after it shoots.
I wanna have it go back to being white
again or no tinting as the case might be.
Okay, so I'll click on Play,
see how this looks.
[SOUND] And then building up and
then down, building up and down.
So you could put a little bit of a flash
at the end there just as it shoots.
It could be yellow, for example.
But this is gonna give the player
a little bit of visual flair.
So there's a lot more you can do for
color.
I think this is pretty interesting
white add some depth to this bright.
So we've got, now we have our animation
event and I believe that's looking
a littler bit different as were expecting
as we don't have any script on our cactus.
And a defender script as we have with our
lizard, we've got another script on there.
So it's looking a little bit different,
our animation event.
So we'll leave it for now.
We've got everything setup
that we wanted to setup.
This was just a quick little video to say,
let's get our.
Defender ready and raring.
We've out or event in there.
That's the point where we want
to say this is where you shoot.
Okay, that's looking pretty good.
We've got our defender.
Last step of prefabbing that, so
drag our cactus down into your prefabs.
We'll do a little bit more
work on the cactus, so
I'll leave it up here in our hierarchy.
Good stuff, so we're ready to create some
functionality where the cactus will shoot
and be damaged and
have health all of those things.
So great work and
I'll see you in the next video.