[MUSIC]
In this video we're making our character
jump and fall with a little bit more
velocity so that he can get back
up again when he falls down.
And we're gonna play around with
the tuning of the jump speed and
of the gravity.
So let's jump in and get started.
As a reminder of what's going
on with our player here,
I'm going to add a line in my run
method that is print playerVelocity.
So that we can print out on the screen
exactly what's happening with
the playerVelocity,
which is going to be a vector two.
So it'll have two numbers in there,
something comma something,
the first something is an X and
the second something is a Y.
And you can see as it starts off
at 00 I'm standing still, 00.
And then my velocity,
when I push left, becomes -50.
My velocity when I push right becomes 50.
Because we've got a very high
sensitivity on our X throw, on our key.
So I'm push it down,
there's not a lot of ramp up or ramp down,
it's happening pretty quickly.
You can see that it goes from 0 to 5 and
5 back to 0 pretty fast.
So, from a logic point of view
what we're trying to do with jump,
I'm just gonna click on my pin tool here.
What we're trying to do
with jump is take this 00,
the something ,0 that
the player will have.
The something is the X so
X zero and we want to add a value
to the Y velocity, so
the Y Vector2 velocity here.
So that immediately, the player
goes from having no Y velocity to
a something Y velocity, for example, to 5.
And then because we're using a dynamic,
rigid body we're allowing
the physics engine to apply gravity,
the force of gravity is constantly
applying down on the player.
Until they are touching the collider, in
which case they can't go down any further.
That downwards force,
obviously known as gravity,
is going to immediately be
reducing this 5 down to a 4, 3,
2, 1, and all the steps in
between with the decimal places.
So, once it gets to 0 that
should be at the top,
the peak of our jump up here is
0 in terms of the Y velocity.
So y = 0 at the top,
not going up and not going down.
And then we start to head back down
into the minuses, -1, -1.1, and so on.
And then eventually, we hit the ground and
we stop moving, and Y returns back to 0.
[COUGH] So what we're trying to do
in this particular lecture is apply
this upwards velocity to the player,
push them up in the air.
And then we'll get a little bit more
complicated in upcoming videos in
terms of when you're allowed to jump and
how that works.
So that's the logic we're gonna
go through here at the moment.
So we'll hop over into our Player
script here, what do we need to do?
Well first of all we need to
create ourselves a jump method.
I'll put this underneath run, just tidy
up a little bit of my white space here.
So we're gonna create
ourselves private void Jump().
And then what do we need to do in here?
Well we need to get some sort of input,
some sort of command.
We're gonna use our
CrossPlatformInput Manager, and
the reason we're doing this is so that if
we want to make this game for mobile or
for Xbox or for PC we can,
using the CrossPlatformInputManager.
Similar to what we set
out with argonne assault.
So rather than having a control throw,
which is setting ourselves up.
If the player runs we say well maybe
the player wants to walk and therefore we
wanna give this ability by using this
access that they can have a little bit of
pressure on the joy pad or they can tilt
their phone a little bit to the side.
That's why we're using this access.
But when it comes to Jump,
that's either you jump or you do not.
You can't jump a little
bit in our current design.
We're not saying slowly ramp up to jump.
It's just jump right now in
the way that we execute this.
So rather than looking to
create a control throw,
we're just gonna have a button down.
So, if CrossPlatformInputManager.,
we'll use GetButtonDown, so GetButtonDown.
Because this is a one time thing,
we're not interested in whether
they're hoarding it down or not.
And then the key we will
use to define that is Jump.
And I broke the rule [LAUGH] I talked
about it in the last video in terms of
going and getting that.
I think Jump is pretty easy
to spell correctly but
let's quickly hop over here and
make Ben very happy.
We're gonna go over to
Project Settings &gt; Input,
we will find on the vertical axis here
there's vertical, there's also a jump.
Which is what we're looking for and
you can see the name of jump is Jump.
We're gonna copy that at the moment
the button on the keyboard is space.
So we're gonna copy Jump,
come back into here and paste it in there.
There we go, it's exactly the same but
that is the right process to go through
because if we mess that up sometimes we
have no idea what has gone
wrong if we've messed that up.
Okay, so Jump,
we don't need that semicolon on the end.
And then, what are we doing?
If we're pressing down on the jump key,
well, first of all,
we need to give ourselves
a new Y velocity.
So Vector2,
we'll call it jumpVelocityToAdd.
So we're going from 0 on the Y, and
then we're gonna suddenly say
now add 5 to your Y velocity.
That = a new Vector2, and we don't
need to add anything to the X axis,
we're gonna keep that the same,
to the X velocity there.
But we need to add something in here.
Something, what should
we call our something?
We'll call it jumpSpeed,
which we haven't defined yet.
So we don't have a jump speed,
we'll go out and grab that now.
So copy jumpSpeed, head on up to
the top under our config here,
well SerializeField.
We need to create a float,
which is called jumpSpeed, and
we'll start that off at 5 as well,
5f cuz it is a float.
Now back down into our jump method.
So just as we did up here with
run we need myRigidBody.velocity.
And then we are going to have
that += jumpVelocityToAdd.
So it's the same as itself
plus jumpVelocity as well
when this jump key is pressed.
Let's save that,
hop back over into our scene.
Hit Play, hit Play again and
then jump, nothing happens.
Why is that?
Here's a micro-challenge for you and
it's not dissimilar to the [LAUGH]
micro-challenge when we're creating run.
We need to add this into our update.
Jump(); then back into our build,
back into our scene, and
what happens here when we push space?
We do a nice floaty jump,
floaty mc jump jump.
[NOISE] And
you can see him floating a long way.
So this is a good starting point.
This is excellent, we're moving up and
then we're floating back down.
And you can see in our
velocity over here when I push
up it reaches around about
just under five it looks.
And then floats back down using gravity.
So what we need to do next, you can see
if we jump out of that jump out of play.
Hop over into Edit, Project Settings and
Physics 2D we need to have a look at
what's going on with our gravity.
So you can see here right at
top we have a gravity setting.
And with the gravity setting and
when your player's Y velocity, it's the
perfect time for us to have a challenge.
The challenge is to tune your jump.
So use gravity and jump speed to tune
your jump so that it feels good for you.
So this is a little bit more of
flexing your game designer muscles.
I want you to decide how many tiles you
want your player to be able to jump up.
And, I know it's early days,
we can change this for sure.
You can have them jump higher or lower
later on, but this is the first point.
Do you want your player to be
able to jump up, for example,
three tiles as I've got here, or two
tiles as I've got here, or only one tile?
This is part of the reason that I set
up this little level the way I have,
to make sure that I've got a one and
a three or maybe it's four or
maybe it's seventeen tiles.
So when I say tiles I mean these blocks,
the tiles that we've added
into our tile map here.
So how high do you want
your player to jump?
That's a starting point, and then also
decide how far you're okay with your
player floating horizontally when jumping.
So at the moment my player
floats a long way when we jump,
which I'm not happy with.
Whoops, I'm gonna start again,
cuz [LAUGH] I wanna be able
to jump back up that ledge.
He fell down.
This time it'll be a little bit
more smooth, so just to there.
Currently, my player can jump,
whoa, quite a distance.
[NOISE] Nearly that whole way across,
which is way to much.
I don't want the player to be able
to do these massive jumps like that,
that's too far.
So, for you,
how far do you want your player to jump?
How quickly do you want them
to drop with the gravity?
And how many tiles up do
you want them to jump up?
So pause the video and
tune you're jumping now.
Okay, welcome back,
I hope you have your game feeling good.
This is the part where your game actually
starts to feel like a game cuz having your
character just bounce
around should be enjoyable.
For me when I go into gravity,
Project Settings, Physics 2D,
I'm gonna put the gravity
up pretty agressive.
I'm gonna put mine up to 100 so
that when I fall off this ledge
I really fall off the ledge.
I want my game to feel zippy, so
blunk, down like that, blunk.
I think that feels pretty good.
This is excellent if you've got
this collision problem we'll
get to that in just a moment
after we've tuned our jump.
So I've got this good falling that I like,
pretty strong gravity.
If I jump now, blup, blup, blup, doesn't
really get off the ground, kind of an old
man, a little bit how I feel a lot
of the days when I'm trying to jump.
But let's make him
a little bit more agile.
Let's make him like Rick in his 20s
rather than like Rick in his 40s.
Jump speed here,
I'm going to put my jump speed up.
I've played around with this a little bit
already, I tried to start off with 10,
then I went to 15, I found that 28 is
a pretty good [LAUGH] jump speed for
my character.
Let's just have a look at that because
bloink, bloink, up and down pretty quick.
I like that pace,
if we do the how far can you jump test,
I'm gonna make my speed
a little bit faster.
I think how fast he can run horizontally,
but I'll get to that a bit later on yet,
and you can see jumping about halfway
up so three and a half tiles.
You don't wanna have it exactly
on three it's a bit hard
to get up on to the next level.
But that's enough to have my player
jump up three levels pretty comfortably.
Cool, we've had that happen twice now, so
let's go on and
figure out what's going on there.
If you have a look at your character,
your character has some
collision information on it.
Captural collider, rigid 2D,
we have a look at our tilemap,
we've got our foreground has collision on
it in terms of our Composite Collider.
Sort of a little of a mini challenge for
you, if you wanna go dig around and
see if you can figure out what's going on.
Why do you think our player is
falling through the cracks like that?
Why is he falling through the world?
We don't have little cracks in our tile,
cuz in our collision we've go in and
changed that but why do you think that is?
Well, it's a little bit of a tricky
question, you'd need to go and
search through the docs a little bit.
But unity docs you'll
see Collision Detection,
we have the option of Discrete and
Continuous.
And I've given you a link in
the resources, against this lecture,
in terms of the difference
between the two.
Basically you use discreet
if your character or
if your units are moving quite slowly and
collision is happening quite easily.
If you've got things
that are moving quickly,
you need to have continuous
collision detection so
that it doesn't accidentally fall through
the cracks like was happening there.
Continuous is a bit more expensive, so
that's the reason that
discreet is an option.
So now, if we click Play we have should
have it that our character can jump down
here, and this has been the problem area.
Yep, no problem, so sometimes, if you're
moving too fast then that very initial,
this capsule collider touching
this collision doesn't happen,
cuz we're moving too fast,
it doesn't happen in the particular frame.
So therefore we need to switch to
continuous collision detection.
I'm just gonna remove my print statement I
added in there so I don't forget later on.
Remove that, and there is our run, sorry,
running and our jumping, and
our flipping, we now have in our game.
Well done,
I will see you in the next video.