[MUSIC]
You will have spotted the problem we have
in our game at the moment that I jump,
that our player can jump,
and jump, and jump, and
go flailing way off into the screen,
and then return again eventually.
In this video, we're gonna resolve that
by having that the player can only jump
when he is touching the ground, when
he's touching this foreground tilemap.
The way we're gonna do
that is using layers.
So up here in layers,
we kinda have everything on default,
but we're gonna do that by setting up
a different layer for the foreground.
Just a little bit on that,
layers are useful if we have the same
functionality across multiple GameObjects.
For example, you see this a lot when you
want to have a whole bunch of things
ignored by the camera.
So in other words, not displayed on the
screen, or you wanna have them clickable,
or, as we're doing, as a collision check.
So if we go into our foreground
tilemap here and change the layer,
we can scroll down to Add Layer, and we've
already had a look at the sorting layers,
which is to show what is displayed
first and second on top of each other.
And then we go to User Layer 8,
and add in here Ground, so
we now have this option
of a layer called Ground.
Go back to Foreground,
and change that to Ground.
So now, anything on this layer has
been designated as layer, Ground.
Why do we have layers and tags?
Well, it's just an extra layer
of organization, pardon the pun.
It's an extra step of organization, so
that we can have a whole
bunch of things on ground.
And then,
also if we wanted to tag particular things
that are within ground or
on different layers, but
we still wanted to access them
then we can use tags as well.
In this section we're not touching tags at
all, we're just having a look at layers.
An illustrated common use of layers, if we
click on the main camera, you can see here
a culling mask, where we say it's
currently saying everything is visible.
If we click off, so if we turn off ground,
then in our camera here, or
if I click play, we can see that
the mask has been applied to ground and
we can't see the ground.
That's why we can access that in code and
turn things on and off.
Hollistically, this entire
layer we can turn on and
off if that was something that
was useful for our gameplay.
Let's go back and undo that,
turn the ground back on so
we can see it in our camera preview there.
The way we're gonna do
this is to stop jumping
anytime by using
Collider2D.IsTouchingLayers.
I've given you, in the resources,
a couple of docs to have a look at.
They're not super detailed but
first one is Collider2D.isTouchingLayers.
This will return true or false whether
the collider is touching any collider
on the specified layermask or not.
What do we mean by the layermask?
Well, within here,
within Collider2D.IsTouchingLayers,
we pass in LayerMask.GetMask.
So goes in, gets a mask or
gets the mask for the particular layer or
layers that we're interested in.
And in our instance, the layer or
layers, just a layer
at this point is the, if we've got
a foreground, is the ground layer.
And all of the logic for
using the GetMask approach for using this
over here, for using Layermask.GetMask,
is this is a very performant way of doing
this collision check across all of
these different assets that we've got.
So it brings us to a challenge, and
the challenge is stop your
player multi-jumping.
Finish the logic to stop
your player multi-jumping.
You will need to use,
and here are the clues.
Collider2D.IsTouchingLayers, and
you guessed it LayerMask.GetMask and
you need to feed in the layer
that we've been talking about.
You need to pass that
into LayerMask.GetMask.
Also you'll need to use an if statement.
You'll need to be in the player.cs script.
That should be enough clues to go on for
now.
If you're not sure about that, no problem.
I'll see you in a moment.
Okay, welcome back.
We're gonna jump over
into our player script.
First of all, I need to create
a reference to Collider2D.
I'm gonna call this myCollider,
could call it myCollider2D.
Yeah, why not?, myCollider2D.
And then, next we need to get that
component, so myCollider2D = GetComponent.
And now use of type Collider2D,
not at sign 2D but just plain old 2D.
Okay, that looks pretty spiffy there.
And then down to the one line
that I was mentioning before,
where do we need to put that?
Well we need to put it into Jump,
cuz Jump is the time when we're saying,
should this or should this not happen.
We're looking for an if statement in here,
if what's happening.
Or first of all, it's good for
us to say, if, the condition is not met,
then don't let the player jump.
So rather than saying if
the condition is met, then jump.
Otherwise, don't let the player jump,
it reads a lot neater and is a lot more
effective if we say right at the start,
if a particular thing is not happening.
So what's not happening?
My collider 2D is touching layers.
And then we need to pass into
that LayerMask.GetMask().
Then what is our layer called?
Well, because we are good units,
we're going to jump over here,
go over into our Add Layer, double-click,
Copy, so get it 1000% correct.
Pasting ground and then, that saying,
if we are not colliding,
then what would we wanna do,
well we want to return.
We can do that one of two ways.
We can do it the longer way and
say, return.
Or to make the whole thing
a little bit neater,
we can put this all on one line instead
of maximize our readability here.
We have return on the same line.
Okay, so if we are not colliding with
ground then allow the player to jump.
Let's save that.
Hop back over into our scene.
Okay, let's mash the space bar.
Okay, and the player is only jumping once.
Which was our design, just a single jump,
when the player is touching the ground.
Great work.
So
you've set up single jumping in your game.
You've implemented layers,
added it to your foreground.
So that we've got a content of a ground
layer that the play can only jump
if they are touching layers, is touching
layers, you've implemented as well as
the GetMask approach for saying if
the player is touching that ground layer.
So we're done,
I will see you in the next video.