[MUSIC]
Okay, let's have a quick conversation
about the game design for Glitch Garden so
we know exactly so we know exactly
what it is that we're doing.
You can see as always I love to have
a Gameplay Screen for my game design.
You have a massive document,
but a picture tells 1000 words.
So what's going on here we've
got attackers spawning and
moving along a line,
we've got 1, 2, 3, 4, 5 lines.
They start off off screen and
then, [SOUND] get down to here and
then we'll have some sort
of volume down the end.
When the attacker touches the volume,
then it triggers some sort of,
either you could decrease points
if you want to do it that way.
For me, I'm gonna do it when any
attacker gets down to the end,
[NOISE] it's It's game over.
Okay, so we've got our attackers.
We also need to have defenders, and
we buy and place the defenders.
Now, we need to have our
defenders fitting within our grid.
That's why our grass has these grid lines
here to say this is where a defender can
or cannot go.
I haven't marked it on here, but
I think I'll have a dead space up the end.
So you can't just go and put your
defenders right at every start and
block the start,
that will be a little bit too dominant.
So you can only fill out from this point
onwards with your defenders in that
area there.
Okay, and we need a way of clicking
a button that says I want to place this
defender and it's clearly highlighted.
You can place it down on the grid, and
you can also click on the other
spot to get a different defender.
We need at the top of our game,
you can yours down the bottom.
If you wanna put your user
interface down the bottom,
you can shuffle it around
however you like, but
I wanna make sure I've got space for
at least half a dozen defenders.
And it looks like there's space
up the top here to do that,
we also need to indicate
our resource system.
So, we need a resource system that
allows us to earn and to spend points.
So this is a currency, this is a resource,
this is, you know what, they see this as
well, I know some people have been asking
for how do I implement a shop mechanic?
In many ways, this is a shop mechanic
because you're getting points or
this could be coins, it could be dollars,
or it could be wagers or whatever.
And then you spend it on particular things
which will decrease the amount of points
that the player has.access to.
So this is a little bit of a shop in
a way and in a tower defense game,
you know how it works.
You have certain number of points and
then each of these things cost
a certain amount of points.
And also, we need defenders which
can generate points in our game.
So we've got this star kind of trophy
dude here, and after a certain amount of
time that we will need to be
able to tune the amount of time,
it generates a new star, and that star
gives us extra points to our score.
Not to our score, sorry, to our resources.
That's not our score,
it's our resources, Rick, dunderhead!
Okay, so here are the different enemies,
and for different enemies,
not just that they look different,
but they have different behaviors.
I've called out the fox here,
in the previous video.
I was mentioning that when
a fox comes up to a gravestone,
it can jump over it and keep running.
So we'll need to tune the fox so
it's fast, and nimble,
can jump over these blocking defender
things, but probably doesn't have as many
hit points as the big old chunky lizard,
which will get blocked by this guy.
He's gonna get blocked by the gravestone
and sit there and munch on it for
a while while the cactus can shoot at him,
but he's probably got more hit points, and
he's more solid.
So thinking about enemy archetypes,
big and chunky and slow, fast and nimble.
And then also we're gonna
have a level timer.
This will be the main mechanics for
completing the level.
Is that, we will spawn enemies,
spawn enemies, spawn enemies.
Then we now code to say,
when our level timer reaches the end for
whatever you've tuned it to.
That is when we stop spawning out enemies,
and then when the last enemy is killed,
that is when we can
progress to the next level.
Speaking of the next level,
we need a Quit button here.
Well, it's not actually a next level,
it's taking you back to the start menu.
And that's so that we've got a system
that's not relying on someone pushing for
example the Esc key.
We've got something on
the screen that says stop,
take me back to the start of the game.
Or you could fashion into to
pause menu if you wanted,
if you wanna have that
sort of functionality.
You probably won't have a pause menu
in this section of the course, but
we're definitely willing other
sections of the course, but for now,
I think this'll just take
you back to the start.
Okay, and
a quick recap of our core game design.
Player experience, always, always,
know your player experience, or
else you end up with just a mushy,
random sort of game.
Strategic thinking, it's a tower defense
game, so we want strategic thinking.
Where do I place them, and
how many points do I use?
Our core mechanic is place
defenders to stop attackers.
The Theme is a Garden kind of theme,
animals and plants and stuff.
Kind of like Plants vs Zombies but
without the zombies.
So therefore, we're taking inspiration but
we're not doing exactly the same as that.
And our cool game loop, kill all the
attackers to progress to the next level.
And I always point this out when
we go through the screen here,
is it's a little bit duh,
that's all obvious but it's very good
to write down these very obvious stuff and
then not deviate from it.
The temptation halfway through is to say,
instead of strategic thinking let's
make this about slow patience.
It's like, maybe, it's not quite the same.
So you wanna stick to these.
You wanna be very confident after you've
done your prototyping this is exactly what
I'm making.
These are the things that
you stick to religiously.
Okay, and again your challenge is to,
if you would like to use the assets
that I'm using, by all means, fantastic.
I will provide them to you.
You can you that, no problem,
if you want to flex your muscles
you can use your own assets.
If you are using your own you'll need
to come up with a background for
our battle to take place.
I've got my gardening kind of thing and
you should probably some
grids on that as well.
Some defenders with sprite
sheet animations, so
we've using sprite sheets for
our animation in this section.
And you'll need at least and
idle and an attack animation,
you could probably get away with just
I don't know, with just the idle or
just the attacker and just loop over and
over and pretend it's the same thing, but
it's good idle and
an attack to make it different.
And the attackers with sprite sheet
animation as well and a couple of my
attacker I'll be doing jump, sort of
just added there as an extra thing.
So there's your challenge from this
lecture, there's your challenge.
If you wanna go ahead and grab some assets
to have it look different to what I
have created or what we will create
together, the assets I'm providing you.
And this is a good time for those of
you who want to use this project for
a portfolio piece if you can make
it look a little bit different,
people won't recognize it as, yeah,
that's just the same out of that course.
You want it to look a little bit different
so that when it's in your portfolio people
say, this is interesting,
tell me about it.
So that's why I often challenge you at
the state of our section to say, hey,
maybe you can go get your own assets from
the assets store or make them yourself or
get a friend to help you make them.
Okay, so there it, let's jump in
in the next lecture get ourselves
up with our project and get cracking.