[MUSIC]
A quick note before we get started, I'm
moving in this section to Unity 2018.2.
If you don't have that already then you
can click on Official Releases in the hub
and find 2018.2 and download it.
You can tell which version we're
using in a section that's up at
the top of our slides here, Unity 2018.2.
And as I've said a couple of times in
the past, if you're watching this in
the future using 2018.3, or
2019, or 2020, no problem,
usually things are backwards compatible so
long you have at least 2018.2.
Don't try to this course with unity three,
I don't think it will go so well for you.
Okay let's jump and talk about the game
design very quickly cuz we've already
worked through the core mechanic
of this in a previous section.
But if you skip that section, here is
a reminder of the why the core mechanics
works, we ask the player to think of
a number between something and something,
for example, between 1 and 1,000.
Then we give them our guess, which is
basically saying, let's take the upper
level and the lower level and divide by 2,
which will guess right in the middle.
I'm gonna add a little bit more
sophistication in this section.
By adding some randomness to our guest,
we'll do that later on in this
section all going to plan.
And then we ask the player for
input, we show them our number,
we start with 500 and then we say, is it
high, is it low, or did we get it correct?
It's a good idea for
us to map out our game flow because we'll
have multiple screens, multiple scenes.
We start off with our start menu and
you can see I've got some funny images,
I'll explain that in a moment.
And then we go into our core game,
this is the higher, the lower, or
you've got it correct.
And then we go into our win screen,
once we click play again,
we will go back to the start menu.
So that's the game flow, it's good to
know how things are flowing in your game,
good to know what order things happen in.
Our core game design,
the player experience,
it's really simple little
game we're creating here but
it's always a good idea to think about
what's the experience we're creating.
We wanna create something that's joyful,
just fun, just a bit silly,
just I guess the thing.
And as you can see, I'm going with
some silly images here of myself and
Ben, just to spice that up.
The core mechanic is think of a number,
we've talked about that already.
The theme, a little bit silly,
as I've done here.
And then the core game loop,
we now already think of a number,
feedback higher and lower.
It's good to go through this exercise
even if it's really obvious what you're
creating, particularly to think
about what's the player experience.
Cuz if all we're doing is
presenting a tech demo to a player,
it's not gonna be that interesting.
If you're a technical person,
a programmer,
you just like getting into the nuts and
bolts of the code.
It's good to train a little bit of your
brain to be thinking of, what is joyful,
sorry what is the player experience, why
is my player going to enjoy this above and
beyond they can click a button?
Why are they clicking a button?
So this is practicing, in further
sectors we'll get deeper into this, and
it will be a lot more relevant, but
I just wanted to reinforce this step
of our game design at this point.
And your challenge in this lecture,
I want you to come up with a game theme,
think of a skin for your game, you can
see why I jump up a few slides here.
I've skinned it with Ben and
I with silly wizard hats on,
I'm going with this whole kind of wizard
approach fitting with the theme that we've
already determined in the past for
this game.
It's a wizard approach, so we're these
kind of weird looking wizards with our
Elton John got like sunglasses
on I don't know why.
Anyway, so I think of the skin for
your game, what is the tone for the voice?
So when you have the text on the screen,
is it saying I am the supreme
ruler guess the number.
Or is it something that's more in
a different character's voice.
So what's the tone of the voice?
What are the images you're gonna use and
what is the overall style?
And if you wanna have a look at
the different colors from our previous
section were we talked about colors,
that is all good as well.
And then please do share your ideas with
us if you've got something that you think
is a bit nifty.
If your scratching your head and saying
well I kind of don't really know yet,
not a problem, we can implement some of
our game and then you can come up with
your skin and your tone and
your approach for it as we move forward.
Not a problem, or you can just use
my assets, that is fine as well.
Okay great stuff, let's jump into
the next video and start making our game.