Hello and welcome.
I'm really excited for us to start getting
our hands dirty with our C# coding.
In this video we are going to
create four simple statements
that print out to
the console using debug.log.
Let's jump in and get started.
Okay, let's start by creating
ourselves a new project.
You can see from Unity Hub,
we click on the New button.
As we did previously, and we will name
our project NumberWizard Console.
NumberWizard Console,
Because we are creating
a small little game called NumberWizard
and we're focusing just on the console.
In terms of location, we'll find our
repo's Unity 2D as we did in our
previous very quick project that
we set up in our intro setup.
And I've already created a NumberWizard
Console, if you haven't done that
create a new folder or
you can do right-click new folder.
Create a new folder.
Click on that once or double-click it,
either way works just fine.
And then select project.
Make sure the template is 2D and
then create project.
Wait for Unity to load up.
I might skip ahead of this so
you don't have to watch me loading Unity.
I will see you in a moment.
Okay, while Unity is still loading,
not a problem,
I'm going to tell you a little bit
about what we're doing with our game.
So here's the game flow for NumberWizard.
It's a very basic game where we start
off with asking the player to think
of a number between a minimum and
a maximum.
So for example between one and 1000.
We say think of a number and
then we give a guess to the player.
We say we think your number is this and
the way we come up with our number.
We're gonna program this together,
is taking the minimum and
adding the maximum and dividing by 2.
So if it's between 1 and 1,000 this will
give us 1,001 divided by 2 which is 500,
and if we round it down
then it becomes 500.
So that would be our guess.
And we ask the player,
Is your number higher the now
number lower the now number?
Sorry I should say lower than higher
than the now number, or is it correct?
And if the player says it's
correct then we start again.
Okay, think of a new number between 1 and
1000.
If the player inputs lower or higher,
then we have another guess and
we repeat this loop in here
until we get the correct number.
Let me show you that very briefly with
numbers in there, so Between 1 and 1000,
I guess is 500.
The player in this instance says,
no, it's lower.
And then we take the lower
portion of that.
So between 1 and 500, and
our guess becomes 250.
It's a very simple little
binary search mechanism.
But is pretty cool as outstanding project.
And now actions in this video will also
form your challenge in this particular
lecture is to print the following to
the console using your own words.
We're going to welcome the player.
We're gonna ask them to pick a number.
We're gonna say the highest
number you can choose is this and
the lowest you can choose is that.
So that's what we're gonna take on and
that's what you're going to be doing.
Pretty simple challenge
later on in this video.
So let's jump back over into Unity.
Hopefully it's loaded up for you now.
And you can see it's our default
layout as I've mentioned in
the intro section of the video.
If you're not seeing what I'm seeing,
come up to the top right, right here and
select default.
After you've done that we're
going to gravity console window.
Click on console and
have a look at it down there.
We've got a few buttons down here.
We don't need to worry about those at the
moment, we've got Clear, Collapse, etc.
For now, we need to have a quick
look over in the right here.
You can see there's three buttons here.
The first one is showing us any sort of
log that's going to print to our screen.
The next one is showing us the errors and
sorry, the warnings.
And the next one is showing as error,
so if you've turned them off,
you won't see anything
printed in the console.
If you have them turned on then you
will see those respective things,
so if you click it on and click all of
three of them on you'll see all of those.
Just a bit of a little bit of a gotcha,
if you find you're not seeing what
we are printing to the console,
there is a good chance that this
particular button has been switched off.
Now what I want you to do is
grab the console, left-click and
drag it up over into the right-hand side.
We'll put it up here so
that we've got more
vertical real estate where we can see what
is being printed out into our console.
We're mostly using it over here,
we're not gonna be using this
side of our screen just yet.
In the next section, we'll be digging into
Unity and looking at all the different
Windows and buttons and mechanism and
all the awesome stuff of Unity.
For now we are focusing just on the C#, so
we can get our hands dirty with coding.
So the next step is for us to create
a script if you come down to assets area
down here, right click,
create a C# script.
And before doing anything else, and
before clicking anywhere else, type in
NumberWizard, capital N, capital W,
no spaces in between that, whenever
we create a script there's no spaces.
Hit Enter,
then double click on your script,
that will open up Visual Studio And
we see all of the standard information
that Unity puts within a script as
a default when we first start a script.
What we're going to focus on is jumping
straight into the start method and
writing out content in here, we're
going to write some statements in here.
And our first statement
is going to be Debug.Log.
So follow along with me here,
capital D, Debug .Log, L-O-G, and
then open brackets,
put in the quotation marks and then we're
going to type something along the lines
of, ("Welcome to number wizard, yo").
[LAUGH] Maybe not the yo.
Yeah, we'll put the yo in there.
We'll pretend we're gangsta, even though
I'm totally as ungagster as you can get.
And then we need a semicolon down the end.
So here's our first statement.
We've written our statement here.
Now you might say if you went through our
intro section, which hopefully you did,
you might say well, didn't we do
exactly the same thing with print?
So print and
debug work pretty much the same way.
We could have written
print("Welcome to number wizard,
etc, wizard..." and so
on and then semicolon.
We could have done the same thing,
we're using Debug.log because
it gives us a little bit more flexibility
and control Later on in the course.
So for now, you don't need to understand
why we're using it instead of print.
We can use both of them.
If you jump around the Internet,
you'll see print a lot.
It's totally valid.
But for us, we're doing it the slightly
technically better more correct way so
that in the future we've got good habits.
And we know that debug.log
is going to work for
us in all the different situations where
we need it to work and that's why we're
using it now instead of print so type
in debug.log in the statement in here.
Save that and
then go back over into Unity.
The other step we need to do is
attach our script to a game object.
If you see sample scene up here, if you
open that up, we've got a main camera and
as we did in the intro, you can either
drag your script straight onto there or
when you've clicked on main camera,
come back over here to inspector.
So you've clicked on inspector and
drag your script over into the inspector,
which is the same thing as
dragging it over onto main camera.
You can see now that our sample scene
has a little asterisk next to it.
And we can go off and
say file, save scene.
We can also save scene as and
change the name of it.
So we might wanna change the name of
the scene to be NumberWizard, for
example, NumberWizard.
So we're calling out scene, NumberWizard,
you can see now that our whole scene
has been renamed NumberWizard.
And at the top here it'll say,
numberwizard.unity.
So not a big deal,
you can leave it as sample scene,
but sample just doesn't seem
what we're up to at the moment.
We're making a NumberWizard,
that's what we're doing.
Okay, now that we've saved that and we've
added our script to the main camera just
to have somewhere that we place it,
we can click on Play.
And make sure that you've
selected the console.
If you've still got the inspector
open you won't see this so
click on the console, and we can see
welcome to NumberWizard yo, excellent.
So now as I mentioned I've
got a challenge for you,
we can unclick play mode there, jump back
over to our script to see what we've got,
I've left a blinking cursor here because
what I'd like you to do is our challenge.
So I've written out a welcome,
write it in your own words.
Write another statement, which is about,
we would like you to pick a number.
So we're saying to the player,
pick a number.
And then another statement again which is
the highest number you can choose is, and
we'll say 1,000 for now.
And the lowest number is, and
we'll say one for the moment.
And the syntax that we're
using is Debug.Log("Thing
you want to say") and
make sure you put your ; on the end.
So you should end out
with four lines in here.
This first one and then another
three lines saying what we've,
Got here in terms of our challenge.
Okay, so that's the challenge.
Give that your best shot.
Pause the video now, and
I'll give you time to work on that.
When you come back,
we'll go through the solution together.
So this is a great time to pause.
Great time to do the challenge.
Great time to get your hands dirty and
I will see you in a moment.
Welcome back,
hopefully you went well with that.
Let me show you my approach
to working through this.
Let's start by typing Debug.Log,
what are we going to say next,
Pick a number, don't tell me what
it is...); and then Debug.Log.
The highest number you
can pick is 1000.
And Debug.Log, open brackets and
then quotation marks.
In here we are going to say the lowest
number you can pick is one.
Okay, and then semi colon on the end.
So we've now written four statements and
these four statements are living
inside our start method.
In the next few videos,
we're gonna talk a lot more about methods.
But for now we just need to know
that these are the statements, so
these are the individual directions
we're giving to the computer, to say,
I want you to do this and
then do this and then do this.
And the start method
here is like a recipe,
where the start method is saying here
are the four individual steps within my
recipe to make the thing happen
that we wanna have happen.
Now it's saved that, back over into Unity.
Click on play and you can see in
here welcome to number wizard.
Pick a number, highest number and
lowest number.
Excellent, so we've created the first
part, the structure for our game.
So we're giving our player the context
of this is what we want you to do.
And in our next video we'll be looking at
variables and how we can create a more for
flexible structure using those variables
as a way to store information.
So great work, you're doing really well,
I look forward to seeing
you in the next video.