Okay, so
quick video to address a couple of tweaks,
a couple of issues we have
with our ladder climbing.
First of all, as our player climbs,
if you exit while your still moving up,
then he stays in his running up the ladder
state and that's a bug we want to remove.
The other is that the player
slowly drifts back down to Earth,
which you might think that's cool,
that could be a good feature but...
For those of us wanting
to not make it a dance to
stay near the platform if
there's an enemy nearby.
We'll implement something just to stop
the players sliding back down the ladder.
Let's jump in and
have a look at how we're going to do that.
Jump over to the- saying jump a lot.
You know when you implement
a jump into your game,
then you just say jump, jump, jump, jump.
Okay, so let's hop over [LAUGH]
into our script, over here.
I've just noticed one thing,
my climb ladder,
you can see the order of my methods,
here, run, climb ladder, jump, and so on.
They are different in my updates,
so for those of you who are OCD,
you're probably yelling at the screen,
saying, that doesn't make sense.
So we'll say run, then climb ladder,
jump, foot's right,
doesn't make any difference whatsoever to
anything but the order of the universe has
now been restored, climb ladder is
in its appropriate spot, fantastic.
Let's have a look at climb ladder, we can
say, we see that if we are not touching
the climbing layer then return
otherwise do the stuff down here.
We've got our animation state has been
told to transition into climbing.
And we're not elegantly transitioning
back away from climbing again,
because we can get stuck
in that particular state.
So right at the top here we're gonna
implement something that just if we're not
touching, then we will say, we will
change the animation state to be false.
So I'm going to copy my animator down
here, copy this, drop it in there.
We could say that player
has vertical speed or
we could just straight up say false.
That way we know if we're not touching
a layer that is defined as climbing,
then you should just not be climbing and
set yourself to false.
We have a return in there Just so
it's nice and clear.
And we'll hop back over into our scene and
see if that resolves our challenge,
climb up the ladder holding up.
So make sure everything else is fine.
Jumping, okay, no weed stake going on.
Climb up the ladder and
as we hop off, yeah,
it returns to where it should be,
excellent.
And the last part of this lecture is
we're gonna stop our player sliding
down the ladder.
And the way we're going to do that
is by setting the gravity to zero
when the player is on the ladder.
Now that's not really
the way ladders work.
I don't know if you've climbed up to clean
the gutter, clean the leaves out of your
gutter recently, but when you're on
the ladder you're not in zero gravity.
[LAUGH] It doesn't quite work that way.
But this is a video game and we're using
it as a way to simulate, we want to player
not to move, after all, we're jumping
about five times our body height and
we're not breaking our legs when
we slam back down to Earth.
So we're suspending a little bit of
our physics normality and reality and
we're taking a few poetic licenses here.
So that's the technique we're gonna use
is just to set the gravity to zero.
And this is where I'm
gonna set you a challenge.
The challenge is to
Stop The Player Sliding down the ladder.
I want you to Set the starting
gravity on the player's RigidBody
to the RigidBody's current gravity.
So when we first start we need
to know this is what the gravity
is on the RigidBody on the player and
then when the player is on
the ladder Set that gravity to zero.
So here's a few clues for you.
It's a little bit ambiguous, but
it's enough to get going to figure out
that there is something to do with
gravity on the player's RigidBody and
you need to set it at the start, so
that we know what it sets off at.
And then we need to set it to zero and
then return it back to
from whence it came.
So to make sure that you
return the gravity back
to normal when you're off the ladder.
So jump in, give that challenge a shot and
I will see you when you have
got some sort of result.
Right, so let's start by giving ourselves
some sort of cached reference here.
We will say float, we'll call this gravity
scale at start because we will be using
gravity scale and then in our start
method here we need a way of saying what
is our gravity at the start of the get go.
So, we'll say gravity scale at start
equals my rigid body dot gravity scale.
Okay, so we are establishing that
the gravity at start is myrigidbody.
That's the rigid body on the player.
And it will be set at the gravity scale,
which is the current gravity
scale that affects the player.
If you take a look at the player
you can see player rigid body 2D,
we can see gravity scale just here is one.
So we don't want to go manually
messing around with that.
It's already field that we can access.
It's been serialized as a field.
So if it is one at the start,
then we have accessed it here as one, and
then under our climb ladder method,
what do you wanna do here?
We want to, within our starting point,
we need to make sure that we establish
If you're not touching the layer,
the climbing layer,
to have myrigidbody.gravityScale
= gravityScaleStart.
So any time you're not on the ladder,
then make sure your gravity scale
is whatever it was at the start.
Any time you are on the ladder,
then let's set your gravity scale,
myrigidbody,gravityScale =
just straight up 0
there we go okay you could serialize
that and make it a smaller amount if
you wanted to have a little bit of gentle
gentle kind of gliding down the ladder but
we'll set it at 0 pop back over
into our scene click on play.
Now, if we move around, our player snaps
to the ladder, stands there nice and tall.
And I like the way that the state
transitions back to the idle state,
I think that's good.
That implies that I can get on and
off the ladder.
Some games you get locked on the ladder
and you can only leave the ladder when
you're right at the very top,
that's the only time you can leave.
But I like the fact that this shows
the player no, you can actually
just run off the ladder at any point
in time, jumping snaps the ladder.
Okay, I think this is
all feeling pretty nice.
I quite like this.
Okay, mission accomplished,
we've tweaked our ladder layer by
removing that animation bug that we had
As well as implementing a zero gravity
when the play is on the ladder.
Well done.
I will see you on the next video.