[SOUND]
In this video,
we're gonna create a SpawnAllWaves
coroutine that will allow us to spawn
multiple waves, one, two, three.
And we'll have those waves going with
different enemies and different paths.
So let's get cracking.
Okay, we're gonna be doing a little
bit of coroutine inception.
Inception, if you've seen the movie.
Leonardo DiCaprio,
it is a very, very good movie.
It's all about dreams within
dreams within dreams.
We are doing coroutines within coroutines.
So we have our coroutine we've created
already, I'll spawn all enemies in wave.
What we're looking to do now is
create a new coroutine which is
going to be SpawnAllWaves.
And within SpawnAllWaves,
we have a concept that we'll be hooking
up in our inspector, where we say,
here's wave 1, and wave 2, and
wave 3, and 4, and 5, and so on.
And we want to spawn the first one,
do what it needs to do,
then spawn the second, do what it needs to
do, and spawn the third one, and so on.
So within SpawnAllWaves,
we'll be creating ourselves a coroutine.
And the yield condition will be once our
SpawnAllEnemies in wave has finished,
has completed,
so you can see down here how yield
condition is get time between spawns.
And I think, at the moment,
it's set at something like 0.5,
whatever it's reading from our waveConfig.
So it's using a time, WaitForSeconds.
But it doesn't always have
to be WaitForSeconds,
we can use as our yield condition, we
can say the yield condition is finishing
another coroutine.
Which is really cool and can blow
your mind a little bit if you're not
sitting up straight and paying attention.
Okay, so hopefully you are in
a comfortable position and
this shall not blow your mind.
But this is what we are doing, we're
creating SpawnAllWaves as a coroutine and
we will be telling it to spawn a wave, and
to yield once the wave has
finished spawning all its enemies.
So let me clear all that off the screen.
Okay, so what we need to do
is underneath Start, we'll
create a new private IEnumerator.
And we'll call this SpawnAllWaves.
This is going to be,
it's a method of type IEnumerator,
which means we've created
ourselves a coroutine.
And there'll be two parts in this
similar to the way we were spawning all
the enemies.
We have our for loop and
then we have the content of what we
want it to be doing, and then our yield.
I guess that's three parts, isn't it?
And then we give ourselves
some curly braces.
I'm gonna start off with the for
loop here.
If you want a challenge, then see if
you can figure out how to write the for
loop for our SpawnAllWaves.
So pause the video, and take on that
micro-challenge, if you're interested.
Otherwise, we can do this together.
I'm gonna type for, open our parentheses.
We need to create ourselves an integer,
which will be waveIndex.
So we're incrementing
the index as we go along.
We'll start that off at startingWave.
This is gonna change
a little bit of our concept.
We won't be using this current
wave startingWave, but
I'll change that in a moment.
For now, our startingWave starts at 0.
And you know what,
I'm gonna put my semicolon here.
I think at some point, I'll remove
my SerializeField from startingWave.
I'm gonna put that back at
our startingWave variable at
top SerializeField.
So that we can change
that in the inspector.
If we wanted to start our game from say,
wave 82 instead of having to play
the whole way through to get to wave 82,
then we could change
that in the inspector.
Okay, so back down into our for
loop, we've got waveIndex =
startingWave as a starting point.
And then waveIndex, what's the check we
need to do here, what's the condition?
We continue our four loop if
the wave index is less than what?
It's gonna be less than the waveConfigs,
so all of the wave configuration files,
this is a list, so remember, we've got our
angle brackets up here, so it's a list.
That means, we are looking for count to
see how many items we have in our list.
And then semicolon, and finally we
increment waveIndex with waveIndex++.
Now we've created our for loop,
what do we do within this?
Well, let's give ourselves
a real spacing here.
This is where we're going to
shift our currentWave concept.
So I'll highlight, and in our Start
method, highlight var currentWave,
that whole line, for me it's line 12.
Cut, and I'm going to paste that,
As the first line within my code block,
that's being looped in the for loop.
We've got var currentWave, waveConfigs.
And instead of saying startingWave,
cuz that's just the first one,
and we've captured that here, we
want to say the waveIndex that's gonna be
incrementing as our for loop increments.
So we'll say, waveIndex and
then semicolon, here we can yield.
So it's done its job, it's basically
just saying what's the currentWave and
keep looping until you hit the end,
basically.
So yield return, and here's the cool part,
this is the inception part.
We don't need to write new,
we're going to put in a coroutine.
So we'll type in StartCoroutine, and then
what's the coroutine we want to start?
It will be this SpawnAllEnemiesInWave.
SpawnAllEnemiesInWave, what
do we need to pass in there?
Well, it wants us to give
it the waveConfig, so
we will do that by saying
it is the currentWave.
And then semicolon at the end,
so which waveConfig are we
giving to our SpawnAllEnemies?
We're giving it the currentWave.
What is the currentWave?
It is whatever we have currently
incremented as part of our for loop.
And where do we start off, we start
off at startingWave, which is zero.
So we've got our content in here.
I think this is all looking pretty good,
save this up.
Scroll up to the top.
Now we're no longer starting
the SpawnAllEnemiesInWave.
We want to start the SpawnAllWaves.
So that's the start point,
that's the launch point for
our nice loops we've got going on here.
Great.
We'll save that, jump over into unity and
this is where we want to give
ourselves a little bit of a challenge.
The challenge is to
create new enemy waves.
So first of all, create a second
different looking enemy prefab.
We've already got, who is it?
Roger, the orange Tie Fighter,
to create something else as well,
to go in to our game.
And then to create a new enemy path.
You can modify one of your existing ones,
but make sure you've got at least two.
And then we wanna spawn four waves,
Enemy 1, Path 1, Enemy 1, Path 2,
Enemy 2, Path 1, and Enemy 2, Path 2.
And a lot of the point I wanna make here
is that when creating just with a couple
of different tweaks, we have created
tons and tons of variation in our game.
So enough on the preamble,
jump in, take on that challenge.
I'll see you here in a moment.
Okay, first of all,
I'm gonna make myself a new prefab.
Jump over into the Kenney Assets,
find the spritesheet.
No, that's not it, find the PNGs.
Look for enemies, scroll down,
I'm going to find
this kind of weird looking blue guy here
and drag him into the sprite's folder.
I'm going to drag him into my scene,
rename it as, what should we call it?
We've got Roger,
we'll call this one Bernard.
I've been watching Westworld of late, so
that's maybe why I'm thinking of Bernard.
And then,
we need to drag Bernard into our prefabs.
While we're in here,
I'm gonna change boring old
enemy into exciting young Roger.
Jolly Roger, there we go.
We've got Roger, and we've got Bernard.
Bernard, I think he's okay.
Blue cool, so
we've got our second enemy prefab.
What do we need to add?
We need to add a component,
which will be the Enemy Pathing component.
Let's just check, so Roger's got an Enemy
Pathing and Bernard's got Enemy Pathing.
Excellent, so we've got our two enemies.
I will delete Bernard from my scene, we
don't need him in the scene at the moment.
Close up my waypoints, okay, what next?
Look at our waves.
We've got wave one which is
spawning Roger and then Path(0).
Move speed is a bit crazy,
put that down to 10.
Wave two is Roger and Path(1).
Yeah, that's a fine way to do it.
I'm going to duplicate both of my waves.
So now I'm gonna have a wave three and
a wave four.
Wave three is going to be Bernard,
Bernard on Path(0) and
then wave four will be Bernard on Path(1).
And we'll change his move speed to nine,
just to see how it goes.
Number of enemies,
we'll mix them up a little bit three,
actually I'll make this nice and clear.
So on my first wave, I have one enemy,
second wave I have two enemies,
third wave, I have three.
You don't have to do it this way,
I'm just change it this way so
I know exactly which wave we're on,
and we have four.
Okay, so over into Enemy Spawner, I've
gone and put 20 in there, I'll just change
this down to 0, and that will allow me
to look my Inspector, click on my Waves.
Drag my Waves on top of
the words waveConfig and
that is populated my list
with those four configs.
Now, it looks pretty good.
I said I was gonna move my path a little
bit, so Path(0), we'll mix it up.
You can see sometimes the icons disappear.
I'm not sure why, if someone out there has
an answer to that, I'd love to hear it.
Move this over just
a little bit offscreen.
Waypoint(1), Waypoint(2) and
then, also Waypoint(1) and
then Waypoint(2) offscreen,
so it does kind of a V.
That's for Path(0), and
then Path(1) is gonna be top right,
middle, left, and
then hopping offscreen as well.
I'll make sure the first one is offscreen.
I'm gonna go offscreen to offscreen.
That looks pretty good.
Let's save this up, click on Play,
see if what we've done works.
A quick message from the future, thank you
to those people who pointed out that you
need to click Apply to apply
your changes back to the prefab.
Yep, goes nice and quick.
Spawn, spawn, spawn, one,
two, three, four, okay.
And cuz we've got different speeds
that looks a little bit ridiculous and
cuz our paths overlapping, not so
great in terms of game play but
let's just check that again.
The first wave should have one enemy,
it's gonna go really fast,
then the next wave it has two, next one it
has three, and then the last one has four.
Okay, so we have these paths
coming into our game and
we have multiple enemies on multiple paths
and multiple spaces, it's super exciting.
In the next lecture, we're going to
tidy up our waves a little bit more and
give ourselves a looping component
to our entire waveConfigs.
Great work, and
I'll see you in the next video.