[MUSIC]
Hello again and welcome.
This is a quick video on perspective
versus orthographic cameras,
to make sure we're super clear
on what our camera is doing,
when we get into setting up our
Cinemachine camera in the upcoming videos.
Up till now, in our 3D games,
we've been using a perspective camera,
the form of projection is perspective.
That means that anything
close to the camera,
let me increase my game window here,
close to the camera looks bigger, and
further away looks smaller, just as it
would look in real life to our eye.
And that's useful to give perspective, so
it makes the player feel if I am here,
I have to run further away,
run, run, run, run,
run to get to the things
down at the back there.
So the player can see depth,
it's really good with that.
And you can see,
just literally looking at the camera,
that if I move the camera forward our
white lines are showing our field of view.
When our field of view is closer to
these blocks, there's less space.
You can see that maybe another
couple of blocks could fit left and
right in here, but down the end there's
a lot of space between my blocks and
the side of the camera,
where the camera's view is.
And that's showing as well the perspective
that these things are gonna
be smaller because of their relative
size fitting within the field of view,
these things are gonna be bigger because
of the relative size within the field of
view as well.
So that's the field of view and
using a perspective camera to show depth.
If we change the camera to orthographic,
we don't have that depth anymore,
we don't have our field of
view going out to the side.
It is being projected just straight
the whole way, so it's this big,
long straight box.
Nothing will be shown at a different
size because it's relatively the same
within our camera's field of view,
within our camera's projection.
And you can see, our game window over
here shows that the blocks at the front
look the same size as
the blocks at the back.
Now, why would we do this?
Well, it's particularly useful in games
when we want the player to see that this
thing at the back, sorry, at the front,
has the same importance and
the same amount of visual information
as the thing at the back.
When we're at perspective, it's a lot
harder to see if I'm playing a game.
As we did in Rome Rush,
we could see that if we played with our
camera and made it more skewed like this,
it's hard to place a tower at
the back than if we use orthographic.
So you can go back into Rome Rush and play
around with having an orthographic camera,
if you think it can look good.
And to make sure the player can
place towers at the front and
the back without things
getting skewed like that.
And obviously, it's also good if
we're using 2D assets that we know.
This asset placed on the screen here is
gonna look exactly the same if we place
that asset up in the back there.
With 3D assets we don't have that issue as
much, there's a lot more flexibility in
how we can move the camera around,
and rotate, and all that good stuff.
So that's orthographic.
And obviously, we're in a 2D game,
we're using orthographic,
so as you run along,
we don't have any skewing.
If we used a perspective camera as we run
along in our game from left to right,
then we do get this skewing.
Excellent if you wanna get that kind of
parallax scrolling look in the background,
if you've got a 3D side scrolling game,
then having this kind of approach
is really, really useful.
The other things for us to know about
with the camera is our clipping planes.
Our near clipping planes and far
clipping planes is a way for us to say,
at what point do we not display
the thing in the game window?
So you can see,
I'm playing around with it over here,
difficult seeing everything on the screen.
We have a clipping plane that says,
don't show anything if it
is closer than 16 or if it's,
as I scroll this up, If it's closer than,
we'll see when we get
rid of the blocks here.
Okay, if it's closer than 40,
then don't display that on the screen.
And that's really handy if you don't want
the player to accidentally be bumping into
something and
having it render right in their face,
you can use this clipping plane
to prevent that from happening.
If we're using our orthographic view,
we don't have a need to do that clipping
plane so
much cuz we're not really in our 2D game,
we're not gonna be putting
things that close to the camera.
But it's the same principle that
you can prevent that from happening
in terms of clipping.
And the same with the far plane.
The default orthographic is set
way off in the distance, but
we can bring that all the way up to here
to change what we display on the screen.
So you can see the orthographic camera,
it's just straight the whole way, so
if I put it cube way down in
that backend of the camera,
we would see it the same as
we see it at the front here.
And we're on perspective here.
The last point I'll make is in 3D games,
rotation is a fairly natural thing for
the camera to do.
Rotating up and down and around,
and we often follow an object.
So if you have something that's moving,
either the player or an enemy or
you have a cut scene where you wanna watch
something drive past, then you might
[SOUND], you rotate the camera to watch
that thing move across the screen.
And our 2D game, if we're not gonna
be doing any camera rotation,
it tends to look a little bit odd.
Let me just pretend here that one of
these cubes is our background plane,
just to scale this up,
And scale it across.
So if this is the background
behind our scene that we can see,
if we are on an orthographic camera and
we are doing, so orthographic camera,
we can see that there's the background,
there's cubes in the front.
As soon as we rotate our camera, then
our whole background goes sideways and
it breaks, [LAUGH] breaks
what we're trying to go for,
that our world is a 2D world, and
we see this flat plane behind it.
So just I'm raising that point now because
when we're talking about Cinemachine,
when you're applying 3D,
you'll have a mechanism where you can look
at something moving around, and
that will potentially rotate your camera.
But in a 2D world, we don't want
to use look at, all we wanna do,
I'll just move this guy out of the way
a little bit so that we can see our cubes
again, all we want to be doing
with our camera is moving or
transposing our camera from left to right.
It moves around left and
right, and up and down.
And we don't have that
mechanism of rotation,
it just doesn't fit within our 2D
games cuz it doesn't make sense.
Now assets are all flat,
Paper Mario style, so
it wouldn't look very good at all.
Okay, so that's just a quick rundown on
perspective versus orthographic to make
sure we're super clear on
what's going on there,
not confused between
those two perspectives.
In Cinemachine, we do have the option
of using perspective or orthographic.
And in this section,
the section of the course,
we're just doing orthographic
as our camera, and
doing a whole bunch of cool Cinemachine
stuff using orthographic camera.
And that is in the upcoming video,
so I will see you in that video.