In this video, we're implementing
our damage systems so that blank,
there we go, we can shoot projectiles
that kill enemies that have health.
And when they get to zero,
they're destroyed.
So, let's jump in and get started.
Okay, let's start off by
implementing some colliders.
I'm gonna find my Zucchini and
add a component,
which will be a collider, box collider 2D.
I think that's pretty good.
It doesn't need to be
perfect with the Zucchini.
I'll edit just a little bit, bring it in.
Bring it down, bring it in just so
it's reasonably tight.
Click on the Edit Collider.
Okay, there we go.
Pretty good.
It just kinda has to strike the center of
the Zucchini.
We're in lanes, so
we don't need super precise collision.
That's great,
apply that back to the prefab, excellent.
I think I can remove my
Zucchini from the scene now.
We'll just be using prefabs
when we instantiate them.
Now, let's find the lizard.
The lizard, I do need to drag
a lizard into the scene, so
I can see what's going on.
Click on ADD COMPONENT, Box Collider 2D.
That's around the entire outside,
which is a bit big.
I'm gonna switch onto Lizard Walk.
I think that's where I wanna have my
collider around wherever he walks, because
during the jump, I think the wizard
should be little and even vulnerable.
Jump, jump, jump, jump.
Okay, during that stage, I don't really
want my cactus to be hitting it.
So I will just wrap my collider around,
what it looks like when he's walking.
So edit collider on the box,
collider move this in.
Move that in as well, move that down.
Now move that whoops.
That's bit of a pain when that happens.
Back on Edit Collider.
And there we go, excellent.
Apply that back to the prefab.
Very good, and once again, I don't
think I need to my lizard any more.
What I will do is find a Zucchini and
find where we,
is Trigger is on the Box Collider 2D.
Is Trigger, tick that on.
Now, one thing we need to review
any time we're doing collisions,
is our collision matrix.
So let's have a quick look at that.
We can see all of these grids in here.
We've looked at these before.
We're using
a Trigger Static Trigger Collidor,
Dynamic Rigidbody Trigger Collidor,
Kinematic Rigidbody Trigger Collidor.
Well it's not static and it's not dynamic,
so it's gonna be a Kinematic Rigidbody
Trigger Collidor which reminds me.
We don't have a rigidbody anywhere.
So I'll find my lizard.
And add a rigidbody.
I didn't list that out in my requirements.
This is one of those things
when you do the requirements,
you think you're being pretty thorough.
But we missed, that we need a rigidbody.
I'll switch this to kinematic, cuz we're
saying walk across the screen this way.
I'm putting a rigidbody onto the lizard.
And we could put a rigidbody
on the projectile as well.
Actually, let's do that just so
we are being thorough on the Zucchini.
Add Component, RigidBody 2D.
And it's gonna work without this,
I believe, but we'll say it's Kinematic.
Now, temporary over into your scripts.
What script are we looking for
here as I move my microphone
out of the way a little bit?
I'm looking for the Projectile script.
Open that up in Visual Studio.
Let's start a new line, where we're
going to check for the trigger.
So we'll say void OnTriggerEnter2D,
and the auto completes
a bunch of stuff for us.
I'm gonna rename from collision here,
this is what's getting passed in,
rename to this to otherCollider.
otherCollision, we'll
cal it otherCollider.
You can call it whatever you want.
You could call it bob if you wanted to,
but
I wanted to just be very clear that we're
talking about the other things collider.
So this is the projectile, and
when we bump into anything else,
we wanna know details about the anything
else, so that's the otherCollider.
No we haven't even done this for
a while still be printing, so Debug .Log,
and then ("I hit: " what do
we hit + otherCollider-name).
So we'll just make sure that
our collision is working.
Before we go anywhere else on collision,
you always wanna make sure [LAUGH] it's
working, or else you scratch your
head wondering what's going on.
So back over into here, click on Play.
Once it's finished compiling and thinking,
click on Play, open up the Console.
A couple of warnings,
we're not using that, that's fine.
And then when this hits here, boing,
we should get, I hit a lizard, excellent.
Okay, so
collision is successfully working.
That's really important for
us to be confident hat we're
on top of that, good stuff.
Okay, so when we have that collision
moment, basically in here,
what we wanna be doing is reduce health.
That's what we wanna be doing in here.
So how do we go about doing that?
Well, we would call some sort of say,
DealDamage method.
And DealDamage(),
we haven't created that yet,
it doesn't know where it's coming from.
So let's go and
create all of that mechanism.
So jump back over into Unity,
we'll need to make ourselves a new script,
which will be called Health.
Create C# script, Health.
I'll just double click on Health.
Okay, so let's start off by giving
ourselves a notion of how much health
the particular thing will have.
So SerializeField, and
then this will be a float,
we'll call this health,
an issue like that 100f seems pretty good.
Let's have a quick look at our checklist,
we're going through the mechanism
now the Health script.
We've created Health script,
serialize health, yes, create DealDamage,
let's do that.
So for now, I'm going to just
get rid of start and update,
we put them back in if we need them,
create a public method,
cuz we need to be accessing
this from the projectile.
The projectile's gonna say, I hit
something, and we call the Deal Damage, so
we call DealDamage.
And what do we need at this point?
Well we need to know how
much damage to deal,
and we want that to be dependent upon
the particular projectile that's hit you.
So we'll say, when DealDamage is called,
we require you to let us know of
type float how much damage it is,
that you need to be passing
back in to DealDamage.
Okay, open our curly braces.
And then within here we'll have
the standard health -= damage;.
So we're saying, whatever health you
have at the moment starting up for
the hundred is -= damage that's just being
passed through when we call DealDamage.
And then we do our standard if did.
So if you think you know how to do this,
then just if the health gets below zero,
destroy the game object.
Just complete that.
Okay, if health is &lt;0,
then We will Destroy(gameObject).
So basically destroying
me is what that means.
Whatever me is attached to,
whatever this health has been placed onto.
So it's been reasonably good, save that
up, jump back over into projectile.
Now, DealDamage,
we have a mechanism for calling that.
How are we gonna do that,
well we know that when we collide
with the particular thing.
The otherCollider, then at that instance
we know who the otherCollider belongs to.
So we don't need to go searching
through our entire project and say,
hang on a minute who did I just collide
with I just collided with the thing
that owns the collider,
so the otherCollider.
This could be called otherObject that
currently possesses a collider, but
that's a bit too long.
So, let's start of by creating a variable,
which we'll call var,
just a general variable.
var health = otherColider.GetComponent.
And component of type Health.
Now we have a reference to the health
component or the health script, so
just remove my comments in here.
Then DealDamage, instead of just
DealDamage, we're going to say
health.DealDamage, cuz we're referring
to health which is our health component.
And DealDamage,
I spelled it incorrectly there.
DealDamage, let me go back over
into health and see what I code it.
DealDamage, and the problem is
that I'm not passing anything in.
So it's saying we mass over it,
it's saying there's no argument.
And that was because we said we
need to know how much damage, so
thank you Visual Studio for
reminding me of that.
How much damage, well, let's say we
need something a serialized damage.
So we'll say damage in here,
just kind of damage amount.
Up at the time
[SerializeField] float damage.
Initialize that at, say, 50;.
Okay, now it's happy, it's passing, it's
calling, hey, DealDamage, I want you to
give 50 points of damage, or whatever
it's being changed to in the inspector.
Now, let's jump over and
see if we can get any mechanisms
to see what's going on here.
Go to Console, clear our issues,
click on Play.
Now, do we have a way to
visualize what's going on?
Let's find whichever the first
lizard is that comes out.
Let's grab them in our lane that is.
So this guy just here
if I can click on New,
excellent, has health somewhere,
we haven't added the health script.
What are we crazy?
That's what we are,
we need to add the health script so
find your prefab of the lizard.
Click on Add Component, type in health.
Double click on that,
I'll single click on that.
That is health, 100, yep that's fine.
Now let we click on Play, I'm gonna
select one of the attackers that spawns.
This first, it was probably that guy,
they have already hit him that one,
yep, there we go.
Already has 50 health.
That first Zucchini smacked into it and
then second time around,
boom, health goes to 0.
Excellent, so we have cactus shooting
projectiles that's damaging the lizard.
The lizard health is going down.
We've done that by
creating our own trigger,
where we are calling the DealDamage and
by having a mechanism that says as health,
as you're hit, then decrease
your health until you get to 0.
And then I noticed one little bug which
is the fact that we hit 0, so we twice
on 0 health but the attacker wasn't
destroyed, and that's cuz we're saying &lt;0.
So we need to say &lt;=0.
We'll try that one more time,
click on Play,
hopefully we hit this lizard,
it will be once, and then he did
a second time, and it should disappear.
There we go, fantastic.
A few little bits and pieces we can
tidy up but that is good for this video.
I think we got our core functionality in.
Let's put in a little bit more of
that finesse in the next video.
So see you again shortly.