[MUSIC]
Hello again, in this video, we're gonna do
a little bit of tidying up of our code,
and we're gonna implement a death particle
effect when the attackers are smashed into
oblivion.
So let's start by opening
our projectile script.
We can see in here that we've
got a variable for health, and
we've got our health dealing damage.
What I'm going to do is create another
variable that allows us to have
a mechanism to say what is the health,
sorry, what is the attacker, I was looking
at the one above, we've already got
the health, Rick, what are you thinking?
We want to be able to
reference the attacker, and
that's going to equal
otherCollider.GetComponent&lt; &gt;,
and what do we put within
our angle brackets here?
We put &lt;Attacker&gt;.
You guessed it.
Hopefully you guessed it.
Yelling out at the screen randomly,
attacker.
Okay, so now that we have those two
I'm gonna create an if statement
here where I say if(attacker &amp;&amp;),
so double ampersand,
that's what that thingy is,
the and sign is an ampersand.
So &amp;&amp;, say that fast ten times, health.
So that's saying that when
we're colliding with something,
if it has the attacker component,
and it has the health component,
if both of those are true,
then we want to do something.
What is it that we wanna do?
Well, we want to do our health.DealDamage.
That would be the first thing, and
then also, I think what we want to do is
destroy the projectile so
that it's not hanging around.
You could have it that
when your enemy shoots,
you have a slow projectile that goes
through and does damage to everyone,
one of those like rockets that cannot
be destroyed, but for us, or for
the zucchini I want it to hit and then to
go away, I think that makes more sense.
So, what do we type in here if we
want to destroy the projectile?
We type in Destroy(gameObject).
So destroy our cell, save that up.
So now, it should only be
colliding with the correct things.
We probably won't see much of a change,
cuz it's not passing through any of
the incorrect things, but we know that if
there was another cactus in front of it,
then it wouldn't bump into that point.
Boink, there we go, we hit once, and
we hit twice, and it's disappearing.
Excelente!
The moment of disappearing where the
attacker is killed is a little bit bland,
so we're gonna spruce that up a little
bit by putting in a particle effect.
And this where I've got a challenge for
you is to create a nifty
particle effect and to trigger
that when the attacker is killed.
So this is code that we've done before.
It should be pretty straightforward for
you to find where to put that code and
say, how do I trigger this particle
effect so that it happens, and
if you don't wanna create a particle
effect, then I've got one that I'm using.
Just one of our other projects in
this course that I can give to you as
downloadable against this lecture.
So you can grab that, if you like,
as a asset pack or you can make your own.
So jump in, take on that challenge.
I'll see you back here when
you've given it your best shot.
Okay, let's go and grab that asset.
So I've got ExplosionVFX.
When I drag it in anywhere into my Assets
folder it asks me whether I'd like
to import.
Yes, I import, and it brings in
the folder structure as well, so
I've got this VFX folder down
here with the Explosion VFX,
[LAUGH] which you might recognize from
one of the other sections of the course.
I've just gone and grabbed it.
You can take plenty of time to
finesse with your particle effect but
I'm not gonna go through
that in too much detail.
I just wanted to get something
that we could use for now.
Let's just have a look,
make sure it works.
Boink, there we go.
It's kind of stars going a bit crazy.
Good enough.
Job done.
Okay, so
let's go over into our health script.
Above Destroy,
we need a notion of calling a method where
we're going to say TriggerDeathVFX().
Okay, we wanna trigger the VFX and
then we want to destroy it ourselves,
in this case it's destroying the lizard,
and
we want to make sure that
the DeathVFX isn't destroyed as well.
So that's a little bit trickier.
This is why we need to instantiate,
rather than just playing a VFX,
rather than just playing a particle effect
on, where's one of my lizards here?
Prefab &gt; Lizard, drag them into
the scene so we put him there.
So we could have as a child, we could
have a particle effect under the lizard.
But then when we destroy the lizard,
we're also destroying the child,
the particle effect underneath that.
So we're create ourselves
a private void TriggerDeathVFX.
What do we want to do in here?
Well, first of all I'm gonna say, if we
don't have any VFX, then just return,
just in case we forget to
put something on there,
we don't want something to
break where it says, hey,
trigger a particular particle effect and
we've kind of forgotten.
I know that you would never
forget to do that, but
I forget to do these things sometimes.
So say, if there is no,
what are we going to call this?
We'll call this deathvfx, we're going
to make that variable in a moment,
then just return.
Just go about your business,
don't worry, don'tdon't stress about it.
Unity, everything will be fine.
So let's go and
serialize ourselves a variable,
[SerializeField] GameObject,
cuz we want to be able to
reference it as a GameObject in a moment,
and it's a deathVFX.
Okay, so now we have this notion of
we're gonna drag in our deathVFX,
that we just brought in,
the explosion thing I had before.
If it doesn't exist, if you don't have
one of these then don't worry about it,
just return it.
Otherwise, what are we gonna do?
Well, we'll start off just by saying,
instantiate.
Instantiate, what do we need to do here?
Well, we're gonna instantiate(deathVFX, ).
We've done this a bunch of
times when instantiating.
It should be pretty natural by now.
And then where is it?
It's transform.position.
Had to think for a moment there.
And then we can do transform.rotation,
or we can do the quotidian.identity.
I just like doing transform.rotation
when it doesn't really matter what our
rotation is, we're just putting it in
there so that this instantiates happy,
it's not confused saying
what's the rotation, Rick?
Okay, let's see how this goes,
if this works.
Jump back over,
we need to create that reference.
So on Lizard, we should now see,
on our health script,
we can see it's looking for
deathVFX whereas my VFX,
I will grab Explosion VFX,
drag it on over into there.
Click on play just to make
sure that this works.
He jumps out, shoot, bang, and
one more time, shoot, bang, [SOUND].
Okay, we didn't get a VFX, why is that?
Well let's go to our Explosion VFX,
it's probably,
if we scroll down down down to the
renderer, we can see, if we look closely,
the Order in Layer is 0, so
we've gone through that before.
I'll put this at 6 so
it sits over the top of everything.
That's right on the prefab, so that
should be applied to what we're calling.
Okay, we'll try this again.
Okay, it's jumps out.
[SOUND] You know what I'm gonna do?
This has [LAUGH] been bugging me for
awhile.
I don't know, I haven't done this.
I'm gonna click on my lizard.
Go down, instead of 100 health,
I'm gonna give you 30 health, so
you get shot and killed.
I'm gonna click apply,
shot and killed with one shot.
Now if we want to see how it works with
multiple shots then we'll put that back up
again, but for now.
Kaboom, there we go, nice, and
it created a particle effect.
Let's have a look in here.
We've got this Explosion VFX,
now that's gonna
stick around forever if we don't take
care of it, so let's go take care of it.
How do we take care of it?
Well, we need to destroy
the particle effect and
this is why we're instantiating.
Sorry, we're instantiating because
the lizard gets destroyed,
and this creates this whole new game
object here, but we need a handle to it,
we need a way of referring
to this game object.
So we'll create ourselves a GameObject
type called deathVFXObject,
and that's equal to what
we've just instantiated.
So now we have this notion
of there's a deathVFXObject,
so on our next line we can
say Destroy(deathVFXObject),
and we have the option of
saying after how long.
We don't wanna destroy it straight away,
because we need to actually see
the particle effects, so
we'll say after a second.
This is a little bit of a magic number
in here, but I'm okay with that.
We could put it to 10 and
be super safe, but I'll leave it at 1.
I'm pretty sure my particle
effect is gonna be come and
gone in one second no problem.
So we'll make sure all that works and
is hunky dory.
Click on play, watch our hierarchy,
lizard's being spawned, blump,
explosion, and
then the explosion went away.
Now, if you look at it closely,
I think, here we go, when it hits,
when it strikes, boink, the particle
effect is a little bit to the right.
It looks a little bit off.
It's all going pretty quick so
you don't really notice it, but
there's a few ways to solve this.
For now, I'm going to be a little bit
cheeky, okay, and for the [LAUGH]
experienced programmers out there you're
gonna be like,what are you doing?
I'm gonna be a little bit cheeky and
show you how I will move the particle
effect as opposed to trying to
reposition it on the lizard, or
on the lizard's pivot point.
So you see the pivot point there.
Instead of trying to change where we
instantiate it I'm just gonna change
the particle effect a little bit.
So forgive me on this that it's not
perfect, but sometimes I think it's good
to do these little tweaks so
that we can keep on moving.
So let's find our VFX &gt; Explosion VFX,
Drag one of those into the scene.
You can see here is the particle effect.
If we zoom in,
this little symbol is showing it, and
that represents where the middle
of the particle effect is.
If I scroll down on my particle effect,
and find let's see, Shape, and on Shape,
I've got position on my X coordinate,
if I drag that over a little bit,
you can see that this is where the origin,
or the basis of the particle
effect is gonna be, and this is
where spawning the actual particle.
So, if I click play,
that's a little bit to the left.
I know this is a little bit hacky, but
I think this is a great quick solution to
the fact that it's not quite lining
up the way we want it to line up.
Instead of having to go and
mess around with the lizard,
and the lizards animation
we can do that later on.
We'll tidy that later on,
but this is just a quickie.
We'll apply this back to the prefab.
Just remove that from our scene.
Let's have our lizard come walking in,
walk, walk, walk, walk, and boink,
that looked like it landed right
over the top, so that's pretty good.
Okay, as I said,
it's not the best particle effect.
Hopefully you've done something a little
bit sharper than that, and also,
if you've found that it's not
spawning quite in the right place,
I've given you a bit of a hint there on
how you can tweak your particle effect.
Okay, so that's all I wanted to do in
this video, just tidying thing up and
getting a little bit of
a particle effect triggering.
In the next video, we'll do,
I'm not sure yet, something cool [LAUGH].
I'll see you in the next video.