[SOUND]
In this video
we're gonna be shooting and destroying
our enemies when they get below 0 health.
So let's jump in and get started.
Okay, let's kill Roger.
Sorry about that, Roger, but
it's time for you to perish.
First of all, you know what
I'm gonna do in this lecture?
I think I'll highlight the general
area we need to focus on,
which is within our Enemy.cs.
And we're looking at health, and something
needs to happen if the health hits 0.
And that something that needs to
happen is you taking on a challenge.
[LAUGH] Yeah, see what I did there,
yeah, very clever.
Okay, so destroy the enemy.
So if the enemy's health drops below 0,
destroy the enemy.
It should be reasonably straightforward,
we've done this sort of
thing a couple of times.
So jump in, take on that challenge.
However, do it in the way that works,
then we can clean it up
a little bit later on together.
We can look to see how we can
optimize it and refactor it.
But for now, just destroy the enemy
when its health gets to 0.
Okay, so pretty simple in our
OnTriggerEnter method here.
What I'll do is say, if (health &lt;= 0).
I'm gonna say less than 0,
just in case you hit it with a big
hit that takes it to negative 200.
And we wanna say less than and
equal to, just in case you,
it starts off with 100 and
you do 100 damage, and it gets to 0.
You don't want to say just less than 0,
cuz then it'll be sitting there,
sitting on 0 health, which if
you've reach 0, you should be gone.
So you'd say, less than or equal to 0 and
then we'll add our code
block with our curly braces.
And here we'll say,
Destroy(gameObject), straightforward?
Semi-colon, save that up, see how we go.
Jump back over into our scene,
how much health has Roger got, 500,
it should be a quick burst.
We should see him disappear,
so click on Play.
Make sure we're not getting any errors,
cool burst, burst, burst, he's gone.
And these other new Rogers that are coming
into the scene are also getting gone as
well, excelente.
So we've created a pretty straightforward,
just having our enemy be destroyed.
In the future we'll be adding some
particle effects and some sound effects.
So we'll make it a lot more of a moment.
Presently, it's not a moment, this is
a bit of an anticlimax, just disappears.
But we'll put some work into that,
for now it's functionality.
But what I wanted to do a little
bit more of was just tidy this up.
You can see that our OnTriggerEnter
method is starting to get busy.
We're doing the, okay, who bumped into me.
And we're also doing the,
should I die or shouldn't I die?
So I'd like to factor out this process of,
should I or
should I not be dying,
at this point in time.
So what I'm gonna do is highlight
everything from health, down to the end of
our destroy code block, Right-click, Quick
Actions and refactors &gt; Extract Method.
And so I'll rename this as ProcessHit,
and hit Enter, okay.
And something really
cool has happened here,
that Visual Studio has
helped us out a bunch.
It's saying, okay, you wanna
create a new method, that's great.
But I know within this new method you need
some information that was in the previous
method, because you've
created a local variable.
It's just local within this code block
here, within our onTriggerEnter,
called damageDealer.
And for you to do what you want to do down
here, you need to know about damageDealer.
So therefore let's create
ourselves a signature,
let's create a parameter requirement.
The way we do that is in
our parentheses here,
we've created ProcessHit as a method.
And it's saying when
anything calls ProcessHit,
we need to know, who is damageDealer?
We need you to pass into us
something of type damageDealer, and
we'll call it damageDealer as a variable.
We could call this anything,
we could call it Bob if we wanted, or
it would be a lowercase B, if we called
it Bob, but we'll call it damageDealer.
Cuz then it makes a lot more sense
that we're actually referring to
the damageDealer.
And this damageDealer is
gonna come from above.
Where we're saying okay,
when something bumps into us,
let's find out who the damageDealer is.
I'm gonna call ProcessHit, which is
nice and cleanly represented down here.
And I know as a requirement,
I absolutely have to pass into
it this damageDealer parameter.
If I was to remove this and just say let's
push in ProcessHit, then it is going to
give us the red squiggly line,
saying you can't call me at the moment.
Cuz you haven't told me,
there's no argument given that
corresponds to the requirement.
So you'd mouse over it, and
it says I need an argument.
That's another way of referring
to what we've got here,
argument that is requiring this parameter.
Okay, let's save that,
check that it works.
And just a side note, we will be doing
a lot more with this moment where we say
destroy the enemy, and when we do,
we might have some sound effects in there.
We might be adding score and
doing a few other things.
And as we add more content in here, for
example, that's where we would factor
this out and create some sort of die
method that we would have down below.
We're not gonna do that yet,
cuz we've just got this one line.
But just taking note of this domino
effect or this waterfall effect of that.
As we add more stuff into our method, we
factor it out, to just clean up our code,
and to have things only have one or two
things that they're doing within a method.
Okay, let's save, just double-check
that this has all worked.
Hopefully, that point about arguments and
parameters makes sense.
We've talked about it a couple of times,
yeah, this all works.
So hopefully it's cementing, and
the logic of why we have to do it.
Okay, and always, if you have any
questions about what we've covered,
in particular with our argument or our
parameter that we have within our method
here, how we're doing it or why we're
doing it, then feel free to throw it into
the discussion, into the questions,
and let us know.
And if you have an understanding,
if you want to reiterate, this is my
understanding of this works, then put that
in there as well, so you can verbalize it.
Sometimes speaking it out loud and saying,
this is what I think is going on, or
this is how I think it works,
really helps cement your learning.
So great work, and we'll jump into
more functionality in a moment, so
see you in the next lecture.