[MUSIC]
In this video we're gonna create
enemies that run along our ledge.
And when they get to the end they turn
around and come back the other way and
I'll just jump over the enemy here.
And knows when it has reached the end and
returns back the other way.
Okay, the first step in the process is to
grab the enemy sprite that I've created.
I just click on my Sprite folder here and
then drag in.
So download and then drag in
the enemy sprite sheet that we have.
Cool there he is down here,
a little blobby up and down kind of guy.
Fantastic, what do we need to do?
Well we need to slice up this
sprite sheet first of all.
So I'm gonna click on Multiple and
then to make it 32 pixels per unit,
clicks the Apply down there and
then jump into the Sprite Editor.
Let's have a look here, I think I'll
splice this, slice this, sorry,
by grid by cell size.
We know it's gonna be 32 by 32,
Padding should be 6 and
then I'm not sure the offset.
Looks like we do need to have a little bit
of an offset to the right and to down.
I'm just gonna have a guess and
say 6 and 1 in terms of the offset,
6 to the right and 1 down,
I'll hold down Ctrl in here.
Looks like we've got the y offset
accurate, but not the x offset, so
I'll push the x offset a little bit more,
9 to slice that.
I'm gonna have it pretty
much in the middle.
It doesn't quite look in the middle and
push it one more, maybe two more here.
So the offset to 11 and slice that, okay.
It's looking pretty good
touching the ground and
mostly in the middle, excellent.
So we'll Apply that, we now have
a sprite sheet with individual sprites.
We need to go and create ourselves
an actual enemy, to put into our scene.
So let's go and click on the actual
enemy button [LAUGH] just joking.
Click on Create Empty,
we will name this enemy.
Reset the transform,
right-clicking there, Reset.
And our enemy is sitting just there.
Let's move enemy over to near the player.
Hang on a minute, where's the enemy?
Well, first of all, we need to
give the enemy a sprite renderer.
So I'm gonna add the components now.
If you want to go ahead and
add the components yourself,
do a little micro challenge,
pause the video and do that.
Otherwise you can follow along with me or
we'll do it together or
maybe we'll have a race.
Let's see who can add all
the components first.
So gonna start with a sprite renderer,
sprite renderer, and
we need to give ourselves
an indication of who this guy is.
So just drag one of the sprites
we've sliced up already into here so
we can see the enemy.
Or actually we can't at the moment
because our sorting layer is incorrect.
Let's go and create our cells and
use Sorting Layer.
Not incorrect,
we just haven't set up a sort layer.
Click the plus button here.
Rename this to Enemy, and then
the Enemy should be before the Player.
So I think the Player's always going to
be rendered over the top of the Enemy,
that's the right way to do it.
Click back on the Enemy game object and
change the sorting layer here to Enemy.
Now we can see our Enemy, fantastic.
Just put the Enemy down
on the ground just there.
Okay, very cool, got our Enemy here.
Next up, what do we need for components?
Well, we need a way of
moving the Enemy around.
We need a rigid body, so Rigidbody 2D.
We're gonna make our enemy a kinematic
rigid body, so that means gravity and
forces won't apply.
We don't need the enemy to be jumping or
bouncing or falling off ledges.
We actually want the opposite, we want the
enemy just to stay just along the ledge,
just to do its thing,
to be a threat to the player.
But not too much of a crazy,
out of control, chasing the player up and
down ladders kind of threat.
Okay, so we've got our RigidBody in there.
Next up, we need to give
you some form of collision.
So we'll say a collider, Capsule Collider,
similar to the way we did with the player.
Capsule Collider,
let's do a little bit of editing on that,
click on the Edit Collider button.
Doesn't need to be perfect,
just somewhere in the middle.
Now, good, okay so
we're got a collision on there.
Next up we need a way to move and
drive the animation.
Not move, we'll do that in script.
But the animation,
we want the bouncing up and down.
We need an animator, animator to do that.
And what goes hand in
hand with the animator?
Well, we need an animator controller.
You can see the player
animator controller.
That's not gonna do for the enemy.
We need a specific enemy one.
Click over into my Animations folder here,
right-click,
Create &gt; Animator Controller,
and we'll name this Enemy.
Okay, that's opened up by default, but
make sure you clicked on your
Animator window to see that.
And we need to create an animation for
the enemy.
So back to my sprites.
We've done this a few times, so
this should be feeling
pretty intuitive for you.
Right-click to Create Animation.
We'll call this animation enemy bounce.
Drag the enemy bounce,
actually, before I drag that,
I'll click on Looping to
make sure this loops.
Because you go bounce,
bounce, bounce on the spot.
Drag that into our
Animate Controller here.
We don't need to worry
about the transition.
It's going immediately into these enemy
bounces, and it's not transitioning in and
out anywhere.
We click back on Enemy, the last step
here is to make sure that our animator
controller is assigned to the animator.
So I'm going to click on the selector here
and choose the Enemy Animator controller.
And click Play just to make sure that
first stage of getting our enemy set up is
working.
Cool, so
then we're just bouncing on this spot.
Bouncy, bounce, very good.
Okay, and as is the player.
So we've both got a bit of an idle.
The enemy, we don't need to worry
about an idle state or a run state.
It's just gonna be bouncing while moving,
that's pretty much it.
Okay, what to do next?
Well, we need to drive the actual
behavior of the enemy, so
let's create ourselves a script.
We'll call this EnemyMovement Create and
add that there.
Open up that script, and
we have a blank canvas here.
What do we want to do?
Well, we need to get
the RigidBody 2D of the enemy so
that we can move the enemy left and right.
And we need to know which
way the enemy is facing, and
we need a way of saying when you
get to the end to turn around.
So let's start by getting the RigidBody.
So as we've done before, RigidBody2D,
we will call this myRigidBody, okay.
Okay, then we need to get that
RigidBody so now Start method here,
we'll say myRigidBody = GetComponent.
What type is that?
Well, it is of type RigidBody,
2D, okay, so we've got that.
We also need a way of saying how fast
the enemy is going to parametrize that.
So we will create a serialized field
which will be of type float and
we will call this moveSpeed.
So we can change that in our Inspector or
actually we'll initialize that, I think,
to 1f, just so
that we have a starting point of 1, okay.
Now that we've got our rigidBody and
we have a way of saying to
move it a certain speed.
Let's in update, let's just move our enemy
across the screen just in one direction.
So if you want a micro challenge,
pause the video now and go ahead and
just move your enemy
just right by move speed.
Just right across the right of the screen.
So there's a little micro challenge for
you.
If you wanna do this together with me,
then I'm gonna say
myRigidBody.velocity dot.
Sorry, not dot, equals.
So myRigidBody velocity is going to equal,
has to be a new vector too.
And then this will be out.
x and y will be moveSpeed and 0.
We don't need to change or do anything to
the y cuz it's not moving up and down.
So let's save that and make sure that
we actually are moving our enemy
a little bit across the screen,
there we go.
Enemies moving, cool, looks good, and
cuz we've got a collision on there.
This will be interesting to see what
happens when we get down to the end.
It does push the player the whole
way through the wall, save me.
Where have I gone?
Okay, so collision's working.
That's a good start.
Not having any impact on the player yet.
We'll do that in upcoming videos.
We'll have the enemy hurt the player,
but for
now we've got our enemy moving across
the screen, which is a good start.
This is where I'm going
to give you a challenge,
and it's gonna be a pretty meaty,
chunky challenge this time.
To make your enemy turn.
When the enemy reaches
the end of the platform,
as we've talked about, or reaches a wall,
have them turn and go back the other way.
That's the mission,
if you choose to accept it.
I'm gonna give you some hints here.
If that's enough for you to go on already,
then pause the video, jump in now, and
give that a shot.
Give it your best guess to
figure out how to do that.
If you want the hints here we go.
I'll give you some hints now.
So we want to flip horizontal similar
to the way we did with the player.
Flip the enemies horizontal so
that's pretty straightforward.
To use collision to determine when to
flip, well that's pretty obvious as well.
And to add a new box
collider to test collision,
not just to rely on the capsule
collider we've got there.
If you remember with the player
where we're using a different
approach with the feet versus the body.
So adding a second collider to test
out these things can be useful.
Now I'm gonna give you the biggest hint
of all in terms of how to go about
doing this.
So if that's enough for you to go on,
pause the video, jump in now.
If you still get a bit stuck,
you can come back to this hint.
But the big hint is to use
OnTriggerExit2D() when you're looking at
that collision test.
At that trigger test to
see when the enemy has
exited a trigger volume
as opposed to entered it.
Entered it, is that a word?
Entered a trigger volume.
Okay, so this is the clues for now,
if that doesn't make any sense at all,
no worries, follow along with me but
I'd love for you to give that a shot.
And I'll see you back here when
you've given it your best try.
Okay, so if you saw those hints just now,
let's talk about adding an extra collider.
We want to do that at
the front of the enemy,
a little reverse periscope where we
have the, well let me create it so
you can see what I'm talking about,
rather than just talking about it.
So we'll say a box collider 2D
that's going to be around the enemy.
And I'm going to edit this so
that it is a little reverse periscope.
Periscope's a thing that submarines look
at to see what's up above the water.
This is going to be looking at whether or
not the enemy is currently
touching the ground, like that.
So we'll do a little bit more finessing
later on to make sure it's all good.
But basically, this is saying,
at the moment,
the enemy is colliding with the ground.
You can see the enemy there is
touching the ground as they go along.
And because we're talking about
colliding and this physics relationship,
collision to collision.
We need to make sure that the enemy has
the right physics collision layer set up.
So all the way up to Layer here,
click on the default button while we
are on the enemy, and click on Add Layer.
We'll call this enemy
as a new layer in here.
So that is one point.
Back onto our enemy game object and
then assign this layer to be enemy.
Now we need to go and
manage our physics relationships, so
click on Edit &gt;
Project Settings &gt; Physics 2D.
We can see our matrix down
the bottom we have enemy,
that's been added in the enemy.
A little bit hard to see if the enemy
is currently colliding with everything,
we don't want that.
We want the enemy to collide with default,
well yeah I guess.
No, we'll turn off default.
You know what,
the only thing the enemy needs to collide
with is the ground and the player.
So let's turn off everything else
except for ground and player, and
we can turn them back on in
the future if we need to.
But I don't think the enemy
needs to be colliding with UI.
We'll turn off Climbing, we don't want
the enemy to be climbing this ladder.
They run backwards and forwards.
Player, yes, Background, no, certainly
don't want collision with the background.
So the enemy and enemies and enemies,
now we'll turn that off as well.
So if you've got two enemies they
just kind of fly past each other.
You might wish to turn that back on if
we have two enemies on the one platform.
But for now we'll leave that as is.
So the enemy is now just colliding
with the player and the ground.
I'm going to move my enemy a little
bit closer to the wall, so
it can see it's a shorter
distance to bounce off the wall.
One thing to make sure we don't forget is
that with our box collider is to turn on
Is Trigger.
If you find that your enemy is just flying
through the walls and it's not bouncing,
or it's not stopping at the ledges.
Then this is the number one thing
to check that it is a trigger.
Because we're gonna be
using the On Trigger exit.
So let's go have a look
at our coding here.
What do we need to do first of all?
Well we need to go and
do the mechanism of flipping.
So let's go look at what we
had to do with the player.
We're saying that the transform of
the scale is the sign of the velocity.
However with the player, where the player
is giving input saying, run right,
run left.
So this is going to be dynamically
moved based upon the player.
But for the enemy it's going to be
triggered by an event that happens, and
that event is out OnTriggerExit.
So let's use this for some inspiration.
Gonna go back over into our enemy script
here and say void OnTriggerExit2D,
that enters the Collider2D collision,
great.
We want to say in here
that transform.localScale.
If I do this correctly,
transform.localScale,
there we go = new Vector2.
Now we to need to say in this moment,
we need to use this moment to change
the direction, to change the scale.
So I'm gonna use a minus in here, for
the x axis to say do the opposite
of what you were just doing, minus.
And then we'll go and get as we did before
Mathf.Sign of the myRigidBody.velocity.x.
I'll explain this in a bit
more detail in a moment.
And then, 1f because we want
the y axis to stay as it is.
So what I've done in here is said okay,
there's a velocity for the enemy,
it's either moving right or moving left.
And we know the sign of that.
And if it's moving right it'll be plus 1,
and if it's moving left it'll be minus 1.
But what we want to do is force
the flipping of that force,
the flipping of the entire local
scale of the entire enemy itself.
So that we turn it back the other way,
if this is a plus,
then this will make it a minus,
we'll be going left.
If this is a minus,
then adding two minuses together, so
minus of minus 1 make it a plus, so
therefore makes it go to the right.
And so when we do that triggering,
what do we want to have happen?
Well one of the things,
I just want to point out while I'm here,
while I remember, is one valid way to
go about this whole process is creating
a variable which might be
isFacingRight for example.
And then you can say whether
that's true or false, and
store the information just here about
the direction the enemy is facing.
That's a valid way of doing it.
If you jump around the Internet,
that's a pretty common way
of people solving this
challenge of flipping a sprite.
However, storing it is not necessary
because we're calculating it.
We know at this point here we know
that the scale has been flipped, so
we don't need to go and store that.
We just need to know which way it
is at the time of it happening.
So I'm going to go into my update here,
we've got our moving to the right.
We also need to have
our moving to the left.
So I'm going to create
an if statement in here.
Where we say if, is, it's going
to be a method, IsFacingRight and
we'll do this in a moment,
we'll set up the method in a moment.
If we're facing right,
if that's true then we want to
say myRigidBody.velocity =
new Vector2(moveSpeed 0).
So, basically move to the right,
else, we'll go and
copy this, this statement here.
Else, what do we need to do,
well else we need to move to the left and
left is -moveSpeed.
So moving a minus direction,
a negative direction.
And then what is IsFacingRight, I'm gonna
copy this method, copy this name, sorry.
And jump down here and
create a new method,
which is gonna be returning a bool.
So bool IsFacingRight,
and what will that return?
Well, it's going to return true or
false based upon if the
transform.localscale sorry, localscale.
We're gonna do that again.
So I get my autocorrect
transform.localScale.x is what?
Is greater than 0.
So if our transform.localScale
is positive,
that means we're facing to the right.
If it's negative, that's not true, then
it's false, it would return false up here.
IsFacingRight would be false, and
therefore we would say, move to the left.
So we're using this moment of trigger,
this exit trigger,
to flip the local scale,
flip the entire sprite.
And then we're saying up here,
has it been flipped or not?
If you're facing to the right, go right.
If you're facing left, go to the left.
So that's a nice clean
way of setting this up.
Let's save that and
make sure it works before we pat
ourselves on the back too much.
Hop into the game here, click on Play.
And as our enemy gets to the end,
bounce and bounces off the wall and
comes back towards the player, cool.
So quick recap, we've added a box collider
here as a little underground periscope
that says when this box collider exits
a trigger volume, exits the collision.
Then we trigger the local scale,
flipping for the enemy.
What does that mean?
Well if we have a negative local scale,
then IsFacingRight returns false.
If we have a positive local scale,
then IsFacingRight returns true.
And we're using that here in our update.
If we have a true facing right,
we move to the right, otherwise
we have a not true facing right
then we move to the left.
Okay, so great work, well done,
that's a big video, big lecture,
lots of content we've got through.
We now have our enemies moving around.
Great work, and
I'll see you in the next video.