[MUSIC]
This video is gonna be another one
of our problem solution videos.
So let's have a look at the problem or
problems that we've got.
The first problem is that as the enemies
are coming in, they shoot and
then they destroy themselves,
that's one problem.
And they destroy each other,
it's all crazy stuff.
Another problem that we have is that when
the player shoots, it destroys itself.
That's not so good either.
And then another problem,
I'll show you here when I click on play,
is when I shoot you'll see that may laser
goes all the way through the enemy.
It doesn't actually stop and
the laser isn't being destroyed,
despite the fact that we've already
created a method to do that.
So to summarize,
this is going to be the challenge slide
as well as our what are we doing slide.
If you're feeling a bit more advance and
you wanna dive in and
take these on yourself,
then that is excellent.
We're gonna be creating collision
layers and assign to our game objects.
Also, we need to destroy the projectiles
and the enemy as well, when they collide
with something that they're doing damage
to, we need to add damage to our enemy.
And we also need to protect against null
reference with our Damage Dealer collision
object, so we can't get in a situation
where we're assuming that something that
is colliding has damage.
So there are the three main
things that we'll be doing.
First off, let's talk about collision.
So you can see that when our
enemies are disappearing,
that is because the laser is
colliding with the enemy.
Okay that's fine.
I was gonna say, quick get out of the way,
but that's fine.
You'll see that when they shoot
the laser has this power,
saying whatever it collides with,
destroy it.
We wanna say, well, ignore the enemy.
You don't actually wanna
distroy the enemy now do you?
And I'll summarize this in
a little slide I've got over here.
Here with the layer of collisions, so
if we've got the enemy projectile
in the player, we want to say yes,
the enemy projectile,
yes should collide with the player.
But if we've got the enemy
projectile on the enemy,
we say no, the enemy projectile
should not collide with the enemy.
Where do we find this
information in Unity?
If you go to Edit, Project Settings,
and then Physics 2D, you'll see,
right down the bottom in our Inspector,
we've got a Layer Collision Matrix.
At the moment, we've got five layers,
Default, TransparentFX, Ignore Raycast,
Water, and UI, so these are the default
layers that Unity provides for us.
We’re gonna create an extra couple of
layers that have meaning for us, and
then we’ll assign what collides with what.
So it doesn’t really matter what you
click on, but we’ll click on player and
then up in the Inspector, the top-right,
you'll see there's Layer, and next to it,
Default.
Click on Default, and
then there's the option to Add Layer.
You can see that the 0 through to 7 are
taken up, so I'm gonna start from Layer 8.
The layer number doesn't matter so much.
It's just what we're putting in
here that is going to matter.
So we'll say Player for Layer 8.
Layer 9, I'll say Enemy, I'll type Enemy.
Layer 10 we will use,
what should we use in here?
We'll say, Player Projectile.
And layer 11, we'll say Enemy Projectile.
I think that's the main things
that we want to have crushing or
not crushing into each other.
That's cool, then we can exit out of that,
let me click on our player one more time,
take us back to the players inspector.
Now when we click on layer, you'll see we
have the option of assigning that as you
are on the player layer, and
I love that it rhymes, the player layer.
So the player is now a player
on the player layer,
we'll apply that back to the prefab
as we do and click on Roger.
Roger is an enemy.
So up in the top right, we'll assign
Roger to be on the enemy layer.
We'll assign Bernard to
be on the enemy layer.
Any other enemies you
might have in your game,
make sure you assign
them to the enemy layer.
Find our enemy prefabs, right,
enemy laser prefab, and
we'll assign that to be
an enemy projectile.
And then the player laser will define
that as player projectile, okay.
You can add a bunch more of
these as they come up, but
I think these are the ones
that we've got at the moment.
Now back over into Edit, Project Settings,
Physics 2D and our Collision Matrix
has a whole bunch more things on it.
And you can see that they're all ticked
as yes, you will collide by default.
Everything by default collides
with everything else.
So let's go through and say what should,
or shouldn't collide with stuff.
Just looking at the left hand column here,
I'm going to say Default, that's cool.
Things automatically
get defined as Default.
Don't worry about Transparent, down to
what, okay, the first one is Player.
What should the Player collide with and
not?
You can see it's chopped off a little bit,
but this says Enemy Projectile.
So Player and Enemy Projectile, yes.
Player and Player Projectile, no.
That's why we were disappearing
when we shot ourselves.
Player and Enemy, yes.
Player and Player?
Well, that's not really gonna happen,
but we'll say no for now just in case.
And then Enemy and Enemy Projectile?
No, we don't want the enemies
to be able to shoot themselves.
And then Enemy and Player Projectile, yes.
And Enemy and Enemy?
No, we don't want them to
be bumping into each other.
Player, player projectile and
enemy projectile.
No, I don't really want to be
shooting down enemy projectiles,
although you might want to have that.
That could be cool.
And player projectile and
player projectile, no.
And enemy projectile and
enemy projectile, no as well.
Okay, so there's that collision matrix.
If we save this up, click on Play.
Let's see if that has fixed
our problem straight away.
Shooting, okay,
they're not destroying themselves.
We've got a whole bunch
of lasers coming down.
Great, the player died.
One more check I'll do is the player needs
to be able to shoot without destroying
themselves.
And shoot, shoot, shoot.
Yep, good.
And the player is destroying the enemies,
except for, yep got him.
Okay, what was next on our
list of things to tidy up?
We want to make sure
the missile destroys itself.
So over into our do damage script in here.
We created previously this Hit method
which destroys the game object when
it hits something.
And again, this is where we
need to put it into two places,
which is a little bit messy.
And ideally, we would have just one
health component that we would add in
a couple of places, one health class.
But for now, we're gonna leave it like
this so in a way, it's good to feel
the pain a little bit and to think
about how we could factor it out, but
we are going to put this in, let's see.
Where do we want to have
the bullet actually be destroyed?
I think after we do the health minus,
after we reduce the health of
the thing you smacked into.
That is where we'll say
damageDealer.Hit();.
Okay, save this over into enemy
where we're doing exactly the same
thing underneath health being reduced.
We will say damageDealer.Hit(); save and
that should successfully be
destroying the player laser when
it hits an enemy, and
the enemy laser when it hits the player.
But you can see that in
both situations that works.
Okay, cool.
And
then the last thing I wanna
do in this video is for
us to protect against null situations,
so null reference.
And we had this a couple of
lectures ago where Roger,
the Roger we've just dumped
into our scene here.
We're sitting there with an enemy pathing
script and the enemy pathing script
assumes a whole bunch of things, and
if you have a look at our player script.
At the moment, we're assuming when
anything collides with the player,
we're assuming that it has this
damageDealer component and
then when processing with damageDealer.
And it could potentially get to the point,
if we're clever with our collision matrix,
then this isn't going to happen but
it's good to protect against it.
I just want to show you how
we go about doing this.
So we can say at this point we're getting
it, we're saying GetComponent and
then here, we're using the object
that has the component.
But if the object doesn't
have the component,
then this process here is
potentially gonna fail.
So in here we'll say,
if naught or none or no, so
if naught which is the !damageDealer and
that's in parentheses.
Open our curly brackets,
we could do this on a separate line, but
it works here and
it's a little bit tidier this way.
Then we type return;, and
then it will close the curly braces.
And what this is saying is if there is no
damageDealer, if it's not damageDealer,
then return.
End what we're doing,
don't do anything further down
the chain and exit out of this method.
So return, and we do the exact same line.
I'm just gonna copy the exact
same line over an enemy.
And again,
you can see if we had this in one place,
I wouldn't have to type it twice.
And potentially make mistakes,
but if damageDealer, so
if !damageDealer, then return.
And that is protecting us against null.
Protecting us against a situation where
we're trying to do something, but
the information, the data doesn't exist.
And we'll save that up, okay.
So in this video,
we've done a couple of tidies ups.
I think the end result is pretty neat
where our game is working quite nicely.
We can fly around, we can shoot,
we can kill enemies, they can kill us.
The bullets smack into the enemies.
We'll be able to do some really
cool particle effects on
collision in the future.
We have health.
We need to do a whole bunch more, but this
is really starting to feel like a game.
And this is an awesome point, if you've
created something that you're particularly
proud of and happy with, or even if
you're just a little bit happy with it,
then please, please share a video,
share a screenshot in the discussions.
We'd love to see what you're up to.
This is a great time to do some sharing.
So, well done and
I'll see you in the next lecture.