[MUSIC]
In this video,
we're snapping our cactus to the grid so
it appears within our coordinate
system right in the middle there.
We're resizing a little bit and doing a
little bit of finessing to make sure that
it fits nicely and
there's no overlap between our cacti.
Cacti is it the word?
I think it is.
Okay let's jump in and get started.
So what exactly is going
on here at the moment.
When we're clicking worldPos and
spawning at worldPos,
it's spawning at a place that's
just anywhere underneath the mouse.
So let's do a little Debug.Log and we'll
see exactly what the coordinates are here.
What are we logging, worldPos.
Semi colon.
Back over in to unity.
Let's have a look at the console.
Click on play.
Then when I click,
I am going to get 3.9,2.
4.9, 2.9.
Okay, so we are getting all
these point something or others,
it's allowing us to click wherever and
it's being place underneath that.
To one decimal place that is
showing us here at the moment.
So we want it to be not one decimal
place but to be an integer.
Integers don't have decimal places,
so the way that we are gonna do that,
well, I'm just trying to clean my
console and click on a lot of place.
The way we're gonna that is with
a method called RoundToInt.
So we'll create ourselves which we do this
underneath GetSquareClicked I
think that's a good spot for it.
Create our self private
Vector2 SnapToGrid as a method.
Then we wanna take in an argument
that will be the world position, or
the raw world position.
So we need to say what type it is first.
Type Vector2.
And we'll call this rawWorldPos.
rawWorldPos we'll say.
Save ourselves a few lectures of typing,
rawWorldPos.
And now create a new variable which is
off type float, which we'll call newX
that equals Mathf.RoundToInt is the new
thing we're using here, RoundToInt.
And then, what does it want?
It's looking for a float,
we know we've just received rawWorldPos
when this is being called, so
I'll say rawWorldPos.x because we're
just interested in the x value.
So little microchallenge for you,
go ahead and create the same thing for
a new y variable.
Okay, so float newY =
Mathf.RoundToInt(rawWorldPos.y).
I probably could have copy and
pasted that, but there we go.
We've typed it all out.
And then what do we need to return?
Well, we've already said we
need a vector2 being returned.
So return and we're gonna be returning
a new vector2, so it's not just one value,
we're returning a vector2
which will be newX and newY.
And then we need to be calling SnapToGrid
somewhere, somewhere meaningful.
I think we should do
this in GetSquareClicked,
so right above where we're saying return
wolrdPos, we'll change that in a moment
I can say Vector2 gridPos,
this is the grid position.
We finally got to what
we wanna get to in here.
= SnapToGrid, and then what do we,
now a little micro challenge for you.
What are we passing in SnapToGrid?
We're gonna pass in worldPos.
And then instead of returning worldPos,
what do we wanna return?
That's right, we wanna return gridPos.
Okay, so this is converting world
position into grid position,
we're returning grid position.
This was a method that allowed us
to change our floats into integers,
or at least to round to
the nearest integer.
And then when we're spawning our defender,
the same as we were doing before,
it's taking in this world position.
We can probably rename this
just to make it clear.
It doesn't matter.
This is all local within this method here.
But let's rename it just so
we're not getting confused with
that particular worldPos up there.
We'll say this is, use my Control RR.
We will call this roundedPos.
Just so it's really clear,
that's the final round of position.
Save that, jump back over in to Unity,
click on play and we'll see.
If I click somewhere in the square,
it's putting it in the middle.
Awesome and if I click,
it'll produce a whole bunch of them.
We'll resolve that later on, but now,
we're getting them in just one
spot on the grid, that's so cool.
But we do have a little bit of an issue
where it doesn't quite fit properly so
let's do a little bit of scaling
on our cactus while we're here.
And go and find my sprite, cactus,
and find both idle and looping.
The idle my pixels per unit I'll
change this to 125 and then apply.
And then my cactus looping,
I'll do the same thing for.
Change that to 125, my computer is having
a little bit of slow down at the moment.
You can do it computer.
Click Apply.
Okay and then we see clicking around here,
that's much better although you know what,
not quite right.
They seem a little bit lower in
the square than I want them to do.
So how do we resolve that
if we just move our cactus,
we've got our one that we've dropped
in the, not the canvas, the cactus.
Where are you, cactus?
There you go.
I've got that one in here.
I move that up or down then it's gonna
move the whole thing up or down.
It's not gonna change
when we drop in a prefab.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm
going to break out the cactus so
that we have a cactus parent.
So I right-click, Create Empty.
And I will name this, cactus.
It's a new cactus here.
The old cactus I'm gonna
rename to cactus body,
I would just call it body,
just to make it easier.
And then we'll drag body so
it's underneath cactus, okay.
Good, go back into my prefabs.
Just delete the cactus
that I've got in there.
Delete that, yep, drag in New Cactus so
I can be super clear I've got the correct
cactus and not messing it up.
Now I'll need to go to my spawners, no,
I need to go to my core game area and
change from body defender into cactus.
Where are you, cactus?
[SOUND] Alphabetical order, there we go.
Okay, so
now we've got that hooked up correctly.
Let's just check that our
cactus drops into the scene and
does what it needs to do before
we go forward further on that.
It does and it's way off.
That's cuz we have when we had our
cactus body we need to reset that and
then the body is reset within the cactus.
Okay so now the cactus is at zero, zero.
I can move it around knowing that the body
is reset to zero within the cactus parent.
Okay.
Body is reset to zero.
Now that it's reset to zero,
when I place the cactus in the scene.
So I'll click and drop one.
Okay I want it to be
moved up a little bit.
So I'll grab the bodies,
so here's the cactus.
I'll grab the body and
move that up just a little bit.
Okay, you can see that.
Just a little bit.
So now there's an offset
between the cactus parent and
the cactus body that the cactus body
has been moved up by .14 on the y axis.
And then click on Play, and
I'll see if that's centered.
That's a little bit finicky,
but it's feeling better.
I can probably do it down a tiny bit,
but okay,
I'll do that just so
I can sleep easily at night.
0.1, okay, apply that to the prefab.
Click on Play,
did I play it last time to the prefab,
I'm not sure if I did but click it down.
Now, it's feeling a lot more centered.
In the middle there's no overlap and
success.
They're shooting [SOUND].
Boom, yep, they're shooting, okay,
so it's all looking pretty good.
We've got our cactus in the scene.
We can place it in positions on the grid.
It's snapping to the grid.
It's all feeling quite good.
Great work, well done.
We can now place defenders.
I'll see you in the next video.