[MUSIC]
In this video we're gonna add an extra
couple of hazards such as these spikes, or
the water that when the player touches
them blink it triggers out a death
state as well.
So let's jump in and make some hazards,
couple of pieces of housekeeping first.
I have made a misstep in my previous
video where I've re-introduced our
being able to jump off the wall issue.
That's because I changed the capture or
collide of the player to ease trigger.
Instead of having
the player be the trigger
we need to make the enemy be the trigger
when it comes to that collision moment so
the Captual collider,
that's all the way up to be.
Captual collider on the enemy is now
is_trigger, I'll apply that back to
the prefab, click on my player and
apply that back to the prefab as well.
Always good to make sure we apply that
back, now we have eliminated the issue
that I was seeing when I was doing
the double jump off the wall.
So I can no longer double jump so
the player is not the trigger, and
I can die when bouncing into the enemy.
Okay, and now let's make ourselves some
spikes, some hazards it doesn't have to
be spikes it could be anything it
could be water it could be lava.
The opportunities is as far
as your imagination but
what I've given you, is a couple of
little spikes that I've handcrafted,
let me find my sprite folder over here.
I've just gone and
handcrafted very quickly so
we've got something that
clearly represents an obstacle.
Drop it into my scene here
some little spiky spikes,
change the pixels per unit to 32 and
hit Apply on that.
We're gonna go and do a little bit
of sprite editing on the collision,
it's on the physics shape to jump in here
it's close-ish, it's probably good enough.
I'm just gonna click on that point there,
Delete, and drag this in a little bit
closer just so it's a little bit
tighter around our shape here.
Delete that one click on this nodule,
delete that as well is that a nodule?
It's probably a node, isn't it, and
then I don't need that other one there.
Okay, so that's just a quick
tidy up of the physics shape,
so this is a little bit more
reasonable click Apply.
Remove that so that we've got our spikes
all set up with their physics shape
ready to go as well, which is super cool.
Okay, so now that we've got that, now that
we've got now we have a sprite we can use,
I'm gonna give you the challenge.
This should be something that you
should be able to smash through pretty
straightforwardly, there's not much code,
just one little addition to
our code to make this work.
But, the idea is to make the spikes harm
the player, to create a tilemap, consider
collision, and make sure that you trigger
death when the player touches the spikes.
So that's the challenge,
is to lay down some spikes that
the player can interact with.
Or if you wanna put down water or if you
wanna put down little, all right, some
little toy mushrooms or something that
you think the player would be damaged by.
So pause the video jump in
take on that challenge and
when we come back I'll quickly
go through my solution to this.
Okay, welcome back so first of all we're
going to create yourselves a tilemap.
Right-click to the Object Tilemap,
I am going to rename this tilemap hazards.
You could call it instant death if you
wanted if you wanted to be a little bit
more melodramatic about it.
We'll call it hazards for now, and we've
got already on here a tilemap renderer,
which is cool.
We need to add in addition
to that a tilemap collider,
tilemap collider 2D, so
we have that in there.
And we also have to create ourselves
a layer for physics collisions, so
you can come all the way up to the very
top, click on Layers go to Edit layers.
This is another way to get to this
mechanism, and you can see in here we've
got in here our layers that might be
closed up for you, expand that out.
We can add in here
a hazards layer in here,
while we're at it we need to
make a rendering layer so
that we know where it sits
we will call this hazards.
And the hazards should be above
the foreground above probably
the same place as the enemy
I think is the right spot.
Okay so that's how we got that there so
we've added sorting layer hazards and
layers, nice and confusingly named
I'm gonna call this physics layers,
six layers hazards in there as well.
Back over into our hazards tilemap and
we need to say for
the renderer the sorting layer is hazards.
And up at the top here under layer
we will make sure this is hazards,
the next step is to jump over to Edit.
Project Setting, physics 2D and
to make sure that our
hazards are appropriately
colliding with appropriate things.
I'm gonna turn off collision for
every single thing except for the player.
Which means the enemies will run through,
we need to be a little bit careful not
to make that look silly, but
I think that should be okay.
I'd rather have the enemies kinda
run through this spikes for
now until we decide otherwise.
So the player should be
ticked under hazards here,
that should all line up nice and
perfectly now.
Okay, so let's paint some in there,
you can see that I've made myself a little
hole in my world here
pretty straightforward.
While on my foreground I just use my rule
tile here, if you hold down Shift, It
deletes if you don't hold down shift when
you left click then it paints back again,
so I've just created
a little hole in here.
I'm going to on my main pallet drag
the spikes in to my main pallet here,
that will ask me where
I'd like to save that.
It's going to be saved under tiles and
it is spikes, that is correct,
see it comes in all super
good paint that in.
As always,
make sure you have clicked on the correct
tilemap here when you come to painting.
Click on Hazards,
click back on our spiky tiles,
paint a couple of spikes
in the hole just here.
It is looking pretty good
actually I think, not too bad for
five minutes of Rick art,
[LAUGH] pretty quick Rick art.
Okay, so we have our spikes in
there last couple of steps.
Back onto our Hazards layer,
we make sure that we don't forget
the thing I usually forget, which is
the is trigger on the tarmac collider.
So we now have that set up as a trigger,
over into our scripts we need
to go to the player script.
In play a script we will
go to the mask in here,
we currently have Enemy is a bad thing.
And to do our copy and paste,
head up to Layers at the very top right,
down to Edit Layers&gt; Highlight Hazards,
copy that back over into our script.
And under our die method where we have
our LayerMask.GetMask next to Enemy,
we do comma quotation marks,
paste in hazards,
close quotation and that should
add the extra hazard of hazards.
Now let's go see how that works,
click on Play,
make sure we don't accidentally bump
into our enemy before we get there.
Run, run, run, run and blink, yes,
[LAUGH] my flying into space far too
aggressively as we talked about before.
But now we have some hazards we can put
that anywhere in our scene we can have
spikes here, we can have spikes there,
have things the player jumps over.
It doesn't have to look as spikes we
can add a new as in here, in fact,
let's just do that very quickly
to show how that works.
I'm gonna add one of these
little water tiles in over here,
instead of these spikes
I'll add in some water, and
then maybe I will delete these
other spikes we had in there.
And now that we have on water, it's on the
hazards layer, depending on the hazards
layer, and we drop into the water,
and the water kills us as well.
So that's a great way for us to be
putting a lot of variety in our games so
any of these different themes we
can just paint onto this layer and
it will be hazardous to the player,
which is very cool.
And while we're here let's have a look
at what's going on with our enemy.
Why the enemy is unhappy I'll click Play
and then Pause just as he's getting to
the wall there, zoom in a bunch and
step forward frame by frame.
We can see that as the first trigger
volume exits he flips around
which is good but our new problem
is that this collider that we only
just now said is the trigger so
that it harms the player.
We didn't have this before because this
capture collider wasn't the trigger as
that trigger also exits a collision,
it flips around again.
So, we need to just do a little bit of
editing on the size of those colliders and
positioning.
It's cuz of the center point of the enemy
and where our box collider is here so
a little bit of repositioning I
think will do just nicely on that.
I will go to the box collider,
that box collider here,
oops, box collider, and
click on Edit collider,
move this ad a little bit further,
move that as a little bit further as well.
It's the point where the collider exits
the collision that we wanna know about,
and then I'll tidy up my capture
collider a little bit as well.
Edit collider just to make it
a little bit less big at the back,
I think that the player kinda
brushes against the enemy and
doesn't die that's fine
the player's gonna forgive that.
And just if the player ;ands smack
bang in the middle of the enemy,
then we definitely need to have
that the enemy hurts the player.
So let's try one more time make sure
this is all good Pause, step forward.
We'll see where the point of flip usage
still might be a little bit touching
it's only just out of it okay, that's
pretty good, that should work fine now.
If you find that your
enemy is still flipping,
then you might need to do
a little bit more finessing.
Okay, that looks pretty good and
do we still wow okay,
I might need to turn that down.
When I get sick of seeing my
player fly across the screen,
I'll turn the amount of force down.
But for now, I still find it kinda
humorous, so I'll leave it in there, okay,
so great work in this video.
We've now got to the point where you can
put anything into your hazards layer and
it will add a lot of depth to your game.
Your level by putting spikes, by putting
water, by putting hanging chandeliers that
you bump your head onto,
whatever it is that your heart desires.
Great work and
I'll see you in an upcoming video.