[MUSIC]
So in this video we're gonna
have a look at our level flow.
I'm gonna show you a way to lay this out
using tilemap so that you can see all of
your levels together, your scenes together
and your scenes in the hierarchy.
And we'll talk about, well, what is it
that we wanna show in the very first scene
and then the very second scene and
third scene, and so on.
So we're talking about level flow,
and talking about level layout.
Okay, let's do this.
I'm gonna start by creating
a new folder over in my assets,
over here that I shall call levels.
Seems like a good thing
to call our levels.
Make a little bit more room over here.
Drop our sandbox.
You know what,
I'm gonna rename sandbox to Level 1.
Level 1, as we have it here.
And we're gonna have a little bit of
a conversation about naming convention.
Ben is a big fan of naming things
as the functionality of the level.
I like that I think that's not too bad.
For example,
we could call this single ladder level.
Or we could call it two spikes or
we could call it learn to jump.
I think that is an okay way to do it.
I love a little bit old school in
terms of climb thing level one.
Cuz then I know that level 3 needs to
have a certain thing to introduce it
before the player gets to level 4.
So, if you name it level 1, 2, 3, 4 and
you say, actually we need to have
something in between level 2 and 3, that
could cause a whole bunch of annoyance
when you have to go back and
rename the subsequent ones later one.
I think there's a way around that
where you can have level 2A and
level 3B and so on.
I'm gonna show you something that
we'll do in the flow of this video.
That means you can use either
of the naming systems and
it's gonna work out pretty well, I reckon.
I've got a pretty cool trick for
us to have a look at.
But, first of all, we need to duplicate
a couple of extra levels for ourselves.
So I'll do this after I've dropped
that into my Levels folder.
In the Levels folder here.
Level 1 I'm gonna duplicate, probably
call it level 2, which is done fantastic.
And duplicate again level 3,
I'm going to rename to Main Menu.
Here we go, we got a Main Menu,
a level 1 and a Level 2.
Now there's a really neat trick,
that we can do here that I didn't discover
until I've been using Unity for a while,
probably cuz I didn't have a need for it.
But we can load multiple levels or
multiple scenes at the same time
by dragging them into a hierarchy.
So if I drag Main Menu over here,
you can see it's loaded it up.
Now, they are exactly the same, so
we don't notice any difference.
But what I am gonna do is highlight
all of the Elements underneath my
Main M Menu scene, you can see in there.
If I click on main menu itself,
this doesn't work,
I have to click on everything
underneath it on the hierarchy.
Click on my move tool and
then move it over to the left and
I can visualize this scene,
this level next to this other level here.
I probably messed this up a little bit,
cuz I want to have my main menu being
at the center point, being at my 0,0.
That's where I'm starting from,
so I'm gonna undo that move.
Click on my level 1,
grab all of the timemap everything,
big caveat to this strategy,
you can easily leave things behind.
So this is not for the faint of heart.
This is a technique that comes with a few
issues, but I think it helps me anyway.
This is one of those things if you leave
it on the edge a little bit it can
work pretty well.
But just note you've got to be super
careful when you move things cuz you might
accidentally leave your camera's behind
if you don't click on that properly.
But now I can see,
here's my Main Menu on the left here and
here's my level 1 on the right.
And if we do the same thing for Level 2,
drag that over here into our hierarchy,
I can highlight all of my content in
there and move it over to the right.
And now I can visualize
the progression from the first level
to the second level to the third level.
Or in this case main and then 1 and 2.
Which as a level designer,
as a game designer, this can be brilliant.
Now you could just have using
tilemaps amazing abilities here,
you could just have one gigantic level
that has little areas that you kind of
go into and you can't get back from.
The classic gating technique,
let me just show you,
would be if we had a cliff down here.
But now there's a nice big drop all
the way down to here, no way for
the player to get back up there.
That's what is called a gating mechanism.
So I'm gonna show you this so
there's no confusion on this.
What you need to do,
if I click Play Now, it creates havoc.
If you've got all three of these levels
loaded, which one are we looking at?
We're not exactly sure.
But what I am sure about if
I go into the Scene View,
I've got my other scenes where I
can see my other players there.
They've all died at the same spot in
the same scene, but you can basically
be moving around in all the scenes and the
camera doesn't quite know what it's doing.
So be sure to unload the other two when
it comes time to actually looking at what
you wanna look at.
So I'm going to show you
this principle in level 1,
which means I'll click
on main menu in level 2.
Just clicking I'll roll these up
a little bit so I can see here.
Roll these up.
Okay, all right, Shift click on there,
right click and say, Unload Scene.
And, yeah, we'll save that cuz we
moved them all around, which is cool.
And then we size it, and
when we do that, we only see Level 1.
We can only interact with Level 1.
These two I can't do anything with.
If I moved things around.
If I hit Play then it's only
looking at level 1 in here.
So I can have these just sitting
here all the time if I wanted to.
I tend not to, I tend to clean then up and
pop then back down in there
by saying Remove Scene.
It doesn't delete it,
it just removes it from the hierarchy so
we're not looking at it.
So this is a flow I really like to
go through in this mechanism here.
So I was talking about just briefly just a
little bit of level designing conversation
is very briefly.
Is the gating technique of if you wanted
to have one gigantic level in here,
not worry about loading,
not worrying about any of that stuff,
the player starts way down there.
They have to make their way all the way
up to here and that's where we end it.
You can totally do that using Tilemap,
that's one of the beauties of this tool,
it's very lightweight in
terms of how it works.
I could just get there and
say if I'm on the right layer here,
if i'm on the foreground layer,
I could just go and
make a nice big deep hole in here, since
the player runs along there they jump.
And there's no way for
the player to get back up into
here cuz that's too high a jump.
So this is called a gating mechanism or
gating mechanic.
Because essentially it
puts a gate on the player.
They say you can't go
back through the gate.
I gonna put back, I'm gonna undo all this.
So We can get back up there.
That would be a gating technique if
you wanted to have everything in
one big huge level.
But we're gonna do multiple levels so
we can flex our muscles and
learn a few new techniques in terms of
loading from one level to the next, and
having the player persist and
all those kinds of good things.
So we've got our three levels in here.
And what I want to do in this video and
this lecture,
let me just load this again so
I can see them, load load.
You wanna have a little bit
of a flow going from here.
This Main Menu, in the future we're gonna
put just like a start button over the top
of what's going on in here.
But I want the player to have a chance
just to be able to move the controls left
and right while the main menu is in there.
But I want to have,
if I click on the Play in Main Menu.
Should be able to see the camera
if I click on the Player, Cameras.
Not so good.
Sometimes these things aren't as easy to
visualize if the others are loaded so
let me unload those,
unload that and unload level 1.
Okay, now I can save all that.
Now I can see the camera in here.
I don't really want the play to be
running down here if it's a main menu.
I want main menu just to be one
screens width and height so
I can have a stop button on there and
the play can run left or right.
In my first scene, so
my actual level 1, load scene here.
I want the player just
to do something simple.
Maybe we run up a ladder.
Yeah, maybe just run up a ladder.
Jump a couple of times.
Jump over one single spike down here and
then get to a level exit,
which we'll do in the next video,
that then takes them into the next scene.
We'll load that scene, which would be
maybe a little bit more difficult.
I'm gonna put the enemy in this one for
the first time.
So the general kinda progression
of the game is we're introducing
jumping over hazards in the first one and
then avoiding enemies in the second one.
And then we can get more complex in
the third, in the fourth and so on.
And as we build more features
we can build that into our game,
we can add more things like pickups.
And maybe if we were to do power boosts or
any of that kind of stuff or
a rising water level,
we could do that in future scenes.
So the challenge I've got for you in this
video is to construct your three levels.
Put a bit more time into
it if you fancy yourself
as practicing some of your
level design and flow.
Less time in it if you just want
the mechanics and the functionality of it.
Make sure they're short simple levels,
we don't want huge things because we will
be adding more levels in the future, or
you will be adding more levels and
more features and functionality.
So don't make them too huge,
you don't wanna bore the player by having
seven minutes of here's how you jump,
is what I'm saying.
And if you find that you want to make
your middle, say level one here,
wanna make it bigger and progress it
outside of the area that we've got.
Then you can easily just pickup level 2,
and
say, let's move level 2
down there a little bit.
So management of these things become very
easy to move your entire levels around
when you grab the first one and
the second one.
Or we just grab the level 1 and
move that over to here,
giving ourselves more space, and so on.
So that's pretty easy to
move those around and
is a great way to manage our level flow.
So recapping the challenge here,
make some progression,
create a main menu scene, level 1 scene,
and level 2 scene, as we've done here.
Add logical progression using
our limited feature set.
Acknowledge that we don't
have a lot at the moment so
don't try to do too much with the levels.
Just making interesting
with what we've got.
And map out where the end
point will be in each.
So, we know the next video where
we're gonna put out level loads.
So, take some time,
pause the video now and
make yourself a couple of levels
that the player can run through.
Okay, welcome back.
I'll briefly show you what I've
done with my three level here.
This is the Main Menu,
Level 1 and Level 2.
I'll unload level 1 and 2 just for
the presence so
I can focus on my Main Menu screen.
My goal here is so that as the big stop
button is on the screen, the start and
the quick button and maybe an options,
if we get to that point in the future.
Can be on the screen but at the same
time the player has some control for
running around.
So we'll do those menu
things in upcoming videos.
But for now I just wanna make sure
that the camera doesn't move.
Through that I've just gone and
disabled the state-driven camera.
Just turn the whole thing off so
that all we're using here and
the CineMachine Brain
is the important part.
You can probably leave the state-driven
camera on actually and
I'll turn it off now.
But so long as you turn off
the CineMachine Brain we're back to our
regular old orthographic camera.
I've set the size to seven.
I can move it around a little
bit to get my framing right.
Then when I hit Play it's just
a regular camera that's not gonna move,
gives the player an opportunity on
this first level just to move and
jump so they can say,
that's what the controls are.
You could even have this,
the tutorial screen, we just have
a little keyboard layout there.
The hit left to go left, hit right to
go right and hit space to jump, so
you have that printed onto
the background if you wanted to.
So that's our main menu screen and
then we would flow onto level 1.
So load level 1 scene and
I will save and unload main menu.
Just so it's not getting in the way,
here pretty much the same
as what we had before.
My goal here is to introduce
the player to hazards, and
to show them they can jump over hazards.
And to see very clearly that this is
a long pit with spikes down the bottom so
straight away they can see ha,
spikes are a bad thing I should avoid, and
a little bit of the curiosity to the left.
My goal here is to introduce
the player to hazards, and
to show them they can jump over hazards.
My goal here is to introduce
the player to hazards, and
to show them they can jump over hazards.
Ever again and we've got a ladder here.
My goal here is to introduce
the player to hazards, and
to show them they can jump over hazards.
And then for level 2,
I will unload level 1.
Level 2 over here I started off with
the player with a fairly high drop.
I wanted to be out of the camera view so
it can teach the player it's
okay to drop as far as you want.
So there's a little bit of the,
what do I do here?
Can I reach that jump?
And if we've got our camera stuff
on to show the player as well,
if you do a little bit of a jiggle
then you get a bit more of a view
when you're idling, then the camera
comes in if you want to show that.
I can do a jump, bounce on the roof
up there and land here and
see that, that's okay.
The other thing is to
introduce enemies and
to show them that the enemy
will run down that way.
That's an opportunity to run up
the ladder, a nice simple kind of little
puzzle down there, little super, super
simple puzzle, how to avoid the enemy.
And then we've got a ladder up here.
And run, run, run, run.
The last thing I want to show
them is this mechanism of,
this wall is too high to jump.
So this gives the player an opportunity
within the first minute or
two of the game to see exactly
how high they could jump.
On this one is kind of three in height.
They might not be counting out
the blocks the way you and I are doing.
But they see roughly that height,
I can land on that.
But I can't get back this way, so
that's the gate that I was clicking at.
And we're teaching them that if
you get to a point where you land,
you fall down on something.
Then you might not be
able to get back again.
And then just a big ladder ahead,
and the scene, and
this would be where the exit would be.
So that's some level flow and progression.
Laying out our levels in a way that
we can see them all at the same time.
So that we can make decisions about
the flow and the progression.
And in the next video, we'll add
ourselves a level exit mechanism, so
that we can actually go
from here to here to here.
I'll see you in the next video.