Hello and welcome, in this video we're
gonna be implementing our hilarious image
of Rick with silly looking hat on.
And playing around with the anchor
points to make sure that when we change
the aspect ratio of our game, or
if the player's changing the aspect ratio.
That our elements stay anchored to where
we want them to stay on the screen.
Don't have any weird stretching and
don't have any weird floating.
So let's jump in and talk anchor points.
Because we're starting a new section we
need to start a new project, I'm calling
mine number wizard UI, saving it in Repos,
whoops, I didn't mean to click it.
Unity 2D Number wizard UI is
where I'm selecting my project,
and 2D is our template and
I'm using 2018.2.
Create project,
this'll take a minute or so.
So what I'm going to do is pause my
recording, you might wanna pause
the video, and then once Unity has loaded
up the project, I will see you back here.
Welcome back,
I'm gonna start this process by saving
our scene as something different.
I'm gonna Save As and we'll call this,
we'll put it into the Scenes folder.
It's quite clever we have a Scenes folder
in there well done default unity thank
you for that, we will call this
Start Menu this will be the scene.
It's okay I have spaces where we're naming
our scenes no worries click Save on that,
we have Start Menu and Sample Scene,
I'm gonna go ahead and
delete Sample Scene we
don't need that anymore.
Let's go into a hierarchy right click,
got to UI and
click on Canvas, that will create a UI
Canvas, you might need to double click
on it to get it nice and
highlighted on the scene here.
The first thing I'll do while on
Canvas is change how UI scale mode to
scale with screen size.
If it's on constant pixel size then it
will try to keep everything the exact
pixels that we have on our screen here,
no matter what's going on.
Once I got to put the reference
resolution to 1920 by 1080,
that shows Unity, this is what we
think it's most likely to be, and
scale from this,
scale from this resolution.
Use that as our benchmark.
Okay, we've got our canvas, we've set
that up and I'll right click on Canvas.
Scroll down to UI, and
we will put in a Button, click on Button.
And see button sitting
on the screen there,
might need to scroll in a little bit.
I'm gonna make my button a little big
bigger, again just by dragging on
the bottom, dragging on the right,
dragging on the top.
We can scale up our button, I'll move
the button over to the right a little bit.
And there we go,
we have ourselves a button.
And we're looking at the functionality of
the button in the next couple of videos,
but for now we're looking at
the positioning, and the scaling, and
the anchoring of the button.
If you look in the middle of your screen,
you can see that we
have our anchor points.
All four anchor points are together,
that means that we have this
one central anchor point.
The different anchor points relate to
the different sides of our button.
So, the top left anchor point relates
to the top left of our button,
the bottom right,
the bottom right, and so on.
We can grab the anchor points and
stretch them out.
That's gonna show there's a relationship
between this top-left point and
that top-left point there.
What relationship, I hear you ask?
Well, this is important if our
screen resolution changes.
So if I switch from 16:9 to say 5:4,
and you can see 5:4 is more of
a squarish resolution whereas 16:9
is more of a wide screen resolution.
You can see when we change to 5:4,
you'll see that our box
stretched up a little bit here.
If we click on our button, and
click on our anchor presets,
we can change that to for example,
just the bottom right here,
the options around
the outside of a stretching,
and the options within the inside here
at an anchor at a particular point.
So you can see left, center, and
right, top, middle, and bottom.
And you see stretch and stretch.
If you would said let's anchor to left and
top, we click on this button just here.
Now our anchor points all move up, all
four of them move up to the top left, and
we say, what about if it's right and
bottom?
Then they all move down
to the bottom right.
If we click on stretching, that's when
they pull apart, and they say, when
the Canvas grows, then the button should
grow in the same proportion to the Canvas.
It should stretch up in the same way,
that the Canvas is doing,
we see that a lot more pronounced if we go
to free aspect, than when we stretch and
move it, it changes based upon the
distance from this point to that anchor,
or that point to that anchor.
It's trying to keep those distances
the same irrespective of what
size this Canvas is changed to.
What we're more likely to do with our
button is say let's anchor our button to,
for example, the top right of the screen.
And I'll move it up a little bit more so
we can see this more clearly, so
I'll move it up there to the top right.
It's anchored to the top right,
still on free aspect, as we move around,
you can see that it's staying up on
the top right of our screen over here.
It's not moving to different parts.
If I was to move it around like this and
to say let's anchor to the bottom left,
then as we moved around it's
gonna try to keep it in the same
distance from the bottom left to our
anchor point down at the bottom.
I'm gonna switch back to 69, and
I'll show you, move my button back into
the middle here, I'll show you another
example which has to do with images.
So I've given you a couple of images
against this lecture for you to download.
They may be zipped, but go grab those
if you'd like, or you can totally
use your own images, if you wanna
play around with your own images,
I've got my hilarious wizard images here.
So you gonna drag those into my project,
just click and drag.
Here we go, we've got a Rick and
we've got a Ben.
Now, within Canvas, I click on Canvas,
right click, go to UI and
then Image I'm gonna move my image
just a little bit out of the way.
Careful you don't accidentally grab the
anchor points, that's pretty easy to do.
I'm gonna move my image down
the bottom left, that's good.
Now what I want to do, is to have the Rick
image be placed on top of
my image game object here.
So gonna change this to,
rename it to Wizard Rick, so it's nice and
clear what we're doing here.
And from in the inspector, while I clicked
on Wizard Rick, if I click on under image,
you can see there is a source image,
currently is None.
If I click on this selector, scroll down
until I find the image I'm looking for,
which is the Wizard Rick and
that replaces the white box without image.
Pretty easy, now I can move around and
scale this image, one of the issues
you see that if I scale it like that it
gets stretched and a little bit ugly.
And if you do that, if you get it
stretched and it's out of proportion it's
really easy to get it back is by click
Set Native Size in the inspector.
So you say, Set Native Size,
click on that, and
it'll take it back to
the size you imported it at.
And reposition this a little
bit over on to the left and
make it a bit bigger in the screen by
holding down shift and scaling out,
that will scale it in proportion,
that will keep the aspect ratio correct.
Okay, currently you can see that
Wizard Rick is anchored to the middle of
the screen that should be okay.
But, if someone is playing at an aspect
ratio of 4:3, you can see we've now got
this huge big gap underneath Wizard Rick,
and it looks pretty terrible.
So what we wanna do is to have it so
it doesn't float in mid air.
And that is a challenge
I'm going to set for you.
How can we anchor Wizard Rick in
a way that he doesn't float with
a big gap underneath him.
I'm also gonna set you the challenge of
setting up your button, don't worry about
the look of the button just yet,
we'll be doing that in upcoming videos.
But, get your button so
it is anchored to the right of the screen.
So here's the challenge, anchor your
elements, create a start button and
anchor it to the right of the screen.
Import an image or
use the image that I've given to you and
anchor to the bottom left of the screen,
so that if the screen resolution changes,
those two elements stay in sensible
positions and don't look too crazy.
So there's your challenge,
jump in and take that on, and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okay, welcome back, so what I'm going
to do with the Wizard Rick here,
clicking on Wizard Rick I'm going
to change the anchor point to
the bottom left, and I could just move
it down to the bottom left like that.
I'm gonna show you a little trick here,
if you're clicked on the anchor presets,
if you hold down, there's a couple
of clues here, Shift and Alt.
If you hold down Alt, and
then find the bottom left,
if I click on that it will shift
the image down to the bottom left.
I could have clicked on shift to top left,
or top right, or another position, and
that just helps me easily
position things on the screen.
Not pretty cool to do that,
that's just to help you line things up.
So checking my pivot
is in the bottom left.
Now if I change my aspect ratio to any of
these other things, it's still staying
bottom left no matter what, so
we don't get that weird gap underneath.
I know that 16:9 is probably
the lowest of my profiles.
So long as my image fits
on the screen at 16:9 and
isn't chopped off at the top,
I know that all is good.
Now with the button, let me just
make my button a little bit more of
a sensible shape,
don't worry about the text for the moment,
we'll be dealing with
that in upcoming videos.
And I will click on my anchoring, click on
the right, so middle and right is fine.
You could do it bottom right
if you wanted, or top right,
either of those is fine.
l'll do it middle right, that means it
will be maintaining an equal distance from
the right-hand side of our button to this
point right in the middle of the screen.
So if we scale around our screen, you can
see that there's a lot of things added to
the top and the bottom of the space,
added to the top and
the bottom the button stays
mostly in the middle.
And I wanna move that down a little
bit for this aspect ratio and
at 16:10 it looks fine,
16:9 looks good as well.
Okay, so that is us we've started
the process of anchoring,
we've imported an image, created a button.
We're gonna be doing a lot more cool
stuff with buttons in upcoming videos.
Great work, and
I will see you in the next video.