[SOUND] Hello again, in this video,
we're gonna create a simple level exit,
so that when my player jumps
over the enemy, hits the exit,
then we trigger our next level loading.
So let's jump in and get cracking.
The first step in the process is to create
a visualization for our level exit.
I have gone and
created a little exit sign here, that
you can download against this lecture.
I need to sort out my asset folder here,
its all over the place.
There we go, sprites and
tiles, put it into sprites.
Dragging that into our sprites folder,
you can see it there.
Well, I've clicked on this.
If I right click,
created 2D object sprite,
that image is automatically populated
into our sprite slot here which is handy.
I'm gonna rename this to Level Exit and
we don't see it at the moment so
I will move over to the general position.
We need to sort out our layers,
our sorting layer in particular.
We'll go out to the top right here,
click on Layers, Edit Layers and
I will add a new layer which
I'm gonna call Interactibles.
Interactables, which
basically saying things that the player
should be able to touch, pick up.
Coins, power ups,
any of that kind of stuff.
I also create that in our physics
layers here, Interactables.
Pasting it from up the top so
it's then same name, and
then on our little exit I'll assign
the sorting layer to intractable.
Now it should appear and also the layer,
layer to intractable as well.
Such confusion with the layer, layer.
Okay, now that we've got that.
Our last step in this process is to
make sure that the project settings,
physics 2D, without intractable is
interacting with just the player.
So that other things aren't
accidentally causing our interactible
to be interactibled with,
if that makes sense.
So I've clicked off all of the other
interactable check boxes and
it's just player that
can interact with that.
Back over to level exit here.
We need to add ourselves some collision.
So I'll add a box collider 2D.
Make that a trigger, either that or
the player needs to be a trigger.
We're gonna make this a trigger and then,
that looks pretty good in terms of that.
It could be a little bit bigger.
I'm gonna just reset the z axis here to 0,
so that it's not floating in and out.
You can see, if I go into 3D modes,
then it does have an x position.
It doesn't really, sorry,
a z position, or a z position.
It doesn't really matter so much,
but I just like to have it at 0, so
it's all lined up nice and neatly there.
I will also increase it in scale.
I think I'll double it in size.
It's a bit bigger in there.
Okay there we have now exit
image that we can interact with.
Next part of the process is to
create some behavior for that.
So add a component, I'm going to call this
script a level exit, and create that.
Now in level exit, I'm not gonna need
the start and update methods, so
I'm going to get rid of
those right from the get go.
So I'll just pseudo code this out and
I'll make it a little bit cryptic, so
that there's some challenge for
you in the challenge.
So we need to create a method which
will be WhenSomethingHappens.
I recommend you rename this method to
something a little bit more sensible,
but at the moment, I'll call this
WhenSomethingHappens as our method here.
And then when something does happen,
we want to start coroutine.
In the coroutine we need
to have an IEnumerator.
IEnumerator, there we go, and
the IEnumerator Has A Name,
HasAName and
you will name them as you like, and
in here we need to have some
sort of yield with a delay.
Then what else do we need to do?
We need load the next scene.
Okay, so that's our pseudo code.
Something's gonna happen, want you to
figure out what it is that needs to
happen, then we start our coroutine.
Name the coroutine, sorry, start
the coroutine and name the IEnumerator.
And put that up here in the coroutine and
then we yield with the delay and
then we load the next scene.
I'm gonna give the code just now for
loading the next scene actually.
So this is more of a coroutine
exercise than a figuring out
how to lead the next scene exercise.
So I'll show you this process
while we're here together.
I'm gonna create a variable,
we first of all need to get what
the current scene is that we're on.
Which reminds me we need to go into
moment and set up our build settings,
we'll do that in just a moment.
The current scene index because each
scene has an index will be what?
Well we need to make sure we're
using the right namespace using
the unityengine.scene management.
Yep that's the one.
Took a moment to remember that.
So in here we know when
we say scene manager,
we can use scene manager now that
we're using that name space.
Scene manager.getactivescene.
Get active scene, and .buildIndex.
So we find out what is the current
build index and my apologies for
all the squiggly red lines, cuz we
are doing this with in the pseudo code.
With in we've got proper code.
It's not auto completing and
it's got squiggly lines and so
a little bit ugly and a mess.
And I'm sure some of you out there
are yelling at the screen and saying, Aah!
What's going on here.
That's doesn't work proper but
the point is I wanna give you
a bit of a challenge and
not give it to you all precisely.
These two lines will be the once
that when I give to you precisely.
The second line of this is that,
what do we do now with our scene manager,
now that we have index, we need to add
one to it, to save the next scene.
So we say scenemanager.loadscene,
so we want to load the next scene.
Load next scene is this currentsceneindex
up here, which I'm gonna copy and
paste because my auto complete is not
gonna work with that with my ID because
it's not fitting within something
that makes sense to it, +1.
Okay, so this part of the code in here,
I'll just give a space,
this part is written in a way which
will say, take us to the next scene.
And the other part of it is the other
part of the code that you should have
all the foundation now to complete
that in a pretty straight forward way.
Before I give you the challenge, we'll go
back here and setup our build index so
that we know that it is accurate.
I will go into my scenes or
my levels, highlight them all.
Drag them into the scenes and build.
Need to make sure that this
main menu is the top one.
So it'll have seen indexes zero and
then level one, level two.
As I mentioned in the last video,
we can update these in the future so
they have more of a functionality name.
So level with the ladder and
the first time you meet an enemy, but for
now I'm leaving it at level one and two so
it's super clear what it is
that we're doing as we do it.
So you know what I'm up to in my levels.
Okay, we don't need to click build,
back into here.
Having a look at our script, you can
see that there's a little bit to do.
So I'm gonna issue a challenge which is,
let me just roll that back up.
Step one, use collision check to determine
when the player has reached the exit.
Use a Coroutine so that level doesn't load
instantly, and I'm gonna give you bonus
points if you add something flashy and
share with the community!
So I'd love to see something
that you put in there.
A big like particle effect, or maybe a
swirling portal, or have the screen blink.
Or the player do a back flip, something
flashy to say that you have finished
the level, you've completed it,
now you're learning the next level.
So those of you who are into a bit of
flash, put something flashy in there.
Share it with the community, let us
know about it, whether it's Facebook, or
through the Q&amp;A section or
through our community forum.
We would love to see some of your
flair that you've put into it.
That would be super cool.
So there's the challenge.
This is the code that you need
to work through and tidy up and
have no red lines once
you've completed this.
And I will see you back here
when you've got that done.
Okay, welcome back.
So I don't know about you, but
these red lines are really
driving me a little bit crazy.
I'm looking forward to tightening this up.
First of all,
we need to have a on trigger enter.
So, OnTriggerEnter2D will be,
so OnTriggerEnter2D, so
that's the thing that needs to happen.
And that's not gonna auto
complete it complete for me.
That's what I get when I try to be clever,
and give you a challenge without having it
auto fill for me and
my ID doesn't know what's going on.
So I have to type it a lot manually but
that's fine.
It's good to practice typing.
Okay, so start coroutine.
Well, what sort of coroutine?
We'll type this correctly as well.
StartCoroutine.
Now, it knows what's going on.
We'll call this LoadNextLevel
which is what we wish to do.
LoadNextLevel()) semicolon
at the end of that.
I'm going to grab this,
copy this LoadNextLevel,
just in case it doesn't wanna auto fill
for me, that will be our IEnumerator.
So the StartCoroutine(LoadNextLevel()),
then we're coming down
here to LoadNextLevel().
We need our parentheses
at the end of that.
Starting to get a few less
red squiggly lines in here.
What sort of yield do we need?
Cuz we're using our IEnumerator
we do need to yield,
we will yield return is our syntax.
New, [INAUDIBLE] well I like to wait for
seconds real time, so
I know I can count one and count two and
count three, it's the real time seconds.
And then, how long would that be?
Well, we could make that, say, 2f.
Or, even better, we could serialize this,
and say LevelLoadDelay, so
we don't have any magic numbers
buried within our code down there.
And we will right up to the very top of
our class here, we'll say, SerializeField.
This is stuff we've done before.
So it should be pretty familiar.
Hopefully you had good success
with the challenge and
it matches what I'm doing here.
Even if my names are a little bit
different to yours that's okay.
So our [SerializeField]
float LevelLoadDelay.
Okay, and we'll initialize that to 2 F.
So two seconds that will be.
Wait for seconds,
real-time will be two seconds.
As up her,
we can change that in the inspector, and
then we have to load the next
scene is what we need to do.
So we'll save.
Let's hop back over into our scene,
I will click play, and all going to plan.
My player will do what
they're supposed to do.
Jump into that one second,
two second and badoom.
There we go, the next level.
Super cool.
Now, I'm gonna add one
last bit to this video,
which is my own little bit of flashiness.
Hopefully, you took a moment to
put some flashiness in there.
I'm gonna put the flashiness in which
is a little bit of a slow-mo moment,
like a slow-motion moment, when we
go through the level to sort of slow
everything down,
[NOISE] you made it kinda thing.
To do that, to make that look interesting,
I need to grab my enemy or grab a enemy.
Prefabs, Enemy, just so
we can see the effect.
I'll put it right there as an interesting
little obstacle that you have to jump over
the enemy to get in.
This is my Obstacle level.
So I'll take the enemy
out in the future but for
now I'm just using this for
illustrative purposes.
Jump back over into my levelExit script.
And there's a method we can use in
here at the top of our loadNextLevel.
We can use Time.timeScale.
Time.timeScale which allows
us to say how fast or
how slow our entire game is going to run.
We can put that and say 0.2f.
Even better once again run
a magic number buried in there.
Let's say our LevelExitSlowMoFactor.
Nice long, big, descriptive.
I'm gonna copy that up here,
and serialize field.
I'll parametrize and serialize this.
Float, LevelExitSlowmoFactor
= 0.2f semicolon.
It's important that we
return it back to normal.
We return the matrix back
to it's normal speed.
It's also important you don't
overuse this time dot time scout.
It's pretty cool.
You can do it for
really cool moments in your game, but
don't use it to much cause players will
get a little bit upset if it's happening
on every single little time they jump,
for example, but we need to return it.
So we've done our yield,
we've gone back to our co routine.
We've gone off for x number of seconds and
then when it returns,
when it continues with load next level,
it will be after our yield.
So at this point we need to
say time.timeScale equals
back to normal which is 1f,
and that is normal timescale.
Okay let's see how this goes,
save back into the build click play.
Make sure that there is nothing
weird that is going on with that.
Let's see if I can actually hit this
jump without bouncing into the enemy.
Yep, got that, and then in there and
then [NOISE], all slows down, and
then we load the next level.
So that's a little bit of flashiness,
it's probably not
as flashy as whatever flashiness you
put in, but I think it's pretty cool.
The last steps we would do is
we would load our other scenes.
Actually at the moment, in my main menu
scene, I'm gonna click a start button so
I don't need the exit there.
And in level two,
we don't actually have a level three, so
I wouldn't need the exit yet.
So this is actually the only scene
that needs the exit for the moment.
So it's tight for now until we
have more scenes and more levels.
So that's us, we've created a level exit.
Hope you did well in this video, and
I'll see you in an upcoming video.