This video we're going to be learning about tags in unity and we're also going to be creating an unbreakable
block.
So to get started on that.
First of all I want to just recap the block types that I'd like to have in our game.
We've talked about this before right at the very start of this section we're all talking about the game
design.
We want to have damage level so when the ball hits a block it doesn't destroy immediately it has multiple
levels of damage and also to have unbreakable blocks.
And it's the unbreakable blocks we're going to be focussing on in this lecture.
Also we want to have all I want to have some different size blocks so for example we can have a huge
block in the middle.
Maybe that's the thing that we apply the multiple damaged levels too.
And we can also have small blocks that have maybe one here in the blocks and have to have different
block size different block damage levels and unbreakable blocks.
And as I mentioned we're going to be using tags to do this and I've given you the link to the documentation
on tags.
The good thing to look at in here is tags help you identify game objects for scripting purposes so they
help us say is this game object the particular game object we're looking for in our case it's to say
Should this be destroyed or not destroyed.
In other words is it breakable or not but it could be.
Is this a an enemy that I'm trying issue therefore to give the enemy damage or can this rocket collide
with a spaceship or not.
Why with the spaceship so tag's is a handy way of giving something an identity that we can then ask
about you our code and to apply that back to what we're doing here.
If we add the tags to our breakable blocks we had at the tag breakable end of the unbreakable blocks
we had the tag unbreakable then we can say things like if the tag is breakable then do particular things.
If the tag is unbreakable then do some other types of things.
So that's the logic we're working on for our current game.
And if you click on your prefab block or you can also click on one of the blocks in your scene but fanelle
will click on the prefab because then it will apply any changes we make to all of the blocks in the
scene.
If we click on our prefab and then up in the top right of the Inspector you'll see something that says
Teg.
Currently it has untagged next to it.
Click on the untagged.
You'll see that there's one two three four there's a whole bunch of current tag options that are default
with unity.
So for example player on main camera I'm going to add our own tags so we click on Add tag.
You see that list is empty.
There's a little plus button click on the plus and then we're going to create breakable capital B.
And then click save.
Also will create a second one which is unbreakable.
And then click on Save or hit enter.
So you've got breakable and unbreakable now we need to go back to our block prefab up to tag and actually
tag that as breakable.
So click on breakable and because we changed it on our prefab which would click on any of our blocks
in our scene we can see that they are breakable because it applies immediately to all of the instances
while we are here.
I'm going to duplicate my blog actually while I'm here I'm going to rename this to breakable so you
can right click rename or just click in the name area and call this breakable block.
OK.
Now in a duplicate So control deal komenda.
Right click rename.
I'll call this unbreakable lock.
Well clicking an unbreakable block I'm going to make sure that I can see the Sprite renderer in my inspector
and change the colour from yellow to kind of a grey type of colour so I can see that this is unbreakable.
Drag that into my scene.
Now I have an unbreakable block in my scene and while I'm here I'm going to duplicate this a couple
of times so I've duplicated it and then holding down controlled it snap a place.
So I've got this little wall down the bottom of our level which makes interesting.
We have to go around the wall to get up to the main part of our game.
And also if the ball is up here then it can do a little bit of bounce bounce bounce in a little bit
of pinball type ricocheting which I think is pretty cool.
Okay so now we need to have a look at what do we do with our code and I'm going to be focussing on one
script which is the block not seeing scripts are open that up.
Now if you haven't already within block dotsie s there's going to be two places where we need to add
our code to say only do something if it's tagged as breakable.
And I'm going to give you a challenge at this point.
So we'll be adding some if statements will be one if statement will put it in two places so in two places
and if statements.
So our code only applies to breakable blocks.
And here is the code.
If tag equals equals and this is another way of us saying does it.
Is it currently assigned us.
Is the tag currently equalling breakable if we only had one equal in there it would be say I would be
saying I want you to make tag as the thing that's an assignment.
If there's one equals it's assignment same thing on the left should now be assigned the value of the
thing on the right.
If there's two equals it's saying it's saying that Teg currently equals breakable so asking if tag currently
equals breakable.
Then do our code.
OK.
So that's how we test for our tagging breakable.
That's your challenge.
Jump in find two places in Block dotsie is where we can add that and I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okay so what are the two places will place number one is we want to make sure we're only destroying
the block if it's tagged as destroyable.
This is part of our collision method in here.
Right above destroy block.
I'll say if I open parentheses tag.
Equals.
Quotations.
Breakable.
Make sure you spell it exactly the same.
This is one of the downsides of the string reference is if we spell this slightly incorrectly then not
we don't know what's going on or if we create this in here and then over in unity we go and change the
name of our tag we say you know maybe we should call it distractable then we have to remember that we
have a hard coded breakables a string reference.
Now open curly brackets and close code brackets and that E is destroyed block so only destroy it.
If it's breakable call now the other place we need to do this is to make sure we're only counting the
breakable blocks because at the start we say can up pull the blocks is going to count up 8 9 10 11 12
13 14 say there's 14 blocks in the scene after we destroy the eight we can destroy.
We won't be able to destroy these and the game will be sitting there saying well you've still got another
six weeks to destroy.
So we need to make sure they're not included in our calculation to do that.
We wrap our level count breakable blocks in an IF statement.
What I'm going to do is a quick rename I've noticed this just now as I'm looking at it are rename my
current count breakable blocks that's in our level C S script.
We've got our public public method we're calling in here.
I will rename the spectre block dotsie is rename this to just straight up count blocks.
Because we're not yet at the point telling it with that account breakable blocks or unbreakable blocks.
At this point it just knows to count the blocks.
So I'm going to rename that and I'm not sure how to rename we've done this a few times.
But you're right click and rename make sure it's applying to all the places that it is named that for
us it's overing level script as well so.
Yep.
Cowpox has been renamed.
Now if I put a bar of level count box I say if a tag equals equals quotations breakable.
And then again wrap this in our coin brackets.
Level.
Count blocks.
Great.
And then I'm going to do a quick tidy up of my start method.
Generally I don't like to have to interpret and read what's going on.
There's some code in here.
What's exactly happening here.
All of this code is saying basically just the count breakable blocks.
So I'll highlight everything from level down to the cold bracket here everything with my start method
right click and then we're going to re factor on Peacey we have the double click extract method and
this is where we say count what's count breakable blocks because that's precisely what it's doing it's
just counting the breakable blocks and then we can look at our start method count breakable walks.
Okay.
Got it.
And if I need to get clarification then I can go have a look at what's going on in there.
If I add another couple of things that we need to do in the start menu it's not a start method it's
not going to get too full and busy so we'll save this up jump over into unity see if it is time we celebrate
or not just yet.
I think it is time way for my scripts to compile.
It often takes a little bit of time.
Like my game we know a bit bigger.
Click on play drive the paddle over the right shoot up into the air and not braking because I've screwed
it up.
What have I done wrong.
Okay let's have a look breakable.
I left this as breakable which I should have changed to unbreakable.
So that's one of the downsides of duplicating you get everything that comes with it and sometimes you
can forget so it should be unbreakable.
We've done that on the prefabs so it should be applied to all of our breakable blocks.
Well done.
If you did that yourself without making my mistake.
Now let's launch the ball up.
They don't break.
But boy you are definitely not breaking a game is definitely fast.
I just want to make sure that the yellow blocks do break as this is too slow.
That's good drive on over here and they do explode and not exploit.
Excellent.
So we've made ourselves a different type of block which is unbreakable.
The level should still low.
You might want to test that yourself.
I haven't tested that but I'll do that.
Off camera just to make sure that when we did defeat the last destroyable block it does load to the
next level and we've used tags in the process.
Great work and I'll see you on the next like Shah.