Hello Mark.
I I'm in this video.
We're going to be creating our Start Menu our game over menu putting in our text and creating our buttons
so that we can do things such as logging on START and Starting our game.
So things that we've done before about superimportant to make sure that we've got a four game loop so
that's jumping to get started.
This video's going to be structured as a big challenge for you.
So the challenge is to connect the scenes.
What I mean by that is to create a Start menu scene and a game overseen that we can connect with our
games screen and the buttons you all need on the Start menu are a start game and quit an on the game
overseen you need a player in end main menu so make sure you've got that functionality.
And we need to have a level dot C S where we write our public methods.
We need to have a load game over method load games scene loads start menu and quick game.
Now what I'd like to say is that I'm going to do this in a very simple way.
I'm just going to literally say load the game over scene by using a string reference and just that part
of the reason to do that is so that we can use it because we haven't used it before and to see what
the pros and cons are of doing that.
If you want to do something that's more sophisticated or more complicated or more scalable then absolutely
go ahead and doing that.
To do that particularly if you're a bit more experienced.
Sorry take on that challenge and see you back here soon.
Okay so the first thing to do is just to make sure that everything is prefabbed so that I can easily
create new scenes knowing that I have my prefabbed items my Starfield closeness staff feel fine need
to drag into my prefab for is one at a time.
Starfield There we go.
Roger that's hanging out my saying I'm going to get rid of him now.
I think we need him.
Thank you so much Roger for your support.
And we're ready to roll also right click in the hierarchy create empty.
I will rename this to be level as a level game object would be level controller or level loading but
I was going to court level reset the transform by right clicking on level.
I need to add a script so into my scripts folder right click create a C sharp script which I will call
level.
Again this could be level loading because that's all it's doing.
But until we have more functionality just calling it level is totally fine.
So drag level over onto our level game object and we're ready to roll.
Double click on that.
Which will open up visual studio.
I am going to remove my start and update method and create a few public methods in here that we can
call so.
First of all public volleyed What shall we do first.
I will do star load so low.
Start menu.
And then open those parentheses curly braces.
We need to use the scene management so using unity engine Dort seen management semicolon make sure we
are using that and then what are we doing in our load's start menu while I'm going to do a very literal
way of working through this.
I'm going to say just load this particular scene.
It's not super scalable and it's something you can get stuck.
If you do it the wrong way.
But I want to show you a slightly different way to what we've done in other videos and what we're going
to do and other sections of the course loads start menu.
I know in my game that start menu is always going to be the very first scene in my game so I'm going
to say.
Scene manager daut Load scene and then in parentheses I'm going to put 0.
Because I know this will absolutely be seen as zero.
The very first scene I know that for a fact if it was in the first scene then things would not go well
so it's just fine.
Bear in mind take the next method public and avoid load.
What are we learning.
Load the MAIN game again.
I've only got one level in my game if you have a game where you complete the level and you go the next
level.
Next level then you need to do something similar to what we did and block break.
But I've just got the one game scene sorry in here.
Actually I don't call it.
I'm just going to call it load game because in my scenes it's actually called who did it.
It seems called game so I just call that load game and then parentheses.
And in our ops in our calibrators he is seen manager dot.
Seen.
And I'm going to do this slightly differently.
Then I did my load.
The start menu just to show you a different way of doing this.
I'm going to use a string reference for this where I have in my quotations game and then semicolon.
So you can load something based upon the scene index or based upon the name of the scene.
Why don't we like string references.
Well if I went and changed the name of game to B.
I don't know.
Level 1 for example or WIPs or main game or any of those sorts of things.
Then my string reference in here won't update and it won't know what's going on but I wanted to do it
so that we've seen how it is done.
OK.
Next up another public method public void and we will do in here.
The load game over.
Parentheses and then our curly braces again.
Seen manager.
Dot load's seen and I know always my game over it is going to be called Game Over.
So I'll put that in my quotations.
Very cool.
And then the last thing we need in here public voyt Aid.
What are we going to call this quits game.
Parentheses And then my colleague bracers work in a tight application dot quipped.
Parentheses semicolon.
We've got quit game load game over load game and load start menu that's all look pretty good.
Now let's go and make ourselves some scenes.
And I'm going to create my scenes two different ways again to show you two different ways.
You might have done at one or you might have done it the other way before I forget.
I'm going to prefabbed my level game object set sitting in there so everything is blurry That means
everything's being prefect.
OK.
So within scenes a right click create scene if I find scene there it is scene.
We'll call this start menu.
Start menu Exel want and then with my start menu double click on that save Yeah I'll save whatever we
chose we made to game.
Okay now if I go in a prefabs I should be able to drag all of the relevant prefabs in.
So I've got a background although this one looks like the background and that one says background but
neither of them have my background script on.
So this is great.
I think we've forgotten to update our prefabs So let me just go back to my game scene and find the background
that's in the game.
You can see that there's bold font because I haven't clicked on our.
Okay back to start menu.
Get rid of the main camera.
We don't need that because we have our own main camera dropped in drop in the background drop in the
star field the reason I'm doing this is just so the first scene like the start scene looks interesting.
It's got our background.
If you don't have to do that you can have something totally totally different.
You don't have to have all this game stuff in there.
Don't need the player don't need the enemy.
Do need the level so we know what we're loading.
Blue background.
I think that's all yes pretty good.
Okay.
Next up we're going to need our canvas because we need to be putting text and stuff on there.
But here's one of those exceptions prefab rule we've gone and prefabbed the canvas from our game.
But if we go and change and put start like kind of stuff on here we don't want that to be applied to
our game canvas.
So the prefab canvas we have is actually the game canvas.
And I can start off with the game canvas as inspiration so I drag that into my scene game canvas.
I don't want to be applying anything back to it because it'll break the game canvas.
But what I do want to do is use that as my base so I know that I'm starting off with the right sort
of screen resolution and scaling etc..
What we can do here is go up to game object and break prefab instance.
That means that this is no longer linked to that particular prefab it is now its own thing its now its
own game object.
I can rename this from game canvas to start menu Start menu.
Cambers.
Hit enter.
And now I can drag that down a prefab that so it adds its own separate prefab.
Okay so under Start Menu canvas right click.
Fine UI text mesh probe using text mesh porro you could just use straight up text if you wanted.
But I think I'll go a text message broca's the scaling works a little bit better it's a little bit of
a clean font import if you need to do that you might not need to if your projects already been set up
with that but it once made it import the essentials.
Close that window down.
Now we have new tech sitting in the middle.
Our rename this to be laser d Friend.
K. in that voice is very important.
Just increase the font size for now to say 120 Okay.
And I will need to double click on my start menu canvas so I can see the canvas itself.
Click on the text mesh pro text rename that to be heading text heading text and then click on my ARE
told my T all.
Drag to the right track to the left.
Zoom in a little bit drag it up okay.
Click on my w-2 all drag it up a little bit about them.
Okay so we need to make our font a little bit nicer than it is at the moment.
And for me I've gone to duff font and found the what is it best man forever faunt.
And I think looks pretty neat.
Downloaded that and I have that as some fonts that I can unzip just here.
A jump Pogo into unity.
And I will create a new asset folder.
Actually a new folder in assets.
Right click create folder called the folder fonts.
Within font's open that up.
Now if I go to my Windows Explorer I can get my two fonts in drag.
And so the Batmen man forever font had two fonts one is soldered and one is just the outline which looks
pretty cool so we can use that to good effect.
You can use whatever font you want you don't have to use the same font as me jump around we've done
this a couple of times so it should be a pretty familiar process of finding some fonts.
So within hitting text actually first of all we need to convert these in a text mesh pro fonts so up
to window text mesh Perro font asset creator.
This might be a little bit different in future editions as these packages become bit more integrated
but this is what we do for now.
Grab the first font drag it into font source Quicken generate font Atlas when it's done.
We'll click on save as just on the same fonts folder.
So save as it should already be in the right fonts folder save.
That's all good.
And then grab the other font drag that into font source.
Generate font Atlas.
Wait for a moment waiting waiting.
Did a little boo boo boo boo boo boo boo boo.
Okay, that's all done. Save as. Same spot. Save. I can close down my window in my front.
Create a window and we have what we need.
Back over into hitting text.
Scroll down a little bit.
Drag trying to.
I want and I will drag the first one over.
See how that looks okay.
That looks pretty awesome.
Centre my laser defender Tex.
Give it a bit of a funky colour by scrolling to colour vertex click on that.
Maybe a little bit more of a bright gaudy kind of lazara.
There we go.
Okay nice and bright bright eyes lots of it.
That's the point.
And now.
I think that is cool.
Going to click on my heading text duplicate make ourselves a sub beheading sub heading and the subheading
What shall we say in here.
Just move it down underneath the main heading we'll say.
Protest.
Yeah okay.
And then make this a smaller font maybe 60.
See how that fits.
Oh it's pretty good move that down a touch and we'll see how it looks with the other font.
Protect the earth.
Okay a little bit the bit harder to read.
Maskell gives us some possess I will leave that light.
That is I think.
Okay now for our buttons so right click again start menu canvas.
We will create UI and make this our style of making this is a text message pro text and then I'll add
a button component to it.
Is text message pro text.
We will name start but 10.
Change the font to be the solid Batman font.
Increase the size to say 100.
Give ourselves a little bit more space using the teat all drag to the riot drag to the left.
Okay that looks pretty good.
And then this is just going to be straight up Start centre a line.
Find alignment Centre.
That's pretty good.
Doesn't really we'll call centre line though does it.
Not compared to that.
What have we done wrong here.
Maybe it just needs to be moved into the actual centre so it looks centred.
Okay let's be sure this drag out text box all the way to the side all the way it is so I could do some
anchoring here but I'm going to do a little bit fast and loose.
We've gone through ide's.
The one above that's not so right.
We'll done through this a few times.
I'm not going to do it the super deliberate careful explain everything why I'm going to do more of the
fast reminder way.
And if you've got any problems at all.
Throw me in the Q and A and we can help you out.
OK so let's start.
I'm gonna make start huge because I think it needs to have super duper important So 160.
There we go start.
Very clearly what we need to do and then we need to turn this into a button so I'm going to collapse
the text message pro text claps my material.
A component which is a button.
Enter now this.
But when E is going to be.
Where we will keep our functionality so you'll see on click.
List is empty.
Click on the little plus symbol there change from runtime only to Ed and run time drag over our level
game object into our Says none.
Object no function game changer from no function to level.
And what do we want to do on a load the game or find.
Load game book.
There we go.
Now it's duplicate stuff.
Barton changed the name of it from start button to quit button.
Cook on my debut tour move it down a little bit change the size of the font so I'm going to open up
my text mesh pro.
You g.i. element drop it down to say 80.
So quick isn't as obvious or as prominent.
And then maybe change the colour to grey it out a little bit.
Gay and then obviously change the font.
Sorry change the name so it says quit.
Okay.
Pretty good start and quit.
Now the quick functionality again collapse my text prush Text mesh pro use G you I can find my button
and now functionality on click we need to change that from level load gain to level.
What will this be.
Quit application was.
Q. Quit game.
There you go.
Excellent save.
Now if this is all worked well there's one more thing we need to do.
Actually we need to go up to file build settings and we need to say what the scenes are in our game.
We've created one new scene which is the start menu drag that up a bar of our game scene so now we have
a index of zero an index of 1.
Close our build settings click on Play.
Now when we click on start it should take us to.
No where.
OK let's have a look at the start button it looks like for some reason our start button has a small
footprint on it so I click on my.
My t tool just drag it and drag it drag it to the extremes.
Could it be that my hit area has gone and made itself really small for some reason.
So when I click on Play Now.
Click on START.
It loads is the starter Gatwick of course that worked it was just that our Biton had gone in got nice
and small and we couldn't see it so if you click on the quick but you can see around the outside we've
got this area need to make sure that covers all of where your button is going to be.
Have it reasonably centred.
Okay I can see a little circle there and it's lined up with where our middle line is.
Okay so we've got to start with got quit that's working pretty well and a save all of this now I created
the start menu from scratch but there's a lot of the font in the background is gone.
Good stuff there.
I want to keep some going to duplicate the start menu control deal or kamandi the rename.
This is game over.
Very important that it's game over so it matches whatever we wrote in our string reference here.
Yes it does.
Game over.
Double click on that looks the same because it's being duplicated.
We need to change some of the font some of the headings so the heading takes us no longer leza defender.
It's going to be game over are okay change the fonts.
It's a little bit different.
More make a bit on.
The orange yellow side of things that's pretty good instead of protect the earth so this is our subheading.
Change it to something like.
Ah.
Better luck next time.
Cheeky.
Okay just move that up a little bit.
Clicking on my w-2 all up.
But pop.
There we go.
Better luck next time and change the front of that as well maybe make it a more bright yellow.
Bright yellow.
Okay but like next time doesn't quiet fit doesn't look super good blunt going to finesse it too far
I just want to show you the structure of what I'm going through here and make sure that you've got the
tools you need and we can compare notes like kind of stuff.
Sorry but next time we have a start button let's change this to play again play again button in our
text.
We will change it to play again.
Make that a little bit smaller so its on the springing of say 130.
That is good.
And then instead of a quick button I'm going to put into mine a main menu button.
Change the colour of main menu so it's more of a valid colour.
If you're just white as well so play again or main menu just a line though so they look a little bit
more like actual buttons.
Okay that seems decent.
Now with the functionality of the play again but in the quick but needs to be renamed scrotum main menu
button cuts have a look at the functionality of the play again button Well that used to be the play
buttons so load game that's still valid play a game and then play again.
Main Menu button should instead of being quit game.
It should be level and low.
Start menu.
Load start menu.
There we go.
Okay save that up.
Click on play just to check that we've got our play again working.
Come play again.
Yes that does work.
I don't have the death hooked up at the moment so it's not going to take me to the game over a screen
and then click on main menu yet that takes us to start screaming start takes this time there.
Okay cool.
OK.
There's one more thing to do which is to have our game over screen load when the player dies.
We've already spent a ton of time on this video so I'll wrap it up now and I will see you in the next
video.