Hello again.
In this video we'll be adding resources to
our scores by creating an animation event,
and then creating a little animation with
our star so they can visualize
as our points are going up.
Let's jump in and get started.
I haven't scribbled on the screen for
a while so
let's do a little bit
of screen scribbling.
And I wanna talk about the positioning of
where we need to be calling methods from.
So when we have an animation
event that sits on our timeline,
it can only be getting the function or
the method from anything that is
at that level of the game object.
So currently we have the defender script,
so
we can access with our animation event
anything that is in the defender script.
However, the thing we need to
be accessing to be adding stars,
which is what we wanna be doing, like,
[SOUND], and then this score here,
our star display will go out from for
example 100, to 107.
The way that we're doing that is
through these starred display script
which is sitting on our starred display.
So we need a mechanism to say well, we
need to be able to see from within here.
This is the same level.
As the animation event, we need to be out
of call in this particular script in here.
Normally, we would just say
find StarDisplay and go for it,
call the method.
But we don't have that mechanism within
here when we add an animation event.
So we need to do something a little
bit tricky in order for us to access,
that is by calling within
the Defender script.
We need to create ourselves a method,
a public method.
Public method that will call
the method we're looking for
in StarDisplay so
that the animation event can call our
public method that's sitting
on the Defender script.
So if that seems like 1,000 lines and
it doesn't make sense, no problem,
we will sort it all out in a moment.
Let me clean my screen.
Okay, so jump over to Visual Studio,
open up StarDisplay, and
we'll also need our Defender script.
StarDisplay, we're looking at,
in particular,
we're interested in the AddStars method
and we're looking to pass an amount.
So if we go over to Defender now
as our script we're gonna work in,
we'll create ourselves a new method.
So give ourselves a couple of lines, it
will be a public method, public void, and
we'll call this AddStars.
So I am gonna call it the exact same
thing I am calling it on StarDisplay.
You might want to call it something
slightly different if that is gonna
confuse you.
But I know that you're up for this
challenge and that you're not confused
easily so it's all good, and
we will have an integer of amount.
Now within here what are we doing?
Well, it's pretty much just saying go and
do this thing is what we're up to.
So if you know how to do
that pause the video and
take on that little challenge there to
find that object and to call that method.
Okay, what we're doing
is find object of type.
The type is StarDisplay,
well, not star int display.
Getting a little emotional, StarDisplay,
dot, what our method well, it is AddStars,
that was the first one in my list.
What are we parsing in?
We're parsing this amount
that we are requiring,
however calls the Defenders Method
of AddStars to parse in.
So we'll also call this amount semicolon.
Okay, now when we jump
back over into Unity,
we will, you're not here's a time for
a challenge.
I was nearly gonna give you the solution
to the challenge accidentally.
Here's a challenge,
I think this is a pretty easy one.
This should be something that you can
absolutely smash out of the park.
Easy Peasy Lemon Squeezy is to use
an animation event on the trophy
to add resources to our total.
Add as many resources
as you like each time.
And as bonus points,
to make a little star grow out of
the trophy when the resources are added.
And I've given you previously, we're using
this in one of our previous lectures in
sprites currently not in use,
we have the star.
That's what I'm gonna be having animate,
and I'll be using the animation system.
I won't be doing it as an instantiation.
So we making a star grow as well, but
the first thing is animation event and
then taken on that star growing
animation as well if you like.
So I will see you back here shortly.
Okay, pretty straightforward I think,
if we're clicked on trophy, and
we are accessing our
trophy animation in here.
You can see, [SOUND] bounce,
where do I want to be calling?
So where do I wanna say, make a new star,
AddStars' right about bang,
when it slams down.
I think that's a pretty cool spot, so
that's where I will click my Add Event.
And I search from within here.
We've got AddStars,
it's looking for how much.
We're gonna have a really tiny amount, so
I want to have this happen quite regularly
like little factories going [SOUND]
churning out a lot of stuff.
So I'll add, say, all right, three.
I don't even, I haven't played
around with the churning of this, so
we'll see how that feels.
Should add three stars
each time that plays.
So I'm going to make sure I
apply that back to the prefab.
Nothing to apply, because we've
been working on that animation.
Cool, click on Play.
Watch our score, 100, 103, 106, 109.
I think that's really cool.
I like this constant.
And if we add another one or two or
three, it's gonna be adding tons.
Click, click, click, click, all going,
I like that,
I kind of like lots of little ones.
The original Plants vs Zombie games,
you see it and you wait and you wait and
you wait and you wait and you wait.
And then a big kind of thing appears of
whatever it is, 100 points we'll say, and
then you wait and wait and wait and wait.
I like this constant progression.
I think there's better feedback to
the player about, okay, this cactus costs,
whatever, 100.
I need to wait until I get to that point.
Okay.
So that's my preference,
you can do it however you like, though.
You can change the timing and
pacing of your animation.
So next thing I said is let's make
ourselves a little visualization for
that so it looks cool.
I've got my star, I will grab my star and
drag it into trophy,
cuz that's where it'll be hanging out.
And we have our just one single,
one single Sprite of our star.
Cool, now, I'm also, let's see,
what level do we want this at?
Well, we've got our trophy.
We've got the top and the base.
We've set this up in a nice way so
we can move things around.
Do I want the star to belong to the top?
So if I was to move the top over there,
my star is going to be over there as well.
I don't think so.
I think I want the star just to
belong to the entire trophy, so
at the trophy level I will
add a new game object.
So Create Empty.
We'll call this Star, and then add a
component which will be a Sprite Renderer.
It's not a spirit, a Sprite Renderer.
There we go, Sprite Renderer.
What do we want to have it look like?
We wanna have it look like
this little star over here.
Drag that into the sprite.
Now change the Order in Layer to 6.
I believe that'll have
it sit over the top.
Great, it's nice and massive.
We wish to scale that down a little bit,
I think, so I'll start off.
Should we do this on our Sprite sheet or
should we do this on our game object?
I'll do this on the Sprite sheet,
I think, so Pixels Per Unit,
we will half that to 50, and then apply,
oops, that was the wrong way around.
Okay, my bad,
200 pixels per unit and then apply.
There we go, got myself back to front.
Okay, as a starting point
make it a little bit smaller.
That looks pretty cool.
So just a reminder,
I clicked on my Sprite Asset and
then changed the pixels per unit to 200.
Okay so we have our Starlet animated.
Now we'll Add Property, find the Star.
Drill down into the star.
I think I'm gonna use,
I'm gonna go pretty simple on this.
I'll start off by adding Scale, and
then within my star scale just here,
what do we wanna have happen?
Well, I wanna have it nothing like
a zero scale, and then probably around
about bump here start to appear, and
then grow and shrink a little bit.
So I will find the point where I want
it to be at roughly the right size.
So around about here,
I'll have it full size-ish.
That's just a bit after my animation
event, so I click on Record,
add a keyframe.
I'm gonna drag my slider back to where
the animation event takes place.
I could add a key frame or
I could just type straight in here 000.
Then make sure I go all
the way back to the Start, and
I go 000 on my scaling on my star.
So it starts off as a key frame
saying that it's going to be 0000.
The event takes place, the animation
events and then my Star start to grow.
Okay, it gets trumped.
Full-ish sized, that's probably
a little bit bigger than what I want.
So we'll change it to 0.80 and
0.80, just to be thorough.
And then that's the size of my
scaling that I want all the way at
the very end as well.
Okay, so that was a little bit of a clunky
way but you can see it's working.
The manual way okay, so we have 0.8,
it's going from 000 grows to 0.8.
Now we need to put a little bit
kind of a zig zaggy movement.
Let me scroll in so
we can see this more easily.
We'll also add a property of Star and
then transform and position.
We can do a little bit of rotation
as well if our heart desires.
We've got our star scrolling around here.
Okay, you can see it's
growing from the middle.
I'm going to actually start it
I think a little bit lower.
So let's start Record,
get it in the position we want it to be,
probably around about there.
Move it up a little bit to that point.
Drag the star up yonder.
Little bit higher up here
all the way up to the top.
I'm gonna sort of have
it zigzag up to the top.
They how's that looking?
Now drag along.
Yeah, don't yeah,
just nice and simple actually.
No, I'll put a little bit of variation.
I'll zip it up to the top and
then it's gonna wobble a little bit.
There we go, a little bit of wobbling,
nice and then I think I want it to,
then it's making its way down to the back
end so we need to have it up here.
I think I want it to shrink at the end,
so it kind of grows and then shrinks.
So see how this just grows and
then shrinks.
Grows, probably need another scaling key
frame in there just to keep it large-ish.
Okay it's a little bit kind of
just fiddling around with it,
won't go too much longer.
I think that's fine, how's it going?
Yep, wop, yep, okay cool,
that looks pretty neat I think.
Let's test that out by back into the
games, make sure it all looks pretty good.
Doesn't need to be super amazing.
Yeah, and
it's floating up pretty quick, and
it looks like it's coming
out of the base of it.
Okay cool, we got there in the end.
And did I apply that?
Yeah, that looks cool.
Awesome.
Okay, and now our score is going up.
Each time it hits, a little star is being
appeared, it looks like it's floating.
The reason I've scaled it down at the end
is kind of, it's disappearing at the end.
Great, happy with that.
Okay, good stuff.
We've got our star animating, we're adding
our scores so our resource is going up.
I think in the next video we
need to get ourselves a cost so
that we can actually
be spending our stars.
Great work in this video, and
I'll see you again real soon.