[MUSIC]
Really exciting video this one,
we're linking things all together now.
We've got our stars going up, and
in this video when we click and
place a defender, boom our stars will
go down, we'll be spending our stars.
So let's jump in and get started.
Let's by reminding ourselves what it
is we're trying to do with our various
scripts here.
The Defender Spawner is storing
the defender, finding the cost,
finding if we have enough stars,
telling the stars to be spent.
The Star Display is keeping
track of our current resources,
it's letting us know if we have enough
stars, and it's spending the stars.
The Defender is providing the cost.
And the Defender Button is selecting
the particular defender prefab.
And in this video, we're gonna be
working in the defender spawner,
star display defender and
defender button scripts that correspond
with my nifty slide I just showed you.
And we'll start off in
defender dot CS file.
We need a way of being able to access this
cost, of how much a defender costs, and
to make that public.
So I'm gonna give you a challenge right
from the get-go to get you active and
nimble here,
make cost publicly accessible.
So in the Defender.cs create,
a public method called GetStarCost
which returns the starCost.
It should be pretty straightforward,
we've done this a bunch of times.
But good to get the old brain
fluid flowing, so jump in and
take on that challenge now, if you will.
Okay, so public method, we'll give
ourselves a couple of lines here.
Public, it's going to return an integer,
this might have been something
that you stumbled on.
GetStarCost or you didn't stumble
on it because you're amazing, and
public integer GetStarCost return.
What are we going to return here
if you didn't do the challenge and
you've just be following along?
What do we would need to return?
We will need to return starCost.
So that will say,
when something calls this, it will say,
whatever it is in here- 100, or
what we've change it to an inspector.
Okay, that's a great starting point.
Next, what do we need to do?
Well, we need to update
our defender spawner so
that we are being a little bit
clever in how we place our defender.
And we'll do that by creating
ourselves a new method in here.
So underneath SetSelectedDefender and
above GetSquareClicked,
I'm gonna create a new method
which will be a private void.
And I'll call this
AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt.
I know it's super specific there, but
we're trying to say attempt to place
because we have an if statement in there
that says that you might not be able to.
And we need to be passing in a position,
so we'll say Vector2.
And we'll call it gridPos, okay.
And what do we do within our method
here when we're attempting to place
this defender?
Well, I'm going to start off by creating
a couple of variables that I'll be using.
First of all, var StarDisplay.
We're just accessing,
we're finding a handle for that.
How do we find the object of type?
We type in FindObjectOfType, that was
the worse challenge ever, wasn't it?
StarDisplay(); next we'll create
a variable of type integer,
which we'll defenderCost cuz we need to
know how much the defender's costing.
And we are, where are we?
We've got DefenderToSelect,
that's defender.
So we will say defender.GetStarCost().
Okay, so the defender is a reference that
is coming in from our defender to select.
Our defenderToSelect is being parsed in
when this SetSelectDefender is called
from our DefenderButton I
believe we're calling that, yep.
So from the button into
our defender's spawner.
Great, next up we need to run our little
if statement that allows us to say,
only go and
spend the money if you got the money.
So write a little comment in here so
we know what we're doing.
If we have enough Stars or
moolah or cash or schmeckles.
Then what do we want to do?
We wanna spawn the defender,
and we also want to do what?
Spend the money, or spend the stars.
Okay, first of all, we need a way
of knowing, do we have enough?
So let's jump over into star display
which keeps track of whether we do or
do not have enough and create ourselves.
Let's see I'll do it
underneath update display.
We'll create a public
bool cuz we wanna return.
Do we or do we not have enough stars?
So that's why it's a bool.
We'll call it HaveEnoughStars.
Can't really put a question mark in there,
but we can say stars,
which implies question mark.
And we'll pass in each amount, and
I'd like you to finish this off.
What is our simple statement
in here to assess whether or
not we have enough stars and whether
we should be returning true or false.
It is return stars &gt;= amount;.
Which is saying,
when we parse in a certain amount,
do we have more stars than we have amount?
If so, return as true.
So yes, you can go ahead and do this.
Save that up,
back over into defender spawner.
So the first part about if statement is
gonna be using our two variables here.
So why don't you give that go and
see if you can write the first
line of the if statement.
It's gonna be if, and in parenthesis,
StarDisplay.HaveEnoughStars that
we just created and
we need to pass in what defenderCost?
Then, within our code block,
what are we going to do?
Well, we need to spawn the defender, so
what do we currently have at
the moment for spawning defender?
We've got down here, spawn defender,
so we'll just do that.
SpawnDefender and we need to pass in what,
vector2 for roundedPosition.
So we'll say the gridPosition that we've
just received when the attempt to place
defender at has been called.
Sorry that will be gridPos; and then our
next line we need to spend the stars.
So now the chance is for
you a little mini challenge.
Go ahead and spend the stars in this line.
Okay, once again,
it's StarDisplay.SpendStars.
If you weren't sure what it was there,
then you could've jumped over into
our StarDisplay and said,
hang on a minute, what do we need to do?
There it is there, SpendStars,
we're passing in the amount.
What is the amount we're passing in?
That's going to be the defenderCost.
Okay; Save that up,
delete my comments, tidy up my code.
We're looking pretty good.
Now we need to go up to the top on our
MouseDown event, instead of SpawnDefender,
that now is a method that we've
got wrapped up within our
AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt.
So we'll change to
AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt(GetSquareClick-
ed).
And then we'll save that.
You know what?
This might work.
We'll jump back over into Unity,
click on Play.
Once it's finished compiling and
doing what it needs to do.
Okay, we've got 100.
We're slowly producing stars.
If I click on cactus it's worth 100.
It goes down to 15, excellent.
Then you're gonna wait a little while
until it goes all the way back up.
I'm gonna pause and
start again just to make sure it works
if we drop down a trophy as well.
Click on the trophy, drop the trophy.
Great, so now it's working for trophy and
the trophies, two of them together
are ticking up the resources even faster.
This is starting to feel like a cool game,
isn't it?
Well, except for the millions [LAUGH] of
attackers that are coming on the screen.
Let's just wait until it goes all
the way back up to 100 again, and
we'll click on the cactus so
we've done both.
Okay, good,
I'm pretty satisfied with that.
We've now got a resource system
where our stars are increasing,
as well as decreasing when we spend them.
And a quick recap of what we've
done in our code over in Defender.
We gave ourselves a mechanism for getting
the StarCost within the Defender Spawner.
We've updated and created
AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt and within that,
we're basically saying, if you've got
enough Stars, then spawn the defender and
spent the stars.
We also made sure that within the on
mouse down event we updated our
AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt.
So instead of just doing
a straight up yep, spawn the guy!
We've now wrapped it into
the AttemptToPlaceDefenderAt.
So that we're doing a few things in
there including checking if we've got
enough stars.
Okay so great work in this video.
I know it's a little bit deeper there's
a bit convoluted bouncing between
script and script.
If you're not quite getting it, or
if you've got any questions at all,
please throw them in the Q&amp;A.
We'd love to hear from you, and love to
help you out if you've got any questions.
So, great work and
I'll see you in the next video.