[SOUND] In this video,
we're tying a few things together.
We're tying together our life system and
our scoreboard system so
that the player lives are remembered and
printed on the screen,
the score is printed on the screen.
And when the player dies, bloink,
we know it should be 2 and
we know our score should be retained.
So let's jump in and get our game
feeling a lot more like an actual game.
Okay, I've jumped back over to my Level
1 over here, we're on my Level 1, yeah,
where we've already
created our game session.
And I'm gonna prefab the game session,
just drag it down into our prefab folder,
because we'll be needing to use
that in each of our levels.
Okay, the first thing we're
gonna do is jump in and
create ourselves some text to have on
the screen to display score and lives.
So right-click in the hierarchy,
down to UI.
We will create ourselves a Canvas.
Gonna rename this UI Canvas.
UI Canvas, so it's nice and clear.
UI Canvas, underneath which we will
right-click and create UI &gt;Text.
This Text I am going to call,
what's this one gonna be,
we'll do lives first, so
we'll call it livesText, livesText.
And then my mouse wheel scrolls
at the speed of a sloth,
so I'm gonna double click on Canvas
to get the whole thing on the screen.
You can see our new text just here,
and drag it up over in the top left.
I think lives on the left and
score on the right.
We can put a little bit more
flavor into it later on, for
now we're just getting the functionality.
But I do wanna make sure
I've clicked on the anchor,
and we've anchored it to the top left.
And also to increase the font to say 50,
and to make it white.
These are all areas where you can
customize to your hearts content,
so do with it what you would like.
I'm going to do it just nice and
simple for now.
Let me make it bold actually,
that'll be my bit of flavor.
How many lives?
Well, I don't see the player
getting more than 99 lives,
that would be a little bit crazy,
so we'll cap that at 99.
Put that in there so
we can see how it looks with
the maximum number of characters.
And then we also, while we're here,
want to create text for our scoreboard.
So while we're on the UI Canvas,
right-click, UI &gt; Text.
Actually, no, don't do that.
I'm gonna just do duplicate,
that'd be the smart way to do it.
Duplicate livesText, and
then we will call this our scoreboardText,
or it's just scoreText.
I think scoreText is
cleaner in that instance.
scoreText makes sense, and then we will
move our scoreText over to the right hand
side, change the anchor to be
the right hand side as well, and
also change the alignment
to be over on the right.
Okay, so that's pretty
quickly just setting that up.
More numbers are required for
our score I think, so let's see.
Maybe six digits, so you can get to
just about a million in our game.
That looks pretty good.
We can finish this later on.
But that's pretty good
as a starting point.
livesText and scoreText on our UI Canvas.
Now where do we determine what
numbers are put onto the screen?
Well, that's going to
be in our GameSession.
Our GameSession is going to manage and
control, I should say control
where our lives are stored, and how many
lives a player has, and what happens when
the player gets to zero lives, and
also what we show on the screen.
So we'll go into our GameSession script,
and
we'll start by pointing this script
to the text that we just created.
So we'll serialize
a couple of fields here.
serializeField and
the first one will be Text.
So it's of type Text.
And we lighten up TextAlignment.
So okay,
that's gone blank up on the screen,
when it should have said Text because
we're not using the namespace yet.
So using UnityEngine.UI, there we go.
Now when we come down here and
we say Text,
it knows what Text is,
it has an understanding of it.
And we'll start with livesText, and
then I'll just copy-paste that.
The next one, we will say scoreText.
Okay, so we've got these two here,
I've left a little bit of a gap
just to differentiate between my
text fields here and my playerLives.
We'll come back to that in a moment.
So we've got our text back over into
our engine, we need to point things at
the right direction, just wait a moment
for the script to compile, there we go.
So we've got livesText and scoreText.
Where do they come from?
Well, this is livesText and
that is scoreText.
So while clicking on GameSession, drag
livesText over into that field there and
drag scoreText over into
that field right there.
Fantastic.
Okay, so we've set that up.
If we play our game now,
let's see what happens.
It should initialize at what?
3 and 0, I believe.
99 and 999999, okay,
so it hasn't done that.
Why is it not doing that?
Let's have a look,
let's see what is going on.
Well, we haven't told it that these
numbers, the numbers we have in,
where are we, this number here,
we haven't told it that should be
a string that's displayed in here.
So we have to go ahead and display it.
Just doing this is not
gonna do anything just yet.
So we'll go down to our Start method, and
in here we need to say livesText.text
= playerLives.ToString.
We've done this before.
ToString or not ToString,
that is the question.
[LAUGH] Bad joke or not bad joke,
Okay, so we've got that we're saying,
whatever we have as our score,
our number should be
converted into a string.
We'll do this at the same time for
our score as well.
So that was lives I should say, so
whatever for lives we do this for
score and
that will be scoreText.text = score,
which it won't know
what score is just yet,
that's why I tried to auto-complete that,
ToString();.
Okay, we need to define score so
we jump up the top here.
We need to SerializeField,
score being int, and we could say = 0,
we don't have to,
it's initialized at 0 anyway.
But I am going to say = 0 just so I can
cleanly see these two belong together
as I'm flying through and
trying to figure out what's going on.
Score starts at 0, it's a good reminder
if it's starting at anything but 0,
then that might be a problem.
Okay, so we've got lives, we've got score,
we've got the text for those two,
and now what else do we need to do?
Well, let's take a look and
see if it is now updating, if it's
accurately understanding what it should be
displaying on the screen at the get-go.
Click play, it should be 3 and 0.
Okay, now we have 3 and 0, excellent.
As we run along, score's not going up yet
cuz we haven't told it about that.
When we die, bloink.
Back up to 99.
Why is that the case?
Okay, so there's a very good reason
why our lives isn't being remembered,
and it's not that it's not
even being remembered,
we've lost that step of
telling it that it's 3.
So it didn't even go to 2,
didn't even say 3, it's gone to 99.
That's because our DontDestroyerOnload
is only relevant for the GameSession.
So if we click out of play mode here,
we've got our singleton that we've got
on GameSession that says if another
GameSession comes along then destroy
that but don't destroy this one.
And we haven't got that on our UI Canvas
here, so we could go and put a script
which has a singleton there or we can
drag that underneath the GameSession.
And that approach, the DontDestroyOnload
that we've got up in here,
the GameSession DontDestroyOnload,
this will work for
anything that's charted underneath
the object that has that script on it.
So because we've got
DontDestroyOnload on GameSession,
then the Canvas and these livesText and
scoreText aren't destroyed.
So we'll click play and I'll show you that
in action that it should start at 3 and 0.
When we jump in the water,
it stays at 3, stays at 3.
We haven't told it to decrement yet
on the screen but it knows that it
shouldn't destroy the UI Canvas.
Well, I clicked on GameSession,
I'm gonna click Apply there just so
that it makes this whole
thing the prefect.
Okay, now let's get it actually
decreasing when it should decrease.
We scroll down, we look at Start,
ProcessPlayerDeath, TakeLife.
Okay, this is where it's going to be
relevant when it's taking a life,
it is decreasing but we're not
telling it again to update the text.
We're just saying that in Start
that this is what lives equals.
So we'll copy this, and
we'll put it down here as well.
When you take a life,
you should also update the livesText so
that whatever the current playerLives
is should go into a string.
So I'll save that, back over into
the engine, click play, click play.
Always takes me a couple of
clicks to get the play button.
It's thinking, it's like, yeah man,
I'm gonna do these scripts calm down.
If we jump in the water now,
it's now down to 2.
Great and then down to 1.
Okay, so success there with our lives.
We are having our don't destroy work and
we're remembering the state of our lives,
remembering what the value is.
Now let's do the same thing for score.
And we'll get a quick clue
from what we did for lives.
If you have a look here,
we've got our public method we created,
ProcessPlayerDeath.
And then over in the players script,
we're using that.
We're finding the ObjectiveOfType,
which is GameSession, and
then calling the method
ProcessPlayerDeath.
So let's do something very
similar over here for the score.
I'm gonna put this up at the top, so
that I don't have to jump all the way down
to the bottom of my script to find it.
We will say a public void,
what shall we call this?
I think it will be AddToScore.
So something's being added to score.
And then we want to make sure
that whatever calls this method
passes back the amount that it should add.
So we don't want to have
to manage that in here.
We don't want to have to say
the GameSession understands that a coin is
worth 100 points but a gem is worth 200
points and something else is worth 300,
we want to be told that.
When something from another script says,
hey, add to score,
we want it to say add 100 to the score,
add 200 to the score, and so on.
So we will say in here, int PointsToAdd
is the amount that we wanna add.
And then, what will be our method?
Our method's gonna be score +=,
so we want it to be increasing.
So take what you are now, and then
increase on top of that a certain amount,
which will be the pointsToAdd
that we just passed back in.
And then as we did just now with,
down here with playerLives,
we need to make sure that we're updating
the string on the screen again.
So I'll go and copy my scoreText,
copy that, and
now we have scoreText.text
= score.ToString(), okay?
So this whole method here is saying
update and add to the score.
And this is where I've got a challenge for
you and
the challenge is to increase the score.
So update the onscreen score
when coins are picked up.
If you want, you can add a gem
that has a different amount and so
on, but for
now we'll concentrate on the coins.
And to be sure to serialize
the pickup amount, so
in the inspector you can change,
okay coins are worth 100 or 200,
something else might be worth a different
amount, or a huge coin might be worth 500.
And to use the player.cs for
clues on how to go about doing this,
the structure is very similar for
score as we have just done for live.
So you've got all the intel you need.
Jump in, take that in now, and I'll see
you back here when you've given it a shot.
Okay, welcome back.
So the first thing we need to do is
hop over to our CoinPickup.cs and
we want to add some information in here.
First of all, I am going to
say how much a coin is worth.
So SerializedField and
we will use a int here,
pointsForCoinPickup, how
much we'll make that?
Well, make it a 100 for now.
It's a nice, clean, round amount, 100.
And then in our OnTriggerEnter method,
when the player runs over a coin,
we wanna do very similar to what we did
over here with the die method where
we were looking for the ObjectOfType
GameSession ProcessPlayerDeath.
Over here though,
we're going to FindObjectOfType and
again it will be GameSession.
Game session, and the method we
just created was what, AddToScore.
What do we need to pass in there?
Well, we need to pass in this thing we
just created which is pointsForCoinPickup.
We can just say 100 in there but
that doesn't make it as flexible,
PointForCoinPickup.
And it knows pointsForCoinPickup,
say that fast five times, is 100.
Okay, we'll save that,
back over into the engine.
Click on play.
Moment of truth,
we'll see if our logic works.
See if everything makes sense.
Quickly check that we can die.
Yes, we can.
Down to 2, points are going up, fantastic.
And what happens when we die?
Is it still 600?
Bam, it is still 600, fantastic.
There's one last step in this whole
process which bugs me a lot, so
in the next video we're
going to resolve that,
is that when I run over these coins,
if I was to die now those coins,
like happened just now,
reappear, and I don't want that.
I want for the player not to be able
to go and pick up all the coins and
nearly make it to the end and
go pick up all the coins again.
I want that when you pick up a coin once,
it's gone.
And we need to do that in a way
that it works for this level but
when I go into the next level, the next
level's coins are all there and present.
So there's a little bit of messing around
with the state of what things need to
persist in the GameSession and what things
need to persist in the level session
which we'll take on in the next video.
So great work in this lecture.
I look forward to seeing all your
sharing on our Facebook site and
in the QA section in the forum.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.