[MUSIC]
In this video, we're making another enemy,
I've called mine big boy.
He's bigger, stronger, tougher and
drops bombs at the player,
so let's jump in and make another enemy.
Let's start by selecting a new laser
beam bomb and a new enemy to use.
So I'll go into my Kenny assets P&amp;Gs,
first of all we'll find a new enemy.
And I think we'll go
with maybe a green guy,
this green kind of butterfly looking dude.
And we'll drag that into our sprites so
we know we are using that.
And then we'll find a lasers, [SOUND].
Scroll down,
laser red 10 I think looks pretty good
as little bombs that are dropping.
So we'll drag that over into
our sprites as well, excellent.
Now the prefabs,
gonna go into the prefabs folder,
and find one of our existing enemies.
We'll take Roger, duplicate Roger,
and I wanna make a bigger enemy.
So instead of Roger 1, we'll call this
bigger enemy, I don't know, Big Boy,
there we go.
That's a good name for
a big thing, isn't it, a Big Boy.
And then I'm gonna go straight for
my sprites folder and
drag in our enemyGreen currently
at the moment, enemyGreen5.
Okay, so back into our Prefabs,
find where is Big Boy going?
Roger 1, Big Boy, we will rename it
over in here as well to Big Boy.
There we go,
we'll change the image of Big Boy.
It's changes, it's updated, excellent.
Now we'll give it a little bit of color
treatment, drag it into the scene so
I can see when I make these
changes what happens.
This is a pretty crude way of changing
the color of a sprite, of an image.
It's much better if you
change it at source.
But we were making kind of a purply color,
yeah.
Purple Big Boy, there we go,
not too terrible.
Okay, what else do we need to do?
We've got a rigid body, kinematic,
excellent, the enemy script.
Health, well Big Boy is gonna have
more health, we'll say 600 so
it's a little bit tough
to actually destroy.
Score value 460, tougher to kill,
more points to get.
Shot counter, now we don't actually
need to be changing shot counter,
that's left in there from when we
wanted to see it for debug purposes.
So let's go and tidy that up by finding
our script, we need the enemy script.
Open that up in Visual Studio.
We just need to change it from serialized
field to non-serialized field.
So let's find shot counter, remove
the serialized field cuz we don't need to
be messing with that anymore,
save that up.
Back over into your Big Boy, so
Prefabs &gt; Prefabs folder and then Big Boy.
Let's see over here,
okay Min.Time Between Shots 0.2,
Maximum Time 0.6,
not really sure, just guessing.
Projectile right now, this is where
we need to make a new projectile.
So I'll come back to that in a moment.
Let's just finish up going through these
things in Big Boy and make sure it's okay.
So Projectile Speed, we're gonna have
it really slow, we'll see how 2 goes.
Explosion, yeah, Death Effect, and laser,
we'll just go and randomly pick a Laser4.
I think that might be okay, and
then shoot sound volume, okay.
Everything else is pretty good.
What I would like to do is to make Big Boy
bigger, so I'll go back to my sprites.
Find the enemyGreen, and then I'm gonna
rename it while I'm here Big Boy.
Just to show that I'm actually changing
something in here to make this
a 50 under pixels per
unit I'm gonna apply.
That should make it tons bigger.
Okay, a little bit more bigger and
menacing on the screen just by
changing the pixels per unit.
Now back to Prefabs&gt; Big Boy,
make sure we've done everything
we need to do in there.
Damage deal script,
I think that's everything.
Okay, now over to our projectile,
let's find our enemy laser.
Duplicate enemy laser, we'll call this
in here we'll call it, Enemy Bomb.
Okay, and then clicking on Enemy Bomb.
And then let's go to our Sprites folder,
find my LaserRed10,
drag that over into where the sprite is.
And then drag our prefab
from our Prefabs folder,
it's just taking a moment to update.
We can right-click and do a refresh or
a re-import and that updates it.
Okay, drag that in,
it's been tinted with yellow.
I want to tint it more of a red color,
a lighter kind of red.
Maybe a darker kind of red, there we go.
Need to change the collision on this,
because we're using
the previous capsule collider.
I right-click, remove component, and
then instead add a component and
I'll do collider, let's see,
kind of boxy in shape.
So do a box collider, actually no,
I'm gonna change my mind on that.
I'm gonna do a circle collider and
Add Component, Circle Collider 2D.
Yeah, I think that's a little bit
more indicative of what I'm going
for, excellent.
So I have a collider,
we've got our Rigid Body 2D.
We've changed the color, we've changed the
name of it, it's all looking pretty good.
Does it have its appropriate script,
Damage Dealer script?
How much damage, still just 100,
I think that's okay.
Right, save that up,
now we need to spawn these guys.
So let's go to Waves, and what I'm gonna
do is make another path, actually.
So I've already got a couple of
instances in my path in the scene.
They're not doing anything in here,
this is just so
I can easily duplicate and then edit.
So I've got Path (2), if I open that up
and look at Waypoint (0), click on W.
Where are we gonna make this?
Let's make it go right from the top, and
remembering that the top starts
just outside of our camera.
Waypoint 1, coming down from the left,
waypoint 2, zig to the left a little bit.
And then waypoint 3, down to the right.
So it's basically just zig-zagging
its way across the screen.
Maybe we'll make that a little bit more
to the right, and 0 over to the left.
Zig-zags its way down the screen,
bombing the player the whole time,
I think that would be good.
Actually, we need to
have it over to the side.
We don't want the player just
to stand over to the left and
be like, you can't touch me.
We wanna actually cover the whole
play space, as this particular enemy
comes down through the world so
that the player fears for their life.
And then they zero in on the player and
bonk into them, okay, cool.
So find our Paths folder,
drag path2 down there and in.
Like I said, I don't need any of these,
so I'm gonna go ahead and delete them.
They're just there so I can duplicate,
make extra copies of new things.
But I can do that by dropping one of
my existing prefabs in as an instance.
And then to create something new or I
could just duplicate a path down in here.
Now to our Waves,
let's find our Waves folder.
I'm going to click on Wave number 1 and
change it from Roger to Big Boy, Big Boy.
And then from Path Prefab
instead of Path 0 do Path (2),
time between spawns 0.5 and
0.3, we'll see how that goes.
And I'll show you number of enemies we'll
say 6,and then the movements be we'll say
2, so they're coming nice and
slowly into the screen.
Let's see if we've captured
everything in there or
if we've forgotten anything at all.
I should delete these couple
of guys from the screen, but
we'll leave it as now as is.
Okay, so we haven't given it
the projectile that we want and
they're a little bit
spaced close together.
So let's find the enemy wave, so Wave 1.
The time between spawns, we'll say 1,
random factor 0.5, hopefully that's okay.
6 move speed, seemed okay at 2.
And we've got a null reference exception
that'll give us some clues here.
Object reference not set to an instance,
so Big Boy that we've dropped into
the scene, that's just the one
we're playing around with.
So we'll delete here and then we'll
delete the other one out of the scene.
That should clear up those
errors that we've had.
Now we need to change the projectile and
we do that by clicking on Big Boy and
saying that his projectile,
instead of Enemy Laser,
is going to be the Enemy Bomb.
Okay, let's click play Do
a little bit [SOUND] shoot,
out he comes dropping some bombs.
Those bombs are dropping mightily fast,
we need to space them out a little bit,
and he's a bit too easy to kill.
Okay, so health we haven't changed
the health on Big Boy in our prefab.
So let's make the health say 600,
actually you know what?
I'm gonna be nasty and make it a 1000 and
then score value we'll say, 460,
for example.
And then Projectile Speed,
I think a little bit faster, so
a 3 on the Projectile Speed.
And then what I'm looking for?
Prefabs, Big Boy, we want him shooting.
So minimum time between shots, that's
way too little, so we'll say 1.5, and
the maximum time between
shots we'll say 2.5.
We'll see how that goes.
Actually, we'll say from 1 to 2,
see how that is.
Projectile speed, I think,
little bit faster, we'll say 5.
And then we'll click on play,
see how that tuning is, [SOUND].
Okay, we've got him coming out [SOUND],
shooting, shooting, it's taking awhile.
The whole point of this is it takes
a while to shoot and to kill,
and then we're still killing it
when these other ones come out.
So I've got bullets going everywhere,
a little bit of bullet hell,
which is exactly what we want.
We could spawn another wave of them,
here they come now.
Okay, so I haven't got a lot
of variety in my waves,
I haven't really tuned that a lot.
But for now,
I think this is a pretty good wave,
that it's creating some good dodging and
[SOUND].
Yes, okay, I like it, I like it a lot.
Okay, so we got ourselves a new enemy,
a new wave, a new path, a new projectile,
everything's working well,
it's all lining up.
And I just wanted to go
through that whole process so
we're testing out every bit of it.
So reminding ourselves as well of how
we add tons of variation into our game.
In the next video we'll add a little
bit of spice into that projectile so
it looks a little bit
more interesting as well.
But for
now my challenge to you is to add MOAR.
So add more enemies, add more paths.
Add more visual effects,
add more sound effects, and
to show us what you got when
you have done all of that.
So get in there and really play around,
have some fun with making some
challenge for the player.
Making some variety, making
different things, different enemies,
different colors, everything.
So now's a good time to play around
with what we currently have and
to throw a whole bunch of more content
at your game and see how it feels.
Okay, and please do share with what
you've got, I would love to see it.
Great work and
I will see you in the next video.