[MUSIC]
Hello again!
In this video,
I'm going to be tuning my game so
that it has a more of a final tuning
of the gameplay that I'm happy with.
I'm still terrible at it, but
I'm looking for fast and furious, and
I feel I get fast and furious.
So I want you to be tuning your game to
the point where you're happy with how
it plays.
So let's jump in and
talk about game tuning and playtesting.
Let's start by talking a little
bit about playtesting.
When you're playtesting your game,
always tune to your "Player Experience".
That means always think about
your player experience.
And make sure that whatever you change
in your game is creating that player
experience.
Just a reminder of what
my player experience was,
this is the slide from way back in
lecture number two in this section.
We had a Player Experience
of Quick reactions, so
I wanted my player to feel like
the game was fast and furious.
And that is what I need to bear in
mind with every single tweak I do,
am I creating fast and furious?
Also, when you're playtesting, make sure
you aim for challenging but winnable.
We play our game over and
over and over and over.
And sometimes I see a lot
of people create really
difficult games because
that's their own skill level.
So just remember that your player
hasn't played 1,000 times,
so your players haven't played
the game as many times as you have.
And also look for bugs and problems as
you're tuning, that's really important as
you're playtesting,
you're playtesting to improve.
In the last lecture,
we were playing around, just be crazy,
think of whatever you want,
think of extreme tuning.
Now we're looking to narrow it down.
We're looking to find the bugs,
the problems, and to get a tight tuning so
that it feels like a compelling game,
and then ask a friend to play.
This is an important part of playtesting,
is to ask someone else to play so
it's not just you.
So you can see straightaway if
they don't know what's going on or
if it's too difficult or
if they get bored very easily.
That's a key part of playtesting.
Okay, so I'm just going to jump
back into my game over here, and
quickly show you the tuning
that I'm going to do.
I've been playing around with
it a little bit off camera, so
I've got some conclusions.
I am going to go for
a one ball system for now,
just because we haven't created our code
to accommodate ten balls bouncing around.
I think that would be really cool,
but I don't want to do that and
then have to go off and
reinvent all the code that we've created.
So it assumes one ball in a lot of places,
so, we'll just do the one ball.
And then my paddle,
I think I'm going to return that
back to the scale it was before.
Again, just for the sake of simplicity,
where I'm going through and
teaching you guys how to do this.
And for you, you can evolve and change,
and push it in all crazy directions,
but I want to keep mine
a little bit vanilla.
In other words, a little bit neutral so
that you can change it however you want,
now, what else do we need to do?
The ball, I'm giving the ball an almighty
shove with a 50 on the Y Push,
I'm going to turn that down to 12.
So it's a good fast paced game,
but not out of control fast, and
then what else do I need to do here?
My Random Factor, I'm going to put that
up to 1, because that was kind of fun,
between 1 and 2 is kinda fun.
But sometimes the ball goes too slow with
the randomness, it hits something and
then it goes really slow,
and again, we can fix that.
My challenge for
you would be, how could you create a piece
of code in there that would stop your ball
going super slow in those situations
from a random point of view?
But I want to jump into the next
section of course pretty soon, so
I'm not going to go and
dig into those things.
But great challenge for
you to take your game and
evolve on it if you see any of
these things you're interested in.
Make sure we turn for our play space,
I'm going to turn my collider back on,
my Lose Collider, and then,
the score, where is our score?
That's on Game Session,
the score per points, per block,
well, let's put that back to 83, shall we?
And I'll apply that to the prefab,
make sure you're applying all these
things to your prefab, the ball.
I'll apply this to the prefab as well, so
it's relevent in our other
sections throughout other levels.
And then the last thing I would do in
my level just here to make sure it's
interesting and cool,
I just throw a few more blocks in here.
Probably just the level one breakable
blocks, just to make it interesting.
Duplicate and then move it across,
while holding control, duplicate,
duplicate, duplicate.
And bring it all the way down to here,
duplicate just to add a little bit
more spice in this particular level.
I think that's pretty good, I think I only
just made one more extra block, so for
symmetry's sake,
I'll put this block over just in there.
Okay, so I've got my level with some
blocks, I think the tuning is pretty good.
I'd then play my game a whole bunch of
times over to see whether I think it's
interesting, and the right speed,
and is it too easy, too hard?
[SOUND] [LAUGH] Okay, maybe I just
answered the question of too hard.
But I'm going for quick reactions,
I wanted people to be playing my game,
going, what, that was crazy!
But I don't want them to be playing
the game saying, aah, this is impossible!
So, you can see that I'm still pushing
the ball out way too quickly or
what's my game speed at the moment,
is it set at 1?
Okay, it's set to 2.61,
that could be an issue.
So I'll put it to 1, and then make sure
that the game speed isn't crazy out of
control fast, and
now it's way too slow and boring.
So I'm going to give the ball
a stronger push, this is the thing,
it's backwards and forwards,
tune one thing, tune another thing.
Make sure you haven't accidentally
broken something when you tune it, and
apply it to the prefab,
just so I don't forget.
Click on play, this should be fast and
furious, but not fast and
ridiculous, let's see if I
can slow the ball a bit.
Okay, that's feeling pretty close, I'm
happy with that amount of, my goodness,
where am I?
That's going on with my game,
one ball, regular size paddle,
it gets up in there, this is cool, I want
the player to fail a number of times.
The particle effects are kind of
getting in the way of seeing the ball,
I think that's nifty as well,
so I like that.
And then, [SOUND], when I hit that last
one, okay, boink, game over, cool,
that was good.
That was the right sort of pace of
what I'm going for for my game, so
I'm going to save that.
Make sure that my hierarchy
is arranged nice and neatly,
breakable blocks, drop that into blocks,
all looks pretty good.
Okay, playspace, great, so
I'm going to save, and for now,
I'm just looking at the game play.
I'm not looking at the level flow from
level to level to level to make sure
that's all tight.
I'll do that in upcoming playtesting,
but for now,
I'm just looking at
the core gameplay moment.
So the challenge for you,
as always, here's my challenge,
this is what I'd love
to see you get up to.
Tune and playtest your game,
find the turning that you like,
as I did, go through that process of,
is it too fast?
Is it too slow?
Is it too crazy?
Do I like it?
Get to the point where, yes,
you've learned from your extreme tuning.
But you don't necessary have to leave the
extreme-ness in there if it's not helping
your game.
Make sure the game isn't impossible,
as I said, make sure the game
isn't boringly easy, that's no fun either,
and ask a friend to play.
That would be the big challenge,
I'd highly recommend you do that.
This is the stage of the course where
you should be a little bit vulnerable.
And ask a friend, someone that you
trust or a family member or a parent or
a sibling, say, hey,
just give this a play.
And see if you can survive for
more than ten seconds, or
whatever the challenge might
be that you give to someone.
So there's the challenge,
jump in, take that on.
In the next video, I'm going to give you a
tool, a little technique that will help us
playtest through our levels
a little bit more quickly.
And to be able to test
out different scenarios.
So great work, and
I'll see you again soon.