[MUSIC]
In this video,
we're creating ourselves a third defender.
It's the gnome who's gonna sit there and
blink.
I'm assuming because it's kind
of funny the way he blinks.
Blink, blink, blink.
And then he's gonna bounce and
shoot, fire his ax.
The ax is gonna explode the lizards,
and everything is gonna be amazing!
So let's jump in and get started.
Okay we need more defenders!
What defenders do we need?
Well, here's the defenders
I'm going to have.
Just four of them for me.
You can five or 10 or a 100!
But I've got trophy, cactus,
we've made already gnome, and a gravestone
we're also putting into the game.
I've just got a little table here
to show the purpose of them, so
we're not just kind of
slapping them in willy nilly.
You can see that we've got cost, medium,
low, high, medium, damage, and health.
So let's see.
The difference between these is
going to be my two projectile
defenders at the moment.
So the cactus is basically low and
cheap and squishy and
the gnome is expensive and
does a ton of damage.
The gravestone is gonna be something
that doesn't shoot but just acts as
a block to block the attackers so that
it buys you some time so that your guys
behind the line can shoot them and
obviously the trophy generates resources.
So I'm gonna issue you
a big old challenge.
This is gonna be a mega challenge
that brings all your knowledge and
learning together,
is to make the gnome from scratch.
And if you don't have it,
you might wanna go grab the gnome.
Let's see, where is it?
The Gnome Sprite.
I've got Gnome Idle just here that I'll
be using for, obviously the idle, and
also the Gnome Hop that I'll be using for
when the gnome is attacking.
So Just to point that out.
I've got it in my Sprite folder
that I gave you way back early on
in this section of the course,
so you should have that as well.
If you're not using the gnome,
you can use whatever you want.
You can go find your own sprite sheet for
that.
But here is the big old challenge,
and here are the steps as a reminder.
If you wanna just go ahead and
create it now without a reminder of
the steps to see how good your
memory's been, that's awesome.
But if you want the steps, here they are,
so create the game object,
add the animator, collider and the scripts
that we've created for our defenders.
Create the child object with
renderer that will be called body.
Create the Animator Controller, create
required animations with events, for
example, the idol and the shooting.
Add the animations and
transitions to the Animator Controller.
Create the parameters and
conditions for the transitions.
It's all rhyming.
And to add the button to the UI
with the image and script so
you can buy that particular defender.
Finally to tune the health,
the damage and the cost.
And obviously if you get stuck or
want a reminder, then go check out what we
did for the cactus and if you look at
that, and say, I could not be bothered.
Well, first of all, tsk,
tsk, but no problem,
you could just copy your cactus and change
its color to yellow and call it gnome.
So there you go.
You've finished the task.
You can do that if you want, you can cheat
or if you want some excellent practice to
really cement this knowledge, then go
ahead and create your gnome defender now.
See you back here when you're done.
Okay, let's make ourselves
a Gnome Defender.
Right click, create, empty.
We'll call this Gnome, and
we'll give the gnome a body at this point.
We'll call the body, Body.
Great name for body.
And what do we need to do on the gnome?
Well, we need to add our scripts so
this is a defender.
We also need to, let's use the cactus
as a point of inspiration here.
We need a shooter, defender,
Box Collider, and animator okay?
That's all pretty good.
We could duplicate the cactus but for
now I'm just gonna go through
all these individual steps.
So shooter, because it will be a shooter,
we want to add ourselves a Box Collider.
I'm going to do the Box Collider after
I put the Sprite Renderer on because
the Sprite Renderer is going to
give us some shape to it and
then the Box Collider knows
what it should be going around.
Change this to five.
The Sprite we need to go and
slice up our Sprite sheet.
Let's slice up our Sprite sheet now.
We'll start off with the Gnome iIdle
Sprite sheet and block that out of the way
the actual Gnome Idle now Sprite mode
this needs to be multiple click apply.
And let's have a look at
our sprite 567 by 150, so
567: one, two, three, four,
five, six, seven gnomes.
Let's get our calculator here,
calculate 567 divided by 7.
81.
So we need to have these 81 wide.
So click on Sprite Editor up to Slice.
Instead of automatic,
we'll slice by cell size and
change this to 81 by whatever the size,
150, that's the size of it, slice.
Okay, that all looks pretty good.
Got our gnome,
then click on apply that one sliced off.
Excellent.
Now while I'm here,
I'll go slice up the Gnome Hop,
which is going to be used for
our new attack change it
from single to multiple.
Click on group down here, apply.
I'm going to take click on Sprite editor.
And I'm going to take a wild guess and
say that this is also a 81 by 150
slice and that looks like it is good.
Okay, and click on apply.
Now, what do we need to do next?
Well, we've got the gnome,
we've got the body.
Okay, we need to give it a one sprite, so
we're gonna find a Gnome Sprite,
one just there.
Gnome Hop 6 is the one I'll be using.
He is currently sitting right on top of an
ax, that's why it looked a bit funny and
we can see facing the wrong way.
First of all, I wanna reset
the transforms, pops him down there.
Now I can change the scale to -1,
not -11, -1, all the way over there.
Check the gnome body, that needs to be
reset to the transform, as well, so
it's right in the middle.
Looks like it's now at the 0,0 point,
and the gnome has been flipped.
Fantastico.
While we're here, I'm also going to
create an empty and call this gun.
I don't think I had that
in my list of things.
Did I have that in my list?
I don't have that, so
it's a little bit sneaky.
We'll pop this in, gun,
it's just an empty game object.
We need to put it wherever we
think the ax should be coming out.
Technically, it doesn't really have
any hands [LAUGH] in the way we're
using the gnome.
So we'll have it come out of his eyeballs,
how's that?
An eyeball ax-throwing gnome, perfect.
So back over here in the gnome,
we need an animator.
Animator, how do I spell animator,
A-N-I-M.
And also, our Box Collider 2D that
fits around the gnome pretty well.
I'm gonna drag my gnome into
where the center point would be.
That gnome's too big, isn't he?
He doesn't fit in our spot there.
So, how do we change that?
Go back to our Gnome Hop and
pixels per unit, we'll make this one 50,
and click on apply, and then,
yeah, that looks better.
It's just a little gnome there.
We'll make sure we change the idle
while we're here to 150, as well,
pixels per unit, click apply now,
back to the Gnome game object,
we've got our Box Collider which
fits the entire, three and one,
fits the entire area.
Yep, that's good.
Wunderbar.
And we have our animator,
we have to now click on the gnome,
click on our Animation, Create.
We'll create our idle.
So find Assets, Animations Defenders, and
this will be Gnome Idle.
And then click add Property
within our animation window here,
surf our way down to body,
Sprite Renderer, find the plus,
click on plus for Sprite Renderer,
grab our Gnome Idle 0 to 6,
drag those into our animation, Boink!
Excellent.
Delete these last two down the end
that we don't need anymore.
Change the frames to 24 so
it's a similar speed.
See how that looks.
He's just sitting there blinking.
Well, that's kind of neat, isn't it?
He did tilt, I wonder what that was about.
Is that blinking too fast?
Probably blinking a bit too fast.
So grab all these, pull the little
blue handily things out a little bit.
Blink, blink, blink.
That's creepy, isn't it?
I like it.
Okay.
I'm going to save because I
haven't saved for awhile.
I've got him seen in there doing his idle.
We need to make another animation, so
click on Gnome Idle,
create New Clip, Gnome attack.
Attack of the Gnomes, excellent.
Change the frames to 24.
Now, add Property, surf down to body,
click on Sprite Renderer, scroll down to
the bottom, click the plus next to Sprite.
Grab all of the frame from the Gnome Hop,
drag those in from the first frame
onwards, delete the two down the end,
and this is probably too fast as well.
But all that's Baloo doop do doop do doop.
We'll see how it goes,
if it's a little bit slower.
I could just change the samples here,
but I want to keep them all
24 just in case we need to do that for
some reason at some point.
So we'll take this up to the full
one second boop be doop be doop.
Now that's too slow, looks down,
back to what we had before bouncy bounce.
Okay, great.
I like it.
I'm a gnome.
That's what he's gonna be
doing when he's throwing.
You could be changing
the color a little bit.
As he throws is, so
where is he gonna throw it?
He's gonna throw it pretty fast
if we have it every single frame.
This one is gonna be throw, throw, throw,
so what I might do here,
we haven't done this before.
But I'm gonna grab these frames and move
my slider along, I'm gonna go copy, and
then paste.
So it's copying and
pasting the same frames that we've got.
So I'm doing two loops of this.
You know what I'm gonna do,
one I'm gonna do two more loops, so
I'm gonna highlight all the frames again,
copy, and then paste.
So now I have one, two,
three, four loops of it.
But the reason I'm doing it this way
instead of just allowing it to loop,
and loop, and loop is cuz I wanna have my
animation event somewhere along here is
I've got two seconds of animation and
this way I can have the gnome
shooting within that two seconds.
So, probably near the start
of when he wakes up and says,
"I'm now going to attack around about
here." I'll put in animation event.
And then when I click here
in that animation event,
we will say fire is what we're firing.
Excellent, he's gonna be bing
at that point, shooting his ax.
We'll have to create for him.
So back over into the gnome.
I know I'm bouncing around a little bit,
I'm not necessarily following the order
that I've given you but
we're getting all the bits and pieces in.
And this is often how it works, you're
kind of like, now I need one of these!
Now I need one of those so
that all I need a projectile.
Click on our selector.
Find the ax.
You're not gonna drag it in from
I haven't made it as a prefab.
Sorry everyone.
So here's my projectile's folder.
Drag the ax into our prefab's folder.
Delete the ax from our scene because
we don't want that kind of hanging
around in there.
Now, when I click on my
gnome game object for
a projectile I am going to drag in the ax
prefab I just created, link in that, and
for gun, I'm dragging that in from
the gnome object that we've got to gun.
So from hierarchy over into our
inspector we've got ax and we have gun.
What we need to do at this point is,
under defender's folder,
I'm gonna drag my gnome into
prefab the entire gnome.
Okay, great, so let's have a look at his
animator and see what's going on here.
Gnome Idle.
That's good, but
he's not going into gnome attack.
So from Gnome Idle we want
to create a transition.
My gnome attack animation's
in there already.
If yours is not in there,
you might need to drag it in.
But click on Gnome Idol.
Right click make transition
over to Gnome Attack.
While we're here, right click on Gnome
attack, make transition back to Gnome Idol
on the first transition line
that goes from idol to attack,
I'm going to open up my settings, find the
transition duration, change that to zero,
just so it's snapping nice and neat from
one to the other, turn off has exit time.
Remember we don't want it to finish
the attack completely before it
transitions back.
So click on the plus in my animator
window to add a new parameter,
make this a ball click is attacking as
we did last time, so it's the same.
Now when I'm over in my inspector,
we've got the conditions down in
the bottom right and I click on plus,
his attacking is true.
Yes, that's exactly what we want.
Now let's do the other transition
from attack back to idle.
Click on that.
Change your transition duration
to zero as we've done before.
Click the plus under conditions.
His attacking is what?
It's going to be false.
Excellent, okay, that seems like
we've got most of it in there.
Do a save and click on Play just to see.
Actually, you know what, these spawners
are driving me a little bit crazy, so
over on spawners,
highlight all the spawners.
I'm gonna change this random from 2 to 5.
Okay, now click on Play.
I'll give it some randomness in here.
Somewhere between two and five seconds,
someone in this bottom lane's gonna jump
in and bounce bounce bounce, and
he shoots the ax, wonderful.
The ax is not hitting and destroying,
we probably don't have a collider on
the ax, not a problem at this point.
And the ax I think looks pretty good,
might be a little bit high, but
I think that's looking
pretty nice at the moment.
So what do we need to
do to finish this off?
Let's go and have a look at our
ax prefabs, projectile, ax.
Do we have, we do not,
we need a Box Collider on our ax.
We'll assume that it
put the Collider on ax.
Now, let's drag in, have a look.
Where's the Collider?
That Collider is quite massive.
Good thing we had a look at it.
Is that ax the right size?
Okay, something funky
going on with the ax here.
I think it's because it's put way,
way back.
I'm in 3D mode, that's not smart, Rick.
Okay, so my ax is gone and
been dropped in at a weird spot.
That's not a problem because
it's just the prefab,
but we'll make it zero, zero,
zero, and then apply that.
Okay, now when we have a look at this ax,
Box Collider, that's what we're doing.
Click on the Box Collider, bring it
in nice and tight on the ax, just so
it's not bumping anything in other
lanes that it's not supposed to.
Box wider and box, you could have it as
a spherical Box Collider, like a circle.
That'll be fine as well, but
I'm just gonna do it as a box for now.
Okay, looking pretty
tight on the ax there.
Just delete the ax from the scene.
Let's check that the ax works,
save ourselves the upset of if it
flies through the creatures later on and
we haven't tested it.
He's sitting there blinking.
Somebody in my lane excitement alert,
alert, bonk, passes right through
probably cuz it's not a trigger.
Where is my ax?
Drop it into the scene.
What do we go going on here?
Box Collider we haven't got,
is triggered selected.
Okay now!
Actually you know our collider
because Rick is a dunderhead,
didn't apply to the pre fab.
I think we should rename
this entire course
Rick forgets to apply
things back to the pre fab.
What do you recon?
Now we'll apply back to the prefab, and
we'll move this ax aside just
in case we do need it again.
Hopefully we don't, hopefully we've now
got everything buttoned up with the ax and
actually getting to getting
putting the gnome button on there.
So that guy is doing his thing down there.
He said, I'm an ax.
Got his ax is Kaboom!
Kapowie.
Wonderful, that works.
Great, now we can get review,
thanks to your service.
Ax, the last thing we're
gonna do is create a what?
Create a button.
Okay, so how do we do that?
Over into our buttons area.
I'm going to Click on Background,
open that up.
We've got Cactus and Trophy.
I'm gonna duplicate this cuz I
think they're pretty similar.
So Ctrl+D to duplicate.
It's not Trophy, it's a Gnome.
And then Sprite Renderer instead of
being Trophy needs to be a gnome,
find a gnome, find a gnome.
Okay, this Gnome Hop 5 should do us.
Double click on that,
drag along to the right.
It's a little bit bigger than what we
need, so just within this window here,
I'm going to hit my R key, just scroll it
all down a little bit on the entire gnome.
The Box Collide has
scrolled down as well so
I will make that take up
most of the area of the box.
Whoops, goodness me.
Goodness me.
Click on Edit Collider again.
Open up, open up.
Okay, cool, you know what?
Sprite Renderer, yes, color,
right, Collider, Defender Button.
Okay, and then Defender Prefab,
we don't wanna be spawning trophies,
we wanna click on that and spawn gnomes.
Click Save again, just in case there's a,
I was about to say typhoon.
That doesn't make sense, does it?
Some sort of blackout is what I meant.
Click on gnome,
plonk them around in the scene.
Wonderful, they're all
shooting their axes.
The axes exploded the lizards, yay,
we've made ourselves another defender.
That's really cool, we're starting
to create variety into our game.
Let's do a little bit of tuning now so
that we actually have a proper game.
We're giving the player tons of
resources at the start, that's okay.
What should the cost of our
gnome be at this point?
Well maybe I'll go something
like fifty one hundred and
two hundred just to see how that feels.
The gnome's four times more expensive.
Just to see how that goes.
So where do we find
the costs of our gnome?
I'm pretty sure it's on
the defender itself.
So click on Defender, find The Gnome,
we're going to have at
the top here star cost 200.
Perfect.
That's right on the prefab.
So we don't need to apply it back.
The cactus will now change to 50 and
the trophy we will change to,
where's a trophy cost.
It is just here.
We will leave this a hundred.
We'll see how that goes and
then my starting currency.
I'm going to leave it as a thousand while
I'm still playing around with it because I
don't want you guys to be watching me
not being able to place things down, so
we'll leave that at whatever it is now.
A thousand, I think we'll just pretend
it's, for example, two hundred so
I can place down one gnome and
then I have to sit around and
wait and wait and wait and wait or
I could place down say two trophies and
wait and wait and wait or
I could place down four cactuses.
Okay yes.
So that's starting to, we've got some
shape now that things are taking.
So good stuff we've got ourselves,
three defenders.
I really want that fourth defender so
that we can create a proper system of
giving the player choice and having
progressions through a couple of levels.
So in the next video, we're gonna create
ourselves a gravestone, or a tombstone,
which would be a little bit different
to the shooting defenders, so
let's take that on in the next video.
Great work, well done!
If you've created something that
you think is particularly nifty,
then please share it.
Now is the perfect time to share in our
discussion so we can have a look at it and
see what you've come up with.
Okay, great stuff,
I'll see you again shortly.