[MUSIC]
Hello, again, here's the outcome of what
we're going to do in this video that will
change our spawners so that they
are spawning from an array of attackers.
So you can see here it's sometimes a fox,
sometimes a lizard,
sometimes a fox, whereas other lanes
we can say just lizards or just foxes.
So it gives us more flexibility and
variety in our game, so let's jump in and
get started.
Okay in this video we're gonna be working
in the attacker's spawner script and
pretty much no other scripts.
And what I would like you to do
is a challenge for this video.
So it's gonna be a little bit trickier,
but it's gonna be a good test for
how well you understand arrays.
And I'll give you the step for it here,
we wanna spawn attackers from array.
First of all, so I'll give you
some detailed instructions and
then see how you go.
So change our Attacker variable
to Attacker [ ] array and
rename appropriately.
So just to anchor you for
what I'm talking about here, we have our
serialized field attackerPrefab
as type Attacker at the top.
That's what I'm talking about there,
and then to extract.
So to take out where we
instantiate an Attacker[ ] and
put that into a new method called Spawn().
So find where we instantiate, put that
into a new method called Spawn(), and
then make or change SpawnAttacker(),
which is what we have in here currently,
SpawnAttacker().
So to change that so it is responsible for
randomly picking an attacker
index from the array and
calling Spawn() using that index.
And hopefully that's enough for you to
use to jump in, take on this challenge.
So give it your best shot and
I'll see you back here when you're done.
Okay, so right up the top of our Attack
Spawner script, the Attacker Spawner.
I'll change my Attacker into, I'll add my
square brackets, double-click, Ctrl+RR,
I will change this to attackerPrefabArray,
and hit Apply.
Now, that's gonna break some things
down here because we're trying to
spawn from an array, but
we're not telling it where from the array.
So we'll get to that in a moment,
first of all,
I'm going to create my
method that I'll call.
I'll delete my update method that's
hanging out down at the bottom down here,
first of all.
So I'll create a new method I'll
call private void Spawn, and
then within here I need to know what
I'm spawning, or who I'm spawning.
So I'll create a requirement of
a parameter that is an Attacker, and
I'll call this myAttacker.
And then within this method,
we're going to go in and
grab our Attacker newAttacker Instantiate
etc., Cut that, Paste it down into here.
Okay, still a bit of tidying up to do,
we'll get to that in a moment.
Within SpawnAttacker, what are we doing
now, well let's create our index.
So variables so var attackerIndex =,
this is the random part,
Random.Range, there we go.
And that will be from between what,
zero to the length of our array,
and the length of the array
we can find by saying
attackerPrefabArray., what, .length.
Okay, so we've got our index,
it's gonna be somewhere between zero and
how of the many attackers we've got.
And then we want to call
our Spawn() method.
Spawn(), and what are we spawning in here,
well we need to be spawning,
its requiring we've just
created that we feed into it,
who the attacker is and
the attacker is going to be who?
It's going to be from our
attackerPrefabArray, then it's going to be
an index within that, so,
attackerIndex, and then semicolon.
Okay, so just to be clear on here, we've
said, an index somewhere between 0 and
length of the array.
And then let's spawn one
of those particular things,
one of the attackers that we've just
gone and identified within our array.
Now, when we come down to Attacker,
Attacker = Instantitate,
attackerPrefabArray, instead
of attackerPrefabArray,
what are we going to do in here?
We're going to spawn myAttacker,
which is what we've just passed
in from our SpawnAttacker().
Okay, hopefully that all makes sense,
as always, if you've got any questions,
throw them in the discussions.
Let's save that up and see what we now
see when we click on our Spawners.
That should update too, in a moment once
it's done thinking, should update to say
okay, I've got an attackerPrefabArray
in here, currently the size is zero.
And remember if we drag in our prefabs,
it will automatically update the size.
So let's go and create let's just go and
find our attackers,
click on Spawner(1),
highlight fox and lizard.
Okay, I'm gonna have to click on
Spawner(1) and then click the Lock icon.
Now if I click on fox and lizard, drag
those over the top of attackerPrefabArray,
it makes the size of my array two and
puts in fox and lizard.
If I, what spawn was that for, Spawner(1),
right, so if I unclick my lock,
click on Play, Spawner(1) is
the spawner down on the bottom.
Let's see what happens there.
Ignore these top two,
I'm gonna just go to Scene View so
you can see the moment they spawn.
So a lizard came out after two to five
seconds, a fox came out, after two
to five seconds, something came out,
the overactive gnome killed too quickly.
Let's put our numbers down to one and
to one, so
they're being produced very quickly.
Now let's click on Play, I just wanna
check that it's producing sometimes
lizard, sometimes fox, and
that there's a randomness.
So lizard, fox, fox, fox, lizard,
okay, so now we've got this
variability where it's not just always one
particular creature coming out of a lane.
Now we could still keep that,
I could say, Spawner(5),
I want to have as just lizards.
So the top row is gonna be lizards.
Once the player has played this level for
a little while, they realize, uh-huh,
it's always lizards at the top.
I can have strategy in my top lane.
Spawner(4) we might say
that is always foxes.
So no point putting grave stones in this
lane, cuz there's foxes coming in there.
And then Spawner(2) and (3),
I will say both fox and
lizard, if I drag them both
over in there fox and lizard.
Okay so let's just click Play and
make sure that all works.
I've gone and got this bottom lane
spitting out dudes really fast.
The top four lines not as fast,
we've got variability, awesome.
Okay so, it is not,
we haven't created with our game design,
precision, at the moment.
We haven't said it is exactly gonna be
a lizard and then three seconds later,
exactly a fox.
And then three seconds later exactly
another fox, and then five second exactly
a lizard, its not that sort of
mechanic that we've created here.
We've created randomness and
variability, which I think makes for
great replay value and
keeps the player on their toes.
But we do have enough control,
where like in the top lane,
we can say, from a strategy point of view.
Let's push out just one type here in one
type there and randomness down the bottom.
Okay, so great work, and
I'll see you in the next video.