[MUSIC]
We left the last video with
a null reference exception.
So let's have a look at
what's going on there, and
let's have a look at how
we can address that.
So I've given you a link to the Unity
documentation about what is a null
reference exception.
Literally it happens when you try
to access a reference variable
that isn't referencing any object.
So it's when we're trying to be too clever
and say, hey, go to this thing, but
that thing doesn't exist, we thought it
existed, maybe it doesn't exist anymore.
So let's have a look and dig into that
in the context of our own code and
see what that means.
So I'll see if I can replicate this and
get this error again.
Sometimes it's there, sometimes it's not,
which to me says it's something to do with
our execution order when certain things
might be happening at the same time,
might nearly be happening,
or not happening.
Gets to the end, you lost,
we'll click try again.
Didn't happen that time.
We'll click again.
No, main menu, we got it that time.
Okay, so NullReferenceException,
if you have a look at it,
it's talking about object references,
not set to an instance of an object, and
we're looking at attacker.OnDestroy.
So if I open that up,
double-click on that, first place to go.
It's got an issue with this, and
this in and of itself looks fine.
This has been working okay.
This is how we're keeping
track of how many enemies,
how many attackers we've got in our scene.
But there's something interesting,
cuz we're using OnDestroy.
Remember when we looked at
the execution order of this,
this happens right at the very, very end.
So it could be something else is happening
before this and then this is happening.
So it could be something to
do with a level controller.
Let's have a look at where
this method is created over in
level controller I believe.
AttackerKilled, yeah just in here.
So it's looking for in here,
when we call that method it's saying
I want to do something
with numberOfAttackers.
However, if we've ended our level and
LevelController no longer exists,
then numberOfAttackers no longer exists.
This method might no longer exist,
there could be a muddle going on in there.
So it might be that to do a destroying
is happening at the end of our level.
Not just when we think
we've won the level, but
they're also being destroyed when
the level is destroyed and loaded.
So everything gets destroyed
when we load a new level,
everything from the existing level, so
that could be what's going on there.
Let's see if we can implement a fix for
this that works.
We'll go back into attacker.
Now what we wanna say is look for
LevelController, but if this is null
then don't do anything, don't go and
try to call AttackerKilled.
So let's just rewrite this a little bit.
I'm in my Attacker script here,
we'll say LevelController.
So type LevelController, we'll call it
LevelController =, and now we'll find,
so I'm just bringing this line up and
removing the method call from the end.
So find object of type LevelController.
So first of all, we are defining this.
Now let us say if LevelController!=
which means is not null then continue
on with what we are going to do.
So this is a way of saying if
it's not null, execute this code.
If it is null, then just stop here.
We can write it the other way around and
say,
if LevelController is null then return.
But we'll write it this way to say
only do this code if it's not null.
What's the code?
Well, it's gonna be
LevelController.AttackerKilled();.
Okay, save that up.
So that's just protecting
against our null condition.
Save that and then,
let's play the game a couple times now,
see if we can replicate this.
We'll do the same as we did last time,
put down a couple of defenders,
get to the end, click main menu.
And we have a different error, but
not the error that we had just before.
Let's do it one more time, it's always
good when we get a different error.
Gotta track these things
down when we find them.
Click on Play, we'll just make
sure that our try again works.
[SOUND] Okay, and then try again.
We're not getting any errors,
that all looks pretty good, and try again.
Okay, so
I think we've addressed that error.
It might come up again places but
you can only stomp it when you find it.
Do your best with these errors.
Don't drive yourself crazy trying
to find absolute perfection.
Address it when you find
it is usually my approach.
So we had another one that came up
in there that was to do with the win
condition and lose condition.
Let me just play, lose,
and then go to Main Menu,
so we can find that other one as well.
Okay, Main Menu, okay,
let's have a look at what's going on here.
This is the variable winLevel of
LevelController has not been assigned.
Okay, so this one is a very common one
as well, this is what you'll see a lot.
So what's going on here,
in LevelController we're looking for
our GameObject of winLabel.
And then at some point,
we're turning the winLabel on, and
we're turning the winLabel off.
However, in our LevelController
in our start screen,
we don't have or
need this win, loss condition.
So that's something that
I hadn't considered,
I hadn't thought about when I just went
and dragged that in to my start scene.
So let's go to our start scene, or
now scenes, start screen in here.
So here's my challenge for you,
what is the best way for us to fix this?
How do we resolve our issue with the fact
that the LevelController is looking for
our win label and our lose label?
This, if you're understanding what
we're talking about this should be
a pretty easy fix.
But just take a moment to have
a think about how we can resolve this.
Okay, well, the best way to resolve this
is to not have the LevelController script
at all because I don't think we need that.
We're just needing to load the levels,
not control the levels.
This is not game play.
So I think what we can do here,
instead of using the LevelController,
let's say we've already
prefabbed a LevelLoader.
We have already prefabbed a LevelLoader,
which is just a game object that
has a LevelLoader script on it.
So I'm gonna drag that into my stat scene
and just delete the LevelController.
Now we need to get back to our canvas, the
start text is going to be a bit broken.
So we need to drag in the LevelLoader
into the missing object, and
change this to be LevelLoader,
change this to be start, where are we?
LoadNextScene, and then the quick text,
once again, drag in the LevelLoader,
MissingObject, and LevelLoader,
this is going to be QuitGame.
Okay, so I'm not gonna pretend
that I did that deliberately,
put in the LevelController
instead of the LevelLoader.
I did that accidentally, but
the console let me know, hey, Rick,
you've made a mistake because we don't
know what to assign the win label as.
So now when I save this up, click on play.
We should no longer be getting that
particular error, which is great.
Start the game, play it a little bit,
make sure we don't get any other
errors going on, try again.
Okay, and it's clear of errors, and
clear of warnings as well at the moment.
That should give you a big [SOUND]
state of feeling good about that
when you don't have any errors and
any warnings.
I recommend you try to smash
them as soon as you are able to.
Don't drop everything if you
are in the middle of a feature,
in the middle of something heavy.
Don't go and chase bugs and warnings and
errors until it's the right time for you.
But don't leave them more than
a very short amount of time before
you go and address them.
So we've talked a little bit
about null reference exceptions.
It's because Unity is trying to find
a reference to something which it cannot.
So reference to a variable that you're
saying should exist, but it does not.
It's saying it's null and
that null can cause warnings and issues.
So great work, well done, and
I'll see you in the next video.