[MUSIC]
Hey in this video I'm going
to start with a challenge,
I want you to create an options
screen that looks like this.
Sometimes a designer will hand you
a piece of paper or a image and
say make me one of these.
So you need to have a heading,
need to have a couple of text fields,
couple of buttons.
This button is the default button this
is the back button and then sliders so
that the player can be sliding
the volume up and down and
sliding the difficulty up and down.
So go ahead and make this screen.
Also for bonus points, implement that the
Back button takes you back to the Start
menu or the Start screen.
And on the Start screen,
you have an Options button that
takes you to the Options screen.
So there it is, there's your challenge,
jump in and take that on now, and
I'll see you back here when you're done.
I'm gonna start by finding my
Start Screen and duplicating that,
renaming my Start Screen
to be Options Screen.
Then open up Options Screen,
yes, it's opened up.
Find the Canvas, find the Image.
I'm gonna change my image, I've gone and
downloaded one of the other glitch images.
Let me just find Images folder here,
yes, drag that image in.
It's kind of a cool mushroom vendor guy.
It looks pretty cool,
I quite like that one.
And then here we are, Glitch_Meal,
I'm just gonna rename this to being
Options Screen Image, so
it's very clear what's going on.
Find my image Game object and
then drag in Options Screen Image.
There we go, one cool change, wonderful.
Okay, now let's find our Start Text,
it's no longer Start Text,
it's gonna be Options Heading,
I'll call it Options Heading.
Great, change it to
an orangey color I think?
There we go, just to be clear.
Click on W, move it over.
Probably left align cuz I'm gonna have
it over the left side of my screen.
There we go.
I'm gonna make it a little bit bigger
cuz it's a heading, 140, nice and big.
Okay, instead of saying Start Game,
it should say, Options.
And grab the quick text,
change that to be the back,
button and from quick,
it's gonna say back.
It's probably not quick text, is it?
It's probably quick button,
but okay, no problem.
And back down here make
this bigger as well.
I'll make it say 125, see how that looks.
I'll weight this one 140 as well, just to
be really clear, that's how we get back.
And then one more button that we need,
click on back button,
duplicate this,
rename it to be default button.
The text I'm gonna
change to be Default and
then click, move it on over a little bit.
So it's in the middle of the screen.
It's gonna be a little bit in conflict
with this whole Glitch heading here, but
I'm ignoring that for now.
Not very good design, but we're working
with the images that we've got, so
Default, Back, and Options.
Now we need some text, so
click on Options heading, duplicate that.
Highlight this, change it to.
Volume is gonna be the first one.
Volume, drag it down a little bit.
[SOUND] Change the color to
something that doesn't say,
I'm a button and
doesn't say, I'm a heading.
Change it to this bluey kinda thing,
I think.
Make the size smaller, down to 80.
How's that?
80, probably a little bit too small.
100, okay.
100 Options,
I'm probably gonna change this color.
Looking at it now,
I don't think it quite works, but
wait until we've got everything
else lined up first.
So change this to be, say, Volume.
At the very top, Volume, that's fine.
Volume, I will call it Volume Text
to differentiate that it is text and
not the slider we'll have in a minute.
So Duplicate that as well.
This will be called Difficulty Text,
the text will be called Difficulty.
Okay, slide that down a little bit.
Okay, that's most of it stubbed out,
now we need our sliders.
So underneath Canvas,
I'm gonna right-click UI, find a Slider.
Excellent it's nice and
tiny at the moment, let's scale it up.
Clicking on my R tool,
[SOUND] make it nice and bigger.
Okay, that's around a bit so
it looks like it's a 5.
5, 5, 5, nice and huge,
probably don't need it quite that big,
but we'll start there and
make it a bit smaller if need be.
So there's our Volume.
Okay, quite massive,
kind of bumping into the guy's face.
But we'll get it all stubbed in first,
and then we'll finesse it in a moment.
So instead of slider,
this needs to be Volume Slider, excellent.
And then we will duplicate that,
actually you know what,
I'll change it up a little bit.
First I'm going to the handle slide area.
We're gonna change,
we've done this before, the image,
instead of using the knob,
I'm gonna find the star.
There you are, have a little star on
there that we can slide up and down.
Okay there we go to our star slider.
Now let's click on the volume slider,
duplicate that, and
change this to be Difficulty Slider.
And I encourage you to do
your own finessing here.
Change it up.
Create something that
you think looks nifty.
We've gone through this before.
Animated sliders, they're really good.
So I think it is a little bit too big.
Go back to Volume Slider, change it to 4.
I think it's gonna fit on
the page a little bit better.
Okay, good,
good move it a little bit to the left,
there we go and we'll do the same
with our difficulty slider.
Just change the scale from 5 down to 4.
Now I'm going to change up the color,
I'm going to click on the Volume slider,
just put it in the middle so
I can see what happens on my
left into the right of the star.
Let's have a look at the background here.
If I change the background
to be say a red.
That kind of says I'm not here yet,
that's okay.
I can make it a darkish red.
And then we'll see if we
can find the fill area.
Click on fill underneath fill area.
The color here will make
the same color as the text.
So this bluish kind of color.
Okay, so that way, as we're sliding,
click on Volume Slider,
as we're sliding it's kinda going
from I'm filled up with blue,
versus I'm not filled up with that last
little bit of the red there, okay,
to give a visual indication to the player.
And then Difficulty, yeah,
we'll do the same for Difficulty, as well.
So let me go and Find my Background here,
click on the red, highlight
the hexadecimal code and then go over
into the difficulty slider background,
click on the color,
paste in the hexadecimal.
Now we want to slide our
slider along a little bit so
we can see that it's working.
Click on the Fill for
the fill area for the other one,
for the Volume slider, copy that.
And then to paste that into
the Fill underneath Fill Area for
the Difficulty slider.
I know that's a lot of bouncing around.
Okay, Save that up, now we need to get
the functionality for the Back button.
We won't have Defaults just yet,
but for the Back button.
Okay, let's just check, yes,
we have Level Loader in the screen.
We will now go and
click on the Back Button which already had
functionality I think of the Quick Button.
Yes it did.
So I'll change the Quick Button to
be LevelLoader LoadMainMenu, okay.
And then Default, we don't want Default
to accidentally break the game, so
for now I'm going to give it No Function,
just to say that when you click on that,
nothing happens.
So let's save this up,
go back into our Start menu,
Start Scene, [SOUND],
Start Screen, there it is.
And we need to add an extra button
within here, which is Options.
So open up our Canvas.
Click on start game which is not
start text but start button.
I'm gonna change this while I'm here,
start button, and it's not quick text but
it is quick button.
How about naming button up,
Ben would be very proud,
he's very into having things named.
Exactly the way it should be.
So thank you to Ben for
instilling that in us.
Click on Start Button, duplicate,
drag that down a little bit.
Instead of Start Game, we are going
to call this the Options Button.
And then in the text we have Options.
Okay, start game, options and quit.
Our three things in there,
let's scroll down.
Now we haven't added this to our
build index so file, build settings,
let's find our options screen.
I'm going to put that, let's see,
we wanna go straight from splash screen
to start screen, start screen to level one
it's kind of the flow that we're doing.
So put this as the second to last,
at some point we'll have a,
you win the entire game screen,
which would be after all of our levels.
But at the moment we'll put our
options screen just there for me.
It's build index four Close that up, we
need to give ourselves some functionality,
so open up your level loader script.
I don't think we've got that at
the moment, start screen, lose screen,
no we don't.
So I'm gonna highlight my LoadMainMenu,
copy that.
So I'm in LevelLoader,
I found LoadMainMenu method,
and I'm hollowing that,
copying pasting underneath it,
and we're going to create
ourselves a new public method,
public void LoadOptionsScreen
we'll call this.
And timeScale nope, we don't want
to be messing around with that
SceneManager.LoadScene, back over into
Unity to make sure we copy it exactly.
We've called Options Screen, so
I'll highlight that, copy that,
back over into our script,
paste that as our string reference.
[SOUND] We don't like string references,
but
sometimes we use them
because we need to use them.
LoadOptionsScreen, now we can
go into the Options Button.
Click on the Options Button,
scroll all the way down the bottom.
Instead of LoadNextScene, we're gonna
change that to be LevelLoader and
LoadOptionsScreen.
Great, Save, click on Play,
check that it all works.
Click on options takes us
into our options screen.
We can twiddle our sliders.
Well, that actually doesn't look too bad,
does it?
And clicking Defaults does nothing yet,
click on Back, Back into the start screen.
Back boom boom,
just check Start Game works.
So it does, excellent,
mission accomplished, success, great work.
In our next video we'll start
hooking up some functionality
in our Options screen so
we can get it doing some cool stuff.
Okay, great work and
I'll see you in the next video.