[MUSIC]
Hello again, in this video,
we're gonna set ourselves up
a background that looks pretty.
Some trees that have some layering and
some depth.
And this is my little placeholder
game character, by the way.
And our world coordinate system, so
that we know that each of our
squares equals one game unit.
So we can say that if something
is positioned at 7, 4,
we know exactly which particular square it
would be in, versus if it's at, say, 1, 1.
So let's jump in and get all this set up.
Okay so we're comfortable with our
game now, we've got our safe zone.
We know that when we have
a look at this in 4:3,
that it doesn't chop off any of our core
gameplay grid, which is all excellent.
And we know that our squares,
if we have nine of them in the play area,
then they're gonna be 160
by 160 in terms of pixels.
What we wanna do now is
convert our canvas so
that we have it relating to
our play space and world unit.
So that you can see all the way down here,
this is where our camera is at the moment.
This is where our camera's saying, I think
the game should be down here with our
units running around and
our towers and stuff.
And the canvas is independent,
the canvas is just saying, well,
whatever the game does
doesn't matter to me.
I'm just gonna slap myself right
over the top of the screen.
And if the screen is 16 by 9,
this is what I'll look like.
But we want to be using our
background as our play space,
so that we can see the background.
We've put our background into UI, so
we're doing it a different way so
you can see how this works.
We haven't put our background into
the play space, we haven't gone and
put our background right
behind the camera.
We've put our background in the UI,
just as a different way of doing it.
Okay, so what do we need to do?
Well, first of all, we need to have
a look at our render mode for canvas.
We're using screen space overlay,
which is what we normally do,
we need to change that.
Now, we haven't done much of this, but
if you click on the little book next to
the canvas here, you can see the little
books all over the place, that takes
you to the Unity help documentation.
And when we're in here,
we can see the options we have for canvas.
We have screen space overlay,
screen space camera, and world space.
Theses correspond to, in here, screen
space overlay, camera, and world space.
Now, what is the different
between each of these?
We'll just very quickly, when we're in
screen space overlay, anything that we
have in our UI, on our canvas,
will just sit over the top of the game.
If we're in screen space camera,
anything that we have will
fit within our view based upon
the distance from the camera.
So if we say our UI is way a long distance
from the camera, but our game elements
are really close to the camera,
then they will render on top of that UI.
That's you can create a really
cool effect there, if you say,
I want stuff like UI elements,
buttons and all these cool kinda things,
behind what's showing on the front.
What we're gonna use is world space,
cuz we want our world,
we want our background,
which is currently on our canvas.
You see, we've got our background which
is on our canvas, which is a UI element.
We want to have it appear
like it's in the world, so
our characters are jumping on top of it.
We can have elements in our user
interface, which is in front,
elements which are behind.
And we wanna have that closer relationship
between, if something's moving three units
from left to right, then it looks like
it's three units on the background, and
it's actually three units in the world.
So the first step is,
change your render mode to world space.
Nothing happens straight away, but
there's a bunch of stuff we can now do.
So it's still 1920 by 1080,
it's rounded in a bit of a wacky way, but
that's 1080, trust me, 1920 by 1080.
And we're in world space, so
what do we need to do next?
Well, what I'm gonna do next, because I'm
happy with the size of my background,
my play space, and
I'm happy with the number of squares.
I don't need to go and prototype the game
because I've already prototyped it.
But we take you through that journey on
our Unity RPG course where we actually go
through, prototype things in
the order we would do it.
Make the mistakes, changes,
iterate on it, and
do that kind of genuine
game developer journey.
But for now, I'm gonna say, well, I know
for a fact that nine by five is good.
So I've given you some assets against
this lecture called Background Art.
So if you wanna download that and unzip
that, open up your background art folder,
and there's three things in there.
There's a background which has been
created for us by an awesome guy, Chris.
Thank you Chris,
over at 2D Game Art for Programmers.
So Chris, he gets where you're coming
from, he's got a whole bunch of tutorials
and great things that you can go through,
blog stuff that you can read.
Just a good guy, he's living in Australia,
which means he's a double good guy,
if you know what I mean.
And thanks to him, he's tightened
up the background for us and
made it look a little bit nicer
than I had previously, and
we had in the previous
version of this project.
So grab that, drag it into images, also,
he's given us a couple of trees,
drag those over in.
And if you wanna know more about how
to create your own art elements for
your own game, then I've given you
a link to Chris's website as well,
you can have a look at.
So we've got our background here,
excellente,
we need to connect that up to our
background in our scene, in our hierarchy.
So I'm gonna click on source image, change
that to bg_glitchGarden, also change
the color back to normal, so over to
white, so it's not being changed at all.
I'm pretty confident that I can get
rid of my safe zone indicator here,
so I'll find my safe zone and
just neutralize that.
Okay, you can see it's all lining up
nicely when we've turned it off, but
we've still selected it,
you can see the outline of it...
That's great, and you can see that
my squares, how are they doing,
they're pretty close, I was just playing
around with the position of these.
But my squares, if I was to drag them up,
then it would be looking pretty good.
If I had one more square down there,
let's just do that for completeness.
Okay, that's looking pretty good,
and they're gonna line up.
So the way you would do this if you
were working on your own art, or
with an asset provider, is you'd make
your game, and you're like, okay,
this all looks pretty good.
I know this is rough and ready,
just moving around squares.
You can do this as your own grid
that you made in Photoshop, or
something, you don't have to do
it with little Unity squares.
So you make it up and then you say,
yep, this is feeling pretty good.
Hey artists, can you please create
something that looks pretty and
make sure that you get the grid exactly
as I have the grid when I give you
a screenshot for it?
Make sure your dimensions
are 1920 by 1080,
then your artist knows exactly what to do.
So I'm just gonna get rid of my squares,
[SOUND] they're gone.
We have our prettier looking background,
thank you Chris.
And we have our couple of trees,
which I'll get to in a moment.
So now we need to align our
UI background with our game and
our game camera, so how do we do that?
Well, couple of slides for you here,
what I want to do is say one
grass square is one world unit.
What I mean by that is, this square here,
if something moves from here to there,
that's one unit, and that's another unit.
So one, two, three, four,
five units, so to speak.
So I know if I'm placing a tower down
just here, that's going to be at 1, 1.
If I'm placing a tower here, that's gonna
be at one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, at 9, 1, if I was
going to place something down there.
Okay, so how do we do that?
One grass unit, one world unit, so
one grass square equals one world unit.
Our canvas width is currently 1920 pixels,
if you remember.
Click on our canvas,
it is 1920 that we've put in there.
We know it is pixels, but Unity currently
is thinking that's 1920 world units.
So you can see there's not
anywhere in here that says pixels.
It just thinks, I'm 1920 world units, but
we need to shrink this whole thing down so
it fits within here, how do we do that?
Well, we know our squares are 160 by 160,
remember,
we did that in the previous video,
160 by 160 for our squares.
And we know the number of
squares therefore is 12,
so 1920 divided by 160.
So if we have 1920 along here,
and each of these is 160,
then from the left side to the right side,
we're gonna have 12 squares.
Or, otherwise, we're saying we want
12 world units as our width, okay,
does that make sense?
So from here, if we start all the way
there, 1, 2, 3, 4, [SOUND] 12,
would take us to here,
we'd have 12 units from left to right.
So we need to scale or
shrink our canvas by 12,
is how many we want it to be, by 1920.
And that equals,
we need to multiply our canvas
by 0.00625, and that will shrink it.
Okay, so
that's the information I've got for you.
I was gonna go through this and do the
whole thing, but I think you need a little
bit of a challenge to make sure you're
not just sitting there idly watching me.
So I'm gonna give you a challenge now,
and that challenge is to scale and move.
Scale your canvas so
that one world unit equals one square,
a reminder, 0.00625.
If you don't want to just use that number,
you can calculate it
all yourself to make sure you
understand yourself how it's working.
And also resize and align you camera.
In previous sections of the course, we've
talked about how big your camera is, and
how to know the size of it.
So you might need to put back
on your remembering cap and
have a think at camera discussions.
And to add the trees that I gave you, so
they're in front of the grass background.
And so that anything that was gonna
run along the grass will be going
behind the trees.
So it'll go trees and
then world elements and then background.
And there's a bunch of ways to do that.
I'm gonna show you a really quick and
simple way to do it.
I'm not gonna go very
complex in how we do that.
So there's your challenge,
jump in, take that on, and
I'll see you back here in a moment.
Okay, let's start by doing our scaling,
so if I remember, [SOUND] 0.00625.
Okay, so we find our whole canvas,
we've changed to world space.
We want it to be 0.00625, gonna copy that,
and put that into y as well,
why, just because.
And then put it into, [LAUGH] Rick,
and then z, we don't need any scaling.
Just gonna leave it at zero cuz it's flat,
it's a 2D image.
You can see now, our canvas is way off
over there cuz it thinks it needs to be at
position 499 world units.
And our camera, if you can see it
on my screen, is way down there.
So let's, for now, reset our
position to 0, 0 for our background.
You can see now they line up, double click
on the canvas, we zoom all the way in.
Excellent, so
you can see the middle of our canvas is
now right in the middle of our screen.
And our camera is also right in the middle
of our screen at the 0, 0 origin point.
Now what I wanna do is have the camera
match nicely to my background.
And also, have it that my first point, so
the first point of my actual play space,
this is 1, 1 down here,
let's do that one first.
So if I click on canvas,
we're gonna just move it for now,
just drag it up to the right.
You can see where the camera is, that's
showing us where our origin point is,
our 0, 0.
So our 0, 0 is going to be down to
the left of wherever our 1, 1 is.
Cuz remember, if we were go one to the
right and one up, that's going to be 1,
1 from our 0, 0 that's down here.
And you can see that's pretty
much 5 on the x position and
pretty much 3 on the y position.
Okay, the way that we can test
this is by throwing into our scene
just a sprite that we can move around.
So right-click, 2D object, sprite, we
need to give it some sort of imagery, so
I'm gonna click on my select.
I've just got default things
hanging around my scene.
If you don't have these default things,
then you might need to just grab
from somewhere on your directory, or
on the Internet, or somewhere,
just grab a small image.
I'd recommend not using our big old
background images or the trees, but
just grab something online.
If you've got something that is knob or
UI sprite, you can use those.
I'm just gonna click on knob,
which I think is a default built-in
thing that comes with Unity,
so you should have it.
Don't worry if you don't,
you don't have to do this step,
I'm just showing you for
illustrative purposes.
Move it to the side,
you can see when I've got it over the top,
it goes underneath the background,
we'll get to that in a moment.
But for now, actually we'll get
to that right now, shall we?
I was saying about having your elements
be on top of the grass background,
but in front of the trees.
The quickest way to do that is to find
the order in layer and have it greater.
So whatever is the smallest
will be at the back, and
whatever is highest will be at the front.
So if I was to change this and
make it, say, 5, and
then when I move it in front of my canvas,
it will be in front,
cuz the canvas is sitting at 0, sorry,
the background is sitting at 0.
So let's double check on that, click on
background, it is actually the canvas,
sorry, my bad, the canvas is sitting at 0.
So order in layer,
if I was to make this 10,
now it's gonna be back over top of
our little sprite that's in there.
So put it back to 0, okay,
okay, back on to my sprite.
If I have it right down here at the 0,
0 origin ,then I move it to the 1, 1,
I'll just type it in here 1, 1,
we can see it's in the 1,1 spot, great.
If I move it to say, 5, 5,
it'll be at the top, okay,
that's feeling really good,
it's feeling right in the middle.
So we've got ourselves a coordinate
system, which is excellent.
The last thing that we need to do is
make sure the camera is matching up, and
doing what it needs to do.
Let's find our camera, main camera,
I'm gonna call this game camera,
game camera, excellent,
now, how do we move this?
If you remember, our camera,
you can see it's currently 5.
That means it is 5 from the middle of
the camera to the top of the camera, so
it's showing us half
the height of the camera.
I'm gonna move this loosely into
the middle of where we want it to be.
If I was to move it exactly
into the middle, then I'd
be saying the same thing I did before
with my background, I'd say 5 and 3.
Now that should be right in the middle,
we want to shrink the camera, so
to do that,
we need to change the size of it.
What is size of our top to bottom,
so I'm gonna grab my calculator.
Okay, what do we know here,
well, that's on my other screen.
Well, what we know is that our
canvas originally was 1080,
or our image background is 1080,
we know these squares are 160.
So if we know that, 1080, height,
each square, so I'm gonna divide by 160,
since each square's 160,
that means we'll have 6.75 squares.
Which is cool, we want these five to be
intact, and there's a little bit less
than one on each side, which is great,
that's enough room to have our UI element.
So if it's 6.75 squares that would
fit along there, then our camera
needs to be half of 6.75, cuz we now know,
one square is one world unit.
So we find our camera,
and for main camera,
we say, half of 6.75 is going to be,
divided by 2, is going to be 3.375.
So 3.375, and hey, presto,
it fits exactly over the top of our
background, which is super excellent.
Okay, now the last thing I was challenging
you to do was to put in a couple of trees,
where's my little sprite in here?
We'll make sure that it can help
us see whether we're on top of,
I'm just gonna scale that up so
you can see it nice and clearly.
Apologies if you couldn't see it before.
Here it is, here's our little character,
[SOUND] coming to attack us.
Now we'll grab our trees, we're gonna
put it within the canvas as well.
So I'm gonna grab treeLeft, [SOUND] drag,
and I will put that into the canvas,
treeRight, [SOUND] put it
into the canvas as well.
Click on treeLeft, move it to around here.
Now you can see that you can't see it,
it's behind.
My challenge was to have this
over the top of the background.
So order in layer, I've made my
characters that are running along 5,
so I can make my tree 10.
Then when I push it over the top here,
it's over the top of that, and
it's over the top of the characters.
So I'm gonna scale up a little bit, I can
do that by clicking on the scale tool.
Find the scale tool, and
then just going [SOUND] drag it.
We don't need to have it perfect,
we don't need to exactly know
the coordinates and stuff.
Okay, that's way too big and way in the
way, cuz I don't want it going over where
I'm gonna be placing my defenders,
it's a bit too intrusive there.
Put it back down a little bit,
probably back to exactly where it was,
I'm just gonna undo.
Maybe I don't need to scale it at all,
one of those things that live and learn.
Okay, a little bit off the screen,
there we go, I think that's not too bad.
Right tree, place it over there as well,
[SOUND] and change it to order of 10.
Okay, there we have it, so
maybe down there a little bit,
now I've got a little bit of trees.
So that when we have our
pretend guy come in,
they're gonna come from
underneath the trees.
A little bit of depth, which makes
your game feel more interesting.
You can have a couple of things in front,
if you wanted.
This depth, I think's really neat,
and then off it goes underneath.
If we're doing this at
our 4-3 aspect ration,
we'll still see a little bit of
trees dangling onto the screen.
Might not make full sense if someone's
playing on their iPad and doesn't
quite know what's going on, so you might
need to give them a little bit more tree.
This area's pretty safe,
we can't place things up here.
In my game, I'm gonna say,
you can't place in these front two, so
you can probably even move the tree,
or if you wanted to scale it,
you can scale it and
move it in a little bit closer.
But I'll let you finesse with that,
the main thing is that our sprite is going
underneath them, and that it looks
okay on our different resolutions.
Go to the game 4:3 it works, 3:2, works,
16:10 it works, and 16:9, okay, fantastic.
Last thing I'll point out before I
jump off is, if you wanna get more
sophistication, then in terms of the
layering, and I've done it pretty crudely.
It's all just on the default layer and
within the default layer,
we have got our levels, so
I've got order in the layer.
You could go and
create a new sorting layer,
you could call one trees,
you could call another one background,
you could call another one gameplay
elements, if you wanted to.
If you have a lot of stuff,
that's a good way to do it.
If you just have a few different layers,
then I think this is fine,
putting the order in layer.
Okay, well done, great work, we've got
a game that's starting to look like it's
ready to have a game take place inside it.
Weve messed around with our units,
lots of talking about aspect ratios and
camera positioning and world units.
So thanks for bearing with me on that,
sometimes the setup is a little bit dry.
But we're ready to get into the next
part of making our game, so
see you in the next video.