[MUSIC]
I'm sure you've heard the famous saying,
tidy hierarchy, tidy mind.
Well, if we look at our hierarchy when
we start to place down defenders,
it becomes very untidy, very messy.
You can see all these gnomes and
axes, all sorts of stuff going on,
which makes it difficult if we need to
go and figure something out mid-game,
pause it and find what's going on.
Just much better to have it tidy,
particularly when you start making
massive projects, which I know you will.
So I'm going to jump over into
my defender spawner script.
And up at the very top,
gonna create a game object, gameObject,
that will be called defenderParent.
Now I need to put back in my start method.
So start.
What do I wanna have happen on start?
Well, I wanna call a method that
will take care of creating the defender
child parent relationship.
So I'll call this CreateDefenderParent.
And parentheses, semicolon.
Right-click, quick actions and refactors,
to create that as a method just below it.
And what will be in here?
Well, first step, I'm going to define my
defenderParent object as GameObject.find.
So I want to find something.
What am I finding?
Well, I'm finding defenders.
Now, string references we don't like.
They're messy, they're dangerous.
Did I even spell it correctly?
I did on this occasion, yay for me.
What's a better way to do this?
Well, we've just been
learning about constant.
So at the top of our script let's add
ourselves a const, which will be a string.
And we'll use capitals to
show that it's a const,
DEFENDER_PARENT_NAME, and
that will equal what?
It will equal Defenders.
So then we've added our string
reference just once, and
then in the future we will have this nice
little hook that we can access when we're
typing in our autocomplete.
So down here, what are we looking for?
Find, in parenthesis,
I'm finding Defender,
and you can see it's got
DEFENDER_PARENT_NAME.
So it's exactly the same, I could put
my string reference down in there, or
I could just do it once and define it.
Now what if Defender, so this Defenders
game object, what if it doesn't exist?
What if there's no such thing in here or
what if it's called something different?
Then we don't wanna be having all
sorts of errors and exceptions.
So let's say, so if (!defenderParent), so
if the defenderParent doesn't exist, if
there is none, then what do we wanna do?
We want to have defenderParent be defined
as, so defenderParent equals new,
creating a new, GameObject,
and then DEFENDER_PARENT_NAME.
See how nice that was
to have auto completed?
Okay, let's save that up,
and, down the bottom,
we actually need to use
this one we instantiated.
So down the very bottom,
I've got SpawnDefender.
And we're creating a new defender, so
I will write newDefender.transform.parent
is going to be equal to what?
It's going to be equal to
defenderParent.transform;.
So that means that it's instantiated
as a child to our defenderParent.
Save that up, make sure it works,
click on Play.
When I drop down my gnomes, get down
some gnomes, [SOUND] You can see that
they are created within our, now pause,
cuz we've still got out projectiles there.
In our Defenders,
you can see all of my gnomes, and
within our defender
gameObjects which is awesome.
Okay, and because we do have
all those messy projectiles,
we need to take care of those and
that's going to be the challenge for you.
So do the same with projectiles,
have our projectiles parented
to a projectile game object.
Take that on, and
I'll see you back on when you're done.
Okay, where do we find this?
What's the script we're looking in?
Well, I'm going to jump in here.
It's gonna be one of two, it's either
gonna be Projectile or Shooter.
I'm gonna have a little bit of quick
glance at it, which of these, okay,
I'm instantiating on fire,
so I know that it's shooter.
Open that up, same process,
up at the top I'm gonna create
myself a game object which I
will call projectileParent.
Within start we're gonna call
the method weren't created yet
which will be CreateProjectileParent.
Right-click, Quick actions and Refactors,
generate that method just down below here.
What do we need to do?
Well, projectileParent is going
to be equal GameObject.Find.
What are we finding?
Well, we haven't created
our const just yet.
So, let's do that at the top.
Const string, and
this will be PROJECTILE PARENT,
oops, _NAME.
That's gonna be equal to or
assigned as Projectiles.
Semicolon, okay, so
now what are we finding?
We're finding PROJECTILE_PARENT_NAME,
excellent.
Same as before, if there is none,
so if parentheses
exclamation mark, there's no projectile
parent, then what do we wanna do?
Well, we better go ahead and create one.
ProjectileParent = new GameObject,
in parentheses PROJECT_PARENT_NAME.
And you know what?
I didn't do this deliberately,
but I've gone and
made a mistake that I'll show
you how awesome this is.
I've named it PROJECT_PARENT_NAME,
that makes absolutely no sense,
what was I thinking?
So double-click on that.
Control RR, I can see there's three
instances and I can go in here and
say PROJECTILE_PARENT_NAME.
Apply, there we go, and
we've easily renamed that.
Thank you for
having that as a const worked out nicely.
And the of course we scroll all
the way down to the bottom and
we find where we are instantiating and
we need to add an extra bit in here.
Well, first of all, we're only
instantiating this as an object.
We need to instantiate as a game object.
So what I mean by that, in front
of instantiate we type GameObject,
and then we give it a new name.
So newProjectile = it's going to be a big
line, but we'll put it on multiple lines,
=, gonna give this a new line,
Instantiate(projectile,
and the position and
the rotation, and as GameObject.
Why do we do that?
Well, that's we're casting it,
that's what this is called,
and we say as game object we
need this as a game object so
that we can place it within our
hierarchy and we can manipulate it.
When we instantiate not as a GameObject,
it's instantiated just as an object.
And you can see here,
UnityEngine.Object.Instantiate, and
we don't have as much control over it.
A GameObject allows us to do things that
if it's just an object, we can't do.
Okay, it's a very simple explanation but
basically,
we're casting it as a GameObject, so
that we can now do more stuff with it,
which is going to say newProjectile.
NewProjectile, if I can spell
it correctly .transform.parent
is going to be =
projectileParent.transform.
Save that, let's see how we go.
Back over into Unity, click on Play.
Drop down some cacti to make sure it's
not just the gnomes that it works with.
[SOUND] Okay,
they're shooting a bunch of stuff.
We're gonna have explosions that come and
go cuz they're being destroyed when
they have done their business.
And if we look,
there's a Projectiles game object and
we've got some projectiles
that are within that.
Excellent so that's mission accomplished.
Tidied up the hierarchy.
It might seem like a small minor thing but
it's really important to
get into these habits.
So that you can impress your colleagues
when you're out there working in
the game industry with,
look how neat and tidy my hierarchy is.
That's one reason of many.
So great work, and
I'll see you in the next lecture.