[MUSIC]
Welcome, in this video, we're gonna be
creating some animation for our character.
Just an initial idle animation,
setting up our animator controller,
creating a player.
And adding the components to the player,
so that we can visualize
this on the screen.
First of all I'm gonna do
a little bit of tidy up.
I've clicked on my eraser
in tile palate here.
And I'm going to just tidy up
the platforms when I was messing around
with my rule tiles.
In terms of the palate over here
we're calling it manual tiles.
I'm just gonna update the name
of that to be main palate.
Given that we'll probably
only have one and
you can see it updates
there on the palette, cool.
Now, the first step in getting our
character animate, we need a player.
So, right click,
create empty over in our hierarchy,
I'm going to rename this player.
It's always exciting when you put the
player into your game for the first time.
There's nothing there yet, but
we now officially have a player.
Right click Reset, transform as we do.
Okay, so we've got our player,
you'll also need for this video, for
this lecture, your Animator window.
So go to Window and find Animator,
I've placed mine down the bottom here,
I'm just gonna give it
a little bit of resizing.
Not gonna be doing Tile Palette stuff so
we could probably close that.
But for now I'm going to, I'm gonna
drag this down next to the Animator,
just out of the way.
So we go to our Animator
here in our scene.
Okay, so now that we have our player,
we need to add a few components.
And I want to explain a little bit of
the terminology we'll be using in this
lecture, if you're not
familiar with animation and
not familiar with 2D animation
in particular, in Unity.
So here's some terminology.
We have the Animator Component
we'll be adding to the player.
This assigns animations to the game
object through an Animator Controller.
The Animator Controller is an arrangement
of animations and transitions and
we can think of this as a state machine.
And then we have our Animation files.
Our animation assets,
which are specific pieces of motion.
And then, we have the Sprite Renderer that
we will need to add to our player and
anything that we want to display
on the screen as a 2D sprite.
I have an early challenge for you,
particularly if you've been
through this process before.
Here's the challenge,
to set up your character's idle.
So, if you've done this process before,
maybe in one of our other Unity courses.
Might be a good chance to flex your
muscles and dig back in to the memory
bank, to see if you can remember how
to go about setting up this process.
I've created assets for
you, so I've given you a spritesheet
against this lecture of a character.
So grab the spritesheet, slice them up,
add the sprite renderer to the player,
create an idle animation clip Create
the Character Animator Controller.
Add the idle animation to the Animator
Controller and add Animator to Player.
Finally assign
Character Animator Controller to Player.
So if you're looking at that and
none of that makes sense no problem,
we're about to go through
that in this lecture.
Just wanted to give those of you who
are familiar with this already a chance to
jump in and flex your muscles and
to get that done.
So, let's do this together now.
First step in here, I am going to
add my components to the player.
We'll add an animator component.
Animator, there we go in there.
At the moment, you can see
the controller there is none and
we want to create ourselves
an animator controller.
I'm going to actually jump over in
my assets and make a new folder.
Give myself a little bit more space
over here so I can see it all.
A new folder I will call animations.
And I'll put all thing
animations in there.
Animations, the first, though,
is if we click into there,
we will right-click and
create an animator controller.
We'll call that animator
controller Player.
And then you can see,
in our animator window, which is
displaying our animator controller.
That we have a couple of states in here.
So, we'll drag exit over here.
These are states and basically,
a state is a condition that the player
will be in at any point in time.
They can only be in one state and
we tell the player
that we want them to be in this state, or
in a different state by using transitions.
So, that'll become clear in just a moment.
The next step is we need
to grab our spritesheet.
I've given that to you
against this lecture.
And I have created two variations.
The default is the character sheet
that came with the asset pack itself.
And then I've gone and
recolored it a little bit to
make it a little bit different.
And I'm gonna use these
sbplayer_ginger for my character.
So I drag that into my sprites folder,
so we now have player in there.
As we've done before we're gonna
slice that up, click on multiple,
convert it to 32 pixels per unit,
hit apply.
Jump into the Sprite Editor and click on
Slice, jump over to Grid by Cell Size,
same as before, 32 by 32,
a padding of six.
Not sure about the offset yet,
let's slice this and see how it looks.
That looks like, my goal here is to have
the player's feet right at the bottom
of the Sprite selection area.
So, that all looks pretty good.
The feet are at the bottom,
good and nice and consistent.
You can see when we zoom in here,
there is a few different assets that the
asset pack creator has provided for us.
We're gonna be focused mostly on
the idle and the run, and the climb.
We'll slice all of these up for
now, click Apply, okay.
Jump back over into our sprite sheet.
And I'm going to find the idle animation
that we're doing in this video.
So, we can see a little
preview of it over there.
If I scroll through, this looks like
the idle from five through to eight,
five through to eight is our idle, okay.
So I'm going to highlight five,
six, seven, eight.
Five six seven eight for
our four frames of idol, and
right click, create, animation.
Now we use those four frames
to create an animation,
we will call this animation Idol.
We now have an idle animation.
We'll drag that idle animation
into our animations folder, so
it's sitting in there.
And then from the animation folder,
I'm going to drag this into
my animator controller.
And then we now have this idle state
that consists of the idle animation.
You can see the entry point into this
animation to the animated controller
goes immediately into idle.
So idle is going to be our
default state in most of this
state machine we've got in here.
Let's have a look at idle.
What's going on here?
We can see that we have
the idle animation.
See the speed is 1.
There's currently no transitions.
That's fine.
We don't need transitions yet.
But we do need a way to visualize this.
At the moment, it's just an orange box,
and that doesn't really help us much.
So back over to the player and
from the player we need to say
what is the animated controller.
Grab this player animated controller.
We've got a put in our animations
folder and assign that in there.
Or if you're not sure you can click
on this lectern, there's only one at
the moment so that makes it pretty
to know what we need to do.
So now we have animation on our player but
we can't actually see
the player in the scene.
What we need to do next is
have a way to see the player.
So I'm going to add a component,
add sprite renderer, the sprite
renderer allows us to see the player.
But there's no sprite on it yet.
So we need to give it a default sprite, so
we can visualize something
in our scene view here.
What I'll do there is click on Select.
And just find any of these individual
sprites that represent our player.
So I'm just gonna choose this one here.
I think it's one of the idles.
And now have a visualization we will
drag the player off the slide now.
But it's hidden if we drag
it all the way over here.
Hey presto there's our
player in the scene but
we want the player in
front of the background.
So a micro challenge for you, sit up
your player so that your player fits
in front of the background but
behind the foreground.
So there is a quick micro-challenge,
see if you can do that now.
Okay, if you remember back to
when we set up our layers,
we have our sorting layers, edit layers.
Expand out sorting layers here,
we need to add a new one.
We'll call this player.
Player layer.
And we'll move the player layer in
between background and foreground and
then back, click on our player.
We need to assign our.
Sorting layer here into player.
Now the player is in front of the
background doing what it's supposed to do.
Let's see if we click
on play what happens.
Okay.
Nothing much the player looked like it was
starting to do some animation but stopped.
And you can see that our idle has
is locked on this blue bar here.
Now, there's gonna be a reason for
that, which is to do
the looping of our animation.
So our animation is played once very
quickly, but we're not seeing it again.
So if you click on the animation anim,
the .anim down here, file itself,
and then click on Loop Time.
Basically that means when
this animation is called or
being used,
just keep looping over and over.
Let's click play now and
see if that has solve our problem.
It has indeed.
I'll zoom in a little bit so
you can see there we go.
Just sitting on this bouncing,
bouncing which is very cool.
And of course we have
nothing else going on.
We can't move the character around.
We can't transition in and out but
this is the start of play and
the start of having our
animation state set up.
A reminder of the challenge end
of the steps in this process.
If I bounced around,
you weren't following.
Spritesheet, slice it up.
Add the sprite renderer to the Player so
you can see the sprite.
Create an idle animation clip.
Create the Character Animator Controller
so that we can tell the states, and
we can put in for now the idle state.
Add the idle animations to
the Animator Controller which will create
the idle state and then add the Animator
to the Player make sure you do that
with in the animator
component to the player.
And then assign the character animator
controller to the player component.
So those are the steps, hopefully
you've done well on that challenge.
Here we go, we've got our guy,
I affectionately called him Conan
the Librarian, ready to roll.
In upcoming videos,
we're gonna make him move around,
do a whole bunch more, transitions and
animations and excellent cool stuff.
Well done in this video and
I'll see you in an upcoming video.