[MUSIC]
In this video, we're gonna create
the two extra states of running and
climbing to go along
with our idling state.
And I'll introduce you to transitions.
We'll make some parameters so that we
can transition from one state to another
simply by clicking the checkbox here to
show now my character is climbing, and
now my character is running.
Let's jump in and get started.
Okay, let's navigate our way to
the sprite sheet for the character.
We can see it there.
We've got a bunch of
sprites to choose from.
What we're going to start off
with is running, I think.
So we're gonna scroll down and
look for the running.
I'm just gonna go and
open up the sprite sheet itself so
I can see where that goes from.
If I look in there, it's this bottom
one here that's the run animation.
So it'd be the very last frame
starting from 19 and going until 28.
So that's gonna be our run.
Don't worry about doing that.
Okay, so let's go find 19 in our
sprite sheet here, 15, 16, 17, 18, 19.
As we did before, we're gonna
highlight everything all the way down
to the final one down here,
right-click, Create &gt; Animation.
We'll call this Running, wonderful.
Now from here, we can, as we did before,
drag that into our Animator,
Animator Controller.
We have this state of Running that at the
moment consists of our running animation
and not much else.
While we're here, let's click on
Running and make sure we loop that and
drag Running into the Animations folder.
So now we have Running and Idle.
As a piece of consistency,
I'm gonna rename Idle to Idling.
It's not really a word, but
I wanna have my states very clearly be the
thing that you are doing at the moment.
You're running at the moment,
you're climbing at the moment,
you're idling at the moment.
So that's super duper clear on that.
Okay, now we have our Running state.
We need to make a transition
from Idling to Running so
that we can say what needs to happen for
the player to stop being in an idling
state and start being in a running state.
To make a transition, right-click on
the state, click on Make Transition and
then you'll have this arrow
that you can point elsewhere.
We'll point over the Running and
left-click on there.
So now I have a state transition
leading into Running.
If you click on the arrow itself or
the line itself, let me show you
what's going on with that transition.
There's a couple of things
in here to have a look at.
First of all,
we've got a little bit of blending that
Unity is trying to do from
one state to another.
Now that ends up looking a little
bit crumby because we've got nice,
clean 2D animation here.
We don't need it to blend as
we might do with 3D animation.
So I'm going to open up Settings and
just turn Exit Time to 0 and
the Fixed Duration to 0 as well.
Now there won't be any of that
blending that needs to take place.
So we can probably just do
the transition duration if we wanna be
a little bit quicker about it.
So we've put that to 0.
Now we have this movement into Running.
We need to say what condition is going to
be met for this trigger to take place.
So in our Animator window,
make sure Parameters is clicked.
We're gonna click the + icon just here,
and we've got a choice of Float, Int,
Bool, and Trigger.
For now we're going to set up a Bool,
and this Bool we will call Running.
We come back over onto our Conditions.
Make sure you have your transition
selected here, click +.
And the only condition we've
got at the moment is Running.
That's the only one
we've set up over here.
And Running is true.
So basically, it's saying when
the Bool of Running is true,
then we transition into
the state of Running.
That's pretty straightforward.
If we click on Running, right-click,
Make Transition,
we can transition back to Idling.
And a micro challenge for you.
What's the condition where we will
transition from Running back to Idling?
That would be + Running is false,
of course.
Same as before,
I'm gonna make the Transition Duration 0
just to make sure we don't
have any of that overlap here.
I'll put this to 0 as well, okay, just so
it's nice and clear this is gonna happen.
I just click straight into that
other state without any blend.
Okay, so now we've got that flow going on.
This is all hooked up to the player still
cuz the player has the Animator Controller
in here called Player, so
it knows this straight away.
If we click on Play, you should see
the player sitting there idling.
I'll just go back to my Scene view so
I can get in nice and close.
The player's sitting there idling.
If we click on this, this is to simulate
if we were to call it in code and
say, turn the Bool to true.
Now the player's running,
run, run, run, run, run.
And then if we click on it to simulate,
now code's saying turn the Bool to false,
then back to animation again.
So we've got this nice flow from
state to state, very excellent.
Now the next state we're going to set
up is going to be the climb ladder.
That's the other main state
we'll have in our game.
Let's just go have a look at our sprite
sheet to see which one that would be.
Climb ladder is pretty much
just gonna be these two here.
So 14 and 15,
I've got those in my sprites here.
So what I want you to do as
a challenge is to implement climb and
run animation states,
create the transitions from idle, and
create the triggers for
each of the states.
So go ahead and do that for
climb and run, and
I'll see you back here
when you've got that done.
Okay, so it was 14 and 15, I believe.
Let's find those.
There's 14 and 15 [SOUND] excellent,
looks like a wonderful ladder climbing.
Right-click, Create &gt; Animation,
if I can find it, there it is, Animation.
This will be Climbing animation.
Drag that into our state machine in here.
From Idling, right-click,
Make Transition into Climbing.
And I'll do the other one straight away,
Make Transition back to Idling.
Click on this first one and
just tidy up little of this.
You don't have to tidy up the blending,
but as I've mentioned,
I like to do this, dot dot dah, wonderful.
Click on the + button and create
another Bool, which will be Climbing.
Climbing is our parameter.
Then over on here,
our condition going from Idling to
Climbing should be Climbing is true.
And then if we click on
the other direction,
the condition of Climbing should be false.
And again, just tidy this up.
Okay, and you can see in here, we've got
something that's called Has Exit Time.
Basically, this is saying,
you've got a number of ways of
exiting this animation state.
One way is if you want
the animation to play.
And then as soon as
the animation finishes playing,
go back or transition back to the state.
Then you can use Exit Time.
So it said there's ten
frames of animation.
You do those ten frames.
If Has Exit Time is on,
after the ten frames,
it can return back to the other state.
So I wanna click Has Exit Time off cuz
what we're using here is the condition of
the Bool to say when
the transition takes place.
Have a look over here,
turn off Has Exit Time there, and
same with all these other ones,
just turning off Has Exit Time.
We only want that in a situation where we
definitely end after we play a particular
single shot animation.
Now let's click Play,
see if we've hooked all this up correctly.
The character should
be defaulting to Idle.
And you can see the Idle
clicking through here.
This is the state we're in.
It's playing through the frames.
We click on Running, yes, it runs.
And Climbing, no,
it's not climbing at the moment.
What have we done wrong here?
Let's have a look at our transitions.
We have Running is true.
You're probably yelling at the screen,
saying, Rick, you put in Running.
You should've put in Climbing.
There we go, we've found it.
Let's click Play here.
Thank you for yelling at the screen,
if you did yell at the screen
in that instance, Climbing, yep.
And it's stuck, which says that we
are not looping, if I am correct.
We haven't clicked on
looping time in there.
That stays in play mode,
which is all good.
Now that we've got it, our character
can run and our character can climb.
So these are all the states
that we need for now.
As our game gets more complex, we might
wish to add in rolling or shooting or
jumping.
But for now,
all we need functionality-wise is the
player can run and the player can climb.
And after we put all of that
gameplay functionality in,
we might revisit our states in here and
our animations and add more in.
But we don't want to overinvest in this
until we've got our core gameplay created
and we know how it all fits together and
how it looks.
So great work in this video, and
I'll see you in the next video.