Hello again.
I've created this as a special video to let you know that there's some challenging content coming in
the next couple of videos.
We find people for the next couple of years a little bit more challenging than we have been doing.
And that's because we're introducing some new concepts.
When you find new concepts it might not make sense just yet but I wouldn't want you to know is that
as you go through this course we go over those concepts over and over and over.
By the time you've finished the course it will all make sense and we'll all fit together even if the
first time you see something doesn't quite click in your mind.
So keep going and don't give up.
Make sure you watch all of the videos through there's often an answer to a question in the very next
video.
But if you have a question at the time throw them in the question section or on our forum and have a
look through the existing questions against this lecture because there's a very good chance someone's
asked it already and there's a really good answer from one of our teaching assistants or myself already
for that question and to get you prepared for the next couple of lectures.
I want to go through a couple of points to give you a little bit of theory in this lecture.
Just so you've got a little bit more knowledge before you get in there and we actually do it in the
code.
So I've got my little scribble a pencil here.
What I want to talk about first of all is just once again to remind you about variables and methods
so variable is a container.
It's like a box.
It's where we store things and you'll see in the next video we start talking about a variable which
is our starting state and also a variable which we just call state.
What state are we in it might be we're in the first part of our story the second part of our story where
at the end of our story.
So we're using the word state to say where are you in our story.
So at this point in time we might be defining the state as we'll call it B State B.
B might be you're standing in a corridor and it's very windy.
That's State B and we have all of the explanation we have all the the words story now scripted all objects
and any point in time we might say Well I it's no longer state B state now equals state C.
And by doing that we can update what state wearing because we just want to be in one state at a time
and when we stop we need to say what's the starting state so that our program knows where do we start
from.
So we would create a variable which we will call starting state and then at some point we're going to
say state equals starting state and that's a way of saying here is starting state that we're going to
define somewhere.
This is our very first thing very first thing we want to do we know what that is.
There it is right there.
And at some point we're going to say the state we're in now the variable that we're calling state that
we're keeping track of where we are right now.
It's going to equal standing state and what's dotting state well it's that thing we told it.
This is the starting state.
So I'll talk about this more detail in the next lecture but I just wanted to remind you about variables.
It's just a way of keeping track of what the value is at the moment or what the reference is at the
moment.
In other words what are we referring to.
So delete that.
And then the other main thing that we use a lot throughout all our scripts is a method or otherwise
known as a function.
Now I want to give you a quick analogy here so that you understand a little bit more a couple of concepts
to do with method.
So say we've got two people we've got one guy here very handsome we'll call him Rick for example and
another guy here not quite as handsome he's OK we'll call him on an Aubyn for example and we have a
situation where Rick is going to ask Ben to do something.
And in this instance we're using Rick to represent a method coal or a method that's got a list of actions
in it or code in it.
And Rick is going to say for example Ben please turn on the TV.
So our method might be called simply turn on TV or in the seas.
Now we have our curly braces and in there we have the action that it takes.
Maybe there's some code.
This is my commenting out my pseudo code in here.
It's something to do with how to go and switch on the TV.
So that's a method and I'm using that comparing it back to analogy in real life.
It's someone saying turn on the TV.
That's an action to do something for me please.
That's our method.
Now we have a concept as well.
We use a different color for this because it's important returning return so we can return a value.
What does that mean.
Well when we call the method.
So when Rick says Ben please turn on the TV.
That's the action.
Then we can return something so Ben can give something back to Rick.
So when we call our method in this case it's Rick saying Ben please turn on the TV.
You can ask for some information back from Ben and that's the return.
So he might say hey Ben turn on the TV and let me know what the football score is at the moment.
That's going to return something back to Rick.
So Rick's asking Ben turn on the TV and then Ben is returning back to Rick.
The score might be five to two.
And so our method.
Turn on TV can also have a structure for saying how do I give that back.
What sort of information do I want to get back what type of information do I want it to be an integer
like a five is an integer.
So I wanted to be a string.
For example a sentence.
So we have a way of asking back that's returning back and in the next couple of lectures we're going
to be asking a string to return because we want all of the words back.
We want our story to come back.
So when our method is saying do this particular thing.
And by the way give me back what the story should be.
That's the flow of information and then the final concept I'll give to you.
Now before we get into this and do these in the lectures just very quickly is the notion of public versus
private.
I talked about this a lot more in the next lecture.
The main thing to know here at the very high level is if something is a private method.
So it's all about methods here at the moment things a private method that only the things that are near
it or within the same script same class can call that method.
So using my reconvene example here if Ben and Rick are in the same room then if Rick calls a private
method then we'll hear it.
It's all cool.
However if Rick and Ben are in different rooms and Rick calls a private method then Ben won't hear it
or won't be out to do that.
I would need to make it a public method.
I need to be out to pick up a megaphone and yell it across the entire house so he can hear it from whatever
room he's in.
That's a real simplification of that analogy but it's a way of getting you thinking about the fact that
private can only be done in the same script or the same area of the code and public can be done across
all of our project anywhere in the project.
OK.
That's just a quick rundown of some of the concepts we're going to be covering in the next video.
We're going to go through them again I'm going to explain them again hopefully to hear them explain
two or three different ways.
It will really help you out to have it stick if it doesn't stick.
Don't worry about it.
It will make sense as things go along.
Just follow along as best you can ask questions and keep pushing through the course.
I'll see you the next video.