In this video we're going to be refactoring our code will be importing the previous number Wizards script
that we created in the number was a console section and doing a little bit of analysis of what we need
to change and then doing our first refactor of this code so it's ready to be used with our user interface.
So let's jump in and do some refactoring.
Okeydokey first thing we need to do is grab the previous code.
Our number is a code that we worked on from the no wizard console section of the Course.
If you don't have access to that then you can download the file that I've attached to this lecture number
was a dot C S drag that into your.
Scripts folder X or want a next thing to do is to create a game object so we can attach our script to
that game object right click in the hierarchy create empty we'll rename this to game play.
And as good practice we reset the transform.
Now we can drag our number was a script.
As a component on to our game play game object that means that when we run the game the script the script
will be run.
Let's open up number wizard and have a look and see refamiliarize ourselves with the old familiar Coale
code from a couple of sections ago.
Okay we've got some variables we're declaring up at the top here.
We created a stack game method where we're giving the player a whole bunch of here's how you play the
game information and then in our update method we've got our player input where we're using our if and
else if statements to see whether the player has pushed up or down or return and get key down was the
mechanism we're using in there for the players input.
Let's have a little look at what we need to do refactor what I'd like to do is serialise our variables
at the top so that we can change them in the inspector and not have them hard coded into our code here.
Need a removal of our debug information and then change the the player input.
So instead of using our get keyed down our keyboard input we need to create public methods similar to
that which we did in Scene lodo where we had public void load next scene so that we can create public
methods in here that we call from our button presses so those are the three main chunks serializing
removing the debug and changing the player input that we need to do.
And when I say we of course I mean you know what I'd like for you to do as a challenge is to start refactoring
your code serialise field for the minimax variables to remove the debug dialogue text that we don't
require.
And instead of IF statements in Update create two public methods and we'll call them on press higher
and on press lower.
So those are the steps.
The Challenge You should have everything you need to jump in and give that your best shot and when you're
ready I'll see you back here and we'll go through the solution together.
Radio first step is to serialize our variables so serialise field for Max and.
Serialise field for me.
I'll save that just check that that has worked.
Jim back over in here.
Click on game play.
After it compiles click on game.
That we go.
And you can see there is a max an image in here that we could set to say one thousand and one.
Next steps I'll just delete my debug text book.
Get rid of all that.
Anywhere we see debug just gone.
And also within the next guest's method.
So all of that has now been gone.
Excellent.
Next it was the next part of the challenge was to create the public methods on press higher and on press
lower.
So we'll do that right above where we currently have.
Update we'll be delaying all of our update the moment but for now we will start by creating public void
on Press.
Hi.
Parentheses and then our curly braces.
We need to do exactly the same logic that we're doing when we push up arrow so I will grab the mean
equals guess and next guess method.
Copy that pasted inside my own press higher method here.
Great.
Second we need to go public void on press low so be our other method again.
Kelly bracers.
Where is their logic it Max equals guess.
Next guest.
Copy that.
Paste it within here.
That looks pretty good.
We don't need to have anything for our.
Did you get it correct because we already have connected to our success button here.
It calls the load next scenes that's taken care of.
Which means we can delete all of our update method and everything that is contained within it.
So now we just have all variables being declared at the top level of logic we need to tidy up in start
game and our next guess ops.
I accidentally deleted an cares to do that don't delete.
Next guess again.
So just delete what is an update.
There we go.
Thank you Red squiggly line for letting me know I had done something foolish.
OK so on press higher on press lower and next guess we still have they will save that.
Now let's have a look at what's going on in start game.
Just here we've got our Max equals Max plus one.
That was our mechanism for making sure that we absolutely can get to a guess of 1000 because of rounding.
We say Macs Plus mean divided by two.
Then we didn't end up getting to a thousand or was 999 as high as we could get to.
I'm going to move that up to the top.
They are Macs equals Macs plus 1 so we can establish them straight away and then we don't need to be
re assigning max and min.
We also don't need to have Guess haeckel's 500 that's hard coded in there.
Got a whole ton of lines in here for some reason now what we do need to do next is have some sort of
guess so what is our guest going to be.
Well guess as we have done here is Max plus min divided by two.
Copy that line within our next guess and put it in start game so that as we did before were establishing
Let's have a guess right at the start.
But we don't hardcoded it because up here we might say that the max E is out ten thousand or twenty
three whatever we want to sit now inspector now is vector over here whatever we are assigning as the
max and the main.
So then we need to have our calculation based on the variable Max and the variable min right here in
our start game method I get so on start with Call start game.
Excellent with tidy that up.
We have on press higher on press lower and next guess.
Excellent so we've tidied up all our code in here is looking pretty good.
The one last step that we have to do is to display onto the screen what our guess actually is and that's
going to be the topic for the next lecture where we're looking at the two string function and hooking
up all of our text field so great work with your Reflektor great work in this video.
We're getting very close to finishing up our functionality I think in the very next lecture will have
it so that we can play our game the whole way through so great work and see you again very shortly.