Hello and welcome back to the course and party.
Today we're going to add some finishing touches to our wonderful business intelligence report.
All right.
So let's get straight into it.
First of all you can see that I would just add the colors.
I've decided to go with more conservative colors for the job classification and they tie in better to
the overall picture than I've changed some colors on the map and also just the colors for gender and
now what we want to do is we want to first of all have a look at how this report works without analyzing
it at this stage.
We want to just understand the interactivity that is present on this report.
So for instance if I click on something here you can see that everything adjusts so well the number
at the top changes which now shows us the number of people or customers in this region in Scotland tells
us the distribution how it changes.
And in fact you can actually see the previous distribution behind it.
There you can see here.
Here you can see the previous charts previously but you can also see how they changed.
The first question is why is this necessary why do we need this interactivity.
Well just imagine that you deliver this report to a bank and it has four regions as depicted here and
naturally you'd expect that each region would have its own executive.
So for example the CEO of the bank overall would like to see this whole picture and understand what's
going on in the bank or with the customers of the bank generally.
But then the executive in each of those individual regions would want to see what's going on with their
specific customer base.
Right.
And that's what this report allows you to do or allows them to do.
It allows them to drill into or recreate this position and very quickly just for their segment of the
market just for what they are responsible for.
Also Moreover you can drill into separate segments of your bank overall so you can look at just your
female customers or you can look at all of your blue collar customers or white collar customers and
you can look at different age groups so by holding down control as you can see I'm looking now at everybody
under 40.
So we'll get to the analytics of that.
But for now what is peculiar is that when we select something here on the map these charts do have a
history of what the overall looks like with these don't.
So what does that happen.
Well I had a I did a bit of an investigation and I found that this the reason for that is that we added
this table calculation the percentage of total so I'll show you on an example so I'm going to go to
the quick calc and remove the percentage of total.
So just click OK.
And now you'll see when I select the different regions you can still see the previous split.
And then you can see a new overlayed split.
On top of that so it's probably not the best not the best solution in this case so it's a bit kind of
it's a bit counter intuitive or it just doesn't really portray the inside this new part of it is inside.
So it's actually not that's not such a big problem that we can see it when we add a percentage of total.
So perhaps at the time when you're watching this video this has been resolved by power be either constantly
trading or software.
But if not it's not a big deal.
And the same thing for the team.
You can test it out for ourselves if you remove the percentage of total calculation.
You'll see that it adjusted the same way.
Now that is a good segue into how can we control the behavior of these resolutions.
Well over here if you go into a format there's a button called editor interactions.
If you click that it will allow you to decide which interactions you want and wish interactions you
don't want.
So for instance if I click this map you can see that the map selected all of the other elements on this
is a position they now have this additional option at the top where I can select what type of interaction
I want.
So what will happen when I click the map what will happen to this resolution for instance.
Will it be filtered.
Will it be highlighted or will nothing happen.
So if I select nothing then uncheck edit interactions.
Now if I click this map you can see that everything is updating except for this part of the visualization.
OK.
So if I now click Edit interactions and instead of nothing I select filter and then uncheck that you'll
see that what's happening now is that it's no longer show me the history of what was there before.
It's just updating this visualization completely.
So you might want that type of behavior on your visa and you might not want to compare it to what you
used to have especially in this case.
As you can see when you have the history then it's really hard to.
You can be hard to tell what's going on because you've got two layers one after the other.
So that's how this works.
For example click on this again and let's say we want to filter this one as well.
So now you can see that it's updating and there's nothing in the background so it might be easier to
work with this type of visualization but that's totally up to you how you want it to work.
But I personally will probably leave it like this because I'm we're used to this approach where you
don't see what was going on in the background what was going on previously.
And moreover these charts are structured in that way anyway so that way is consistent throughout.
But then you'd have to change it for all of them.
Right.
So you would need to change it for if you're going to be using it for this chart as well you need to
go into this chart and then select filter here.
And then again you need to adjust and check that or you can just keep it checked and just select them
all like that.
So make sure that was unfilter that one in that one.
So let's see how that works.
OK so I guess we need to select each one like that each one separately.
Let's have a look.
That one deadline set up so we'll only have to do is set up this one.
And have we set this one up yet.
No.
All right.
So that should solve the problem so whichever chart I click now they all will just filter to the final
result.
So there's no chart other chart of the background.
That's what my personal preference you might have your own approach in this situation.
All right.
So that is how we set up these charts.
That's how we work with the interactivity or interactions in the background and in the next Tauriel
we're going to actually derive the insights from this visualization.
I look forward scenics them and until then happy analyzing.