Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting Module 4, Agile Estimation,
of Best Practices for Project Estimation.
Let's recap the course and then I'll give you an overview of this module.
Let's do a quick review of the module roadmap.
In the first module we learned about the fundamentals of project estimation.
In the second and third module we learned about several practical tools
and techniques to help you develop your estimates.
And in this module we will provide some context in how estimates
are derived and used in an Agile environment.
Okay, now let's do an overview of this module.
This module will discuss the Agile philosophy and its approach to estimation.
Okay, here are the key topics I will be covering.
Agile philosophy.
Agile myths.
The adaptive approach.
The Agile approach to projects.
Just the right amount of planning.
Old thinking versus new thinking.
Estimation scales.
Planning poker.
Benefits of Agile estimation.
Step by step, creating an Agile estimate.
Iterations, velocity, and schedules.
And best practice framework. Okay, let's get started.