Using estimating models.
In this section we will learn about different estimating models and how
and when to apply them to your estimation process.
Okay, here are our estimating model types.
One type are what I call pre-launch models.
These are performed before the project begins.
These will provide necessary information to add to your PDD to help you
decide whether you're going to launch or not launch a project.
Next will come what I call the post-launch models.
And these are performed during the project.
Yes, your estimation techniques are not done,
your job is not done, even though the project has launched.
You want to continually refine and validate your
remaining hours on your project, your schedules,
during the project.
So we're going to talk about that as well.
Lastly, are the hybrid model.
This uses the pre and during models.
In fact, the hybrid model is what I always use,
which is using the pre-launch to move the project to a go or launch
condition and then as the project progresses,
I apply my post-launch models to dynamically refine the project
estimates throughout the remaining portion of the project.
And let's talk about those in more detail right now.
Okay,
let's talk about the different types of models that we have discussed so far.
We have the pre-launch models and for me, I use five different approaches.
Top down historical, top down heuristic,
parametric, phased allocation, and bottom up.
In fact I use probably almost all five of these on large projects to get a
good feel and perspective of what the estimates might be.
Post-launch models, phased progressive, and of course our hybrid model,
where we use both the pre and the post launch.
There is also an Agile model and that is covered in Module three,
Agile Estimation.
Okay, so let's begin with the pre-launch.
Remember, the project hasn't started yet and we want to get a few estimates going.