Now let's refine our ideal capacity by applying historical capacity data.
To recap, our ideal capacity is 5, 688 hours for our team.
So we want to further refine our ideal capacity by historical parameters.
We want to review our actuals, our historical records,
from our time tracking system.
We also know we have some sick time, seems to be around 40 hours per year.
So now we want to reduce our ideal capacity and refine that down to 1,
856 hours, 40 hours for sick time.
We want to review actuals and average across everyone on the team.
So historical capacity for a work year is 1, 856, for a work week, 35.
17.
And for a work day, we're down to 7 hours.
7.
1 to be exact, but about 7 hours a day is what our team capacity is.
And again, you don't have to do this all the time.
Maybe once a quarter, twice a year, something like that.
Also you want to update this if your team size changes as well.
So to summarize, this is how much capacity my team can perform ideal estimates.
To summarize, this is how much capacity my team can produce.
We will talk about elapsed time or team schedules in the next section.
Let's see how we compute a 'pretty good capacity' multiplier.
Here's an example.
We have an ideal time estimate of 454 hours.
Let's determine our PGC multiplier.
We divide 8 by 7.
1, equals 1.
12.
So our multiplier is going to be 1.
What we're saying here is that we can produce 7.
1 real hours of work, with an elapsed time of 8 hours.
It's like our football analogy where we had 60
minutes of production if you will,
within the elapsed time of the game about 3 to 4 hours.
So for each ideal hour of effort, it equates to 1.
12 hours for my team to accomplish.
So now let's convert our ideal estimate to a PGC estimate.
So we multiply the 1.
12 x the 454 hours, to give us 509 hours.
Now the ideal estimate never changes.
It's still 454 hours.
What we're saying is,
is that in order to accomplish those 454 hours I need a window,
or elapsed time, of 509 hours.
So if I was going to charge my customer money,
per hour, I'm only going to charge them 454 hours.
But I'm going to tell them my elapsed time will be 509 hours.
So you can see how we're now moving into the
scheduling part of the estimating process.
But it will take a window, or period,
of 509 hours to consume and execute those 454 hours.
So the ideal team capacity is 509 hours.
So remember though,
we know we started with ideal time and that was to clarify the
tasks separate from any extraneous activities.
So now we need to begin applying the predictable parameters,
vacation, company holidays that are truly predictable,
to determine our elapsed time, AKA, our beginning schedule.
Why tracking your time is imperative.
If you track your time then you can measure your team's capacity.
By using the capacity of your team,
you can convert ideal time to elapsed time in the most efficient way.
When you track your time you can use the data for
the historical capacity planning.
If you don't track your time, you've lost two very valuable inputs,
which will affect the quality of your estimates.
And the point of converting from ideal time to elapsed time is to set
the expectations of your management or your customer,
so they really know the real time it takes to get the job done.
And lastly,
I want to emphasize that tracking your team's time on task is just so critical.
The historical data is used and leveraged throughout the
estimating and scheduling process.
So let's summarize determining your team's capacity.
First, determine your team's ideal capacity.
Refine using historical capacity.
Determine your PGC multiplier.
These are really easy to do, they do not take a lot of time,
and now you're ready.
Given any ideal estimate you can determine your team's true capacity.
It takes into account known parameters, such as vacation and sick time, etc.
Add more parameters that relate to you and your company's environment.
But always update these parameters regularly to make
sure your multipliers are accurate.
Now, what other attributes might affect your team capacity?
Skill sets, training needs, of course team size.
So the next section we'll explore team schedules and how these other attributes play into your scheduling process.