Arbitrary padding is never a good idea.
Never.
And later we're going to talk about managed padding, what I call good padding.
Now let's dive into arbitrary padding.
It affects the performance of the development team.
If you're just throwing padding and hours on here and there why should they
take any care in making a good estimate or a good schedule?
So it supports the negative response of "who cares anyway?
" It also affects the motivation of people on the team.
The type of developers you want on your team will get
bored if there is little sense of urgency,
structure, organization, or quality in your estimates and schedules.
It also generates a lot of distrust among other stakeholders.
Other people, such as your management team,
your customers,
possible other business units in your company who
look to you and your team as well,
their estimates are always wrong and they're always padding.
They can't trust you, therefore the distrust.
"They, IT, always exaggerate the numbers.
" You do not want to have a perception like that.
In the next slide we have a few more side effects.
Now here are a few more downsides to arbitrary padding.
It doesn't contribute positively to the bottom line
of the product being developed.
And this ultimately affects everyone's success.
If you paid too much, for example,
do you need to hire more people to complete that task?
And if you're not sure what that padding or buffering is,
how could you possibly hire the right people?
So in software development, as we kind of know,
work expands to fill the available space.
There won't be that sense of urgency,
people may be working a more unstructured approach
than a more structured approach.
I don't like that at all.
The more time one allocates to a task the more time it will
take to effectively complete that task.
I really believe that.
I really want, expect,
and demand clearly defined tasks with absolute estimates to drive
the team forward and be successful and build trust in those
stakeholders so we can all be successful.
Now let's address what I call good padding in the next slide.
Managed padding, or good padding.
Let's look at a definition of managed padding.
It's time added, proportional to the risk and impacts of the project.
Also known as a buffer.
Also known as good padding, because I want to say it's thoughtful padding.
Padding has a negative meaning of course.
So let's use the term buffer.
This isn't just for semantics either.
But to mean managed, thoughtful padding or buffering,
rather than arbitrary padding.
And it's important to understand the distinction between
arbitrary and thoughtful and managed padding.
So, as I said, it's not arbitrary, it's thought through in the following way.
Use the percentage confidence technique for example.
If you are 80% confident in your total estimate for a project,
maybe add 20% as a buffer estimate to the estimates itself or to the schedule.
So if you're estimate is 1, 000 hours, maybe you add 200 hours,
as a buffer, to the 1200 hours.
And maybe your rule is something like 100% minus your confidence factor,
equals the buffer to add.
So we're going to 100%, minus 80% equals 20%.
Now again, you're doing this with some assumptions.
You're going to say,
I'm using this confidence factor because I may lose a resource,
I hear rumor he's leaving the company,
there are two other new projects in the hopper that
might come against this project, it might take resources.
There's a reorganization going on.
So, you are thinking through thoughtfully,
writing down these assumptions so when you present back to management,
they know clearly why you've put this padding or buffering on.
It isn't just an arbitrary, out of thin air padding.
So this will be your reserve estimate.
In other words the team is still going to drive towards the original goal of 1,
000 hours.
And you, as a project manager or leader,
know that you have 200 hours of buffer you might be able to manage,
or play with based on the other extraneous
activities swirling around your project.
Now let's look at some best practices to guide the development of your buffers,
or managed padding.
Determining your buffer.
Here is some best practices for determining your buffer.
Use expert judgment and templates in developing your estimates.
So you really know what's going on and you really understand
the deep assumptions of your project and your customer and
other projects around your project,
or other things that could affect your project.
Use subject matter experts to provide valuable inputs.
You don't know it all and these people may not even be on your team,
but they may be other business leads or other IT experts
you might want to pull in to better understand the effect
of your project against those.
Again, good padding,
only by project manager at the project level or as a team activity.
Again, it's not arbitrary padding,
you must put on good padding or good buffering and write down the
assumptions that drive that additional padding.
And explain that to your management or customer.
Build trust, not distrust.
Use estimating techniques to help develop your buffers.
That we've talked about in the past.
And the idea of range of estimates or range of schedules.
Confidence factors.
Those kinds of little techniques will really help you better
pinpoint the buffering or padding that you need.
And then understand your company's entire project portfolio and the
impacts across those projects with your project.
I've mentioned tracking your time many times.
In the next section I will address just how important this best practice is to your success.