This next model is phased progressive.
So, we're going to carry out or perform,
again, our estimate in phases or stages.
This is also known as phase estimating, a bit like a waterfall approach.
By the way, waterfall is not dead or necessarily bad, in this particular case.
And why I say this is because your customers,
your clients,
might only approve an initial phase of discovery first and
then they only approve the next phase, next.
So it may be phase by phase, out of your control.
So here's why I like this approach.
Or here's how I would deal also with this approach.
So again, then the client may ask for an estimate then to complete the project.
So you may have done phase one, discovery,
maybe even phase two, design or whatever your phases might be.
And after each phase your client may ask for the
remaining estimate of the following phases.
This allows for re-estimating for improved accuracy,
based on what you've learned in the preceding phases.
Again, each phase drives the estimate for the next phase.
Here's an example.
Initiation or discovery phase was 60 hours to complete.
Design/analysis phase is 120.
In other words I might want to use the multiple, based on my experience, of 2.
So whatever the discovery takes I can tell my client I think
it'll be 120 hours for the next phase.
Construction and development phase.
Okay, we're going to start writing some code now, 360 hours.
I might make it a 3 multiple of the design phase.
That might be one of my criteria,
one of my parameters in coming up with the following estimate for construction.
Deploy phase.
Install, deploy, etc.
Maybe I don't use a multiple here,
maybe I can tell by the size is 24 hours for the average,
you know, deploy phase.
This is our last model, hybrid model.
And I think this is a very important technique to
incorporate hybrid into your estimating process.
This technique is called hybrid because it uses actual time spent and
compares it against the other pre-launch estimating models.
So we had our original estimate, our project starts,
we start gathering actual hours spent against those tasks,
and we compare it to how well it shows against our estimates.
If we're off, we need to adjust.
But,
a prerequisite in order to do that of course is you
need a task or a time tracking system.
I just can't emphasize enough how important it is for you to do this.
All tasks, hours and minutes, must be tracked per planning units.
Whether it's a task or a screen or however you lay it out,
all the hours expended against that task,
the original estimate,
you must capture and compare to see whether am I behind that estimate,
or am I ahead of that estimate?
Behind meaning too many hours, and ahead meaning you have less hours.
So here's an example.
Let's say we've developed six screens, four reports, and two API interfaces.
So we want to use this information as parameters to
re-estimate the remaining tasks of the project.
Again, our project is underway.
So the original estimate per screen is 18 hours.
Okay, that was the original estimate.
So how are we doing?
We would look in our time tracking system and it would show us,
oh, actual average hours used per screen is 27 hours.
Oh, okay, so we are actually over.
Now there could be a variety of reasons.
Maybe they were harder than we thought.
Maybe our estimating model wasn't very accurate.
Maybe our team needed some additional training.
But now that we know that,
we want to use that information to re-estimate the remaining screens.
So now we're going to use the 27 hours as our estimate per
screen to re-estimate the remaining screens.
Because that is what it's really taking.
And then educate our management or our steering group on hey,
here's what it really takes to go do, now we can be more accurate.
And we want to repeat this for other work unit types.
Reports, APIs, and things like that.
So we are always monitoring the actuals against the estimates, at all times.
The team and/or the PM needs to be doing this.
Again, this only works if you accurately track your time on all the tasks.
And I can't re-emphasize this enough.
This is very important and critical.
As I've mentioned throughout the description of these estimating models,
I mix and match these for each of my projects.
No one estimating model may work for you and I would suggest don't use only one.
I use several at a time and I always use the hybrid model because I
always want to know how am I doing against my estimates?
I don't want to be 1, 000 hours over,
I want to only be 100 hours over and be able to talk to my
management or my steering committee team saying,
hey, look I'm a little bit over now here's the data to prove what it takes,
etc.
So you may use two or three models, which may be the best for you.
And you may use different models based on the
nature and the type of the project,
big or small or medium or something like that.
Recommended throughout the estimating and project development process.
So it's not just at the beginning, make an estimate and go and away you go.
You're always going to be re-estimating throughout
the project for increased accuracy.
So your goal, as the project manager or estimator, is to do a couple of things.
You want to always be able to predict and provide the
highest quality estimate or estimates, at all times.
Especially before the project launches,
gather several estimates based on the different
model and the different assumptions.
And then if it's a go,
you're going to start tracking your time in a time tracking system
and comparing those actuals against your estimates.
So using the information at hand throughout the entire project lifecycle,
you'll be able to better make estimates in the future, you'll be able to improve your skills, and have much better estimates.