Now here's a very simple example of posting time.
You can see below is a spreadsheet or maybe a web-based
application that's captured the following information.
I call your attention to the heading up above, in darker blue.
Date, Hours, Customer, Project, the Resource or person,
the Task with task number, and Description.
So each row is an entry.
And as an example, that row that I just highlighted in light blue,
from left to right,
so on 9/19 eight hours were spent and it was charged to customer Michael Inc.
under the Project Enrollment-Development.
The Resource for this particular entry is Jim.
The Task was 140, Consult with GAIT SMEs,
and the Description of the task was Continue reviewing the database to
identify the tables needed for creating a login,
profile information, company, etc.
That's one timesheet entry for a person.
So you collect these up each day, for each person,
on each task, project,
customer and you'll have your historical actuals to use against your estimates.
And to apply to all the other estimating models we talked about in the past.
What to report?
I use this report to get a quick view or status on
progress of each task in a project.
Maybe something like this would be good for you too.
So,
on the previous slide was the time entry values
themselves that each person entered.
And on this slide I'm showing you an output report that I can
look at quickly to see how we're doing.
At the top row are the headings, left to right,
Name, that's the task name and the number.
Charged Hours.
Maybe I had some No Charge Hours.
Estimated Hours.
% Consumed, the Difference, and the Start Date,
and the Last Worked Date for that task.
These are handy items.
So for the very first one I see the task, I see that there is 14.
5 hours charged against it.
The total estimate is 26 hours.
So we've used 55.
77% of the time.
I could then meet with the software engineer and say do
you think you're about halfway done?
If the answer is yes, we're on track.
If the answer is no, I can find out why and take corrective action,
specifically for that task.
But I could always learn from that to maybe modify and
improve the estimating and scheduling process,
upstream for future projects.
Now based on analyzing progress, I may need to revisit the estimates.
And let's see how.
Revising estimates after project launch.
This is very, very important.
And earlier in the module we talked about the estimating hybrid model.
And this is what we want to do.
Prior to launching the project, our top down model estimated say for example,
16 hours per screen.
Since we're tracking the time now,
we can see exactly how many hours per screen were actually used.
So the tracking system reveals for us the following things.
Actual hours of 12 hours, on average, per screen.
Hey, we're ahead of plan.
Initially we planned for 16 hours and that was in our estimates,
but now that we've been working the project for a while,
we see that the actual results are only 12 hours.
Or maybe the actuals were 23 hours per screen.
Uh, we're not on track, in fact we're actually behind plan.
And we may need to revisit.
So either case, we should re-estimate or modify our plans accordingly.
Whether we're behind or ahead,
to accurately predict the remaining time to do those screens and then
reflect that in the schedule accordingly as well.
Wow, we have covered a lot of material in this module. Now let's cover the key points in the summary section, coming up ahead.