Now let's determine velocity.
Remember team capacity, from the previous module?
In the Agile world it is known as velocity.
Velocity is a measure of the team's rate of progress.
And you can see the little velocity chart to the right.
What I'd also recommend is after each iteration,
you determine how many story points you produced and just put it on a chart.
And over time you will see what your average number of
story points that you could produce, per iteration is.
And that's your velocity.
You fold that back into the planning process and you
know how much you can produce.
There's an example.
Let's say the team delivered the 41 points, in a 3-week iteration.
So,
all the different user stories that added up to the 41
points were completed in 3 weeks.
So the velocity of the team is 41 points per iteration.
As the team works through multiple iterations,
the velocity is recalculated to be as accurate as possible,
to help predict the productivity of the team.
That's very important for planning future iterations and for scheduling.
So a simple chart, as you see on the screen, is certainly appropriate.
You can see the similarities between team capacity in the previous
module and team velocity in the Agile world.
The whole Agile process is seen as delivering business functions.
You don't typically talk in terms of hours or sick time or computer tasks,
like designing the database for example.
Now let's do some scheduling.
Here is a simple way to schedule in Agile.
Add up all the story points for the project.
If you know the team's velocity, which you should,
you can divide the total story points by the iteration's
capacity to determine the number of iterations.
You then turn the iterations into a schedule.
It's that simple.
Example, we have 201 story points.
If an iteration is 3 weeks, and the team's velocity is 41 points,
we divide the 41 into the 201.
So basically, it'll take about 5 iterations,
or 15 weeks, to accomplish all of those user stories into usable software.
So just like in the previous modules, we first derived size,
hours versus story points, old school versus new school,
if you will.
And then we derived schedule.
Okay, now let's see how we do re-estimation.
Now let's do some re-estimation, Agile style.
But first, remember in the previous modules we discussed the hybrid model?
It used actual hours posted against tasks during the project execution.
And then based on the team's capacity,
we could then re-estimate the remaining work.
Very important, very handy tool.
Same for Agile.
If the velocity changes based on the team size or skill mix,
sick time,
etc., you can use your newly adjusted velocity to recalculate the
remaining iterations and then apply it to the calendar.
And now you have a new schedule.
It's that easy.
Okay, now let's recap the section on the next slide.
Now let's recap this section by what I call the
best practice framework for Agile.
Agile plans are typically more reliable because they are
planning for a smaller time horizon, planning for a smaller amount of work,
focused on usable features.
Remember the more time you spend planning,
sometimes the less likely it will add any value.
Short iterations are very important and very successful.
Keep in mind, there's a diminishing return on time spent estimating.
It takes a greater effort for a more accurate estimate.
It is a balance though.
Will it be worth the extra time?
It'll be up to you to decide as a project manager or a leader.
There is a relationship between estimating accuracy and effort.
Agile teams typically acknowledge that they cannot
eliminate uncertainty from estimates and embrace that
small efforts may result in big gains. Okay, now let's move on to the summary of this module.