Our final section of this module is an overview summary.
As you have seen, the Agile approach may seem more streamlined or lightweight,
compared to some of the techniques in Module 2 and 3.
Let's review the key points on the next slide.
Module summary.
Useful capabilities versus a series of tasks.
Agile planning is at a higher, more abstract level.
So think in terms of business functions or user stories.
Customer involvement is key.
Remember customers may not be that comfortable with the Agile process.
They may want to know how much and when for the entire project.
So educate and build trust with your customer.
Use ideal time as a unit of measure.
Ideal time can still apply in the Agile world.
So what you've learned in the previous modules may apply here as well.
Since Agile planning is more high level and abstract,
you might consider ideal days and ideal hours to make it
easier or more comfortable if you're not sure or
comfortable with the abstract approach.
Use relative estimation scales.
We discussed two relative scales, Fibonacci and exponential.
Choose a scale, educate the team on their relative values, and use it.
Planning poker is quick and easy.
Planning poker combines expert opinions,
analogies,
or comparisons and decomposed user stories to drive story point values.
Agile estimation focuses on user stories,
and is team oriented and customer centric.
Prioritize user stories, with your customers.
This involves the customer, of course.
They can see the relative value of effort to get the job
done and feel part of the planning process.
Collect prioritized user stories into iterations.
A key part of any work is to deliver, based on the priorities of the customer.
Perform re-estimation with each iteration.
With each iteration you have captured the team's velocity,
capacity, for that collection of story points.
Your team is more experienced and now you can re-estimate
the next iteration with more granularity.
Lastly, thank you very much for listening to my course.
Don't forget to check out another course of mine
that ties right into this course, Best Practices for Requirements Gathering. Thank you.