Elements of a project definition document.
So what's in it?
A project definition document is a collection of elements that can
adequately cover all of the potential pieces of information that would
be required to create your initial estimates.
Such as, purpose, goals, objectives, success criteria,
what's in scope, what's out of scope, assumptions,
recommended approach, business drivers, budget and schedule.
Return on investment, constraints, risks,
stakeholders, preliminary schedule and estimates.
Policies and standards, legal and regulatory, and competitive drivers.
This is just a short list of what might be part of
your project definition document.
In the following slides we'll go into detail in each
one of these and what's required.
Now let's go into a little more detail of each one of those.
Purpose.
Replace the current student enrollment system.
So we're going to be giving examples of each one of these
elements and what you might write for each one.
So for example, purpose, replace the current student enrollment system.
Goals and objectives, improve student services,
provide better financial management, avoid end of life of old hardware.
These might be some of the initial goals and objectives for
replacing the current student enrollment system.
Success criteria.
All data successfully migrated and accessible on the new system.
Sounds like a good goal, good success criteria.
New system online by December 1.
Now this is just a short list of these.
But purpose, goals and objectives,
and success criteria are some of the most important elements
and should be flushed out as much as you can.
More elements of a project definition.
What's in our out of scope?
In scope.
Student enrollment, financial management, cashier, accounts receivable.
What's out of scope?
Sales, marketing, student grades.
It's very important to itemize what's out of scope.
In other words, what things the project will not be covering.
Assumptions.
Insufficient budget for adding an IT staff.
Maybe there's not enough programmers to do the job.
No off-the-shelf solution available.
Must migrate Legacy data from an old system.
Recommended approach.
You've put together this approach going forward.
Hey, we should develop use cases, some screen sketches.
We think it's going to be custom development, be the right path.
Initial architecture, web application.
Additional elements.
Business drivers, unsupported hardware and infrastructure.
So we're using some very old hardware now that
we're going to need to get off of.
Inadequate service support to students.
Another business driver, students may not be as happy as they used to be.
Maybe our revenue is down.
Inadequate access to financial information.
All critical business drivers.
Budget.
Remember budget from estimate?
So the budget is what we have available to spend.
We have a three year budget.
We're going to allocate this capital expenditure,
25% the first year, maybe 40% the second year,
35% the third year.
I have five million dollars.
Schedule.
Must be online by December 1.
I left the year off of course.
Here are the next three.
Return on investment.
Say a five hundred thousand dollar investment will return seven
hundred and fifty thousand dollars in six months.
That's a 50% ROI, a 50% Return on Investment,
and that formula is simply net profit divided by investment times one hundred.
The financial folks in your company will always do an ROI.
Projects should not be approved as a go without a reasonable ROI.
Constraints.
Projects must begin by July 1.
Data migration must be performed during summer, which is the low usage months.
School's out maybe, something like that.
Risks.
The old hardware may fail.
Business continuity,
in other words our business might fail or slow down if the hardware does fail.
The budget may only be available for this fiscal year.
Here's an opportunity now to move forward.
Additional elements of a project definition.
Stakeholders.
Stakeholders are key individuals in an organization that have an
interest in the success of the completion of the project.
In this case we have the Dean of the University,
IT Operations Director, and the Chief Financial Officer.
Next is preliminary schedule.
Project planning, we want to begin Jan 1.
Specification development, Feb 1.
System release, April 1.
Preliminary estimates.
Again, this course is on the portion that creates these estimates.
In the next two modules we're going to talk about how we
fill out this estimate portion certainly.
But in this case, we think at this point in time,
consulting is one hundred thousand dollars,
infrastructure one hundred fifty, and development two hundred fifty thousand.
And here are our last three elements.
Policies and standards.
Every organization has a set of policies that must be followed.
In this case there's a security policy.
It must be PCI compliant.
Standards.
Follow the university application lifecycle management standards.
Legal and regulatory.
Legal, it must be ADA compliant.
Regulatory, we know of none at this time.
Competitor drivers.
Other universities enable a much better student enrollment experience.
So, this project is going to help us beat those other universities.
Greater competition among schools, that's also a big drive here for our project.
Construction of a Project Definition Document, or sometimes PDD for short.
Remember this is just your starter list.
Continuously build up your PDD with each project.
Continuously add in more major and minor elements.
A major element for example was legal and regulatory.
Under there you have what I call minor elements.
ADA, HIPPA, PCI, SOX, things that would fall under legal and regulatory.
With my first project, back years ago, ADA was a requirement.
So I had that in that section.
Then came a healthcare client.
Then came a university.
And then came a business client.
All of which I add these, so later when the next project comes up,
I say hey customer,
I have legal and regulatory sections here to talk about and do
you have any requirements under any of these?
Because these will drive requirements, which in turn drive estimates.
A solid PDD will enable you to quickly gather requirements. Good, quality requirements drive better estimates.