Making estimating easy, or at least easier.
Estimates must be iterative.
An initial, high-level guestimate if you will,
or approximation is what we're looking for.
Followed by one or more iteration of estimates.
This is what the PDD is for that we talked about,
the Project Definition Document,
to help us quickly gather high-level requirements and
come up with an initial approximation.
Estimates must be continually refined.
As more data is collected, requirements are more understood.
So your first cut estimate is much different than
your formal and final estimate.
Lastly, in order to be successful,
at creating quality estimates you need process,
templates, and tools.
As we'll go through in the following module.
So continuing from the last slide, making estimating easier,
we need to have a solid planning and estimating best practice.
And here it is.
We develop a process, and we're going to do that in the next module.
This process will be a solid planning and estimating
process to use with your team and management.
We're going to document the process,
document the process and train your team on its process how it works.
And why are we doing all this?
There are great benefits of an optimal planning process.
It's going to reduce risk to the business, which is important.
It's going to reduce uncertainty of the business requirements.
We're going to dig in and iterate and better understand them.
Enhances better decision making of where we're going to spend our money,
time, resources.
Establishes trust with your customers.
This is paramount and probably one of the most important
aspects of a good estimation process.
We convey customer's expectations by what we write in our
planning documents and our estimates.
And we have it sufficiently reliable for business
leaders to make good decisions from.
We talked about a lot of estimating activities and process
and philosophies and fundamentals so far.
But are you up for the job?
Not every software engineer is cut out to be proficient at
gathering requirements and developing estimates.
It just may not be your thing.
You need to have strong communication and people skills.
In my experiences,
those two skills are much more important to quality estimates than say,
C#.
You need to have the ability of extracting true business requirements.
That's very essential.
You need to have good business acumen and a solid technical foundation.
But if you did come from a software engineering background,
you have half the picture right there.
You have that good,
solid technical foundation and all you need now then is to
learn more about gathering requirements,
making estimates, and working with people.
Know the business requirements you're estimating as much as possible.
Again, it will be iterative and over time,
but as you build that business domain, that's really important.
You need to possess a decisive character to confidently
and quickly arrive at results while not having all the
necessary information at hand.
I find this character that's somewhat challenging for some software engineers.
They tend to want to know it all, in other words know all the facts,
know everything before they're comfortable making an estimate.
You're going to need to be able to live in a world
where you are a bit uncomfortable.
And you have some soft estimates in there and then you iterate to improve.
Lastly,
able to gauge and adapt to changing requirements and customer expectations.
Customers and users are always changing their mind.
Business is dynamic, requirements are always changing. Therefore, customer expectations are always changing.