Hello and welcome to Shopify Theme Development: How
to build or customize your own online store.
I'm Chris, I'm a top teacher here on Skillshare.com,
covering topics such as web development and online freelancing.
And in today's course, I'm going to take you through an efficient process to
building and customizing online stores using the Shopify platform.
Shopify is one of the leading e-commerce platforms in
the world with over 800,000 active Shopify stores,
and in my opinion,
the most ideal place to get started building your first online store.
As a designer or someone with basic web development knowledge,
all you'll need to unlock the power of Shopify is
some basic knowledge of the platform itself and its templating language called Liquid.
And that's exactly what we'll get into in this course.
In the following lessons, we're going to focus on building out and
customizing your store front through the use of a Shopify theme,
which is basically like a template that determines
the way that your online store looks and feels.
We'll learn about theme structure including layouts,
templates, sections, and snippets,
how to edit your code efficiently and instantly update your storefront, and finally,
how editing your code can not only update the look and feel of your website,
but also provide options within
your Shopify admin to dynamically add and customize content.
By the end of the class,
you should have a solid understanding of what you can do with
Shopify themes and the confidence to make changes when needed.
Whether you want to sell your own products,
or use these skills to help businesses as a freelancer or agency,
this course will get you started on the right track with Shopify.
So if you're ready to get started,
click on the next video and I'll see you on the inside.