In this lesson, we are going to go over sections and snippets.
Obviously, we have already touched on sections and
snippets a little bit in the previous lessons.
Indeed, there's going to be some overlap in this whole structure,
but let's dive deeper into talking more
specifically about sections and snippets in this lesson.
One of the templates that I didn't show you in
the previous lesson was the template for the homepage, which is interesting.
If I go back into ADaM and you can see here,
collection uses this selection collection template.
I must have accidentally put that in there, let me save that.
If you go into a lot of them either they have a bunch of
their own custom content or they just link to a section such as the collection page,
just links to the collection template,
the blog page just goes to the blog template.
As we will soon find out so that we can use
the features of sections which include customizing in the customizer.
We had looked at that a little bit,
but I want to show you the index.liquid template first.
This is the template that loads on our homepage
and it includes this dynamic tag content for index.
If we go back to Owl theme structure,
I had this template linked to content from index,
but I deleted it at the start of two lessons ago.
That's because it's not related to every single template,
but it does show up in one template,
and that is the homepage template.
But you know what, I might be wrong because maybe we could
put content for index in every template.
Let's just run that experiment right now and honestly,
I've never tried this before,
so I don't know if it's going to work,
but let's see if we can just shove that in any of our templates.
That is the collection template.
If I go into my customizer.
Be interesting to see what happens with that dynamic tag.
Any errors in our theme watch?
No. Let's go into collections list. Sorry, that's the wrong one.
We want collection pages.
Interestingly enough, we have this section
here which has been hard-coded into the collection.
But then we also have the selection that we had on our homepage content for index,
which allows us to dynamically add,
remove, and order sections.
Pretty cool. I've never tried that before and I don't know whether that is too practical,
but how it's set up by default.
I'm going to revert this to how it was before.
Is on the homepage,
you have this content for index.
Maybe I need to put that thing back in my diagram there we go.
You have access to this super awesome tag called content for index,
which allows you to have a dynamic list of sections
and if it makes sense for you to put on any other page other than the homepage.
Feel free to do so,
but on the homepage,
by default, you have content for index.
Now of course, you can go in and make this template like any other template.
This template is here for you to use it does not have to just be content for index,
but content for index is cool because we can,
as I mentioned before, add sections.
Now we are going to go deeper into sections in a later video by creating
our own section and then you are going to really learn the power of sections.
But for now, let's dive into the code of one of them.
we've gone a bit into this already but if we go into
templates and look at a template for cart,
everything is contained within a section.
If we go into here section for cart template,
then we have everything that shows up in our cart page with a schema for editing.
This is basically the part that separates sections from
any other of the files in Owl theme code.
The schema might look a little bit daunting at first,
but it's an amazing way to add in customizable options that we
use throughout our code here and we allow the user to edit them.
As you can see here,
there's a bunch of different language data and this converts
the label or the name of the schema based on your language.
But you don't have to do that,
you can just get rid of this object all together.
If you just wanna do it in one language,
you can have cut page.
Most of the themes actually I work on are like this.
There's not so many different options for languages.
I'm going to just get rid of that object and simplify it and you can see here,
we've got the top level of our schema.
We've got the name of this section,
settings, and then within our settings,
we've got all the different settings that we can change.
Just like we had here in our settings.schema,
we can create a schema for
each individual section and then only call in those options when we need them.
It works in a similar way to the schema in our setting schema,
this is for the whole theme.
If we go into a specific section,
what did we have before?
We had collection template, wasn't it?
Anyway, it does not really matter.
They are all similar in how they operate.
It was not this one but let's have a look at this one too.
We've got a name, collection pages,
and here's our settings.
We've got different input types here,
and the different input types we have available to us we can go over right now.
I'm just going to go into the documentation.
Just typing into Google,
Shopify input types, configuring theme settings.
Let me have a look and see if this is the document we are looking for.
Input settings if I click that, here we go.
Now we have in the documentation,
the various input settings.
You can create different inputs based on whether we are going to use texts,
whether we are going to select an image,
whether it is going to be a true or false boolean selection like one or the other,
whether it's going to be a select box, checkbox range.
We can see this working if we go into
our customizer and we can look at the rich range of different input types we have here.
This is going to be an image one.
If I go to here,
this is going to be image picker.
I go back to my customizer, these are selects.
If I go into here, that's a text.
This is a text area,
and this is actually a link or URL field.
Let me check the name on that one to see if it's a link or URL, link list.
There was URL.
So the input type for that one,
which majorly looks like a standard textbooks, but it's not.
If you actually click on it,
some options come up and we can set that by using the input type of URL. Okay?
So let's look at slideshow, okay?
Because that's a pretty good example.
If I go into here and find that section in our theme code.
And I looked down at the schema.
This schema will directly represent what's going on here.
So if I look at the things at the top,
it has to have a name and it has to have settings.
So the name of it is slideshow,
and that's what comes up here.
The class, is for setting CSS classes on the actual section.
So we can't actually see it here,
but it's in there.
And then we go into our settings.
Okay, this will be our first setting.
And it's select the ideal slideshow height and the label is slide height.
So if we go in here, there it is, slide height.
And then what defines these options here?
Well, that's in the schema as well.
And we can go down to this field called Options.
And then you've got a list of options here.
Again, you've got so much language information that's just making it confusing.
So I'm just going to delete some of this to just make it simpler for you guys.
We're all speaking English here.
So you'll still be able to understand what's going on
here without setting it to so many different languages.
Alright, so first option,
the label is adapt a first image and the value when they select that,
is going to be adapt.
Okay? Adapt to first image.
And then it's going to set this value which the user doesn't see.
But this is the value we get to look at within our templates.
So if I search for adapt now,
I can see that if we look for,
that's not a great example.
But we'll have to have a look at where this is being used.
Let's just look for
the slideshow height because there's no point in setting it if it's not used in the code.
So this should be somewhere else in the code.
And you can see here,
we can call that option by first calling it object section,
then going into settings,
and then looking for the slideshow height.
And actually there was adapter right there.
So it's saying if the slideshow height is set to adapt,
that option that we looked at before.
Here, adapt. Then we want to do all this, okay?
So we're using the value that we've set in our schema,
which the user can edit over here.
And we're directly putting that into the code.
So hopefully you guys can start to see that this is really powerful.
You can create a bunch of customizations within your new code that once built,
you can actually go in here and use a user interface to interact with.
And that's going to be good for if you're developing a website for say, a client.
And it's going to be good even just for yourself.
You build it once and then you don't have to go into the code anymore.
It's an option for you to customize.
Maybe you want to switch it back every so often,
that's an option for you to do.
So I know the schema might look a bit
confusing and honestly once you start to get nested into deeper levels,
starts to get even more harder to read.
But over time, you should start to relate what you see here,
to what you see here.
And it should be easy to create more options. Alright?
So just as an example,
what's something that we can add to this slide show as a
customization?Maybe we want to change the text size.
That was my idea, but now I can see it's already been done.
Yeah, anything basically you want to change about all
or give us a customization option in the customizer,
you can set up in your schema and then reference in your section code.
All right, so just to recap how we can use sections.
We can either select them in content for index.
We can slide them specifically in the code into a template,
or we can slide the section into a lab.
And of course, header and footer,
why they appear on every page is because they're sections included in the layout.
These headers and footers are going to be on every page unless of course, we went in.
And let's say we deleted section header from theme.liquid.
We refresh the page.
After we confirm that the page is updated,
we reload the page.
We'll now see that header is gone and it's gone for every page that uses that template,
which as I mentioned before,
for theme.liquid is standard.
So even header and footer that you include in the theme layout is a section as well.
So going back to the diagram,
you can insert sections dynamically into content for index,
into templates by hard-coding them,
or into layouts as well by hard-coding them.
And just to recap how we do that,
it's just with this liquid tag here.
The curly brackets, the percentage sign section,
and then the name of the section.
So, hopefully you get it now that sections are
pretty powerful and they kind of sit at the heart of your theme.
Now, as I mentioned, we're going to build our own section,
and that's going to hammer home this theory a little bit more to you.
So you're going to get some experience with this section and really learn the power
and how you can develop your own custom sections.
But we have one more thing to go over, and that's snippets.
So snippets, you can think of as almost like a dumb section.
Basically just a piece of code that you want to reuse on different parts of your site.
So, there's usually nothing too fancy going on in here.
All it does is bring in,
let's say this is products.
What's this one called?
Product price.liquid.
So if I want to go search in my theme,
search in folder for product-price,
it's going to show me all the references and
I can see here where that snippet has been included.
So, I can go into Collection.liquid.
And you can see here,
I'm including that snippet.
So, if I wanted to edit the content here,
I will have to dive into the snippet and edit that code within the snippet.
Just to show you basically creating our own snippet based on content we already have.
Let's just say, we wanted to reuse
a section within here and it just made more sense to have it as a snippet.
So, let's just say we want this search drawer to be a snippet.
So I could just take all of this, remove it.
Put in a liquid tag.
Right. Include search drawer.
So I'll call it search drawer.
Okay, save that and make sure you have that code saved in your clipboard.
Or you can just Ctrl + Z to get it back.
And what I'm going to do,
is go ahead and create that snippet now.
So, I'm going to call it by the exact same name that I've put in next to the include.
Search drawer.liquid.
Don't forget the.liquid,
and I'll put it in there.
So, now if we go back to our website.
I wonder if this is still using the naked,
that one's still using the naked layout.
But if we go back to our homepage we'll have a header again.
And the search drawer is what comes up when you click on this I believe.
Let's just check
that. It's up here.
Search drawer is this thing that comes up at the top.
And you can see, even though the code is not in there anymore,
we're including it still from another source.
So as you can see, you could really get away with no snippets,
but it's a really good practice to use them if you plan on reusing code or
maybe you just want to clean up this file and
not have so many different components in there.
Maybe this reads a bit better for you.
So, you go into your theme.liquid,
you see all includes search drawer,
then it goes into the header. Okay, cool.
On the flip side, it means that you're going to have to go
and find more files if you use more snippets.
So, that's the trade off there with using snippets.
Is you get to put them in a nice little place that you can reuse later.
But then you're obviously going to have to go in and find that snippet,
which I'm trying to do now.
And you're going to have to edit it there, cool.
So that covers pretty much the everything in this diagram.
So, we've talked about layout,
we've talked about these dynamic liquid tags,
header content and content for index.
We've talked about content for layout.
And we've talked about how the four major areas of your theme,
layout, template sections, and snippets all interact together.
And once you start to play around with Shopify,
it really starts to make sense why it's created in this way.
And it gives you a good structure for really doing anything you want with your theme.
So it's really cool.
The one thing that might have confused you through all of this is of course the liquid.
So, we've been seeing a lot of this templating language called liquid.
Here's a great example,
lots of liquid in here.
In the next video,
we're going to dive deep into liquid.
So, don't worry, we're going to cover what's going on with this liquid code.
Maybe not specifically on this template,
but we're going to talk about liquid in the next video.
So, I'm excited to continue on this journey and I'll see you in the next video.