In this video, we're going to talk about JSON templates.
JSON templates are a newer alternative to
Liquid templates that provide for greater flexibility in the theme editor,
allowing us to create reorderable sections in the admin for not just the homepage,
but for the other templates as well.
If we look at the index file in the previous default theme of Shopify Debut,
you'll see the tag content for index.
This tag dynamically generates our homepage based on a list of sections.
This list of sections we can both edit in the admin,
as well as inside the settings_data.json file.
If you check out the settings_data.json file,
you'll see here the list of sections in the homepage under the current object.
If I scroll down to content for index,
you can see this is the list of
sections that appears on the homepage for this particular theme.
Notice if we go back to the index.liquid file here,
there is no liquid code in this file apart from this singular tag content for index.
What if instead of this tag here,
we stored the list of sections that we found over on
settings_data.json inside this file instead?
This is essentially what Shopify have done in their newer theme, Dawn.
If I navigate over to the Dawn theme which I have stored right here,
click on Edit code,
you'll see that the index template is now a JSON file.
Just like our settings_data.json file in our Debut theme,
you can see that similar data exists now in the template itself.
Here is the order of sections,
just like we had in the content for index array on the previous theme that we looked at.
The index template is now a JSON file that
stores the list of sections as is the product template,
the article template, the page template,
and so on and so forth.
This is what enables reorderable sections in all of our templates now,
not just the homepage template.
The consequence of this is that you will need all liquid code that may have been
stored inside these templates to be moved into sections instead,
even if you only plan on having one section in your template.
Let's take a deeper look at the code that goes into these JSON templates.
Here, I've got the dawn-two theme that I set up earlier in this class.
It's exactly the same as the Dawn main theme with a minor edit,
but seeming it's published and it's right here,
I will edit this one.
If I go into Edit code and then I click here to Add a new template,
you'll see there's now an option here to create your template
as either a Liquid template or a JSON template.
Let's keep the JSON option selected here,
and instead of article,
I'm going to switch this to product.
We've got product.json,
and I'm going to leave it with this default name of alternate.
Let's create that and just like we saw a few videos ago about templates,
we can create alternate templates with JSON as well.
I'll show you how that shows up in the latest theme customizer in just a second.
Now, as always, what I like to do is open up
the documentation and we had that just on our screen a second ago.
Let's switch back to it now and what I'm going to do is put these side-by-side.
Put this over to the left and then I'm going to close that down,
put this over to the right,
and zoom in on our code.
Unfortunately, it seems I can't get rid of this so I'm just going to
move this over, and there we go.
Let's read about JSON templates.
As it says here, JSON templates allow you to control the look and
feel of different pages of the online store using sections,
and they are now data files that store the list of sections to
be rendered rather than templates that contain Liquid code.
I encourage you to read everything on this page,
but let's scroll down to the important stuff, the template structure.
JSON templates must be valid JSON files,
the root should be an object with the following attributes,
so we've got some here that are required and some here that are not compulsory.
Obviously, we're going to need to have
the required fields filled in in our object over here.
But for the ones that aren't compulsory,
we don't necessarily need to put them in the object,
but we can if we want to.
As you see here,
this is already been populated with a section's object and an order array.
What's missing is the name string here,
so I'm going to add that now.
Name, and I'm going to call it Alternate
Template because I can't come up with anything else right now.
Let's hit Save on that, make sure we haven't got to any issues.
Here we go. Sections can't be blank and order can't be blank,
so it will give you this when it starts up.
But then if you try and save on it,
it'll come up with an error.
In order to fix those errors,
what we're going to have to do is fill out this object and this array.
I'm going to open up this object and inside,
what we're going to have to do is create a section object.
What we need to do before we do that is decide on
what section we're going to load in because we need at least one section,
and in the Dawn theme,
we have a section called main product which goes in the main product template as well.
Let's just use that one,
and so I'm just going to call that one main.
Let's open up an object for this main section and inside here,
what we do is scroll down and look at section data.
Again, we have this table of the different fields that are required, and basically,
all that's required inside this section itself,
unless we get into blocks is the section type.
As it says here, it's the filename of this section file to render without the extension.
That's very simple.
All we need to do is put main-product in here without the.liquid.
We've got type and then inside type, we got main-product.
Now, of course, the other error that we've got to fix is that order can't be blank,
so you've got to put in even if there is only one section,
we've got to put in what's here,
the name as we defined here inside the section object,
we need to put that in our order array.
If I hit Save on that,
we shouldn't get any errors.
We're all good, and now if I go to Customize theme, open that up,
I'm going to open this up to full,
minimize a little bit,
and then click up here to choose the template that we're editing.
I'm going to go into Products.
In here, you'll be able to see the alternate template we
just created which we simply named alternate.
If I click on that one, you'll now see that we've got
this product information section here which is in fact main.
We now have our section here and we can start to add new sections to it.
It's important to note that any changes we make
here will now be stored inside the template
itself because this JSON template stores
the list of sections and it also stores the settings.
Now no longer we have this need for so much data to be stored in this one JSON file.
The data for each individual template and
its customizations get stored in the template itself.
Even if we click on settings_data.json,
you'll see this current object is completely empty
because that data has been moved into the specific product template.
What I'm going to do here is add in an extra section here,
and you'll see this reflected in the customizer.
I'm just going to copy this object here and what should we add?
Let's add in a newsletter section.
We're just going to call this newsletter and then inside the type,
remember we've got to use the name of the actual file minus the.liquid.
Newsletter.liquid, remove the.Iiquid and there's our type right there.
Of course, we need to add that to our order here so I'm going to add
comma and then I'm going to put newsletter.
I'm going to hit Save on that.
Now let's go over to our customizer and refresh,
making sure we're on the alternate template,
and here you can see we've got product information and email signup.
Now, remember I said any changes we make here will be
reflected back in our file as well.
You just saw we made an edit here to the file
itself and those changes were reflected in the theme editor.
Well, it works both ways in the sense that if
we change the order of these or add blocks,
it will be reflected in the file as well.
If I hit Save on that,
reordering the email signup above the product information.
This is all broken anyway,
but we'll refresh over here,
and as you can see,
we've now got newsletter first and main second in our order,
and we've also had some default settings being added to our object here.
I'll type newsletter which we had before.
It's now at the top and we've got
some default settings populated in this settings object.
Like I mentioned, we've got two-way data binding here so if I was to change this here,
it would reflect in the customizer.
If I go up to email signup,
you can see all these color schemes,
background one, background too.
I'm going to assume that the ID for the second one is background-2,
so I'm going to change that in the file itself.
Hit Save on that, head back into the customizer
refresh and you'll see that background 2 is now stored.
Then again, I can change that to background 1,
head back here and you'll see that that setting is stored in the file.
The paradigm shift is this.
JSON holds data, whereas.liquid files hold liquid code.
Here you can see that the new system of
templates is having templates as data, not Liquid.
What that allows us to do is make them more dynamic and make it so that we
can edit our section data and section order in the customizer,
allowing us to do that on every template now because we've
got template data stored on the template itself.
Now what we have is data stored in templates rather than Liquid,
and what that allows us to do is have customization on every page,
whereas previously we used to hard-code in
section tags in different parts of the Liquid code to say put the section here.
Now it's all just data and it's a lot more dynamic.
One more thing to note here is the block data,
and I don't recommend trying to do this manually in the file.
Just go straight into your customizer here, Add block.
Let's say, we want to have a heading here,
subscribe to our email.
These are all default settings and putting it in email form.
Let's hit Save on that and let's just have a look at how that affects our JSON object.
Refreshing the page over here,
you'll see that just like it says in the documentation with the blocks and etc.
Let me move this over.
You can see that we have a block ID for the block.
We have the block type which is arbitrary.
It's just whatever your code responds to and then we have
a settings object to store the settings inside that block.
All the documentation is here,
and our documentation can be hard to read for some beginners,
hence, why I'm here providing this tutorial.
But essentially the main points to understand here is that we're storing data,
not Liquid code in our templates when we're using JSON.
This is the way moving forward so that we can have the most amount of flexibility for
our admins to go in here and edit whatever they
want and reorder sections on different templates.
It's been a big frustration of
Shopify users for a long time having a homepage where they can
reorder sections like this feature has been available for a long time on the homepage,
but it hasn't been available on other templates until now,
until JSON templates and this is the technology that enables it.
Of course, you can continue to use Liquid templates if you so choose.
But we have these JSON templates now and you'll start
to see that more commonly as time goes on,
this is the modern way of doing it.
Hence, why I've added this section to the class.
Any questions, obviously, leave them in the comments,
and in the next video,
we'll dive a little deeper into Shopify liquid.