All right guys, welcome back.
In this lesson we're going to talk all about Liquid.
In the previous lessons,
we looked at our theme code and we talked about the structure,
and I showed you that diagram,
but throughout our theme code,
if we go to any of our templates sections or snippets,
we're inevitably going to see some liquid.
Look at this one, for instance.
The product dash template.
We've got lines and lines of Liquid.
You should be familiar with HTML.
You can see here, there's HTML,
but there's plenty of liquid around it as well and there's also liquid inside.
Liquid is like the templating language of your Shopify theme.
It's kind of like a dumb down programming language that,
as it says here, gives you some programming logic that tells a template what to do.
Tags are wrapped in these characters except
for when we're just outputting a simple variable.
Instead of using the percentage sign,
we put out a second curly bracket.
If you're wondering what's the difference between these ones which start and end
with two curly brackets and this one which
starts with a curly bracket and a percentage sign,
this is when we're performing logic,
and this is when we're just outputting a variable to the screen.
This dash here also,
I recently learned that, that removes whitespace.
So,if I just remove this from either side,
it's going to register a new line in
your code and so you're going to get some whitespace.
It doesn't actually affect the logic,
it's still going to work, but you'll see in your output file,
if you don't use these dashes,
that you'll get a lot of whitespace and that might make
your site load slower. Just as a side note.
How are we going to break up this section?
Obviously there's a lot to cover with Liquid.
We're going to talk about variable tags,
theme tags, control flow tags and iteration tags,
in a kind of high level broad way,
and if you want to go deeper into any of these,
inevitably you're going to have to do so the deeper you go into theme development,
this is the place that you'd want to look.
There's also a quick reference called the Shopify Liquid Cheat Sheet.
If I just type in Liquid Cheat Sheet,
I can grab this.
This is the original I believe,
but it's now broken,
so the one that's on the Shopify website,
it's probably going to be better.
Now you can see the cheat sheet,
which basically has all the different options and what they do.
Say for instance, if I just press command-F or Control-F on Windows,
I can now search the page and maybe I want to find the title of a product.
I'm going to type in, products dot title,
and then I can learn more about what it does.
Just simply returns the title of the product.
I was thinking, maybe it's a product name,
search that, that doesn't come up, title.
That's the key word I got to use or maybe I'll go just to product and see
what variables I have available on the product object and then,
I see, that's the one I'm looking for.
The cheat sheet's really valuable.
Some people recommend printing it out and having it on your desktop,
but you've got this link here at all times and
at least you can search if it's in your browser.
I always like to keep the cheat sheet handy,
but luckily, it's only a short Google search away.
Definitely reference this as a quick reference,
and then you've got your Shopify documentation for deeper learnings.
What I'm going to do is start from the bottom up.
I'm going to click on variable tags first,
and let's learn about our variable tags.
As you can see here,
there's a summary and we can go to each of
these different ways of interacting with variables.
The main one is going to be Assign.
If you've done any programming in the past,
you should be familiar with assignment.
In Liquid, we just need to use the word assign,
and then a variable name,
then the equals sign,
and then the value we want to assign to it.
As you can see here, a very basic example,
assign apples to favorite food,
and then when we use the double curly brackets syntax,
we can just output the value of that,
and then your output's going to be this.
If we go into our code,
we can see here a lot of the signs for product, dash, template.
Assigns make it easier for us to say,
for instance, we have a value that we want to use multiple times on the page,
maybe it's a good idea to assign it as a variable
at the top and then you can change it in one place or maybe you
have a very long string like this product dot selected underscore or underscore first,
so on, so forth.
You don't want to have to write that every single time,
so you can put it into a smaller variable name that's perhaps more descriptive.
Here, we have a Case Statement which we'll get to in a sec,
where I'm assigning the value of things based on different cases.
If I take this,
this is obviously where it's being assigned and I search it for other code.
This right here is obviously where it's being outputted.
You may assign variables yourself,
but more likely you'll be using variables that are on objects.
If we go back to our reference,
and we go into our theme cheat sheet,
we can go down and look at
the different objects and what variables are available to them.
So, we have an object for cut,
we have an object for checkout,
object for article, object for address.
So many different objects.
The more obvious ones,
products object right here.
When we're working with the products,
we want to be able to access all of these different variables within a product.
We've got the page object right here.
The great thing about Shopify is it's quite logical in
the sense that if I'm in the page template,
I have access to the page object.
If I'm in the product template,
I have access to the product object.
Just showing you as an example,
we had a look at the page template before.
If I go to this one right here,
you see we're in a page template right now.
We have access to the page object,
and then we can call a variable of the page object right here by going dot title.
You can see here, I haven't assigned a title to page.
There's no assignment in the code itself.
What it's doing is it's looking at the page we're currently on and finding the title,
as we said in our pages admin area.
That's probably more common,
at least in the beginning,
than assigning your own variables,
you're going to be looking at variables that come on the object that you're dealing
with and you're going to either output them or do other operations with them.
That covers "variable tags."
Obviously, there was a few others in there.
Sorry, I'll just go back to it.
You may want to look at "capture",
"increment", "decrement," but "assign" is the main one.
I definitely recommend you go back and read this documentation,
but we're going to breeze through this in this lesson
because it's only one lesson to go over the entirety of Liquid.
All right. So going into our "theme" tag section,
these are things like "include",
"layout" that we saw before, "section",
so anytime we included a "snippet."
If I go to "theme.liquid" we're probably going to see the best example of all of these.
So remember we created this "snippet" earlier that is considered a "theme" tag.
And obviously if we go down,
we've got "sections" and then "layout" was one we used in our "page.about."
We decided to use an alternative "layout" that we set out in our "layout folder", okay?
What other ones do we have here?
We also have "Comment."
So if we want to make a comment in the code,
we can do so using the "comment" tag pretty common in any programming language.
"Include" for "snippets."
We can also send variables to the "snippet."
If I include this snippet name,
it's going to obviously include the content of that,
but then it's also going to give that "snippet" access to variables that I sent to it.
Okay. Also if you're creating a "form" instead of using a standard "form" tag in HTML,
you can use a more intelligent version in Liquid by using the "form" and "endform" tags.
Okay. We're going to breeze over that because we could
get caught up on "forms" for quite a while in itself.
There's a bunch of different "forms" in Shopify.
And if we use this syntax,
we can take advantage of some of the built-in logic of Shopify.
All right. "Layout" we used before.
"Pagination." This is really cool because "pagination" can be a pain in
the ass to program yourself but in Liquid, it's quite simple.
We just need to "wrap"
the thing we want to "paginate" in this "paginate" and "end paginate" tags. All right.
Then we can "paginate" by five or whatever value we want.
"Raw" allows us to put out Liquid in raw form.
I don't know why you would ever need to do that.
"Section" we saw and we can use "style" to output some styles in a actual template.
The reason why you might want to do that is because it allows us to make
live color updates from the theme editor without a full page refresh.
So if you saw before when we were working with our
"customizer" and we edited something and then it came up "live."
Like if we changed a color and right next to it in the preview, it updated instantly.
It's because we're using these "liquid style" tags.
I'm pretty sure if you put in your own "style" tags that aren't Liquid,
so if you just put in the standard HTML ones that look like this,
it won't update automatically,
but it will still work.
It's better just to use this because then you get instant feedback.
"Theme" tags are handy.
They're used throughout your theme.
They're the ones that are more of
the "programming type" ones that you'd see in any programming language.
"Control-flow and Iteration".
Lets go over those right now.
"Control flow" is basically conditionals.
So if you've done any programming before,
you would have seen an "if then" statement.
So right here, it says "if product title equals awesome shoes" then it will output that.
If that's the case, you will get this.
If not, you won't get anything,
unless it's like the opposite of "if."
It's basically the same as "if product title does
not equal awesome shoes" then you get that.
You can also add in an "else if."
If it hits this and it doesn't,
then go this one, and if it matches that, then output this.
But if it doesn't, then you can go to an "else" and then you end the "if."
That's pretty standard in any programming language.
Also a "case" statement.
If you have one variable and you want to
check the value on that for a different variables.
This is a nicer way of writing conditional rather than having to do "if",
"else-if" and on and on and on.
If you want to have multiple conditions,
you can use the keywords "and" and "or"
which is good because it's just standard language.
It's not pipe or other kind of weird characters.
This reads pretty nicely.
"If line_item.grams is greater than 2 thousand and
customer_address.city equals Ottawa" then it'll output this code in-between these tags.
That reads quite nicely.
It just make sense in English reading it.
On the flip side you can use "or."
We'll have a look at a few examples in just a second.
Let's go into "Iteration" tags finally.
This is stuff like loops.
The main one that you're going to see over and over again in liquid is "for."
The language for "for" in liquid is pretty self-explanatory as well.
You're going to loop through every product in "collections.products" and
you're going to grab that particular product object using this word.
This word could be anything you want.
It's just best to use a descriptive word.
For product in "collection.products"
you have access now within that loop cycle to the particular product,
to that particular object,
and then you can do stuff with that.
I know that's vague, but there's a lot of things you can put within here,
but this is a great example of you're going to want
to loop through a collection of products at some time.
This is pretty standard in Liquid and any programming language for that matter.
You can also put an "else" statement within a "for."
You can break the loop if it matches the sonic condition.
You can also skip one cycle of the loop if
something matches a certain condition and you can limit offset,
define a range of different things with "for."
But usually, it's just as simple as this right here,
just cycling through a list of objects and outputting
the same thing for each of those objects in that collection of objects.
Like I said, it probably makes more sense to actually see it.
Let's take a look at some random Liquid code now and see what's going on.
Actually, before we do that,
there is one more thing that we need to look at
with Liquid that is going to trip you up if you don't know,
and that is "filters."
Quickly, we're just going to have a look at "filters" before we dive into the code.
"Filters" is kind of a unique thing to Liquid.
If you're familiar with other programming languages,
usually you would use functions or methods
to get the same result as what a "filter" does in liquid.
Once you get used to "Liquid filters" you'll find that they're actually quite simple
and it's pretty easy to be able to "filter" content that actually makes sense.
Let's look at an example right here.
We've got the product title that we just want to output on the screen.
But now we've got a "filter" that says "upcase."
What that does, is it'll take whatever is here and make it uppercase.
Your output is going to be,
if the product title was "awesome shoes" which it is here,
it's going to create an uppercase version of that and then output that to the screen.
There is, of course, lots of different "filters."
One of them is "remove."
This filter will remove "awesome" from the "product.title" so you'll just get shoes.
You can also "chain" multiple filters together.
You've got "product title" "upcase" and "remove."
We're going to "upcase" the "product.title"
and then after that we're going to remove "awesome" from it.
Then you just get "shoes" in uppercase.
Let's have a look at a few others.
Obviously, we're not going to be able to get through all of them.
Yeah, actually, there are way too many to look at.
Let me have a look at some that we might see often.
"Image" tag is a good one.
We can just put the name of the image and we can grab the "asset URL" of that.
We can also "wrap" that in an "image" tag and so you'll get this,
which is pretty cool.
That's an example where tags really come in handy,
instead of trying to find the address of
this image and then having to put tags around it,
you can literally just define the image name in your assets and then
find the "asset URL" wrap that around that and then find "image" tag,
wrap that around the output of those and you've got this.
You can "chain" a bunch of them.
Sometimes you want to put in a colon and some options.
Other times you just put in the "filter" by itself,
but without going deep into all the different
"filters" that's essentially what's happening when you see a "pipe."
You'll see a piece of "content" then you'll see a "pipe" and then a "filter" name.
If you don't know what's going on,
all you need to do is look it up.If I search this in our cheat sheet.
I can go in here and see it returns the URL of a file in the assets folder of a theme.
Very descriptive, and it shows us a pretty good example right here.
So, that's the final thing.
We've got our tags,
and we talked about objects and filters is also important,
but filters goes quite deep.
Let's dive into the code now and see some examples,
because I think that's where it's going to make the most sense and hit home the most.
Okay, so right here we've got a really basic template.
I like to show the page template,
because it is quite basic,
but we're inevitably going to get ones are a little bit more complicated.
If I go into the product dash template in sections.
You'll see here we've got a bunch of variables that we're assigning.
Then we've got a case statement,and
the case statement is to figure out what we're going to
assign to these variables based on the image size set in our section settings.
Now remember, when we see Section dot settings,
that is set in the schema below.
All right, we're going to dive deeper into sections in the next lesson.
So we're going to have a little bit more exposure to sections,
so you'll learn more a bit about what's going on here and how to use it.
Here we can see a for loop.
And this for loop,
as we can probably tell from just reading it,
it takes the image out of the product images.
For each of them, it does a bunch of stuff amongst just displaying the image.
If you're wondering what all this is,
this is how it does responsive images.
Instead of just doing image SRC,
this is like a New Age HTML thing where we can output a lot
of different images based on the screen size and resolution.
Just a side note for those who aren't familiar with responsive images, okay?
We can see throughout our template,
we're getting just variables that we want to output into various sections of HTML,
and we can see that the loop is ending here.
Now we can see an if tag here.
So if products, dot image sizes, dot size.
That's basically if the length of product images or how many products images there are,
if that is greater than one,
then we do all of this,
and if it's greater than three then we want to enable thumbnails.
So, a lot of logic in here.
You're not going to be able to get your head around it straight
away on something as complex as this.
But, we'll soon see when we work with blocks in a section in the next lesson,
you'll start to see that for-loops, case statements,
if statements they are very common and then not that scary.
It's just in this one,
we're seeing a lot of it all matched together.
Here you can see a filter.
Here's an example of a filter that you're going to see throughout your project,
is the translate one.
This one is a special one because it looks up this variable in our languages file,
and it outputs the text based on what language we're in.
A more common filter,
let's have a look, escape.
Using what I showed you before,
if we wanted to figure out what this filter is doing.
Obviously we're outputting a value,
but we want to see what escape does.
Let's go to our cheat sheet and type in escape.
Here we go, string filters.
Escape. Escapes a string.
That's a bad example because basically what we're doing is,
we're taking the string and we want to actually output the HTML tags.
Let's look for another one.
Another filter.
Here we go, pipe json.
All right, so let's look in here.
We can see general filters.
So, what does the json filter do?
It converts a string into json format.
Again, not the best example because it's a little bit complicated,
but we're taking a piece of string here,
converting it to json and you'll see here that we get this json version of the object.
Let's try and find a more simple filter,
because I don't want to overwhelm you with these crazy filters
and you just think that they're too hard or too complicated.
We can see image URL here.
We're taking the logo that we've set in our section settings.
We're running it through a filter of image URL,
with the argument of one by one.
Let's look up that one in the cheat sheet.
Image URL. Click on this one,
returns the URL of an image,
accepts image size as a parameter.
So, if we put in one by one,
it's going to put in a one-by-one image.
You might be wondering why we're putting one-by-one in.
Well, we're running it through replace again with a dynamic width.
Probably another complicated example,
but we'll try and use some more simple filters in a later video.
Here's one that's a little bit more simple, append.
If we search for append,
it just appends a character to a string.
So, sales append JPEG,
it just adds it to the string.
So, that one's a simple one.
We're just taking this and we're adding an X to the end of it.
That's pretty simple, let's end on that one.
Going back to our documentation,
if you need to review more about liquid,
I definitely recommend you go in and read more.
Probably the way you're going to learn better,
is by going into the code and just trying to figure it out.
Start with the less complicated templates first,
and if you see a filter that you don't recognize,
which is going to be pretty much all of them if you are new to this.
Actually go in, look it up in the cheat sheet, or the documentation.
Sometimes you might need more information.
The cheat sheet is good, because if you click learn more,
it's going to take you to that part of the documentation.
But the cheat sheets a good reference because you've got
everything on one page and you can just search for it.
Obviously, there's a lot on this page and there's a lot in documentation,
we don't have forever to go over every option in liquid.
But I think it's a good idea to do as much as you can when you're developing your theme.
And whenever you come up against something,
look at the cheat sheet, look at the documentation,
and hopefully you can start to get a grasp on what liquid tag you
need or what liquid tags that are already on your project are doing.
So, that's liquid.
In the next section we're going to bring our knowledge of the structure of
our template code and what we've just learned with
liquid to build our own custom section,
and then we're going to include it on a template.
So I'm excited to tie and what we've learned already and show you
the exciting power of sections in the next video. So I'll see you there.