So in this course we learned how to quickly spin up a Shopify development store,
how to edit the code of the debut theme that came with the store and in the process,
we learned how themes work and the options available to us to
customize virtually anything to do with our online store friend.
Now this knowledge alone might be enough to satisfy your basic Shopify needs.
But inevitably, you're going to need to make changes beyond the scope of this course.
Now in the next bonus lesson,
I'm going to introduce you to a much more complex way of developing Shopify themes,
starting almost from scratch.
But before that, I'm going to assume
that the debut theme or any other theme that takes your fancy,
provides a good base for how you want your site to function.
And this is definitely what I recommend to everyone who's developing Shopify themes.
There is a lot of great themes out there and especially when I'm working with clients,
I usually use an existing theme as a starting point.
Doesn't always make sense to re-invent the wheel unless you really need something custom.
And that's why we're going to talk about slate in the bonus lesson.
We're also going to talk, after this lesson about,
how to take your site live.
I've actually put this lesson before, that one,
because once you actually transfer ownership of your store,
you may lose access to it.
Unless the person or the account that you've
transferred ownership to starts on a paying plan.
So if you're ready to get on a paying plan,
you can definitely learn about how to move your site
onto your actual Shopify plan in the next video.
But for now, what I wanted to talk briefly about is how you would
take the next step in learning what you want to do with your Shopify theme next.
So let's just dive into our theme and
talk a little bit about maybe some customizations we would want to make.
Now the first customization that you might want to make is a styling change.
And that is very normal
and that's probably going to happen at some point with your theme.
You might want to change say the margin between this heading and this right here.
So you go into your section and you look for that option in
your customizer and you don't have a option in your customizer to change the margin here.
So you have two choices.
You can either go in and just create the change,
or you can create an option in
your section code to allow yourself to do this in your customizer.
So if it is a styling change and you just want to apply
it to side-wise without making it a customizable option,
what you can do is just throw it in your theme.scss.liquid.
So let's just use that example that I just talked about.
Let's find out what this is.
So we are in the image with text overlay section,
and unfortunately we can't look it up by the template name.
We're going to have to search the folder and find image with text overlay.
So image with text overlay and then in here we can
see where that appears and that name appears
in the schema of this section right here, hero dot liquid.
So this is the section that we're currently looking at.
If we look at it right here,
maybe it's not clear which of these divs actually relate to what we see on the page.
So we might want to inspect and this is something I often do.
Using our development tools,
we can see what that is.
And as you can see here,
it is this div with a class of R-T-E dash setting mega dash subtitle,
mega dash subtitle, dash, dash, large.
So looking into my code here,
I can search for mega subtitle.
I can already see it, but just to be clear.
So we've got mega subtitle,
and mega title. Here we go.
We've got it in a few different places,
but this is the one we're looking for.
So if we wanted to make it a option in the customizer,
what we could do is add an inline style
and set margin top and we would define it maybe as,
so we go into section dot settings and maybe we called it top margin.
Now we'd also want to check if we actually have set the top margin first.
So we'd want to put an if statement around this.
But let's just say we want to change the top margin site-wide.
So we would go into our theme dot S-C-S-S dot liquid,
scroll all the way down.
This is a very big file and let's create a rule for mega dash subtitle.
And in here, we're going to set the margin top to something ridiculous,
just so we can see that it's working.
So I'm going to press save on that.
Check that we haven't made any errors.
Yes, it's updated now and if I refresh this page,
you can see now that we've got this ridiculous margin top that's
affecting any element with a class of mega dash subtitle,
which should hopefully only be
that section within this section or that piece of text within that section.
So I've just removed that.
It's updated our code.
If I refresh the page again, we're back to normal.
So that's one scenario.
Maybe you want to update the styling.
So you can do that with CSS.
Maybe you want to update something that happens with JavaScript.
So I'm not sure how much ajax we have on here.
If I put that up to three,
looks like the debut theme is not heavy on the JavaScript.
I have to click update here when quantity updates.
But this could be a customization option.
Instead of having to click Update,
maybe we want this to update whenever we click on this.
And because this is a live page change,
we would want to do that with JavaScript.
So you would research how to do that and then you would go,
and likely you put it in your theme dot js.
So let's say we want to do that,
how would we word that problem?
Open up a new tab and search in Google,
make quantity update price automatically,
and then of course,
we need to put in what platform we're using; Shopify.
Okay. So there's a bunch of different articles on here.
I haven't actually searched this before,
but this is the process I would go to find the answer.
So this is not the best thread.
You're not always going to find the perfect answer on your first search.
Here we go. Here's something that looks about right.
So judging from my knowledge of JavaScript already, and of course,
this is not a JavaScript course,
so if you do want to get deeper into JavaScript,
I have got a course on JavaScript here on skillshare.com as well.
But you're going to want to set up an event listener here to
check when this changes and then we're going to have to update these parts here,
rather than having it updated when you click the update button,
which you can see here is reloading the whole page.
So that's a customization you might want to do.
Of course, before you customize anything with code,
you should check whether you can actually just customize it using
the inputs that you already have in your theme customizer.
I mean, that's why they're there for you to use without having to dig into your code.
And as a side note,
if you are digging into your code
and you're creating something that you might want to change later,
make it a option in your schema and that way you can
edit it here and flip it around without ever touching the code.
That's one of the reasons why to use this schema at all.
So it could be a styling change,
could be a change you could easily fix with your schema,
could be some dynamic JavaScript stuff.
But it's likely you're going to come up against
something that you don't already know how to do.
Again, as I mentioned in this course,
we only have enough time to do an overview.
So your best places to go find some answers,
if you're okay with reading documentation,
let's go to the Shopify documentation again and go to themes.
Here is where you're going to be able to search for
all the information that Shopify makes available for you to develop themes.
So if we want to learn about sections,
search for sections in the documentation.
Click on Theme sections.
And then you can learn about the schema.
You can learn about including JavaScript style sheets,
rendering section blocks, all sorts of stuff.
So the theme documentation should be your Bible,
should be your textbook on this stuff.
And then also the Shopify cheat sheet,
which we looked at earlier.
So if you go and click the first link,
this is like a summarized version of the documentation,
and were able to use command F or Control F on a Windows to search
for what are the different variables on a particular object like product.
So those are the two main places you might want to look.
Obviously, there's two other courses on Shopify,
on this platform, skillshare.com.
They are a little bit outdated and one's quite basic,
and the other one just goes really advanced really quickly.
So I guess pick your direction with that.
But otherwise, I was actually thinking of creating a start-to-finish Shopify course.
If there's enough interest,
if you guys want to learn that,
definitely let me know in the discussion box below and if you have any issues or
any customizations that you want to do within
Shopify that you are struggling to figure out,
definitely leave it as a comment in the discussion box
below and I'll do my best to point you in the right direction.
So as I mentioned in the next video,
we're going to talk about taking your site live and then in the video after that,
we're going to do a bonus on Slate.
So Slate is if you want to get really serious about
theme development and start from basically scratch, that's where you want to look.
So two more lessons and then we're going to wrap up.
Hope you guys are enjoying the course.
I'll see you in the next video.