All right, so for this lesson,
I've once again closed down those tabs and I've brought us right back to our store.
We also have the tab for our Shopify partners account still open.
What I'm going do in this lesson is show you
how to essentially take your site live or migrate it.
Or get it ready to become a live theme on the internet.
To have users come in,
use the theme on a real store front.
So there's a range of different ways we would do that.
So the first scenario, let's say,
is that this is an existing store.
So Chris's skill share store is a store that's running.
There's orders coming through there's products already in here, customers.
This is a live store.
All right, so we've done our development in a separate theme,
which is not live, which is the way we should do it.
If we're ready for that theme to go live,
all we need to do is click in Actions and then click Publish.
Now if you are working in an existing store,
you want to be careful about the things that you edit,
that aren't the theme itself.
So if you're redeveloping a website and you're adding pages,
those pages are going to be live on the site the moment you create them.
But it's not such a big deal unless you really need those pages to be
private because you're not going to be linking to those pages most likely.
The other thing, navigation.
So you might have to create some new menus.
In your theme you're going to link to those menus.
Those menus are going to be there with
the existing menus that are in the live store all in the same place.
So stuff like blogs, pages, navigation,
and products are in your store itself.
All right, they're not specifically related to the theme,
so we need to be careful with that as well.
So scenario number two,
you're working with a client store,
but you are developing your theme on a development store.
Now you may want to do that for this particular reason that I've just mentioned,
because they have their own products,
blog post pages and navigation already set
up and you want to create something that's completely separate.
So what you're going to want to do is maybe packaged this theme.
So Download it and then Upload it to
the other store and then migrate the other stuff that you want to come across as well,
like products, blog posts, pages, and navigation.
That would be the most time-consuming and manual way to do it.
So usually you would try to avoid that.
So a good mix in between those two scenarios is to develop on an actual store.
But be careful about what you create in the products,
blog posts and pages,
and where possible, maybe hide them or obscure them
or not have them linked to anywhere on your current website.
If they are still in development and not ready to go live,
you want to make sure that they're almost invisible to the public.
But if this was your store and you haven't even gone live yet,
you've developed your theme.
You just hit Publish. As simple as that.
So let's say scenario three,
you only have your partner's account and you've just
developed this store as a development store and now you want
it to be a real store where you can accept orders
and basically become a legit store of its own domain.
Or maybe you want to transfer this store to somebody who's going to do that.
So maybe you developed this for a client and you can transfer
this store to their account so they can start paying for Shopify.
Now they have a duplicate of the store we just created on their own account.
So that's really what development themes are built for.
They're built for us to be able to develop a theme,
get it ready for the client.
Whether that's another person or it might just be us.
Get the theme ready and then it goes over to a paying Shopify plan.
So, a warning before we demo this,
as soon as you do this,
it's going to be transferred over.
There's a likely chance that you will lose access.
In fact, I'm actually pretty sure that once you transfer
this development store off your list of development stores onto a client's plan,
then for as long as they take to actually stop paying for that plan,
neither of you will have access to that site.
So warning, do not migrate or transfer
ownership of a site until somebody is ready to pay for Shopify.
So if [inaudible] out of the way,
let's go through the process.
So I'll actually close down the store and I'll go to the partner count.
Just refresh this because the links actually expire.
So we want to make sure that we have the most recent page.
As you can see here, we've got Chris's skill share store under development stores.
Now to make this a real store,
we want to transfer ownership to somebody.
So right here it warns us what's going to happen and
this dot point right here is the warning I gave just before.
The store cannot be accessed until the new owner selects a plan.
All right, so we're going to go in here.
Right now, we cannot select
any new owner because what we have to do is add a staff account.
So I'm going to click "Add a staff account" and it's going to take us back to our store.
So I'm going to create myself as a staff account, Freelancer.com.
This staff account will have full permissions.
So I'm going to click Send Invite.
I have actually already done this.
So let's see if I can find another email to do this in.
I have a few different emails, luckily.
Now I've sent the invite.
So you can see here the account owner is Chris's skill share store admin,
which is our partner account,
but now we have this stuff account.
So if I go into my inbox,
I can actually accept that invitation.
So let me do that right now.
Here we go ahead, it took little bit.
But now it's here and it's asking me to create a staff account.
So I'm going to create a staff account.
I'm going to have to put in a phone number and a password.
Let me generate a new password with my password management app.
I'm just going to use this same one actually as we used for the store.
Then I'm going to click Create Account.
Now I am logged into the store.
But as you can see here,
my name is Christopher Dodd and not Chris's skill share store.
So same store, different user logged in.
Now I have full permissions to access the store.
I can do whatever I want.
But the issue with this is I'm still on a development store.
So if I want to take this store live,
I am going to have to go back to the partner account.
So getting out of these stores and I'm going to refresh the page we run before.
Now I should have that option to transfer.
So if I go into the Select box now,
I can see Christopher Dodd, okay?
So I can click on Christopher Dodd,
Transfer the store and this is where I will lose access to the whole store.
All right, so you can see here that this Chris's skill share store.
If I go back to development stores,
It's no longer there.
Actually, it's going to go over to manage stores.
Actually, it's right here.
I actually did a test one before.
As you can see, it's inactive.
But if I click Login,
looks like I still might be able to access it.
No, so I can't access it right now.
What's going to happen?
Like it said, in the warning before,
I will have to wait for the account that I transferred it to starts paying for a plan.
Alright? So if I refresh the page
now on that account I was logged into as Christopher Dodd.
We will try and log back into the store.
Fortunately, it's not letting me. This is convenient.
But let me just go back and type this store name in explicitly [inaudible].
Alright, so we've got this.
Be back soon. I'm going to click Sign in.
Maybe it's because I'm logged in in two different accounts.
So I'm just going to open a private window.
Chris's skill share store.
Was it Chris's skill share store?
Yes. Click Sign in here.
Hopefully, it allows us to sign in.
Yes.So now we can sign in with that partner account that we
created and hopefully my password's still saved to the clipboard. No, it's not.
I'm just going to grab that from my text edit.
I have that now. Now it's logging me in.
What you're going to see coming right up at this dot is choose your plan.
So this is why I warned you about doing
this until you're ready to actually start paying for
a plan because there are no other options once you login to that staff account,
than to start paying for a plan.
So you would choose and you would go
through the motions and set up your billing and all that.
So from the perspective of the partner,
so I'm logged in in the partner account here.
It's a managed store that I actually can't log in to or access until this staff account,
the person or the account that's actually going to take the store and go live with it,
chooses a plan, and starts paying for Shopify.
That's what that box is.
But let's just assume the client or yourself or whoever this account is associated with,
chooses a plan and starts paying for it.
Well, now you'll be able to access the store
in your partner account still by clicking login.
So it'll go from like it already has done,
from development stores to manage stores.
Then you can start to manage it as a quote, unquote, Shopify partner.
So this makes total sense if you are developing a store for a client,
you've transferred it to them,
you've told them, start paying for Shopify.
Your site's about to go live. They do this.
Then as you're the developer or the partner working with them,
you can still log in and collaborate and work on their website as well.
So that's how it works with development stores.
Again, like I mentioned,
and we're not going to have access to the store anymore.
Are we?
Yeah, so we have been totally locked out now.
But as I mentioned before,
unfortunately, I can't show you because I'm logged out at the store.
But as I showed you before,
we could just download the theme file itself and then upload it to another side.
If we didn't want to go through this whole transfer ownership part of the whole process.
So there's a few ways of doing it,
but this is essentially how you would take your site live.
Step number one is you need to actually turn that theme live.
Then you need to start paying for a plan if you're not already.
Then you have a fully functioning Shopify store.
So that pretty much concludes the whole process from
spinning up a Shopify store with a default theme,
going in, exploring the code,
creating a custom section,
customizing it as much as you want, and then finally,
transferring it when you're ready to
another account for you to start paying for Shopify and start running your store.
So that's the whole process.
In the next video, we're going to actually show you
a different process, starting with Slate.
So if you're interested in that,
stick around, otherwise, I'll see you in the conclusion.
Thanks so much for watching guys.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.