That pretty much concludes this class on Shopify theme development.
For your class project,
I want you to create your own store and share it with
the rest of the students in the class projects section below.
Of course, don't be concerned if your store is just for
practice as we're all here to learn skills.
Just make sure that you either share the password or remove password protection entirely,
so that other students can view it.
In terms of further learning,
there's a lot of information about the various aspects of
liquid and Shopify themes on the official Shopify website.
Plus, you can access the Partner Academy through
your partner account by clicking on the Education link.
That being said, if you need any tips or guidance,
be sure to leave a comment in the discussion box,
and I'll do my best to point you in the right direction.
Anyway, guys, thanks for watching and I hope to
see you again in some of my other courses.