In the previous video, I mentioned that it's
only the homepage that you can customize and reorder sections on.
That's now no longer the case with Shopify's online store 2.0 updates.
You may notice that my appearance in his video is quite different to the intro,
and that's because this video,
as well as a few others scattered throughout the class,
have been recorded a couple of years after this class was first published.
That being said, these videos should fit pretty seamlessly into the structure of
the class and provide a good complement to the existing videos.
Something you may have noticed is that the theme customizer,
now called the theme editor in most of the videos of this class,
will look quite different to yours.
If you're watching this class in 2021, for instance,
you'll notice that blocks appear in this tree view now,
whereas in most of the videos in this class,
they'll appear like this.
It's important to note that Shopify is constantly changing
the user interface of the theme customizer,
and there's no need for immediate concern as the core fundamentals
of sections and blocks have stayed the same over time.
The big change that theme developers need to be aware of
is something called "JSON templates".
We'll go deeper into JSON templates later in this class,
but for now understand that templates can be of either two types, Liquid or JSON.
This is getting a bit ahead of ourselves here,
but it's important to note as if you choose to use JSON templates over Liquid templates,
you won't be able to use Themekit,
which is what I'll show you in the next video.
Instead, you can use something called Shopify CLI,
which I'll use in the video directly after.
I think it's a good idea to know how to use Themekit.
If you're working with modern themes,
those are the themes that created after June 29,
2021, you may want to skip the next video.