Welcome back everyone. In this video,
we're going to finally dive into our theme code and talk about what's going on.
Let's open up our code editor,
or if you want to follow along in the edit code section of your theme, either is fine.
As I mentioned previously,
I recommend you make all your changes here.
But just for looking at the code,
you can look at it here if you prefer.
I'm just going to look at it in the code editor
because that's where we're going to be editing,
but you'll see here that if I contract all these parent tables,
we've got assets, config, layout,
locales, sections, snippets, and templates.
Templates, snippets, sections, and layout are the main folders of your theme.
That's the ones you're going to be editing to edit the look and feel of your website,
what you'd expect from a theme.
But there's other important supporting folders here;
assets, config , and locales.
In this lesson, we're going to cover those first,
and then we're going to go into the main ones,
break them down in the following two lessons.
To start with assets.
Assets, if you're new to web development,
stuff like images, style sheets, and JavaScript files.
That's really what we have here.
We've got images that we use within the theme,
we can put in here.
We've got JavaScript files.
This one is for when you do gift cards.
We have SCSS files and you can see there's a.liquid at the end there.
The most important one in your assets file would probably be your theme.scss.liquid.
Something that you may not be familiar with is a technology called SAS.
SAS is basically a CSS compiling language.
It basically comes before CSS and allows us to do call things like functions,
and variables, and nesting.
What it does is it compiles or transforms
into regular CSS when we either choose to compile it,
or, and this is the great thing about Shopify,
is that SCSS is compiled for us.
When you see an SCSS file,
you can basically put in whatever CSS you want in there.
CSS is backwards compatible with SCSS,
but this is basically your style sheet of your whole theme.
Now, the reason it's got.liquid on the end of it,
is because we're able to put it in liquid variables.
We're going to go into liquid in a later video,
but I can search for this right here.
You can see here that we're loading in
some SAS variables with variables that are set in our customizer.
We're also going to look at this in a sec in our config.
But settings here, the global settings object,
is what our theme settings is.
If we go back to here,
this is going a bit too deep too quickly,
but we'll get there.
If we go into here,
so we are going to the customizer part of that,
then we go into theme settings.
Here at settings color text,
that's going to be in colors,
and it's probably going to be one of these ones,
probably the body text.
It's essentially putting what selection you have here in
your customizer inside a SAS variable.
Then what you can do instead of calling a specific color,
you can call this.
You can search for usages of that variable.
As you can see here,
this is pretty normal CSS apart from the SAS variables.
If you're not familiar with SAS,
I definitely recommend looking it up.
It's not too complicated to learn if you already know CSS.
If you are overwhelmed by this and you didn't expect
to learn SAS as well as learning Shopify development,
don't worry at all,
you don't have to use SAS.
You can throw in regular CSS in here.
If you want to think of this as your main CSS file,
you can go right ahead and do that.
Don't worry too much about SAS if you're new to it.
But if you are familiar with SAS or you want to learn it,
it's great that Shopify does compile SAS and
allows you to do stuff like I showed you where,
let's see if I can find it again, it's too hard to find,
but basically where you can set a variable in your theme settings to
a variable in your style sheet and then call it throughout your style sheet.
Very cool. The other one is your theme.js.
Now, this could easily be theme.js.liquid,
but with this theme,
it appears that there is no liquid variables that are going to be inserted in this file.
It's just theme.js, and that goes for here as well.
If you're not inserting any liquid into it,
you don't have to put.liquid on the end.
This is going to hold all your themes JavaScript.
If you're not too familiar with JavaScript,
this could get a little gnarly as well.
Best to leave this unless you need to dig into the JavaScript.
Here you've got some other JavaScript libraries.
Lazysizes is something that a lot of Shopify themes
use in order to optimize image sizes on different screens.
Again, you don't need to worry too much about what's going on in here.
What you do need to know is that the assets folder is there,
and that's where you find your style sheet,
which you'll likely be editing,
and your JavaScript file.
Moving on, we've got another folder here called config.
Config is interesting because you know how we talked about how
that color text was set in your customizer, in settings.colortext.
Well, you can actually look up that value in your setting_data.
If we were to do that, find out what it's calling color text.
If I copy that and I go into our data,
I can actually find where that is set.
Here, you can see there's thirteen of them.
Let's have a look.
Current. Here on current,
which is what we're using right now,
you can see the color text is set to this specific value.
But if we were to go in and change it here,
it's going to update in that theme settings_data.json.
All the data in Shopify are setup in json format,
so that's J-S-O-N. Again, if you're new to web development,
that might be something that you're not familiar with,
but it's pretty simple,
you nest within these curly brackets.
Say for instance, you wanted to get to current.colortext,
go into current, go into color text,
and there you have it.
Pretty simple stuff.
In settings_schema, that is the layer that sits outside of what data you have in here.
You have the value for color text here,
but in your schema,
you set that as a value that users can edit within the customizer.
As you can see here, settings, Id, color_text,
this is what sets it up as a customizer option,
and the type is a color selection.
To show you, if we were to delete this altogether,
this option, you'll see that it doesn't even show up in the customizer anymore.
Press save on that.
I'll look at theme watch.
By the way, if you made any errors,
it should come up here.
Definitely keep an eye on this.
If there's any errors,
it actually won't compile and send up to the store.
But if I want to refresh the editor here and head into my theme settings,
go into colors, you can see that color is gone,
and it wasn't actually the body text, it was the one above it.
I can't remember what that one was called,
but if we bring this back,
you can see the label was headings and links.
If I save that,
which I've done, it's going to re-upload again.
Refresh the page, theme,
settings, colors, and there you go,
that option is there again.
This is a first introduction to schemas for us.
We basically got a giant schema that sits on top
of the whole theme with a bunch of different settings,
and this mirrors what we have in our theme settings.
This is like the developer backend JSON representation of all the data we have in here.
I could even change it here,
and it will update over here in our actual theme.
Or I can change it here,
and that will update in our theme here.
Both are tied together.
Now, when I deleted this before and I brought it back,
you'll notice that it still has that value.
Now, that probably is the default value that's set here.
But even if it wasn't,
even if there was no default value,
the data still saves.
If you go into your schema and delete something like we did,
it doesn't actually delete the data as well,
and maybe you want to delete that.
But usually when you're doing theme development,
this is specific to the store and you don't necessarily want to edit this stuff.
I would generally leave this stuff alone.
It does come in handy when you're maybe
migrating a store and you've made some changes to settings,
you may want to copy those settings that are
all listed out here when you make those changes.
If that was a bit overwhelming or it went a bit over the head,
don't worry too much.
The main reason to know about this stuff is,
say for instance, if you wanted to create your own setting.
If you wanted to create your own setting,
you could come in here,
maybe you want to create another color text type.
You could just throw that in there,
rename the ID, change the label,
and then suddenly you would have that in
your list of options here and then within your code,
you could reference it just like we had in our example here.
You can reference that new variable that you set anywhere within your template.
That's the real benefit of having the schema here to edit.
You can create theme settings from this file and then this one just stores your data.
You probably shouldn't need to change anything
here unless you wanted to do a migration and
you didn't want to have to go through and update
all these different values yourself through the Customizer.
Final one and then we'll move on to the actual like layout files is Locales.
In Locales, it's basically your languages.
If we go back into our online store and in the theme section,
click on actions and edit languages,
we can see a user interface for us to change all the language options.
Now what are these language options?
Well, if we look through our code,
so let's just go into,
let's just choose header and we can see here a bunch of them already.
We can see { layout.
navigation.search} and then we can see this pipe symbol here with a'
T.' The 'T' basically says, filter by language.
Why that's important is,
instead of hard-coding in values here,
we can set them up in languages and then we can translate them.
Hopefully this will make sense,
I might provide an example later in the class,
but let's look at a more obvious one,
just for demonstration purposes.
A common one is Cart language.
If I click on I'm going to do it with my customer, I might as well do it here.
If I go into here and I see your cart on the cot template.
Let me go into templates,
cart and it links directly to a section called cart template.
I'm going to go into that section.
If I try and find your cart, it's not there,
I can't find it and the reason why is because your cart is set in the language settings,
so you see here your cart.
If we wanted to change that label,
we could go in here,
find where the language variables come across.
I think it's this one { cart.
General. Title}. Let's just go in and change that.
I'm going to get rid of that liquid tag and just put in,> this is the cart<.
I'm going to save that,
check that everything's working fine with theme kit and then [inaudible].
Let me just click on it from over here,
making sure we're on the correct theme.
It's not that one,
so we've obviously edited the wrong one,
but I can actually find what it's [inaudible] in here.
This is the English language file and we're running English at
the moment as you can see and if I was to go to find title.
Let me just look for cart and they'll have general title, your cart.
I need to find that cart general title.
Some product title, sorry,
there's a few uses of the word title in here.
It appears we were editing the right one,
but we just don't have any items in
our cart that's why this header is not actually showing up.
Let's just add something to our cart to demonstrate this,
so we don't have whole products showing on a homepage yet,
but we can go to the old collection.
Let's just add this to our cart.
Now we're in our cart page and as you can see,
the text we put in,
this is the cart is showing.
We can obviously cart code values into our project right here.
Just to show this is the cart cart to make it clear,
like I am editing this particular page.
I am editing it right here,
we don't want to do that and the reason why is,
if we change to say, for instance,
German and we offer this website in German as well and we want to have
certain language that is easily translated
into that language to come through and be in that language,
is going to come up with this is cart cart while everything else has been translated.
That's why we use languages.
If say for instance and you may not care about other languages,
may be you are only advertising to the one market.
Maybe we don't care at all about languages,
but even still, it's a best practice to use these variables.
I'll go into here and Instead of changing that in the code here,
I'm going to update the variable.
Instead of your cart,
put in, this is cart cart.
I am just making it really obvious that we're changing it.
Because nobody would say this is cart cart, quite obviously.
If we refresh the page it will come up with this is cart cart.
Essentially the same result,
but just a better practice to have all of these common words in a file in your locales,
then calling that variable within your template.
You'll see here we using a lot of standard language and
it might trip you up a little bit if you didn't know
about these language files because you might go in and be like,
well, I want to change this text.
Let's refresh it again,
back to your cart.
You know, it might trip you up if you want to go on, well,
I want to change that word in my Shopify theme.
Let me search for your cart in cart template.
What the hell, I can't find it.
Like, how am I going to change this?
That's why we need to talk about
language variables because if you want to change something like that,
you're going to have to change it in here.
All hard-coded, as I said,
hard coding is not best practice.
If you want to change language like that,
that standard across the theme,
change it in here and if you ever in future,
when I translate it into a different language,
you've got these other files here.
You can see cart general title and this is what it is in English.
If we go into this which I believe is German,
you can go cart general title and
that value on a German [inaudible] is going to be this word instead,
which I won't even try to pronounce because it looks hard and I don't speak German.
That's locales, that's config and that's assets.
Maybe I rushed a bit through this because there is a lot to cover with Shopify themes,
but essentially, this is where you store variables related to language.
This is where you store a schema data or like
General Settings data and this is where you
define what options are available in your schema,
which translate directly to your Customizer.
Finally, to review assets.
Assets is where you put your style sheet,
you JavaScript file and any images or other files that you
need to call in Frontend assets that will help your store run.
But again, you shouldn't have to edit any of these, it's just theme.
SCSS. liquid which is the most important one because
inevitably you're going to want to change some CSS on your page.
You can do that using liquid,
you can do that using SAS.
But you can also just put in plain old CSS that'll work to,
all of those options are available to you.
In the next video, I'm excited to get into the other parts of your theme template.
I look forward to seeing you in the next video.