To set us up for the next two lessons on editing our theme code,
I have closed down a bunch of tabs and now I just have my store,
my partner account and this diagram that
I've prepare to break down what's happening with our theme.
Now, this might look nully,
but it should provide a good overview of how it all works.
Essentially, we've got these colored boxes and these
represent rather the four major sections that we're going to be talking about.
If we go back into our code,
sections, snippets, templates, and layout.
At the very top, this is the entry point.
Anyone entering our website,
they're going to get the layout.
Then within the layout,
you might have snippets which is why you've got this line going down here.
You might have sections in fact,
you're very likely to have sections.
Inside the content for layout,
which is in the middle of your layout,
you'll get a template.
These lines show the flow of the templating structure.
At the bottom you have sections here,
then sections flow into this template,
but they also can flow into layout they also can flow into content for index.
Then you have this template which flows into layout.
So layout sits at the top.
Trying to find another word other than layout,
but it's basically the structure that sits at the top of each page.
Then you get served the template and then sections
are really cool dynamic pieces of code,
dynamic sections that we can put into our homepage,
throw into our layout,
throw into our template,
and then snippets are just reusable bits of code that we can basically throw in anyway.
Now I've got these clouds in here as well.
I made it a cloud because it's dynamic content.
We can't actually edit a theme template for header content or content of index.
It links to different parts of your theme with this double line.
The double line is just to signify a dynamic link.
In your layout, it's linking to header content,
which because it's denoted with a Cloud is
communicating that we can't actually edit this specifically,
but it's an out layer.
The same for content for index.
Actually this line here probably shouldn't be here.
This is only on a specific template, the homepage.
So I might delete that link.
But as you'll soon see,
and something I touched on briefly is that content for index is
the thing that sits on your homepage and you can add in sections dynamically.
This diagram might look a bit nully at first,
but after these two lessons hopefully the relationship
between all these parts should make pretty clear sense.
In this video we're going to talk about layouts and we're going to talk about templates,
and then we're going to break it up so in the next lesson
we talk about sections and snippets.
Let's start at the entry point.
Let's just go preview our theme.
When the user comes to our store,
they're presented with this which is a mixture of all we have in here.
First of all, it's going to hit a layout file.
That's why layout, if we go back to the diagram, sits at the top.
We're going to go into our layout photo.
Usually you only have one layout and it's theme.liquid.
As you'll see in this video,
we're able to create our own layouts,
but the standard layout is theme.liquid.
If you haven't set a custom layout,
it's going to go to theme.liquid.
Let's just assume that you haven't set a custom layout.
It's going to go theme.liquid.
This is the code that will generate what you see here.
That goes for not just the homepage,
it goes for pretty much every page that doesn't have an alternative layout.
This is the skin that will run on every page of your website.
But as we'll see, there's some dynamic bits of content in here.
We've got liquid tags as you can see here,
which are denoted by the two curly brackets ending into curly brackets.
There's another one that you might see that has instead of two curly brackets,
curly brackets and a, there we go.
Curly brackets, percentage sign,
and a dash to eliminate white space,
we're going to go into liquid and how it works in a later video.
But I just wanted to go through and let's see
where this page links to other parts in our theme.
We have got some liquid logic here.
Don't worry about that too much.
What I'm looking for is this first tag content for header.
Basically by putting content for header here just before the closing head tag,
what it's saying is take whatever we have and put it right here.
Again, seemingly can't edit it,
it might be hard to understand what actually goes in here,
and that's why I've written this box here.
This is according to the Shopify documentation,
that content for head of variable must be placed between the opening and closing tags.
It inserts the necessary Shopify scripts into the head,
which includes scripts for Google Analytics,
Shopify analytics for Shopify apps,
and more editable in preferences.
That answers the question of where would I go to edit that?
So I can go in, click on Preferences.
So things like Google Analytics code.
If I had some Google Analytics code,
I would paste it in here.
That would dynamically go into content for header.
Then with this liquid tag,
basically controlling where it goes in our liquid layout.
But it's something that you shouldn't really mess with.
I'm just letting you know that that's where it inserts.
It doesn't really make sense to move it because it needs to be in that head tag.
Going down the page,
we can see this word include and include followed by a string here.
What that's doing is including a snippet.
If I go into My Snippets folder we're not going to be covering snippets in this video,
but you can see if I look for Icon Search going down,
there's a lot of different icons here.
Right there it is. It's just an SVG file,
but I can basically can include it anywhere I want on my whole theme.
Going back to theme.liquid.
Let me scroll down again by putting in include and then the name of the snippet.
Going back to the diagram,
you can see that we can include snippets anywhere in our theme code,
layout, template or sections.
That's why the line links to those three.
If we scroll down the page,
we can see another keyword here, which is section.
Just like include, we can bring in the header section by using the section word.
So Include to bring in a snippet,
section to bring in a section.
If we go into our sections folder,
there should be a file called header.liquid.
Remember we don't have to use the.liquid to call a section snippet or template,
we just put in the word without the.liquid.
Liquid knows what you're trying to do.
As you can see, we've got another section here, and in between,
we've got this other dynamic liquid tag called content for layout.
Going back to my diagram here,
we can read what content for layout is.
The content for layout variable must be placed between the opening and closing body tag.
It outputs dynamic content generated by all the other templates.
Index.liquid, product.liquid and so on.
As you can see, I've got this box in-between layout and template.
That's because this is where the template comes in.
If we go into our templates here,
the code in these templates will be loaded into here.
You might be wondering, well how do we know which page to load in here?
The answer is, it depends on the URL that you're in.
If I'm on here and I go to collections.all,
like we have beforehand.
I'm still on the theme layout.
I'm still on this layout file.
But then once I hit content for layout,
it sees that I'm in a collections page.
Load up the collection template.
We're in the collection template right now.
As you see, there's pretty much nothing in here apart from a section.
We'll get into more details or more reasons to why that is in the next video.
But essentially the main reason why,
and if we dig into this section briefly,
is because we want to make the whole section customizable using a schema.
We can set a bunch of options here,
and then we can use that within the code.
If you're ever curious as to why you would have
a template file and then suddenly you have it linked to just a section,
why is that the case?
That's why. Because in our templates we don't have a schema to edit anything.
As I showed you before,
if we go into the customizer,
so I'm going to get out of preferences and I'm going to click customize on our theme.
I'm going to go to the collection page.
You can see here that we've got this section block here.
So we're able to edit settings within this collection.
We can also add in a random section if we wanted to,
which we'll do just in a sec,
or we can remove this completely and there's no content in the template file.
But just to demonstrate if I was to get rid of
this section and just maybe put a random div.
Maybe I still bring in the collection content because we're in the template here.
So I can bring in a collection.
I'm not going to, I'm just going to type in hello.
Just to demonstrate.
Theme watch is running fine.
I'm going to preview the theme so you don't need to leave the customizer.
Go to that page again, collections.all.
Now you can see that we've got just Hello.
You're Okay, that makes sense,
but now if we go into collection pages in our customizer,
you'll see that it just has collection content.
There's no little section here for us to go in and edit settings.
Hopefully that makes it a bit more clear why it just links directly to a section.
It gives us the ability to go into
a tab right here and not just have our content in there,
but also have options to edit it from within here as well.
That pretty much covers the layout.
If we go back to liquid.
You can read it here in the code itself or you can have a look at the diagram,
but main liquid tags you've got is header content,
content for layout over here
and any snippets or sections you want to include in your layout as well.
I am going to demonstrate alternative layouts in just a sec,
but let's talk more about templates.
We showed a quick example of the collection page,
but what I want to do is create a template for About page.
Let's go into our templates here and as you can see,
we've got page, we've got password, products, search.
Maybe I want to create a new page.
Let me go into my back end here,
click in pages, add a page and this should look pretty familiar.
It's pretty similar to products,
it's just title and content.
I'm going to put in About Us and I'm going to
generate some Lorem Ipsum just to fill it up.
I'm just going to search for a random Lorem Ipsum generator,
just grab a bunch of dummy text to put in there.
I'm going to click Save and what I want you to notice here,
because it is a page,
we've got the page template suffix, that's by default.
If we go and click on View page,
you can see here that once again,
it's loading our theme layout,
which is going to happen on every page unless we specify otherwise and
then because it's a page, it's loading this.
Then within here, we have our dynamic content,
which we just set up in our back end here,
a title and content.
You can see here in between the h1 tags is title and in our div here is content.
We could change this up, we could structure this however you want it.
Maybe we want to take this here and the first line we want to say,
this is the page for Save
that and we go back to
here and you can see this is the page for About Us and then it goes on with the content.
Not very practical, but you can see here,
we can take those two variables and we can use them however we want,
this is totally customizable.
But I want to show you a more practical example,
and that is to be able to include a section in this template.
For that, I'm going to create my own custom template.
I can do that by going, New File,
and here's how you would create an alternate page template.
You do page, then you'd place a dot after that,
and then you put in the name of your alternate.
Mine is going to be About and then of course you need to end with.liquid.
If a page about, I'm going to copy the exact same content as page,
but I'm going make one change and that is,
I want to bring in a map section.
If we look in our sections here,
we have this section called map.
As I'll show you in a later video,
sections are great because we can pull them into
any area of our website through templates.
I'm going to add in a section like we saw before,
the section map, press Save and see if that worked.
Now there's going to be a two-step process to
changing this page into the About Us template.
This is what you would expect the behavior to be.
You would expect to be able to go in here and just change your About.
You've got it in your theme code.
You should be able to go in here and update that template suffix.
Well, the gotcha here and something you're just going to
have to remember to do if you ever get caught on this step,
is the alternate template needs to actually be on the live theme as well.
This is not a problem, it's just an extra step.
If we go into our current theme,
click on actions, click on edit code.
We can create a template of the same name and it doesn't have to have the same content.
It just has to have the same name so that we can select it from within that admin area.
I know this sounds silly,
but this is what you have to do within Shopify,
because this page menu here,
this is for everything.
This doesn't change the pages,
the blog posts you have on your site based on what theme you have.
That answers the question why it's not related to the theme you
have published because it's going to pull the templates from the published theme.
Again, I think it should have all the templates that are available in all the themes,
but that's just not how Shopify works.
Anyways, just a little bit of a gotcha and the way we can
get around that is create the same thing,
but we use this user interface here on
the Shopify website and what we can do
is just choose page and the alternate is called about,
and then Shopify are going to create it with the correct name, page.about.liquid.
Once that's done, we can refresh the page and we can
come down here to template suffix and we have that page.about.
I'm going to click on that, click Save.
Now, when we go back to our About Us page,
we will have a map section underneath.
Look at that, isn't that great?
Now, what we will also have because we want to be able to customize this.
Unfortunately, we can't customize the section within
this page from within our pages because we can only edit title and content,
but what we can do is find this template in our theme customizer by clicking here.
Unfortunately it's not there,
we're just going to refresh the page.
Click there again and as you can see,
we've got this new section here for pages with About Us.
Now we can go in and we see this section here,
we can actually go in and edit the section.
Store is the Skillshare store or whatever you want to call it on Fake St. Toronto,
Canada and you can add an image there or whatever you want do.
That is a great example of maybe you want to insert a section in a certain page.
You don't want it to happen in all pages so you create an alternative template
and then you're able to call that alternate template on any page.
Now remember, I said that I would talk about
alternative layouts as well because what's the point of having
this layout file here in a folder if you aren't able to change the layout?
The way we do that is also in the page template.
We got to use a little bit of liquid at the start of the template.
We're going to use a little bit of liquid at the start of
our template to call the layout that we want to use.
Like I said, by default it's theme.liquid,
but we can choose another one if we so choose.
What I'm going to do is I can do this in either order.
This is probably the backwards order of doing it,
but what I can do is I can write the tag first and then create the layout.
I'm going to call this naked,
and the reason why is I'm going to remove a bunch
of stuff from the standard theme.liquid.
I'm going to create a duplicate of that and instead of theme.liquid,
I'm going to call it
naked.liquid and I'm going
to remove the header and footer.
Don't ask me why I'm doing that.
I'm just doing it for demonstration purposes.
If I hit Save on that,
if I go back here, no errors and
I refresh the page because remember we're already using this template.
You'll see that the header and footer have disappeared and that's because I have
signaled this particular template to use the layout of naked.
Right here we set an alternative layout based off the theme.liquid,
which is the standard layout.
Remove the header and footer from that.
Now we're able to update the layout on this particular template.
That's basically the major points with theme templates and theme layouts.
Finishing on the diagram here,
hopefully this diagram starts to make a bit more sense now.
We've got the header content that comes
from preferences and other areas coming into our layout.
We have the content for layout,
which brings in the template and then we can stick sections in
either the template or the layout and we can also stick snippets in wherever.
In the next video, we're going to go further down the chain here,
talk about sections and snippets.
Snippets are quite simple,
but sections are really exciting and powerful.
I think we can cover both of them in the next video.
I'm excited to show you that and wrap up this section on the theme code.
I'll see you in the next video.