To create our database table, let's go ahead and open up MySQL Workbench.
I wanted to do it from a fresh start-up,
so in case you'd forgot how to navigate to that workbench.
I'm going to go down to my Start button and click MySQL Workbench.
And it will pull up this workspace desktop and inside of here you'll have one
called local instance that doesn't really look like a button,
but you can click on it and it will actually launch you into that workbench.
Once we're inside of the workbench,
just for good measure and in case you hadn't set yours before,
right click on your ride_tracker schema and say set as default,
and you'll know it's default if the name of that schema is bolded,
such as mine under ride_tracker.
From here we can right click on the Table item
underneath ride_tracker and say Create Table.
And this is going to bring up this editor for us.
First let's start by naming our Table Name ride.
And then underneath here we can start adding columns.
I'm going to add three columns.
The first one is id,
and we'll go ahead and say that this is a primary
key and it's auto incrementing,
so they don't do a great job of telling you what these
checkboxes are without hovering over them.
So we're going to check the primary key column,
the not null column, and the auto incrementing field or AI column.
The next column we want to add is the name of our ride.
So we'll call this name and it's defaulting to a VARCHAR,
so we can go ahead and edit the size of that and say that
we want to do a VARCHAR to a size 100 and we'll also
select that as being not null.
Then we're going to add a third column and we'll call this one duration,
it's just the duration of what our ride is,
and we'll make this one an INT.
We can use the dropdown, choose INT,
and then we'll also set that one as not null.
Now that we have everything defined in here,
we can go ahead and click the Apply button and it
will create this schema for us,
and really all this does is take that schema and execute it behind the scenes,
but we can go ahead and click the Apply button right here.
You'll see a successful message saying that that script was
ran and it was applied to our database.
We can go ahead and click Finish now.
Now we can close that Table editor and you'll notice
underneath here that we have a ride table and you can go
inspect the columns if you want to.
You can also go ahead and do a select statement
here using a select * if you want,
but suffice it to say your table was now created inside your MySQL instance.
Now let's go ahead and start writing the code to do our unit test and call our controller.