To create our test, I want to go ahead and open up the
unit test that we have underneath our src/test/java
directory called RestControllerTest.
Currently we have our GetRides test that we had in here from before.
I'm going to go ahead and just add another one inside of here.
So, I'm going to start off by just grabbing this code and
copying it in here and paste it for us to have a starting
point for our testCreateRide method.
I want to walk you through the RestTemplate for doing a put to here so you
can see the object that we're passing in so you more conceptually
understand the whole test that we're trying to write.
So the first thing I'm going to do is, just like our other one,
create an instance of the RestTemplate here.
The difference this time is that we're going to create an instance of a ride.
So we're going to say Ride ride = new Ride, and we're just going to use the
default no arguments constructor, and then we're going to go ahead and say
ride.setName, and we'll call this the Bobsled Trail Ride.
And then we also want to set a duration,
so we'll say ride.setDuration, and we'll say that it took us 35
minutes to do. So I just put a 35 in there.
Now, we can call the RestTemplate's put method.
So we'll say restTemplate and we just want to put, and we're
going to enter in our URL. So we'll put in a string here and say
http://localhost:8080/ride_tracker.
Now if you named your project something different,
you'll want to change this context, of course, and
then we'll call the ride controller.
Then the next thing we're going to do is pass in our ride object
and the put will automatically call that for us.
Now we currently don't have this endpoint in there, we need to
go ahead and modify our controller to do so.
So I'm going to go ahead and open up our RideController.
And right now it's quite simple,
we just go ahead and have our get for all of the rides in there.
I'm going to paste in this code that I have written previously
just so you don't need to watch me type all of this in, and
we'll walk through what it does.
So, I have a request mapping for /ride and a method type of PUT, and we
go ahead and we call this and it takes a request body in, which is the
object that we passed in from our test.
Currently this just returns null, but it's going to
eventually call our service and return an object.
So let's save this. To test this, we can go ahead and start our server back up,
make sure that there's no deployment errors there, everything looks fine, and
we can go into our test that we've now created and right‑click on
testCreateRide and say Run As, JUnit Test, and we should see that the server
then gets the call for deploying it and we have our unit test that also gets
ran. And we can check that by looking at the tab for the unit test and see that
it came back green.
Let's go ahead and now write the code to talk to our service tier that will eventually call our repository now.