Hello everyone and welcome to the H.T. mile level one section of the course.
It's time to start learning about h Timo this section of the Course is going to start off just by covering
the very basics of H Tim L and female stands for hypertext markup language.
It's one of the most basic building blocks of the web and every Web site will need it in some form or
another.
It's her first fundamental step in understanding how to actually build a web application later on in
future sections of the course.
We're going to be learning about other technologies such as CSSA style reached him hymnal and javascript
to add a functionality.
Then in future sections such as the Python and jingoes sections of the course we're going to learn how
to add Gengel template tags connect it with Python and needs HTML to dynamically generate content based
off a user's interaction with the Web site.
However all of that is still quite a bit away.
And when you just start off with the very basic fundamentals of Timo and that's level 1 and level 1
we're going to be discussing the following topics.
HTL basics tagging the faced him out how to create lists in each T.M. what divs and spans are and then
attributes.
NH Tim L Okay one quick final note.
Remember as you code along with the course you can always reference the corresponding lecture notes.
Check your code.
Let's get started.
I'll see you in the next lecture where we cover each HTML basics.