Hello everyone and welcome to this quick advance side lecture where we talk about the Gengel de-bug
toolbar.
We've already seen how to manually debug Django at the end of our clone projects but maybe there's a
better way that we can try to get a little more help and luckily there is it's called the Django de-bug
toolbar and it's a favorite tool for jangles developers to help them try to catch where errors are happening
inside of their project.
The jingle toolbar gives useful panel tools about your project that can help you clarify why certain
behavior is occurring or happening.
It won't be able to pinpoint the exact source of a bug or help you figure out how to actually change
the syntax.
It really just contains useful information that you may find helpful to actually find and help fix the
bugs.
So this with the toolbar actually looks like we'll actually play around for a lot more in the next lecture.
But essentially you see on the right hand side this toolbar and there's various panels they can click
on and then it gives you information about your website.
Now keep in mind this may or may not fit with your workflow style but it is helpful enough that many
developers that work of Django keep it up to date of their open source contributions so it may not work
for you but it's a very popular tool for developers in general which is why it's worth talking about
in order to get the debug toolbar in your virtual environment.
Go to your command line and type Pipp install Shingo dasht debug cache toolbar and depending on how
you actually install Django and your version you may even already have installed but again go to a virtual
environment and do that Pipp install command OK in the next lecture.
What we're going to do is briefly go over the panels and what information they show you.
Then you can decide if it's a good fit for your workflow.
A lot of the projects in this course are small enough where the toolbar may not be a deciding factor
in whether or not use it though once you become a developer either as part of a larger company or you
start develop your own really large projects.
The toolbar may be a good choice for your workflow.
OK I'll see you at the next lecture.