Welcome to your next social clone project in this project we're going to be taking bits and pieces from
other social sites to build our own platform and our site is basically going to be a social outer space
fan community site.
So people who are big fans of things that do have outer space can come here and be part of the site
this clone project also takes full advantage of some of jingoes onepoint elevons newest features such
as loggin view and log out view.
So the basic idea of the site is that users can create groups on various topics that have to do with
outer space things like Space X NASA Pluto etc..
They can then create posts inside those groups and they can also leave and join other groups.
Let's discuss a few of the key features.
So as I mentioned there are groups in this web site similar to things like sublets except for just calling
them groups.
There's also multiple users and authorisations just like any social media site or a social network site.
There's also posts inside the group similar to posting a tweet.
We're also going to be linking user profiles with an at symbol.
So if you ever see a user name somewhere there's a little symbol attached to it you can click on that
symbol and then go straight to their profile.
And there's also multiple applications.
Unlike the previous clone project.
Let's take a quick peek at the actual project and remember you can download the zip file in this lecture
as a resource which has all the code that we're going to be needing for this project.
Let's jump to the browser and check out the project.
All right.
This is what the Web site actually looks like it's called Star social and let's say it's the best community
for all things on outer space.
And one of the funny little features of it is with javascript and CSSA we can't create stars and let
him bounce around etc..
So the main idea is that we could sign up as a new user and then we get this sign up page.
So we have at this plaining so we'll call this space fan.
One is our display name.
Give this an email address of hello at gmail and then we'll say test password and we need to confirm
our password so we'll say test password.
I didn't mess that up.
There we go.
And now let's log in.
So I'll a space fan 1 and lie test password log in and it says Now I'm logged in.
Go to groups saw select go to groups and I can see there's some groups already created here for me so
I can create a new group and it will tell me it's create a new group.
So we'll give this group something that says like NASA rocks and then we'll say people who like NASA
will create that group so we can then join the group.
So it has no members right now so we'll join the group and now we can see has a member count of 1.
So there's no posts in this group yet.
Now you notice that we have a post button a group button and a create group button will be on groups.
And now you can see in the group list we have my new group Nassor rocks and then the second group so
we can end up doing is posting to any of these if I click on post it allows me to do and you message
so I'll say first post in NASA exclamation point and then I'll choose this Nassor rocks group hit post
and then I can see here I'm not superzoom then but hopefully you can see this.
I'll zoom in a little more that I have the first post in Assa space fan and I can see space fan once
I had this little symbol I have the time I post it.
And NASA rocks.
And if I hit on a space fan 1 there is my post history at space fan 1 and it's basically since I only
have one post.
There it is.
And I can also delete posts so I can hit delete here.
It says Are you sure you want to delete this post.
I can either confirm to delete or cancel it so I'll just confirm that delete etc now takes me back to
just a list of all the posts currently available for me.
So again it groups.
I can see members I can join other groups etc..
All right there's a lot to this project even though it seems pretty simple on the back and there's a
lot going on but it's going to feel like a natural extension of our blog project.
So let's discuss various things to know about this project and how to approach it.
A hop back to the presentation slides now so as I previously mentioned you can download the zip files
in this lecture for all of the code and this project workflow will also be a bit different than the
previous project.
We're going to be focusing on a more realistic development process where we build out applications one
by one versus the previous project where we kind of built all the views first and then all the templates
etc. We're actually going to focus on applications one at a time.
And this approach we take here is definitely going to be more realistic but by its nature it's also
going to contain a lot more debugging especially because some applications depend on other applications.
And while the blogging isn't very fun when first learning a concept by now you've learned enough that
you feel really comfortable enough to debug often so keep that in mind as you approach these videos
you're going to see us debugging a lot.
But it's definitely part of a realistic development process.
OK.
Another note is that we're also going to be using some outside libraries to keep this in mind.
If you happen to just immediately run the file that's in the resource for this lecture.
If you don't have the right modules installed you may get something that says No module names etc..
Then these can be easily fixed of just a simple Pipp install in your environment or in your virtual
environment and we'll do this in the video lectures as well as you run into those modules so keep that
in mind.
If you get something that says maybe no module named bootstrap theory then you may have to install bootstrap
3 OK.
This project is also specifically designed to feel like an extension of the previous block clone project.
And what I really want to get across here is thinking of social media Web sites as extensions of simple
blogs will really help your understanding as far as building a social media website with Django.
So remember that we created a text blog for a single user really similar to medium dot com if it was
just a simple single user blog site.
Now we're going to try to do is expand this concept of a blog site to an actual social media site by
simply expanding to multiple users.
So let's think of this in some examples.
Instagram.
You could technically think of as just a photo blog with multiple users.
Twitter is literally just a microblog service with Again multiple users.
YouTube is just a video blog service with multiple users.
They'll be full.
However it does take a lot more work than I'm kind of throwing out here to build sites like these especially
at scale but the basic premise is the same.
We can expand the idea of a single blog for a single user attach multiple users to it.
And now we're dealing with a social media network especially if things like Instagram Twitter or YouTube
where they're especially focused on a particular type of post or blog.
OK so these ideas are still there.
More importantly you now have awesome jingle skills and we're going to learn even more.
So let's get started building out our site of Social Network.
Thanks and I'll see it the next lecture.