Hello everyone.
To change a level 5 in this section of the course we're going to be focusing on user authentication.
So far we've only created applications that assume everyone's going to see the same pages.
And this is one of those aspects of Django where there are lots of built in available tools as well
as plenty of external packages that enhance the functionality of user Athens cation.
We're going to be focusing mainly on the built in tools for this particular section of the course and
we'll be talking about users in the user model talking about permissions groups passwords and authentication
and then how to have users log in and log out of your Web site OK.
Let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.