Hello everyone and welcome to the Jay queery section of the course.
Let's briefly break down what Shakeri is and why you would want to use it.
Keep in mind this course is not meant to be a full course on Javascript in any way.
There is a lot more Javascript can do than what we've covered in this course and there are many other
libraries for it such as angular re-act no jazz.
Really this course is not going to cover any of those topics because they are outside the scope of this
course and we won't really need them to build a full web application.
What we do is we learn javascript and Jay query in order to use of Django later on.
So what is Shakeri.
Well Jay queery essentially just the javascript library and its a large single thought just file that
has many pre-built methods and objects that really simplify your workflow.
Specifically when you're interacting with the document object model and making HTP requests through
the use of AJAX which we're going to talk about when we talk about Jing.
Later on previously we've learned how to interact with a Dom using what's known as vanilla javascript
which is another way of saying just plain javascript and we were able to use methods such as document
Dockett element by id and later on we learned about methods such as document query selector when Jacqui
was first created.
The more robust and convenient method such as the query selector inquiry selector all actually didn't
exist in vanilla javascript so J.Crew was created as a way to help simplify interactions with the Dom
in one of its main features is the use of the dollar sign.
So how do we actually get Jey query.
Well you have two options.
One is to link a CD and host that file like we did for we we're using bootstrap and then the other one
is to actually download the database file from Jay cories official Web site and just link to it locally
using a script tag.
So again once you connect to the queries in the script tag and reached him L..
Then you can call the specialized J.A.G. recalls that allow you to interact that Dom and eventually
a few examples of how J.A.G. differs from a village javascript so on top of what a J.Crew call acts
like and on the bottom we have what a vanilla javascript looks like.
Here you can see that we basically replaced the document thok query selector all call in normal javascript.
If a single dollar sign in here.
Both of these Shakeri and vanilla javascript calls are grabbing all the elements that are under a div
tag and hopefully just from this clear example.
You can see they are going to save a lot of typing and a lot of work with the simple dollar sign command
that Shakeri has.
Let's imagine another situation where you actually want to edit the styling of a certain variable.
So here with Jake Query we have some variable called E-L in here we've grabbed E-L and we said that
C Ss border with and then set it to 20 pixels in vanilla javascript.
You would have to call E-L dot style that border with is equal to 20 pixels.
So hopefully I can see now that.
Query basically allows you to just input any property of CSSA any style property directly using that
CSSA method and then as a second argument what you want the change result to be.
And that's a better workflow as far as being more robust.
And then file it.
Show you something that would be a function call with Cheikh query versus vanilla.
So on the bottom here you have vanilla where you are saying is a document in a ready state loading.
If not adding an event listener Dom content loading here Jay query can do this all in one simple line
code.
OK as you can see some situations are helped tremendously by a query.
While others may not really necessitate it due to its massive popularity it's still very important to
understand it because you're going to be running into it a lot in the real world.
And if you didn't know J.A.G. you would end up reading someone else's code and just be flabbergasted
why these dollar sign calls were everywhere.
OK so let's start learning how to interact with the DOM with a query.
I'll see at the next lecture.