Hello everyone and welcome to javascript level on welcome to the first javascript section of the Course.
This section will begin to build our understanding of adding interactive functionality to our Web sites
in javascript support is actually built directly into most modern web browsers.
That means we can run javascript directly into the browser console or as a fool dot javascript that
connects to an HTML file which means there's nothing to download right now javascript is mostly full
programming language meaning I like to mail or C Ss.
It supports things such as raise loops and general logic.
We will briefly cover major programming concepts as we encounter them with javascript eventually we're
going to be showing you how to use javascript to directly change to stem cell or CSSA shown on a page.
Now we're really going to touch on that topic in the document object model or deal M or dom section
of the course to begin with however we're going to be focusing on just the javascript basics all by
itself.
OK so we're going to start off with javascript just straight in the browser console and later on we'll
show you to connect fooled javascript's to an aged him.
File all the code used in this section can be found that JS scripts under the javascript level one folder.
Let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.