Hello everyone and welcome back to how the web works.
And this lecture actually going to be discussing the following ideas.
We'll talk about how the web works what is actually happening when you put a pro into your browser and
how it connects and retrieves the Web site that will also talk about what we mean when we say full stack
and full stack web development.
We'll get a brief overview of the Course technologies that we teach here and also why we chose Shingo
for the course.
Let's get started.
So before we can begin to learn about all the technologies in this course we need to understand how
the web works and what actually constitutes the full stack.
So what actually happens when you're at home and you open up your browser and visit web site.
Let's break down the basic steps you start off by typing your your L into your browser.
So you're home.
You open up your browser and you type in whatever web site you want.
Facebook com google.com etc. then your computer sends this request as a packet which includes the IP
address of the Web site you want the IP address allows servers later on to actually identify what Web
site you're looking for.
And it sends requests through wires or a satellite which eventually links to wires using your internet
service provider.
So if you're at home your request is eventually sent through either copper wires or optic fiber wires
to the server that we're about to reach or if you're on your cell phone it links to a satellite which
links back down to earth which then ended up going to some sort of physical wire.
And at a very very basic level the Internet is basically just wires connecting computers with some sort
of protocol.
So your ISP will then reroute the request the appropriate server location using the IP address as the
guide.
And then once your request reaches the server it can send back the Web site you asking for However a
full web site of content is too big to send back as a single packet of data.
And the way we solve this is the server sends back the Web site split up into many many packets and
the packets come with instructions on how to get back to you and reassemble themselves once they reach
you.
And the packets though actually care how they get to you just the final location.
So all these packets may take different paths to actually get to your computer or back to your cell
phone or whatever browser you are using.
What they really care about is the fastest way to get back to your destination at your home IP address
and then once the packets reach you they're reassembled to show whatever page you were looking for.
All of this moves at close the speed of light.
So it happens very fast.
OK that was a really high level explanation.
But for our purposes it's really all we need to know for now.
Let's continue on by discussing what we mean by the term full stack.
There are two main components of a Web site.
There's the front end of a Web site in the back end of a Web site the front end of a web site is what
you see as a user on the Web site and then the back end is the technology used to actually decide what
to show you on the front end.
For instance let's say you're looking at Facebook dot com.
So what you see the colors the actual content there that's all the front and stuff the back end is what
the sides if you're a user coming in what pictures or content or comments to retrieve from the database
and then show it to you on the front and so let's talk a little bit more about that front and the front
end really revolves around three key technologies.
L CSSA and Javascript.
You will hear about the front end technologies such as Jake queery and bootstrap which we also cover
in this course but those are actually all things built using those previous three H.M.S. SS and Javascript.
Those are really the three core front end technologies that basically every modern web site uses today.
H.T. email is hypertext markup language and every Web site will have HTL.
Its the structure of the page and you can actually view it by right clicking and selecting new page
source.
If you're using the Chrome browser on any Web site so you can open up your browser on this page right
click select View page source and you'll actually see the page Tim L..
For whatever web site you're looking at then there's CSSA which is cascading style sheets.
And C Ss is the actual styling of the Web site colors fonts borders etc. it's all defined by CSX.
And C Ss is not mandatory but almost all sites have it in order to make the Web site look good.
And then finally javascript allows you to add interactivity to the Web site including programming logic
and he said if interactivity uses Javascript in some way.
Otherwise if the site doesn't actually do anything it just displays information.
The site is known as a static web site.
OK so the first half of this course is going to focus on the front end and the front end in some way
it's always going to use those three technologies.
However it's the back end where a multitude of options come up so the back end of a site has three components.
The language you choose for the back and the framework you choose for that language and the database
you want to connect to technologies such as ph P..
No it's Ruby on Rails Java pythonic cetera are all viable options for a web site.
So how do we actually decide which option to choose will our course Bakan uses the python as the language
Django as a framework for Python and then sequel.
As the database Python is a great language to learn.
It's simple powerful and already has many libraries for it.
So what does that actually mean.
Well it's simple because the actual syntax of programming through python is based on code readability
and clarity.
Meaning you're going to save yourself a lot of time programming because of how easy Python is to learn
and type with.
And then it's powerful and scalable and it also has many libraries already attached to it.
So if you're interested in an application such as machine learning for your web site data visualization
free web site or even things such as gaming for your web site.
Python already has many libraries you can use to implement those ideas into your project.
And Django is the most powerful and popular framework for Python.
It's fast secure and scalable and it's used by many actual web sites such as Pinterest Instagram bitbucket
they all run on Django and then sequel light comes of jinglin Python making it a very easy choice to
use as our database.
As we continue along the course we're going to be discussing each of these topics in much more detail
but for now you should have a high level view of what we use in this course to turn you into a full
stack web developer with Shingo full stack meaning.
We combined the front end technologies with the backend technologies so you can create a Web site all
the way through from scratch.
Ok now that we have the high level overview Let's go ahead and get started with the rest of the course.