Hello everyone and welcome to part 7.
Control flow in this lecture are going to be discussed in the Python syntax for control flow and this
will include operators.
If LCF and statements and loops like for loops and while loops we will cover the main principles behind
these topics.
Hopefully you remember them from the javascript lectures will just cover the general syntax and what
makes Python a little bit different than the programming languages for some of these control flow operators.
OK let's get started.
All right so let's begin our discussion of comparison operators and logical operators that have copied
and pasted here from the notes because we will need to code that much.
A lot of it's pretty straightforward.
So for greater then you just use the greater sign or greater than sign less then is the less than sign
you have greater than or equal to Lessner equal to and then free quality is a little different than
it was for Javascript.
So there is no triple equal sign in Python because Python will automatically check for types to be different
or the same still Micheaux an example of what I mean by that.
So here I'm going to say one equals equals one and it's true.
But if I say one equals equals and then I pass a string one I get false.
So there is no type coercion in python like there was in Javascript.
So if I say hi is equal to by then this is a really clear case where it should be false.
OK so again for Python it's just going to be two sets of equal sign and for any equality is just an
exclamation mark.
So you can say one not equal to one.
That's false one not equal to the string one.
That is true.
Now to discuss logical operators of Python.
I think this is one of the coolest parts about Python.
The logical operators are just literally the words and and or.
So that makes reading logical operators.
Python really simple even if you have a program for it.
There's no ampersand or pipe operators here.
So again that's just the keyword and the keyword.
Or you can have multiple logical operators like this or an or.
Now let's move on to discuss.
If Elif and L statements or else if statements and before we begin to talk about that.
Something to note with Python that's going to differentiate itself from other languages.
Is that indentation is extremely important in Python and it's basically Python's way of getting rid
of enclosing brackets.
So a lot of other languages you're going to be using in closing brackets a lot as we saw javascript.
These don't really occur in Python.
The reason for that is because Python really stresses readability due to whitespace and that whitespace
comes from indentation.
So let me show you some examples of if.
Elif and else statements if ought to have an if statement.
And let's actually quit python here so that I can run this code.
I will clear my screen and then what I'm going to do is say if one is less than two and then a colon
indicates the code block and hit enter here.
Note that it automatically indents for me.
And if your work if any ID either recognizes python files it should automatically indent for you.
And then I'm going say Prince Yes.
So now if I run this I'll say Python notes.
PI enter and I get a yes output.
So the main features here.
We can zoom in a little more and make this really clear is for any control flow statement.
With Python you have the keyword operator.
Here it's if we'll see ELSE IN FOR loops etc..
You don't need to worry about print C's here.
You just type in whatever you want to actually compare or whatever the boolean operator is.
Then a colon here indicates that you're going to start a new code block and then the code block itself
is indented in everything that's indented at same level belongs to the same code block.
So if I want to have a nested IF statement.
So for instance if two is less than three Crantz.
So let's save this in.
Let's zoom back out a little bit so this isn't so massively as him then.
And then let's actually run this and we get true.
So now let's make one of these false so I won't say if 20 is less than 3 and then I'm going to print
first block here and let's change this to say second block.
So what's going to happen here.
First off in order to run anything that's indented Pass Line 1.
This has to be true.
One has to be less than two.
So then we go along we see Prince first block.
So that is true.
Then it goes to line 3.
If 20 is less than 3 that's not true.
Nothing is going to occur in line for all x Q..
So now if I run this I get first block only.
So again hopefully you can begin to see how the indentation works here and this block of code is indented
at same level so it runs together.
And then this block of code is indented in.
So this is the top level for this block of code.
So again it's just a colon an indentation.
OK so that's the basics of an IF statement.
Let's see if else statement I can say something like.
If one is less than two prints hello and then if I want an else to be attached if statement.
All I have to do is line it up so that I will say else colon Crantz last Let's just say last save and
run the notes here.
And I said hello to print.
Now this changes so that is one greater than two which is not true.
So if I run this then I get last Again main idea here is you have a colon instead of the curly brackets
and the parentheses from other programming languages.
And then finally if you want to add a more conditional checks like an else if in Javascript you just
use a single phrase Ilive which is short for else.
If so I can do something like this.
Elif and then some condition here so ilah three equals three
Crantz Elif Ramm
we save this and I want to run Python notes it sets ilah Fran nuts because this first condition wasn't
true and this Ilive condition was true.
So what's happening here.
These are all lined up together on their indentation.
So if I have something let's say if one is equal to one colon I could grab all of this and it hit tab.
And now these are all lined up for each other.
So a note here indentation is really making it clear which code blocks belong to which conditional checks.
All right so that's the very basics of if.
Elif and L statements with Python again.
Really want to point out here the whitespace in the colon is what's the finding code blocks instead
of like normal programming languages where you have parentheses and brackets.
And this really emphasizes how fast you can code of Python how readable Python is and how much time
we're going to save working of Python versus other languages.
Ok so now let's go ahead and move on to a big topic which is Loups.
We've already covered loops in javascript so we won't define here the general principles behind loops
will just show you the syntax for working with them with Python.
So first off are for loops.
And for loops are going to behave a little differently depending on what you're working with in Python.
So usually you're going to be using a for loop with a sequence and a sequence can be something like
a list.
So let's create a sequence 1 2 3 4 5 6 and the for loop syntax for Python looks like this.
You say for some item in the sequence colon and then what ever you do is code here.
So then let's just say prints the item.
So hopefully it looks a little familiar from the four of or four loops in javascript and if I run this
year I get 1 2 3 4 5 6 so you can see I kept printing it every line or what I could also do is say prints
hello.
So if I save that and run this I get.
Hello hello hello.
For each item in the sequence and I can call this whatever I want doesn't have to be item.
So I always make this really obvious by saying something like jelly and then I'm going to print jelly
every time.
Save that.
Run this and I get back all the numbers in that sequence.
OK hopefully it's pretty clear.
It's just for whatever variable you want in the sequence.
And then you do some action for each of those variables.
OK so that's how you iterate through a list.
If you end up calling a for loop on a dictionary.
So let's make that let's say D is equal to Sam
1 and let's say Frank is to and Dan is three if I say for item in D and say prints.
Item if I save that and then see what this looks like it ends up printing out the keys.
Sam Dan and Frank.
But notice it's not it's not printing them out in order.
And remember that's because dictionaries don't retain any sort of order.
So if you're ever going to use a for loop of a dictionary don't count on it happening in order if you
actually wanted to get the keys out what you should do is something like this you can say for K
and since we are just printing out these we can say print the key and then print the key.
And this is how you can print out if I run this what Dan is three Frank to Sam is one again orders not
ever going to be the same when you're going through dictionary.
There are also methods you can call off a dictionary for to get all the items are all the keys so I
could say the values to get all the values that key is to get all the keys etc. but we won't actually
cover those right now if we ever use them in Django.
I'll be sure to clarify what we're doing there.
But again dictionary and with for loops it's automatically going to be the keys.
All right.
Let's delete that.
And now let's talk about iterating through a tuple an about tuple and packing.
So a lot of times built in functions in Python are going to end up giving you structures that look like
this.
It will be a list and inside of that lists you'll have tuples that look like this.
So one two five six so what do I have here.
I have a list of three tuples.
So if I say for item in my pairs prints item I'm going to save this run it.
I get each tuple out one two three four five six.
But what I can also do and this is a special case is if I have a sequence that consists of tuples I
can do what is known as tuple and a packing of Python so I can kind of type A tuple here and say something
like Type 1 to 2 and then I'm going to print to you P1 and then I will print to you too.
So if I save that.
Basically what happens here is I'm unpacking that tuple in my for loop.
So I run this and I can get one two three four five six or if I switch up the order here I should get
to 1 4 3 6 5.
So let's do that.
Save it run this and I get to 1 4 3 6 5 because it's printing out the second item and tuple and then
the first item in the table.
So that is tuple and packing and you usually don't see it.
These princes usually see it just like this.
So if you ever see something like this don't be confused or intimidated it's just to pull in packing
and this sort of formatting is really commonly used in Python.
So tuple Impac is definitely something we'll be working on if in the future.
OK.
So that's really all you need to know about for loops.
Let's quickly discuss while loops with Python.
I'm going to delete this.
So while loops again allow us to continually perform an action until a condition becomes true.
And it's really simple.
I'll show you a quick example.
Say is equal to 1.
And then we will say while I is less than five then colon that indicates the code block will say Prince
is and always print formatting here ass and I and then we will say I's equal to I plus one.
So again really simple example.
Let's clear this.
If I run Python it's again says eyes one eyes two eyes three eyes four and then once I get to five it's
no longer less than five.
So the while loop breaks.
So it's just a colon in a white space in the cane.
The loop now is quickly discuss a few more useful topics to know since we're talking about control flow.
One of them is the range function and range functions can quickly generate integers for you based on
a starting point and an ending point.
So if I do something like well let's actually show this with Python over here directly in the command
prompt.
So if I do something like one two three four five I have a list that goes from 1 all the way to five
but I can use range to help me out in Python 3 if I just type Prange 5.
I get back this range zero to 5 object.
What I have to do is say list range 0 5 and then actually get backlist 0 1 2 3 4 where the first parameter
in range is the starting index position and the second one is D and index position.
And I can add a third argument indicating a step size so I can say list range and let's go from zero.
20 and then I'm going to type in two.
I hit enter and I get all the even numbers that go up to but not including index 20 and try to remember
back to slice notation.
Sometimes students are confused.
They expect a 20 to show up here but it's not including 20.
So if we wanted 20 we would have to say 21.
We have to say one greater there.
All right.
Now another question you might be thinking is well what is range 0 5.
What is that and why did it return that that is a generator.
And basically what that means is it's going to generate the items or elements in this list.
Instead of saving it all to a list and that saves your computer memory.
So instead of having to store this entire huge list in memory cause let's say you had range and then
some humungous number you wouldn't want your computer to have to save this entire list if you're just
going to iterate through it what you want is just a generator where it remembers the previous number
and then adds 1 and then saves that previous number adds one saves it and keeps the leading sort of
only has one number in memory at a time and it knows the formula to get to the next number.
So for instance it would say I remember to add two to it to get four.
Get rid of two.
Now my current numbers for.
Oh you want the next number.
Add two to it.
Now have six.
Get rid of four from memory.
And that way we go along just remembering one number.
That's kind of the idea behind a generator.
So you can actually then use something like for item in range and usually see something like 10
Crantz item we'll save that and then let's quit python here.
Call Python.
It's not pie and here you can see I'm getting 0 1 2 3.
All the way up to nine.
So it doesn't include 10 or remember only goes up to nine here OK.
Now let's quickly recover list comprehension.
We mentioned that before.
But let's show you a more practical example Now imagine I have the list x is equal to 1 2 3 4 and I
want to create a list of those items squared.
I could make an empty output list just with empty brackets there and say for numb an X.
So in my list x take out and then appends to the power of two and then say print the output and note
that the print out is lined up with four meaning it's going to occur after this entire four loop ran.
So I will save this run Python notes that pi.
And here I can see I get 1 4 9 16.
So that's how you would do this normal for a loop.
But if you ever find yourself running a for loop like this and always appending something to a list
from another sequence or another list the way you can do this is write this as a list comprehension.
And what you do is you essentially break down this for loop.
So we take the original X here and it says Fortnum in X we changed this out.
We get rid of it completely change here.
Make this into a bracket and then make what we have on the append go in fronts of the four and that
is the basics of a list comprehension.
It's just the for loop rewritten and the flattened form and then we can say call this whole thing out.
Whoops.
And then let's print it.
Say print out save it run this and we get 1 4 9 16 and those are the basics of a list comprehension.
OK that was control flow of Python.
Do you have any questions feel free to post to the Usenet forums.
Thanks and I'll see at the next lecture.