Hello everyone and welcome back to part A.
We're going to be going over the solutions to the loop exercise questions from the previous lecture.
So let's continue going to open up my editor to get started.
OK here we have the actual problems uploaded in the javascript with the comment that I had to follow.
Now we're going to be doing.
First is problem one where how do you use a for loop to Prince or console log out the word hello five
times and we never actually did something quite like this.
But hopefully you're able to figure it out with both methods.
So if a while loop Let's show you how we can do that we'll see variable x is equal to zero.
And you could have chosen any variable name here that the name doesn't actually matter.
The say a while loop.
Now I'll say while X is less than five I'm going to cancel that log.
Hello and then I want to remember to add 1 to X and increment it.
So now I run my code I see hello and it's been output 5 times.
Google Chrome just lets you know that this little shortcut the bubble of Fibe there.
Up next we have the for loop and I wanted to use a for loop to do this.
So essentially you can just break down what we were doing up here above.
So I have variable I's equal to zero.
Since I is going to be less than five I put that here and I'll leave.
Plus plus.
And then I can actually just copy and paste the cancel command and just to make sure it's actually working.
I'm going to say something like hello with for loop.
We'll save that.
Let's run this code and I see hello and then hello a for loop.
The above ran five times.
Great let's move on to Problem Two problem too just to use loops to cancel that log or print out all
the odd numbers from 1 to 25.
And we wanted to do this using two methods the while loop and then a for loop.
Let's start off with the While loop.
I'm going to make a variable called num and in the solutions actually just reassign them from a previous
problem.
And then I'm going to say while my num is less than 25 if numb maade to is not equal to zero.
Remember previously if you want to check for an even number.
We said Number two equals zero.
In this case we're doing the exact opposite for our numbers.
I'm going to log that NUM and then I also want to make sure that I continually add to them.
So I'll just say no.
Plus plus.
So let's make sure that actually works and want to refresh my page here.
And there are all the numbers one all the way to 23 for the while loop and now for the for loop.
Let's do that as well.
Ongoing same for and then I'm going to fix some of these so it says instead of the actual length of
the array this is going to be five Let's expand this a little bit.
So I'm going to say if I maade to is not equal to zero.
Log.
I that's really all there is to this.
Make sure my brackets are balanced so I'll save that.
And let's comment everything else out.
So we make sure that only that is running.
So I will save this scroll the way down refresh my page and here I only see one through three make sure
it went all the way.
That should have been 25.
OK.
Now is refresh page.
And there we have it 1 through 23.
Great.
And that's how you could do it with a for loop.
So that's it just to pretty simple problems and hopefully you can begin to see the relationship between
the while loop and the for.
OK.
Thanks everybody.
And in the next lecture we're going to get practice on everything we covered in javascript level 1 with
a little bit of an assessment project.
Thanks.
And I'll see at the next lecture.