Hello everyone.
Welcome to part five decorators.
Decorators are an advanced tool in Python and I want you to feel free to skip this lecture.
Come back to it at another time.
Since we all actually encountered decorator's until much further on into the advanced Gengel material
it might make more sense for you to skip this lecture and once you encountered decorator's in the jingoes
sections of the course come back to this and reviewed decorator's Otherwise you may find yourself understanding
the syntax.
But being a little forgetful by the time you actually reach the use case of decorators.
OK so again we leave this lecturer in this section because material wise it makes the most sense to
leave it here as far as using it in this course.
I would recommend that you actually skip it for now and come back to it when you see decorator's mentioned
again right.
Is that all being said.
Let's get started.
OK so start off with decorator's.
They can be thought of as functions which modify the functionality of another function and they really
help make your code shorter and more pythonic.
And there also used a lot in Python with frameworks especially Django and flask.
Now you don't actually run into decorator's in Django until much further along in your learning of Django.
But to properly explain decorator's we're going to be slowly building up from functions.
So let's break down all the steps first.
We'll start off with a very simple function or view.
Remember if we want to create a function we can just say the F the name of your function.
Any parameters you want to pass and then you can say return.
For instance the number one.
Now if I want to call this function later I just say func.
And if I want to print something I can say prints func.
OK so if I save this and I run this hopefully by now you have no problems with this.
Your returns 1.
It all makes sense.
Now let's discuss scope.
So also remember from the scope lecture that I have global variables and local variables.
So if I have the string s global variable and I save this and thence inside of this the func I say something
like taken s and then I say print's S and I save this and let's say over here.
I just call func Well lips Phunk with s.
Scuse me and then I run this I get back global variable and now if I don't provide s as a parameter
to the function and instead do this and run this again it still works because here I don't have anything
in the local namespace called S..
So I jumped back out and look for the global variable namespace for S and I still find it.
So the printing variable.
Now I read the fine s to be equal to 50 inside of this save this run this I get back 50 when I call
function but if outside of this I call print s save this I get back with the global variable.
Remember if I actually want to re-assign not just the local variable s but instead the global variable
s I have to say this global s.
Then I save that run this again and go back.
Now I get 50 50.
So actually calling that global keyword calls in and tells me to affect the global not just the local
variable S and there's actually a way you can grab a dictionary or a list of all local's variables and
all global variables and the way you can do that is inside of this function just say print and then
call locals so locals returns a dictionary puts locals close parentheses.
We're going to save that and then I'm going to call the function here so I can save this run the code
and here right now.
I have an empty dictionary because I don't have any local variables defined here.
If I do the find something like my local to equal to 10 save this run this and now I see my local is
10 so that's just a convenient dictionary call to actually grab the local variables.
Now if I say something like Crantz Global's this will print out all the global variables and there's
going to be a lot here.
So if I say Python it's up-I I get this huge function of global variables and that's because it not
function excuse me a huge dictionary of global variables and that is because there are a bunch of builtin
things.
So even though we haven't defined a whole lot yet there are a lot of things so there's notes that pi
is a global variable for the file s.
Here we saw a global variable string so I can also just call this like a dictionary.
So Global's remember it's a dictionary.
So if I called the key for s.
Now let's hash tag about how I run this and I get back global variables.
So printing Global's s finds this key value pair.
OK so now that we remember what Global's and locals are let's start by continuing on with functions
in function assignment.
If I have a function called hello and it takes in some parameter name will have the default value be
Jose and I'm going to return Hello plus whatever name is provided.
And let's say I call prints hello.
I save this run notes up high and it says Hello Jose.
We can put a space in there so it makes a little more sense.
Now I can also assign a label to a function meaning I can say my new create and set it equal to hello.
And note that I'm actually setting equal to the function itself.
I'm not setting equal to what the function returns.
I'm not doing these princes here.
I'm sitting equal to the function itself which means I could say this my Negrete close print sees and
print this out.
Let's do that let's print out my new greets save this run this code and I see now I have twice.
Hello Jose once from hello.
And then since I defined my new green Ziegel to hello I also get my newgroup and now that we understand
how we can assign functions to new variables.
Let's continue on with functions within functions will flee so far everything seems sort of like Review
non-points create a function called Hello again takes a default parameter name Jose and right off the
top in this function of going to Prince the halo function has been run.
So if I ever call halo I can see that the halo function has been run that makes sense so far.
Now inside the hello I will define another function.
Now I will call this function greets and what this does.
It returns.
No it returns it's not printing.
It returns something that says this string is inside greets.
So if I run Python lodestar PI I shouldn't expect anything else to be different because I don't actually
call greed.
I just define it here and I'm going to do one more that says the.
Welcome and this returns this string is inside welcome.
We can save that again if I run this code.
I shouldn't expect anything different to happen because I'm only defining these functions inside of
this function.
I'm not actually calling them now and pay attention here to the indentation with the same indentation.
Let's zoom out a little bit so we can see all this.
So if the same indentation still inside the F Hello.
What I'm going to do is say Prince
greet and then I'm also going to Prince welcome
I'm going to say Prince and of Hello.
So now if I save this and actually call the function.
Hello.
Nope.
Back I get the hello function has been run like it.
The string is inside Greece.
So actually the fine greet and call greet here and then I find a welcome and also call welcome.
And then I get the hello and remember because of scope I cannot call greet or welcome outside of this
so I cannot say flips I can call hello.
But if I try to call welcome outside of the scope of this function you can quickly check what's inside
this function by just collapsing that entire function here.
So I run this welcome.
I will get an air says name welcome is not the fine because welcome's only inside the scope of the hello
function so keep that in mind.
All right so that's the basics of functions within functions and I promise this will build up to decorator's.
Now is talk about returning functions something we haven't actually seen yet.
So let's say this inside of my halo function I will say if my name is equal to Jose put in lowercase
Jose return.
Greets.
So note here.
I'm returning a function we haven't actually seen that before and then I will see else return another
function will return the welcome function.
I'm not saying return the call of compunction I'm saying return the actual function itself meaning it's
returning this entire function not just the string itself.
And now I will say this x is equal to hello close parentheses and then I'm going to say save this if
I run Python it's upaya.
All I see is Hello function has been run but I don't know yet what has actually been returned so I can
do this.
X close parentheses so I run that it says hello function has been run in because this was just a return
String.
I need to actually print this out.
I can say prints X run this.
Now it says the string is inside Greek.
So again let's break down what's happening here.
I'm saying if the default name is equal to Jose which is the case if name is equal to Ozy return the
grete function and the function is this entire thing and a function just says in itself.
Return this string.
So I set X equal to the result of hello and by default the name is Jose.
Meaning I'm returning X to be equal to greet.
This is the exact same thing as saying x is equal to greet except if it was happening inside of this
function.
So remember X hello and then I can call X since it sounds green and print out its result which is this
string is in sight greet.
Ok really take your time with this one.
This kind of one of those jumps that might be a little confusing at first but it's actually not so bad.
Again we're just returning a function assigning it to a variable and then calling that variables function
and printing it out because it returned the string.
Now we have one last concept to go over before we actually talk about decorators which is a function
as an argument.
So I'm going to delete all this code and say hello and it will return.
Jose.
And then it won't create another function will say other and it's actually going to take in a parameter
func and it's going to Prince
hello
and then it's also going to Prince phunk will save this and I'm going to pass in a function as an argument
so will call my other function and I will pasand the hello function and keep in mind I'm not passing
what the hello function returns.
I'm passing the function itself so I don't have open and close princes at the end of Hello.
So if I run notes the reply I get back here.
Function Hello.
At this.
Which means if I actually run this inside of the other function would close Princie is here.
Now I should see.
Hello.
Hi Jose.
So again make sure you really understand what's going on here.
I'm passing in a function as an argument and the inside of the other function I can call that function.
So again here we can see if we can pass and function as arguments just like we could pass strings numbers
dictionaries etc..
We can pass and functions themselves inside of another function and then play around with them.
And now it's time to actually show the basic steps to create a decorator which has to do with all the
concepts we just covered.
So in the previous example we essentially manually created a decorator.
So let's show and modify this to make it really clear.
I'll create a function called new underscore decorator and this takes in some function and then inside
is function.
I find another one that says wrap underscore fun.
It doesn't take any parameters and it's going to prance code here before executing
and then here I will execute fun.
And remember I can call phunk because it's in that namespace.
And then after that going to Prince Bonk has been called
in and outside of all this I'm going to return wrap fun
and then I'm going to create a new function called phunk needs decorator and I'm going to have it just
prints.
No it's not returning It's just printing that this function can spell is in need of a decorator.
So let's start off a simple example which happens when I call func needs a decorator.
So if I just call that run Python it's up high.
It says this function is in need of a decorator that makes sense so far.
But what happens if I actually reassign it to say func needs.
Decorator is equal to the new decorator with func needs decorator passed inside of it.
So if I run this and then call func needs decorator save that run Python code pie.
It says code here will it's actually expand this a little more says code here before executing phunk
this function is in need of a decorator.
Thunk hasn't called.
So what happened here.
The decorator simply wrapped the function and modified its behavior and all of this code can be rewritten
with the at symbol.
So again what's happening here is mainly all in line 13 member.
I have this original function that needed the decorator.
It just does a simple print command and I'm now passing it as an argument inside of new decorator and
inside of that I'm calling it inside of this wrap function and returning that wrap function in all of
this can be done with the at symbol.
So let me show you what that actually looks like.
I could say here instead of these lines so I let me just comment this out so you can compare.
So I have the func needs is that grid equal to new decorator.
What the funk needs a decorator instead of that sort of re-assignment I can use the as keyword and type
in the name of the decorator want.
Which is at new decorator and then call the function.
The func needs decorator.
Well I can actually call it.
I would basically type this entire thing so we can just grab this special keyword that at keyword.
And this is the same thing as doing this.
So Neph I call Blunk needs decorator.
Save this I need to run this.
But remember what happened I said code here before executing function.
This function is need a native decorator func has been called.
I run this and I get back the exact same thing.
So the key point of all of we talked about is this that if you ever had a situation where you would
need to pass a function that needed a decorator into a new decorator and then reassign it.
That's all going to be done with this simple at call.
So the new decorator with this at symbol call is the same as doing this and that's all we wanted to
get across.
Now you might be wondering when the heck am I ever going to need to do something like this.
Well it's not really clear now and it won't be clear until we actually show you an example with Django
go much further along in the course but hopefully you're actually watch that already and came back to
this because you were confused on what the heck we're doing with the decorator and I hope now this made
it all clear.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture.