Hello everyone and welcome to part nine function exercises.
Let's take a quick look at some of the function exercises that are here for you to answer the relative
files are part 9 function exercises and part nine function exercises solutions that high.
Let's open them up in the editor and see what they're all about.
OK.
Here we have part nine function exercises open and complete the tasks below by writing functions and
keep in mind these problems are actually meant to be really tough.
Even if you do know Python it's all about breaking the problem down into smaller logical steps and if
you get stuck on this don't feel bad about having to take a peek at the solutions file or at the solutions
lecture for the first problem you'll be given a list of integers and I want you to return true if the
sequence of numbers 1 2 3 appears in the list somewhere.
So for example in this first one here we have 1 two 3 in the center.
So we return true.
Here we don't have one two three.
So we return false.
Here we have 1 2 3.
At the end to return true and just fill out this array check function and here we're actually using
camel cases.
We should be using snake case in Python.
But don't worry about that too much slower.
Either way with Problem 2 given the string we want to return a new string made of every other character
starting with the first.
So hello yields.
H l o.
Again some examples here.
Hopefully you remember string slicing and indexing enough to make this an easy task for you.
And now on to problem 3.
Problem 3 is given two strings.
I want you to return true if either of the strings appears at the very end of the other string and I
want you to also ignore upper and lower case differences.
So in other words the computation should not be case sensitive.
And a quick hint slash.
Note.
You can use estat lower to return the lower case version of a string.
So here we can see three examples that will yield true.
I have high ABC and ABC.
Note that ABC is at the end of the first drink so that returns true.
Then I kind of have the opposite.
ABC and hi ABC ABC is at the end of the second string here so that also returns true and then I have
ABC and then ABC NBC ABC here Piers the end of this once that was hers true again.
If either string is at the end of the other string you return true problem for is given a string return
a string where for every character in the original There are two characters.
So here we're kind of just doubling the characters in the string so you can check out these examples
so get an idea of what I mean.
Then problem 5 is probably the most difficult problem here but it's basically just read this problem
statement carefully and then check out the actual examples here.
So it's kind of a longer read but check it out.
It's probably the trickier problem.
There's two functions for it then problem 6 is a bit easier.
It just says return the number of even integers in the given array.
So this one should be pretty straightforward if you have an off list or an array of comany even integers
are inside of it.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture were actually be programming through solutions.