Welcome everyone to part 12 of the social clone project.
Now go ahead and try running our application our Web site and see if there's any debugging that we need
to do.
I'm sure we've made typos along the way.
So let's see how we can actually fix those.
We also need to make sure we do our migrations and double check our settings that PI file so that the
applications that we just created groups and post are actually inside that setting that profile.
Let's get started ok here and back at the editor and I want to open up our settings that py files under
simple social project.
Open up settings that pi and then I'm going to scroll down to the installed apps and I want to make
sure that we add in the groups app that we've made as well as the Post's app.
So we will save that and I also want to make sure that we do the migrations so I'm going to clear my
console or CLX if you're on Windows and then say Python managed up high so make sure and then the right
one.
See the two simple social Python managed at PI and then I'm going to type migrate it should complain
and we'll run that.
OK great.
So it complains.
So we're going to do say Python managed up-I make migrations and we'll start off with groups hit enter
and then want to do Python manage that PI make migrations and then we'll do posts enter and then files
say Python managed up PI migrate and then it's ready to go.
So now it's actually try running this and see if we need to debug anything.
I'll say Python managed up high run server.
Ok it looks like it's running.
Let's hop over to our browser.
OK my browser everything's looking like it's functioning.
So let's actually log in and see if we can create a new group and then create a new post in it.
I will log in.
Actually let's sign up just to make sure everything's working.
So I will sign up as Jose my e-mail address will just be Jose at gmail dot com.
That's not my real email address so don't bother.
Whoever that Jose is will say yes password just password and then sign up.
Ok now I'm going to log in username Jose password is test password log in and it says now we're logged
in.
Great.
So I have this create group.
So let's try creating a group on that.
Actually we haven't linked that yet so we still need to on our actual navigation bar.
Make sure that's working.
So that's something we can add in.
Let's go ahead and hop over to the editor and fix that.
So back in the editor I will open up the base h team I'll file that's the one that actually has a navigation
bar let me collapse my directory tree so based on age HTML where the navigation bar is remember I have
all these kind of missing links so let's add those in.
First the your URL for a post is just going to be your goal posts create and then for groups.
It's going to be it's the template tag here.
Dorel groups all and then four create groups.
It's going to be
groups create and then let's also fix this one so.
Else we will say groups and that will be your el groups all.
So the list of all the groups.
OK save that.
And now let's hop back over here and refresh this page.
And I have a syntax error so it says groups create expected.
Elif Elser and.
Did you forget to register or load this tag.
So let's make sure it was actually groups create for the groups creation page and a hop back over and
make sure I fix that.
So here am seeing groups create and looks like it for its Taipan.
So not going to save that.
It'll refresh again.
OK.
So it looks like post is not a registered namespace.
So what does that actually mean.
Well it says error during template rendering based on each T.M. line 29.
So if I come over here it says posts create it's not valid.
Let's make sure that you're not py file.
I've actually defined posts as the app name.
So hop back over here.
Open up my directory Chewey under posts.
I'll open up your All-Starr pie looks like my app name is registered.
So now let's make sure we have create registered.
It looks like that's working as well.
Which means it may be an issue with the Urals that py file in the project level.
So let's go over to your oles that pie at a project level.
And if I scroll down here it looks like I still have the groups and post links so that's definitely
something I need to add in.
It's a good thing where the buggy now and hopefully this is kind of obvious to you as you kind of went
along here.
So I'll do Khama add in your l and now it's time to register post-soul say using regular expression
curat posts and essentially just linking to the actual post-soul say include.
And I'm going to include posts.
Or else.
And then let's give it a name space which is essentially what it was complaining about.
So this was the era that we were getting.
It wasn't complaining about the other posts.
And let's add one more here for the groups.
So we'll say Kurt groups forward slash then I'm going to include groups stop your else and then give
a name space equal to groups and I will save that.
OK.
Perfect.
Now try again you can see auto restarted for us.
We'll come back over here refreshed the page says Now I'm logged in.
It's looking good.
Let's get on groups and it says welcome back at Jose that's looking good.
Groups Welcome to the group's page.
And then of that I'm noxious plus sign but it says create new group.
Obviously we can add more CSSA styling to make that look better.
Let's try getting create group here make sure that works so that works as well.
I'm going to go back to space and make sure this button works as well and it looks like they're taking
us to the same groups new.
So that's looking good.
I will say first group and description will be my first group.
Then hit create.
OK.
Looks like we have an issue here says groups name.
Reverse is not defined.
So hopefully by now you kind of realize I probably forgot to import reverse somewhere so somewhere along
the line I need a reverse call.
I probably called it but didn't actually import it because it says name reverse is not defined.
So let's go back and make sure in our group's file or we're actually having that create group view.
We imported reverse.
So welcome back.
So coming back to my actual editor I can now see if I expand my command line here that I get this name.
Err name reverse not defined in going up.
It actually tells me where it's coming from it's coming from simple social groups models not by line
30 and get absolute L.
So that's probably where the issue is.
So let's go ahead and find that models that py file.
It's not in views so we're willing to scroll down a little bit.
Come over to models PI and then over here we're actually going to see if we can fix that mistake.
So over in line 30 it says if you scroll down.
Return reverse.
So it looks like we just forgot to import reverse.
So now we'll come back up here and we'll save from jingo core your resolvers in poor reverse.
OK so we will now save that and it looks like it's running again.
Come back up here.
Go back and then refresh this page.
And let's try a second group and we'll labeled scription of second try create.
All right so now back at the page after refreshing it looks like a group was created.
Now the fonts actually really large here.
That's because I'm zoomed in 200 percent so keep that in mind.
A lot of the things that we do have bootstrap may look a little strange here just because I'm zoomed
in so much to make sure you guys can see clearly but we have the second group member count is zero.
Let's try to join this group and see if it works.
I joined and now the member count is 1 and let's leave.
See if that works and looks like we have a problem with leave so it says name models is not defined.
So over here we're saying models not group member the object filter and that's in the views that py
file of our groups.
So looks like we forgot to import models or do something for actual views that py file inside a group
slut's head over and mixture.
We actually imported the group models will come back over here and this is the views that py file and
what I need to do on is from the import models.
Save that now let's head back and refresh this page.
And looks like we're still getting leave.
Group has KQ 0 6.
Definitely misspelled something here that should have been a W.
So again we'll come back over here and let's see if we can search for that K-Q.
There you go.
That should be KW args.
Save that and make sure that there's double asterisks here as well and will come back.
Refresh the page and number count 0 so try joining again and illustrate leaving again.
It looks like it's working perfect.
Now there's no post in this group.
So try posting something I'll click on post and say this is my first test post exclamation point in
under group.
Just to assign this to second group post.
All right now we get this error that says user posts object has no attribute post and the fact that
it's saying has no attribute.
You remember you call attributes with a dot or period meaning.
Probably somewhere along the line I'm calling Post Office something where I really shouldn't be doing
that.
And it says right here it's under simple social post views that pie in line 28.
So let's head back to views that pi and other posts views that pi.
Here it is.
I'm going to take a look at this on line 28.
I can see here I'm saying try self-taught post thought user equals a user object.
Really what it should have been doing is assigning this.
So here I said self-taught post underscore user and that's actually what I meant to do.
Inline 28.
Basically creating this attribute object or editing this Ashby object of posts user.
So now that I've saved that let's send it back over and refreshed the page.
OK it looks like Jose.
I can see this is my first test post and it just says delete here let's try that.
Going to try to delete and looks like template does not exist.
Post delete one post.
Post based I aced team else so somewhere along the line we are getting a failure for post underscore
Bass says this template doesn't exist.
Let's head back and figure that out.
Then hop back over and let's confirm that we do have a post underscore bass so that looks good meaning
over here on the Confirm delete.
Probably something is happening here that's wrong and it says X10 posts.
Post a female looks like X only have double quotes there so let's delete those save it and then try
again see if that fixes the issue.
And there we go.
So it was just an issue of accidently having double quotes there and that extents call.
So it says Now are you sure you want to leave this post.
Let's try to confirm delete.
It looks like messages are not defined.
That probably means I didn't import messages.
So that's under it.
Views that py inline 70 going head over posts of used up by line 17 if you take a look at it.
Messages success.
I forgot to import that.
So save from Django and I believe from them contrib import messages save that come back here and I'm
going to refresh this continue and it looks like it delete that post.
Please try again to make sure that's working for US groups.
I see all the groups all come to first group or join that group and then I'm going to post to first
group this time.
OK so let's see if this is working.
Let's put this to first group.
Post it.
OK let's see it is working Jose and willing to delete this.
Are you sure you want to please post let's see if it's working confirmed delete.
It looks like deleted it now right now what's happening is the redirect is probably not working after
delete so we should definitely check that as well.
And if you notice off the posts it looks like the date or time stamp wasn't working as well.
So if we come back to groups let me add a post here so I'm going to.
Why not actually actually join it in this post.
So just say blah blah group second group post.
And now if I take a look at the groups I can see the second group has one post looks like the counting
is working and then it says right here at this post.
If I hit my Poso function I want to delete this.
Looks like it's working.
I'm going to cancel and see that it redirects here.
OK so it looks like we're able to post but notice that we're not getting a lot of the functionality
we thought we were going to get things like the date that the post was created that or my Jose isn't
actually linking to my profile and it's probably because we forgot to put some things either on this
particular template page or one of the templates It extends from or injects into.
So let's go back to our editor and you'll notice that for this page that would have been the user post
page or the Post confirmed.
Fact if we go back this is post by Jose.
Number three is actually the post detail page so posts underscore detail if we take a look at it essentially
just in Jecks underscore posts.
H m l.
Meaning all the issues are probably within underscore posts.
HTL.
So again coming back here I'm getting some issues at Jose I expect that to be clicking.
I expect this to probably say Jose instead of just Jose.
I don't know what this is doing there.
So there's still some problems here.
Let's come back and this page is directly what we're looking at since there shouldn't be any problems
here.
Just about five lines of code.
It's probably all an underscore post that takes him out so we'll go to underscore postdates HTML and
add some stuff in here.
The collapse is their victory tree.
It looks like we actually forgot to add in the text for these anchor tags which was probably a big oversight.
So let's do that now.
Underneath media heading these anchor tags should probably have something since they're linking to something.
So we will say at and then this will be the username.
So I will say postop user the user name save that let's go back and see if that affected something.
OK.
So there you see Jose and I don't really want this double Jose there so we'll come back here.
And then let's get rid of this so post user post username.
I'm going to just comment that out because I feel like I don't really need it now.
There we go so let's look looking a little better.
Come back up here.
And looks like the time isn't actually posting so let's do something there as well.
Insert here or inject post created at.
Remember those that property over time was created that save it and then I'm going to refresh.
OK.
Looks like we have creation Jose.
That's looking good.
We see that we still have this weird esque floating around there.
And if I refresh this page it's still there.
I can see it it's after the delete button.
So I try to confirm that it's an underscore post or if it's actually in the user post list.
So coming back here if I type something outside of this this is outside underscore post save that and
then refresh this page looks like that happens.
So outside underscore post which means this s is not part of the injection itself.
So that means the problem is not actually an underscore postdated demo.
So I'll save that and it should have been under user post list.
So clicking on user posts list I can see include and whip's looks like S was right here the whole time.
Delete that s.
Save this.
Come back here.
Refresh the page.
And now the S has gone looking good.
If I come back to start social that takes me to walk on the start social I can see a list of groups
first group second group and it looks like everything is working let's try creating a new user going
through all the actions and then verifying that everything is working.
So I will log out says Thanks for visiting come back soon.
Let's sign up actually before we do that let's see if we can view the groups without being logged in.
That's looking good.
First group no post in this group yet hit the groups over here.
There's one post and second group and there's the post itself.
OK that's looking pretty good then I'm going to sign up.
Will sign up as new.
Underscore user new shemale dot com.
This will be a test password.
Test password.
Sign up.
OK so I have new underscore user and I the same phosphorus Joses will just log in.
Ok now it says I'm logged in perfect and going to try to create a group and this will take me to my
new groups.
Make it really obvious brand new create.
Ok so my new group member count no posts in this group yet.
Then again I am pretty zoomed in here so that's why it looks a little weird.
I'm going to join my own group and Elosha posting it.
So this is the first post in the group and then I'll go to my new group post and there it is.
This is the first post a new group new user interface a new user takes me to the same page.
So let's try exploring.
If I go to groups the second group that had a post buy at Home sales try looking at Jose and I can see
Jose's profile essentially it's like his profile or Twitter feed and I can see whatever post that this
person has done.
Perfect.
So it looks like all our functionality is working up coming up next.
We have to do is set up our CSSA files.
Kind of give this a nicer look OK we'll do that in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.