Hello everyone and welcome back to Part 10.
Simple game project.
So we've learned enough python for actually create a simple command line game to finish off Python level
1.
Let's discuss the rules of the game and then show you an example run through of a finished game.
The computer will think of a three digit number that has no repeating digits like three four six or
seven to one.
So again no repeating digits and it's just a three digit number.
Then you're going to enter at the command line in input of your own guess of what three digit number
the computer's thinking of.
Then the computer will give you back some clues which will Taqwa a little bit based off these clues
you're going to guess again and you'll keep doing it until you actually break the code with a full match
three digits up your guess to the three digits that the computer originally guessed.
So the possible clues are this based off your guess.
The computer will say close if you've guessed the correct number but in the wrong position it will then
also add a clue of match.
If you've guessed the correct number in the correct position and then it will return.
No.
If you haven't guessed any of the numbers correctly.
So we can get multiple clues back and that's possible.
We'll show you.
Now a quick run through of the game but you're going to need to look up a few things on your own to
complete the project.
There are hints for you left in this particular file.
Part 10 simple games up PI.
We haven't actually told you how to get input from a user but the hint is in part 10 simple game.
Why do you get stuck on anything though.
Feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'm always happy to help out or to check out these solutions.
Pi or the solutions lecture.
OK so let's see what this actually looks like.
So here I've copied and pasted the solutions to the notes the PI file have opened.
So when I say Python most up-I they'll say something like welcome Codebreaker Let's see if you can guess
my three digit number.
The code has been generated.
Please get a three digit number.
What is your guess.
I'll get something simple like four five six enter it and it says there is a match somewhere.
So I know either 4 is in the correct position 5 is in the correct position or 6 is in the correct position.
So I can swap some of them out to double check this.
So let's say four to three and I get a match.
So I'm going to guess that four is the first number let's confirm that by saying for instance 4 7 8
and now I get a match again meaning 4 is definitely the first number.
And then you just keep guessing the number over and over again until you've actually broken the code
again.
The three possible clues are no close match and you can get multiple clues based off your numbers position.
Thanks everyone.
If you have any questions of this feel free to post the Kewney forums and I'll see at the next lecture
relict through an example solution.