Welcome back everyone to the final part.
The social clone project.
Now our Web site actually has full functionality.
We can sign up new users have them log in and they can create both groups and posts and the groups have
a count of how many members they have and how many posts they have.
Now we're going to go ahead and do is add in the SS and javascript files to give this Web site a cool
look.
And this is where you can diverge and customize the site to your own liking.
We will copy and paste from the right notes and a lot of this code just comes from a code pen that's
publicly available.
But again this is really a personal preference up to you how you want to style your particular site.
Let's up over to the notes and finish up this project.
All right.
Here I am in the editor and the first thing you want to do is make sure that in our settings that PI
file we have the static files linked and if you scroll all the way down I believe we may have made a
small typo.
So you should have static underscore you all equal to static and static files underscore.
It should be d i r s.
So static file directories.
And the reason for that is because you pass it in as a list.
It could have multiple static directories.
And then we say oh estopped path but join based directory static.
So make sure you change that and save it so that it's static files underscore Diyar.
That's ok once you have that what you need to do is come over to static and inside of simple social
C Ss in javascript create a M.Z. SS file and a master javascript file.
Now inside of these I've already copied and pasted the code from the notes as well as the code in this
master CSSA other see a source file.
In case you ever want to play around with other things you can link this as well.
Mainly we're just going to be using the C S S file which essentially makes everything black and the
color white and then this javascript file which is sourced from this Koeppen.
So you have the link there and this is what allows you to set the stars when you click on something
on the Web site.
The stars will pop up.
So right now the javascript master javascript file isn't linked yet so we're going to do is linked that
to our baseline team l page.
That way it shows up in every single page.
So we'll come over to base that each T.M. scroll all the way down to the bottom because we want this
to load after the entire body is loaded and we're going to add in a script call here.
So script it's going to be type text javascript and then let's say the source.
So the source is going to be static.
So over the static directories and it's just simple social javascript slash M.Com jazz or whatever he
happens to call it.
So that's where we can find it.
I'm going to save that and then this whole thing.
The source should be in quotes itself.
There we go.
And the syntax heiling can kind of hint at that.
OK so that should be all we need for that particular script.
Let's save that change and then let's make sure we scroll up and actually loading the static files.
Ok we are loading the static files so everything should work.
Let's run this and finish up this project.
Confirm we'd have no bugs right now coming to the Web site we can see here it says Welcome to our social.
Everything's turned black and as we hover above buttons now they're kind of inversed in color and if
you click somewhere here you'll end up seeing the stars being created so you can click a whole bunch
and you'll see a bunch stars being created and that's basically it.
Now given the way that the actual nav bar and the content is created there is kind of a buffer zone
here.
As far as the stars so they're bouncing off and there's essentially I can click here to close the border
so you can see it.
There is no way to go above that.
Now you could spend a lot more time with CSSA and Javascript and make sure all these elements that their
background and their canvas is linked so that the stars go everywhere.
I mean kind of up to you.
That's a lot more work on the front end.
That's really not what jangles about.
So really up to you how much you want to customize this if the stars are really your thing to be in
with but that is an example of how you could spruce up your project and just make it look better.
OK that's basically all there is to this project.
Hope you had fun.
The main thing to really get out of this project is creating users and creating groups of users and
having them connect that way.
So those two kind of model ideas essentially just an expansion off the blog project.
All right.
Hope you enjoyed it.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lectures.