Hello everyone and welcome back to the some project one solutions lecture this lecture will just begin
cutting out an example a solution for the cap some project let's hop through an editor and get started.
OK so here you have the text editor open as well as the example of what we eventually want the landing
page to look like.
Say Welcome to the longeing landing page.
Scroll down.
When we hit sign me up it takes us to a think Page.
So let's focus on that right now and I'm going to need basically three files one each time I'll file
for this main page one each time I'll file for the thank you page and the CSSA file for the CSSA the
project.
Let's start out by creating the H-2A mail for the main project page this landing page.
So I have a aist him l file called Project H Tim L is actually currently linked here so I'm going to
refresh.
It's cleared now and we should have a blank slate to begin with.
So let's refresh will expand this just a little bit and decrease this browsers.
It matches up.
Now let's get started.
So we're going to do first is actually type in HVM L and do the autocomplete there and then let's get
the something like trajectory.
Call it landing page and then we also want to make sure that this is eventually linked to that project
that CSSA file or whatever you happen to call the CSSA file for this project.
So there's our style sheet and then we want to do is have the heading one that says something like welcome
to the landing page.
And since we're a startup we'll have to say we're a startup that is cool or something whatever you want
to say is totally fine.
And then we want some filler text all add in the paragraph.
There were Florham ipsum will put in another paragraph again with Florham up some.
And then what we want to do is add in the form.
So the form is also going to come here and will do is say H to say something like sign up for our lunch
call the form.
Ted and right now we'll just give it no class or actually we'll call.
Call it the class email form in case you want to access it.
But remember we want to link to the page upon and the action call upon hitting that submit.
So I want to make sure that my action goes to think about the smell and then that means this method
needs to be get.
And we have discussed really post versus Get yet we will in a future lecture.
But right now you should just know that from our previous discussions in the T.M. forms lectures.
OK.
So we had three inputs we wanted.
We had the first name the last name and the e-mail.
So let's put these in.
We want the input.
This type is going to be just a text input.
And we'll give the name of this to be first so I can reference it later.
We have another input that's also text.
We'll give it the name last.
We have another input and that's going to be an email input.
Now we'll just give it the name email and it would be also smart to pass in values right now.
But we're really not doing anything since this is just a shell landing page.
We're not actually accepting these values so we won't put anything for input right now.
But we do want to do is add in some labels so we'll say this label is for first so that it matches the
name.
And then let's say first name for this label the second input you also have a label that's going to
belong to last call a last name and then finally we want to label here and this is going to be the label
for email memberships matching the name here and then we'll say email so let's save this refresh and
see what we have.
So far it's looking pretty good.
I'm zoon then.
So the fots a little weird but we can see here that I have.
Welcome to Lenny page.
We're a startup that's cool let's change that save in a refresh.
We're started this cool we have to purchase a lot of maps some sign up for launch.
First Name Last Name and Email something that you may notice however is that the first name last name
and email inputs are all on the same line.
There's a couple of ways we can take care of that.
One way we showed earlier was to put in a blank paragraph and between these to try to get those line
breaks so if I click save here I can see that in putting that same paragraph or empty paragraph gets
me what I was looking for the other way to do this which is a little better is by using a break tag
and a break tag basically just says hey break to a new block and that can be used with this command
you just put an open symbol B are and that's your break tag and you can actually just type in your and
it will automatically fill that in for you.
And then we can put in one more here so we can save that refresh and we can see if we have that line
break.
But then the issue of this break is that they are very close together.
So we end up having to do is add in the break to the labels as well.
So we can add in those breaks.
So it might have been a little easier just to do those two paragraph calls but it looks a little more
professional and nicer to use the actual breaks since the paragraphs are being used.
You could probably use breaks even though there are more of them.
It looks a little more professional nicer because they're the actual use case of the break is being
used here versus the paragraphs themselves.
All right.
So looks like everything's done for each team out on the project page.
Let's open up the.
Thank you.
Actually we still need to do the submit button.
So let's type that in real quick.
Well say input submit and the value for this guy is going to be.
Sign me up
and let's give it an ID so he can edit it later because remember we're going to try to make these corners
rounded on this.
So we'll give it the ID some refresh.
We see Sign me up.
Great.
So let's continue.
We're going to open up the.
Thank you Tim L..
Here it is blank right now.
Let's start by just typing in HCM l saving this.
We want to make sure that we are linking to the eventual CSSA file which is going to be project about
C Ss or whatever you happen to have called it save that that I'm going to add in Heading 1 say something
like thank you for signing up and then we'll also add in a heading to that's something like we'll reach
out to you soon.
Exclamation point.
OK.
So so far what we've done is we said we have our team I'll set up our project team all set up.
So if those have saved if I refresh this and add in some context these guys so at gmail dot com and
click sign me up boom now I get the thank you for signing up.
Last thing I want to do is change the font right now.
We're still on the default Times New Roman.
Let me just make this a little nicer by choosing a Google font so I will open up and you have to Fahnestock
Googlebot com.
Roberto is a really nice font that I like a lot but let's use something a little more fun.
So senese the that looks pretty cool.
So I'm going to add that says one family selected.
I'm going to copy and paste this link and I'm going to make sure that it's in both.
Thank you.
And project files.
And then I'm going to copy and paste the thing I need to specify for CSX which means I should open up
my CSSA file.
And then put in something like body
and then just copy and paste that font family save that save this save that and refreshed to make sure
the font has changed and there it is Wakata landing page.
Things looking at here.
All right.
So next thing you have to do is just edit the CSSA to match what we had earlier.
We're going to continue editing the see SS in the very next lecture so you can take some time just to
go over everything we did in the aged hymnal.
I know we went through it a little bit quickly in this lecture so feel free to take your time with the
actual HTL notes that are available to you under the capstone project one folder or just watch this
lecture at a slower pace or at a faster pace if I'm still too slow for you.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.
We'll finish off this project by editing the rest of the CSSA file.