Hello everyone and welcome to the Django model's lecture and this lecture we're going to be covering
the main concepts behind models databases and how it works with them.
We will actually be doing any live coding in this lecture.
We're just going to be looking at concepts through slides.
So make sure you have enough time to just fully enjoy this lecture and the concepts.
And then in the next lecture we're going to comb through a lot of the stuff we talk about here.
All right.
In the central part of any web site is the ability to accept information from a user and input it into
a database.
Then later on retrieve information from a database and use it to generate content for the user.
We use models to incorporate a database into a single project and Django comes equipped with sequel
light which is a sequel engine sequel light will work with us for our simple examples who won't be doing
any huge web sites so it should be totally fine.
But Gengel can also connect to a variety of sequel engine back ends.
It can connect to post-career sequel My sequel.
Now all you have to do is just switch out the actual engine and we'll talk about that later on.
But for most of our project sequel life is more than enough in the setting up file you can edit the
engine parameter used for databases and that's where you would actually connect to a different backend
if you didn't want to use sequel like then to create an actual model we use a class structure inside
of the relevant applications models that py file which we haven't actually edited yet but we will in
the next lecture this class object will be a subclass of jingoes builtin class jingled that D-B that
models that model.
So basically you're going to inherit from this builtin model class then each attribute of the class
represents a field which is just like a column name with constraints and sequel.
This will all feel very natural.
If you already have some sequel experience that in case you don't let's quickly review what a sequel
database looks like and if you already have sequel experience you can just kind of fast forward through
this little explanation.
OK.
So basically sequel operates like a giant table.
If you're familiar with Excel or spreadsheets and general sequel operates in a very similar fashion
with each column representing a field in each row representing an individual and true or data point.
So here we can see a table has a website ID a web site name.
And then if you are el.
So each column has a type of field as well such as a character field an integer field or a date field
and each field can also have constraints.
So here we have Web site ID and that's an integer field that we have web site name.
That's a character field etc..
And for those kind of constraints for example the character field should have a max length constraint
indicating the maximum number of characters allowed.
So you have the type of field and then constraints on that field.
The last thing to note is table or models with Django.
The relationships between them and often models will reference each other for this referencing to work.
We use the concept of foreign keys and primary keys.
So to show an example imagine we now have two models which are essentially two databases one to store
Web site information and another to store data information.
So here the last we have the Web site ID the web site name and the URL on the right.
We have the corresponding web site ID and then they accessed so we could say that the Web site ID column
is a primary key in the left table and a foreign key in the right table a primary key is a unique identifier
for each row in a table.
A foreign key just the notes that the column coincides with primary key of another table.
Later on we're going to move on to discuss things like one to one or many to many relationships.
But for now this is all we really need to know.
That should be enough for understanding of models and Django and just a general quick overview of what
sequel kind of looks like as a concept.
Now let's show an example of the model class that would go into the model up-I file of your application.
So as I mentioned we have these model classes and the inherits from jingoes builtin models not model
class.
So let's imagine we have a topic model we would have the class topic and then we can say top name is
going to be models not the type of field character field.
And then as arguments you passen these parameters that are constraints so we say it with the max length.
Is this every topic name has to be true or unique or should say and we can set that unique equal to
true then we have let's say another model for a web page and essentially each of these classes is going
to act like a table in your database and then we have category name your L and then we say models a
foreign key the character field the field.
So those are all different fields.
And then you can pass parameters.
But no here how the category equals to models that foreign key and the way pass topic there because
that's going to be a foreign key from the topics model then we can have the web page model where we
have the topic again that's foreign key the name which is a character field and and you are all models
that you are all field.
And if we can then have a specific method to return the actual name.
So if you say Prince web page it grabs the name and after we set up the models we can migrate that database.
So don't worry if you didn't fully understand that code in the next lecture we're going to be coding
and explaining a lot more.
So again when we actually set up the models we can migrate that database.
And this basically lets Shingo do the heavy lifting of creating sequel databases that correspond to
the models we created.
And this is the part that's really cool about Django.
You can just write up those classes.
And then with a very simple command jingoes going to do all the heavy lifting of creating a single database
that corresponds to that model you can do this entire process with just a simple command.
Python managed up-I migrate which we talked about earlier in the course when we got a warning from Django
telling us to do this migrate call but now since we actually are going to work with models we can do
it.
After that we then register the changes to our app shown here are some generic app one.
So we would say Python managed up-I make great creations and then your application name app one first
that whatever you happen to call it we then migrate the database one more time.
I manage that PI migrate and then later on we can actually use the shell from the managed up-I file
to play around with the models and will show you how to do that as well.
So in order to use the more convenient admin interface with the models however we need to register them
to our applications admin that py file.
Now we can do this with the following code.
We say from Jingo that contrib import admen and then from app thought models or whatever app happens
to be name you import the actual models.
Model one model too in those previous examples that would be things like topic or web page day accessed
etc. and then we say admin that site that roadster and you pass in the model as an argument then with
the models in the database created we can use jingoes fantastic adamant interface to interact with the
database.
And this is something that's really cool and awesome about Django.
It's one of the key features the fact that once you set up these databases it's jingoes going to do
all the heavy lifting to create those models into Jeng into databases and you're going to have full
admin interface so it will show you how to log in to the admin interface and then you can read what's
going on in the models.
So in order to fully use the database and the admin we're going to need to create a super user and we
can do this with the following command.
Ice on managed up high create super user and then you're asked to provide a name email and password.
So remember when we actually are cutting through this in the next lecture or the next couple of lectures
that you're going to have to remember or write down the name email and password we provide for this
super user OK.
Then once it's set up the models it's always a good idea to populate them with some test data.
And we're going to be using a library to help with this called faker which produces fake data and will
create a script to do this as well.
All right.
I know I've been talking a lot and we've discussed a ton.
Don't worry if you didn't actually understand how to implement all that stuff.
But hopefully you did get a general idea of how the Django models the databases and the admin interface
kind of connect with each other in the next lecture in the next few lectures were going to be coding
through an example of all of this to really help your understanding.
Okay.
Thanks everyone.
And I'm excited to get to the next lecture because we're really going to see the power of Django coming
up with the models.
Thanks and I'll see you there.