Hello everyone and welcome to part one.
We're going to be discussing tables and set him out.
Tables and HTL consists of several tag's working together and those tags are the general table tag that
lets your age him well know that there's going to be a table here.
Then there's the T head tag which allows you to actually set the first row or the header row of the
table and then inside of that you have th which are the actual elements that we're going to be placing
inside of that header or head row the very top row.
Essentially the name of the columns in the table and then beyond that you have the table rows and then
you have t d for each of the table elements inside corresponding to each column.
Now here I've shown the breakdown with just the opening tags every opening tag would later on have a
corresponding closing tag.
So with that being said let's go ahead and construct the table to understand all of this and get a real
sense of how all these different tags work together.
I'm going to jump to the Adam text editor now.
All right.
Here I am at the Adam text editor and I also have a browser open to the html file I'm working with right
now which is just called tables that age HTML.
You can call your HTML file whatever you want.
Let me just collapse that side directories so it can see the full HTML file a little better the first
time you're going to need is the table type which is basically going to declare that we have a table
and is going to autocomplete that there and everything we're working with is going to go inside these
table tags.
First thing I want to do after that is the table head which is the head.
And this is where your column names are going to go.
So right now if we save this and refresh our Web page we don't see anything because we really don't
have any content in the table yet.
But as I put a th which is basically the actual content that goes to the table head.
Wolves do something like a number.
Now my table will show something and here it is just a number.
Now let's add a couple more th elements are th tags for something like color and then let's add another
one.
Th.
And we'll do country saved that refresh over here and now we have number color country and note how
there a line there are lines as if they are the titles of the column names that are going to be coming
up.
So then the question is how do we actually add rose to the table.
And then how do we actually add table cells.
Well outside of this T head we say TR And that's going to stand for a table row and now we can do is
inside of this table row put in tiddy for our table cells.
So let's start off with a number and that corresponds with the first column which is the number column.
Let's put in the next cell.
And this is in the first row that first TR And now we need a color.
Let's put in something like red and Alice put in a country.
Let's just say USA will save this and refresh.
And now we can see that we're actually starting to construct the table.
Let me zoom in on this.
It's a little more clear.
OK.
So we can see we're actually constructing a table.
A lot of times you want your table to actually have a border and we'll be discussing styling tables
a lot more or we talk about CSSA SS But a quick way to do it is in this table 10.
Just do a space and add in border and Adam text editor is actually going to help you out here.
And if you just hit enter here automatically thought border for you and then just pasan a number like
one.
And then when you refreshed this after passing that number in you get to see this auto border created.
And like I mentioned there's a lot more styling can do instead of getting like such an ugly border for
a table.
But right now so help us differentiate rows and columns.
OK.
Let's practice adding in one more row.
Again it's TR for the table row and then tiddy for the table cell.
Now let's see what happens if we just add in one table cell values.
I just put in 100 and I click save and refresh here.
Note that I still get that 100 values.
So I can still add in values and basically have blank values for certain columns.
Now it's always suggested they try to fill out your table completely but just keep that in mind that
your table will still be able to generate.
There won't be an error thrown at all if you only have one corresponding value for your row.
So let's fill that in.
Next what you want is a color.
Let's just say blue chips and let's put in one more which is going to be a country unless you say France
I'm going to save that and let's refresh and there we have it one more row.
OK.
And that's really all there is to creating tables in him.
It's pretty straightforward.
Let's just quickly review the steps.
Everything we've done goes inside these table type.
We have an opening one and a closing one.
And then if you want to have a border here you can just say Borders equal to and then it quotes Harry
put in one.
If we put in larger numbers such as five basically what's going to happen is you will get a thicker
border.
Now I'm zoomed in here so the effect is a little more pronounced but let's make it really large say
50 and then refresh and see if we get a extremely thick border on the outside.
So you may be wondering well how do I actually edit these borders on the inside.
That's something we're going to discuss a lot more in the CSA section of the course.
Right now you can just put in one.
And that should make things clear enough as far as what's a row and what's a column OK.
Then after that we have the T head section and a t head section is differentiated from the TR section
in the sense that it's actually just the column name.
So it represents and it's in bold versus just regular text so we see number color country you can call
these sort of rewashed that basically defines how many columns your table is going to have.
Now if we remove this t head let me just cut that out save this and refresh.
You still get a table just fine.
So don't want to give the impression that every table requires a head tag.
You can build a table without the head.
So that's totally fine.
But you should try to at least for a viewer sake keep in mind is it readable without the T head.
And here I have put in the T head back in and for the head.
Those elements are under the th tag then everything else is a T R for t row the table row and then each
table cell inside of those rows is just Tiddy.
And you have to place them in the order that the columns come in.
Which is why we choose t head.
So we can always make sure we have a reference that corresponds to the actual order of the elements.
All right that's basically it.
Thanks everyone and I will see you in the next lecture.