Hello everyone and welcome to part one scope.
We've already discussed scope a bit in the past specifically in the javascript section of the course
but Python scope rules can sometimes confuse beginners.
So let's quickly go over the key rules of Python's scope Python's scope follows the.
Be rule local inclosing function local's global and builtin.
And what this actually means is if you define a variable name somewhere in your code and then later
on in your code you want to call that variable.
Python needs to look in what's known as the namespace which is basically where it knows what variable
names go where but sometimes it needs to follow rules to know what scope you're actually calling and
the order it goes in.
Is it first looks for local variables then it looks for inclosing function locals then it looks for
global variables and then finally if it still can't find that namespace it goes to the builtin.
So it's actually defined these four topics a little more so the local level or names assign that.
Anyway within an actual function that includes a function or lambda expression and they're not declared
global in that function meaning they don't use some sort of global keyword call.
Then we have the enclosed function locals and that's names in the local scope of any and all inclosing
functions.
The E-F Orlando expressions from inner to outer now has to do with functions within other functions.
Then we have the global level and those are names of sign that the top level of a module file or declared
global and ADF within the file.
And that again is either at the top level or using the global keyword.
Then finally if we still can't find that variable name we look into the built in level and those are
names.
Pre-assigned and the built in names module things such as Open the range function a syntax error or
even things such as the Eliane which has the builtin length function OK.
Let's actually walk through some simple examples to make Python's scope a lot more clear to you.
Let's hop over to the editor now.
OK to begin her discussion of scope.
Let's start off with a simple experiment.
Imagine at the top of the file I define X to be equal to 25 and then I'm going to re create some function
we'll call it my func.
It doesn't take any arguments or parameters but what happens is it sets X equal to 50 and then what
it will do it's going to return x.
So that's what it does.
And then what I'm going to do outside of this is say print x.
So take some time and think what the actual output is going to be when I run this file.
So I will say Python lodestar PI enter and I get out.
X is equal to 25 or just 25.
Hopefully that makes sense to you because we haven't even run this function yet.
All we've done is to find it.
The only thing that X here on line 7 is aware of is the Global X which is appear on line 1.
Now let's imagine this we say print and I call my phunk inside of that print statement.
Now remember this my function returns X after reassigning it to X equals 50.
Now if I save this and run it.
What do you expect to come out.
Well hopefully expected 25 and 50 so that actually makes sense because remember Line 7 is looking at
the Global X and then if I call my func it redefines that global x 25 to be equal to 50.
Only inside the scope of the function and then returns X which in this case it will print out 50.
Now sometimes what confuses students is this third line what happens if I say print x.
Now what happens if I say print x.
After I call my function in this manner.
So let's comment these out and see what happens.
So take some time.
What do you expect to happen here on lines 9 and 10.
I'm going to run this and will see.
I get x is equal to 25.
Hopefully that's what you also expected.
If you expect that x is equal to 50.
Let me quickly explain why that didn't happen and that has to do with scope when we read the fine x
is equal to 50 inside of a function that reassignment is limited to the scope of the function meaning
it doesn't actually do the re-assignment in what's known as the global namespace and that has to of
those scope levels remember it goes local inclosing functions global and then built in.
So here when we call my function X is only being redefined inside of this function namespace.
And then when I say Prince X it's going to call this Global X because it really has nothing to do with
this function call OK.
So let's see some more examples of EJB that scoping level in order to really understand what's going
on here.
So that's our a little experiment to kind of introduce the idea of scope.
But let's go ahead and create a land expression.
This will begin to show the very first level which is the local level.
So if I have a land expression that looks something like this Lamda x x to the power to this particular
x is local.
So this is a local level knowledge shoyu inclosing function locals.
And this is the next level.
So this occurs when we have a function inside of another function and which is known as nested functions.
So again for this lambda example you'd probably have this inside of another function but let's show
you inclosing function local's this next level and going to create a variable called name and say this
is a global name.
And the reason it's global is because it's not inside of any function it's at the top level of the stop
pie file which is sometimes also known as a module although we haven't really say that as a module and
aren't calling it in another the PI file.
It's just a simple dot PI file but it is outside of any function.
So it's at the global level.
Now I create a function called grete and inside is great function.
I'm going to assign name to be Samie and inside of this function I define another function called hello
and then I say print Hello last name then outside of all these functions I'm going to call Great let's
say this and hopefully you will know when I run this.
What's going to happen.
So I'll say Python notes that PI take your time.
And before we actually run this think about what you expect to happen.
Note here that I'm calling greed.
Think about this greet return anything or perform any action.
So we enter and we get nothing out and that makes sense because so far greets all it does is it resigns
name equal to Samie in its function name space here and then it has a function defined inside of it.
However no function is actually called Inside of Crete if we want to actually print Hello plus Sammy.
I have to call.
Hello.
So I've only to find that so far.
And look here how in calling Hello lined up with it's the call if I did this call hello.
Within function.
Hello.
That wouldn't make any sense.
It wouldn't know what Hello is.
And you'd get an error there.
So we're going to do this.
And now let's see what happens when I call Python it's supply I get.
Hello Sammy.
So now Samuel was used because the hello function was enclosed inside of the group function.
So what's actually happening here.
I have this global variable name inside of the function.
I re-assign name to be the Samie I assign Hello being equal to print Hello name and the most outer level
it first looks for name is right here inside this enclosing function.
If I put a hash tag here and comment this out then it's not going to find name outside of it.
So it's going to look at the next level which is going to end up being global.
So now let's run Python floats up high and we should see.
Hello.
This is a global name and there it is.
This is a global name.
So you can see here the different levels of where Python is looking for variable names in the name space.
And that's really the whole point of scope knowing what variables are going to be used if you have things
like nested functions.
And it's always important to remember and this is sometimes a point of confusion.
It doesn't matter if inside of a function scope.
I read the file name.
If I go back outside of this function completely and asked to print the name it's going to find it here
globally first.
It's not going to be able to go inside a function and look for it because it really has no business
going inside the function until it's been called.
And even if the function has been called that variable namespace is only here in this local function
scope.
So let me run this hit Python notes and I see.
Hello Samie.
This is a global name because I said name is Sammy.
So greets in its scope when it calls hello.
Name is equal to Samie.
But when I say Prince name it goes to the global one name.
This is a global name.
OK.
Now beyond this there is the built in level and the builtin level is just things that are already built.
So things like elhi end basically anything that pops up in this list here to help you out is built into
Python.
And these are things that you never want to actually read the fine.
You would never want to say Eliane is equal to 23 Otherwise you're never going to be able to call the
length function again.
You would have accidently read the fine in the global space.
So again these are built in function names in Python.
You should never overwrite these.
And you'll notice you've typed based off the syntax highlighting and based on the fact that it's already
trying to help you finish that statement before you've even defined it.
OK so let's talk a little bit little bit more about local variables.
When you declare variables inside of a function definition they are not related in any way to other
variables with the same names used outside of the function.
That's a key point I keep repeating myself on.
So variable names are local to that function.
And this is called the scope of the variable itself.
All variables have the scope of the block.
They are declared in starting from the point definition of the name.
So let's show you another example and it's going to seem like a repetitive example.
So if you kind of already get it maybe you can continue off with this lecture go on to the next one.
But if you're still a little confused Let's show you a couple of more examples.
So I've create a function and I define it at the top globally that x is equal to 50 and then I say DPF
take function X and I'm going to say colon here.
Prince X is and then we can say comma X there is kind of like a fast way to print something and then
I will say X here redefine it to be 1000 and then after that it will print x local x change to come
x.
So we'll save this and then outside of this I will call phunk X save it and then if a hit Python lodestar
PI note here it says X is 50.
So since it hasn't found anything redefining X before Line 4 it goes to the global space.
OK Ezekial 50.
Then locally we redefine X to be 1000.
And it says local Xchange to 1000.
But here's the main catch.
If I say outside of this function even after the function has been called Prince X and I run this you
get back to 50.
So here if we're in the global namespace we're going to look for things in the global namespace.
So the first time that we print the value of the name x with the first line in the function body Python
uses the value of the parameter declared in the main block above the function definition.
Next we assign the value there x to 1000 and the name x is local to our function now.
So when we change the value of x inside of that function the x defined in the main block remains unaffected.
Now what I mean by main block is the X appear.
So if that last statement what we're actually doing is we display the value of x as the find in that
main block thereby confirming that it's actually been effected by this local assignment.
Now let's say you are in a situation where within sight of a function you actually want to change the
global x.
So far it seems like you're only limited to changing the local x.
What if you actually wanted this function to reach out to the global level and rename ex-secret to be
1000.
How can we do that.
Well the way you can do that is with the global keyword call.
Now as a quick know it's recommended that you try to avoid using the global keyword call because doing
this if you have a really long line of code or a large file of code can really mess up your namespace.
If you're not super careful about it.
So again I'm showing it to you here but I don't recommend that you ever actually use the global name
or global keyword unless you really have to.
But basically what the global keyword does is it says hey I'm going to be using the global x when I
call X here I want to actually reach out to that global namespace grab that X and then play around with
it inside here.
So if I say DPF func X and the Klare global x and we're actually going to not even take any input here
we'll just say call the function grab x from the global namespace using that global keyword and then
say x is equal to 1000
then I'm going to save this in here what I'm going to do is say Prince before function call X is and
then say Khama X and let's comment these two lines out for now.
So all I'm doing here is I'm never act of only to find this function I'm never actually calling it I'm
just saying exercycle to 50.
So we would expect this to say print's before a function call x is equal to 50.
So I run Python notes that pi and it says before function call x is equal to 50 now I'm going to call
function and note here inside of this function on calling Global X which allows this function to reach
the global namespace and grab that X then after this I'm going to copy and paste this here and then
say after Save it run this.
And note what happened it says before function call X is 50 after the function call X is 1000.
So now with this global keyword I've been actually able to rename or redefine or re-assign something
in the global namespace.
So now the x 1000 is actually causing that effect to be permanent.
Again if I do something like this comment this out and I just say x is equal to 1000.
Then if I run this I get twice.
X is equal to 50 x is equal to 50.
So that global keyword allows you to reach out to the global namespace and actually clarify that.
No I do want to reassign that global variable x.
Again this can be really confusing if you end up having a bunch of global calls all over your pie script
so it's recommended they try to avoid global.
Instead what you should do is use return keywords.
So if you actually want to send back an X you wouldn't want to say x is equal to 1000.
You'd want to say x is equal to 1000 return X and then with that return statement you can use it in
the global namespace.
So then you would say something like x is equal to phunk and then run something like this.
And here we get 51000.
So this use of the return statement has pretty much the same effect as if we had the global keyword
without any of the risk of accidentally redefining something the global space.
OK so that's all we really need to discuss about scope in python we won't see such complicated examples
and we're working with Django.
But it is something I want you to be aware of as you continue to program.
If you have any questions I definitely suggest you check out the part 1 scope that Paice group which
has full notes and many more examples of what we covered here.
Always feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums if anything confused you.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.