Well everyone and welcome to part two content interaction in this lecture.
We're going to be seeing more examples of how to interact with the c.m. from the document object model.
We'll show you how to do things such as change text change the age to smell code and affect the attributes
the relevant files for the structure are part to content that H.T. T.M..
That's the actual file how open my browser and part to interact but yes that's just the copy of all
the commands I'll be inputting into the console.
Let's get started by opening up to content buddy T.M. in our browser.
All right so here we have the HTL document open and we're going to be doing is showing you how to change
the text it's him all content and attributes with the actual Dom.
So imagine that you've used queery selector to actually select an element from the document object model
and you call that variable.
My variable then you could use some of these methods to actually affect or interact with it.
So we could call my variable dot text content and that returns the actual text.
So you could set that equal to some new text if you wanted to change the text or whatever.
Team l variable you're messing around with or if you want it to actually affect the T.M. and have effects
on things such as the strong tags or the emphasis tags.
You could do something like inner or excuse me inner H.T. a male and that returns the actual age to
a male if you want to effect attributes or interact with them you can use the doc get attribute or the
set attribute.
Now let's show some actual examples of all this.
Here I'm going to be actually manipulating this page and I'm looking at right now.
So again to edit styles you've already seen we can use the dot style tag.
Now we're going to show you how to edit actually email or text or attributes.
So I'm going to grab this paragraph right here that I'm highlighting.
Let's show you how we can do that or create a new variable let's call it P for paragraph.
Although you can probably call it whatever you want.
Well say document dot query selector and I'm going to grab the paragraph tag here and if I type paragraph
I can see I have the paragraph tag and I can expand this to actually view everything that says to edit
styles.
I see there's a link here it's attributes.
So if I click on this attributes link it takes me to Google dot com.
So here I see Google opening up now what you actually want to do is change some of the text here.
So I will clear this and I'm going to say P Di
text content and I can set it equal to any thing that I want.
So let's call it all new text.
And then hit enter.
And now I see that I've actually changed the text here.
So it says new text.
Now imagine that I wanted to make the text bold.
Well what I can't do is this I'm not able to say text content and then passen a strong tag and say something
like I'm bold closing strong tag.
The reason I'm not able to do something like this I will see why what happens is because I'm just grabbing
the text content.
If I actually want to affect the age T.M. I need to grab the inner h tim L.
So I will say P dot inner HVM L and I'm going set it equal now to I previously did.
So let's grab this and just copy and paste it back grab it with the quotes and then hit enter.
And I can see now my paragraph is in bold says I'm bold and I can see that it's darker.
So that's different between text content and each T.M. if you want to actually pass in HTL tax when
you're interacting with the HTML then you're going to need to call in each team instead of just text
content.
Now let's show you how you can get attributes and set attributes.
So if we look down here there's a link to Facebook all the way here at the end so click on this.
It takes me to Facebook and says I'm another Hetter with the special I.D. so don't worry about that
for right now.
Instead what I'm going to do is clear my console and I'm going to grab everything with the special I.D.
so I'll save our special as equal to document weary selector and remember it's night.
So I say hashtags and say I can use CSSA style selectors and then say special and again you would use
there.
And again you would have to know that there's a special I.D. in the HP M-L here it's actually telling
me that but you'd have to actually reference the symbol to know this.
So it's not like special is just some sort of normal ID.
So here I can see now if I type in special I have heading for IDs with a special.
It says I'm in the header.
Looks like the header has emphasis.
And then I also see h ref to Facebook dot com.
Now how can I actually change this.
Well I can say this I can say variable special a is equal to.
And then I'm going to grab special dot and I will do a query selector on that LCA query selector grabbed
the anchor incontact
enter and now when I see special 8 I see that I only grab Denker tag so i can see that I can actually
call multiple queries selectors until I actually find or get what I'm looking for.
So here's the ref it goes to Facebook dot com actually want to get just the attribute.
I can say special
attribute and then I can grab the Tref itself if I only want to grab that link if I want to change the
attribute that I need to use the same attribute.
So I need to say especially the set attribute and the stakes in two arguments the attribute that you
want to change.
And then the actual value you want to change it to.
So I'll say HTP Yes and let's change it to something like Amazon.com
we hit enter and now we've actually changed this to Amazon.com.
So if I click on this link instead of Facebook we see that it takes me to Amazon.
All right.
So that's the general way of using these four methods member text content is just for returning the
text interchange team l returns the actual each T.M..
And if you want to effect attributes within something you need to do it with set attribute if you want
to just grab the attribute and get say attribute if you want to change it instead of doing just an equal
sign like we said earlier you said attribute where the first argument is the actual attribute and the
second argument is what you want to set it to.
All right thanks everyone if you have any questions feel free to post to the Q&amp;A forums.
And I'm happy to help you out.
I'll see you at the next lecture.