Hello everyone and welcome to that deploying on Python anywhere lecture some of the blame and process
steps may take a while especially some of the downloading of the libraries.
So keep this in mind before beginning this lecture.
Make sure you set aside enough time like 20 or 30 minutes to run through the whole thing and just click
on the resource link to get started.
We'll take you to Python anywhere.
Let's get started.
OK.
Here I am.
Python anywhere.
And as a quick note on another tab I also have a link to the repository we made and if you click here
on clone or download there's going to be a link here that's going to be important to us later on.
So make sure you're able to have this open as well should be on the main page of wherever your repository
is.
Well let's start off with Python on anywhere where you're going to do is sign up.
So if you click on pricing and sign up right now we'll create a free beginner account.
It's a very low CPQ bandwidth Web site and it's also you can't have your own custom domain on it will
be your user name dot Python anywhere.
Dot com.
If you end up expanding on this and wanting to work that more the pricing is actually pretty fair especially
if you really want to focus on Python apps.
You can read all about it here.
But for now I'm just going to create a beginner account and then you will pass in your username email
password and then password again going to sign up now.
OK.
So once you sign that and log then make sure you confirm your email if you plan to actually use this
more than once.
Right now I have an unconfirmed e-mail address so we can do that later on.
But once you have this web interface you'll notice that you have a couple of tabs you have the council's
files web schedule et cetera.
So coming to the consuls this basically is a console's tab that allows you to create and interact with
just Python and bash console instances.
Then the next thing over we have files and this allows you to upload and organize files within your
disk quota.
So right now our quota is 512 megabytes not a whole lot but more and more than enough for what we're
going to be working with later on if you decide to do a larger project.
You may need to pay in order to get a larger quota.
Then we have a web tab which allows you to configure settings for your hosted web applications which
will work later.
Then you also have a schedule tab that allows you to set up tasks to be executed at certain particular
times and also the databases tab which allows you to configure a sequel database for applications if
they require it also allows you to do a post gresse if you're actually on a paid account.
And I have all these tabs were mainly just going to be working with the councils tab and the web tab.
The first thing we're going to do is set up a virtual environments.
Now all you have to do is click here on Bash and this will open up a bash console for you should look
something like this.
They'll say loading console loading bash interpreter and then right here we have the actual console
and I'm going to zoom in a lot so you can see what I'm typing.
OK.
And what we're going to do is make a virtual environment so I'll say this.
M-K virtual D-NV.
So previously we had to use Konda create on our own computer to create a virtual environment I Python
anywhere it doesn't have the Anaconda distribution of Python.
But what it does have is this virtual NVI which is going to work pretty much the exact same way.
So then we're going to do say dash dash Python is equal to.
And then we will call this all type in Python and we'll say 3.5 because that's the latest version of
Python that's available on Python anywhere that come maybe by the time you're viewing this python 3.6
is going to be available.
It's Python therapist who's already released.
I'm not sure if it's already available in Python anywhere but our application will work with 3.5 or
3.6 either way.
And then the actual name of our projects.
So we'll call it my P R O J.
And that's the name of your project's virtual environment.
So basically what this is saying is create a virtual environment or make a virtual environment where
Python is equal to the version Python 3.5 and call it my PR Ojay so will enter.
It's going to run this and install all the setup tools and everything we need.
So again this may take a little while depending on the internet connection that we're using.
So be patient and I want to fast forward in time while this finishes installing everything OK.
So it's finished installing that took maybe about 30 seconds for me.
That should also not take a whole lot of time for you then here I have imprints sees might be Aro J.
That means my virtual environment is activated just like when we we're using conduit create zone what
I can do is check out what packages are already installed and I can just say hit list enter and that's
going to list all the packages that are already installed here.
So I have at the IRS packaging pit pipe arsing set up tools six wheel.
These are all very basic packages and tools that essentially just help you install other packages and
tools.
But what we need is Shingo.
So we're going to say this will say Pipp install and we're going to say that capital you space Gengel
equal to and then whatever version of Django you happen to have been using for your project.
The way to find out what version of Jingle you're using on your project is actually really easy when
you're going to do it on your own computer.
Open up the command prompt or terminal.
So I'm going to bring that in.
So this one's from my own computer.
This is the command prompt that my Windows machine.
Open up your terminal on your Linux or Mac.
And then what you're going to do is with your virtual environment activated or if you aren't using one
that's also OK.
Type in Python and then you're going to import Django and then you're just going to type Shingo dot
underscore underscore version underscore underscore enter.
And it should report back the version you were using.
And in my case it was 1.1 0.5.
So we will minimize that.
And then I will say jingoes equal to one point one zero point five enter and that's going to Pipp install
that specific version of Django.
And I'm really zoomed in here so I got kind of some weird looking output so I will zoom out a little
bit.
But essentially you should see something that looks like this is going to install a bunch of stuff and
it's going to kind of show the loading process.
All right.
So this may take a little bit of time.
So keep that in mind.
I'm going to fast forward in time.
It's looks like it's about just installing the collected packages so everything's been downloaded and
it's going to install again.
This takes a little bit of time.
Feel free to go get a coffee right now and I will fast forward in time and meet you back here.
OK so Ginger has finished installing for me.
I'm going to zoom back in here so he can see my command line a little better.
In order to confirm that Django has been installed what you can easily do is pass in the jingo Adam
in a command line tool.
So what we can do is say which jingo dash adamant up high enter.
And if you get something that looks like this back virtual environments my project been jingo had and
up high.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
It's basically telling you that when it runs Shingo dash adman is going to grab it from the virtual
environment.
My project which is exactly what I want.
So that means he has successfully installed this if your particular Gengel project depends on other
applications of Python.
You'll need to install those as well.
Our applications so far have been simple enough or we just need to install Django.
Well let's say you depend on other libraries like plotting libraries or data analysis libraries machine
learning libraries.
Those will be new to installed here so that would be another Pipp install step.
OK so now it's time to actually get a copy of our Get repository onto our hosted Python anywhere.
So this where you're going to come over here and then where it says clone or download.
You are going to copy this.
So whatever this thing is you're going to copy it to the clipboard.
Will say copied.
Come back here and then you can type it's clone and then right click or control V to paste that in there
it goes and then we're going to hit enter and it's going to clone it there.
It sometimes may ask you for your password or username depending whether it's public or private.
So keep that in mind since ARS is totally public.
They closed that no problem and we'll be talking about security things later on.
I'm showing you a very open loose way of doing things right now just to get the general ideas down.
We definitely don't want to do this for a more realistic project.
We've left our security key open and it's publicly available for viewing.
Definitely don't want to do that but the general process going to be really similar.
Or so I've cleared my console I had a lot of stuff in there and Connal Connal is basically on a Linux
machine.
You have to do is type in wups clear to clear a console.
OK so let's type LS to list everything we have read me that text and then Gengel deployment example.
I'm going to CD into Gengel deployment example just click tab to auto complete that and then type in
LS That will list everything.
Looks like we have learning templates going to CD into learning templates and then Emett jingo deployment
example or in templates list.
And I have my basic app that sequel like learning templates manage up-I templates.
OK so typically you're going to have models that you need to actually migrate and set up.
So this is the step in which you would do that.
You would say Python managed up-I migrate it enter make all the general migrations you have to do in
our case we didn't really have anything besides the admin operations.
We had no actual models in our applications.
If you do you'd see a lot more here and then the other thing you'd have to do is just like we did locally
say Python make migrations and then the name of your applications that you needed to make those migrations
to.
Such as in our case basic underscore app.
Again we don't have any models here so we shouldn't see anything here.
Whoops I forgot to say Python managers up high make migrations.
Basic underscore.
There we go.
So again no changes the text and app basic app.
If you do have models there you will detect those changes.
And then again you have to repeat Python managed up-I migrate.
OK so again no migration is to apply.
But those are the kind of steps we've done them before locally.
You'd have to do it again here.
All right so something else we want to make sure we do is we'll work if the admin interface we probably
need a super user.
So I have to say Python managed up-I create super user enter and then just create a supervisor.
Always the same person to be using all the time.
Let's actually get this training
and data that entered in the password
password won't show up and then pass it in again.
And then your super user will be created successfully.
OK so the database is set up all your migrations are done.
You created a super user you've marked down the password somewhere and you are ready to actually set
up your web application and that involves setting up the actual WSG settings and this basically just
involves telling Python anywhere to actually serve your application.
If someone visits your page so we're going to be doing is zooming out of this again.
And here we're going to go back to our dashboard.
So click on your dashboard.
Come back to it.
And then click on the web tab.
And then say add a new web app pop up a pop up box is going to appear and then you're basically going
to follow the instructions here.
If you want your own custom domain name you're going to pay for that.
So right now I'm just that Parian data practice that Python anywhere that I'm going to take this down
so probably by the time you're actually viewing this you can be able to see my example web site so I'll
click next then we'll say select a python web framework so we'll select Django since that's what we're
using.
And then we're using Django 1.1 0 with Python 3.5.
So we'll hit that as well.
And then there's a quick start new jingle projects.
It says this will create a brand new jingle app.
If you already have an app you want to use use the manual config instead.
Which means we actually need to go back and what we're going to do is hit manual configuration on this
and then we're going to select Python version and then the Maino configuration evolves.
Editing this WCI file this configuration file.
So we're going to do is when we click next to create one for you it's just a simple Hello World app
and then we're going to change it to actually point to our soul say next it's going to create that for
us.
And then what you can do now is copy this so we can open this Lincoln and you tab and you shouldn't
see your actual web site instead you'll just see something that says Hello world.
So it says hello world.
This is the default welcome page for a python anywhere app to figure more.
Click on the web app set up page so you can actually click on this page and it has a list of instructions
that were going to be following.
So it says everything that we need to do here.
So on this web tab page you're going to scroll down and to see virtual EMV.
So we'll we're going to do is enter a path to the virtual end of the.
So let's do that now we will click here enter path and it's going to be home all slash home slash your
user name.
In my case it's Parian or period data believe training or data practice.
That's why I called it.
You can view it actually appear on the actual euro.
So it says user orientated practice slash and say Dot virtual E and V S slash and then whatever have
you happen to have named your virtual environment.
In my case it was just my PR Ojay So we'll come here and say that virtually in VS and say My p r Ojay
they'll hit the check mark and it's going to line up perfect.
And as long as you did this all correctly you should be able to start a console.
So what we're going to do next is actually set up the source code for this.
So you come back up here to the code section and then what are we going to end up doing is setting up
the code.
So we'll do this.
So we need to set up the link to the actual project folder.
Now I've actually kind of forgotten so I'll show you how to get it again.
Just started con. and has virtual NVI going to bring you back to the bash con. we'll do the X Q. environment.
Take us back there and let me actually grab the virtual excuse me the file path to our actual project
so I can zoom in here.
So this way you can do in case you forgot it.
Like I just did it.
LS All right so there's the jingle deployment example Singhalese CD into jingle play an example.
LS again and I'm going to see the into learning templates and then I'm going to type p w d that's going
to print my working directory.
Let me zoom out a little bit.
So this actually prints out nicely.
So P.W. the.
And here it is.
So it's home.
Whatever your username is whatever you have to name that folder and then the name of your actual project.
So I will copy this and this is what I'm going to be using.
So we will come back to our dashboard and then paste that into the source code.
So again come to the Web tab then come down to code says enter the path here and we are going to enter
that path.
So let's make sure it starts with Slash home yep it's good to go so hit the check mark and that should
now show us that it's match the source code for actual project and now one of the very last things you
have to do is just set up our ws G.I. configuration file.
So click on that and it will take you to a place where you can actually end up editing that file and
you have this nice little editor in here.
And so what's really great about Python anywhere I really enjoy it because it's really meant for people
who love and use Python a lot.
If you're using another language don't use this site.
Obviously it's called Python anywhere for a reason.
OK.
So let's get to editing this going to zoom in so we can see it a little better.
There we go.
So the very first thing to show you is the hello world.
That's what it was displaying before.
And what we're going to do is just really all of this.
So this little line of code basically from line I guess around 13 to 47.
This was just the Hello World page.
So we're going Adley all of that because we don't need any more.
We're going to be telling it to go to our page.
And what's nice about Python anywhere's they actually kind of said it already up for you.
So what we can do here is scroll down to where it says Django and then start uncomment some of these
lines.
So we're going to say import os import Ciss for system and then we're you going to set up the path.
And again that's just going to be commenting these three lines so path if etc..
So it says right now home your user name my site we're going to need to change that to actually point
to your project.
So my project is not called my site.
It's underneath this jingle deployment example so the name of that repository.
And then the name of the project itself.
OK.
So that's what I need.
And then you can keep this here.
If path moments as paths as patho pentad that's totally OK.
And then from here on where are we going to do is do a couple more edits.
And what we need to do is change to our project directory.
So out here will say OS c h d r so change directory and we'll pasand the path variable that we just
defined as our path to our project.
So again all I'm saying right now so far is import os import Ciss path set equal to learning templates
if path on its path paths path out a pin path.
That's OK as well.
OS that change directory to the path we just created and then I need a Telecinco where the settings
that py module is located.
So one way to do that is through something that looks like this.
In other way to do that which is kind of a little more in line with what we did locally is say oh estop
environ set the fault the fault and then passen in all caps jingo underscore setting's underscore module
comma and then the actual path to your settings so that the path to see actual settings folder SLB learning
underscore templates that settings.
So that's kind of where the settings that py file is.
And then we're going to do say import Django Django setup and in fact a lot of this code is actually
up here already.
So you kind of scroll up will say custom WCI some of this code that we're going to be using as a peer.
So that's OK.
We can just get some practice writing in ourselves.
So what we do just as we're using a version of Jingle that's greater than 1.5 just say from Django that
core this guy and then we're going to save this what it save.
Then we will come back and actually check to make sure we have no gate where's.
So let's go back to the actual dashboard.
And then where it says web I'm going to click on this link and here it says welcome to index.
Hello click on other takes us to the other page and click on brand takes us back to the home page and
you'll notice if I click on admin I get this sort of weird Django administration it doesn't look as
nice as it usually looked for us.
That means we actually need to go back to the Web tab and tell where to look for the static files.
So here I can fill stuff out.
Hit log in and you'll notice that it still looks ugly.
So let's go back to the Web tab and fix this.
OK so coming back to the Web tab we have the web open here and we're going to scroll all the way down
until you see the static file.
OK.
So here we see static files and this is where we're going to be linking files that aren't dynamically
generated by our code like C Ss and Javascript and there's basically two main static files that we need
linked to one are these static files for the admin page and then the second one are your own static
admin files.
Now this particular project.
I don't believe actually had any static admin files so we'll create the link and then we'll also show
you how you can create new files and edit those to actually add in the static.
But first we'll show you the one that you're always going to have which is the static for the admin.
So the you are all that this goes under here is static slash admin put that in.
And then we're going to enter the path.
And this is kind of a long complicated path.
It's home slash your user name for the Web site.
So in this case it's well you use a name for Python anywhere that calmly be clear on that period data
practice slash and then the dot virtual end vs slash the name of your virtual environment they created.
So in my case it was my proj slash lib slash and then you pass in the Python version you're using.
So it's Python 3.5 for us years maybe Python 3.6 by the time you're watching this and then we say slash
site dash packages slash Shingo slash contrib slash admin slash static slash admin.
All right kind of a really long path so go ahead and pause screen if you need to copy and paste this.
And the next one we're going to do is actually set up our own static file.
So we'll keep this static admin and directory as it is right now and will come back in a little bit
and fix your own directory for own static paths.
But after you ever edit something here you need to reload your web app which means come all the way
up to the top and click here on reload the web that.
And then there's another thing we're going to have to do which is turn off debug mode and also make
sure that we've allowed our Python anywhere that com to be an actual host.
Because if you click this right now you'll get an error.
So you should get something like this a lot of hosts if you click here you'll get something like this
and it says make sure that Pierian data practice stop by anywhere that COM is to a lot host.
So in order to fix that we'll come back here and we're going to come to files will come to files on
Gengel deployment example go to learning templates and then learning templates is the name of the project
itself.
And then here we can see the settings up my file click on that because that's what we're going to be
editing.
And what's nice Python anywhere has this nice Python editor free to play around with.
So here we see everything that we usually saw and what we do say under a lot of hoes pasan a string
that is your username your Python anywhere username that is wups.
Make sure spell that right.
Practice slash.
Who's me thought Python anywhere.
Dot com basically whatever is hosting it.
So save that so we can save that and then let's come back to learning templates.
And here we can either create a new character or a new file.
So under learning templates all this outside one.
So here we see basic app learning templates templates and ways to create a new directory name and we'll
call it static it neither rectory and there's nothing in there right now.
So this is where you can upload static files later on.
So we've already gone over how to do static stuff.
But let's actually set up the link to it.
So it's under learning templates.
Static member it always goes there on the same level as the applications in the project.
Now we're going to come back to web and show you how we can add that.
OK so once we made those changes back at the Web tab we're going to reload the actual site.
Make sure those settings went through and then click again on configuration.
Open that and then you tab.
And we shall see.
Now welcome to index.
Hello.
And if you click on admen it will look like the normal nice adamant means your static files were actually
linked together.
Now what happens if you go to somewhere that is not on your Web site so let's say you go to your name
and then pass some random numbers enter.
Notice that we are still in debug mode and you're seeing the error because the bug is equal to true.
If you change it to false Shingo will display a standard 404 page.
So let's actually make sure that happens we don't want debug.
It reveals a lot of stuff about our actual code.
So we'll come back here at this hour.
Let's get back the old disallowed come back to files and then come back to the point example.
Learning templates and then come back to our learning templates project the has are setting up py file.
Click on it and then here where it says the bug will set it to be equal to false.
Will save this and then we're going to come back to learning templates and then come back to web and
then I'm also going to now set up the link to the other static files so there is no other static files
right now but maybe you have static files for your projects that you had actually do this.
So are you going to end up doing is the following you will set the URL to just be slash static as it
suggests you enter and then we passen the file path to our actual static file.
So in our case if we go back it's under home Pre-N data practice slash.
And then let's make sure we actually find that file in order to do that I'm going to double check and
scroll back up and open our files tab in the new tab so I can check on it.
OK.
Jingle deployment example learning templates.
Static.
OK.
So it's under Jingo the plumbing example so let's scroll down here past that back in so slash jingo
that's the placement dash example slash.
Then let's click on it again.
Learning the underscore templates.
Perfect.
So all the way to the right learning underscore templates slash static and then now this is linked to
the static CSSA files.
We don't have any on our particular example but this is what you would do for your own examples.
OK.
So let's try this again make sure we reload these changes.
Take time to reload and then we're going to open up our file again.
Our actual Web site great.
And now it's working and everything's linked so if I come to the admin it's link to the admin static
files and if I had my old static files those would also be linked.
And I also noticed that if I say slash something that doesn't belong I get a not found 404 page.
Now you can eventually put in your own 404 pages and we'll see this all again when we talk about clones
later on.
All right.
So this was a super long lecture.
I know it's a kind of hard to separate out the steps because it's kind of all one long flowing process
but hopefully you saw that Python anywhere has a lot of built in stuff that's ready to help you out.
OK.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Q&amp;A forums.
But definitely make sure that you followed all of the steps even if you mess one of them up everything
further than that can be messed up as well.
OK.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.