Hello everyone and welcome to the Urals with templates code examples lecture this lecture.
We're going to be coding through everything we just discussed in the previous lecture.
As a quick note the project for this lecture and the Project for the entire section can be found under
the Gengel level four folder in your notes and it's called template project.
All right let's get started.
I'm going to start the project entirely from scratch and Adam text editor I think it's always great
practice to get through the workflow of starting up your project setting up your settings up high file
ex cetera.
You can skip ahead if you don't want to go through that process if you just want to meet me at where
you would start at the template project.
OK let's hop over to Adam editor and get started.
All right.
So I have a folder called Jingle level 4 that is totally anti-right.
Now what I'm going to do is after setting up my virtual environment that's optional of course I'm going
to CD into it so I'll say CD into Django level 4 and then I'm going to say Django dash Addleman start
project and then we'll call this project learning underscore templates and sets going to be what we're
doing in the section the course learning templates saw.
I'll enter make sure that all sets up automatically and then after that we'll also set up our basic
application.
This will just be a one application project.
OK.
So I can see here have learning underscore templates ready to go.
So then again what I'm going to do is say CD into the learning templates and then I'm going to say Django
ash admen star app and we'll just call this basic underscore app and enter.
And that creates our application perfect.
We have basic app and learning templates and incited this.
I'm also going to create a new folder called templates and then inside of that let's create an actual
other folder that matches the name of our application.
In this case it's basic app perfect.
Now let's go to settings up pine and make sure that our setting's is aware of our templates directory
and the fact that we have a basic application here.
So as always we come here and set up template underscored the are equal to OS path that join and then
I join my based directory with templates and hopefully the search field really naturality.
You don't have to keep looking this up.
I know when I was first starting out I constantly had to look up this exact line of code that as you
get used to started the project over and over again this becomes really natural to again installed apps
we want to make sure application is in there.
So we say basic app save that and then coming down to our actual templates let's add in our templates
directory and then what we're going to do is say template the error save that and that should be all
we need to do for now.
You can always master all of this other stuff later.
OK.
So let's come back to basic app and we're going to be discussing here is how to use those relative URLs
in order to actually show all that though we need a couple of HVM files that we're actually going to
be linking to.
So under templates under basic app let's create a couple of files will say create based HVM L and we're
actually not going to do anything with this file for now.
We'll do that in a subsequent lecture but we'll keep it in for an hour or also create a new file called
index the HTL.
They'll be our home page.
And then again under basic app we'll create in other file and we'll call this other HVM L and this will
just be a quote unquote other page to link to using the relative Your else.
And then finally let's create a page that's actually going to have all our information about relative
your templates so you can call this file whatever you want.
I'm going to give it a really obvious name so I understand what it's about.
I'll call it relative.
Underscore Yoro underscore templates.
H Tim L.
A really long ugly name but that way there's no mistake of what's going on in this age HTML file.
Ok so I'm going to work with everything right now but base team L.
You can feel free to close Bastet h t m l.
We'll talk about this file again when we talk about template inheritance and then we need to we can
clogger settings that py file Donelly the Wacom guide.
So all relative your templates save that other.
Let's put in some Each T.M. code save that and then index H-2A now.
Save that.
OK.
So in all of this let's add a heading in that way once we actually visit the page with jingo we know
what's going on.
So I'll say welcome to index save that in other.
I'm going to make a heading one that says welcome to other and then relative your all templates will
say H-1 welcome to relative your old templates and this is where we're actually going to be messing
around those template tags that we just learned about in the previous lecture to actually show all these
pages we need to set up the views so let's come to our basic app come to views that pi and set that
all up.
So again all we're going to be using is the render function these are going to be really simple views
we're not creating any forms or any models.
So we're just essentially going to return to the actual pages we'll say.
Index taken that request and then I'm going to return render passen that actual request for the page
and then just a path to it under templates so under templates all of these are under the basic app folder.
And then for the index page just index that each T.M. now we're going to do a really similar thing for
the other ones so for the other page and it's kind of a general name so maybe when you're creating your
own web applications don't create such a general render.
Or excuse me it's such a general other page.
It's kind of probably a bad name for it.
And then we're all say basic app slash other than each T.M. and then the other view we'll just call
it relative.
And this is going to be the page that has those examples of how to actually create relative paths so
say return render pass in the request and then pasan.
In this case basic app slash and that kind of ugly name it is relative your el templates.
Lits.
H Timo OK.
Save that.
And now we have our views ready to go.
Now we need to set up our Urals to actually point to these views.
And this is where we have to make sure we set up the orals correctly to actually use the template tagging
correctly.
So let's start off with the your elves for the project itself.
So coming to learning underscore templates remember the name of our project will come to you or else
that PI file scroll all the way down.
And here we can see the link to the admin page.
Let's create the links to the other pages so that means we import the views from our application.
So we'll say from our basic app import views and then what I'm going to do here is set up the actual
import.
So we'll call your l.
And then I need to use regular expressions here will say your L carat dollar sign and I'm going to pasan
for the index page views dot index and then give it the name index.
Remember that's one way we could do this.
If you want kind of a Southern directory so for instance that your configuration we can do something
like this.
You are el regular expression carrot and let's say anything that starts with basic app slash and then
we'll call include
all say basic app or else.
All right save that.
So again just to reiterate what this is doing with the oral patterns when we use this function of views.
That means we're directly calling it from the function.
So using this regular expression.
If someone just comes to your domain page that's that 1 2 7 0 0 slash 8000.
Ill just say OK go to views grabbed the index and show it to this person on the home page then if someone
goes to our Web page slash basic app.
So again carot symbols anything before that slash basic app and then the name of the actual page or
the view such as basic app slash relative or basic apps.
Other basic apps flash etc. then we tell it OK go to the basic app Urals page for the subsequent views
to show or the subsequent mapping of the Oreilles which means we come over here to our basic app right
click on the basic app folder create a new file called your L's not.
And now we have the urls that pi file for application.
And this is where we need to make sure we set stuff up correctly.
There's going to be a namespace that we need to set up.
So right now inside your application you're going to say from jingo Siona for configuration that you
else import your L and then we're also going to need to save from.
And this is where you have many options you can just say from DOT in poor use I just from habit like
to say from basic app import views.
Definitely check the Pepp on what your official styling should be.
But I like doing this from a teaching perspective just because it's really clear where the CS is coming
from instead of saying that dot.
So again some of my styling here is really tuned more towards teaching this topic versus what you would
actually do for a full on Project.
Right.
So this is what I was referring to as far as like setting that namespace whenever you're going to be
using template tagging.
So this is for template tagging what we need to do.
Zoom in here is set a variable name a global name called app underscore name and jingoes going to automatically
look for this.
And then you need to set this equal to whatever the name of re-application is app name is equal to basic
app as a string.
And this is what's going to allow us to use that template tagging to actually tell Django OK look under
the basic app and then find that you are all that matches.
And then we have our you all patterns list here.
And that's all I can say.
Your El and we'll use regular expressions again and we'll say for relative slash and then we can say
dollar sign for anything after elative we will call views dó relative and we can give it the name equal
to relative.
Now let's create another view or excuse me another link.
For the other of you that other that each time I'll pitch a slash dollar sign here and we can say viewers
stop other name is equal to other all right.
Save that.
So basically what this is saying is OK if you're coming to your project page and you see something that
says home pay domain dot com slash basic app slash then you're going to come over here go to basic appier
URLs and then say OK domain name dot com slash basic app slash relative gives you the relative view
domain name dot com slash basic app slash other comes and gives you the other view and later on we're
dealing with clones.
We'll talk about how to continue on a regular expression here to show pages for specific users and all
that kind of stuff.
But right now just focusing on templates and your all templates.
Okay.
So this should all be set up.
Now let's come over here to our relative underscore your underscore templates on each table.
And let's show you how to actually implement those templates.
Everything we've been talking about haven't shown yet.
So we'll call an anchor tag here.
And the big part of an attack is the trick for you actually are telling it to go to a file.
And we've seen before that we usually do something like this basic app slash other HTL and then we say
this links to the other page or something like that.
So we want to replace this so that it's relative and we don't have this actual pathway here.
And that is relative to the actual application.
So can find it.
So since we're going to be inputting actual essentially tags and code we use a percent sign here for
that template and then we use the keyword you are el and then inside of this instead of single quotes
is the name of that allocation.
So I'll say basic app Colin.
And then that name of what you want to show.
So if we come back to you remember your L's that PI file I have at name basic app this basic app is
what needs to match over here that's where this is from basic app.
It's not from the folder name.
It's from this app name right here.
And then this other name is what we're going to look for for the second part of this.
So we'll say other.
And that's all you need to do for the your all template tagging and this is the way it's going to be
used in the future for Django 2.0.
The other ways will eventually go away.
And this is going to be the way of the future and obviously you can see that it's actually pretty simple.
The key thing to note here is a naming convention.
So you need to set up an app name inside your applications your pie file.
That's the first part of this.
On the left hand side of this colon in on the right hand side of the colon is a name it looks for.
So over here on your PI that's the name is looking for.
OK so we will save that.
And let's see if this all worked.
Make sure they don't forget anything.
I'm going to say under learning templates Python managed to apply and I will say run server.
And let's hope this all worked out and we don't have to debug anything.
Ok looks like I'm forgetting something.
And I forgot to include.
OK so says here I include is not defined so it's come back to your Allsopp pie over here.
Forgot to do this include save that.
Let's try it again.
All right.
Now looks like we are getting something running so let's copy this.
Bring in the browser.
See if it works.
So far so good.
Looks like it says welcome to index.
Now it's time to really test this out.
I'm going to go to basic underscore app slash relative enter and out says Welcome to the relative your
all templates.
And remember we have to use this slash basic app slash relative because that's what we're doing in the
project.
Or else that py file and the project is up high file.
I'm saying right here if something starts of basic app go to basic app or else to get the next piece
of it and then basically you him saying OK if it says basic apps like relative then bring back that
relative view which is the views that read to which links to this h tim l file.
OK so let's see if this template actually worked for the link coming back to the browser here it is
again.
So it says here at the other page.
Let's hit the link and it says welcome to other.
Perfect.
And this we can see right here is basic app slash other and that's what you have to do for your template
tagging.
It may have seemed like a complicated process at first but it's really actually not so bad.
All you had to do was set up that app namespace and then set up the name set up the mapping and you're
good to go basically.
Now you can easily call the URL template tags.
OK so we covered the very basics of how to use your template tagging.
Let's show a few more examples for sites or pages that you typically don't have within your own custom
application.
Things like the index page are things like the admin page but a quick note before we get started on
that.
A really common bug or error that will be a head scratcher is if you accidentally leave an extra line
here in the string either before you have this or after you have that what happens is Django ends up
looking for space.
Basic app as a string instead of just basic app as a string.
Or they use the name other blank or a space there.
So make sure that the actual quotes end up touching that that can be a really tricky error to solve
because when it prints it out it says oh I can't find the name other.
And then you'll look over here and your spine you say no I really do have the name of what's going on
here.
So definitely be careful of this one.
That's a really common error and it happens to me sometimes and it's a big head scratcher.
So keep an eye out for that.
OK.
Let's move along to show you how you could add something like the admin page as a anchor tax will say
ref per percent sign and then for this again you call your L and in this case you're going to call admen
index.
So basically what's going on is if you go to settings that pine your project you'll notice that not
only is your basic app a application but also jingle that.
Adamant and we don't actually have that open.
But if you wanted to you could open up the jingle source code or just check out the application admin.
That's something that always gets imported as an installed application.
But inside of that in it's own Urals not py file.
There is an adamant application with an index named view that it will take you to something to note
here is that in order for this to work sometimes you have to make the migration just because admin wants
it that way.
So we can go ahead and do that.
So it can say Python managed up-I migrate it enter it will run all the migrations for everything that's
a default application and then we can actually say Python managed up-I run server enter and then we
can bring in the browser page and here I have it on welcome to index.
Let's take it to a basic app slash relative.
And now actually forgot to put some text in there.
The anchor tag.
So let me do that first.
So if you notice I have my maker Tag but I picked up that text in there.
So let's bring that in and let's make this a link to like come here.
Link to Addleman and we'll save that see if that gets updated as I refresh the page.
OK.
So I just refresh the page are here.
You can see I refreshed it and now it is linked to oddments unethically linked to admin.
It takes me to the admin page so we can expand on that.
And we see jingo administration username and password.
I could hit back if I hit the other page it takes me to the other page.
OK.
Let me show you one more example of how to get to the index page which is also a little different because
it's not in your own application.
I'll move this aside show it to you here for this it's actually even simpler.
All you have to do is create an anchor tag and the ref again it's the block.
But in this case it's your L and just straight up index again to make sure that there's no spaces before
or after index in that string.
So we can save that and let's say linked to index and let's refresh my page and says OK welcome to other
let's go back here.
Refresh this and it says the other page link to admin linked index.
And there's my index page.
OK.
So those are three main examples that you're going to be using your own application view.
Know the admin index view and then just the home view.
And again keep in mind with these spaces that could really trip you up hopefully saw this is a pretty
simple process if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
I'm always happy to help out but this is a great way to use relative your Ural and the power of templates
in your Gengel project.
I'll see you at the next lecture.