Hello everyone and welcome to part three of the bootstrap section of the course where we talk about
Neph bars Neph bars are those navigational bars that you often see on the top of the Web site.
We've actually already seen them on booze trips his own Web site and in this section of the course we're
going to show you how to manage to create the basics of NF bar.
So when we start out coding we'll actually code line by line a very basic nav bar and then later on
we're just going to be copying and pasting from the course notes and the reason for that is a lot of
the class calls that bootstrap uses for the nav bar components are really repetitive and kind of hard
to memorize.
There are things such as navs space nav bar dash nav and it gets a little confusing and the naming convention
is a little bit of a poor choice specially we're trying to memorize things.
So we're really just going to be copying and pasting to focus on just accessing the information or learning
what it does seeing what's available if bootstrap instead of memorizing how you could code out a bar
from scratch.
So we'll focus on just the basics for cutting it out by scratch.
Everything else was going to be copy and paste from the course notes so keep that in mind as we continue.
We're also going to see briefly how to connect and HDMI LPs to javascript and Jake Query and we haven't
really discussed those two technologies yet and we're definitely not going to dive into them really
that deeply at all this lecture but we actually need them for some functionality of the nav bar such
as a dropdown menu being on the nav bar only really works when you connect the HTML page to Jake Query
and Javascript.
So again this lecture really not going to talk much about javascript.
Jake Query we're going to do that in future sections of the course but we will show you now how to connect
the nation email page to some online hosted javascript.
Jay queery codes.
All right.
Let's go ahead and get started by jumping straight to the editor in our browser.
OK so here you have my editor open a have an H T M L file open and I've already linked that to the latest
compile the modified C Ss of bootstrap.
And here I have my body ready to go as well.
So if I come over here to the project page it's link up.
First let's check out how we can find more information about nav bars in the documentation of bootstrap.
So if we come up here to bootstrap you can actually see there's a navigation bar already on that strip.
You can see it says getting started the SS component so this is what a typical nav bar looks like.
As you begin to explore the page and if you just come here to components will take the components page
and down here there's a nav bar section so click on that.
Now we can see some information about the fault nav bar and we can see that it requires javascript plugins
for certain things such as collapsing and dropdown menu which are going to be talking about later on.
So here is an example of an app bar.
There is a brand.
Some links a dropdown menu some search tools link an inlet dropdown menu on the right hand side and
you can copy and paste this entire code if you want to take a look at all this.
Instead all we're going to do is start off a building up the very basics and then we're going to add
in components from the course notes.
So let's show you how to just build a very basic nav bar in your age team file and then we'll start
copying and pasting from the course notes and just a little bit.
All right so the very first thing we do is called the Navteq that's the NIV tag that's going to be an
team L that we can use to actually begin to build our NAV bar.
And what we will do here is give it the class nav bar space nav bar dash default and we'll be adding
a few things to that class later on to explore a couple of more things about it.
And within this Navteq ongoing to create a divide so that it take a DIV tag here and give it the class
nav bar dash header and this will actually be the header of the nav bar which is usually known as Brande's
So this is where your company's brand or the main name of the Web site is going to go all the way on
the left and inside of this we add in an anchor tag.
There's an H ref there.
And the reason for that is usually when you click on that link it takes you back to the home page which
is leave that as a hash tag for now.
Now we'll call it company.
Let's save that refresh our page and see what it looks like.
OK so here we see that we have company.
However right now it doesn't look like the actual bootstrap company.
So if we come back up here we can see with the nav bars if we scroll down to nav bar that brand usually
looks stylized.
It's come back here this looks just like normal the same links.
So we end up doing is inside of the anchor tag add in a class called Nev bar dash brand.
And hopefully you can begin to see that a lot of the classes start with the word nav bar.
Second get a little confusing as far as trying to memorize these things which is why reference documentation
is so important for the section.
But now if I refresh I can see it looks like a typical company call.
And as I mentioned here this Tref would usually take you to the home page you can really put in any
link here.
Just like for any other anchor tag so i can say HTP Yes.
Coal and coal say W.W. Google dot com.
Save that fire refresh this and click on this company.
Now it takes me to Google dot com right now.
We'll just leave this as hashtag and we'll discover later on how we can use the hash tag to link to
different parts of the page.
OK so we have a company brand over on the left now is discuss how to add in more components to the actual
navigation bar so outside of that div I'm going to create an unordered list and an ordered list is how
you add more things.
This nav bar and to make it look good we give it the class nav space nav bar dash nav pretty repetitive.
I know probably not the best name in scheme but that's how it goes.
That's why you reference documentation for a lot of this in inciters unordered list.
We put in list items and then we give an anchor calls where it just like the company or brand page we
could give a link to another page.
But right now we'll just keep it simple.
We'll call this item 1.
Put another one in here or tag and we'll call this one item to and let's see what they look like.
Now as I refresh this page and there is item one item to their leaks so I could click on them to go
somewhere but right now they don't really lead anywhere because a ref is just a hash tag.
Now everything we've created so far is lined up to the left.
If I want to add components to this nav bar that are lined up to the right I just add in the class Navarrete
That's right.
And let me show you by adding in a new unordered list and putting in the class same as last time nav
nav bar.
And then I add in here now.
Barbash right.
And then we can add in some more list items saying on the right save that refresh and we can see here
we have on the right as they expand this I can see that it's kind of all the way to the right.
What I can do is put everything inside a container tag to try to balance that out a little bit so create
div container and this is something you'll find yourself doing often when you're working and bootstrap
is kind of put in these container tags.
To contain things save it.
Refresh this.
Now I can see this is nicely centered.
So even as I expand the page from the left and the right it's a little more centered around the middle
which is nice.
OK.
Make sure you don't actually wrap the entire nav bar on the container.
Let me show you what happens if we do that.
So if I wrap this entire nav you're in the container.
What's going to happen is the entire nav bar is going to be centered and it will stretch across the
entire page.
So that's usually not what you want you want just the components themselves to be inside the container.
So lets undo that.
Let's do this.
Great.
So saving that refreshing here.
Now we have the nav bar as ready to go.
So as we continue I want to briefly discuss keeping a nav bar fixed to the top of the page.
Even as you scroll down and in order to really show that we need to add some more material to this page.
So I'm going to just copy and paste this from the notes but basically it's just a container class so
let's copy and show it says.
It's a container class with a Jumbotron inside of it says hello Lorem some lordship some other container
more stuff Florham up some some.
So if I save this refresh my page over here I can see that I can scroll up and down but you can see
as I scroll down I eventually lose the nav bar.
Now a lot of times that's how you want it you want it so that you scroll down the nav bar is no longer
visible.
Other times you may want the actual nav bar to scroll along with you as you go through the page.
So let me add in a little more content here.
We'll do one more alarm ipsum or at least two more so we can really get the effect.
Refresh this page so you can see I have a little more to scroll down up and down with but the nav bar
stays on the top and it disappears.
If I want the nav bar to actually be fixed the top of the page even as I scroll down I just come back
up here to where it says Nav. class nav bar space nav bar that default and I can add in this class call
right here which is nav bar dash sixt dash top and this will fix it to the top of the page no matter
if you scroll.
So right now have an activity.
Let's refresh this.
And you can see already the change is kind of obvious the margin on the bottom went away.
And as I scroll down the nav bar comes with me and the way to do that is just adding the bar at that
fixed top and other quick note on the nav bar.
Usually you will personally define the color using CSSA But if you want to stick to the basics but you
don't like the light color there's a nav bar dash dash Inv. class you can add and here and this will
essentially just make it dark and invert the colors.
OK.
So that's all I wanted to show right now.
Let's take these out.
Wups come back here.
Like I said let's delete these.
The fixed top and also the inverse.
Call save it refresh.
And let's also get rid of all this junk right here.
Those last paragraphs are coming back down.
Going to get rid of what we added here.
Just so we can focus on the nav bar right now.
So refreshing this.
I only have my nav bar.
OK.
A big thing about now is bars especially a strap and also do a bit with the grid system is when you
collapse it it actually forms what's known as the hamburger.
And if I come back up here to the components page of the Get Bitstrips site you can see as I begin to
collapse this down I get this little hamburger icon.
The reason it's called Hamburger is basically you have two buns and a burger in the one and a click
that.
Then I get the rest of the left bar right now.
You'll notice that even as I squeeze this browser all the way I don't get the actual collapse of the
burger icon I just see the actual items beginning to reformat themselves.
But I don't get the collapse.
So let's show you how you can actually get that collapse in and to do that.
I'm going to delete a lot of a lot of what we already have here.
So let's get rid of these divs and I'm going to copy and paste from the notes and then walk through
that.
So it's copy and paste what's underneath the collapsible container here.
So I just copy and paste it a lot of stuff so let's walk through it and explain says I refreshed this
we can see we have this brand linked link and dropdown but the dropdown doesn't actually work yet.
And we'll explain why in just a second.
But expanding this let's actually show what I copied and paste it here.
And this is all from the notes.
So here I have my div class nav bar Hetter and we actually had that before.
Then I added in a button right here.
And basically we have this brand and toggle get grouped for what is essentially a bit immobile display.
And this is going to be the code that actually creates the hamburger Rikon.
So right now I have this button call and it says class nav bar toggle collapsed.
So even with this already as a part of my nav bar as I begin to drop down I can see that it becomes
the hamburger icon if I click on it nothing happens right now but I can see that it does collapse.
Now that I've added those lines of code.
So hamburger icon as I expand I get back the nav bar bullets explore what's actually going on here.
So here's the code for the hamburger icon.
And basically what it is it's a Spanish class.
It says Esser only toggle navigation.
And then we have these three calls for the cumbers and we can see as I collapse this I get those three
icon bars I can add in more here.
So let's make that for now.
And if I refresh this I can see actually get four icon bars in if I keep going if this add in the bunch
more refresh I can see him adding in more icon bars here.
However it's typical just to use three.
So let's save it with three.
Refresh the page and we can see you have the three that little hamburger icon.
OK so this is the actual code for the hamburger icon.
Again just using the class icon bar and then toggling of navigation.
So that's all inside this button for the button class is nav bar dash toggle space collapse and there's
some more information here that usually just be copying and pasting.
All right.
So that's all under the F var header.
And then anything inside of click collapse nav bar that collapse goes into the hamburger.
And basically what that means is this.
So anything any unordered list that you add in that's inside of a div with this class to collapse nav
bar bash collapse is going to be collapsed into hamburger.
And she what I mean by that is let's add in an ordered list.
Outside of that.
So I'm going to add an unordered list.
And just like we did last time at the very beginning we'll give it the class
nav bar or nav space nav bar dash nav
and we'll say something like Hello.
So let's save this.
And you notice Hello here no longer goes into the hamburger.
So as I expand this I see brands.
Hello.
Link link and then a dropdown menu.
Then as I begin to collapse this everything that was inside of this div class had collapsed nav bar
that collapse went into the hamburger whatever was not inside of that which in this case was this halo
happens to not go into the hamburger and basically details the same behavior we saw last Tyne-Wear just
get squeezed down but doesn't actually go into the hamburger.
All right.
So that's what that class is doing.
And usually you're going to put almost everything inside the collapse.
Now if Mark collapse unless it's really so important they don't want it to go in this hamburger class.
But it's really common.
Just put everything inside the collapse.
Especially for mobile viewers the last thing we need to do however to actually complete this is if we
expand back or menu here and we can't refresh this well let's save this and then refresh as we see we
have the two links and then the dropdown menu but the drop down menu is not working.
And we also noticed that when we collapse this the dropdown menu here wasn't working.
And that's because we actually need calls to query in javascript to make those functionalities work.
And the way we're going to do that is in our case we're just going to copy and paste from the notes
and later on we'll show you how to actually grab stuff from Jake Query.
So either go to code that J.Crew dot com to grab this or just copy and paste it from the notes but we're
going to do in our case is copy and paste this and put it at the very bottom.
Of our body call right here.
And what this is doing is copying and pasting a script call to Jake Query and this one is copying and
pasting the bootstrap Javascript.
And if you went back to the very first page of javascript you probably noticed that there were some
calls there that you could have also copied and pasted so if bootstrap went to download bootstrap as
we scroll down here we saw there was a modified CSSA but there was also this bootstrap Javascript.
So that's what the second line is right here.
This bootstrap javascript that's what I'm copying and pasting from this other line is code that J.
Queried dot com.
That's actually a link to Jay queried.
Yes which we're going to talk about much more later when we talk about Jay query and how it connects
to Django.
But right now you can just copy and paste these two lines from the notes save this and then refresh
our page.
And we should see now that the dropdown menu is actually work.
So here we have dropdown items.
And as we collapse this we see the hamburger icon I can click on it and now everything is working.
All right.
And if you want more details on how to actually add in your components the dropdown you can there check
the documentation which is really good.
Or just check out the notes and you can see here that's basically just another unordered list with the
class dropdown menu.
And then you can add in links list items there.
OK.
Thanks a lot everybody.
If you have any questions feel free to post in the Q&amp;A forums.
I know this was a lot of stuff especially if these kind of goofy class names.
But I want you to really get out of this is being able to reference the documentation for nav bars and
know what's possible if bootstrap.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.