Hello everyone and welcome back to a real left off last time.
So last time we created the sample class it's very simple.
It just has the past keyword.
But really what we're going to have in classes are attributes and methods attributes are characteristics
of an object methods or operations we can perform on the object.
So for example what we will be doing is creating a class called Dog an attribute of a dog Maybe the
dog's breed or the dog's pet name a method of a dog can be something like the bark method which will
return a sound we can say Prince will fluff or something of that nature.
So let's start off by learning about attributes.
So I will make this class B dog and then let's change sample so be dog here and let's say instead of
lowercase X we'll call this my dog.
Kind of like the same way we created something called my list and they shut the type of my dog.
So we'll save this run Python it's not pi.
And here it can see class.
Main dog.
So far so good.
So we you do is start off with attributes the syntax for creating an attribute is self datt the attribute
name equals something.
But there's a special method.
So whenever you have a class where you're going to be doing is defining methods inside that class and
the methods look like functions inside of a class.
So we start off the DFA keyword and then a special method has a set of underscores surrounding its name.
So we say underscore underscore in its underscore underscore then we passen self and then we can have
a colon here and here I will just put in pass.
So this is the most basic special method you can have the in its method and that stands for initialization
and this self keyword is always necessary.
Basically what the self keyword here does is it tells that this method refers to itself itself being
the actual class object.
So if we save this and run it we shouldn't see anything else different pop up.
So we still have class dog who we're going to do now is inside this initialization method.
In that method a member has two sets of underscores surrounding it defining it as a special method.
What we do is we add more attributes.
So for instance let's add an breed so dogs can have a breed and then what we do here is we have the
syntax that looks like this.
We say self daat breed is equal to breed and this is where it can get a little bit confusing.
So what we will do is run this and we should expect an error to pop up and it will say in it missing
one required a positional argument Breede which now means whenever I create an instance of a dog class
I require Breede as an argument.
So here we say Dog let's provide a breed.
So we will say create a dog with the breed and we'll pass in a string called lab we save this run this
again.
And oh I see I have class main dog so we're going to do now is instead of printing the type of my dog
since we know now that it's always going to be a dog class I'm going to say Prince my dog breed.
And then if I run this notice I get back out.
Lab and also note that they don't have close princes around breed.
I don't have something like this.
And that's because it's an attribute it's not a method I don't want to call it to action.
I just want to report back what that attribute is.
So let's break this all down one more time.
We have that that method and it's called automatically right after the object has been created.
So once we initialize the object we actually call this method automatically.
And then each attribute in a class definition begins with a reference to the instance object and that
by convention is this self keyword which is basically saying refer to this particular instance of this
object.
The breed here is the argument and the value is passed during the instantiation or initialization of
the class itself where we say Breede is equal to Labbe here.
And now we've created an instance of the dog class.
So let's create one other instance we can say other Dogon is equal to dog breed equal to and I will
say Huskie save that and then let's print out the other dog that breed save it.
We run this and we see we have lab and husky come out.
Now let's practice at adding one more attribute so angling to get rid of this other dog and we'll just
stick with my dog get rid of this other dog as well.
And this dog or dogs in general won't just have breeds.
Let's say they have names.
It is kind of like a pet name.
So what we do for every attribute what we do is we say self dot in the name of that attribute is equal
to name.
And again what this is doing is it saying self which refers to this dog that name so the attribute name
for this dog is equal to name which is going to be the name here.
So again this name on the right hand side of the equal sign refers to the input name.
This self-taught name is kind of assigning the name to the initialization of that dog.
So now if I save this and try to run this I will get an error because I need to provide a name.
So it says it is missing one required positional argument name.
So let's give it a name.
And we'll name this Sammy.
Which is my real dog.
Now if I run this I get lab and I can also print out my dog's name so I'll say my dog got name save
this.
Run it in I.S. lab and Sammy.
And usually when creating an actual instance of an object you won't specify breed is equal to something
name is equal to something else you want to really specifically target that.
So you come back to your code and read.
Oh yeah.
Lab stands for breed Sammy stands for name.
If you're really comfortable with an object and you tend to use it a lot we'll end up seeing something
more along the lines of this where you just say lab and Sammy they have to go in the correct order to
be assigned to breed and name but you'll most likely see in his saturation of an object look like that.
And if I run this code I get back same thing.
Lab and Sammy.
All right.
That's the very basics of attributes.
Again if you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But I also recommend that you check out the part two object oriented programming that pi which has a
lot of notes and a lot of explanatory text for everything we're doing here.
Next I want to talk about class object attributes.
So class object attributes are always the same for any instance of the class.
So for example for a particular dog you may have a different breed or you may have a different name.
However all dogs are mammals regardless of their breed or regardless of their name they're always going
to be a mammal.
What we can do in that case is add what's known as a class object attribute and a class object attribute
goes outside of any of these special methods or normal methods.
At the very top so will say class object attribute to pointed out.
And then I can say something like species is equal to mammal and if you study biology you know that
species doesn't actually relate to mammal.
It's more of the class of Somalia I believe.
But cut me some slack here because I can't really use this class keyword so we'll just say species is
equal to mammal regardless if that's biologically correct.
All right so now I'm going to save this.
I run this again and I see lab Samie.
So no I haven't actually defined species equal to mammal here.
That's taken as a class object attribute to be true regardless of what kind of dog I have.
So whether it's a husky a lab regardless of what its name is if I say print my dog species I will get
back mammal which makes sense regardless of whatever I want the breed or name to be this class object
attribute will always be true to be equal to mammal OK.
Now let's move on to actual methods.
Methods are functions defined inside the body of a class they're used to perform operations with the
attributes of our objects and methods are essential in encapsulation concepts of the object oriented
programming paradigm.
This is essential in dividing the responsibilities in programming especially in large applications and
basically methods are kind of the whole point of view would want to even create your own object.
So let's kind of Dilley Aldus and show you some more examples of how to create class not just of attributes
but with methods themselves.
So I will create a class and I will call it Circle class and I'm going to give it a class object attribute
where pi is equal to three point 1 4.
Now there are ways to call pi from the math library in Python but we'll just ignore that for now.
We'll say that regardless of what kind of circle you have the PI that special number is always going
to be equal to 3.1 for our estimated next.
I'm going to create my initialization special method.
You're always going to have this.
So I'll say underscore underscore in it so initialize with self and every circle in order to be defined
needs a radius.
So will say radius.
And if we want to be instantiated with a default parameter just like we could with a normal function
I can say equals 1.
Which means if I don't provide a radius I will provide the default value of 1 and since I have radius
there I need a say self-taught radius.
So self-taught radius which means the circle that radius is going to equal to the input radius.
Now let's create an instance of circle we'll call it.
My C is equal to circle.
Close parentheses and then I'm going to print my C radius save that run our notes and we see here my
radius is 1 perfect.
OK so let's show an example of a method and remember that methods are functions defined inside the body
of a class.
And basically they're going to allow us to perform actions based off the attributes of the object.
So let's create a method that calculates the area of a circle.
We'll call it the f area and we need to pass in the keyword self.
S E L F.
And that basically tells this method area that it's not just some free floating function inside of this
class.
It's actually a method of that class and that's what the self keyword is doing.
Then I'm going to calculate the area and remember that the area of a circle is just its radius squared
so radius times radius times pi.
Here's an issue if I just type this out.
This is a common mistake that beginners make.
They type radius times radius times pi and they think they are good to go.
But the problem here is what radius are you talking about.
Are you talking about the circles radius or some variable called radius.
The way to make sure that you know you're talking about the circles own radius when you actually instantiate
it is you need to say self-taught radius and that tells this method.
Hey look at the objects current radius and call it self-taught radius and I need to do the same thing
here.
And then since pi is an object level attribute what I can do is say circle about pi and now if I say
that let's create a circle my C with the radius equal to 3
I save this run this I get back out as my output three which makes sense.
Now let's see what happens if I call area and let's call area with no open and close princes just area
like this and see what happens.
I hit enter and I get an interesting line of output.
I get that I have a bound method circle that area of main circle object at this kind of sequence of
letters and numbers.
What this actually means is this if I just call that area that is a method bound to the Circle class
and it's a particular instance of the circle class object located at this position in my computer's
memory.
If I actually want to execute this method I need to just like I would for a function have a set of open
and closed parentheses on it.
Then when I run this code Qype on notes to apply I see here that my area is twenty eight point to six
or estimated to be given that we're using three point for as our value of pi.
Now let's imagine that I want to have a method that allows me to reset the radius.
So there's two ways you can change attributes of a class in Python.
One way is to just call it directly off the object itself.
So we can say my C radius is now equal to.
We'll put in 100 to make it really obvious.
And then if I call my C area we'll get a different answer.
So if I run Python this time I get thirty one thousand four hundred because I read the fine the radius.
Sometimes you actually just want to have a method in order to read to find something like that so that
it's really clear.
So let's make a very simple method that says set radius l taken self and then it will take in some new
parameter which will be something like New our.
And then I will grab my current radius which is self-taught radius and of equal to new R and know that
I'm not returning anything and that's OK.
Now all object methods need to return something some object methods just affect the object in place.
So now instead of saying my C equals my C that radius is equal to 100.
What I can do is say I see the set radius and then pass in that new R-value 100 and this will just to
show that this is working let's pasand something like 999.
So when I run this I get some huge number here.
So that's one way you can create methods that reset object attributes.
It's sometimes more common to see mice the way we first thought they might see that radius is equal
to something else.
Sometimes depending if you have a really large file or you work with people that you really want to
make sure they're doing things correctly you set it to a particular method.
It's really up to you.
That's more of a programming choice.
Programming Style choice that is all right.
So so far we've covered methods and attributes in the next section we're going to be covering inheritance
of different objects and then we'll discuss some special methods.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.
Do you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums and I'm happy to help you out.