Hello everyone and welcome to the populating models lecture.
It's usually a good idea to create some sort of script that will populate your models with some dummy
data that is fake data.
Let's show you how you can use the faker library to create this sort of script going to hop over to
the editor now.
OK.
So here I am open at the editor and the first thing we need to do is to actually install the faker library
and you can do that with a simple Pip install and make sure you're in the correct virtual environment
before you do this.
But you'll say Pipp install them for capital F A K E R enter.
And this should be installed the figure Python library for you.
And it's a pretty quick download so it shouldn't take that much time.
All right.
Looks like it's finished installing for me.
So that's all we need to do for that.
OK let me quickly show you what the documentation for faker looks like.
You can just come to Baker read the docs the IO and then check out the master link here.
It just shows you the basic usage of faker.
I can kind of zoom in here.
Basically what you're doing is after you Pip install F.A. you say from faker import factory or from
fake or import faker.
That's what we were going to do it.
And then you just say fake is an instance of fake or class and you can call different methods off of
it create a fake name create a fake address create some fake text et cetera.
And they have tons of methods here.
So you can check out the documentation for all the various methods you click down here on providers.
It shows you things like fake credit card fake date time fake Internet address person python files et
cetera.
So let's show you how you can use this library faker to actually create some fake data to populate our
models with so inside of my top level first project folder I'm going to right click and create a new
file.
And it's kind of up to you where you want to save the population script.
I usually save it on the top level file.
So again it's up to you.
But we'll call it populates underscore first underscore at that pie and we'll have it open here.
Let's minimize some of this stuff so we get a little more room to read this and then I'm going to say
import O S and then I'm going to need to configure the settings for the project.
Now I actually need to run this before I call any code so I need to say OS environed for the environment.
And I'm going to set the default and then I'm going to pass in all caps.
Jingo settings underscore module and then set it equal to or passen as a second parameter first underscore
project settings.
And basically what this is doing is just configuring the settings for the project they need to do this
before you start manipulating the actual models that are from here we can import Django and then set
it up so I can say jingoes set up and this is set up and configured the project settings from here on.
Next is our sake pop scripts are fake population scripts so they import a couple of things or import
random and then I also say from me from first app the models import will do access record web page and
copeck.
And then finally the library we just downloaded will say from thicker import with a capital F. Saker
the naming convention isn't so great there but that's the way to do it.
Then we create an instance of that faker object or call it fake Jennifer fake generation and then we'll
call Flaker close parentheses and then I'm going to just make a list of topics or remember the topics
that was a very simple model.
So I'll just create those manually.
I'll have one topic of Web sites search on topic of Web sites.
Be social in other one.
Be a market place type site.
And then finally we'll have news in games so various topics for different Web sites then we'll create
a function that can actually add topics so say add topic and this is going to look really similar to
using those shell commands.
I'll say T is equal to topic objects.
And in this case I'm going to call the Getz underscore or creates and what this does is it's either
going to retrieve the topic if it already exists in the model or create it and I'm going to pass on
top name is equal to and I'll say random choice the random choice method from the top X list and then
I grab here a zero because of the way this is formatted back and to discuss this sort of formatting
from get recreate a little more is the general format.
It's essentially a tuple that returns object and then something that's created and the first element
in the tuple object is a reference to the model instance that this get or create method creates the
data it base century wasn't found and then the entry is created using the parameters that you pass here.
In this case I'm just saying pick one of these topics as a random choice and you can check out the official
jingle documentation if you want more information about this or create method.
But the basic idea here it's going to return a tuple and I just want to grab the first object in that
tuple which is that reference to the model instance.
So that's why I have to add an additional index of 0 here.
Then once I've done that I'm going to say teeth that save as we've done before and I will then return
to the.
So that's my simple add topic.
Now let's show you kind of the more complicated ways for populating access record and web page which
aren't just a simple one word.
So I will say the and we'll just call this populate and we'll have a default and to populate with.
So the user can then later change that or provide it.
We could also make it some sort of command line parameter.
You can pasan right now we'll keep it as let's say Nickols 5 and we're going to do say four entry in
range and Herse we need to do is get the topic for the entry so say top is equal to add topic
and then I want to create the fake data for that entry.
So I create a fake your L objects like call fake Jeon which is the instance of faker and the method
for your L is just u r l then any that creates fake dates for that.
And that's just again fake Jan and we call date offer that the date method.
And then I need to get a fake name for this Web site like a fake company name so I can call fake.
Jen dots and then call a company office.
There are a ton of different more or a lot more methods you can call off of this like fake first name
fake last name fake credit card etc..
Again you can explore the documentation if you're interested in those.
Right now that's really all we need.
So then I'll create the new web page entry and I'll create a variable w e.
The PGE for short for Web page and only web page the objects.
And then I'm going to use that get or create again.
And then I will specify that for this web page the topic is equal to top your L is equal to that fake
your all generated and the name of it is equal to that fake name I generated.
Again I need to grab the first object in that tuple that's.
So keep that and then I want to create a fake access record.
Or that web page.
So I will say A.S.C. underscore R-S.C. is equal to access record.
Again objects get create and also apply that the name was the web page and then date is equal to sake
underscore dates.
And again I just want that first object so no this is going to be a little different on this first parameter
because if you remember back to the actual models look like they click here for Web page.
The topic was the foreign key topic.
So when I'm actually generating that fake data.
Notice that instead of passing just some fake topic name I'm actually grabbing a topic object so if
we go back here I'm returning see from AD topics I'm actually returning a topic object which is why
I'm passing it here when I'm saying get or create and it's the same thing for access records.
Come back here for access record it's foreign key for the name is web page so actually belongs here.
The web page means I'm going to pass an entire Web page here so that web page that I just created and
passing it in to the access record because it was a foreign key.
So keep that in mind.
You can't just pass on a string here if you have it as a foreign key in the models
OK.
Next finally at the end of all this thing I'm going to say if main name is equal to Main here I'm going
to print some command like Papilio scripts
and then we can say populate and here you can actually pass in whatever number you want number the default
was 5.
We could change it to be 20 if we wanted to.
That should be no problem.
And then once that's done we'll say something like population or we'll say populating complete save
that.
And now it's time to actually test to see if we got this all right.
So I come back up here and then I'm going to clear my Consul and let's make sure I'm in the right place
they should be under first project and I will call Python wups we'll call him right Python.
Populate underscore first underscore at that pi enter populating the script you see kind of a bunch
stuff here happening with D-B sequel like that.
The higher end value you provide the more time it will take to generate all that fake data.
So keep that in mind.
It looks like it all works.
So now its actually tested.
Let's run our Web site.
I will say now Python managed up-I run server is going to run the server and let me grab the URL and
put it in my browser and bring that browser up.
So here's the browser and then let's say slash admin.
And if we take a look at this let's check out the web pages we have.
And now here I can see I have a bunch of fake web pages that I just generated and populated.
Pretty cool.
Come back to access records.
You have a bunch of fake access records and you could have limited the access record dates.
It doesn't really matter for our use case but we see that we're able to click on one.
Check it out has a name.
We can also reassign the name but now you have a better idea of what a fuller database actually looks
like.
So here web pages again here are the topics from the topics or just a few topics but I could click on
social change.
Cetera.
OK.
That's all we need to know now for population scripts.
Hopefully you'll find them useful when you're working if your own web sites.
We won't touch on them too often in the future.
But keep in mind that we can use them and that faker libraries hopefully really useful to you.
Thanks.
And I'll see you at the next lecture.