Hello everyone and welcome to part two strings strings in Python are used to hold text information and
are indicated the use of either single quotes or double quotes there they're a sequence of characters
meaning they can also be indexed using the bracket notation.
Let's explore the basics of strings.
Some useful methods and more with Python.
Let's go to the editor now.
OK.
So in this lecture We'll cover some string basics such as creating strings and printing strings.
And we'll talk about string indexing and slicing some basic methods for strings and then how to use
print or string interpellation.
OK.
So to start off with the very basics with a string you can either use single quotes like this or double
quotes like this.
And if you want a single quote or a double quote within string itself just use the other quote to wrap
it.
So what I mean by that is if you want to type something that says I'm a dog and you want this to be
a string notice it has a single quote inside of it.
So you can just wrap that in double quotes and now it's a string so you don't get an error with this
single string or single quote right there.
All right.
This is the string basics.
Now something that is sometimes confusing to beginners is how to actually index and grab things from
the string sequence.
So let's spend a little bit of time talking about that and to show this since the basics are almost
the same as JavaScript.
Let's show some indexing with an example.
I will say my string is equal to A B C D F G.
And then let's print my string.
We'll save that.
And down here this is saved in a file called strings that PI inside of this folder locations.
I will say Python strings up PI enter and I get out my string.
Perfect If I want to actually grab a single element all I have to do is use the square bracket notation
and then pass in the index location of the actual elements I want indexing starts at zero with Python.
So if I want the very first letter in the string which is a all I have to do is pass and in square brackets
after the variable name 0 and then that returns a I the very last one python string support negative
indexing so I can type minus one which means if I run this now I get Geo and if I want anything else
in the middle then I just count it in this look index locations.
For instance if I get the letter D That's at index 0 1 2 3 pasand 3 and I should get out the letter.
Do you want to run this script.
And there it is.
OK.
Now let's talk about slicing.
Slicing is something that confuses beginners at first.
So let's make it very clear by breaking down the steps.
There's going to be three parts to slicing the beginning of the slice.
The end of the slice and then later on the step size.
We don't need to always find the step size.
So let's start off by defining the beginning of the slice.
If I want to grab everything starting from the index to all the way to the end of the string then I
just have to type in a colon.
So if I run this right now I get the letters out.
C D E F G.
And basically what this command says is start index 2 which is the letter C 0 1 2 and grab everything
all the way to the end of the string.
That's what the colon here stands for.
So let's imagine I want to grab everything from letter e.
All the way to the end so e f and g.
Then I just need to count out 0 1 2 3 4 and a colon to go all the way to the end.
And if I run this I get e f g.
All right.
Now let's discuss how to do slicing.
If you want to start at the beginning but go up to a certain index the way you do that is you essentially
reverse this.
So you say colon and then type the index you want to go up to but this is sometimes a little confusing
for beginners because indexing starts at zero.
Python is going to get everything up to but not including the index.
So if I run this command right now colon three it goes a b and c.
You may have expected d the letter at index 3 to be included.
But for Python index slicing notation only goes up to but not including that index.
So again what we're here telling Python to do is to grab everything from zero up to but not including
index three.
And you'll notice this a lot in Python where statements are usually in the context of up to but not
including in the main ideas because indexing starts at zero and moving along.
We can expand this idea to define a starting point and define an ending point.
So let's imagine that I want to grab the letters C D and E What I have to do in this case is to find
the starting point which happens the index too.
Then I write a colon and define the ending point which is up to but not including a particular index
so we'll see 0 1 2 3 4 5.
So I want to go up to and including five and this should get me these four letters C D and E.
I run this there is C D and E.
So take your time with this a good practice for you if you're having trouble with this slicing notation
is to make a really long string and then in your mind think of some letters you want to grab in the
middle of it and then practice grabbing them.
OK so the last thing I want to mention about slicing is that you can actually define step size.
So if you want to grab everything in a string you just have to say colon colon or even just a single
colon and that return.
If we run this the entire string if you wanted the final step size what you do is you say colon colon
which basically stands for all the way from the beginning all the way to the end and then a number or
integer for your step size.
So if a step size of one it grabs everything.
But if I make this a two and then run the code it ends up skipping every other.
So the step size becomes two.
It goes in jumps of two so a C E G.
OK.
Those are the very basics of slicing.
And we'll talk about it more when we actually deal with strings in Jane Doe.
But that's all you need to know for now.
Here's a quick note.
Strings are immutable meaning I cannot say my string grab a particular index cation and then try to
redefine it so I can't say something like my string of zeros is equal to x because if I try to run this
I will get an error saying SDR or a string object does not support item assignment meaning a string
is immutable in that fashion.
I could always read the find the string to be something completely different but that will just delete
everything and redefine the variable itself.
OK now I want to talk about a couple of basic methods that are built into strings.
A really useful method sometimes that you may find yourself using is upper an upper is a method and
you can actually see Adam is beginning to help me as I type upper here.
But what it does.
Returns a copy of the string converted to uppercase so he can say this and let's define this as X and
then say Prince X I will save this and run it.
And now I see Yagan uppercase version of a b c d e f g and the opposite of upper is lower lips spelled
wrong.
Or we can see are at their lower and you can actually see that as I say my string dot I get a bunch
of methods available for me.
Adam has helped me out here.
We won't use a lot of these methods but remember they're all here to help you if you have any questions
on one of these methods.
Feel free to post of the Q&amp;A forum but a lot of these will actually be defined as you begin to type
them out.
So let's say I wanted to learn what capitalized.
Well then I just start typing capitalize.
And as I do that we see right here what's known as the function or method docstring and it tells you
it returns a copy of the string s with only its first character capitalized.
So unlike upper if I'd select capitalize and then run this I noticed that only the first letter A is
capitalized that's different and capitalized an upper.
The last method I want to show you which is really useful is the split method which ends up splitting
a string.
So if I just run this right now I get a single item in a list but let's imagine I had multiple words
here.
So I say hello world save this and run my code.
Then I get a list in Python which will cover in the next lecture that has hello is its first item and
a world as its second item.
And basically what split does it allows you to split on anything you want for a string and you would
actually uses for it in a similar case in Javascript.
But let's imagine that I want it to split on the letter E..
By default it splits on whitespace which is why we got Hello world.
But if I wanted to split on the letter E I run this and notice I get back.
H the ears popped out because we split on it and then everything else becomes a second item in my list.
I could also do it for something that shows up more than once such as Oh.
Now if I run this I get hell space w SP.
Next item is R L D.
OK.
So that's the basic split.
Finally I want to talk about print formatting with Python.
So let's show you how we can do that.
So there's many methods that you can use what's known as string interpellation which is basically trying
to input a string into an other string.
The best way to do it is with the DOT format method.
And I will show you the basic way to do this.
You say some string.
So I will insert in other string here and then you have curly brackets.
Note the syntax highlighting there and then off of the string you call format and then pass in whatever
you want to insert.
So I'll say insert me save this.
And now let's run this.
And we haven't actually printed this yet so let's say this is equal to x and then print x
save that run this.
And it says insert another string here.
And it says insert me.
OK.
Perfect.
Now let's say I want to insert multiple strings.
How I do that.
Well all I have to do is say Item 1 and then just pass and let's say Item 2 in other set of curly brackets.
And over here in format we just passen multiple strings so we can say something like.
Dog is our first item comma assonance of the string cat as the second item we will save this and then
we can print X and we get item 1 dog.
Item 2 cat.
What's also nice about this stuff forment method is you can actually define variables inside of this
format so I can say something like x is equal to dog.
And then why is equal to cat.
And then inside of these curly brackets I can an x and y and it will come back here to format and read
what X and Y stand for.
So if I say this and run this I get back the exact same result.
But what's nice about this is I can easily switch out the order or double up on things so I can switch
at the order here and if I run this now I get item one item to his dog or I can have him both print
out X which is dog.
And then it says item 1 dog item 2 dog and this is how you're going to see format.
Most of the time it's curly brackets a specific variable that you find over here and format and then
you just call it there.
OK.
That's the very basics of string formatting and strings in general if you have any questions feel free
to post to the Q&amp;A forums.
But as far as this course is concerned that's really all you need to know.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.