Welcome back everyone to part three of the social cloning project.
Now we're going to continue with the accounts application and we're going to do now is focus on setting
up our temple HVM elf files for the log page.
The sign up page as well as connecting that to our actual index page with the navigation bar.
Let's get started and hop over to the Adam sex ed..
All right here I am at the Adam text editor.
Now before we get started what we're going to be doing is installing a library called Bootstrap 3 for
Django or Django Dasch bootstrap 3.
And what this library does is it formats forms in a really nice way using bootstrap.
So go ahead and in your virtual environment or even in your default if you're not using your virtual
environment say Pipp install jingo Dasch bootstrap 3 lips and then hit enter and let that install.
Now I actually already have it.
So it just set all packages meet the requirements already satisfied.
But for you inside your virtual environment again say Pipp install Shingo dasht bootstrap 3.
So that's something we're going to be using throughout the project to actually just make the forms look
a little nicer.
Now once you've done that going to go ahead and just clear that come over to your settings that py file
and in your settings up-I file scroll all the way down to where it says installed apps.
And here we're going to say is bootstrap theory and then a comma.
So again Pipp install bootstrap 3 and then add it to your installed application.
It will show you in a little bit how to use it.
It's essentially just the two lines of code.
You load it in and then when you call form say bootstrap form right before it and it will actually make
it look a lot nicer in your application.
OK let's come back to our accounts templates in logon to HTL and sign up that each team T.M. we're going
to start off with the Sign-Up parish team L and it's actually going to look really similar to the loggin
that each team L.
So in the sign up page what I'm going to do is say extends and I'm going to extend from base start h
t m l which we're going to work with at the very end of this.
And then the other thing going to do is load bootstrap 3 which is the library just installed so extend
from base storage Timo that we created earlier and then load bootstrap 3 and then we're going to do
is call block content so that content block and then I'm going to create a div of the container class
inside of this I'll have a heading 1 saying Sign up and then I will call a form so inside of this form
I'm just going to have a have a class or even an action because the action is going to be taken care
of by jingo.
And the method should be post and I always like capitalizing it.
It works the same if it's not capitalized but that's just for readability for me.
And inside of this we always need our token.
So you can start typing in C SRF underscore tokin inside a token call like that.
And then the last thing we're going to do is create a form and once you have bootstrap 3 installed you're
going to say is bootstrap underscore form space form and that's going to allow us to actually make this
form look a lot nicer using bootstrap on our Web page.
And that's a bootstrap theory.
You can check out the documentation links for it.
But essentially that's the way we're going to be using it for our project.
And then after that inside this form we're going to have an input button.
It's going to be type submit.
I'll give it a value of Sign-Up.
So that's what it says in the actual button.
It won't have a name but we will give it a class.
Let's give it a class between PTEN the default and save that.
OK then I'm going to select all this of control a and then copy it and bring over my log in that is
HTML file and I'm going to copy and paste this because essentially we're going to be doing something
really similar here.
So I am again going to extend from the base to a small bootstrap 3 block content container but instead
of Sign-Up this is not going to say log in and then save that and then the value over here is going
to be log in and then I'm going to save that.
Okay perfect.
Now let's go ahead and set up our views that PI file and or you are also PI file and the connection
between them.
So coming over to views that pi.
Again this is all under accounts you should already have this from the previous lecture.
Just sign up create view then go over to your PI.
Or if we haven't created yet what we need to do is create it.
So underneath accounts say new file your L's not pi.
So it says new file you are Elle's that PI enter.
And now here we're going to import a couple of things.
I'm going to say from Django configuration that you are L's import are el.
And then I will say from jingo doc contrib dot th authorization in poor views as off underscore the
views.
Now the reason we're doing this is make sure you have jingle one point eleven at least to do this but
jingle one point eleven introduced a log in view and a log out view.
So we actually don't have to take care of those interviews that py file anymore.
Previously we had to do.
Inside of that pi create a log in view and a log out.
Now Gengel one point eleven has taken care of that for us and that's located under the control of a
T-H views.
So I'm going to say import views as authorization views or ATHM underscore views.
So I don't mix it up with my original views which is here.
So I'm saying now from import views.
So this is going to line number three is going to import my own views that py file.
And so I don't mix the authorization views I'm going to import as authorization views and let's set
up our Apennine so we'll call this app name accounts that way in case I ever want to use your old templates
in my base or each time I'll file for example at the navigation bar I can refer to it as the accounts
application and then we'll set up our world patterns list.
So inside IList I will say Yoro.
And then using regular expression I'm going to say log in and out this is we're going to use that new
Gengel one point eleven feature elysée say off underscore views dots and then the loggin view is the
actual view.
And I'll say as view and that's when you log in every feature of Django one point eleven and then inside
of that I'm actually going to connect it to the template name.
So inside a log in view as view I can say template name is equal to and whoops you can do that.
That's going to be a string and I'll zoom out just a little bit and collapses so we can see the whole
thing.
It's going to be accounts slash log in HTL and I'm going to give it the name equal to log in that's
going to be for you are all templates in the future.
And if you want you can separate us separate this out into more than one line.
Here I'm just writing in one giant line.
But you could just break this up into multiple lines.
So.
All right.
So again this is our logging your you are all connected to log in we call log in view from this authorization
views as View and then pass in the template you want to connect the.
In this case log in each table and give it the name log in for future your templates then a comma here
for our next URL.
And that's going to be pretty similar except it's going to be logged out.
So I will say regular expression log outs dollar sign and then I want authorization views and now I'm
going to ask for the log out you as a view and set the name equal to log out.
Then finally I will have the sign up view.
So the whole way your el
Sign-Up view right there and then from my view is file say views the sign up view it created as a view
and then I will say name is equal to.
I'll just call this site up.
OK.
And now are your PI file inside of our accounts application is ready and just to quickly review what
we just did here.
We're already familiar in putting your L's again in importing contrib off views as authorization to
use so I don't mix it up with my own view is that PI file and that's going to allow me to use these
new features a jingle one point eleven log in view and log out view.
A quick note for log in view you have to connect it to your template name for log out view that has
a default view that we can use.
So that's what we're going to do.
Say lock up you as View and then log out.
That will essentially go back to the home page once you log out and that are sign up we already have
that connected.
So I will say sign up as you name sign up and that's all we have to do for our Urals not py file.
OK.
Now the next step is to actually connect our accounts application to our full project using views in
your L's.
So let's open up our tree and come back to simple social pie and then we're going to connect it via
your else.
So right now I'm in the main project.
You are also not py file and let's fill this in so it actually connects to the log in pages for the
accounts we're going to do is over here I will say your l.
So Creedon and Yunior L and using regular expressions we're going to do is say the counts forward slash
and then we will say include and I'm going to occlude include accounts you are oles so that you are
also file were just made and then give it the name space.
And this actually should go inside include I will give it the name space.
And let's just say accounts here comma and then save that and then the other thing I'm going to do is
say are accounts slash and I'm going to include jingo contrib dash or dot th dot or else OK.
And then comma and we're going to leave that as is.
And that should be it for the actual Your file for connecting to the accounts.
So essentially what this is doing is it's connecting the accounts main space to accounts or else.
That way someone has log in or sign up that connects directly to your Olsdorf PI file that we just created
in the accounts application.
Now this jingoes that contrib the author or else that's going to allow us to connect the thing that
Django has under the hood for authorization.
You'll notice that if we hit over on admen PI undercounts we actually really need to register any models
here because we're using jangles built in use user's model so we don't really need to register anything
with the admin remember with users was already included.
Whenever you log into your adamant page so we're just using what has already nicely provided for us.
Now jump over to our base let each team mail file.
So based on each C.M. all the way under our main templates and essentially what I'm going to be doing
is copying pasting from the notes themselves and explaining each copy paste.
So the first thing I want to do is let's just give this the title of star social save that and then
underneath or inside this head it should say.
And underneath that title I'm going to be copy and pasting some links.
So the first thing I'm going to copy and paste is just bootstrap itself.
So let's put that in.
So there's that giant link for the stylesheet to bootstrap the next one I'm going to do is the optional
theme that goes a bootstrap.
So I'm going to copy and paste that as well.
You can copy and paste this either from the bootstrap site or from the notes themselves.
I'd recommend the notes just so we make sure we're all using the same version or on the same page.
And then finally and going to copy and paste the javascript line that's again also from the bootstrap.
OK.
So those are my three bootstrap blanks.
The other thing that I do is copy and paste a link to a style so the style sheet is going to be linking
to is our own style sheet but also google fonts API.
So we're going to be using this fonts from the Google API.
So as we've seen before I'm just going to link that up in the head and I'm going to link the master
CSSA file.
So let's do that as well.
Underneath this I'm going to link to the M.C. SS.
Now what's important to know is how I'm actually linking this.
You remember that we created a C Ss folder underneath our templates folder and then underneath that
I created the master C Ss file and I'm going to link it using this static call.
So wherever we say that load static I'm going to be able to connect this.
So we just say stylesheet ref.
And this is probably the most important line here as far as getting everything connected will say static
which means go look in the static directory.
So we set up in the settings that py file and then go to simple social C Ss and then master C Ss to
actually link everything.
OK.
Now underneath the body outside of the block I want my actual navigation bar.
So let's actually build this together.
And I will say nav and there's my nav and in my nav I will say class and it will give this a nav bar.
My nav.
And then we can actually just give it the default rules so I'll say this is rule navigation.
You can basically just copy and pasted it from the documentation.
But I want to walk through it just in case you end up copying pacing and are wondering what's going
on here.
So I gave it this class nav bar my nav my nav is something I'm going to be using later on.
So that's my own special navigation.
In case you ever want to add your own CSO styling.
You can do is just kind of tack on classes and then the next thing to do is set up a div here and I'll
call this container from Bootstrap that we've seen before that goes inside nav bar.
And now it's time to add an anchor and the actual link is going to be to our home page.
So we're going to do this with a your all template tagging and we will say you are el and give it the
name home that will link to the Home link and then we're also going to say here let's just say this
will be store social and let's make this into an actual brand which means I'm going to say the class
of this anchor tag is nav bar dash brand and I will tack on my nav class in case everyone at the CSSA
for that.
So again right now my name navigation.
It's all in a container.
I set my brand.
Remember that's that large home button that goes all the way to the left.
And now I'm going to start an unordered list.
And inside this unordered list I will say class is equal to now have nav bar dash nav nav bar dash right.
So kind of right align everything.
And these are going to be just a couple of buttons things that go to a post a group a create group and
a log out page and then a log in page and assign a page.
Now some of these we won't be able to fill it out right away because we haven't actually created them.
So we're going to kind of leave certain links blank and then we'll fill them in later.
OK.
First thing I want to do is I want to check if a user is authenticated so a user object is going to
be returned to this web page so I can actually check using some template tags if the user dot net can
call the is authenticated attribute off of this which means so the user is authenticated they logged
in.
It's been successful.
And we're going to basically see what the actual navigation bar will look like.
So I put in list objects and there's an ordered list an anchor tag here and right now I will leave that
blank as an address but it's actually going to say inside this anchor.
It's just going to be post.
So that means that the users are locked in.
They can then have a little button in their navigation bar that allows them to post something.
The next thing to do is again list anchor tag.
And this will be groups.
So if the user is logged in they'll be able to see the groups again and leave that blank.
We haven't actually created any groups yet.
And then again after a log then I'm going to allow them to create a group.
So we'll have a create group option over there.
And then finally I'm going to have a log out.
So if the user has authenticated that means they are logged in.
So we should probably have a log out button here.
It will say log out and this one I can fill in because I do have a Treffry to go.
So we're going to say for the your template is going to be called to in a string accounts colon log
out and that connects to that your Else up-I which connects to that log up view.
And now I'm ready to do the other options in case my user is not authenticated meaning they haven't
logged in yet.
So else they have a log then I will do the following.
I'll create a group's tag.
So you should still be able to see the groups.
Whoops let me do it.
Tref call in here.
And just type in groups and they're the anchor.
So we still be able to see the groups even if you're not logged in.
That we can just kind of visit as an and not logged in user.
And then the other option we're just going to be either log in or to sign up.
And these actually do have the links right.
So we just create them.
So let's create those here I will say your el accounts log in for this guy.
And then in the H.F. here for the sign up it will say your el accounts sign up save.
And then as always if I have an if statement with templates I need to say.
And if so and if.
OK.
So we're going to be filling this a lot more into your posts in groups created.
But right now we're just using the basics.
I have accounts log out log in and sign up and that ends my unabridged list.
So that should end my navigation bar and then I'll have my content.
And actually I'm going to wrap this content in a class container so I will see a container and then
I'm also going to put in my content which can be a class I later edit in my CSSA file that master C
Ss and let's put the content inside of this.
OK so going all the way down to the bottom we're going to eventually link to our javascript.
Right now we don't have a javascript file that we've been messing around with but we'll take care of
that later.
So let's just save that.
So by now we should have a simple navigation bar.
A lot of the links are just empty.
But we should at least be able to see the empty buttons themselves so we'll see some of that says Post
groups create groups and this will allow us to kind of check if user authentication is working.
So that's our based H.T. mail file and we should already have the index file ready to go.
Since we've done that earlier.
OK.
Our template files should be ready to go.
We still have to do a couple of things such as make them migrations and make sure the accounts are fully
set up.
We're going to do that in the very next lecture.
So I will see you right then and we'll continue on right where we left off here.