Welcome back everybody to part for the blog Klon project.
So now it's time to actually get to the meat of the project which is creating views and templates and
connecting them to your else.
We'll start off with the class based views handling the actual blog posts and the basic structure that
we're going to follow here is we'll try to create a view see how to set it up and then we'll create
the template that matches with that view.
A lot of class based views have some sort of default template name so we'll create that template we
will actually fill out those H.A. files.
We'll do that in a future lecture.
OK.
Let's get started.
Hop over to the editor.
OK so the first step here is to actually go to views that pie underneath our blog folder and other need
templates I also have a blog folder here which is where I will be adding those ASTM l files.
So let's start off by actually creating the baseline each team file that will be inheriting or extending
from.
So I will create a new file under blog and call it base h TNL.
So there it is.
And I'll just type in H-2 him here later on we'll work a lot more with his team files.
But coming back to views that PI Let's start off with that about page since that's one of the simplest
ones we have to do.
So I will say from jingo views the generic import and I'm going to import with princes since I'm going
to do multiple imports.
I can use princes have them across multiple lines.
And the first one that I want is this template you so will say.
Class and we'll call this the about you and this will be a template view and all we do here is say the
template underscore a name.
And we're going to connect that to about the H Tim L and that's really all we have to do.
And then we're going to come here to blog create a new file call it about each T.M. and then we can
say well we're here or something like extends and then in quotes something like blog slash based Timo
and then we can add a lot more content in here like the body block etc. But once we have that the other
thing I want to do is add this to our list of your else.
So coming back to your stop pie notice I'm under the blog you're up high which is currently empty.
So let's set up a way to connect our sites Yarl's that pie to our actual blog you are that pie.
So I'll come first to the Eurostar pie of our entire site.
So this one already has a configuration that will scroll all the way down.
And then when I'm going to do here is say also import include since I'll be using that and then I need
to import some views so I will say actually we'll skip that for now.
I we'll say your el and basically I'm just going to say anything.
That's not the admin page go to blogs thought else and we can pass this as a string and then that's
going to do is going to look for the blocks application and then find that Urals that PI file.
So we'll save that for now.
And that means we can come back to this Yarl's that PI file and start editing it.
We're not quite done with the project's URLs that PI file but for now we'll just leave it like that.
We have to add in all that registration stuff but we'll talk about that once we actually get to that
for the PI file of the blog application.
I'm going say from Jingo the Siona for configuration thought you Elle's import Yoro.
And then I'll say from blog import views.
And as always you could have also said from datt import views and then we're going to have a your all
patterns list and this will eventually grow to be a super large list and we just have this all basically
feeding into the single application.
But let's start off by saying your L and we'll have the about page B slash about.
So let's do this with regular expressions and we'll say about slash dollar sign.
And this is going to be views.
And then the about you we just created.
Remember we have to say as of you know we'll give it the name about Khama save.
All right.
So our first view is basically done now.
So let's come back to use that pie and start the next one.
And basically we're going to be doing over and over again there's going to be a ton of your all's views.
And as I mentioned that's kind of the meat of the entire project.
So the actual home page is going to be the list of all the posts so I'll say class a post list view.
And that's going to inherit from a list view so let's have that in on our import statement comma list
view and then I'm going to start a new line here.
Later on we'll add some more imports so I'll have a list of you that I'm inheriting from and then I
need to connect that to a model.
So I'm going to connect this to the post model but in order to do that I should actually import it.
So coming back up here we'll say from blog models import and let's import both models are created.
We created a post model and a comment model and then the other thing I want to do here is actually define
how I want to grab this list.
So when we get a little more room here Heidi that terminal and basically what I can do is I can create
a method called Get underscore query set self.
And this allows me to use jingoes or M when dealing with just generic views.
That way I can add a little more of a custom touch to it.
So we kind of do this a lot when we were in a function based views but we can actually do this as well
with class based views.
By the finding particular get methods and we'll get a lot more practice with this in future projects.
But basically what I say is the actual queries I want is going to be post all the objects and I want
to filter them by the published underscore dates and then I'm also going to add an underscore underscore
T and I will set that equal to time zone.
Now and then I'm going to also say dots order by and let me collapse this directory tree to get some
more room here and then I'm going to say as a string dash published underscore dates.
And that's my whole query set.
All right so what does this all actually mean.
Well with the get queries set I'm basically almost doing a query like a sequel query on my model.
So this is essentially kind of pie funnies version of writing a sequel query.
So what I'm saying is grab the post model all the objects there and filter out based on these conditions.
So then we have grabbed the published they and then with the field queries you can do this really interesting
thing where you say underscore underscore and then the actual field.
So in this case it's going to be less than or equal to.
And I'm going to hop over to documentation link a little bit to kind of explain this part a little more
because out of all this is probably the strangest thing.
Underscore underscore LTE which we've never seen before.
We haven't really died this deep into the OR AM of jingo but basically this is asking is OK grabbed
the published dates that are Lessner equal to the current time and then order them by published day.
Except with this dash we can clarify whether we want ascending or descending because if we were not
to order them by Dasch published they would be happening is we would see the oldest blog post first.
So here with this dash I can order them in kind of a descending order.
So the most recent blog post comes up front or at the top of this list view.
So this is the get query set method and essentially allows you to use this or sort of a particular query
on a list so you can only get items that you want in the list with some sort of filter and then you
can also order them.
So let me hop over to the documentation briefly to explain a little more about this kind of curious
line underscore underscore LTE.
All right so here I am at the documentation now with the documentation for 1.1 0 although if that by
the time you're looking at this it's one point eleven This should be basically the same.
And I'm on their slash topic slash slash queries and I can just do control Ephor command and look up.
Underscore underscore LTE and you'll find a simple example but this all falls under field lookups where
it's essentially how you can specify some sort of sequel query using the query set methods.
And there's three main Chrisette set methods filter exclude and get and the basic lookups look like
this.
The actual field you want the fields of our model member those are the attributes and then underscore
underscore and then the lookup type equal to some sort of value.
And again that's a double underscore.
So for example in this kind of plays along with what we've done is we say entry so whatever that model
was the object so grabble as objects and then filter them based on some condition.
In this case they want where the publication date is less than or equal to this particular value.
So roughly translates into the following sequel.
If you're not familiar sequel don't worry about this too much.
But if you are this is probably really helpful to you.
So it says select everything from a blog entry or whatever entry we have here where the publication
date is less than equal to this particular date.
So almost exactly the same example that we're working with here.
Now if you're curious more about how this is actually possible because this is definitely some more
advanced Python as far as how the creators of Django kind of built this and with this underscore underscore
they have a link here to keyword arguments.
They can read more into but but you're probably more interested in is how to actually figure out what's
possible here in this double underscore how you actually keep scrolling down.
And then there's various examples that are available to you so you can say underscore underscore exact
which translates into just an equal call and keep scrolling down you can say I exact which is going
to be case insensitive matching you can say contains.
And this essentially just he keeps rolling down a bunch of stuff that has to do with translating sequel
code into Python.
But the weird confusion about it is this more advanced Python mechanism where you have these double
underscores separating the actual field versus the type of comparison you're doing.
Now we're not going to be using these too often throughout this particular project but I do want you
to be aware of them and later on in a few trial section.
We'll talk more about the OR em that Shingo has but I just want you to be aware.
Again you can always check the documentation page here if you want more in-depth information on this
but that's a little background to where we got all those commands from.
OK.
So that's the post list view.
Let's minimize this and go add this view to actual Uriel's that PI file.
So I'm going to come over to your Allsopp high of my blog.
So there it is.
And let's actually listen.
So I'll say Khama call your all again.
And then what I'm going to do here is since this is actually going to be the home page let's delete
this and let's make this the top one.
So usually you always see the homepages First you are a pattern.
So let's do that here.
So I'll say our care and then dollar sign and this is going to accept the use dot post list view to
underscore view and then I'm going to set the name equal to post underscore list which is kind of the
default name it expects here and that's it.
So again I'm setting the home page to all my current blog posts that are published and that's it for
that particular post list view.
So let's continue moving along.
And you can always reference the code to make sure it matches exactly.
So if you ever get stuck on something.
Make sure you're checking out the code notes next year we're going to make is another class based view
So let's say you have those lists of posts at click on one.
It takes me to an actual blog post.
That means it's a detailed view.
So this one's a lot simpler.
All I have to do is say post detail view and then what I'm going to do is appear.
Let's import detail.
Say that and here I'm going to say detail view and underneath the detail view.
All I have to do is say model is equal to post and that's it.
That's a detail view as we've seen before.
Let's go at it in I'll come over to my Urals up-I blog.
And then a lot of this is taken care of for me.
So we'll say your el and then here we're going to do is for a post the tilt view I'll say that's going
to be under post and then I'm going to add some regular expressions here which is going to basically
be taking the primary key and we've seen this a little bit before but let's go ahead and show it again.
It's going to be question mark p..
And then it's going to accept piquing like this backslash the plus and then outside of this dollar sign.
And again I would never really expect anyone to know this off the top of my head and lost it working
a lot with Django.
This is more the kind of thing that you reference other examples with documentation for.
But we've already seen how do a detail.
So we've seen this or something very similar to this before but luckily a lot of this heavy lifting
for us in our lives that say is post detailed view and call as View.
And this will automatically take care of matching the primary key to whatever you clicked on.
And then let's give this a name and we'll set the name equal to just post underscore detail.
OK so that's a detail view of that post.
Let's save that and we'll hop right back over to use that pi and move onto the next class based view.
We're going to kind of get some more space here.
And next thing I want to do is sort of create view so I'll say class and we'll say create post view
and then we want to inherit from create view.
But first thing you need to do is actually import it.
So we'll come back up here and then we'll say create a view save that come down.
And then what I want to do is connect my model to be able to post.
And that's what we've seen before.
But there's a couple of more things so we want to do here.
And the main thing we want to do is I don't want anyone to be able to access this create post view earlier
when we were talking about authentication authorization.
We discussed using decorator's So remember we had that at symbol we have something like lock in required
but that only really works for function based views.
And now we want to know how do we actually work with that sort of log in required with a class based
view.
And that's where the term mixdowns come in.
So you haven't seen any real Moxon's but they're really easy to use just like those decorators were
easy to use.
You just scroll at the top here and you're going to import them.
So I won't say from jingo contrib you th mixdowns.
I'm going to import.
And then the one we want is called loggin required Mixon and you can basically think of this akin to
the decorator so I'll show you the example of a decorator one where we're we said from Django da contrib
a th da decorator's import loggin underscore required.
So essentially back when you're dealing with function based views to actually get that sort of automated
logging required functionality you had to use these decorators.
But luckily a class space to use the analogy to that is using these mixdowns and these are essentially
classes that we mix in to the classes we're inheriting with.
So not only do we want to create value but we're going to mixin that log in required.
That's kind of where they get their name from.
So I'll say log in required Mixon Khama.
So now I'm going to inherit methods from both of these classes.
So not just create new but also logging required mixin in with the mixdowns they take in a couple of
more attributes that are necessary.
So one attribute we want to do is set up the log in you are all some cases persons not logged in.
Where should they go.
And later on we'll say they should go to slash logon.
Almost like when you're setting up the static files and then we also want to do is have some sort of
redirect field so that attribute is called redirects underscore field underscore name and I want to
set that equal to blog slash post underscore detail dot h HVM L and what we're going to do is going
to say.
All right.
So redirect them to the detailed view and then we'll say form class as equal to post form.
But that means we actually need to import that.
So I'm going to scroll back up here and we imported the models already let's actually import the forms
themselves say from blog that forms in poor host form and import the comment form.
So what does this all doing.
Well I have the Create post view that we've seen before.
We've seen it just to create view where you kind of have these models or these forms connected.
But now I'm also kind of mixing in the slogging required just like I did with decorator's But this is
kind of the class based view version also very easy to use.
You just end up having these two fields where you want to read redirect or where the lock in your l
should be.
So we'll put those all in here and we will save that and we're going to come back to you or else that
pi file and then match set up to some sort of your alcohol.
So I will say your L and we'll say this says post and you can say post create but you're not limited
to just saying create you can call this whatever you want.
So oftentimes you're not going to want the your all to just always say create.
Maybe you want your own specific thing especially of larger sites for users.
In this case let's call this post new which kind of also makes sense.
So say our posts slashed new and then over here what I'm going to do is say views die and I'm going
to create a post that you underscore as you and then I will say name is equal to post underscore.
You and I'm going to say that.
So this is now my create post view.
So let's continue on.
I've been able to check out the details of a post create a post to my home page and then at my About
page tech checking off a lot of these boxes on generic views.
Let's continue on.
A lot of times I'll probably want to update a post.
Maybe I made a mistake so I don't want to just be able to create them.
I want to update them which means coming back up here.
Member This is all from those crud lectures.
Going Say up the view.
Scroll back down and then we'll create a new class and we'll call this post up.
You and we'll have this also be loggin required makes sense if I need to actually update something I
should be logged in.
And then we'll call up that view and then this is going to the same log in your Arel and our field name
as the creation of it.
In fact it's actually going to have everything the same so we can just copy and paste this and whips
out my colon and there it is.
All right.
So all these attributes are the same for update and creation which makes a lot of sense.
Basically the only thing you're saying is OK now you're updating it instead of creating a brand new
one.
Which kind of has to do with whether or not you're creating new primary key or linking to an old one.
So same thing has always come back to your not pie hopefully or begin it's kind of fill out the pattern
of what we're doing here and we'll start some regular expressions.
So I'll say this is post and actually this should be you should have carrots on them.
So I apologize that I forgot about that.
But there we go.
These were off carrots now and then what we're gonna say is for the post up they will say post slash
and then I'm going to call the same sort of primary key.
To make sure it matches the primary key essentially just making sure you link to the correct one.
And then let's say something like slash at and then we'll have a dollar sign here so I'm going say something
like oh post number one at that post and then we'll say Khama views thoughts and then I should have
a post up that you.
There it is as always in your column as View.
And then we'll give it some sort of name and let's call this name post underscore at it you can have
us call the post up.
If you just remember that name and match it or I call post at it.
OK.
Almost none of the post use.
Coming back to views that pi I have right now my creating updating detailed view listing view about
you.
This is all just for the blog posts.
And then what I also want is to take care of the drafts.
So remember I publish posts but before they're published they're going to be drafts.
So let's actually create a view that lists all my unpublished drafts which means I'm going to create
a class and actually before we do that let's kind of sneak in a simpler one.
What if I want to delete a post.
I'll need a post delete you and I will take care of that draft in just a second.
But this should also be log in required and this is going to inherit from the view.
We have an important so let's do that as well.
So update delete.
And if this is confusing you definitely check out the crud lecture inside of the advanced class lecture
or section I should say.
OK so here's class Postol view.
Logging required mixin.
And then I'm going to call you this is a really simple one.
We just connect it to the model that we're going to be the leading from and then we need some sort of
success.
You are all so hopefully remember this as well.
So what happens when you actually delete it.
Where should it go.
And remember that when you're deleting have you you don't want the success you are l to actually activate
until you delete it.
Otherwise what kind of be jumping always to another Web site or another page on your website.
I should say in order to do this we need to use the reverse lazy.
So again scrolling all the way back up here will say from jingo your Elle's import reverse underscore
lazy.
That way it waits until you've actually deleted it to give you back the success you are ill that you're
going to be going to.
So we'll have it go back to the home page which is going to call reverse lazy and then we'll pass and
the post underscore lists and I will say that.
OK so let's delete view.
And that basically takes care of our crud.
This sort of creates updating the actual retrieval process well that's just displaying it.
So that's kind of inherent to all these slices and then deleting.
So these are my credit views right here these three.
And then I also have the detail list and about or a template I should say.
OK.
So come back to your old pie and her blog and I know there's a lot of code hopefully isn't seem super
overwhelming if you saw this all at once.
It would seem kind of crazy but I believe the way we're kind of structuring it out here.
It shouldn't be so bad.
And we just create the delete view.
Let's set that up.
So we'll say post underscore and are going to copy and paste this again.
And then we will say slash and let's call it.
I don't I'll call it remove dollar sign and then we'll call you use dots and this should be call post
delete you there it is.
And then we call it.
View and we'll give it a name and we'll call this name so kind of matches up with the other one will
say post remove comma.
OK.
Now you could always break this up into multiple lines.
So a lot of people when at work of these you or else they kind of style them like this just so it's
more readable.
I'm going to follow along with the actual notes that I have for you guys where everything's on a single
line.
But keep in mind this isn't exactly the best pep 8 styling since it's going beyond the number of character
limits here kind of line.
It's a very faint line.
But again I think it's a little easier to read if you just kind of scroll back and forth versus having
everything on multiple lines.
OK.
Just a little side note coming back to you is that pie.
We have one last class based of you will come over to use that pie and finish it.
And that is that draft list I was mentioning.
So let's create it will say draft's list of you and this is just another list view.
So again I'm going to call a loggin required and this will look a lot like the post list view except
it's going to have a query set specifying that I want to make sure the published day isn't there so
will specify a log in the oral is equal to log in
and then get some more lines and here I also want the redirect.
So let's actually say the redirect field name is going to be equal to blogs slash posts underscore list
HVM El and then connect to a model.
The model is just going to be the post.
And this looks basically exactly like the post list view.
So if we jump back up to the post list view Remember I said for the post view get me stuff that's actually
been published less than or equal to the times are now to kind of make sense you know and stuff.
So you should publish just in case you get some more air that way.
And then we also have the ordering of it in this case.
If I scroll down for the drafts I want to also get a query set.
But I want to make sure that there actually isn't a publication date on it.
So I'll say the get queries sent pasand self and I will return post the objects that filter and I will
grab that published dates underscore underscore and the method I'm going to use here is called is null
and I'll set that equal to true.
So what does that actually say.
Well if this is a list of my drafts that I want to make sure that it doesn't actually have a publication
date meaning I want is not true.
And then we're going to do is offer that I will call order by and I'll order these by the created the.
You could also say Dasch created they kind of up to you the pinning on how you think they should best
be ordered.
So we'll save that and then we make sure that my principles are balanced that pier times are now ordered
by and it's I look at this post to you I should actually have in other parentheses here.
OK.
So that makes more sense.
So I was getting some weird errors because there was some unbalanced Princie here.
Let me scroll that way over here and delete that one.
OK.
So just a quick note I forgot to add this predeceased because it should be an entire filter command
and then off of that should be entire order by command.
So I was actually calling off the now instead of off the entire filter call.
It's kind of more clear if we scroll down here we have this entire filter command and then we have this
entire order by command.
And last but not least we need to still add the draft list view.
You are also again turning back to the API file.
And let's hit it up.
So let me make sure I have a comma here and I will say your L and hopefully on your screen this is a
little more clear.
Right now I'm zoomed in for you guys but on my screen I'm kind of program about myself and a zoomed
in.
So what I'm going to say is post and this is going to be for that draft list.
So let's say for instance we want actually just make the stress keep it simple so traps are signed.
So if we're ever go to drafts and I'm like then I'll be able to see all my dress and it's going to be
views on the draft list of you since it's a class based for and to say it's view and let's give this
a name.
It's a really obvious name so don't forget it will say post draft list comma folks.
So that is all the class based views were going to be working with in our project.
Now I know I said that's all.
But there's definitely quite a bit of them.
Definitely take the time to review what we've done here.
There is a lot of code.
I mean basically we just wrote what about 46 lines plus all these specific or else about 50 lines of
code stuff.
We take the time review what we just did check with the notes make sure things matching exactly in case
you run into any errors.
I know we haven't actually been running the site but that's just to make sure you completely understand
each of these views.
Hopefully this all made basic sense.
The main things that were near that we introduced was the ability to have this get queery set inside
of these template views.
And the other thing we introduced is if you scroll down this sort of logging required Mixon which is
just analogous to those decorators that we've worked with before.
OK I know these are really long lectures so definitely take some time walk around relax.
You definitely earned it.
After listening to all of this.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.