Hello everyone and welcome to part three of CSSA level 1 a major part of what we've seen so far has
revolved around the idea of CSA selectors where selectors in general are used to target HVM elements
that we want the style so far we've only approached the idea of selecting HTL elements by their tags
so grab all paragraph tags or grab all lists tags.
But what if we only want to select subsets or select the single elements.
That is where we can use selectors to clarify exactly what elements we want in each team T.M. we can
use IDs to target single elements and we can use classes to target groups of elements and then we can
also use a wide variety of combinations of selector tags to target certain combinations of elements
things such as descendents or adjacent siblings and we're going to talk a lot more about that.
So let's jump right in to show how this all works.
All right so here we have it.
HVM male called Part 3 him and it's linked to Part 3 underscore mastery that CSSA and in the body of
this aist hymnal I'm going to add some content I'll add a heading theory that says Aima H-3 heading
and then I'm going to add some divs.
And now when it says class member auto completes class I will actually add some classes to this so I'll
call this first div class and we'll put a paragraph in here it says I'm inside the first class.
That way we can see what's going on when we actually begin to Selby's that I will add another division
container I will call this second div and in a paragraph.
All right.
Inside the second div class
and then we'll add a little bit more I'm going to add a paragraph and with this paragraph we're going
to add an ID to it.
So out of the are we're going to set it equal to singled
And in this paragraph will say these must be unique.
Then we're going to make another heading three that says here's a list and you can also just copy and
paste this from the part 3 or 8.
If you don't want to type it all out yourself will have an unordered list.
I'll say something like.
Confirm you can write whatever text you want in here.
And then I will say something like feedback.
Question mark and inside of these list elements we're also going to add inputs.
So the first input is going to just be a checkbox and put.
And the second input is going to be a text so checkbox really similar to a radio button that we've seen
earlier except in our case it's actually just a check box that you've probably seen before.
Online.
And then another list we're going to drop an anchor tag here and we'll give an address to our Web site
this website will be my web site Parian data dot com and we'll say higher data.
I know there's a lot of content so feel free to pause or just copy and paste from the notes and then
we'll put another anchor tag here that has an RF of some other Web site which is say npr.org or you
can put any news Web site you want here or really any web site.
Also it's NPR.
All right.
Lots of stuff here.
So let's break it down real quick let's refresh this to make sure things are linked.
Expand that a bit.
All right.
So right now I have this H-3 heading something that's inside the first day of class something that's
that side the second class.
They make sure I spelled that correctly.
Refresh this and then IDs must be unique or ID.
We have here is a list conferred with a checkbox on it that we can click on and off feedback with some
text input here.
Then two links here Paria data and NPR.
All right.
We have all of this.
So now let's jump to CSX and actually talk about how we can link to this.
So notice here they have classes.
And then my idees.
So if I come to my C Ss and I say something like DIVX and I specify the color of all divs to be read
and then I come back here and I refresh this no matter where the div is no matter what class it is as
long as it has the tag it is going to be the color red.
So first div becomes red.
Second div becomes red.
Normally however you don't want to affect every single tag that has.
Did you want to select subsets.
In that case we can use these classes that we assigned so I can select first or second div instead of
selecting everything that's inside.
And he did.
And that's the key to using classes.
Now what you can't do if a class is just say first div and then color something blue.
Otherwise if I refresh this.
Notice no change occurs when you're dealing with a class.
You tell CSSA that it's a class through a dot.
So classes always start with a dot or a period.
So now if I save this refresh over here I can see that I'm inside the first class has now become blue.
And likewise I can grab the second do and color that red.
Refresh this.
And I can see now inside the first class inside second class are there own individual color.
So this is a very common tool to use and this is where we're getting in today of selectors.
So for classes the always start of this for this period.
OK.
Now we noticed that we also had an I.D. and for IDS one I.D. to be unique.
It just is attached to a single element versus classes can be attached to multiple elements so for an
I.D. It's usually just a single element.
Classes can be across multiple divisions multiple centers multiple paragraphs etc..
Classes use a hash tag so shift number three.
There's a hashtag Lehre.
And then we put in the name of the class which in our case was singled out.
Now we can see that also the syntax highlighting tells you oh you're doing a class here.
Let me double check that it's singled out.
There it is.
Unless change is something to Kolar let's say green
Now let's also give it an it's something called a text decoration text decoration.
I'm just going to kind of throw this in.
These are things such as over lines under lines or like a strike through a line through.
So we'll give that a line through.
Save it.
Let's refresh or can see here we see IDs must be unique.
Is now the color green.
And also has a line through.
So there we're kind of just throwing in a little tune on both how to use IDS and the fact that you can
use text declarations as another property and you can always use the CSSA references and the notes for
various properties if you're looking for them.
And other common thing actually not common sorry is the Asterix the Asterix is a selector for selecting
every element on the page.
So if I say color elements and then say black I save this and refresh is going to color everything black
and it's going to overwrite certain things.
It won't override IDs but you can see here that it's overwriting these class calls this asterisks call
tries to overwrite as much as it can over all the elements.
A quick note though.
This is actually very uncommon usually don't want to just call everything like this.
Maybe if you want something like a background but it's usually pretty uncommon to just call an asterix
there.
Although I do want you to be aware or you can use an asterix to select all the elements in the page
HTML.
However it will be overwritten if they have a particular ID.
All right.
Finally I want to discuss a few different types of selectors.
You can check out the links in the actual CSSA file if you're interested in more of these.
And I have the link open here in a nother tab but basically here is a CSA selector reference and you
can actually call elements on many many types of selectors.
So there's a huge list here of the various types of selectors and I want to show you a few examples
of the more common ones.
So far we've seen things like class like Dot class hash tag ID Asterix to select all the elements and
then certain elements like just calling the element tag.
All right.
Let's show an example of one of those CSSA selectors known as adjacent siblings and that has to do with
elements that are next to each other.
Let's imagine that I wanted to select all unordered list items that are next to an H-3 heading 3.
I would do this I'd say heading 3 and then I use the plus operator unordered lists curly braces and
then whatever property I wanted.
So let's give them a border and we can do border border style and border thickness all in one line.
So instead of saying like we've done before border color and then order with and then border style I
can actually just call border by itself.
Pasan a thickness.
So let's give it four pixels then give it a style let's say it's the dotted style and then give it a
color let's give it purple and that's kind of a quicker nicer way to create borders.
So I'll save this refresher page here.
And now I can see that any unordered list that is next to an H3 now has this border.
So that's known as adjacent siblings and you can always reference here on the links in this SS file
for the notes the various different types of CSSA selectors.
So in our case this plus basically says Select all unordered list elements that are placed immediately
after an H-3.
OK there are two more CSSA selectors that I want to cover for this lecture and one of them is known
as descendants.
And the other one is for attributes.
So for the students It basically looks like this.
If we want to grab all anchor tags that are inside a list you just put a space between them so all the
tags inside of a list and then we can affect them.
So let's give them a color let's say something like red.
So my colon there refresh our page and we can see now that any anchor tag that's inside a list now has
the color red.
And then the last one I want to show you is how to actually effect attributes.
So let's say you want to go further than this and actually grab any anchor Ted inside of a list with
a particular ref and actual link that it can use square brackets for this and say Atra here equal to
the libido E.W..
Now let's go with the last one which was npr.org or whatever website you happen to put in there.
We'll give it a color.
Let's just give it the color something like blue and let's give it a Borders.
Let's practice using that border again.
Remember you just give it a thicknesse such as five pixels.
The style looks give it the style solid and then some color.
Let's give it orange save this refresh our page and we can see now we selected any anchor tag with this
particular ref inside of a list and changes color and it's border.
All right.
So that's really all there is for these particular CSA selectors.
They're at the course the most common ones we're going to be dealing with are really class selectors
and Id selectors.
Well we will show various things such as Jason's siblings or the ascendence attributes et cetera these
throughout our course are going to be less commonly used just because we won't be really focusing on
those type of my new details we're learning.
We will really more focused on classes and ideas so make sure you really know these two types.
Right classes.
Hash tag for IDs.
OK.
And if you ever want to reference the various other type to see selectors just open up the CSSA file
and it has links to the SS reference selector pages.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.