Hello everyone and welcome back here I am at the Adam text editor in my project folder under the application
folder basic app.
I've opened up the models that PI file and this we're going to be actually working with the user model
that we talked about in the previous lecture.
So let's get started.
The first thing I want to do is actually import that basic user model.
NET comes from Django contrib 88 for authorization models import.
And then we're going to import the user model.
Now I'm actually going to collapse that directory trees just so we get a little more room here and start
creating that model.
So we'll see class and we're going to create a user profile info class and that's going to inherit from
models.
Model and what we're going to be doing the very first thing is that user this attribute user for the
user profile info is models.
Da a one to one field.
So that's one to one field with user itself.
And the reason for that is because this is basically a model class to add an additional information
that the default user doesn't have.
Raemer the default user already has things like their username email password first name and last name.
But if you want to add more attributes to your actual user you can essentially almost like extending
the class of this one to one relationship.
What you don't want to do is just directly inherit from the User class.
That may seem really tempting but doing that may screw up your database in thinking that it has multiple
instances of the same user.
So instead we use a one to one feel relationship.
Then below this are the additional classes.
So for instance if we want a portfolio site so maybe this is a Web site where people post their portfolio
projects of things they've been working on we can say portfolio underscore site as one of the attributes
for this model and they will say models dot and we'll call a Ural field here.
And we'll say whoops we'll say blank is equal to true.
And that just means that the user doesn't have to fill it out.
There's not going to be an error if they don't provide a portfolio site and then we want a nother one.
Another attribute that is called profile underscore pick that's going to be called two models dot image
field and then we need to specify where we actually want to upload this to.
And we're going to upload this to and we'll set equal to profile underscore picks as a strain and then
we'll also set this blank to true.
That way the user doesn't need to actually provide their profile picture first that they don't want
to.
Now because we specified We want to upload to profile pics.
That's going to be to need.
That's going to need to be a subdirectory in the media folder we created last time.
So BREENE up that directory tree I have the media folder here.
We're going to expand this and then I'll say new folder and under that I'm going to call it profile
underscore picks enter and then when people upload their images or profile images they're going to be
saved here under media profile pics.
OK.
So continuing on with our models.
What I want to do is add in one more method not an attribute just for printing this out.
So if I ever need to print out a model of a user profile and I can get something back.
So I'll take an self because it's a method and here will just say return self user dot username where
username is that default attribute of this user.
Because remember we just said user is equal to Models 1 to 1 field of user.
All right.
And that's actually all we need to do for our models not pi.
But as I mentioned if you're going to be working with images we want to make sure we have the pillow
library installed.
So here in my virtual environment I'm going to say Pipp install pillow enter and it should collect pillows
and install it.
This may be a little bit of a longer installation than what you're used to.
So keep that in mind.
I'm going to hop forward in time until it finishes installing.
All right.
There it is.
And mine took less than 30 seconds.
Hopefully yours is the same.
And then check out the notes as well especially on the models that py file.
If you're getting the error that says something like a j peg disabled there's like no.
And the previous lecture about what you need to do is set some global options there.
And if you want the actual line of code check out the jingle level five notes are the models that py
file.
There is a line of code above the image field.
You can just copy and paste that.
Anyways that's models up high now is create the form for our models not py file.
So under application we'll say a new file and call it forms that I enter and are ready to actually work
with the forms.
So the first thing you need to do is say from Jinggoy to import forms then we'll say from Jingo that
contrib off models in poor loops import user and then we'll import the model we made which was from
basic app models in poor user profile info.
And save that and now we're going to create two classes here.
One will be the user form.
And this is kind of the base form and this is going to be inheriting from forms the model form.
Review the Django level that talked about forms if this is a little fuzzy to you but we'll have here
a password.
Attribute that we want to kind of edit a bit and we'll say from forms or is equal to forms said equal
to a character field.
And this is going to be a widget with two forms the last word and put those parentheses and then finally
we have that metaclass that we talked about and we'll set the model equal to the user model and then
the fields we want from the base user model.
I want the user name and I want the email field and I want the password.
We will be asking people for their last name or their first name but you could about that add that in
if you want to next for class will say user profile info.
And again we inherit from forms the model for and this one there's nothing I want to edit as far as
the attributes are concerned.
So just say class Meta I will say the model is equal to user profile info.
And I will say the fields is equal to the two fields I want what Charlap portfolio site field and the
other field I made was that profile pic field OK.
Save that in your forms are ready to go.
One last thing we want to do though is actually register the model we created to the admin.
That way if we log in as an admin we can see the actual model.
So I will come to admin that pie under basic app and I'm going to say here from basic app models we're
going to import the user profile info that I created and then I'm going to say adamant that site register
should be lowercase our going to register that user profile info save that and we've created the models
that we're going to be using essentially just that user profile which is a one to one match to the built
in user with Django the forms that's going to collect the information the actual registration page and
then the admin that PI file and that is essentially part 1 of what we need to do to set up everything
as far as the models and the forms part 2 of what we need to do is actually connect all of this to the
templates so the home page the registration page log in page et cetera.
So we're going to end this here and we'll see at the next lecture where we begin to discuss how to expand
off of this.
But ending this you should have models up high Adam in that pie informs that pie ready to go inside
of re-application.
And remember whenever you add it the admin that pie file or create a new model where you're going to
want to do is down here at the bottom.
Say Python managed up-I migrate enter and then once that's done you see you may see something like says
make migrations.
So you also need to do that using the say Python whip's Python manage the pie make migrations and then
the name of re-application.
So basic app enter that's going to create some.
And then we'll say Python managed up-I migrate one more time and we're ready to go.
OK.
So thanks everyone.
I'll see at the next lecture or begin discussing how to connect all this to the actual templates and
those extremophiles.
I'll see you there.