Hello everyone and welcome back to the solutions lecture for the Django challenge.
Well we're going to be doing this lecture video is just going through the solutions to the previous
challenges together.
If you are able to figure it all out then you can go ahead and just skip this lecture.
But if you want to see the process gone through one more time feel free to stick around as I go through
it.
I'm going to jump to the Adam text editor to get started OK here I am at the Adam text editor.
Now the first thing we needed to do was actually create a new Django project so I'll just go ahead and
put this under that same.
My Django stuff folder that we had earlier makes you change directories so you're matched to it.
And then well I will go ahead and do is say Django dash adamant.
What was.
And then I do the starts project command.
Hopefully we're able to remember that and then whatever you want to name the project in this case we'll
call it something like pro to we'll hit enter and then we can see here that the project too has been
created.
So under my jingoes stuff I had this new pro to folder and it's ready to go.
Then the next thing I needed to do was actually create an application inside of this pro to project.
So I will do is change the rectory to be inside of Pro-Tools.
So I will say see the two row to and now I should be aligned of this managed up by file so I can call
that file and then call start app and create that second app.
So say Python managed up PI and then the commander I want to call for that the star app and then let's
call this something like app to create it or it can see we have app 2 inside of that project too.
Great.
Then the next thing you want to do is actually create a view.
So I click here on a view and here we say create your views here.
So let's fill in the needed information.
The typical view is shown you how to do so far requires that HTP response and we need to actually import
that.
We will say from jingo.
H t t p import HTP response.
And then we'll go ahead and create that index for you which is going to be DPF to create that function
index and then it takes on a request.
Remember this could actually be called whatever you want but by convention it's request and we will
return that HTP response and pass in some code and in this case actually wanted you to pasan some H
Tim L So will say my second project and then close off the H team Elkhead am.
Now obviously you won't be passing in an entire h m l string here for most usual circumstances but I
just wanted to show you what would happen in case you wanted to test out the capabilities of Django
for this views that py file.
So I will save that and then we need to link this new view to our u r l.
So I come over here to you or else start.
Scroll down and then we have the URL pattern's list.
And just like we did last time and going to say from and in this case it's going to be app to import
views that views that py file and then under your patterns.
I'm going to say your L looks good and to have that in your l using regular expression.
I'm going to use just like we did last time the Chevron with the dollar sign.
And then as a second argument let's make sure we only have one single quote there I will say buse dot
index.
So I call index off of that and then we'll just give that the name index comma to complete that.
And then finally I need to edit my settings that PI file under pro 2 to let the actual project know
that my app 2 application actually exists.
So again we come down here until we see installed apps and I will add in here as an argument that app
too.
And then I will save this then we can actually run our server and make sure everything works correctly.
Let's go ahead and do that just come down here and I will say Python managed up high run server enter
lets make sure everything works out OK.
Looks like we're running it here.
So I'm going to copy this.
Put it into my browser and hopefully we see that string.
My second project and looks like it came out well in the drag it over.
Now we can see here we have my second project in a taluk So it's actually able to understand that that's
HVM L when it reports back that view.
And what I want you to do is sort of get used to this workflow of creating a project and creating applications
hopefully you feel comfortable with the few commands that we've learned so far.
All right.
That's really all there is to this challenge.
If you were getting stuck on anything or had any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums and I'll
be happy to help you there.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.