Hello everyone and welcome back to the solution lecture part one for the front and PROJECT.
We're going to be cutting through the solution for the connect for game.
Let's get started by hopping over to our editor.
OK.
So to get this project started I have three files in HTL file a CSSA file and a javascript's File.
We're going to start off with the HTL then we'll Stylo some CSSA.
And then finally the majority of our time is going to be spent coding through the logic we have.
Jake Query and Javascript.
Let's get started with the HMO.
So the smell is actually quite straightforward.
First we just do the basic aist him all call.
We can give it the title K'NEX for save that.
And then I want to link to bootstrap as well as my own CSSA file.
So let's start with my C Ss which is I have it just being called game that C Ss let me save that and
I'm going to copy and paste the Cdn link for bootstrap and you can just copy and paste this yourself
either from the notes or from Boots get bootstrap dot com.
So there's a C and for bootstrap lets make sure everything's working just by saying hello in the heading
and refreshing our age Tim Page.
OK it looks like it's connected networking.
Let's start by putting everything into a div container so that we keep it organized and centered on
the page.
And I will make sure that it's completely aligned centered by saying a line center as a parameter in
that div and all have one say welcome to Connect for all have heading to say something like connect
4 chips to win and then H-3 will say
let's start or want to delete this refresh.
Make sure everything is working.
Looks like it's good.
Now the task we have to accomplish is actually constructing the table that's going to be connect 4.
So what I am going to do and you don't have to do it this way there's many ways you can bill at this
table to create a table row with each table cell.
What's containing a button inside of it.
And then something else going to do is make sure I call table here.
Let's put this row back and say that table and then let's give this table a class equal to board so
we can reference it later.
Although this will be just the only table tagging RHC mail we could just use the table tags or reference
it later on who will give it a class so it makes a little more sense.
And then finally type button.
We don't need a name for this button.
And the button itself can be blank.
So the idea is we're going to be clicking buttons on and off we'll have them change color to depict
whether the chip is inside of that area or not.
And we need to add a couple more cells to this row so we can just copy and paste this.
There we go.
So let's save that.
It's going to be seven cells per row.
And then I can just copy and paste this row and then continue on and connect four has six total rows.
So I need to do this five more times.
Let's make sure that's one row to row three row for row five row six row I believe.
But let's actually make sure of this by refreshing our page here I can see a little table it's kind
of messed up and that's because it's actually not inside of our container class.
Let's bring this div all the way down here.
Save this refresh.
Now I can see I have a seven cell across and the rows and six rows total grape.
Finally I want to T.M. connect my script so I'm going to call scripts and I will connect this to the
can say source.
I actually don't need to specify the type for now.
We'll call it my script that just that's what my empty files called right now.
And then I also want to connect it to a query.
So again we just copy and paste to see the end point to do that here.
You can either do it from the notes or from code that just queried dot com.
So we have our east T.M. all set up.
We're going to do now is style a little bit so that these buttons actually make sense.
You can see here it can kind of click on these buttons right now but it's way too small.
OK so to start off to see SS I'm going to call the board and then every button within that.
And then let's give them all a whiff of 100 pixels about the Kallen and a height of 100 pixels going
to save this.
And here we can see we're starting to get something that looks quite a bit nicer.
So if I zoom out a little bit here we now have our connect four board.
Let's keep styling it a little more let's give them all the background color that's gray.
Right now they have a bit of a fade to them.
So if we refresh we can see they're all gray now.
We'll give them a bit of a margin.
So we have a little space in between them save that come appear refresh.
That's nice.
And let's make them round.
So to make them round we use border radius and we can just set this to be at 50 percent and that should
make them circles OK.
And then we get this kind of a weird effect over here when we click and the way to get rid of that is
by giving them a border will give them a four pixel solid black border.
Save refresh.
And here we can see our board is now complete.
OK.
So our HTL is done and our CSSA is done.
Everything looks to be styled correctly.
Coming up next we're going to be doing is dealing with the majority of our code which is all happening
on the javascript's side.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you in the next lecture.
We're going to pick up right where we left off.