Hello everyone and welcome to the models templates views lecture for Django Django operates on what
is known as a model's templates and views paradigm.
It's also called MTV for short and it encompasses the idea of how to connect everything we've talked
about so far.
So we've talked about models and databases we showed a little bit of templates and their tagging and
we've talked about views as well how do we actually connect everything.
There are a few basic steps to achieving the goal of serving dynamic content to a user based off the
connection of those models we use and templates.
Let's walk through these steps.
The first step is that that views that PI file we import any models that we will need to use.
The second step is to use a view to query the model for data that we will need.
The third step is to pass results from the model to the template.
The fourth step is to edit the template so that it's ready to accept and display the data from the model
and then the fifth step is to map a L to that actual view.
We can practice this methodology by changing what we display on the front index page.
So to get our understanding of this entire process we're going to start by actually generating a table
on that index page.
The table will display all the web pages and access records from the Access record database we created
and populated.
Will also be using template tagging to connect the model to that age Tim Page.
This entire process is going to be introducing a lot of new things so don't be intimidated.
The template tagging especially can seem confusing at first.
We've already seen a little bit of it with the static images that we use template tagging to inject
into the HD M-L But again don't worry if the template tagging seems confusing.
We're going to be getting tons of practice with this later on as we develop more clones of Web sites
after we walk through all of this with some code.
You will have a challenge to practice your own MTV skills on your own.
Level 3 is going to focus a lot more on expanding this idea of MTV and the mapping or else step that
step number five which we haven't really dived into yet and we won't focus too much on this particular
section of the course.
OK let's get started.
No knowing to open up my editor to walk through this entire MTV paradigm OK let's get started showing
an example of how to actually use MTV paradigm.
So I'm going to come over here to first project first app and open up my views up py file and so far
I have this simple index request that took this dictionary and then used that to actually inject with
template tagging the actual content and taste.
You know we're going to be expanding on this idea by connecting this to the database.
So I would say from first app models import and then the three models we had a topic we had a web page
and we had access record.
And then here in this actual index.
And I would change this if I wanted to do a different view.
But right now we'll keep things simple everything on the home page.
I'm going to make a variable called web pages list and this is going to be equal to access record.
And then I'm going to call the objects and then I'm going to call the objects and say order by which
is a method off of these objects and then order by the date field.
So if you're a little confused by that order by it's a really common sequel command so you can if you're
used to sequel that probably feels really natural but it basically just says order this by that date
field or that date column.
That is going to create a dictionary.
So say dates underscore the T is equal to and then I'm going to call the key access record.
All access records and then that web pages list is going to be the actual value for that.
So let's get rid of this dictionary.
And then finally going to return render first AB slash index let each symbol and then for the context
it's going to be instead of that my dictionary will be that the dictionary date underscore the ICC OK.
So the main thing is to get across here is that we are infused up high in that first I remember is we
actually import the models and then here I'm going to use render to actually grab stuff from the model
itself and then use template tagging later on to inject that into the H T.M..
So so far we're done in steps 1 and 2 where we imported the models and use the view to query the model
for the data we need.
Now I'm going to come over to my actual HVM L and that's over here under templates.
First app index that each T.M. and then go into I'm going to essentially clear all of this.
This is now going to be the original index that each team L.
So if you open up the Django level two files you'll notice that there's two HVM L's original index and
then index.
Right now I'm going to go with the index the original indexes just everything I deleted.
All right so I said H Tim L and then if we're ever dealing of static files will want to load them.
We may or may not have this time but it's always a good idea to say load static files in case you're
going to have them and then we'll keep the title say title is Shingo level 2 and also in the head.
Let's give the link to the CSSA file so we can get used to doing that.
So I'll type and link.
It's a stylesheet ref is going to be an injection here with template tagging.
So I'll say
static.
And then here in quotes.
And actually this whole thing needs to be in quotes.
Let's make sure that's correct.
And I'm going to say closing tech here static and then if another set of quotes see assess and then
whatever happened to be I believe it was my style and we can add that in that SS So we'll save this
in if I expand my static folder or I should CC SS and there's my style that that's SS.
It only changes heading to color red.
But we can work that later on.
OK so so far I floated the static files and I was able to do that to link to actual CSSA.
But what we really want to focus on here is using the template tagging to grab from the view the requested
information from the models.
So inside the body I'll say H-1 I will say Hi welcome to Gengel level 2 and then H-2 will say Here are
your
access records probably won't want to do something like this realistically on a Web site where you just
display all the information from your model.
But right now keeping things simple and I'm going to make a diff here and this class is going to just
be Jeng too.
Now I can grab it later on.
OK and this is where he's going to look a little strange with the template tagging.
I'm going to say here with the curly brackets and then the percent sign.
If axis underscore records.
So what does that actually mean.
Here I'm just checking if I actually have the access records from.
But go back to views that PI right here.
So if I actually have this key then do some stuff so you can see it's a little bit like Python is not
quite full Python as far as a syntax but it's similar.
And then I'm going to create a table tag and then will create the head and then I'll say site name.
And then here I will say they accessed.
OK so those are the basics here and now I need to do is actually insert the table rows in the table
rows are going to be connected to the actual model.
So I need to somehow add in logic here that loops through every row in the access records and what that
looks like is this.
I say for some temporary variable name will say A.S.C. in and then access records.
And this has to match in whatever you had over here.
Views for the key.
So what I'm saying is for this temporary variable in access records remember access records is going
to be this list of web pages that's ordered by the date from the model.
Hopefully here we can begin to see kind of that peak of the iceberg of that MTV how we're connecting
all the moving pieces and then what I do is I create the table rotate TR And I'll create table cell
tag tiddy and inside of this.
Now I use this set of curly brackets of No percent sign because it's not actually logic is essentially
just injecting text right now.
I will say A.S.C. dot and then we actually call what we want so I'll say that name for the site name.
And then again I'll call a CC and then the actual field I want.
In this case the field is date because that's how I have it here.
Site name and they accessed and then finally you have to make sure that whenever you have this for tag
that for luteal you end it.
So here I'm going to make sure that we end that by saying And for now that's a little different than
anything we've seen in Python so keep that in mind and actually want this whole thing to be inside that
closing table tag.
So I will save that.
And then since I have this if access records I need an else to go along with it.
So let's add that in and that's going to be outside of the table.
Well say else we'll print out a paragraph no access records founds and then since I have that if else
I need to end it.
So we say and if and then that's the end of the div tag.
And that's really all we need here.
So we'll save that.
And let's check out the or else that PI file make sure that's all linked up.
So on their first project they have your L's up high.
Make sure that's OK.
And that also looks good.
Looks like I'm connecting views that index to the home page so that makes sense and if I look at my
uro's up high fall at first that that also makes sense here.
Great.
So let's see if this actually worked and tried out going to say Python managed up PI run server enter.
See if we get any errors here OK no errors it's a good sign.
We're going to copy and paste this into my browser.
Let's bring it over so bring it over.
Get this.
It says Hi welcome to jingle too.
Here are your access records and embarrassingly I spelled your wrong but hopefully you forgive me.
And here I can see that I have the actual table.
So let's give a little bit of styling to this table so it's a little bit more readable.
And I can do that simply by affecting the SS.
So if I come over here to static remember I'm loading the sexual static.
So let's change it up so we get a little bit of color on those table cells.
So I will say here.
Table and then it give it a border let's say two pixels solid black.
And if I want to actually give border not just the outside of the table but to the table header and
table rows I can put a comma here.
Th comma CD.
Or since I actually gave it a class if I remember correctly.
Coming up here so is Django too.
So let's actually grab this Jing to class and then added in.
So I'll say that jingle to see if that actually works.
Come back here bring back my actual age T.M. or excuse me refresh the page.
And we're getting not found static.
Let's come back here to index that smil.
Make sure that was all correct and I missing the percent sign to close this so that should have matched
OK.
Now let's save this run this again.
Control-C.
My thumb is up I run server.
Bring back my actual browser and if I bring it back here now I see that the heading is also connected
so I probably should add those that last time and I can see here that I have the table of the border.
So looks like I need to actually add in some more.
So let's just make it table.
Th.
T The Save that will refresh the page and restart this and refresh on that page.
Now I get these nice double borders.
OK.
So hopefully you can begin to see how you connect that.
Everything OK.
Now I wanted to take a little bit of time to discuss how Django can help you debug your code especially
if template tagging.
If you ever feel confused on it.
So as you probably just notice like even I can confuse the tempo of tagging or actually accidentally
make mistakes the error reporting is actually really good for this sort of thing.
So if you come down you know you're doing a template tagging and you forgot to write.
And if so your code is really long.
You had the statement up here and you know typically in Python you know how to say and if so you just
accidentally forget.
Well if you take a look at what the refresh site looks like after you say and if I refresh it and here
we already see that I have a template syntax error and bringing the page over look something like this
it says unclose tag.
If looking for one of.
And if it actually reports back that it's looking for an end if and if you scroll down it will actually
tell you what it's looking for as far as it's match.
So it says hey this highlighted line if access records has no matching and if and you can see there's
an entire traceback here.
You can follow as well.
So the error reporting is actually really good on the Web site.
So definitely take advantage of that.
Well essentially almost always tell you that correctly what it's looking for.
Now if you don't actually know what this means then you can always google search it or search stack
overflow and you'll probably find your answer there.
OK.
Hopefully now you have a better understanding of how to use the MTV paradigm to actually connect your
models and inject content into the T.M..
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.