Welcome back everyone and this lecture will learn how to do additional fields.
Currently we can only see one field of our models in the list view on the Admin Page.
We can actually add more fields to view AND ORDER BY.
And again this is also just an easy addition of an attribute in that class.
We've been kind of playing around with the up overs of the editor unsure how to do it.
All right so here we are back at the admin PI file and before we actually added the attribute I want
to show you what it currently looks like when we look at the list view of a particular model and to
bring in over my browser and right now if I don't do any filters or if I show all I can see all the
movies.
So I only see right now movie in this list view of a model.
So bringing that over again.
Let's go ahead and show you the attributes and the attributes quite simple as just list display lists
underscore display and let's go ahead and just copy this list so we display all the fields.
Usually you probably don't want to do this depending on how many fields you have in your model but that
should be enough for us.
We'll save it and then let's bring back our list view page and then I'm going to refresh this and I
can see the really cear the length and the title and the order you put them in the list is the order
they show up.
So I probably want a title over here on the left hand side.
Let's do that as well and move this over and let's go ahead and have title be first.
So don't cut that here.
It's actually his insert title and then remove it over here on the back.
There you go.
So I'm going to save this and now refresh the page.
And I can see.
Title is now here first.
So whatever is first in this column is the one you can click on to go to the detail view page.
So again this is the list view.
Click on one of these.
It shows you the detailed view.
You can also now sort by these guys so you can notice these little kind of pop ups here so you can sort
by really sure just by clicking here on the top column and that's how you can add more fields in your
list for you.
Simple as that.
Again the attribute is just lists underscore display and hopefully now you get the theme of how easy
it is to work with Django admen.
You essentially just create a class here.
Inherit from Adam in that model admin and then add in attributes as you need them.
Things like filtering displaying search fields etc. and then just remember to register that particular
class.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.