Hello everyone and welcome back to part two of coding out the user models to actually fit the registration
part of this project.
What we need to do is start working with the team else so those templates we're going to do is come
over here to templates create a new folder we'll call it basic underscore app to match name for application
and then under this I'm going to create a new file.
Now call it base h T.M..
So it's going to be the base H.T. mail that we will be inheriting from or create in other new file and
we'll call this index.
H team L that will be the actual index page then we'll create one new file and this will be registration.
H T.M..
So the registration page and then we haven't talked about it yet but after someone's registered they're
going to want to log in and log out of the page.
So we'll create a new file called log in.
H t l and we won't work with that right now.
We'll have another discussion about logging and logging out.
But right now I want to work on these three main files base index studies T.M. and registration and
once you've them that we'll also edit the Urals up high file at the project and create your Allsopp
profile for a basic application.
Well let's start off with the base which is going to have everything we need for the project.
So the first thing on the base page html page we don't have that open restriction.
Basically Sammael page let me collapse this so I get a little more room is type HTL and let all the
automatic input and we would just call this base for the title actually won't give it anything because
we don't want to inherit the title block there.
You could make another block for a title block and then inherit everything kind of separately the head
and the body.
That's totally a normal thing to do.
But we won't focus on that until we actually get to the clone projects because we don't care too much
about looking good.
Right now what I'm going to say is pass in the bootstrap I mention we don't care about looking good
but we want to look a little bit good.
So it hasn't bootstrap and then I'm going to create a bar on this page just so we can quickly jump to
links on the page.
So this nav bar.
It's going to be with the class equal to nav bar space nav bar dasht default space nav bar bash static
the top.
Then after that going to make a div and that's going to be inside of a container class and then after
that loops then after that I'm going to create a unordered list.
And that's going to contain all the links.
So this unordered list is going to have a class of NAV space.
Now Barbash nav and you can always copy and paste this from the notes.
If you don't want to watch me code this whole thing out.
So inside this unordered list are going to be the actual links to the other pages on the site.
So create three anchor tags and these anchor tags are going to have a class equal to either nav bar
brand or nav bar that links all say nav bar.
That brand will have this link back to the actual home page.
So we'll use template tagging for this.
Hopefully remember from the template tagging lectures that we can just type in your l and then index.
If we set up their view or the you are up high file properly we haven't actually set the URLs up by
file so we'll have to do that and make sure it matches these.
RFE RL template calls but I will have here be the actual text say something like Django or home or whatever
you want.
And then we'll create another list in other anchor tag.
And this is going to be of a class as well will say class and this anchor tag is equal to NAV bar dash
link and I'm going to copy and paste this because we're going to see it again right below to link to
another page on the site.
So this will be the adamant site and let's make this be the register site.
So for the actual registration then what we will do here is say under Tref
create a URL tag and make sure have the percent signs up here as well.
For the index page there we go under Atra here will say your old template that looks for basic app
and then what it returns is whatever is named the register you.
And then here we're going to say the same thing we'll call your L and then we'll say.
Adam in and then passen index.
All right so basically what we did is we set up a nav bar on the base.
Each T.M. and it links back to the home page with chain go links back to the admin page and then links
to the registration page which we haven't actually created yet.
So we will in just a second.
Later on when we talk about log in we'll show how we can use template tagging to add a Fourthly that
will either say log in or log out the pending on what the user is doing.
But after all of this outside of the nav bar what I want to do is say simply tagging Crit. a block all
this block the body block
and then I will also say and block
and anything inside of this we'll just put them into a container.
So for the other pages everything that's going to be there will be inside a container.
Obviously that's optional.
But for now this should work for us for a baseline age T.M..
Now let's focus on the other files such as the home page so the home page is just going to extend from
that.
So we'll say extends basic underscore app slash based HVM bill.
And I've noted a lot that you have to make sure the very first line in any age female file is this doc
type H HVM L.
The reason I can just say extends here is because if I extend this properly the very first line should
be doctype HTL and the second line will be T.M. et cetera.
Sometimes if you're a little paranoid you can always just copy paste this onto the first line to doublecheck
although you have it twice doctype doctype.
But just make sure that it's the top at the base h t m l at the very first line is extends and that
should work fine as well.
Up next one actually called the body block that we made.
So we'll say block and then body underscore block and then we will say div Jumbotron.
I tend to really like jumbo trons and will say Shingo level five is the home page.
And then what we're going to do is continue on by calling the end block.
So I will say and block right here.
And the Block saved that.
And now let's move on to the registration page.
So we have registration and what's going to happen here is we also are going to extend going to say
extends
from basic app slash based HVM L and then I'm going to set up the actual registration form that's on
the page.
So we're going to look a little bit different but usually you're going to want to import some files.
So maybe we want to import or load static files.
We don't really have any.
But just to show you what this would typically look like if you have static files maybe you want to
import some images like welcome to the page like your brand image or whatever on your registration page.
Typically you would need to load those static files in and then we're going to call block body block
and whenever you do that you also want to call in and end the block and now let's actually put in the
form so I'll say div this is a jumbotron.
And what we're going to do is have some logic here.
And the logic is going to look like this and this will make more sense when we talk about the views
and the context dictionaries we return.
But it's going to say if registered me in the context dictionary it returns something that says registered
because I have an if I want to make sure I have an end if so I'll say if registered this person is going
to say thank you or the site is going to say thank you for registering exclamation mark because I have
an if I can have an LCR I will say.
Else this person is not registered.
Then we're going to actually display the Himmel for registration which is something like register here
and let's pass on the actual file we'll say fill out the form
and then we need to make the form using template tagging.
So first we want to have the actual form.
We don't need a class and we don't need an action we can take care of that later.
But we do want to make sure that the method is equal to post and because we're using multimedia data
that we're uploading such as the image file we just say E and C type is equal to.
And we're going to say multipart form data.
So make sure you have that.
Otherwise the image uploading won't work.
So we can have that and usually you want the method to be last.
Although that doesn't actually affect it just for readability.
Having this is more common.
And then we're going to do is call an R C S R token C SRF underscore token and then call in the parts
of the form Zoomer that former created we can say a user form as underscore the that's the base user
form is going to ask for if we go back to the forms that come without.
Member user forum we're asking for the user name to email the password that we need to call the user
profile info form for the portfolio site and their profile pic.
So coming back to registration and then once we grab those attributes from the bases or form I'm going
to also want to grab stuff from my profile form as underscored.
And this term user underscore form and profile underscore form.
Those are going to be defined within the context dictionary of the views.
So we haven't actually done that yet.
So that type in an input is going to be a Samit type doesn't need to have a name but it does want to
have a values will say register and that's the end of our form.
So pretty simple so far.
So we will save this.
And what we've done so far this lecture is set up three main Tim L files.
We set up our base the H team l file has a nav bar which has the links with the morals on them and then
it also has the body blocks the index page.
This is just the home page not much here except for Welcome to jingle level 5 essentially and then registration
that each team L which has the tokens user forms and profile forms.
So these are things from the user sending back the context dictionary that we haven't actually worked
with yet before we actually conclude this lecture.
Let's set up the Oreilles not py files to match up.
And then in the next lecture we'll actually talk more about the registration and what the views that
py files are going to look like.
So let's start by jumping to the actual project that PI file to have opened here.
We'll scroll down and set everything up.
So what I want to do is say import your L now will also import include import admen and then I want
to say from basic underscore at import views.
Now we haven't worked out all the views that py file in fact if we take a look at it it's totally empty.
But so far this is going to be a bunch of functions that we need to fill out later.
So right now we'll kind of assume the names of those functions and then work backwards to them.
Let's set up the home page and that's pretty easy every time we'll set up your el and then using regular
expressions.
I just want to say just the domain name Buzkashi index and we'll give it the name index.
Let's set up a couple of more views.
We'll set up the admin page to be your L up.
That's actually what is set up for us.
Never mind.
Let's set up your l.
Anything that has to do with basic app so we'll say our Here here basic underscore app slash and then
I'm going to call include the basic underscore app.
You are else OK.
And then we'll talk about logging in and logging out later on.
But these three views should work for now and if we come over to our basic app it doesn't have a girl's
up-I file yet that will match up to include here so let's create it will say basic app you file your
Alstott pie and let's actually do the Urals PI file for application.
Firstly you say from Django.
C o f dot you are else import Yoro and then we'll say from basic app and poor views.
Again you can just say from Daut import use up to you and since we're using template tagging or I should
say template your Elle's number we need to set up the app name variable.
So here say something like.
App name is equal to and then it has to match the actual application name not cases basic up and create
some of your patterns and the patterns we are going to create is one for someone who's about to register.
So we'll say our car register slash dollar sign and then this we'll call views and will have a function
in there called register.
We haven't made it yet but we'll create it in a little bit and then we'll say register there.
So we'll add more to this later on but this should be a nice cutting off point.
So let's quickly review everything we did.
We set up base HD mail in the mail and registration that reached him L..
And those are linking to the actual contex dictionary so we're going to return back.
We will work with the views that PI file.
Then we also set up the basics of our year olds up-I for both the project and the application.
We're not done with them yet.
We'll still add more stuff to them.
When we talk about working up the logon page but now coming up next is the majority of the work and
a lot of it happens right here with the views that PI file.
So thanks everyone for watching and I'll see in the next lecture where we talk about the use of high
file and setting up the registration here.