Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture we're going to be going over an example solution to
the Spectrum project.
Remember your solution may not look exactly like mine as far as sizing and color choice but the overall
ideas hopefully similar enough that you can follow along these solutions and reflect back on your own
work.
Let's jump to our editor in browser to get started.
OK.
So here I am with my editor open.
I have two files project thought CSSA and product thought HMO.
They're empty right now.
Here is what we're trying to recreate something that looks similar to this with our own color palette
choice and our own custom font choice.
And right now I have this project thought to.
Just refreshed it so that it's clean and there's nothing there.
Let's get started by working on the Tim elf.
The first thing I'm going to do is just type H T.M. and we'll call the title of this project and we
also want to make sure that it's linked to our actual sheet.
In our case such is called Project that the SS and that's all we have to pass since it's in the same
directory.
And then for the body itself I'm going to give a Heading 1 and we'll call it my spectrum project and
then let's make a table.
So we'll make a table.
It's going to have one table row.
And if we look back at what the solution looks like remember we have one table row with essentially
five cells.
So I would call t d and i will copy and paste that for more times so that my total is five and if I
want to actually reference stuff here it might be useful to give the table a class that I can reference
later.
So let's give it the class something like art and for the table cells let's give them each an individual
ID.
That way I can assign them each individual color and we may not use that class but it's just there in
case we need it later.
The idea is we will definitely use though.
So we'll give each of these our own ID
and we'll label this five.
So let's save that come back to project that each team will refresh and I see my spectrum project.
But the thing is all my table cells are empty.
So let's come to CSX and assign them overall something to make sure that stuff is working.
So let's give them all a background color of black.
And if I refresh this I won't see much.
I see essentially five little tiny cells there you may not even see them on your screen.
So what I have to do is expand the size of these.
So let's continue doing that with something like giving these table cells a height.
Now let's give them a height of 200 pixels with such a colon
save that refresh.
And now you can see there a good height.
All right the next thing I want to do is actually give these table cells a with as well so let's do
that.
Let's give it something like 100 pixels that should be fine.
And then refresh over here in I can see my spectrum project is starting to look similar to what I have
here.
We can measure off the size of the height and the with if we want to make it larger.
So if we want to just expand this a little bit so it's a little nicer.
There we go.
And what I want to do also is start to grab the heading one and text the line to be Center.
Let's refresh this.
And now we're getting to really think of something that looks like closer to a spectrum project.
Something else we noticed here is that the table itself isn't centered.
So let's try to use the margin on auto to do that.
So I can use that class I used earlier or I could also just call table itself since it happens to be
the only table there.
And we'll just call auto save that and now I have a centered margin here or the margin is the outside
the very outside of the box model.
So let's review what we've done.
We've been able to create our table cells.
We have the art class here which allows us to just grab if we go back to the page C.M. that entire table.
So I could have also just called Table but I wanted to be a little more specific in case we have multiple
tables here and use margin auto to center it and have also text the line center that heading 1.
So everything looks good here.
Now what I'm going to do is come to this coolers CO and actually grab some of these hex codes.
I went ahead and just grabbed a basically a random color palette and I'm going to copy and paste these
text codes so let's copy each of these.
So there's my first one there's my second one
third
fourth and let's grab the fifth one and we have to make sure each of these starts with that hash tag.
There we go.
So those are my hex colors and the way I can assign these is by calling the ID's.
Remember we gave each individual table cell in ID and eventually will be able to get rid of this background
color black.
So let's do that.
Let's go.
Hash tag 1 and we'll call the background color for it to be the very first
let's refresh this now we can see we beginning to override some of these the colors because if remember
about CSSA specificity.
The ID is going to be in the hierarchy or above the hierarchy of just a normal element call.
So it's called background color again let's keep doing this for the rest of them.
And if you want you can basically fast forward through this because I'm just repeating myself here.
So let's copy that excuse me
semi colon and we're gonna do that two more times for the for class.
Give it a background color
and let's do that again for five class or five Id excuse me I should have been saying Id not class.
And then let's paste in these colors here
copy and paste that color there.
All right.
So let me save that.
Refresh this.
And now I can see my spectrum project is looking pretty good.
I have the colors lined up and they're overwriting this tiddy call.
In fact I can just delete that save this and I'll still look the same.
Now I want to affect the spacing in between these if we look at Spectrum 5.
There's a little more spacing here in between these actual table cells.
So to do that what I can do is mess around with the box model and remember the important part that box
model is the actual border.
So quick way to do this would just be to get each table cell a white border.
So I'll say something like border and give them each let's say six pixel solid white border.
Save that and refresh.
In here we get the nice spacing out that I was looking for.
And finally I want to add my own custom font to the Heading 1.
So I already have Google fonts opened here and I wanted to just scroll down to a random one.
Let's say something that's.
This one looks nice is Anton.
So we'll add that the family selected will open it up here.
I will copy this as a link into my m l file save it come to project C Ss and copy the font family call
and put it under H-1.
So now when I refresh project I can see my spectrum project now has that new font and that's really
all you have to do for this project.
Again hopefully you have enough practice with the box model so you can play around with this.
You didn't have to do it with the border you could have messed around with the margin and padding as
well but it's really up to you.
There were multiple multiple solutions to getting something to look like this.
So do not worry if your solution did not follow mine exactly.
There are multiple ways to get something that looks like this.
If you have any questions feel free to post them to the Kewney forums.
Hopefully at a fun time recreating something you just saw the front end and you could recreate it using
H TMLC SS on the back.
And thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.