Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture we're going to quickly cover some more your L mappings
methods.
So as we continue on throughout the course we're going to be dealing with mapping or else quite a bit.
There are several ways of doing this.
So I want to briefly touch upon another way but first off let's review what we've done in the past.
Previously we showed a very direct mapping that imported the views of Pi file directly into the thought
pie of your projects.
So you're connecting your views of your application to the or else that py file of the project itself.
Now we want to do is show you the ability of using the include function that you can import from a Django
module the include function allows us to look for a match with Figler expressions and link back to our
application's Own Your else thought py file.
That way each application has its own your L's py file as a quick note we'll have to manually add in
this Yarl's py file because when you start your application it doesn't automatically create one for
you.
Unlike when you start your project it does create the Oreilles that PI file for the project.
So we would want to do is add the following to the project's Uriel's that PI file will add that first
line which basically imports that include function and then where it says the usual patterns list.
We've worked with before.
What you will do is called the function from before and then add in a regular expression as a first
argument.
And basically what this regular expression does is it just says OK look at your domain name slash and
then whatever that string is in the first regular expression slash and then call the app your Elle's
from the include function and this will all make a lot more sense when we actually code this out later
on.
But just to touch upon what I just explained.
Basically what this does it's allowing us to look for any URL that has this sort of pattern.
Bill GWW that domain name dot com slashed first underscore app or whatever you happen to have put there
in that first regular expression.
In this case I'm just calling it what the application was called first underscore app slash.
And then if we match that pattern what happens is the include function basically tells Django hey go
look at the Urals PI file that's inside of the first app folder not the world's top pie file it's inside
of the project.
And basically this might seem like a lot of work especially for such a simple mapping but later on we
really want to try to keep our projects or else the py file clean and modular that we want to set the
reference to the application instead of listing them all in the main Your Alstott py file.
So you can easily plug and play a few applications.
Everything is modular now.
And the Jor-El's are inside the actual application.
So let's quickly walk through an example of all this just to show how it all works.
And as a quick note we've covered everything in part 1 of jingoes official tutorial.
So after this lecture you may want to go visit part one of that efficient Tauriel and browse through
it.
You can check the resource for direct link to part 1 of jingoes official tutorial.
All right.
With that said let's jump to Adam and actually code out everything that I just explained.
Ok so here we are at.
Adam the first thing you want to do is actually check out our original your PI file from our first project
and important we need to have their so previously we just said from first app import use and then we
called using the URL function a regular expression here and that just said OK put in the use that index
in case you ever get anything just the domain name.
What we all do now is add in another your I'll call here and put in a regular expression with an extension
of this.
And basically was going to say is something like first underscore app forward slash and then we're going
to use the include function in order to use the include function I need to import it and I can do from
Django got C-L an F for configuration.
Got you or else in poor include.
And then with this function I can actually now just pass this in as the second argument include.
And then I'm going to call my first underscore app dot you are else in it takes it in as a string and
then finally I want to make sure I have a comma here OK let's save that.
And then the next thing I want to do is actually create this stop file inside our first application.
So I'll say right click on first map.
Create a new file and call it your ELSE STOP pie and it's going inside that first application I made.
And now what we will do is essentially create almost like a mini your old Pif file is going to have
a lot of the same functionality we just saw earlier.
So again I will say from jingo dot CNF got you Earles import your el WIPs you r l Cingular.
And then I will also say from ferse underscore app poor use and then I will say you are all pattern's
is equal to and I will do another call to your el and now I'm going to do a very generic regular expression
so I will just say for basically anything there.
And I will call you start.
Now let's just go ahead and call the index right now.
Later on we'll test to make sure things are working by creating a new view and then I will say name
is index and we can have a comma here so we can have this on three lines.
Then I will just say that now let's make sure this actually all worked.
I'm going to say Python helps manage that pi and then run the server.
You have to make sure you're in the correct they're accurate do this.
I'm going that initial first underscore project folder.
I'll enter run my server lets make sure everything works OK.
So we have our server running.
Let's copy and paste this and we'll copy that and dragline over my Chrome browser.
Let me bring that into frame.
Here it is.
Great.
So that's what we actually had before.
Now what I want to check to make sure it works is say slash or forward slash first underscore app and
then hit enter.
And you notice it's working we still get.
Hello world.
And just to prove that this isn't a coincidence or anything let's do something that we haven't defined
forward slash new page hit enter and you will get a 404.
This page has not been found.
So clearly what we've done is working.
We're able to actually direct some extension of our domain into the or else stop pie of the application.
And this is basically what we're trying to get at as an overall idea that I can have the application
itself host its own neural patterns that I can then call from the Urals Alstom project or you are also
up high in the first project folder.
So again here I'm going to use this include functionality and then passen as a string.
My application name dot your else and this we can actually call whatever you want.
So for instance let's say something like this my new extension and then I will save files save this.
And let's go ahead and make sure this updated.
I believe it updated right now.
Let me just control C and restart it just to make sure everything worked correctly and then let's bring
back in that browser.
OK so bringing this browser again.
Now let's go ahead and say first underscore app enter.
Great.
That's not working.
So now let's actually try and this new extension just made.
So I can say my new extension enter.
And we can see it's calling.
Hello world.
So all of these basically are calling the same thing.
So the main index page that home page is just the domain name is calling the exact same view of the
my new extension page which we can do just for simplicity call first app.
So it is a nice idea to try to get these regular expressions to match re-application application name
that way it's easier to reference you know get lost.
It will always happen but it's a good idea to try to make things at least in your own mind readable
so when you come back to them later things make sense to you.
But all right that's all I really wanted to show you for this particular lecture.
And again the main idea here is that the applications can have their own URLs that PI file that we can
then call from the projects your patterns list.
All right.
Hope you enjoy that.
And I will see at the next lecture.