Hello everyone and welcome to the model forums exercise lecture and this lecture we will work with the
pro to project folder from Gengel level 2.
So if you still have that around you can just download the notes and grab that pro to project folder.
Remember from Gengel level to that final project was to have that user that HTL file use template tagging.
This playlist of all the users and their first thing is their last name and the e-mail information.
So we had that for loop inside that template tagging and then we displayed all that information directly
from the model.
We're going to change this to be a sign up page and it's going to be connected to a model form that
we previously discussed so that the user goes to slash users signs up on the user page and once they
hit submit that information goes the model and the user gets taken back to the home page.
A great exercise would be to try this on your own first.
So operationally you can attempt these exercise steps before viewing the rest of the lecture as an attempt
to try this on your own.
And these are the steps you're going to have to follow.
You'll need to create a model form and forms that pi will have to connect the form in the template then
you'll need to edit views that pie to show the form and work with the form in case there's a post and
you'll figure out how to save that data.
That's something we didn't talk about in the previous lecture.
So as an exercise you have to look up in the documentation how to save the data and the way I wrote
SAVE here is a really big hints on how to do it off the form.
Once you figured that out then just verify that the model is Adam unregistered registered.
So once you hit submit you can log in as an administrator and see that the data is actually there.
Inside the model OK.
So again I highly encourage you to try it out on your own and you're going to need to look at the documentation
or to do that successfully.
If that's not really your speed and you don't feel that comfortable doing it yet feel free to just continue
watching this and code along with me.
All right let's get started.
All right.
Here I am at the editor and right now I have my Pro two project inside a folder called Gengel level
3 and it has the app too.
That was the second application we made.
We take a look at the templates we have this index page HTML page and then we have the users.
Remember this was the template tagging we used earlier to actually display all these information directly
from the models.
And we're going to be replacing all of this with an actual form that connects directly to the models.
So as a quick note the Pentagon when you actually downloaded this you may not have the models registered
on your abdomen up file.
So make sure other app to added up pie for this Pro-Tools that you have these two lines here app to
that model import user and Adam that site register user member we need to register our models in order
to see them when we log in as an administrator.
All right let's start off with the front end actually.
And then we'll come back to it later on as well.
But here on the index page we'll say Welcome go to users too and we'll say sign up and I'm actually
going to add in Bootstrap.
So this looks a little nicer.
And I copied and pasted the link from Bootstrap dot com or get bootstrapped dot com.
You can do the same.
So I'll put that on the index page and also put it on the user's page in the next section of the course
we'll actually learn how we can use one single basic template and then keep inheriting from the same
template.
So you don't have to keep writing so much H-2 him but for right now we'll have the same link in both
of these files in this user's page.
This one is going to say please sign up here.
And I'm going to clear the rest of this since we won't be using it for now.
Everything else that's in the body.
And just to make this look a little nicer we'll put it inside of a container class and then we'll grab
this and put that in here and then on the index page that home page will put all of this into a container
class as well.
And in fact let's put it all into a Jumbotron just so it looks a little more home page.
And grab this stuff and we'll put it in here.
All right.
Looking good.
And we'll come back to users that each time and do some additional stuff in here of the actual forum
later on.
But let's come to the forums excuse me app to folder where we need to make a Forms up high file.
So say you file forms that PI enter and we should have the forms that PI file to here.
Now what we need to do is import forms as we did last time.
So I'll say from Gengel import forms and then we also need to import our actual models so we can say
from Daut but I prefer actually naming it.
So I'll say from app 2 even though we're in the directory don't need to actually say that.
I just say from DOT will say from app to that model's import and then the actual name of the models
we intend to use.
This case is just user and now it's time to create that class.
And in this case we will call this something like new user it will say forms dots and then we call model
form instead of just normal form so typically before we were just using form but if I actually want
this to connect to a model and edit that data off the top model form and then we also have that in-line
class which is going to be this Medich class.
And if you want to do your own custom validations then you would define a field tier something like
whatever they're actually called first name equals blah blah.
The forms the character field and then eventually you would add in your validator.
But right now we're not going to do any of that.
We already covered head to custom validations if you want to do that.
That's fine if you don't that's also fine.
Alycia class Metta L.M. create the model attribute this should always be called Model and then you assign
it to whatever model this form happens to linked to this case is just one form here.
User if we had another model to import that would have its own class with its own form model or own
model form I should say and then we have the fields attribute and we talked about the fields attribute
in the previous lecture and the various ways to handle it.
Since we're going to be using all the fields we'll just use that special keyword underscore underscore
all underscore underscore as a string.
And as a quick note for this meta you can either just do meddle like this or have the open closed princes
for Python 3.
That doesn't matter.
It's basically the same thing.
And now that we have that ready to go let's go to our views that pi file and make sure that it's connected
to the form properly and that it's going to do something if the user actually hit submit.
So we'll come to views that pie and right now we just have our previous users that was returning information
from the model.
But instead we're going to be returning information directly from that form.
So we'll delete that.
Right now the index view that's totally fine will keep the same home page return the index or C.M. but
for users we're going to do something a little different.
First thing you have to do is actually make sure the form is working which means we need to import it.
So previously we were importing the model direct directly.
We won't be using that since we're not actually grabbing information from the model to post we're just
going to grab stuff from the form.
So I'll say from in his case app to dot and it's the forms import.
And we're going to import the new user in just to make it really clear.
Let's actually call it muties or form that we we don't get confused so we'll come back to forms up PI
and let's call this new user form.
Save that and then interviews we'll call this new user form.
That's a little clearer to me.
Just so I don't get anything messed up and then we're also not using HTP response anymore.
That was one of the most basic things we learned about.
So we'll comment that out.
So we just have the render and user form that we're going to be working on this.
And let me grab some space here by collapsing the directory tree and also collapsing the terminal will
bring them back in a little bit.
But the first thing I want to do is create a object or a variable here called form and assign it to
an instance of that new user form so create an instance of that needs reform inside the user's view
here and then we'll say this if the input request method is equal to a post then we're going to reassign
form to equal to an instance of new user form except passen request form or actually request that post
and then we'll scroll down get a little more focus on this one function here.
So OK so basically saying is right now our form is an instance of that form class we just made it the
request method is equal to post meaning someone hit submit on that form is sending information back.
We pasand the request up post and then we check if it's valid or not.
And as we discussed before you can have your own custom validation checks but we'll just do the automatic
ones.
So the form is valid.
Meaning essentially they didn't mess anything up when hitting the summit.
And so an email was an e-mail etc..
Then here's the thing we didn't cover in order to save the form.
You can say form that save as the method.
Now we can also do it or it's committed to the database.
Is it commit is equal to true.
So we'll save that.
So we have if form is valid form that save it's true.
And then after this what we're going to end up doing is returning
and we'll return the index page so we'll return the index view and then pasand the request.
So this basically means if someone says Post mean they give back information and it's valid we will
save that form using the Save method off of it and then we're going to return the index view of the
request which it will just return the render request of the home page.
This will basically take you back to the home page.
Now what if they actually don't do anything.
So we can say have an else statement here let's say the form isn't valid.
We can just say.
Else.
And there's a lot of things you could do.
Like Rayson Eric cetera right now we'll just prints error form invalid.
We will actually end up experiencing this because we're not going to have an invalid form anywhere and
then outside of all this we need to actually return something so that it matches the actual page.
So say the users and on the very first level of indentation inside of this view function are going to
return and we'll say render request and then pass in wherever our users pages it's under app to and
let's make sure that the folders matches so under templates we see app too.
So that's actually capitalized although as a string passing it I don't believe it makes a difference
but we can always just check on that.
So two member templates app to index I smelled the ghost templates app too and we send back whatever
pages and it was called users.
Each team L.M..
Then finally we want to send back that context dictionary that actually contains the form and it's very
common.
Just to give it the key form and then pass in that form object which is this guy.
All right.
So we will save that.
Now let's go back to users that it's T.M. and fix this up so it contains the form.
So the first thing we need to do is actually create that form tag.
We don't need to really worry about action right now because we're kind of handling that ourselves.
Now the age T.M. and we don't need to assign it a class if you want to add more styling to it you can
do that.
We definitely say methods Posto and either lowercase or uppercase works.
I like putting in uppercase just so it's very clear to me what's happening.
And then we're going to do is use that template tagging and we'll pass form.
Technically that's all you need to do but in order to get those nice line breaks we can say as underscore
P..
So that way each actual thing each actual widget form is a paragraph tag.
And then remember this is something beginners often forget is that C S are f tag or token I should say.
So we have C S R F underscore tokin and we need that in order to make sure the form is secure.
And just so it runs period.
And then finally we need the input so the input style is going to be or the type will be submit.
We don't need to give it a name but we can't do is give it a class just since we have bootstrap here.
Make it look a little nicer.
So we'll give it to class between and then between primary and then finally the value whatever the buttons
actually going to show can be submit.
All right.
So hopefully we've taken care of everything.
We have our users ASTM all ready to go.
Index looks good as well.
Jumbotron or else already matched up from the previous iteration of this projects we have users calling
app to that your Els and your Elle's up high here.
Looking good.
Users not users.
And then we have our actual views.
This is probably the hardest part of all this and it's returning back that dictionary which we're calling
in the users of HTL over here with form.
So let's actually test this out and see if it all worked.
We're going to see the end to go to and then when I'm going to do a same Python managed up high and
then will say run server if depending on how far you got in the previous Gengel level to Pro 2 folder
you need to actually run the migrations if you went along with me throughout the entire course and we're
coding along correctly then you shouldn't need to make those migrations but keep that in mind.
You may need to make the migrations north to have everything be connected.
I should already have everything connected.
So it's actually run the server.
Let's make sure we don't get an error out.
So that's a good sign no error.
Let's copy this.
Actually we don't need to copy x and have it here or else I'll just refresh.
OK so far so good.
It says Welcome to users to sign up.
So let's do that.
We'll go to slash users enter.
And now we get this please sign up here.
Also looking pretty good.
Let's make a really obvious first name so I'll say I'm new first or the first name that we when I look
into this page as an administrator I can easily know that actually worked correctly.
Last name I can say my last name and then email will say it works at whatever yahoo dot com we'll hit
submit.
And perfect.
It took us back to the home page just like we thought it would.
Now we can see that it also sent a post.
So that's looking pretty good right now.
Now let's go to the Admin site and make sure it all works.
So go slash admin.
And if you don't remember your username or password from Django level.
Feel free to just use Python managed up high create super user number that command all you have does
provide your username and email and type in your password twice.
So hopefully I remember my password it was just test passwords something very simple and I use it and
was able log in see if that works.
Ok looks like I did not remember my password so I don't remember this.
So let's actually create a new one.
You probably are in the same boat as me.
So we'll say Python managed up high create super user and then lets it Jose.
Email address hello at gmail dot com doesn't really matter.
And then the password just doesn't matter.
We'll say test password test password and now is try this again.
It will say Python managed the high run server we're going to refresh actual admin page and let's try
this again.
So Jose and then as password log in perfect.
And now if I expand this I can see here I have two users.
And as I mentioned a few times users may not be the best name because under authentication authorization
you already have users but it's up to you.
He doesn't mind.
Right now everything is so simple and small.
Shouldn't be much of a difference.
So we'll click on users over here and we see we have a bunch of user objects.
So if you ran the population script you'll also have a much easier objects.
The most recent one should be the one at the top which is the one we just entered so as click on it
and here it is I'm new first my last name.
It worked at Yahoo dot com.
Perfect.
So now we can do whatever we want with this as a super user but basically we just showed that the user
can input information and then we can access it in our models which connects to a database and that's
the basic premise of using a model form.
All right I hope you now really see the power in your mind the gears are working here and you can essentially
realize that you now have the power to start making almost any website you want to make.
You have the ability to gather information from the user save it and you also know how to return it
back to the user.
I'll be you know in very simple fashions but eventually the rest is just styling.
OK.
Hope you enjoyed the lecture and we'll see you at the next section of the course.
Thanks everybody.