Hello everyone and welcome to Part 3 O.P. Project Object Oriented Programming is fundamental to becoming
a good Python programmer.
And we're going to be using it so much in Jingo that it's great to get some extra practice by building
a game will use object oriented programming to create the card game known as war.
It's a very simple card game.
The relevant file for this lecture is Part 3 O.P. project up PI and there's also a solution's file.
Don't check the solutions file yet and leave attend to the project.
Feel free to either treat this as a COTA long project where you just go straight to the solutions lecture
and actually code along with me.
But I do recommend that you attempt that on your own.
First let's take a quick look at the actual project file which has some extra code to help you out.
If you attempt to do this on your own I'll jump to my editor now.
OK so here you have three opii project up-I file open and when you open this file you'll notice that
there's a bunch of commented code.
These are just the rules of the game war.
If you haven't played war don't really know what it's about.
You can read this to actually understand the rules or you can actually read the wikipedia link to war.
The card game but the basic rules are very simple and the way we're going to do it for this project
is you playing versus the computer.
What's going to happen is you have a deck of cards.
It gets split in half and half of its face down to you half of it is face down to the computer and you
and the computer will flip one card face up at the same time.
Whoever has the higher card wins both of those cards and that's the basic premise of war.
But there is a special event that happens when both cards they pull face up happen to be equal to each
other in rank.
If that's the case then you and the computer pull out an extra three cards and then you pull out another
card to actually compare to each other and then whoever wins that wins the war and then wins all those
cards.
So that would be all 10 cards.
OK so then we want to scroll down here and we can see that I've imported some useful things for you
so I've created already from random import shuffle and then we have two lists here that are really useful
for creating cards.
They're just lists that are created by splitting a string based on the whitespace so you can play around
those you don't have to use them but they're there just to help you out.
Now we have the deck class.
The hand class the player class and then some game play.
So what you're going to be doing is the following.
You're going to be using this deck class and this object will create a deck of cards to initiate play
and you can then use this deck list of cards to split in half and give to the players.
It will also be able to use these two lists here to create the deck.
It should also have a method for splitting and cutting the deck in half and shuffling deck.
We also have the hand class and each player has a hand and they can add or remove cards from the hand
and there should be an add or remove card method within this class that we have the player class and
that takes in a name and an instance of a hand class object and the player can then play cards and check
that they still have cards.
And in Filey over here we'll have game play again.
You don't actually have to use these three specific classes but you do have to use at least one class
and use object oriented programming in some way.
But this is just skeleton code here.
Just some scaffolding free to fill out if you want to follow along with the solutions.
OK best of luck and coming up next is the solution lecture where we will be coding along.
Any example solution.
Thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.