Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture will show you how to create edits from the list you as I mentioned.
You can also add the ability to edit attribute values from the list view.
Instead of having to click into that detail view and again this is an easy attribute addition.
Let's quickly show you how to hop over to the editor.
OK so here I am an admin that pi the attribute need to add to this is called List underscore editable
equals and then you just add in the list of the attributes or fields that you want to be able to edit
from that list view.
Now keep in mind those attributes are fields that you can edit.
Also have to be displayed.
Otherwise it won't make sense.
You need to display something so you can edit it.
So I'm going to go ahead and say let's edit the link.
And then I will save this and then bring back my actual browser so bringing in my browser and this is
what it looks like right now.
Let me refresh this and you'll notice now in my list view I can edit the changes so maybe I can make
this 100 minutes here and then save that and can see the changes and you can even see the filter affected
those changes as well.
So this makes it really easy to do both changes or bulk additions from the list view instead of having
to click in to the actual detail view based off some sort of field.
So again this hopefully makes your life a lot easier.
Now as a quick note you should be cautious with this approach because if you intend the multiple people
to have access to the admin page and have access to this list view you may cause problems.
If they're trying to edit the same attribute or same field at the same time.
Basically whoever clicked Save last ends up having the final say so keep that in mind that you kind
of play around with this again.
The attribute is if we can come back here is just list underscore editable and you have to remember
that needs to be under display as well.
OK thanks everyone and I'll see at the next lecture.