Hello everyone and welcome back to part six form selections in this lecture we're going to continue
exploring the variety of input methods for each time forms.
And those are going to be things such as a single radio button how to link multiple radio buttons dropdown
menus and then text area inputs.
Coming up next after this lecture will be an assessment exercise so we can fully understand everything
it has to do with him all forms and that will end our H-2 him all sections of the course.
But before you reach the next assessment let's get some quick practice with these various input methods.
All right.
So here I have a normal age team I'll file open and it's linked to my browser just called forms.
H Tim L.
And you can see here I've set the tile to hotel feedback so we now know enough HVM that we can try to
mimic more of a real world situation.
For instance let's say you've stayed in a hotel afterwards that may send you an email to a link asking
for some feedback.
So we're going to try to mimic what that feedback page would look like and to do this let's just start
with a heading that says something like hotel feedback form.
Save this refresh over here.
Looks like it's linked correctly.
Great.
Now let's start with our form.
And if you just auto create form you'll have class action method etc..
Right now we don't really need that.
If you want you can set method to just be get right now as I mentioned earlier we're going to be covering
what and post is much more in the future.
Right now you can just leave it as you see here.
First thing I want to do is understand how radio buttons work.
So for instance do you just type an input and and type instead of text you pass in radio.
You can save this refresh and you see a little radio button pop up here and if I click it I can see
it it got filled in.
Right now if I try to click it again nothing changes I can't click it on and off it's just clicking
once.
So let's try to expand on this concept by actually asking a question here.
So in a header or heading 3 I'm going to say this.
Are you from inside the US or outside the US so may we have international travelers and we want to know
do they come from the United States or outside the United States if this hotel is in the United States
or somewhere internationally and then we'll have an input as a radio button and we will label this radio
button and let's review how we can label using that for method.
So I can say something like for
us and then give this particular radio button an ID of an let's say in USA.
So let's save that in this label.
I'm going to say something like inside say that refresh and he see are you from inside the US or outside
the US in the right now I can just highlight the only option available inside and I can only highlight
it on a can't change anything about it.
So let's make another one we'll make another label we'll call this for how USA now we will call this
outside and then create another and put we'll make another radio button type and give it the ID to match
that label which in our case is out USA.
We will save this refresh and now we see we have a hotel feedback form.
We have two options inside or outside.
Right now we have a little bit of a problem.
I can actually highlight inside highlight outside and that's it that's all I can do right now.
What I would really like to do is to link these two radio buttons together so that if I click inside
than outside cannot be selected or if I click outside then inside cannot be selected so I want to be
able to turn these on and off in respect to each other and the way you do that is you give them the
same name and that's where this name comes into play.
So let's give this first radio button a name Alosi for location.
And let's give the second one the same name Alosi.
Now let's save this refresh.
And we notice if I click inside it's highlighted by click outside inside becomes highlighted so we can
see now that they're linked because they share the same name and that makes sense because given what
we know about names and the assignment we'll have to assign something to that name.
In this case we can only assign one of these to either be inside or outside.
And that's how you link radio buttons together you just give them the same name.
They can have different labels but if you want to link them together you just give them the same name.
All right let's start exploring another type of input here.
And this one is going to be let's say Well asks How was your service.
So how was your service.
Save that.
Make sure it worked.
All right.
How was your service and let's actually make this better to instead of just the paragraphs that kind
of matches along with the other one.
And let's make this other one too.
So it's not so big a head or two over here as well each to save that refresh over here.
So are you.
From inside us outside that's linked together.
How was your service for the service.
Well we're going to do is explore a dropdown menu and the way dropdown menu works is not with the input
tag but with the select tag and the select.
It works like this.
You say select you can give it a class right now.
That doesn't make sense for us because we haven't learned about C Ss So we'll come back to that later
and we can give it a name.
So let's give this the name stars.
So we want a drop down menu of how many stars and what we can do is give an option and then this option
has a value.
So let's give a value of great and in-between these option tags is going to be in actual numbers so
we'll say three.
Let's save this and see what this looks like so far.
So here we have the dropdown three in so far.
That's it.
So let's create a couple of more options for the stropped on menu and then we can break down what value
is so going to make another value that just says OK.
That's too and then let's make one more option and we will say this is bad.
And it was one star.
So now if I save this I have my select which in the case a dropdown menu.
I've given a name to my select and I have various options here with what happens in between the option
tags is what's actually displayed to the user.
But behind the scenes they can have their own values.
So let's refresh this.
And now that we say how is your service I see the dropdown gives me three two or one that I can choose
from.
So let's add a submit button to this so we can see what happens when it hit submit.
So outside of this but inside the form I'm going to create a submit button and give it a value called
submit.
Save that and refresh and let's pay attention to what happens to the url after I hit submit.
All Sam from inside the U.S. and my service was too.
So now that I've clicked submit we see here in the URL I have ellos is equal to.
And right now it's actually blank.
And then it says.
And stars is equal to.
OK.
So what I want to do is back in these radio Open's actually fill in a value here that corresponds to
the radio button.
So I will set the value for inside or the inside radio button and set the value here for outside.
Let's save this and refresh and let's actually delete these values here.
Go back to the forums page refresh this.
And now let's try again.
We'll say Hotel feedback form.
Are you from inside.
We'll say we're from inside.
How's the service.
We'll give it one star and notice here.
Now I have corresponding values in both the dropdown menu and the radio buttons.
So if I click Submit now I can see here the your L that my ellos see the name is equal to the value
inside.
Since I chose inside and stars is equal to the value here.
Bad.
And that's a really nice way that you can have your own value names on your back ends but show something
else on the front end.
So notice that the front end here is wishing for the dropdown menu was three to one but on the back
and I had these set values great Ok bad well might be more realistic is if you actually set values on
two numerical values three to one.
And then here the options are great.
OK bad.
And then you can maybe take mathematical averages.
Behind the scenes that we can learn a lot more about back and stuff later on this course hopefully you
get an idea now of what's possible.
Finally I want to add one more type of input that we want to check out.
And that's the text area.
So I'm going to put a paragraph here and we'll have a question that says something like.
Any other feedback you want to give as a paragraph.
Let's actually make that a head or two.
Way it's the same size everything else.
And we so far have learned about the text input.
In fact it's the default.
So if I click save here refresh I see any other feedback.
But usually you don't want the user to just type everything in one single line.
You want an actual box text area.
So the way we can do that is instead of text where you can say text area and that actually creates its
own text area tag.
So I will delete this
and say text area.
We can give that a name so we can just use the default here or we can say my text and you give it a
number of rows and a number of columns you want it to expands.
So let's save this now refresh and see here.
Now I have my text area so hello this is my text area.
And now we have multiple lines so we can start typing stuff in.
And we're going to learn more about text areas right now because it's a little different than taking
in a single value because you have whole blocks of text.
But I just want you to be aware they have a text area here at your disposal.
All right so that's it for the various types of inputs we wanted to cover here under form selections.
Let's do a quick review.
Let me expand this.
We've covered how to do radio buttons remember that just input and the type is radio.
And if you want to link radio buttons together you make sure the group of radio buttons just has the
same name and you can assign values to them so that when you click submit you can get those values back
then for a dropdown menu.
Use the select tag with options and you can then again assign values and the values don't have to match
up what the user actually sees as their dropdown options.
And then finally we learned about the text area which allows you to basically make a block for a text
area.
And if we come back here to the browser you can see that we can actually kind of play around with this
a little bit.
As far as how far down it can go.
And then finally we have the submit button that we've covered before.
All right.
Coming up next is an assessment exercise so you can get a lot of practice if everything you've covered
in the section.
Of course.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next lecture.