Hello everyone and welcome back in this lecture you have a challenge and it's a jingle template challenge.
Templates is a big leap forward for us.
So it's a good time to quickly get some practice using them and we're going to be using your older pro
to project they you created for the previous Shingo challenge.
If you don't have that project anymore.
Just quickly recreate it using the creating project commands and accreting application commands that
we've learned in previous lectures.
Once you have that set up you want to go ahead and complete the following tasks.
Create a template character and connect it to the settings that py file of that new second project.
Then create a new view called help and use.
You are all mapping to render it for any page with the extension slash help.
So again you're going to go to your second project folder create that second new application create
a new view.
So the function within that views that py file and use that you are all mapping that we've learned to
actually create a rendering for any page of the extension slash help.
And then I want you to use template tags to return help page.
So in the templates directory that you made create a new folder and within that folder there should
be something like help that H T.M. and then that should have template and template tags that basically
returns help page.
So just get everything connected so that it's clear that you understand how to use templates to connect
to a view and actually inject code into the template HTL.
All right.
Best of luck with that and the next lecture.
We will briefly code through the solution.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you there.