Hello everyone and welcome to part six exercise review.
You've learned about the basic data types and data structures in Python and now it's time to put your
new skills to the test.
The part 6 underscore exercise underscore review that py file has commented tasks for you to complete.
So let's go ahead and take a quick look at it.
You can find this file under the python level one folder.
It's just five simple problems.
So let's take a quick look.
OK.
This is what the file looks like.
Part 6.
Exercise review and problem one just says this given the string S is equal to jingo.
You want to use indexing to print out the following.
The D O.
D.
Jan just Jan and then just go.
So again you string indexing to print out the as 1 2 3 4 or 5 different portions of the string and then
as a bonus question you can use indexing to reverse the string.
You may want to review the notes because we didn't actually show that in the lecture video OK.
Problem number two given this nested list right here this is l equals 3:7.
Then there's a nested list inside of it.
I want you to reassign hello to B.
Goodbye problem 3.
Using keys and indexing grab Hello from the following dictionaries.
So here we have three simple dictionaries we can see as they go wrong.
They get more and more nested.
So what you need to do is grab Hello from D-1 dictionary one D2 dictionary to and then D-3.
And remember there's also lists and D-3.
So you have dictionaries inside of a list inside of a dictionary inside of a list etc..
This one is quite tricky so take your time with D-3 see if you can work.
Layer by layer problem.
Float for.
Says to use a set to find the unique values of the list below.
Hopefully you're able to do that we kind of just did that in the last lecture so maybe review that.
If you're stuck on problem for and then problem 5 It says you're given two variables.
Age is equal to this integer for name as equal to Samie.
I want you to use print formatting to print the following string.
Hello my dog's name is Sammy and he is four years old.
So again review the format method of what's known as string interpellation or putting these two as strings
inside of this string.
Ok thanks everyone and I will see at the next lecture where we're going to be going over the solutions.