Hello everyone and welcome to the template filter's coding example lecture and this lecture we're going
to be walking you through the basics of using an actual template filter and also how you can create
your own template filters if you ever feel you have the need to Gengel makes all of this really easy.
So let's hop right back to the editor and get started.
All right so all the work the learning underscore templates project that we've been working through
the entire section of this course it's really easy.
All we're going to be doing is affecting the index that HTL page to actually inject the variables and
reform the template filters.
But in order to do that we need some sort of context dictionary to actually pass to this index for you.
So we'll come over to views that high under basic app and under index we're going to do is create a
basic context dictionary so say context dictionary.
Now we'll have a couple of keys in here.
We'll say some text and this will be hello world.
And then we'll also say number and this will be something like just make it 100 and we're going to pass
that as a contex dictionary here.
OK.
So save that and then to make sure it works on the index page.
Let's just inject those two variables themselves.
So remember the first one was just called text and then the second one was just called name.
Numbers are number Lemi mixture.
Number OK.
So we'll save that.
And let's actually run our server so Python Myners up higher on server and call it make sure to actually
there on that index page.
I'm going to copy this spring over my browser and bringing in my browser I can see it right here.
Hello world.
And 100.
This is actually quite small so let's enlarge it.
Bring that away and let's put this under H1 tag.
So I'm going to actually say welcome to index comment that outs and make an H1 tag that this will go
into.
So we'll put the text in and each one that way we can just clearly see and don't have to awkwardly zoom
in that far.
Copy that paste that in.
Save this and refreshing my page and oh I see.
Welcome to index.
Hello World 100.
OK.
So what does a typical filter actually look like.
Well the majority of them actually usually don't take parameters or additional arguments.
They're usually based off of some sort of Python method that you would call on that basic data type.
So if you ever think Oh man there's a python method I would like to do on the string.
Definitely look up the filter reference.
At least the built in ones.
It's almost 100 percent sure to actually be there already implemented for you.
So let's do that with Hello world.
The text.
Let's say I wanted to uppercase all the text.
Well you could use the upper parentheses on a python string and it's really no different over here you
just say text the pipe operator and then pass in the name of whatever the filter using is.
And in this case it's upper and usually syntax wise they're both going to be touching that pipe OPERATOR
So you will see it like that without any space OK.
So let's save that and bring in our page refreshed so refresh the page coming in.
Now I can see Hello world.
It's all in uppercase now.
Same number it's also a very simple process.
Let's show you an example of one that would have an additional argument for instance one of the most
simple ones is just adding a number so we can say number the pipe operator ad is the name of that actual
filter then we say colon and in a string you can pass in whatever you want to add.
So in this case let's add the number ninety nine to it just to make it really obvious.
So we'll save that refresh our page and bring it back in.
And here if I bring it back in I can see it's 1 9 9 after the refresh.
OK.
Now let's talk about how you can create your own custom filters.
Usually you'll be able to find your own fill of the built in filters to be more than enough and sometimes
you will even be doing a lot of this logic on the back and then some other Python script.
But let's say you really need to do it with a template and you need your own filter.
Well it's absolutely no problem.
Django can certainly handle that.
So you need to do is create a function that will work with that filter.
In order to set this all up we have to follow a convention as far as where to actually place our custom
template filters and what you end up doing is inside your application.
At the same level of models and views since you are you going to do is underneath the application you'll
create a new folder or new directory and you will call it template tags.
And then inside of this you're going to make sure it creates a new file and you will call it underscore
underscore in its underscore underscore that pi and that file is just going to be totally empty.
Basically what this file says is it tells Python to treat this as a module.
That way it can call it and load it in what you're going to be doing usually is creating a new file
and then this is where you're going to actually put in your custom templates so we can say something
like
my underscore extras that pie and I'll show you how you can actually create your own filters and you
can always reference the documentation.
Just look up Django custom template tags and this would all be in there so you end up doing is first
you need to actually register all of this.
So you will say from Django import.
And that's going to be template.
And then you create an object called register.
You said it equal to template dot and it's a library.
And actually this should be capital.
There we go.
So register equals template library.
And then what you're going to do is write a function that will be your custom template filter.
So we can say the F and let's follow the one that's in the documentation example such as cut.
And this is the one that takes in an actual value so that's whatever the variable or value from your
context dictionary going to pass and then any additional argument.
So we'll just call that Arg and we'll say what this function does.
So it is good to give it a docstring will say This cuts out all values of arg.
From the string and then what we're going to do is we'll say return and we'll grab that value.
We're going to assume it's a string.
Again you're going have to be careful with your kind of assumptions here.
And then we'll say arg and then that.
So basically you can call the replace method off a python string and then pass in what you're looking
for and then what you want to replace it with.
This is a really common Python string operation.
So we're just kind of putting this whole thing and wrapping it into this nice little custom filter called
cut.
And then what we need to do is register this.
So what we do is over here we can say register dot filter and I pass in as a string what I actually
want to call this filter.
So when I call it in my custom filter template tag we'll just call it cut and then you have to actually
pass in the function itself.
You just create it which in this case is also cut.
So the first one is going to be the string that you call the function when you use the template tag.
The second one is the function itself.
So it's not a string just a direct call to this function.
OK.
So that's the very basics and kind of in the order that you're thinking of.
So from Gengel import template register then you create whatever custom template filter.
And then here it is.
So let's actually try this out.
Now it's coming back to our index.
Let each team page instead of saying text upper.
We're going to do is this will say text and then we're going to say cuts and then let's cut out the
term.
Hello.
So I will save this and let's bring back in our project over here.
And if I refresh this no it cut off.
Hello.
So that was our own custom filter cut and it cuts out anything that would place as a parameter.
And that's the very basics of how you can create your own custom filter.
Now as a quick note there is another way to register the filter itself.
So if we come back here under a template tagged in it and then my extras we registered using this register
equals template library.
That is one way to do it but you can also do it with decorator's and it looks a little cleaner.
So remember back when we were introducing decorators in the Python level 2 section of the course I mentioned
that later on in Django I would talk about decorator's and then advise you to go back.
So this is that time.
If you haven't learned about decorator's yet now's the time to go to the decorator's lecture.
Go through it.
It's a little complicated but it'll make a lot more sense when you actually see it here.
So I'm going to comment this out this register that filter since I'm passing in essentially what is
a function into another function call.
I will do this.
We can say at register that filter and then give it the name equal to cut
save this and now we're going to do to make sure this all worked.
It's come back to index and instead of cutting a flow and going to cut world save that as well and then
bring in an actual browser refresh this.
And here we see just hello.
So world got cut out and that's how you can use decorator's to actually registered these custom filters.
And this looks kind of a lot nicer and a lot clearer especially if you already know decorator's.
All right.
So that's it for templates.
There's still a lot more you can explore in the documentation but this should be enough for you to create
basically any normal Web site that you want to work with.
Thanks everyone and I'll see you at the next section of the course.