Hello everyone and welcome back and this lecture will be coding through the solutions for the jingle
templates challenge.
Let's quickly review what we had to do.
We want to create templates directory and connected to settings that py file.
So we'll tackle that first.
Then we want to create a new view called Help and used you are all mapping to render it for any page.
The extension slash help.
And then we wanted to add template tags to return something like Help page.
OK let's jump to the Adam text editor and accomplish all these tasks.
OK here I am at the Adam text editor to start off let's create that templates directory so I can just
right click on to add a new folder called templates and then hit enter and then inside of this I'm going
to do a subdirectory for my application.
This case will just use app too.
You could have also created a new application for this.
Whatever made more sense to you.
Well let's call this app too.
Again I would have been surprised that something like help and created a new directory an application
called help but right now we have templates an app to create it.
Now let's go to our approach to our project to setting's file and sync up this templates directory to
our actual settings.
Remember we use the convenient import os command to actually do this.
So I will create something that looks like this will say template directory and I will say oh estopped
path dot join and I will join my base directory.
With templates great.
And then I have to scroll down.
To my actual list pass installed apps past middleware and then here in templates this list has a dictionary
inside of it and under diers for their victories.
I want to just say templates underscore the IIR and then save this.
All right.
Great.
Now let's continue on the next thing we want to do is sync up and map the or else and in order to do
this we have to do a couple of things.
First off I want to do what we've done in the previous mappings you are Elle's lecture where we actually
have each application have its own or else that py file.
So all right click on app to create a new file and I will call it your Else.
Net goes inside app 2 which is inside project to and then hear what I will do is the following.
I'll say from jingo dash dash you or else import your L and then I will also say from app to import
views and we haven't actually created the help yet but we will in just a second.
And then finally we'll have our own your moral patterns list here and inside of this list I'm going
to call the oral function that we just imported and then pass on something that looks like this will
put some regular expression here.
And then I will say views da.
And in this case we've previously done indexed but I wanted to create a new view called Help haven't
done it yet but I will so we'll call views that help there and I will give it the name.
And then let's save that.
And now let's go to our actual Urals dot PI file of project 2 and connect this you URLs to this your
URLs.
So we'll scroll down and here we have the usual patterns for the entire project.
So let's connect this to our actual you or else PI that's inside of our application.
And in order to do this remember we need to import the include function.
So I will say from again Jingo that QOF thought your else that could have actually put this up here.
So there's no need to really write this twice but I just want to make it really clear what we're doing
all put and include.
And again I could have just done something like comma include here.
The same thing.
But just to make it clear I'm going to put it in as a new line.
Save that and then we have our index page admin.
Well let's add something else here.
We'll say you are el and using regular expressions.
I'm going to say Chevron or carot now say help.
And then I will say include I will call up to you or else college finished that list and save that and
then a couple of things you have to still do is actually create that view and then create the HTL that
we call for that view.
So coming back to use an app too right now I have this index for you.
Let's create a new one called help and it will take in a request and then there's something we still
need to add to this which is actual use of that render.
So I'm going to make a dictionary will call this help dictionary or really whatever you want to call
it.
And then create a dictionary and we'll call this help.
Inserts.
And as the value for that key we'll just say help page just to make it really clear.
And then I'm going to return the render function taking in that request realizing that it goes with
app too and will say help that HMO.
So what that's actually calling is over here this template that we're about to create and then the context
of this that we actually inject using the template tagging is going to be this help dictionary
ok.
Save that.
And then finally last step is to actually create that CML file so will say new file.
And this will be help.
H HVM l enter.
I'll say h tim L here title will say something like help page.
And then finally let's actually insert using template tags so healthy right now you realize the most
basic template tags is just the double brackets double curly brackets on each side and then we want
to actually insert the dictionary that we created that context and something to keep in mind that we're
not actually inserting the dictionary but the key of that dictionary.
So if we go back to our page here under views we want to import this help insert.
So sometimes a common mistake to accidently put in helped dictionary.
But you should really have any in this variable rate here.
Help answer.
So I will copy that and come back to help here and paste that.
All right so that was a lot of steps.
Let's hopefully make sure it all worked out.
I'm going to say here on their project too.
Python managed up-I run server enter and if we did everything right we should be able to copy this your
L and paste it into our browser.
Let me bring that browser over.
And here we have our browser it says my second project that makes sense that's the index page that is
set up previously.
But now let's test this out and write.
Help.
And you know we get the help page so it takes in the template tag that we inserted and it looks it up
and we can see also help page here.
That's the title that we insert it here.
So just to clarify this help page appear on the top.
That's from the title.
This Help Pages HVM l text is coming in from that template tagging of help underscore insert.
All right if you were having trouble with this than I really suggest that you take the time to review
the previous lectures on template tagging and setting that up and try another shot at this exercise.
This is definitely a big leap forward and it's really important that you have this foundation of connecting
the templates and the views together.
Coming up next we're going to learn how to connect this two models to your actual database.
All right.
Hope you enjoyed that little challenge and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.