Hello everyone, and welcome to
the comparison operators lecture.
In this lecture we'll be learning
about comparison operators in Python.
So, these operators are gonna allow us
to compare variables and output a Boolean value.
We've already seen a few of them throughout the course,
but now we're really gonna dig deeper.
And if you have any sort of background in math
these operators should be pretty straight forward.
If I look at the Jupyter notebook
that corresponds to this lecture,
I have a table of comparison operators,
and then a couple of examples for most of them.
So let's go ahead and zoom in, into this table,
and just tackle them one by one.
The very first one, operator, is two equal signs in a row.
And what that means is if the values of the two operands,
whatever the two objects you are comparing,
are equal, then the condition is true.
So in this case, a equal equal b is not true.
But, if a equal equal a was written,
then that would be true.
So as long as these two objects are the same,
then equals equals will output true.
If they're not same, it'll output false.
Moving along, the opposite of that is
exclamation mark equals.
So, that means if they're not equal,
then the condition becomes true.
So this statement basically says
a is not equal to b, which will output true.
Another way to write this is with
a less than and a greater than sign back to back,
so that's the same as this operator right here,
but in most cases I would encourage you
to use exclamation equals mark,
that's what most people use.
Okay, then as far as greater than
or less than or equal to et cetera.
So for this symbol right here,
this means greater than, so, a greater than b.
Similarly you have less than, so a less than b.
And depending on which the values,
so for instance numerical values,
you can see is two greater than one?
That will equal true.
Is three greater than ten?
That will be false, et cetera.
And then if you wanna do greater than or equal to
or less than or equal to,
you just add an equals sign to those symbols.
Okay, so let's go ahead and see these guys in action
by jumping over to the live code.
Alright, so, comparison operators.
Let's go ahead and dive in.
So, remember we have the equals operator
and we can go ahead and play with that.
So I'm gonna say two equal equals two, is that true?
Yes it is.
So one equals equals one, is that true?
What about one equals equals zero?
Well, that's false.
Okay, so now let's go ahead and practise with not equal.
So switching to not equal.
Remember that was exclamation mark equals.
So, is two not equal to one?
That's true.
Is two not equal to two?
That should be false.
Remember we have the other way of saying it,
which isn't as common but we can still use it,
which is the less than and greater than sign
put back to back.
So, is two not equal to one? That's true.
Is two not equal to two?
That's true, excuse me, that's false.
Two does equal two.
Like I mentioned the more common way
is with the exclamation mark equals sign.
So, moving along, we're gonna now go with greater than.
And that's just gonna be two is greater than one.
That's true.
Is two greater than four? That's false.
And similarly, we have less than.
So I can say two less than four
and two less than one.
That's false.
And then we have greater than or equal to.
So I can say is two greater than or equal to two?
Yes, 'cause two is equal to two.
Is two greater than or equal to one?
That's also true 'cause it's greater than one.
And I can also do less than or equal to.
So is two less than or equal to two?
Yup.
Is two less than or equal to ten?
Yes, it's less than that.
So that all works out.
Okay, so, hopefully that should
have been pretty straight forward.
If you have any sort of math background or basic math,
this greater than or less than sort of operations
should just pretty much make sense.
If you have any trouble with it,
you can always go back to this Jupyter notebook
and read the table in more detail,
in case you need any refreshers
on what these comparison operators do.
Alright, so, that's it for this lecture
and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Thank you.