Hello everyone, and welcome to the while loops lecture.
What we're gonna be learning about in this lecture
is how to use the while statement in Python
and it gonna be, it's actually
one of the most general ways to perform iteration.
And what happens is the while statement
will repeatedly execute a single statement
or a group of statements until a true value occurs.
So you can see here, if we zoom in,
that the general format for a while loop
is you have while, then some sort of test condition
and then as long as that test condition is still being met,
then you have whatever code is executed.
And then if you want, you can have an else
to have have a final code statement.
What we're gonna be doing throughout this lecture
is just going through some of these examples.
So you can see here I have the Jupyter Notebook open
and we're gonna be going through these examples
and then we're also going to be learning about the terms
break, continue and pass.
Then we're gonna be working
through some more examples there.
Okay, great.
Let's go ahead and check it out.
We're gonna hop over to the Jupyter Notebook.
Now we're at the Jupyter Notebook for the while loops
and let's go ahead a look at
a few simple while loops in action.
I'm gonna say, make a variable called x = 0.
And then you'll notice the formatting looks pretty similar
to a for loop except we have a while statement.
And I'm gonna say while, notice the syntax highlighting,
x is less than 10
and here we can say, do some code.
So if I just said right now,
print
'hello!',
and clicked enter here, this loop would go on forever
'cause nothing is affecting x
and x will always be less than 10 as long as x is 0.
So I'm not gonna actually run that.
What I'm gonna do is say,
I'm gonna say, print
x is
currently,
space, and then
I'm going to print the value of x.
And then what I'm gonna say is,
I'm gonna add 1 to x
for every instance in that loop.
So let's go ahead and see what happens.
If you notice, while x was less than 10,
I said, okay, print this statement, x is currently,
and then we printed x.
And then the next step was x, add a 1 to it.
So after that it became 1.
And then, was this statement still true?
Yes.
At 1, is still less than 10.
So this while loop basically keeps performing
until the condition is met.
And in this case once x was greater than or equal to 10
or basically no longer less than 10,
this loop stopped.
Okay.
So hopefully that should be pretty clear.
And notice how many times the print statements occurred
and how the while loop kept going
until that true condition was met
which occurred once that x equals 10.
So you can see, it actually stops at that 9
because once you had 10 there, none of this code executed.
So it's important to note that that occurred
and the code stopped.
So let's go ahead and see how we could have added
an else statement to this.
So I'm gonna make another cell here.
I'm gonna say, x = 0.
And I'm gonna say while,
let's go ahead and just zoom in one more.
I'm gonna say while,
x is less than 10,
print x is
currently,
comma, x
and then I'm gonna say go ahead and add that 1 to it
and I'm gonna have an else statement
so this is gonna occur after
the while statement condition is met.
I'm gonna say print,
All Done!
So let's go ahead and run that cell and see what happens.
So you'll notice we have x = 0
and after I met that condition on that while loop,
I did my else statement.
I printed all is done, or all done.
Okay, great.
So hopefully this is pretty straight forward to you.
Basically what we have is this while condition
and the while loop will just keep running
until the condition is met.
All right.
So now we're gonna learn about break, continue and pass.
So that's gonna be the words,
break, continue
and pass.
Break.
Continue.
Pass.
All right.
So let's go ahead and hop over to the notebook
so we can explore it a little further.
We can use break, continue and pass statements in our loops
to add additional functionality for various cases.
These three statements are defined by,
first off, break.
So what happens is, break, if you put that in your loop,
it's gonna break out of the current closest enclosing loop.
What continue is gonna do, if you type that in,
it's gonna go the the top of the closest enclosing loop.
And then pass does nothing at all.
So when we're thinking about break and continue statements,
the general format's gonna look
a little something like this.
You can have a while test condition and then some code
and you can say, maybe, if another test condition, break.
Or if another test condition, continue
and then you have an else.
So you'll notice the break and continue statements
can appear anywhere inside the loop's body
but we we'll usually put the further nested in conjunction
with and if statement to perform an action
based on some sort of test condition.
So to explain all that, we're gonna go ahead
and explore some more examples.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So, again, we're gonna start with that same example
we've been working at.
I'm gonna say x = 0
and then I'm gonna say, while,
x is less than 10,
print
x is
currently, space,
comma, x.
And then I'm going to,
I'm gonna add another print statement.
I'm gonna say,
x is
still less
than 10,
adding 1 to x.
And then I'm gonna do it, I'm gonna add 1 to x.
So notice what's going on here.
I'm saying while x is less than 10, print the current x
and then also print a statement that verifies
or just tells you, x is still less than 10,
I'm adding one to x, and then I go ahead and add one to x.
And now what I'm gonna do is add an if statement here.
And what this if statement's gonna do is it's gonna say,
if x
is equal to 3,
go ahead and print some sort of alert.
So I'm gonna say, hey,
x
equals 3!
And then I'm gonna go backspace to come back
and line it up with that if
and then I'm gonna say else,
print
continuing
...
And I'm gonna say continue.
Okay, so let's go ahead and break this down,
what's going on in this cell.
I'm saying while x is less than 10, print this statement
which is gonna print out your current x.
Then I'm gonna say print, x is still less than 10
then I'm gonna add 1 to x right here.
And then I'm saying, okay, now if at that point in time,
is x is equal to 3, print this statement.
Else, if it's any other number that's not 3,
go ahead and print continuing....,
and then we continue on with this outside loop.
Okay, let's go ahead and run that and see what happens.
So let's take a look at the output.
I print out x is currently the number,
x is still less than 10, adding 1, and then continuing.
And if you notice, hey, x is currently 2,
x is still less than 10, adding 1 to x
and at that point in time, I've added 1 to x
so it's gonna say, hey, x equals 3!
So you get that little alert there.
And it's gonna say, hey, x is currently 3.
It's still less than 10, I'm adding one,
at that point it's four so it's going to
go ahead and continue going.
All right, so you're gonna have to note
how we have that printed statement,
when x is equal to 3, and then the continue being printed
as we continue through that outer while loop.
So let's go ahead and put a break once x is equal to 3
so we can get a sense of how break works.
I'm gonna go ahead and go back here
and I'm gonna say, okay, put in a break statement.
And remember, what the break statement does
is it's gonna break that code for the outer loop.
So now I'm gonna run this cell.
And if you notice, once that statement's true,
so hey, x is equal to 3, print this, and then break.
So it stops the outer loop that it's nested in.
And then you have the hey, equals 3
and it doesn't continue going because of that break.
So, note how the other else statement wasn't reached
and continuing
afterwards was never printed.
So these are pretty brief examples
but hopefully you have a comfortable understanding
of this while statement, how to read and write it.
Okay, I want to make a quick word of caution.
If you have something that is always true,
you can run into danger of having infinitely running loops.
So if I were to say something like, while True,
print,
let's say, infinite.
And I'm not gonna actually run this cell
'cause if I ran this cell, I would just get
an infinite print statements.
And if you notice here in this Jupyter Notebook,
you'll notice it's actually a super long Notebook
because I've run
a quick sample of, Uh Oh infinite Loop!
by always having that true.
Okay, make sure you do not do that in your code.
Always, before you implement a while statement,
make sure that there's at least some sort of break statement
that you'll hit or you're affecting the test condition
where you won't have
an infinite loop occur.
So, that's actually it for this lesson on while loops.
Just to reiterate, the general format of a while loop,
you have a while, some sort of test condition
and then your code statement.
And then you can have an else, for when you finish
that while loop, you can have final code statements.
So we went through a quick example using 10
and we kept adding to it.
And then the next example we had an else statement.
And then after that example we learned about
break, continue and pass.
So a quick reminder, break is going to
break out of the current closest enclosing loop.
Continue is going to go to the top
of the closest enclosing loop.
And then pass does nothing at all.
All right, so we'll be revisiting while loops
and then break and continue statements
as we go on throughout the course.
So don't worry, we'll be covering this more and more
as we get more and more complicated programmes
throughout the course.
Okay, so that's it for the while loop.
I will see you at the next lecture.