Hello everyone,
and welcome to the comprehensions lecture.
So we've already seen some sequence operations
and list methods in Python,
but Python also includes this more advanced operation
called a list comprehension.
It's super useful but it's one of those things
that sometimes beginners have a hard time
being able to read.
So, what list comprehensions allow us to do
is build out lists using a slightly different notation.
So you can think of this as essentially
a one line for loop that's built inside of brackets.
So we're gonna go ahead here,
I have the Jupyter notebook open,
we're gonna go ahead and work through several examples
so we can make sure we understand what's going on.
So the first thing I'm gonna do
is do a building out of a list, basically,
an old fashioned way using for loops,
the way we know how to already do.
So I'm gonna create a list
and I'm gonna make an empty list that's just brackets.
And then I'm also gonna create, I'm gonna say,
for letter in word,
and I'm just gonna pass in that string, word,
take my list and append that letter to it.
And then I'm gonna say, outside of the for loop,
at the end of that, print L, that list.
So what's gonna go on here,
I'm gonna build my empty list out,
I'm gonna go through every element in the sequence
that is a string, so that's gonna be every letter there.
And I'm gonna append that letter to the list.
So let's go ahead and see what happens there.
Okay, so I've built out that list,
and it's basically every element
is one of the letters in that string.
So, now I'm gonna show you how to build this out
using list comprehension.
So list comprehension, the format is,
you basically kind of flatten out this for loop
within a list, so, or at least within the brackets.
And I'm gonna say letter for letter in word.
And that's it, that's the syntax for list comprehension.
So, you begin with what you actually want
the list to consist of.
So I want the list to consist of the letters.
So for letter for letter in word.
And that's it, you don't have to worry
about the sort of append structure,
because you're in a list comprehension.
It knows that it wants the letters there
based on what you've put in.
So now if I check what L is equal to, it's the same.
And let me go ahead and just make a new object called lst,
so we really make sure that it's
the list comprehension that's doing it,
and there you have it.
So it's the basic idea of list comprehension
that you're kind of flattening out that for loop.
So, if you're familiar with mathematical notation,
this might kind of feel familiar.
So sometimes in mathematics, just to type,
let's say something out, so I'm gonna change this
to a markdown cell to show you what I mean.
Sometimes in mathematics we have this kind of notation
where you say, like, X squared colon X in,
and then you have some sort of set of numbers.
So maybe you've taken some more advanced math classes
and this sort of notation makes sense to you.
So that's basically what you're doing in list comprehension.
Where this colon stands for for.
And you're gonna say something like,
X squared for X, and then, in some sort of iterable,
so that could have been a range, like that.
So let's go ahead and actually build out that example
that we just talked about.
So I'm gonna square numbers in range,
and then turn it into a list.
So I'm gonna say lst is equal to brackets,
I'm going to take an X,
and square it for X in range
zero up to but not including 11.
So what's going on here, I'm going to take every X
in this range, and I'm going to square it,
and that will be the result of my list.
So that's list comprehension.
And also, quick note, we could have done X range here,
since we're using Python Two,
that's gonna be the same thing.
Okay, so again let's just break down what's happening here,
and something that's a little confusing
when it comes to list comprehensions,
sometimes you feel like you have to know already
the results, so when you're writing a normal for loop,
you kinda start more on this end first.
And then, put in whatever object or output you want.
And in list comprehensions you actually start
with the output you want, and then define
how you're gonna get it through some sort of for loop.
Okay.
So in this example we're saying,
take my X, square it for X in range blah blah blah,
zero to 11, and then we have brackets there.
Okay.
So, let's go ahead and do another example
that checks for even numbers in a range.
And now we're gonna basically introduce
an if statement in our list comprehension.
So, let's go ahead and make an example
that checks for even numbers in a range.
So I want a number, I'll just type it out, number,
and I want that, I want even numbers from zero to 10.
So I'm gonna say give me the number for number in range,
and I'm going to want up to but not including 11,
remember default for range starting is zero,
and since I only want the even numbers,
I'm gonna write an if statement here.
I'm gonna say, number for number in range,
if, that number, remember we can check for evens
using the modulo, modulo two, is equal to zero.
So if I run that, now I have a list of even numbers
from zero to 10.
So let's go ahead and quickly
break down what's going on here.
I'm saying, number for number in that range,
keep that number and build out the list
if that number, when it's modded,
modulo two, is equal to zero.
And let's go ahead and deconstruct this list comprehension
to make sure we really understand it
by building out a for loop of it.
So the way I would do this in a for loop,
I would say list, build out an empty list,
and then say for number in range,
11, if number, mod two, is equal to zero,
append it to my list.
Append that number.
And now the list you'll see is the same thing.
So the reason list comprehension is so popular in Python
is that once you get used to list comprehension syntax,
this kind of thing becomes a lot cleaner
and more Pythonistic than this for loop.
Now it's kind of debatable what is easier to read.
Frankly a lot of times, depending on how complicated
list comprehension can get,
I actually still find this kind of for loop easier to read.
But sometimes it's more efficient
and just cleaner looking syntax
to have everything a singular list comprehension.
And as you start getting more and more comfortable
with list comprehensions you'll find yourself
using them more and more.
Alright, so now we're gonna do a more complicated example.
So we're gonna make an example
that converts Celsius to Fahrenheit.
So I'm gonna start with a list called Celsius,
and it's just gonna contain some temperatures
that I'm making up that are in Celsius.
So zero degrees Celsius, 10,
let's put in some floating point numbers,
and let's say 34.5.
Okay, so I have my list of Celsius temperatures.
And now I'm gonna use list comprehension
to convert those into Fahrenheit.
So I'm gonna create a list called Fahrenheit,
and create my brackets for the list comprehension,
and let's build out what we actually want to do.
So, temp for temp in Celsius.
So what's that gonna output?
Well, that should output basically a duplicate list
of the Celsius, right, if I just grab
every temperature there, that's the same as Celsius,
woops, misspelt it, Celsius.
Okay, so right now, Fahrenheit should look exactly the same.
Okay, so what do we want to do with this temperature?
So if you look up the conversion equation,
what I actually want to do is,
take temperature,
I want to divide it by five, actually wait.
I want to take the temperature
and multiply it by nine divided by five.
And I'm gonna go ahead and put 5.0
so we don't have any floating point errors
since I'm working in Python Two.
And then, I'm gonna add 32 to that number.
And I'm gonna go ahead and wrap that in parentheses
to make sure there's no order of operations error.
Okay, so let's go ahead and see if that works.
And there you have it, and you can quickly check,
hopefully if you're familiar
with both Celsius and Fahrenheit, you know that zero degrees
is the same as 32 degrees in Fahrenheit,
so you can see that this matches up.
So let's go ahead and break down again real quick
what we just did.
I'm saying, take my temperature, multiply it by some factor,
add 32 for it, and do that for every temperature in Celsius,
and then because this statement is in brackets,
it's a list comprehension and it's gonna build out
a list for you.
Okay, great.
Now moving on to a more complicated example.
We're going to perform a nested list comprehension.
And as you start nesting list comprehensions
it might get more and more debatable
how useful and how clean it is,
but it's important that you're able to at least
be aware of them and read them.
So what we're gonna do, is, make one list comprehension,
I'm gonna say, let's go ahead and do
that squared comprehension we were talking about earlier.
In range 11.
Okay, so, now my list is every number squared.
But I can actually nest that list comprehension.
So, that's already a list,
kind of the same way Celsius was a list earlier.
And now I can do something for every item in that list,
so let's go ahead and square it again,
so I'm gonna say, X squared for X in,
and since I have a list here,
Python's gonna treat that list comprehension we just made
as an already completed list,
since it's nested inside this list comprehension.
And now I should get every number to the power of four.
Great.
And you can see that worked out.
So, you could keep nesting and nesting list comprehensions,
but just be careful and make sure
that you yourself can always go back and read them.
And as always you can use just comments,
so I could say, here, final result is X four from range,
let's say for num in range 11,
so if I came back to this later I would understand
what's actually going on.
Okay, so later on in this course
we'll actually learn about something
called generator comprehensions,
and I know I've slowly been sneaking in previews
and dropping hints about generators,
but after this lecture you should at least
feel comfortable reading and writing
pretty basic list comprehensions.
So let's go ahead and hop back to the Jupyter notebook
and just make sure we got everything.
So remember, list comprehensions,
they're basically like deconstructed for loops
that are flattened out within brackets.
And you can do list comprehensions
on any iterable or anything you can do a for loop for.
So if you find yourself making a for loop
that's just building out a list,
keep in mind that maybe a list comprehension
is a cleaner way of doing it.
Okay, and again, all these examples
are in the Jupyter notebook,
so you can go ahead and feel free to explore them later,
and we'll be using list comprehensions
later on in some projects down the road.
Okay, thanks everyone.