Hello everyone,
and welcome to your first coding lecture!
So in this lecture, we're going to be learning
about numbers and more in Python.
And we're gonna cover the different types of numbers
that we can use in Python,
some basic arithmetic using those numbers in Python.
We'll also learn about some differences
between Python 2 and 3 when it comes to division,
and we'll get a quick peek at object assignment in Python.
So here I have open the Jupyter or IPython notebook.
So you can scroll through this notebook, check it out
if you wanna go in a little slower at your own pace.
There's tonnes of information here.
And we'll be going over all this in this lecture video.
Okay, great.
So let's just get a quick presentation
on the two types of numbers we're gonna be working with,
which are integers and floating point numbers.
So, I'll do a quick break to the presentation.
Okay, here we are at the presentation now.
There's a lot of different types of numbers in Python,
and we're going to focus on two types right now,
integers and floating point numbers.
So, integers are just whole numbers, positive or negative.
So for example two and negative two
are just examples of integers.
And floating point numbers is the other number type
we're going to be concerned with right now.
So floating point numbers have a decimal point in them
or they can use an exponential e to define the number.
So for example, 2.0 or two point zero there
and negative 2.1 are examples of floating point numbers.
Also, 4E2, either capital E or lowercase e
is an example of a floating point number in Python.
And all that means is four times 10 to the power of two.
We'll mainly focus
on those 2.0s and 2.1 type of floating point numbers,
the one with decimal points in the.
Okay, so let's go ahead and hop back to the code.
Okay, and we're back to the Jupyter notebook,
and now I'm going to hop over to our live code session.
All right, so here, I'm just going to be going over
the code that we do in the notebook.
So let's go ahead and check out
how to do some basic arithmetic in Python.
Here, I have my cell, and for addition,
all you do is you type the number in
and put in a plus sign so two plus one,
remember, Shift + Enter to run your cells,
and there you go.
That's how you can do addition.
So, for example, two plus two, again, just four.
All right, subtraction.
It's also pretty simple, just a simple dash sign there.
And we can do another example.
And three minus two.
So right now, when we're first looking into Python,
we can go ahead and think of Python as just a calculator.
So multiplication, the symbol for that used in Python
is an asterisk, so there you have two times two
or three times two is six, et cetera.
Okay, so here's where we have to kind of keep
close attention as we go into division.
And the reason I say that we have to pay close attention
is because of the following.
So let's say I wanted to do three divided by two.
So, what would you expect three divided by two to be?
Probably 1.5, right?
So if you notice, I'm using Python 2 right now.
You can see up here in the right here corner.
And the output is one.
So why did this happen?
And if you hop over to the Jupyter notebook,
you'll notice you get a Python 3 alert here.
So what's going on?
So the reason we're getting this result
is because of Python 2.
In Python 2 and Python 3, you perform division
using this forward slash symbol for division.
But the difference is in Python 2,
this symbol performs what's known as classic division,
and that means that the decimal points are truncated off.
So 1.5 gets truncated to one.
In Python 3, however, this single forward slash for division
performs what's known as true division,
so you would get a 1.5 if you had inputted
three divided by two using Python 3.
So, what do we do if we're using Python 2
and we want to avoid this kind of floating point error?
So there's different methods.
One method is that you can specify
one of the numbers to be that floating point number.
So I can say 3.0 divided by two,
and then you'll notice we get out 1.5, the expected result.
And that can work for either number.
So three divided by 2.0, the difference being
just one of 'em has to be defined as a float.
Some other things you can do in Python 2
is also cast one of the numbers to be a float.
And what casting does is it uses a function
that basically turns integers into floats.
So, what that would look like,
and we haven't learned about functions yet,
but we'll get a quick sneak peek,
is you can call float like this on one of those numbers.
So it's float, parenthesis, three, parenthesis,
divided by two, and what that's basically doing
is casting that integer three as a float.
So if I check what's going on there by itself,
I get 3.0.
Okay, so there's one other thing that we could possibly do,
and again, this is just kind of a sneak preview,
because we haven't gone over functions or modules yet,
but a really interesting module
that Python 2 has is called __future__,
and it'll actually allow you to import
some capabilities from Python 3 into Python 2.
And we'll go over what this is actually doing
and how it's working later on in some lectures,
but with this line,
division, let's see.
So right now I've written down from, space,
underscore, underscore, future, underscore, underscore,
space, import division.
If I go ahead and run that line,
what's that done is it's imported division
from this future module, and what that basically does
is now it treats division as if it were using Python 3.
So you notice I can just say three divided by two,
and now that's corrected to 1.5.
So, let me just reiterate
the three different things we can do here.
You can make sure one of the numbers is a float,
or you can actually cast
one of the numbers to be a float to make that happen,
or you can run this line, from __future__ import division,
and that will take care
of the rest of the divisions you do throughout Python 2.
So, my suggestion is running this line.
We'll learn later on in lectures about modules
and what this is actually doing and how this is working,
but right now you can just kind of treat it
as this magic line.
So if you're ever going to be dealing with division
a lot in your code, you wanna go ahead
and put this at the top if you're using Python 2.
Okay.
So moving onto some more arithmetic,
how about we check out powers.
So for instance, two to the power of three.
So the way you do that is by doing double asterisks.
So two, asterisk, asterisk, the power of three is eight.
I can say four to the power of, let's say, five.
That's 1024.
And we can also, if we wanna do roots that way.
So I could say like the square root of four
is the same of four to the power of one-half,
in this case, 0.5,
and that's the same as the square root of four.
You can also do square roots by importing the math function
or importing the math module, excuse me,
but we'll look at that later on in the course.
Okay.
So, moving along,
we can also learn about order of operations
that are followed in Python.
So your standard order of operations are followed.
So what I mean by that is if I say
two plus 20 times 20 plus three,
order of operations indicates
that multiplication has to occur first before addition.
So this 10 times 10 is gonna happen
before the two and three get added.
So Python's not gonna follow this reading left to right.
It's actually going to follow order of operations.
And I can see that occur due to the 105 result we get there.
Okay, so what if I want to specify some orders?
I can use parentheses, just as if you were writing
a math equation in perhaps like a TI-83 calculator.
So, if I wanted that two plus 10 to occur first,
I can use parentheses to specify my custom orders there.
Okay.
So, that's the basic arithmetic, just a quick overview.
Addition is just a plus sign.
Subtraction, just that dash, that minus.
Multiplication is the asterisk symbol.
Division, forward slash.
Careful to note that if you're using Python 2,
you're not going to perform true division;
you're going to perform classic division,
unless one of 'em's a float or you use this
from __future__ import division line.
Okay.
And if you're interested in some more details on that,
you can go ahead and read this Python 3 alert
in a little more detail in that Jupyter notebook.
All right, so moving along,
I'm just going to give you a really quick introduction
to assigning labels to objects to create variables.
So what I mean by that is I can use a single equals sign
to assign labels to objects.
So to show you an example of this
is I can say a is equal to five.
Sorry about that.
And so now, I've set a label, a,
as a reference to that number five.
So if I call a in my script again, anywhere,
Python's gonna great it as if it was the number five.
And I can also add those objects together,
so I can say, for example,
variable a+a, and it's gonna treat it
as if it was five plus five.
So an interesting thing that we note
in Python is what happens if we reassign this label.
So what happens if I say now a equals 10.
So Python lets it write over.
So now if I reference a, it's 10 now.
So you can write over those assigned labels
on those variables, and we'll go in,
on the next lecture, into a little more detail,
in case you're jumping in from another language
on how Python actually deals with these labels.
But for the basics right now, you can just treat it
as you choose your variable name, an equals sign,
and then whatever object you wanna label that.
Okay, and you can also use the variable label itself
to reassign the variable.
So what I mean by that is I can say a equals a+a,
and what Python will do is now it will say, okay,
so a is now equal to a plus a.
So what was a originally?
It was right now 10.
So a is now going to be equal to 10+10.
So if we check that out, there we have 20.
Okay, great.
So you might be thinking, okay,
so what are the rules on creating these variable names?
And there's a couple rules that they have to follow
so I'll jump over here
to the Jupyter notebook where I have 'em all.
Okay, so these names, they cannot start with a number.
There can also be no spaces in the name.
If you want to specify some spaces,
probably use an underscore instead.
It can't use any of these symbols right here.
All of these symbols are forbidden,
and it's usually considered best practise
that the names are lowercase.
So let's go ahead and go over a super simple example
of how we can use these labels and these variables
that we make to clean up our code a bit.
So these variable names help us keep better track
of what's going on in our code.
So to give you a small example,
I'm going to make a variable called my_income,
and I'm going to set it equal to the number of 100.
And then I'm gonna make another one called tax rate,
tax, underscore, rate, and I'll set that equal to 0.1.
Great.
And so now, finally, I'll say my_taxes that I have to pay
is going to be equal to my_income multiplied by my tax_rate.
Great.
And if I run that cell, now I define my_taxes
as my income times my tax_rate,
and if I call it to see what that value is, it's 10.
So 100 times .1, that 10% tax rate,
my taxes are $10.
Great.
So, what have we learned?
We've learned some of the basics of numbers in Python.
We've also learned how to do arithmetic
and use Python as a basic calculator.
And we wrapped it up with a quick introduction to variables
and how we can create them and label them in Python.
So next up, we're going to learn a little bit more
of how this variable creation and labelling works,
but go ahead and feel free to just mess around with Python.
I think one of the best ways to get a quick introduction
to Python is just treat it as a calculator,
and then with the introduction of variables and label names,
you'll slowly get more and more complex with your code.
But go ahead and mess around with different additions,
multiplications, powers, et cetera, divisions.
Make sure you really understand how to do
all those operations, because numbers is gonna be
one of the main building blocks we work off of in our code.
So keep in minute the difference
between integers and floating point numbers,
differences between Python 2 versus 3
when it comes to division,
and all the different arithmetic you can use Python for.
Okay, so that about sums up our lesson.
Remember, there's always more to read
in the Jupyter notebooks
if you wanna go into a little more detail over anything.
All right, guys.
Thanks, and I'll see you at the next lecture.