Hello everyone, in this lecture we're actually
just going to be going over the questions on the
Statements Assessment Test to just make sure
you understand everything.
So let's go ahead and get started.
So this first question here, I want you to use this,
these three different methods: for, split and if
to create a statement that will print out letters
that start with S, given this string.
Okay.
Next up, I want you to use range to print
all the even numbers from zero to 10.
After that, I want you to use list comprehension
to create a list of all numbers between one and 50
that are divisible by three.
Then, I want you to go through this string below,
and if the length of a word is even,
go ahead and print even.
Then, I want you to write a programme that prints the integers
from one to 100, but for multiples of three, I want you to
print fizz instead of the number.
And for multiples of five, print buzz.
For numbers which are multiples of both three and five,
print fizzbuzz.
Now this is a really common question,
and it's one of the first basically screening tests
for a lot of interviews just to make sure you actually
know syntax of a language.
So make sure you really understand that question.
After that last question, I just want you to use
list comprehension to create a list of the first letters
of every word in this string below.
Okay.
So, it's a pretty short assessment test
and the reason for that is we're going to be using
a lot of this knowledge as far as statements and assessment
or statements go throughout the course,
so you're going to be seeing this over and over again.
Okay, so best of luck and great job.