Hello everyone and welcome
to the functions and methods homework solutions lecture.
I'm just gonna quickly go over
the solutions that I came up with
for the functions and methods homework.
The first one, wanted you to write a function
that computes the volume of a sphere given its radius.
I just started out with def, called my function vol,
v-o-l, took in an argument, r-a-d, for the radius
and then returned, you'll note here the floating
point number since I'm using Python too.
Four divided by three, times 3.14,
so four thirds times pi times the radius cubed.
Then I wanted you to write a function
that checks whether a number is in a given range,
inclusive of high and low.
What I did here was I created a function, def space,
ran underscore check, takes in three arguments,
'num', 'low' and 'high'.
It checks if num is in range, low high,
so that would be a list.
If it's in that list, print
it's in the range, else print numbers outside the range.
Then if you only wanted to return a boolean,
what you could've done was def ran bool
and then just returned the boolean itself,
num in range.
After that, wanted you to write a Python function
that accepts a string and calculates the number
of upper case letters and lower case letters.
For example, had 'Hello Mr. Rogers,
how are you this fine Tuesday?'
and expected output was number of upper case characters,
number of lower case characters.
If you were feeling ambitious,
you could've explored the collections module
but the way I did this was I created a dictionary
with upper and lower
as my keys and then I said
for character, or for c in s,
so for character in the string,
if it's upper is true, so that's a method on a string,
add a count to that key.
If it was lower, add a count to a lower key,
else, if it was like a period or something,
just pass and then I printed out the results
of that dictionary.
Next I wanted you to write a Python function
that takes a list and returns a new list
with unique elements of the first list.
The way you can do this in this case
is start with an empty list in this function
then say, for a in l, if a is not in x,
if it's not in that unique list,
the one you're gonna output,
append it to a and then return x.
You can also use sets but we'll mention that later on.
Next I wanted you to write a Python function
to multiply all the numbers in a list.
You have a sample list, expected output.
What I did, I said total is equal to numbers, index zero,
so that very first item.
Then I said for x in numbers, total times x,
so total times total times x
and then return the total.
After that, I wanted you to write a Python function
that checks whether a passed string is a palindrome or not.
This is a quick way to do it.
You just check if the string is equal
to the string reversed through indexing.
Last one was a little harder.
Had to write a Python function
to check whether a string is a pangram or not.
I mentioned the string module.
What I did here was I used set to say
this alphaset is equal to the set of the alphabet
and then I wanted you to return
the alphaset, which was less than or equal to
the set of the first string, everything lower case.
Go ahead and read over that one,
make sure you fully understand it.
I know it's pretty tricky, but this boolean
is the main trick here as far as
this function's implementation.
Thanks, go ahead and review the Jupiter notebook,
and I will see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone!