Hello everyone and welcome
to the lambda expressions lecture.
So in this lecture we're going
to be learning about lambda expressions,
what they are, and how to use them.
So we're gonna start with a brief presentation
just describing lambda expressions purely in words,
and then we'll learn how to do it in the live code session.
So one of Pythons most useful tools,
and a lot of times it's really confusing for beginners,
is the lambda expression, and what lambda expressions
basically allow us to do is create anonymous functions
so just quickly make ad-hoc functions
where you don't want to spend the time
defining an entire function using a def statement.
So what is lambda?
Lambda's body is gonna be just a single one line expression,
it's not gonna be a block of statements,
and the lambda's body looks really similar
to what we put in a def body's return statement,
so you can simply type the results as an expression
instead of explicitly returning it.
And then because it's limited to just
like a one line expression, it's gonna be
less general than a def function.
So when are you gonna use lambda?
You can only squeeze design to limit programme nesting.
So the issue with lambda is that
it's designed for coding simple functions.
If you want a larger task to be done
you're gonna have to use def.
Okay, so the best way to learn
how to use lambda expressions is too slowly convert
a normal def function into a lambda expression.
So let's go ahead and hop over
to the code to see how that's done.
Okay, now we're at the lambda expressions
Jupyter notebook, and I have it open here
and this is basically what we're gonna all go through
and a couple of examples during this lecture.
So let's go ahead and get started
and what we're gonna do is go ahead and
jump to a live code session,
so I'm gonna make a really simple def function
using just normal syntax, I'm gonna say def space,
gonna name my function square,
it's gonna take a num as an argument,
it's going to set a variable called results,
square that number,
and then it's gonna return the results.
So that's my simple function, it's just squaring numbers.
So if I call it square two, it releases four.
Okay, so let's go ahead and continue
breaking this down and you'll see
that we're gonna slowly form it
into a lambda expression, so
how can I keep reducing this function.
If you notice, I'm returning results
and setting results as a variable
but I actually don't need to do that,
I could just return
this num to the power of two, right,
so I could just say return
num to the power of two,
and that's gonna be the same thing,
I don't need to save this variable
if I'm just gonna return it.
So let's go ahead and make sure that works.
So square of let's do four this time,
and we get out 16 so that makes sense.
Okay, so how can we put this all into one line?
So Python, I know we've been making
a big deal of white space for functions,
but I could actually write this in one line
in this fashion, def square num colon
return num to the power of two.
Now this is kind of bad styling, but it is
okay syntax-wise to do that,
although I wouldn't recommend doing that normally,
but we're doing that just to
slowly convert it into a one line lambda expression.
So again, let's go ahead and do square of three
and we get nine, so notice how
in this format it still works.
We have kind of this one line function.
So this kind of form is the form
that a lambda expression's gonna try to replicate.
So when you're using lambda expressions,
you're basically going to write
kind of a one line version of a function.
And the way we would convert this square function
into a lambda expression would look like this,
I would type lambda num colon
num to the power of two.
So the syntax is you write lambda,
you write what it's gonna take in,
and then you write colon and what you want
the output to look like.
So this is one of the most basic
versions of a lambda expression,
and notice how when I run that,
Python's gonna treat it as a function.
So I can actually get the function back
by assigning a label to it
and as we've gone over a little bit
throughout the course, we can actually
assign labels to functions.
So I can say square is equal to
that lambda expression.
Okay now if I call square, you'll notice
it works just as it did for the full function
and just to make sure that it's actually
taking its results from this lambda expression
let's go ahead and put square two,
put square two on ten, and notice
you get the exact same thing.
So that's the simplest breakdown
of a lambda expression, and I'm just gonna
go over it one more time.
You can think of a lambda expression
as basically kind of this one line
condensed version of a function
where you have lambda, what you're taking in
and then what you wanna do with it
separated by a colon.
Now usually you actually don't save
lambda expressions to a variable
since you want what's called a anonymous function
which means you never spend the time
to actually save it, you usually run it
within a context of your code
where you just need something to quickly perform
some sort of expression and then not worry about it later.
So let's go ahead and go through a couple more examples
and really drive this lambda syntax
into our heads, so I'm gonna say
let's make an example to check if a number
is even using lambda expressions.
So I would say lambda,
I wanna take in a number, num
and how do I check something is even,
remember if the mod is equal,
mod two is equal to zero, then you know it's even
so I'm gonna say num
mod two, equal to zero.
And there's my even function, or function
to return a boolean, right?
So I can set that equal to even,
that lambda expression
and now I can check if numbers are even.
So just like we did earlier,
where we converted a function into lambda expression,
let's work backwards now and convert
this lambda expression to a function
just to drive the point home.
So what does this lambda expression actually
trying to do that a function would?
Well, it would look something like this, right?
Even, take num, return
the boolean if num mod two
is equal to zero.
And that's gonna be the exact same thing
as that lambda expression.
So you notice now instead of writing
this entire syntax of death, we can just actually have
one line lambda expressions throughout our code
if we ever need just to do a quick function.
Okay, let's go through a couple more examples.
So let's say I wanted to make a function
that grabs the first character
of a string.
So what would that look like?
Well, I have lambda, I'm gonna take in some s,
some string, and I know the first character's
just gonna be zero index there, right?
So again, I have my function,
we can go ahead and save it if we want.
Let's give it a variable.
And now I'm gonna say first of hello
and you notice it returns that zero index.
Okay, so let's move along, let's see
how we could reverse the string.
We've seen this a couple times throughout the course,
but remember to reverse a string,
you take it in, that s
and then you can actually just
go through it backwards for indexing.
Hopefully you'll remember this from the indexing lecture.
There's our function, let's go ahead
and set it to a variable label called rev
and say rev hello.
And you'll notice it's reversed.
Okay, so moving on to a little more advanced
we can, just like a normal function,
accept more than one argument into a lambda expression.
So let's go ahead and see what that looks like.
Let's say I wanted to add two numbers
together as a function.
So let's say I made a function,
and this is just a normal def function
called adder, and it took x and y
and it returned the sum of them.
So if I say adder, I could say add,
let's say 10 and 12, we get 22 back.
So now let's breakdown this function
that takes in multiple arguments
and turn it into a lambda expression.
So I would say lambda,
I'm gonna take in two arguments,
and you'll notice I separate them by commas
just like I would in a normal function.
And then what do I wanna return,
I wanna return x plus y, and that's it.
And then I could, say, call this adder
and now if I call adder in my code
you'll notice I can say 30 30 and I get 60 out
so lambda expressions are really gonna shine
and be used a lot when they're used
in conjunction with three main functions,
map, filter, and reduce, and each
of those functions actually has its own lecture
so feel free to explore them if
you're more interested in lambda functions
but you'll be introduced to these three functions
specifically since they have a lecture each.
Okay, so, there's a really, really great blog post
that I highly recommend you read
after you go through this lesson and it's called,
it's at this site called Python Conquers The Universe
and it also has a great breakdown on lambda expressions
and some more explanations for common confusion
so if you click that link in the Jupyter notebook
it'll take you to this website right here,
Python Conquers The Universe,
and he says Yet Another Lambda Tutorial,
there's actually a tonne of tutorials
out there for lambda so you can
check out his own links as well,
but again, he goes over
basically the necessities of what lambda's good for
and right now you may not think
that you'll be using lambda a lot
instead of just writing a full def function
but you'll notice as you go throughout your code
and don't need an entire function,
you just need a quick expression,
lambda will come in super useful.
So as far as his blog post, he goes more into
why you should use lambda and more
of the theory behind lambda than actual coding,
but I think it's a great blog post
and I highly recommend you read it
after you go through this lesson
and understand how to build your own lambda expressions.
So let's go over quickly what we learned in this lecture.
So we learned about lambda expressions,
how they're pretty useful as anonymous functions,
and these ad-hoc expressions,
and we notice that they're made
of a single expressions, they're not
a block of statements like you usually would
for a full dev function.
So we have this def square function
and we slowly broke it down until we got
a lambda expression that served a similar purpose.
And then, our own lecture here in the live coding
we then created a lambda expression
and kinda did the reverse, broke it back into,
or built it back into a full function.
And then we went through a couple examples
of lambda expressions.
So just to reiterate, remember,
a lambda expression takes the form lambda,
some item or object, and then what you wanna do
to that item or object, so you could
maybe take the length of it.
And in context, usually you don't save,
let's call this length check,
you don't save a lambda expression to a
variable like this, you use it
in conjunction with map, filter, and reduce,
which I know doesn't make a lot of sense right now
since you're not familiar with these functions
but you'll see that when you're using
map, filter, and reduce,
you'll actually just end up passing
this lambda expression as the argument
instead of saving it to a variable.
So now we can do length check.
Let's say a string,
how many chars does this string have?
37, okay.
So go ahead and make sure you understand
at least how to read a lambda expression
and how to build out simple lambda expressions.
Don't worry too much about implementing
these into your actual code.
As you get more and more advanced in Python,
you'll suddenly feel like, hey, maybe I can
use a lambda expression here instead
of writing this full function.
Okay, so that's it for this lecture
on lambda expressions, hope you enjoyed it,
and hope you got something useful out of it
and I'll see you at the next lecture.
Okay, thanks everyone.