Hello everyone, and welcome to
the milestone project one complete solution walkthrough.
In this lecture, what we're going to be doing
is going through the entire walkthrough solution,
each of the steps, solving those functions.
So we're going to be going through each major function.
Try to solve and create the function on your own first,
but let's go ahead and jump,
and get started to the Jupyter notebook,
and see what's going on.
Okay, so here we are at the
milestone project one walkthrough steps workbook.
What I've done is I've downloaded this Jupyter notebook
to my local computer so we can actually go along,
go through each of these steps, fill out the functions,
and make sure we match up correctly
with the solutions notebook.
So if you want to follow along
with the actual coding that I'm doing,
you can go to the other notebook,
which is Milestone Project One:
Full Walkthrough Code Solution.
And this is basically what we're going to be doing,
I'm going to be typing this out
and explaining the logic along the way.
Let's go ahead and get started.
So again, if you want to follow along here,
what you should be doing is you should have downloaded
this notebook, Milestone Project One:
Walkthrough Steps Workbook,
and be following me working through it.
And before we do each step, I'm going to really stress
that you should pause the video
and really try to solve this on you own.
It's going to be really helpful
if you give it a fair shot at solving on your own.
Okay, with that being said,
first thing we're going to say is
from underscore underscore future import the print_function.
I'm just doing that so I can always use the print function,
so for example I can do something like this.
"Hello" Instead of using the print statement,
which would have looked like that.
That's just to make sure whether people are using
Python two or three, all the code matches up.
So if you're using Python two, like I am right now,
go ahead and put this line here.
If you're just using Python three,
you don't have to worry about this line,
you can just use the print function naturally.
One other note, that I want to make sure you guys realise,
is Python two users, you'll notice throughout some
of the functions we're going to be
asking for input from the player,
Python two users should use
"raw_input" to get the player input.
Python three users should just use "input".
We'll go over that later on,
when we actually use those functions.
Alright, so what's our first step?
First step is to write a function
that can print out a board.
We're going to set up our board as a list,
where each index, one through nine,
corresponds with a number on a number pad.
So you get a three by three board representation.
Here, what I've done is said
"from Ipython.display import clear_output."
That just allows us to clear the output.
So I'll show you an example of that.
If I say print "hello,"
I get "hello" here.
Let me go ahead and run this, so I've imported clear_output.
So I just ran the cell, but now I'm going to say
"clear_output", no other arguments, close the parentheses,
and you'll notice it will basically print "hello,"
and then clear the output so you don't get anything out.
And if I add another print statement after that,
like "world", then I just get "world" out,
because it printed "hello," it cleared the output,
and then printed "world."
It happened so fast that you only end up
seeing "world" at the end, but I just wanted to clarify
that's what clear_output is doing.
That's for Jupyter Notebook, you may need to use
another output, or clearing of output,
if you're using a different IDE or development environment.
This is what you have to do for Jupyter Notebook.
Say "from Ipython.display import clear_output"
Okay, you can go ahead and google search
for your particular developer environment
what you should do to clear the output.
So first thing we're going to do is
write a function that can print out the board
and set up our board as a list
where each index, as I mentioned of course,
corresponds to a number on the number pad.
First thing I'm going to do is say "clear_output".
That way every time I call "display_board",
all the previous output is cleared,
and then I can actually print out the board.
Alright, so here again I'm going to stress that you
pause the video and really try to think
how can you display this board?
Alright, now lets go ahead and continue.
Hopefully you've had a good shot at this now,
but when I say print board, all you have to do is,
let's go ahead and practise printing an empty board.
So an empty board might look something like this.
If I say, just a string that looks something like this,
then right below it I'll print, maybe another string,
that looks something like this.
Maybe it has a couple more dashes there.
But this is basically all this step
was trying to make you do.
Just print out a board right now.
And then later on we're gunna, in just a second,
we're going to add what we would need to add
to take in a board and print it out.
But let's go ahead and just practise this.
If I call "display_board", lets see, and pass in a board,
in this case, I'm just going to pass in an empty list,
you notice we get a very simple board.
And we're actually missing a couple lines here,
but we'll get to that in a second.
What we're going to do now, is go ahead and assume
that our board is a list that looks something like this.
The board is going to be a list from zero to ten,
and its going to have corresponding strings.
So, we'll ignore the zero index, so don't worry about that,
but it's going to look something like this.
Where each of these indexes
matches up with some sort of position.
So if I do something like this,
blah blah blah, all the way on,
what we're going to do is have a board
that looks something like that.
So I'm going to go ahead and
there's a lot of print statements here,
so I'm going to copy them from the solution notebook,
which you can do as well,
and then I'm just going to go ahead and call this,
and explain what it looks like.
I'm going to go ahead and make a board,
going to say it's 'X', so we're just going to have all 'X's,
and lets multiply this by ten.
And say "display_board", call in the board.
Let's go ahead and see what that looks like.
Alright, so now we have a board full of 'X's.
And I can edit this list so that I have zeros in there too,
or "O"s I should say,
so I can do something like 'X', 'X', then let's have,
copy paste this, and let's do 'O's.
And if you notice, I get my list index out of range
because I need to have one more there.
The reason for that is because we're using one through nine,
so that the numbers correspond with a number pad.
So if you notice up here I'm indexing nine,
and that's because we're always just
going to ignore the zero index.
So this can actually be pretty much
anything you want it to be,
it's just always going to get ignored
for this particular displaying of the board.
That way, if you notice here,
one two there, four five six, seven eight nine,
it looks and matches up with the numbers of a number pad.
So that's the function "display_board".
Lets go ahead and break it down one more time,
just zoom in, what's really going on here.
We're printing a line, that's the top
of the tic tac to board.
Here, is where we're actually taking
the string values from that list,
and then adding empty strings,
plus those vertical dash marks,
in order to construct the board.
Okay, so that's our "display_board" function.
Again, we're just taking in a board,
we're assuming that it already has one to nine
correspondents with some sort of number pad,
and then we're just printing out the values
so that we get something that looks like this.
You can choose however you want to display the board itself,
as far as dashes or lines, but this is the basic premise
of what this function and step was trying to get you to do.
Okay, so we've done that,
lets go ahead and go on to the next one.
The next one is "Write a function that can take
in a player input and assign their marker as 'X' or 'O'.
What we want to think about is using while loops
to continually ask until you get a correct answer."
Alright, I encourage you, again, to pause the video now,
and see if you can solve this on your own.
Alright, let's go ahead and get started.
I'm going to say "marker" equal to just an empty string,
that way I actually define my variable
inside this function called marker,
and what I'm going to say is while not marker equal to
either an 'O' or marker equal to an 'X'.
I'm going to ask for the user's input,
so I'm going to say "marker = raw_input"
and for this input function it's going to be
"raw_input" for Python two, just "input" for Python three.
I can say whatever I want the actual line to be,
so I can say, "Player 1: Do you want to be X or O?"
and what I'm going to do is I'm going to call upper on it,
to automatically uppercase it,
so that it matches with uppercase O or uppercase X,
and then I'm going to say
"if marker is equal to uppercase X,"
I'm going to return a tuple in this case.
Again, you have some flexibility on what you want to return,
the way I've constructed this is so that it returns a tuple.
So I can later on use something called tuple unpacking,
which I'll show you much later on in this solution.
But this is basically assigning player one and player two,
or the reverse, player one and player two,
based on that tuple position index.
Let's go ahead and explore this function,
make sure it makes sense to us.
Alright, so I call "player_input",
and I'm just going to run this.
And then I see a little, you see it has an asterisk here,
that means it's running, but that actually means,
because I have input, it's waiting for an input.
So we get this little dialogue,
says "Player 1: Do you want to be X or O?"
So that's coming from this string here, in raw_input.
And I'm going to say "x".
And then you notice it just returns X and O as our output.
So that makes sense, let's just go ahead
and run this again, type in O.
Notice, whether I put a lowercase o
or if I put an uppercase O, it still works
because I called ".upper " here.
Let's go ahead and check,
what if I put in the wrong type of value?
If I put in a "2"?
You'll notice, because it says "while not",
the markers equal to O or X,
it's just going to keep asking for this raw_input.
So that's a great way to use a while loop,
to keep asking if you get the wrong type of inputs.
And then once I actually put in a correct one,
it returns the correct tuple assignment there.
You'll see later one why
we actually return tuples in our function.
Alright, so that's it for "player_input".
Let's go ahead and move on to step three.
But before we do, just let me break this down one more time,
we're setting a variable called "marker" as an empty string,
it's just, there's no space there.
Then we're saying, while not marker is equal to O or X,
which is the reason we set it as a empty string,
so we don't set it beforehand as O or X,
otherwise this while not loop would never execute.
We say "raw_input" "Player 1: Do you want to be X or O?"
So if I just take this line,
just to make sure you guys understand
what raw_input is doing,
it's just going to.
If I just say, "answer equal to raw_input"
and run this cell, say, "Player do you want to be X or O?"
and I put in some value here and click enter,
then if I check what my answer is,
it just sets it equal to a string version
of whatever you put in.
What'S nice about this though,
using raw_input in Python two,
if I put in a "2", and click enter,
it'll automatically still keep it as a string.
So just keep that in mind, again,
if you're using Python three, this should be "input",
Python two, this should be "raw_input".
So that's all that functions doing.
And upper, just to remind ourselves,
if I have something like "hello" and call upper on it,
it will just uppercase everything.
Alright, that's it for our player_input function.
Step three was to write a function that takes
in the board list object, a marker, 'X' or 'O',
a desired position, numbers one through nine,
and assigns it to the board.
Alright, this was actually really easy.
Even though it was difficult
to describe what's actually going on.
But, all we should have done for this is say
"board at that position and set it equal to marker."
You're just assigning that index position on the board list
to that particular marker value.
So that's all we had to do there.
Alright, step 4 was to write a function that takes
in a board and the mark, X or O,
and then check to see if that mark has won.
This ones a little bit more complicated,
and it's actually, it's a simple idea,
but it just takes up a lot of typing.
So, what you have to think about is,
how can you write a function that
takes in a board and a mark, X or O,
and then checks to see if that mark has won.
Alright, go ahead and pause the video,
see if you can figure this out on your own.
Okay, so what we're going to do here
is, think of how I can win at tic tac to.
Either, everything across the top matches,
across the middle, across the bottom,
diagonals, and then up and down.
So what I can do here is show you an example
of what one of these would look like.
I essentially want to do this,
I take in that board list and a mark,
and I want to check, lets say I just wanted
to check across the top, if they all matched up.
Then I could say this,
"return board value at seven equals that mark,
and board value at eight is equal to that mark,
and board value at nine is equal to that mark."
And this would check if everything
on the top row was the same.
This would then check if the top left corner,
at seven, was equal to the mark,
if the top middle was equal to the mark
and if the top right was equal to the mark.
So that's checking across the top.
So what we're going to do is keep doing these checks
for every single possible win that you could do.
And I'm just going to go ahead and copy this
from the solution notebook, because its quite a few checks.
There's a couple of ways that you can be more clever
and get around this, I just went ahead and copied this here.
But really, there's going to be a lot of typing here.
And you can see here how we're checking it.
And this ones also a diagonal check.
Alright, so we're using parentheses
to make sure we mark everything
and then we're using the key words
"or" and "and" to check everything.
So, each of these in parentheses is its own separate check.
And then we're saying "or" to keep checking
every other version of three matching in a line.
And then we're just taking advantage of indexing here
across our board to check for the wins.
Alright, and that's going to be down the left side.
So, that's step four, what we're going to do,
is go ahead and stop the video here.
Coming up next, in the next video, we'll go through
step five, step six, step seven, step eight,
and we'll see if we can get
to step nine and step ten in a reasonable time,
otherwise, we'll do a third video for that.
But just to review what we've done so far,
we went ahead, learned about from future print_function,
learned about raw_input and input,
for Python two versus Python three.
We discovered how we could display the board,
learned about clear_output for Jupyter Notebook.
We understood now how we can display a board
and print it out in Python.
Then, we wrote a function that would ask
the player for input and then assign a marker,
and then return tuples in our case.
This you could do in various ways depending how your final
logic game structure is going to be.
Here, we wrote a function that takes in
the board, the marker, and a position,
and then just uses list indexing to assign that marker
at that position of the board.
And then we wrote a function that takes in the board,
a mark, X or O, and then checks to see if that mark has won.
Which we can do like this, by checking each possible
combination across top, middle, bottom, et cetera.
Okay, with that being said, thanks everyone.
Hopefully, these steps aren't too hard for you,
but I do hope that this walkthrough guide does help you
and that you find this video helpful.
Again, in the next video, what we're going to do
is going over the next couple of functions.
Thanks, and I'll see you at the next lecture.