Hello everyone.
Welcome to the part two lecture video
for the Milestone Project 1,
walkthrough solution through all the steps in that workbook.
So in the last video lecture, we went ahead and
went over Step 1, display board function,
Step 2, the player input function,
Step 3, the place marker function,
Step 4, that win check function,
and then Step 5, which is writing a function
to use the random module to randomly decide
which player goes first.
Let's go ahead and now begin that task.
Gonna zoom in just a little more
so it's a little more clear.
So as I mentioned, you may want to look up random.randint.
Let's go ahead and see what that does.
If I wanted to find out more about this function,
I could just do Shift+Tab with my cursor
inside the parenthesis,
and then I get the document string,
also known as a DocString,
and it says, Return a random integer in range a, b,
including both end points.
OK, great.
Since I am only going to have two players,
then what I'm gonna say is,
if random.randint,
and I'll just say 0, 1, is equal to zero,
since it's including both end points,
the only two integers available are zero and one,
so it's basically a coin flip here.
I'll say, Return Player 1,
else, I'll say, return Player 2,
and that's all we're gonna do for that particular function.
And if I just go ahead and say, Print choose first.
In that case, it's Player 1.
In that case, it was Player 2.
Player 2 again.
Player 1,
so that makes sense, right?
It's basically a coin flip for who's going first.
OK, the next function we're going to do
is actually quite simple.
It's just write a function that returns a boolean
indicating whether a space on the board is freely available.
I can actually do that really simply.
I can say, board at position
double equal sign, check, if it's a string,
and just return this.
So this will return a boolean,
saying, OK, is the board at that position,
that indexed, so that number between one and nine,
is that element equal to a space?
Just return True or False.
So, return True if it is equal to a space.
False, if it's not.
All right, Step 7 is write a function
that checks if the board is full
and returns a boolean value.
I'm actually gonna take advantage of space_check to do this.
So, I'll do the following.
I'll say for i in range one to 10.
I gotta do 10 because it goes up to, but not including 10,
and I want the numbers one through nine here.
I'll say if space_check, then I'll say board,
at that position index,
so I'm checking for all the numbers here.
If that ever comes up as True,
meaning there is an empty space,
I'm gonna return False here,
because the board isn't full yet.
Otherwise, I'm just gonna return True.
And the reason I don't put an else statement here
is because I want to actually run
through each of the possibilities here,
so basically what's gonna happen here
at full board check
is I'm saying for i in range, one through 10,
which is just, in this case,
going through the numbers one through nine,
if the board at that index,
if space_check ever equals True,
meaning there was a space there,
I'm going to return False,
because that wasn't a full board.
If I go through this entire For loop,
and I never return False,
then I'm just gonna return True,
because I know now the board is full
and that's why we don't use an else there.
All right.
Time to to go Step 8.
Step 8 is write a function that asks for
a player's next position as a number between one and nine
and then uses the function from Step 6
to check to see if it's a free position.
If it is, then return the position for later use.
OK, let's go ahead and think about how we can do this.
I'm gonna go ahead and make a variable called position
and set it equal to an empty string,
and what I'm gonna do is I'll say while position.
Just gonna put a dot-dot-dot for a second there
to show you what I'm gonna actually do.
I'm gonna say raw_input.
I'm gonna ask the player to "Choose your next position."
One through nine,
and then what I want to do is continually ask
this person or player to choose the next position
until it's a valid topic.
So I'm gonna say, "while position is not in,"
and this is where we're gonna do a little trick here.
I'm gonna say, "1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9. split."
Let me show you what that's actually going to do.
That's going to take that string,
and it's going to split it into a list.
So what split does, it's just a method on that string
and it automatically splits on empty spaces.
In this case, in between the numbers
and then returns a list.
OK. So we have that.
So that's gonna check if the raw input
is actually there or one of these string numbers
and then I'm gonna say, "or not space_check,"
and in this case, what I'm gonna do
is I want to make sure the number isn't already taken,
so I'll say space_check board,
and then cast that string into an integer, by using int
and let's go ahead and put a colon in there.
So what I'm doing, let's just read this along.
I'm saying while position not in this list,
meaning the player hasn't actually put
the right number in.
Maybe they put in a different number
or they put in the wrong string.
They just said, "Hello,"
when you asked them, "Choose your next position," et cetera.
Or, we'll do a space_check on that position,
cast that as an integer,
meaning the space is taken.
I'm gonna say, "Please choose your next position."
Basically, I'm gonna keep asking this person
for the next position over and over again,
until they give me a value that makes sense,
and then once they do,
I'm just gonna return that value position
as an integer, so I can use it later on.
OK.
Step 9 is to write a function
that asks the player if they want to play again,
and returns a boolean True if they do want to play again.
So I'm just gonna say, return.
Because I'm using Python 2, I'll use raw_input.
Python 3 users should use just input.
I'll say, "Do you want to play again?
"Enter Yes or No."
And you can have a couple of If statements here,
checking If string is equal to "Yes,"
or while string equals "No," et cetera.
In this case, I'm just gonna kind of do a little trick here.
I'll say .lower,
and I'll say .startswith "y."
And basically what it's gonna do
is I'm going to go ahead and run that
and then show you something.
So let's say I have a string here that's just "hello."
This is a little bit of information
from the Advanced Strings lecture,
which is why I'm gonna go over that "startswith."
There's tonnes of methods you can do on a string,
but if I just wanted "hello,"
let me set this as a variable,
my_string, just so it's really clear.
So my_string is hello,
and then I can say, my_string,
and if I put in Tab, that gives me
all the methods available on this.
There's one called "startswith,"
and if you're interested in more of these methods,
you can check out the Advanced Strings lecture,
but "startswith" will just go ahead,
and if I click Shift+Tab,
it'll say, Return True if that string s
starts with the specified prefix, False otherwise.
If I've just put in "h," it returns True.
And then if I turn for something like "n,"
it returns False.
So in this case, I expect the user to say something
like, "Yes," but maybe they put uppercase or lowercase,
"Yes," or they say, like, "Yeah," or "Yep," kind of thing.
So even if they just say, "Yep,"
if I say startswith.y, it'll say True.
And if I say lower first, and then I say startswith,
now I don't even have to worry if they say, like "Yup,"
something like this with a capital,
because I've already lowered case it,
and I can do the same thing,
if I just said something like upper,
and then only checked for uppercase ys.
So that's what's going on with these lines right here.
And I'll make more sense when we actually
implement Step 10, which is the hard part.
We're gonna use a bunch of while loops
and the functions that we've just made
to run the actual game.
All right, since this is quite a bit of code
for this block,
I'm gonna leave that for the next video.
As a quick review of what we did in this video,
we went ahead, made a function
that randomly chooses which player goes first.
We wrote a function that returns a boolean,
indicating whether a space on the board is freely available.
We wrote a function that checks if the board is full
and then returns a boolean value
and then we also wrote a function
that asks for a player's next position
and then uses that space_check function
to check if it's a free position
and then we return it for later use.
And then Step 9, we just wrote a function
that asks the player if they want to play again
and returns a boolean True if they do want to play again.
All right, so for Step 10, we'll do that
in the next lecture,
but basically we'll take everything we've just done,
all the functions we just made,
and use a bunch of while loops
to actually run a tic-tac-toe game.
OK, thanks everyone, and I'll see you at the next lecture.