Hello everyone,
and welcome to the Ordered Dictionary lecture.
In the last lecture we covered the default dictionary
and now we're gonna cover the ordered dictionary.
Which is a dictionary sub-class
that actually remembers the order
in which the contents are added.
If you remember, one of the recovering dictionary,
they were mappings and they didn't retain any order
as to how you added the keys or values to the dictionary.
Well, if the ordered dictionary, you will retain the order.
Let's go ahead and check out what
a normal dictionary looks like.
So if I create a normal dictionary,
using curly brackets and then let's assign
a key, a, to have the value, one.
We'll assign a key, b, to have the value,
let's say, two, and close off.
Finally, c, to have a value, three.
If you take a look at that dictionary,
we have a, b, c, one, two, three.
I'll do couple more, just to make sure there is
some mixing up of the order in the mapping eventually.
So, five, alright.
Now if I say, for k,v and
d.items, prints k,v.
Notice we don't get the order that we put the items in,
so we get one, three, two, five, four.
The order is being mixed up because
a normal dictionary is just the mapping,
it doesn't retain the order.
But, if we import an ordered dictionary from the collection,
so we say, from collections, import OrderedDict.
We can say d is equal to an ordered dictionary
and now we're gonna do the exact same thing.
Copy, paste this here, add the elements in that order
and you'll notice when we say,
for key value and d.items, print key value,
the order is retained.
So something that's interesting with this sequence order
is that since the regular dictionary
only looks at contents when testing for equality,
in ordered dictionary, we'll also consider
the order of the items as they were added.
For example, if I were to make a dictionary,
let's say, dictionary is d1
and let's put an a equal one
and have b equal two, then I'm gonna
make another ordered dictionary.
It's gonna have b equal two, d2,
of b equal one, whoops, excuse me, of a.
Alright, so you notice these dictionaries,
as far as the key value pairs are the same.
So if I print d1 equal d2, it'll return true.
But, if I make these dictionaries,
not normal dictionaries, but ordered dictionaries,
so I'll make d1, an ordered dictionary,
I'll make d2, an ordered dictionary
and then run this statement again,
it's gonna be false because they
were added in a different order.
So it's definitely something to keep in mind
as you work for ordered dictionaries.
Technically speaking, these two ordered dictionaries
are not true, or not equal to each other.
But if they were just normal dictionaries,
they would be equal to each other.
Okay, so up next, the last thing we're gonna cover,
as far as the collections module, will be the namedtuple.
Alright, I'll see you at the next lecture.