Hello, everyone,
and welcome to the Advanced Lists lecture.
So, in this series of lectures,
we're gonna be diving a little deeper into all the methods
available in a list.
So, these aren't officially advanced features,
just methods that you wouldn't typically encounter
without some additional exploring.
So, we've actually seen quite a few of these,
append, count, extend, index, insert, pop, remove,
reverse, sort, so we may have seen a lot of these already
just by using lists and in the Methods lecture itself,
but let's go ahead and go over them
just in case you need a refresher.
Okay, so let's start by making a very simple list.
I'll call it l,
and I'll have one, two, three in it.
You definitely should've used this method by now.
It's append, whoops.
It's the append method, and of course,
it just appends an item
to your list.
Alright, so we discussed this also a number of times,
the count method.
So, we can use the count method, and it'll count
how many times an object occurs in your list.
And, it'll actually count whether it's in there or not,
so notice how I count a 10,
doesn't occur any times.
One occurs once in my list.
So, moving along, here's one that you may not have heard of,
and, or may not have used yet.
It's called extend.
So, many times people find the difference
between extend and append to be unclear.
So, I'm gonna show you by means of example.
So, let's go ahead and make a list called x.
It's just like y, it's, er just like the l list,
it's gonna have one, two, three.
I'm going to append
another list to that.
And, this list will contain four, five.
And then, I'm gonna say print x.
Okay, so what happened here?
So, remember append just adds the entire element
to the list, so what's it's doing here is
it's adding this and appending this list
to an element in itself.
Now, what happens if you wanted to extend this list
into your original list?
So, that's where extend comes in.
So, now I'm gonna show you again,
but in this time we're gonna use extend.
So, I'm gonna say x.extend
and pass in a list again with just two elements, four, five.
Then, I'm gonna say print x.
So, notice the difference here.
You're actually adding in the entire list.
So, your extend will append each element in that iterable.
And, that's the key difference there.
So, again, just to cover append
is going to append elements just the entire iterable,
all the elements in it.
And, what extend does is appends elements individually
from the iterable.
Alright, so let's move along.
Take a look at our l list that has one, two, three in it,
or one, two, three, four, excuse me.
And, index is another method
that we've probably seen already.
So, what does index do?
Index will return the index of whatever element
is placed as an argument.
So, let's find the index of two.
And, it's one, right?
'Cause, yeah, indexing starts at zero,
zero, one, the object at the one index is two.
Something to note here is that you will get an error
if you try to index something that's not in your list.
And, it'll tell you very clearly value error
10 is not in list.
Alright, let's move along with insert.
So, what does insert do?
Insert takes in two arguments.
It takes in index and the object.
So, this method places the object at the index applied.
So, for example, let's just make sure we know
what l looks like.
L looks like one, two, three, four.
And, what I'm gonna do is in that list I'm going to insert
at index two a string called inserted.
So, note the order here of the arguments.
You put in the index first
and then the object you want to insert.
So, what does my list look like now?
Notice how it has the inserted at the two index.
So, zero index, one index, and at the two index
it's placed this string inserted here.
So, again, you put your index in first
and then the object you wanna insert second.
Okay, might be useful if throughout your code
you really wanna make sure that you know
the particular index of an object.
Okay, moving along, you've definitely already seen pop,
which allows you to pop off the last element of a list.
So, again, here's the list,
and I can pop.
And by default, it's the last element in that list.
So, I set l pop equal to ele,
and ele, you notice it was four.
And again, remember that change is permanent.
It's in place on your list.
Okay.
So, something else to note is that
you can pass in an index into pop.
So, I could say pop zero,
notice how it's one,
so now l looks like this,
two, inserted, three.
So, what's another method for a list that we can use?
Remove is another method.
So, the remove method removes the first occurrence
of a value.
So, for example, I have my list,
and let's say I wanna remove that string inserted.
So, I pass in the value,
and it will now remove it in place.
So, I wanna show you one more example with this,
just to make sure you get the idea
that it's only removing the first instance of it.
So, here you notice my list is one, two, three, four, three.
There's two threes in it.
So, if I say l.remove
it's only going to remove the first instance of it.
So, that's something to keep in mind with remove.
Another method we can use if I see l here is reverse,
and as you might guess,
reverse just reverses your list
and reverses the indexes for them.
So, note that this occurs in place,
so it will affect your list permanently.
And, we can also use a sort method on our list.
And, sort will sort your list also in place.
So, those are all the methods on a list.
Some of them we've covered a lot.
Some of them might be new to you.
But, just go ahead and again review the Jupyter notebook.
Make sure you understand everything.
So, let's just go a quick rundown of everything we learned.
So, append, you've definitely used this method.
It appends an element to the end of a list.
Count, we've discussed this as well.
It'll count how many times that object
takes place in your list.
Whether or not it actually occurs in your list
it won't return error.
Extend, here's the tricky one.
Remember in extend appends each element in that iterable,
so it appends here four and five,
not just the list with four, five.
Index will return the index of whatever element's
placed in as an argument.
But remember, it has to actually be in the list,
otherwise you get an error.
Insert takes in two arguments,
first the index and then the object.
So, here we insert it at two,
this word or string inserted.
And, notice now it's inserted in the set index two.
Pop, we've seen that already,
allows us to pop off the last element of a list,
or we can also pass in a specific index if necessary.
Remove, the remove method removes the first occurrence
of a value, so we just saw an example of that.
Reverse, as you know reverses a list,
and sort will sort your list in place.
So, both reverse and sort are in place
and will affect your list permanently.
Okay, that's it for the Advanced Lists lecture,
which is basically just all the methods on a list,
and some of them you wouldn't typically encounter
without some additional exploring.
Okay, thanks everyone, and I'll see you at the next lecture.