Hello, everyone,
and welcome to this lecture on the datetime module.
So Python has a datetime module that will help you deal
with timestamps in your code.
And the time values are represent of the time class,
and they have attributes such as hour,
minutes, second, and microsecond,
and they can even include timezone informations.
So the arguments to initialise time instance are optional,
but the default of zero is unlikely to be what you want.
So let's go ahead and explore the datetime module.
Okay, so first thing we're gonna do is import datetime,
and then let's go ahead and take a look at how we can
extract time information from the datetime module.
So we can create a timestamp by specifying datetime.time.
So datetime.time.
And the format goes like this,
it goes hour first, so I'll put in a, let's say, five.
Then it goes minutes.
So let's say five, 25.
Then seconds.
So I'll just put one second.
I won't put any microseconds.
Next one would be microseconds.
So I'm just gonna put that in,
and call that my time, t.
So I created this time, t.
And then what I can actually do
is say, print, t, and it prints the time,
five, 25, and one second.
And I can actually grab the separate components from it
by calling those attributes.
So I can pull out the hour.
I can pull out the minute.
I can pull out even those microseconds,
which were zero in this case since I didn't supply any.
And you notice there's a lot
of different things you can pull out here.
The resolution, the timezone info,
timezone name, those are all things you can add in.
So if I look at datetime.time,
notice I can pass in hours, minutes, seconds, microseconds,
and then even timezone information,
which it belongs to a separate subclass.
So something to note here is that a time instance
only holds values of times,
not a date associated with a time.
So we can also check the min and max values,
a time that they can have in the module.
So for instance, I can say,
datetime.time min.
And so the minimum I have if I print this out
is zero, zero, zero, zero, zero.
Which makes sense, right?
That's the earliest time you can possibly have.
And I can also print out the maximum time.
Which is basically right before the 24-hour mark,
which would bring you back down to zero.
And then I can also check the resolution
of a datetime instance
by calling the resolution attribute.
And so it can get down up to this resolution
as far as microseconds.
So the min and max class attributes,
these reflect here the valid range of times in a single day.
So now that we've learned about times themselves,
and timestamps,
so hour, minutes, seconds, microseconds,
and even timezone information,
let's go ahead and look at dates.
So we looked at the time part of datetime,
and now let's go on on to dates.
Datetime allows us to work with datetime stamps.
So calendar date values are represented with a date class.
And instances of the date class have attributes
for year, month, and day.
And it's pretty easy to create a date
representing today's date using the today class method.
So I can say, call a variable, today,
call datetime,
and now I'm calling date, not time, off of it.
And I can call 'em attribute called today.
And then if I say, print today,
it'll say in this case, October 6th, 2015
is the day I'm actually doing this lecture.
Okay, so what else can we check out?
We can check out today. a time tuple,
which is just a different structure to have.
And it basically is almost like a named tuple,
and it gives you more information on the separate aspects
or attributes of your date.
What else can you do?
You can actually call year, month, and day separately.
So I could say, today.year,
or .month,
or .day.
You can call all those attributes separately.
So as with time, the range of date values supported
can be determined by the min and max attributes.
So for instance, I could call datetime.date,
and then check the minimum date possible.
And if I print that out,
so we can see it in more layman's terms,
there it is, one, one, one.
And then the max date you can ever have
is December 31st, year 9999.
And the resolution
for a datetime.date object is one day.
That's its resolution.
So another way to create new date instances
uses the replace method of an existing date.
So for example, you can change the year,
leaving the day and month alone.
So I'll show you what I mean by that.
I can create a variable called, d1,
call datetime.date,
and then let's go ahead and pass in the year,
the month, and the day.
And I'm gonna go ahead and say, print d1.
So here we have 2015,
March 11th.
And notice, I can use replace as such.
I could say, d2 equals d1.replace.
And I'm gonna say, woops, d1.replace.
And let's just change this year to let's say, 1990.
And now if I call d2, it's the exact same date as d1,
except we replaced the year with 1990.
So this is actually a pretty useful method
in case you just wanna make adjustments
on date objects that you already have.
And real quick, what I'm gonna show you
is that you can actually perform arithmetic
on date objects to check for time differences.
So for example, if we just check back again what d1 equals,
d1 is datetime 2015, three, 11.
D2 is datetime 1990, three, 11.
So I can actually perform arithmetic,
so d1 minus d2,
and it gives you the time delta.
So this gives us the difference in days
between those two dates.
And you can use the time delta method
to specify various units of times.
You can ask it for days, minutes, hours, et cetera.
So that's all there is as far as the basics understandings
of using timestamps in your code.
And if you hop over to the Jupyter Notebook,
you can go ahead and check out some more examples,
and it laid out in a little more detail here.
So again, just to go over it,
import datetime if you ever wanna deal with timestamps.
If you ever wanna deal with timestamps in the hour,
minute, second range, or microseconds,
go ahead and use the time class on the datetime module.
If you wanna deal with dates, then you use datetime.date.
And you can go ahead and read through the Jupyter Notebook,
or even the Python documentation
to get more information on the various methods available
in the datetime module.
But other than that,
I hope it's given you a basic idea
on how you can use this in your own code.
Alright.
Thanks everyone, and I'll see you at the next lecture.