Hello everyone,
and welcome to the lists lecture.
So in this lecture we'll be learning about
the list data structure in Python, and we discussed earlier
that strings are a type of sequence in Python,
and we're gonna learn now that lists
can be thought as probably one of
the most general versions of sequences in Python.
So let's go ahead and get started.
Here I have open the Jupyter Notebook
and we're gonna learn about creating lists,
indexing and slicing lists, some basic list methods,
and then nesting lists, and we'll get
a quick introduction to list comprehensions.
So this is a quick overview of everything in
this Jupyter Notebook, you can go ahead and check it out,
but let's go ahead and dive into the live code.
All right, here we go.
So now in the live code let's go ahead
and assign a list to a variable.
So I'm gonna create a variable name called my_list,
and I'm going to create a list.
So lists are constructed with square brackets,
and then they have commas separating
every element in the list.
So for instance if I wanted to make
a list of the numbers one, two, three,
so right now in this format my list
is everything in-between these two brackets,
and it allows me to keep track of this sequence of elements,
one, two and three, and they're all separated by commas.
Shift + Enter to run that cell.
So we just created a list of integers,
so if I say my_list, and I can remember
to do Tab to autocomplete, there I have my list output.
So as I mentioned, this is a list of integers,
but what's nice about Python is lists
can actually hold different object types.
So for instance, I can create my list
and I'll set it equal to a new list,
and this list is going to contain a string, an integer, 23,
and even like a floating-point number, so 1.2,
and let's put another string in there for good measure.
There we go, and now if I call my list again,
you can see the list is holding different object types,
so it's holding a string, it's holding integers,
floating-points, so lists can hold different object types.
You can go ahead and mix and match them within the list.
So just like strings, there's a length function,
and the len function also works for lists,
so I can say len of my_list, remember Tab autocomplete,
and there I get the list's length is four,
and that's because there's four elements,
there's the string, 23, 1.2, and that o string.
Okay, so let's go ahead and jump
to indexing and slicing.
So indexing and slicing is gonna work
just like we explored indexing and slicing in strings.
So let's go ahead and make a new list,
or just reassign that list label,
so I'm gonna say, I'm gonna make a list of one,
that's string one, two, let's say three,
and then let's go ahead and put in some integers
to mix it up, so one, two, three in strings,
and then 4, 5, and remember each of
the elements is separated by a comma.
So since this is a sequence I can index
and grab stuff in that sequence,
so if I say my_list variable name,
with brackets and then zero, that's gonna grab
the element at index zero, and in this case,
it's just that first one, it's that one.
So just like in strings the notation is the same, so whoops.
Let's say I wanna say my_list, and let's say I wanted
to grab index one and everything past it,
I can use that same colon notation,
so my_list, grab everything in element one
and then everything past it.
So that's two, three, 4, 5, 'cause remember
our index zero, that's the one string.
So let's say I wanted to grab everything up to index three.
I can say my_list, and I'll say everything up
to element three, so :3, and that returns one, two, three.
Great, so we can also use the plus symbol
to concatenate lists, just like we did for strings.
So if you remember from the string lecture,
I could say hello plus, space, let's say world,
and now it concatenated it into
a single string, 'hello world'.
So I can actually do the same with lists,
so I can say my_list, and that's just
that one, two, three, 4, 5 there,
and I can concatenate it with another list.
So I'll create a new list, and concatenate it.
So what I have here right now is this variable,
my list, my_list representing my list,
and I'm gonna add, or concatenate
this list consisting of a single item,
which is just a string here,
and that's denoted by those square brackets.
There we go, and if you notice when you concatenate it,
it basically kind of just appended it
to the last item on that list.
Now again, it's important to note,
since we're not reassigning anything here,
if I just copy and paste my list here,
that list hasn't been changed,
'cause I'm not reassigning it.
Okay, so if I wanted to make the change permanent,
I would have to reassign it.
So I'd have to say my_list is equal to
my_list plus, let's say permanent add,
and now if I check what my list is,
here I've added it permanently,
because I've reassigned it using that equal sign.
All right, so we can also use the multiplication
or the asterisk symbol for duplication,
just like we did in strings,
so I can say my_list multiplied by two,
and that's basically gonna just double my list,
so one, two, three, 4, 5, permanent add,
and then again, one, two, three, 4, 5, permanent add,
and you'll notice the output is just
a singular list of the elements twice over.
So again, that's not permanent
since I'm not reassigning anything.
If I just call my list again I get that original list.
Okay, so if you're familiar with
another programming language you might start
to draw parallels between arrays in another language
and lists in Python, but lists in Python tend
to be more flexible than arrays in other languages,
and there's usually two good reasons for that.
They have no fixed size constraint,
so for instance this list, it can be as big as we want,
and we can keep adding to it.
So I don't have to set any restrictions beforehand,
I don't have to say, "Hey, this list is gonna
"be five elements long in the sequence."
Python allows us to just keep adding
and growing to that list, and like we saw
what's nice about lists in Python
is that they have no type constraint.
So you saw earlier I was mixing strings,
and integers, and floating-points,
and different object types into that list.
So let's go ahead and explore methods for lists.
So I'm gonna say l is equal to the list [1,2,3],
so here I have my list l equal to three elements,
1, 2 and 3 in that sequence.
So one method we can use is the append method.
It's gonna be one of the most common methods you use
on a list, so again, the way methods work
is you take that variable or label name,
put a dot, and then type in the method you use.
So in this case the method I'm gonna use
is called append, and then append looks like this,
has closed parentheses, and the argument you pass into it
is the item you wanna add to the end of the list.
So for instance, I wanna add a string called append me!,
and if I look at the list now, l,
you'll notice I have appended to the end of
that list that append me! String.
So just to reiterate again, since we're using
the Jupyter Notebook, and it's such a great tool
for learning, if I say l. and then click on Tab,
it'll give me a list of all the available methods.
Go ahead and check out the advanced list lectures
for a breakdown of a lot of these methods,
but we're gonna go over a few of 'em
in this lecture as well, and again,
I can say l.append, and since we're using
the Jupyter Notebooks, I can say Shift + Tab,
and it will give you the Docstring
and some additional information.
So it'll tell us L.append, you put in the object,
and you can append object to the end, great.
So right now we have l is equal to 1, 2, 3, 'append me!'
Another method that's commonly used in lists
is the pop method, so you can use pop
to basically "pop off" an item from that list.
So by default, pop takes off the last index,
but you can also specify which index to pop off.
So what I'm gonna show you is just a quick example.
So I can say l.pop , and that basically returns
that last element in your list,
and it also permanently affects your list.
So it just says, "Okay, I'm gonna grab off
"that last item, pop it off, and then return it back."
So let's go ahead and say l., well I'm gonna say
x is equal to l.pop, and I can also specify which index.
So by default the index is negative one, which would be
your last element in that list, but I can pop off
whatever index I want by passing it through.
So let's say I wanted to pop off the zero index item,
which in this case would be one, that very first item.
So here what I'm doing is I'm saying l is my list,
call the pop method on it, that .pop,
and then I'm passing the index I wanna pop off,
which would be zero, which corresponds to that 1 element,
and I'm using the equal sign to set
that equal to a variable here, great.
So if I check out what x equals now, x is equal to 1,
and if I check out my original list l,
I notice now it just consists of 2 and 3.
Okay, great.
So it should be noted that list indexing
will return an error if there's no element at that index.
So for instance, right now my list consists of
the elements two and three, so let's say I call index
at one, that should return 3,
remember indexing starts at zero, so zero, one,
but let's say I said index of 99.
So that's gonna return an error,
and if we read the error right here, it's an IndexError,
and that's because the list index is out of range.
So that makes sense, we can't index something
that's out of range in that list.
Okay, so let's go ahead and make a new list
to explore two more methods, sort and reverse.
So I'm gonna say new_list is equal to,
in this case I'm gonna use strings, just letters,
so I'm gonna say a, e, let's say x, b and c,
and the reason I'm not just doing the straight alphabet
is because I'm gonna show you how
to sort and reverse some of this.
So go ahead and make a new list that looks like that,
let's go ahead and make sure everything worked.
Okay, so here's my new list, remember we're just
using square brackets, the elements are separated by commas.
So what can I do is sort and reverse methods.
So if I check out new_list. and Tab
because I'm in Jupyter Notebook,
I can see that there's a reverse method here.
So let's go ahead and click Enter and see what happens.
As you might suspect, it reverses the order,
and it's a permanent change to the list,
so now it's reversed the order of that list,
and what if we wanted to sort that order,
then I can say Tab, let's go down to sort,
and now if we check out that list, it's been sorted
into alphabetical order, a, b, c, e, x, great.
So in the case of numbers, if that list
was full of numbers it would sort them in ascending order.
All right, so another great feature of
this data structure in Python that is the list,
is that they support nesting, and you'll notice
a lot of data structures in Python support nesting,
so that means you can have data structures
within data structures, so for this example,
we're gonna do a list inside of a list.
So let's get a quick look at how this works.
I'm gonna make three lists, I'm writing right now,
well let's say l_1 is equal to [1, 2, 3],
I'm gonna say l_2 is equal to [4, 5, 6],
I'm gonna say l_3 is equal to [7, 8, 9].
Okay, so I've created three lists,
and I can actually make a list of lists.
So I'm gonna make another object called matrix,
and I'm gonna set it equal to a list of lists,
so I'm gonna say this matrix is a list itself,
but I'm gonna put in the elements as lists,
so I'm gonna say [l_1, l_2, l_3].
So now I can treat this as a matrix,
because if you notice here I have my list,
which is the matrix, and the elements inside of it
are actually lists as well,
and this is what we mean by nesting data structures.
So I have a list inside of a list,
and this can keep going deeper and deeper,
as you can have a list inside of a list,
which is inside of another list.
So we can again use index to grab elements,
but now there's gonna be two levels to that index.
So the items in the matrix objects,
and then the items inside of that list.
So I'll show you what I mean by that.
So let's say I have my matrix object,
which is just that list of lists,
and I say index zero, so what's that gonna return?
That's gonna return the first element
in that matrix object, which will be [1, 2, 3].
All right, so now that I have this first item in
the list, I can actually index it again
because it is a list, so I can say grab
the first item in that matrix object,
and then grab the first item, or element in that list itself
by putting another pair of brackets there.
So you can see that I have multiple levels
to this indexing, and I'm just kind of exploring them there.
So I encourage you to kind of play around,
see how I can get this number 5, how would I do that?
So in matrix that's the second list, or element,
so I'd have to say zero, one,
and then within that one, that list,
it's zero, one again, so that should return 5 there,
and for another quick example,
let's say I wanted to get 7, how would I get that?
Well we note that it's the item at the second index, right,
zero, one, two, so it's that third item at index two,
and then 7, it's the first one so that's at index zero,
and if we get that, there we have the 7, excellent.
So I'm gonna give you one last topic in this lecture,
and that's gonna be list comprehensions.
So Python has a pretty advanced feature
called List Comprehensions, and it allows
for quick construction of these lists.
So I'm just gonna give you kind of a quick sneak peek
of what this looks like, but don't worry
if you don't understand it because we have
a whole entire lecture devoted to list comprehensions,
but in case you're familiar with another language,
or you've kind of gone through a tutorial with Python before
I'll show you how we can build a list comprehension
by basically deconstructing a for loop within brackets.
Now I know we haven't gone over loops or anything,
so if this doesn't make sense to you don't worry about it
at all, we're gonna go over loop statements,
list comprehensions in much more detail in the future.
But just for a cool sneak peek, let's say I wanted
to create that first column of that matrix.
I could say, first_col, that's my object name,
and set it equal to...
[row for row in Matrix].
Now I know if you haven't seen any for loops
or any statements, this doesn't make too much sense,
but don't worry about it.
What this is basically breaking it down
is I can create a list by kind of writing
a flat for loop within the brackets.
So we'll have lectures devoted to this
in further detail, but just to give you kind of
a sneak peek at what this is doing,
I just created an object that consists of
the first column of that matrix,
that 1, that 4, and that 7.
Okay, so what that basically did is just said, "Hey,
"for every element or row in that matrix,
"grab the zero index of that row,"
and then, using this list comprehension,
I can actually make a list out of it.
Okay, so that's a little sneak peek,
we'll hit that in much further detail in the future,
but just a quick overview of what we've done,
I'm gonna hop over back to the Jupyter Notebook.
We've understood how to create a list using brackets
and separating the elements by commas,
we understand that a list can hold different object types,
such as integers and strings all mixed together,
we can use the len function to check the length of a list,
we can use indexing and slicing just like we did
for strings, because it's a sequence.
So we can use those square brackets on that list variable
to go ahead and grab things from that list.
We can concatenate lists using the plus sign,
we can use the multiplication or the asterisk sign
to multiply, or duplicate lists,
and then we went over some basic list methods,
the append method, the pop method, sort and reverse,
and then we saw a quick introduction to nesting lists.
Okay, so that's it, you can go ahead
and check out the advanced lists section later on in
this course to go over some more details of those methods,
but that's about it for lists for right now.
All right, thanks guys!