Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture
where we're going to discuss the built in function zip.
Which basically makes an iterator that aggregates elements
from two or more iterables.
Okay, so, let's go ahead and see how this works.
Just to give you a quick note,
zip, you could actually write it yourself,
This is what the function is equal to,
so if you want to explore,
if you had to make your own function
that was similar to zip,
this is how you would do it.
What we're gonna do is actually just
go ahead and see it in action first,
cuz I think it's best explained through example.
So let's say you had two lists.
We're gonna make one list called x,
one two three,
and another called y,
one two, let's make it different,
let's say four five whoops, four five six.
Okay, so you have these two lists.
X and y.
And now what we're gonna do is use zip
to essentially zip them together.
So I'm gonna say x comma y,
and the output is gonna be basically tuplets,
or tuples, pairs of two, or, pairs inside a tuple,
excuse me,
and a whole list of them.
So, let's go ahead and see an example
of how we would use this.
So what we're gonna do now is create two more lists.
A,
which let's say is gonna have one two one,
let's say one two three four five,
and b which is gonna not be sequential,
it's gonna take, two, two, let's put in 10,
one, one.
Let's make sure they match up, okay.
So we could use zip to pick
the largest between both of these.
So what I mean by that is let's say we only wanted
to return a list that included the largest in each index.
So between a and b, the first largest at the zero index
would be from b.
The second largest would be from a, et cetera.
So there's actually lots of ways to do this,
but we're gonna use it with zip.
So let's go ahead and see how that would work.
So I could say,
something like this.
I could say
for pair
in zip of a b,
return the max
of that pair.
And let's see what we get.
Oops I have return outside of function,
I need to put that in a function.
Or I can just say, let's say print.
Let's bring that back in.
Okay.
So what did I do here?
Instead of writing a whole function, just a quick foreloop.
So I went through each pair in the zip
for these guys which would have looked something like this.
Let's go ahead and copy and paste this
so we know what we're looking at,
so it went ahead, saw each pair,
and returned the max from that tuple.
So let's go ahead and do this now using map.
Since we learned about it earlier.
So I could say map, with a lambda expression,
for every pair we wanna return
let's say the max of that pair,
and go through zip a b.
Let's see if that works,
and notice now we have the exact same result
but as a list.
So this should really show you how powerful zip can be.
Now something you might be wondering is
what if one iterable is longer than the other?
So let's say I have one list that says one two three,
and another list that's much longer,
let's say it's equal to four five six seven, eight.
So what happens if I zip these two guys together now?
Well what happens is you're defined
by the shortest iterable.
So you can only go as far as the shortest iterable
in that zip function.
Okay, so what happens
if we try to zip together dictionaries?
So we've done lists,
but let's go ahead and explore dictionaries.
So I'm gonna make two dictionaries.
One of a key a, with a value one,
one for key b, with value two,
a dictionary d2,
key c value four,
key d value five.
Okay. So, let's go ahead and zip these and see what happens.
All right.
So you notice we only get the keys.
And that's because simply iterating through a dictionary
if you remember, will only give you the keys.
So if I say,
for I in d1,
print I,
remember from dictionaries lectures,
we only get that key back out.
So what if I want to get the values?
Well if you're using Python 2, you can use iter values,
or if you're using Python 3 you can just use values.
So I could do something like this.
Let's say d2, and let's say I want the values from d1.
So I can say itervalues,
and there we go.
All right, so that's a couple methods we can use
to mix keys and values.
So what we're gonna finally do is use zip
to switch the keys and values of two dictionaries.
So, let's go ahead and make a function to do that.
So I'm gonna call this function switcharoo.
And what it does it takes in d1, d2,
takes in two dictionaries,
I'm going to define an object called dout
as an empty dictionary,
that'll be the dictionary it returns
when I say return dout.
And so how do we wanna build this?
So I wanna say,
let's say for d1 key,
and d2 val in,
zip
the first dictionary keys
and the second dictionary's values
iter values,
and what I'm gonna do is say dout, d1key
has the value from d2 val.
And, whoops. That should have been an equal sign.
And now let's go ahead and see what happens
when we say switcharoo.
So remember d1 looks like that,
d2 looks like that,
and if I call switcharoo on d1 d2,
then I've switched the values from dictionary one
with the values from dictionary two.
Okay, great.
So, hopefully you've seen how zip can save a lot of typing
in a lot of situations,
and you should have a good understanding
of how to read zip and how to use it.
So remember zip is pretty simple,
you just take two iterables
and basically zip them up together in tuple pairs.
All right, and one last note.
Is if one iterable is shorter than the other,
you're defined by the shorter iterable.
So feel free to play around with zip,
it's gonna be a great tool to have
as you code more in python.
Okay everyone, I'll see you at the next lecture.