Hello everyone, and welcome to
the coding lecture for dictionaries.
So with strings and lists, we've been learning about
sequences in Python, but now we're going to switch gears
to learn about mappings in Python.
So if you're familiar with other languages,
you can sort of think of dictionaries in Python
as a hash table.
So right now I have open the Jupyter Notebook,
and we're going to be going over how to construct
a dictionary, various ways to access objects from
a dictionary, learn about nesting with dictionaries,
just like we learned about nesting of lists,
and then we'll learn about a few of the basic
dictionary methods.
Okay, so let's go ahead and get started with the code.
So like I mentioned earlier,
dictionaries in Python are mappings.
And what mappings basically are is just a collection
of objects that are sorted by a key.
So unlike a sequence that stores objects by their
relative position, so if you remember in a list,
for example, I can make a list l, 1, 2, 3.
So remember I could access things from that list
by indexing.
So that's how a sequence works.
What a mappping's going to do is is it's going
to store objects with a key.
So it's an important distinction since mappings aren't
going to retain order like lists and strings did.
So let's go ahead and see how we can construct
a dictionary.
So in Python a dictionary consists of a key and then
an associated value.
And the value can be pretty much any Python object.
So I'll make my first example dictionary by saying
my_dict as the variable name.
And we make dictionaries in Python with curly brackets,
so if you just put shift above your square brackets,
you should get these curly brackets on your keyboard.
And then the way we can construct a dictionary is,
the most basic example is you put in a key name,
usually a string, pretty much always a string, and
then the value you want.
So in this case, I'm going to put in values, and there's
a colon separating the key in the value.
And then we have commas separating the various key
and value combos in our dictionary.
So then I'm going to put colon and put in value2.
So this is probably the most basic version
of a dictionary you can have in Python.
So if you notice, what we've constructed is I have
these curly brackets and then I have a key, colon,
and then the value that's associated with that key.
And then comma for every key value combo throughout
that dictionary.
So if you remember, we could use square brackets
to access index elements in lists and strings.
In this case, we're going to use the keys for a
dictionary with the same bracket notation.
So I have this bracket notation, but if you notice
if I put zero, it's not going to work.
It's going to say KeyError.
And that's because it's not a sequence; it's a mapping.
So what I end up putting is the key instead.
So if I put in key1, it outputs the value
that's associated with that key.
So another important note is that dictionaries,
just like lists, are super flexible in the type
of data types they can hold.
So for example, I can get my_dict, and I'm going
to create a new dictionary now.
I'll put k1 for key one, and I can put a number,
such as like an integer.
I can also mix data types, so I can say key two, colon,
put in a floating point number there, and let's say k3.
I can set that equal to string.
Close off with another curly brackets.
And so now I can say my_dict, and I can call any one
of those keys, and it will return the value associated
with that key.
So let's try calling another item.
Let's try getting that third key out there, which is string.
Cool.
So what's really interesting now is based on the value
that gets outputted from that key, I can then call
different methods on that value.
So right now, if you notice my_dict with the k3 key
is this string, which is also labelled string there.
So I can actually perform different things that I would
be able to do on a string such as index, which would
output s there, or maybe I could reverse it like we
did for strings, which is ::-1, and then I can even
call different methods, so I can say maybe like
upper method, if you remember, upper case.
So what this is basically doing is it's returning
that string, and I can do anything I want with that
object that I'd be able to normally do with a string.
Great.
So we can also affect the values of the key as well.
So for instance, right now if you notice my_dict, k1,
remember that square brackets, that k1 key,
is equal to 123.
So if I say k1, let's say 123, minus let's say 120,
that's going to be equal to three.
So that makes sense.
Right now I'm just calling that number and subtracting
120 from it.
But if copy and paste this, you'll notice it doesn't
actually affect that value permanently.
But what I can do to affect that value permanently
is use an equal sign.
So I can say my_dict of k1 is equal to my_dict k1
minus 120.
And now what that's done is it's actually changed
the value that's associated with that key.
And so now it equals three permanently.
So now if I print out my dictionary just by calling it,
you'll notice that I've permanently affected the
value associated with that k1, that first key.
Cool.
Alright, so now what I want to mention is that
you'll notice while you're doing your various coding
exercises throughout the course, you may be trying
to do this type of operation a lot, this take a value,
set it equal to either addition or subtraction
from the value itself.
So some sort of self-subtraction or self-addition
or even like a multiplication or division.
So what's really nice about Python is it actually
has a quick syntax for you to do self-subtraction
or self-addition or multiplication and division.
And what that looks like is you basically put the
operation before the equal sign.
And I'll show you a quick example of what I mean.
So remember right now we have my_dict,
the k1 key is equal to three.
So if I say my_dict, k1, plus 100,
now it's going to be equal to 103.
So I can use a quick syntax to basically fast forward
through this notation, and the way that works is
I end up taking this plus sign here, putting it
behind the equal sign and then get rid of this
notation there that's self-referencing it.
So this is the exact same thing, that plus minus,
performs the exact operation that we just did before.
And you'll notice since I ran both of these cells,
now it's at 203.
So you can go ahead and check out the Jupyter Notebook
for some other examples.
So for instance, if I wanted to do a self-subtraction,
I just do minus equals and then the number
I want to subtract itself from.
You can also do multiplication equals and
then division equals as well.
Great.
So that's just a nice syntax so you don't waste a
lot of time rewriting the same object over and over again.
So I can just say minus equal and then 120 here
in this case.
Alright, so moving along, we can also create keys
by assignment.
So for instance, if we started off with an empty
dictionary, we could continually add to it.
So I'll show you what I mean by that.
I'm going to make a label or a variable called d
and I'm going to create an empty dictionary.
And I can create an empty dictionary just by putting
curly brackets with nothing inside them.
So d is now just an empty dictionary.
So the way I can create a new key is through assignment.
And the way I do that is I can say d, and we'll have
the key be called animal in this case, and I'll
set it equal to a value.
In this case, I'll have it be equal to Dog.
And we can do this for any type of objects.
I could say again d, answer for a key, and I can set
this equal to 42, for instance.
And now if I check out what my dictionary looks like,
I've actually added in those keys and the values
associated with them.
So this is how you can add new keys and new values
to your dictionary through this sort of assignment.
Okay, so now we'll look into nesting with dictionaries.
So hopefully you've seen right now that Python is
super flexible with nesting objects and calling
methods on them.
So now we're going to look at a quick example
of a dictionary nested inside a dictionary.
So you remember we were able to nest lists.
So we can actually do the same thing with dictionaries.
So I could say d is equal to, and we'll make say k1
be one of the keys, colon, and in this case, that k1 key
is going to refer to another dictionary.
So let me close off that first dictionary,
and now I'm going to have another dictionary.
I'm going to call this key nestkey, and to show you
how deep we could go, we could even create another
dictionary inside that one and then say like
subnestkey, colon, and then let's just put a string
in called value there.
And you notice this is almost like quite an inception
of dictionaries, so how can we grab that value,
this string right here?
How do we go about doing that?
So first off, I have my dictionary, and my dictionary
actually only consists of one key, k1, this most
outer dictionary, and the rest of it is just
dictionaries nested inside.
So if I say d, k1, what does that return?
That returns those two nested dictionaries.
So I can go again and say nestkey off of that
return dictionary, and now I have that subnestkey
in that value.
And then one more time, I can say subnestkey,
and finally I get out that value.
And then again I can call different methods on it.
So I could say upper, and then it returns
a capitalised version of value.
So hopefully you can see just how powerful nesting
with dictionaries could be within your code.
So you're probably never going to go this deep
for basic codes, but it is really useful to go
at least one nest deep as you get better
at programming.
Okay, so what we're going to do now is go over
a few of the dictionary methods that are built in.
So let's go ahead and create a new dictionary.
I'm actually going to call an empty dictionary
to go over how we can construct it again.
So let's say k1 is equal to 1.
I'll say d of key 2, so k2 is equal to 2.
And then I'll make one more key, and I'll have its
associated value be 3.
And now if I check out what my d, that dictionary,
is equal to, it's equal to k1 of 1, k2 2, k3 3.
Great.
So now I have my full mapping where I have three keys,
k1, k2, k3, and then three values associated
with each of those keys, 1, 2, and 3 respectively.
So there's different methods.
If I put d, and since I'm using Jupyter Notebook,
I can actually click tab, and these are a bunch
of the different methods that are available to us
for dictionaries.
You can go ahead and check out the advanced dictionaries
lecture if you want to learn about all of them.
But in this case we're going to look
at some of the basic ones.
So for instance, d.keys, closed parentheses since I'm
not adding in any arguments there, will actually return
a list of all the keys.
And there's a similar method for the values
in the dictionary.
d.values will return all the values.
And you notice here they're out of order from what
we originally printed out that dictionary.
And that's important to note because remember
dictionaries are never going to hold a specific order.
Since they're mappings, the way they keep track of things
is through the keys and the value combinations.
So there's no such thing as indexing a mapping.
So we could index lists and strings since those
are sequences, but we can't index a dictionary.
What we'd have to do is call things by its key.
So it's not a direct index of like d zero, d one, etc.
You're referencing things by their keys.
Okay, so we have d.keys method to grab a list
of all the keys, d.values to grab a list
of all the values.
And if you wanted a combination of those,
we can say d.items, and that will return a list,
something called tuples or sometimes called tupples,
of all the items.
So if you notice here we have a list and we have this
notation of these parentheses that are all the pair combos.
So we'll learn about tupples, or tuples,
in an upcoming lecture.
And that's about it as far as just this beginner's
introduction to dictionaries.
So let's just go over everything we covered
in this lecture really quickly.
Remember dictionaries are mappings in Python.
They are different than sequences because they don't
retain any order, so we refer to the values or the
objects within that dictionary through their keys.
In order to construct a dictionary, we use this
curly bracket notation with the key name, a colon,
and then the value name.
And then we can call values by their keys using
that bracket notation.
Continuing along, dictionaries are super flexible
in the data types they can hold.
For instance, here I have a list inside of a dictionary,
numbers, we can have dictionaries inside of dictionaries,
and then you can call items from that dictionary,
and then index our methods on those values as well.
So we also learned about this quick notation
of self-subtraction or addition.
Remember we could do that minus equals instead
of doing something like this, which was that object
self-reference minus, so that should save you
some time with you're coding.
And then to create a new dictionary, you can create
new keys through assignment just like we did here
with that equal sign sort of assignments,
and then here's the result.
You can nest dictionaries.
We went over that.
And keep calling the keys to go further and further
in those nests.
And then we went over a few dictionary methods,
the keys, the values, and then items.
So hopefully by now you have a good basic understanding
of how to construct dictionaries.
There's a lot more to go into here, but we'll be
constantly revisiting dictionaries throughout
the lectures.
Alright, great.
So let's go ahead and move on to the next lecture.