Hello everyone, in this lecture we're gonna
go quickly through the solutions of the
Advanced Python Objects Test.
Okay, so first one you had to do is use bin and hex
functions in order to do these conversions.
After that you had to use the round function,
in order to round.
Problem three I was expecting you to use the is lower method
and then similarly in problem four it was another method,
first string count and then w.
Advanced sets, the methods here were difference
for problem five, and union for problem six.
Advanced dictionaries, this one might have been tough if
you didn't see the pattern.
And also dictionary comprehension in general is
a little strange, but this was the solution for the
dictionary comprehension, it was just cubing all
those numbers, and the key was the number,
the value was the number cubed.
Okay, advanced lists hopefully these were pretty
straightforward, should have been just
from the problem itself,
reverse and sort.
Okay, so that's just quick overview,
go ahead and check out the Jupiter notebook if
you wanna see the code yourself.
Okay, thanks everyone.