Hello everyone and welcome
to the StringIO Module lecture.
So this is going to be a very brief lecture
on what the StringIO module actually does,
and then I'll let you go ahead and explore
the documentation in Jupiter notebook if you feel
the need to ever use StringIO in your code.
StringIO is sometimes confusing to beginners,
but the best way to think about it is StringIO
module basically implements an in-memory file like object,
and I'm actually not going to do any live code,
I'm just going to walk through the Jupiter notebook here.
And then this object can then be used as input or output
to most functions that would expect a standard file object.
So the best way to show this is by simple example.
So here you see an imported StringIO,
and then create an arbitrary string with some message
that says 'this is just a normal string'.
Now what you're seeing is that I can use StringIO,
and then you use the dot StringIO method in order
to create a file object out of a string.
And we set as the variable F,
and then you can actually perform
like read and write
so you can treat that object F,
just like you'd be able to treat a file,
so you say F dot read, F dot write, F dot seek,
all those things we learned back when we were dealing with
files in Python in the very beginning of this course.
So that's really all there is to it.
You can basically just convert strings
and be able to read and write to them
as if they were files.
So you can go ahead and check out the link here
to the rest of the documentation,
there's quite a few methods and there's also
a faster C StringIO which is just a C implementation
of StringIO, which will be faster and it provides
similar interface just to the StringIO.
So go ahead and check those out
in case you ever need them in your code,
but I can't think of any examples for you
as far as typical code usage.
Usually when you're just are using StringIO
it has to do with scraping from the web and trying to read
strings from the web as files,
so that's where you'll see it come into play
during your code.
Okay, so that's it for StringIO,
I will go ahead and see you at the next lecture.
Thanks everyone.