In the module on writing testable code,
I mentioned how tests can be used as a means of documenting a system's behavior.
In this module,
we will explore in depth into how we can leverage automated tests into
writing living documentation on a system we write.
But before we do,
let's once again understand the problems with the
status quo way of documenting systems.
So we have all been there.
Long days, and possibly even nights,
working to crank out a new application or feature.
Finally, after a couple of failed deploys,
an all-nighter or two, you have finally pushed code to production.
After the first couple of inevitable bug releases,
your manager asks you to write up documentation on how the new
application or feature you have just written works.
This is perhaps one of the least liked, most often over looked,
and in some ways, most difficult step in a development cycle.
How do you explain all the lessons learned from writing the application?
How do you remember them?
How can you explain what a successful transaction looks like?
How about conditions under which a transaction should be declined?
How can this be written in a concise enough manner so the next
developer will be interested in reading it?
Beyond that, how long will this documentation even remain valid?
The documentation might be somewhat accurate right now,
but what about a year from now?
Two years from now?
In my near decade of experience as a developer,
documentation generally has been suspect at best.
Perhaps a general summation of the goal of a system or feature is documented,
but how to interact with the system is often left undocumented,
or the examples are out of date.
And if there are examples, it's typically only happy-path examples,
and don't cover edge cases.
This is where automated testing can come in.
Automated testing can help with documenting a system in two ways.
The first is writing tests so that other developers can easily read them,
and from the test, learn how the system works.
The first step is giving tests names that accurately
describe the scenario being executed.
This helps other developers understand the intent of the test.
Within the test itself, particularly if the test is somewhat complex,
it can be good to add comments within the test that make clear the
distinction between setting up the preconditions of the scenario,
the code that is being executed,
and what is being checked after the test has been run,
or given, when, then.
What is also particularly helpful about using tests as documentation is,
when a test fails,
it gives clear indication that the "documentation" is out of date.
This will tell the developer either the documentation,
the test, needs to be updated, or some unintended change was added to the code.
Either way, once the test is fixed,
the documentation is again back in sync with the code.
The second way automated tests can help with documentation is using tests to
directly generate documentation in a more traditional format.
While having descriptive test cases is helpful for developers,
it doesn't cover all the documentation requirements.
If you're developing a RESTful API,
providing publicly accessible documentation on how to interact with
the API can be very helpful for potential clients.
We will also be looking at how to produce documentation
from acceptance tests that can be helpful for ensuring
business requirements are being met.
Just like with directly reading tests though,
when test fails, the documentation doesn't update either.
This gives confidence that when tests are passing,
your documentation is an accurate representation of the system being documented.
While descriptive tests and producing documentation from your tests
won't cover the entirety of documentation requirements,
it will cover a significant portion.
And as mentioned,
the documentation provided will also be in sync with the system.
Using tests as documentation is also a further way of
increasing the value of tests being written.
Instead of just verifying the system meets business
requirements and detecting regressions, valuable in their own right,
tests can now help future developers and coworkers
understand a system you wrote.
During this module,
we'll look at tools and methodologies that will help make
tests more descriptive and easier to read, and how to produce documentation directly from the tests we write.