Hey, this is Billy with Pluralsight,
and we are looking at how to write effective automated tests in Spring.
In the previous module,
we learned one of the biggest impediments to writing
automated tests is poorly designed code.
When classes have too many responsibilities,
or when they don't have a way of abstraction from their dependencies,
test complexity and maintenance costs rise sharply,
to the point where automated tests no longer provide enough value to
justify the time spent writing and maintaining them.
In this module,
we will learn how the patterns and practices covered in the previous
module allow for the easy injection of mock dependencies,
and how to leverage these mock dependencies to test the
business behavior of our application.
During this module,
we will take a closer look at the key characteristics and goals of unit testing.
We will look at the different types of mocks and
when and where they should be used,
have a brief overview of the demo application we will
be building during this course, learn about test-driven development,
or TDD, and finally,
run through a few scenarios of modifying our application and adding new features to it.