Hey, this is Billy with Pluralsight,
and we are looking at how to write effective automated tests with Spring.
So far in this course,
we have been learning about how to structure our code to make it easier to test,
and learning how to effectively unit test our code.
Now we're going to go a little bit deeper and start testing some of
the more difficult areas of our code to get into,
such as security testing, how our application handles JSON,
or if we are using aspects, for example,
to help with logging.
Luckily for us,
Spring provides a lot of excellent tools for testing
these parts of our application,
and we're going to be learning about them in this module.
Our agenda for this module will be defining component integration testing,
what are its goals, and what separates it from unit testing.
Using Spring and Spring Boot testing utilities,
we will take a look at testing several different layers of our
application including testing our RESTful APIs,
testing the data layer, and security testing.
We will also look at how to test JSON marshalling and unmarshalling, and testing aspects as well.