As this course draws to a close,
let's take a look at what we have learned and some
resources for additional learning.
The first and most important thing I hoped you learned is that
automated testing is a critical step when writing software.
Automated testing isn't an afterthought to be completed if you have time
near the end of a project or after you've fixed a bug,
but can be a helpful guide during development,
allowing for rapid feedback as you build a feature or fix a bug.
Automated tests also help development teams maintain
their cadence over the long term,
as automated tests help guard against introducing bugs into production.
We also learned one of the biggest impediments to writing tests is
that the code we write is often difficult to test.
To that end,
following SOLID principles can help guide you towards
writing software that is easy to test.
Keeping classes relatively simple and focused,
using interfaces between higher-level classes and low-level
implementations allows for the easy swapping of mock
implementations with real implementations.
Passing in dependencies through constructors instead of as
fields all greatly help in easing the burden of both
writing and maintaining tests.
While unit testing is often the first thing thought
of when writing automated tests, it is important to test underlying libraries,
as well as integration with external services.
Testing underlying libraries allows you to keep up with the
latest features and security patches.
Integration testing with external services ensures you don't run into issues of,
it ran on my machine.
Finally, we learned that tests can be used as documentation,
and that can help further increase the value of a test we write.
Tests aren't just a sunk cost,
but can provide ongoing value by documenting how
areas of code will behave when used.
We also looked at tools that can retest and then write out
documentation they can then share with interested parties.
For additional learning, I would recommend checking out these resources.
My friend Josh Long produces a video series called Spring Tips,
which are short videos on how to use various Spring Tools and libraries.
This is a good general resource for learning about Spring,
and he's occasionally covered testing subjects as well.
If you find yourself in the C# world,
I would highly recommend watching the Effective C# Unit Testing for
Enterprise Applications course here on Pluralsight.
Petri Kainulainen, I believe that is the correct pronunciation,
has a blog that focuses squarely on testing in Java,
that I have found very helpful in the past.
Finally, I would recommend checking out my company's blog.
I will be writing a series of blog articles covering topics I
didn't have a chance to get to during the video,
or going into more depth on a couple of other topics I do cover.
If you've found this video interesting,
I would highly recommend also following my blog series as well.
Producing this course has been an incredible learning experience for me.
I can honestly say I have taken many lessons I have
learned or covered during this course,
and been able to apply them directly to my day-to-day
job that has made my life easier.
I hope you learn as much from this course as I have,
and what you learn helps you code better. Thanks for watching.