Like other types of testing,
system integration testing has its own unique set of goals and characteristics.
It's important to understand what they are to help ensure that
applications we develop have proper automated test coverage.
In doing so,
we are able to deliver on the goals of automated testing
that verify the correctness of code, document how our system behaves,
and detecting regressions.
Earlier in this course, I introduced the testing pyramid.
In this module,
we are getting near the top of the pyramid in
covering system integration testing.
So what is system integration testing?
Well as the name suggests,
it is testing how applications and services communicate,
or integrate, with one another.
With that, there are two major goals of integration testing,
validating contracts and testing specific failure scenarios.
To get an idea of what I mean for the first goal, let's play through a scenario.
So we have our customer service and order service.
The customer service talks to the order service through a few endpoints,
GET:/orders/id, POST:/orders, and GET:/orders/customer/id/history.
These services are deployed to prod, or some environment,
and generally communication is going fine.
Calls to GET:/orders/id work.
Calls to POST:/orders id work.
However, when customer service calls orders/customer/id/history,
we get a failure.
This is odd.
You go to the customer service code and look at where
it's calling orders/customer/id/history.
Well that looks fine.
You go to your test, you run the test, and they pass.
Okay, so customer service is fine.
You go and look and the order service and how its endpoints are set up.
Well, those look fine as well.
Again then, we go to look at the unit test for order service.
We run a test, and it too returns green.
Well this is really weird.
The code looks fine, the tests are passing, but our code is failing.
This is a classic case of unit testing your code,
but not integration testing your code.
While it's important when unit testing, and even component integration testing,
to keep chunks of code we are testing isolated,
we mustn't forget that our code will eventually have to
communicate with outside sources.
So we need to write tests that actually simulate such behavior.
If you are watching closely,
you might have already noticed what the issue is in my example.
While the customer service was calling orders/customer/id/history,
order service actually named the endpoint order/customer/id/histories.
So this is the first goal of integration testing, validate contracts.
So what exactly do I mean when I say validate contracts?
Well as in the given example,
one part of that would be validating an endpoint and our addresses.
This doesn't merely mean resting points or something over HTTP,
but could also mean a database table name for example.
A second element of validating contracts would be validating shapes.
This would mean validating fields, field names, and the format of fields.
Is a name of a field first name or FName, for example?
Or, like from the JSON example in the Component Testing module,
how a date field is being represented.
Another element of validating contracts would be security requirements.
When calling another service,
is a consumer passing the correct security information,
and is a producer properly checking for security?
These are some of the major elements of contract validation,
but is by no means all inclusive; however,
remember, we are validating contracts, not specific scenarios.
So when validating a field, say a phone number field,
you'll want to test that the field is a string,
all the characters are numeric, and there are exactly 10 characters,
rather than looking for a specific phone number.
Doing the former helps to keep tests more maintainable should test data change.
It also better communicates the requirements of the field.
While I just spent a lot of time talking about
high-level testing with validating contracts,
there's another element of integration testing that goes against that wisdom.
At a previous client, I wrote a workhorse management service.
This service of course worked great and had quite good unit test coverage.
The service also talked with a database.
And most of the time,
this service happily communicated with the database sending SQL queries.
Until, of course, it didn't, and it brought down my service.
At a high level,
the issue I was running into was the database my service was talking to
would occasionally be brought down for maintenance; however,
even after the database was brought back up,
my service couldn't successfully call the database.
The problem was,
my data source wasn't dumping connections from the connection pool that failed.
The fix was relatively simple; however,
an integration test simulating this scenario would be necessary,
as a unit test couldn't give the appropriate
confidence that the issues remain fixed.
So the two major goals of integration testing are to validate
contracts and to test failure scenarios.
But how can we be more effective at it?
Well historically there have been two major difficulties
when it comes to integration testing.
One of them is it's time consuming to write and run integration tests.
Even if you're being good when it comes to validating contracts,
it can still be time consuming to find and/or create test data.
It can be time consuming to run integration tests as well.
It might mean rebuilding an entire database,
scheduling time with a shared resource,
or being forced to deploy code to an environment to run
integration tests because it wouldn't be practical to
recreate an environment on a local machine.
Another common issue with integration testing is that they can be unreliable.
A shared resource could go down, test data may no longer be valid,
or someone might incidentally change test data,
causing your test to break.
These issues lead integration tests to not being written,
or ignored when they failed.
Either way, confidence is lost in the automated test process.
The good news is,
there have been some tools developed fairly recently that
have made integration tests easier to write,
more portable, more reliable, execute faster,
and more flexible.
And during this module,
we will take a look at two of these tools which can be used to cover a wide variety of integration testing needs.