A very hot topic in the tech industry, possibly over-hyped,
is containerization, particularly using Docker.
If you haven't heard about containerization or Docker,
you're among the few; however,
before I can cover how to use TestContainers to
help in writing integration tests,
I want to give a brief introduction to containers,
and Docker as a means to level set.
To get an idea of what containerization is,
let's first figure out the problem it is attempting to address.
Out on a server, we have our customer service deployed.
Our customer service, being a Java application,
of course depends upon Java being installed on the server as well,
in this case, JDK 8.
Eventually, the order service is also deployed out onto the server as well.
Order service is a Java application as well, and it's compatible with Java 8.
So everything works without issue.
Sometime later, the order service starts making use of Java 9 features,
and so needs the version of Java running on the server updated.
Upgrading the version of Java running on the server could introduce bugs
to any application that has not been tested with it,
like customer service.
This is doubly so with Java 9 as it introduces modularity and
several other breaking changes to Java.
Docker seeks to address this problem by encapsulating
applications within their own containers.
Now order service can safely upgrade to Java 9 without
risk of breaking customer service,
and customer service can continue using whatever
version of Java that best suites it.
Containerization isn't just limited to applications though.
Even other services, like databases, can be containerized as well.
If this all sounds pretty similar to virtual machines, the comparison is apt.
What separates containerization tools like Docker from
traditional VMs is that they have lower overhead both in
terms of storage and performance.
This makes containerizing individual applications much more
practical than it might have been in the past.
What has further fueled the growth and popularity of Docker and other
containerization options is a tooling that has been built around them.
A container can be created,
and then easily shared by placing the image of the container in a repository,
which in the case of Docker is called Docker Hub.
Now other developers can pull down the Docker image and use the service
without having to go through the possibly difficult and time-consuming task
of configuring their machine to run the service.
This is where TestContainers comes in.
TestContainers is a library for easily using Docker
containers directly in your JUnit test.
TestContainers makes use of JUnit rules to wire up and
incorporate Docker containers within JUnit tests.
The TestContainers team has created some pre-built
containers for common services, like in this example,
connecting to a MySQL database.
The MySQLContainer class has several convenient methods for
performing common database operations like getting the username
and password for creating a connection,
as well as some other behaviors like special database
drivers that can be set up to execute initialization scripts
when connecting to the container.
Of course,
there might be cases in which the Docker image you want to use isn't
one that the TestContainer team natively supports.
In this situation,
you can use a generic container class to wire in the
Docker container into your JUnit test. In the next section, we will take a hands-on look at using TestContainers.