Most any web application at some point interacts with a database.
Information about a customer, order,
or something else of business value is persisted to the
database so it can be retrieved later.
A company's data is among its most valuable of assets,
and so like anything else,
it is critical to ensure data is being stored and retrieved properly.
As of Spring Boot 1.
4, it's gotten a lot easier with the addition of some new test utilities.
During this demo,
we will take a look at Spring Boot test tools to test the data layer.
We will also verify Spring Data's query builder functionality.
In the Customer class,
we have added some JPA annotations to handle the persistence and
retrieval of customer entities from the database.
We also added an annotation telling the data store to handle
the generation of IDs for the ID field.
This is a very standard JPA implementation.
Over in our repo, we are using Spring Data to handle all the JPA work.
We are extending a standard CrudRepository,
which as the name implies, stands up a repository with create,
read, update, and delete functionality.
We will test some of the read functionality in our test class.
We have also added a look-up call.
Spring Data has a domain-specific language,
so based on this method's signature, findCustomersByFirstNameAndLastName,
Spring Data will automatically build a method that
implements a call to the customers table,
looking up a customer by first name and last name.
In our test class,
we will add the RunWith SpringRunner annotation and the DataJpaTest annotation.
The DataJpaTest annotation was added in Spring Boot 1.
4 as well.
DataJpaTest stands up the data layer of your Spring Boot application.
It also provides a test entityManager,
which makes testing the JPA layer of your application much easier.
Our first test, testFindAllCustomers,
will test Spring Data's findAll functionality of the customer repo.
In the test,
we will use Test entityManager to simulate any customer to a database.
Next, we will actually make a call to the customer repo to find all customers.
For asserting,
we want to ensure the customer we just added is
faithfully returned from the repo.
We also want to make sure an ID is being generated.
Finally, we will want to ensure only one customer is being returned.
Running this test returns green,
so it looks like everything here is behaving as intended.
In testFindCustomersByFNameAndLName,
we will be testing the look-up call we added to customer repo.
This time we will want to add several items to make sure only the
item that matches the look-up value is returned.
The asserting for this test is pretty similar to what
we did with the findAll test case.
Running this test also returns green.
This is only scratching the surface of database testing,
but this should give a good start to some of the tools Spring Boot provides for database testing.