In the previous section, we learned about Docker and TestContainers.
In this section,
we will step through a demo of using TestContainers to
do integration testing on a database.
We will also review the plugins Maven uses for executing automated tests,
and how we might leverage them so we can get feedback
from our automated test suite faster.
Here in ITCustomerRepo,
I'm setting up a test to verify that my application can connect to a database.
In this case, a Postgres database.
At the top of the test,
I am customizing how I'm setting up this Spring context for this
test with a ContextConfiguration annotation.
In the Initializer class, I'm setting up a data source.
If you're not familiar,
a big concept within Spring Boot is convention over configuration.
Rather than having to go through the rigmarole of
configuring a database connection, if you follow the naming standard of spring.
datasource, Spring Boot will take the values and create a data source for you.
So this is how I'm setting up a data source for this test.
Within the URL of the data source connection, I have an initialization script.
For the username and password,
I am having TestContainers provide that information.
In order to have the initialization script run when I connect to a database,
I must use a special testcontainers ContainerDatabase connection driver.
I do this for convenience and simplicity in this test; however,
in a more real-world scenario,
instead of using the default Postgres container TestContainers uses,
or whatever database you're connecting to,
instead you would use the Docker image of your database.
This would be done by passing in the name of the Docker image into the
constructor of the test container you are using.
This Docker image would ideally have a preconfigured version of your database.
This would give increased confidence that the integration test
you're running is reflective of how the application would
interact with the database in production.
That sidebar aside, we have set up our Spring Container to run our test.
Below,
I am using a ClassRule to have TestContainers set up the Postgres container.
Finally,
I am verifying that I can successfully call and retrieve data from the database.
Let's go to run this test.
That took a little time to run, about 15 seconds,
a little longer than the usual time of when I've run this of 12 to 13 seconds.
Regardless, this has returned green.
Let's look at how we can leverage Maven to help us
with long-running integration tests.
You likely noticed I named this class ITCustomerRepo.
IT in this case stands for integration test.
Within Maven, there are two commonly used plugins for executing automated tests.
There is a surefire plugin for running unit tests,
which would have covered all the tests we have written in the
modules on Leveraging Dependency Injection,
and component integration testing with Spring tools.
And there is the failsafe plugin for running integration tests.
So why are there two plugins for running automated tests?
So unit tests are heavily isolated,
which make them very liable and also overall they should execute quickly.
While TestContainers helps to greatly increase the
reliability of our integration tests, we won't,
for example, have to worry about a development database being down,
they still aren't executing all that fast.
While the about 15 seconds it took to run that test might not seem so slow,
it can add up in aggregates.
If I run all 18 tests in this application, it takes about 16 seconds to run.
So just the one integration test made up about 80% of the time
spent executing this entire test suite if we're going by the more
common 12 to 13 seconds it takes to run.
If we were to add more integration tests to our test suite,
such as for connecting to a cache,
and perhaps an integration test that recreates a failure scenario,
it won't be long before it takes several minutes to run our entire test suite,
most of that time being running integration tests.
That might not seem so bad,
but it really starts to add up if you're wanting to
run these tests very frequently.
This is where the two plugins come in.
Using Maven,
we could just execute our fast-running unit test to get fast
feedback on the changes we are making, while executing integration tests,
perhaps only before we check our code in,
or having the ability to execute them.
Additionally,
the failsafe plugin has the pre-integration and post-integration tests spaces.
These spaces, as the name suggests,
offers opportunities for setting up and tearing down
an integration test environment.
And by default,
the reason why we named ITCustomerRepo that name is because the failsafe plugin,
by default, looks for IT as a prefix for integration tests.
If we run Maven install, we can see both of these plugins in action.
After compiling the code, Maven executes the unit test.
As can be seen, they execute quite quickly.
If all the unit tests pass, Maven will then execute the integration test. With all the tests passing, the Maven build is successful.