Security testing is a critical aspect to get right in any application.
Even if your application is not handling sensitive
information or is behind a firewall,
you want to ensure that only authorized users are accessing your application,
as this helps add layers to your security infrastructure or
helps protect your applications against denial-of-service
attacks and other malicious behavior.
Spring Security is a fantastic library for implementing
security in your Spring application; however,
security testing isn't the easiest thing to do.
In this section,
we're going to take a look at some of the utilities Spring
provides to make the process of testing your application's
security infrastructure easier.
In the SecurityConfig class,
I more set up a test configuration than anything you would
see in a real production application.
But because of how widely varying and complex security configuration can be,
trying to create a security configuration that mimics
something that would be seen in production wouldn't really
mess with the goals of this course.
In the SecurityConfig,
I have simply set it up to make sure the users hitting the
different endpoints have their proper roles.
In TestCustomerControllerSecurity,
we will verify if our security configuration is behaving as intended,
and verify some of Spring Security's default behaviors
for when security violations occur.
TestCustomerControllerSecurity is set up pretty
similarly to TestCustomerController.
Here, however, we are obviously keeping security turned on,
and we are pulling in the SecurityConfig class.
In FindAllCustomersWithNoUser,
we will validate that Spring Security will return a 401 if no authentication
information is sent in a request to a secured endpoint.
Running the test gives us the expected green.
In testFindAllCustomersWithInvalidUser, a user is being sent,
but does not have any roles.
In this situation, Spring Security should return a 403 forbidden,
instead of a 401.
Again, running this test returns the expected green.
In testFindAllCustomersWithUserWhoDoesntHaveRightRole,
we have a valid user and a valid role in the system; however,
the role being passed in doesn't match the role required for the endpoint.
At this point,
this test is more about validating if security
configuration is set up correctly,
which is important as the only way to test this effectively is by
standing up at least part of the Spring container.
Again, we get a green result.
Finally, we will want to do the happy path and testFindAllCustomersWithValidUser,
passing in a valid user with a valid role,
and we get green here as well.
Like other areas of testing, this only scratches the surface of security testing,
but serves as an introduction of the tools Spring Boot provides for testing in this area.