JSON has quickly become the defacto standard for
communicating between client and server over HTTP.
JSON is a lightweight and human readable standard,
which is why it has become so popular; however,
ensuring that a JSON message is properly formed for
consuming in our application,
or our application is properly producing a JSON message,
raises some interesting challenges.
Within the Spring framework,
the default library used for handling the marshalling
and unmarshalling of JSON is Jackson.
Like with other areas of testing covered in this module,
we want to ensure that as we upgrade the version of
Jackson our project depends upon,
we are not inadvertently introducing bugs or behavior changes.
Let's take a look at how some of the utilities Spring
provides to aid in JSON testing.
In this demo, we will be testing parsing a JSON string to an object,
converting an object to a JSON string,
test that JSON enforces required fields properly,
and finally test that Jackson ignores extra fields in a JSON string.
Let's look again at the customer class.
At the top of the class, we have the JsonIgnoreProperties set to true.
This annotation tells Jackson to ignore any fields it doesn't
recognize when deserializing a JSON string.
A little further down, the dateOfLastStay field,
as can be seen, is a date field.
By default, when serializing this field,
JSON will convert the date to milliseconds from epoch; however,
such a format isn't very human readable.
So to make it easier to read,
I added the JsonFormat field to print out a prettier date.
In the all argument constructor for the class,
I annotate it with the JsonCreator annotation,
telling Jackson to use this constructor when deserializing a JSON string.
I also annotated the arguments of the constructor to claim
required fields and the name of the field in JSON.
Note that simulating a legacy issue, the dateOfLastStay,
is actually represented lastStayDate in JSON.
Following up with that,
the get for dateOfLastStay must also annotated so that when
serializing a customer class to a JSON string,
it also prints the dateOfLastStay field as lastStayDate.
Alright, so our customer class is exercising a good bit of Jackson functionality,
let's write some tests to make sure if any of this
behavior changes between versions of Jackson,
we catch it.
In TestCustomerJsonSerializing, yet another Spring Boot 1.
4 feature is adding the JacksonTester tool.
As its name suggests,
it makes testing Jackson easier by providing convenient
shorthand for marshalling and unmarshalling JSON.
Our first test, testValidFullCustomerParseJson,
is going to serialize a JSON customer message to a customer object.
In the test method,
we will create a customer object that is equivalent
to what is in the JSON string.
We will then use JacksonTester to verify the values are equivalent,
and we get back green.
The next test, testValidFullCustomerMarshallObjectToJson,
is essentially just the inverse of this,
verifying that we can take an object and convert it to
the JSON string we've just used.
This might seem redundant,
but it's how I knew I needed to add the annotations of the
dateOfLastStay field to the constructor and the getter.
So once again, this test returns green.
The next test, testCustomerMissingRequiredField,
is verifying that if a JSON message is missing a required field,
Jackson throws an exception.
In the test, the JSON message is missing the first name field,
which is required, and we get green when we run the test.
Note it's important to include the fail on this test as well.
If Jackson stops throwing an exception, we want to know it.
If the fail wasn't there, the test would still return it as green.
The last test, testCustomerIgnoreExtraField,
is verifying Jackson ignores extra fields.
Pretty similar to above, just with the fail moved into the catch block.
Once again, we get green.
So now these tests should give us good confidence that as
we upgrade our Jackson dependencies, we are not introducing any new or unexpected behaviors.