In this module, we covered the goals of system integration testing.
Integration testing makes up a key aspect of testing an application,
microservice or otherwise.
While unit testing can cover a significant number of test cases and
roughly makes up the majority of automated tests run,
integration testing is key to ensuring that all
parts of a system can work together.
During this module,
we also learned about some of the tools that have made the
process of integration testing not only easier,
but more reliable.
Instead of having to depend upon deployed instances of
a service being in a useful state,
tools like test container allow instances of services to be spun up on demand,
and tools like Spring Cloud Contract allow a simulation of services as well.
And the use of contracts can validate that those services will
actually communicate when deployed in an environment.
These tools help make integration testing not only much faster to run,
allowing them to be run more often, but also much more reliable,
allowing test failures to be taken more seriously instead of being excused as a result of system instability or similar other such excuses.