Welcome to another module.
So we already covered a lot
and now in this module, I want to touch on a very important topic which is key to develop successful
Javascript applications.
Now which topic might that be? Errors and debugging. When you write your code,
you will get errors,
that's just a normal thing,
you won't write perfect code all the time. So you will have some nasty bugs
and in order to find them, you will have to debug or you also might have parts in your program where
you can't control if you will eventually get an error or something like this, in such a case you need a
built-in way to handle errors. In this module,
we'll have a look at both things.
I'll start with the debugging and for this, I'm here in my editor, Web Storm because I need to create
a local project but no worries,
it's really simple.
I'll only create two files here,
the first one will be an index.html file
and here I'll just create a very basic HTML5 skeleton
where I have my doctype, my HTML
tag, my head section here and my body and I won't write any HTML code
besides that, all I will do is later I'll import a script file, a script file I'm creating now.
So I'm just creating my script.js file file and in this file, I'll copy
some prepared code.
Now of course, you'll find the code attached to this lecture,
that's for sure.
So this will be the code and
all I'm doing here is I'm setting some variables or initializing some variables here, then I have
a for loop where I mess around with my values here and reassign some of them or assign them for the
first time, like C for example and then I log them all, so
not a really useful program but great for demonstrating how you can debug your applications
with various tools.
So in my index.html file,
I'll then just add a script tag and import
this file I just created, so the script.js file so that I'm loading it in my program. Next,
I will simply run it,
so load it in my browser and don't get confused
by the URL, it's just a little service of Web Storm, it's like hosting a little mini server here
but you may just open your HTML file in your browser,
so just right clicking on it in the explorer for example or double clicking and auto executing it, so
just run this file in your browser.
Now you won't see anything here of course because it's just an empty page
and now the important part comes. I'm using Chrome here and Chrome has great developer tools built-in, you
might of course also use Firefox or Internet Explorer,
both of them also ship with developer tools,
however the part of showing here only refers to Chrome since I strongly recommend Chrome for development
because it really has a good support.
If you want to use another browser, simply look up how the developer tools there work. In general, developer
tools all share some basic functionalities
and I'll open up my developer tools here in Chrome by hitting command alt and I or control alt and I on Windows
and this will open up my developer tools here.
Now in these developer tools, you most likely start on the elements page in Chrome here where you can
see your HTML element, the various elements you've got there, so the HTML code or the DOM, you will
later come to that in the course and so on,
so that's not really the interesting part. Here
you'll see that we log something to the console and that of course is due to these four statements
here.
So our code is running which is great
but in order to debug the Javascript code, you can either click in Chrome, on this link here,
this shows which line and which file was responsible for this log
or you go to the sources tab here and then you will find the sources of your project
and if you don't see it there, simply hit reload one more time and you should see this script.js
file here.
So that's the script file and Chrome identified that this file is being imported and therefore run by
your index.html
file in this case.
So now you can see your code here
and that's great but you can do even more, for example you can click on multiple line numbers to set a breakpoint
.
Now the next time this script gets executed, the code execution will stop here and give you a chance
to have a look at the current values of the variables and so on during runtime
and I'll demonstrate this.
So I set a breakpoint on that if condition here
and I will reload my page.
Now you see I have this paused in debugger message here and the page hasn't finished loading, as you can also
see in the console where I'm currently not logging something,
these are still the old logs.
So now you can see, we're pausing here, this line is highlighted and here, you got
some interesting analysis.
You for example can analyze that your global scope, the window, has certain properties, quite a lot as
it is the window of course
and amongst them here you will also find your variables, a, b and so on.
So that is one thing, you can check your scopes
and if we would have a local scope here due to a function, you would see that here too.
You also see your breakpoints like the one we're pausing here and if we're here,
you can hover over your variables and you will see their current values,
for example the B is 5 or I is currently 0 because we're in the first iteration of this loop.
Now with these buttons here, you can now continue with the code execution.
You can either hit this blue play button here to resume script execution and let it run until
the end or the next breakpoint
or you can now step through it step-by-step or if you have a function call, even step into that call
so that you get into that function, instead of just returning or continuing with the return value and
have a look into that function.
So I can now click step over next function call and you will see that
now the blue line jumped to the next if statement.
Of course it didn't go into the if statement because the condition is not satisfied, I is 0, A is
2,
so I is not greater than A and therefore the condition already fails because with a boolean operator
which requires both conditions to be true and therefore it doesn't matter that the second
condition here would be true,
so I 0 is of course smaller than 5.
But the first one fails, therefore we get to the next if statement where we check if I is equal to 3.
That of course is also not the case since I is 0.
So we'll skip over this and start with the next loop round.
So we can now step into that, to not only skip over it and now we see I is 1. So we can go ahead,
click on this button all the time to get into it
and here you just see the various parts which are executed and now we see that I is 3 and A is 2.
So I is now greater than A and it's also still smaller than B,
so now we should get into this if statement and we do. So now C is still undefined because we haven't
finished this line yet
but if I click this button one more time, you'll see that now C is equal to 1000
and this is how you can check your code and check during runtime
what the values of your variables are.
You can even go ahead and I will show you this
if I add another breakpoint and
now click the play button to continue until the next breakpoint and I will remove this one simply
by clicking on it.
So now it stops here and the value of A currently is 2.
Well the cool thing is you can select A and then, you can either watch it to open up a new watcher
on the right here or to constantly track the value of A
or you can also evaluate in the console to print it
and now in the console, set A
equals 3, hit enter
and now A is set equal to 3
and if I continue, you see it get updated here and I also printed 3. So you can also change the values
during runtime, you cannot only watch them, you can also change them to simulate some other scenarios
for example.
So now I can just let this finish and now I will see the screen unlocks again and we finished the script
and this is a very useful tool to help debug your code and to find your errors
and one you will probably oftentimes use in your code or when creating your applications.