We covered a lot.
I hope you have a clear understanding of the different features Javascript offers, how they work
together and which power Javascript offers to you, how you can really enhance your applications or build
front-end focused applications with Javascript.
How you can interact with the user and the DOM, how you can change the structure of the page and overall,
how to work with Javascript.
Now what are the next steps you could take?
Well a good step of course is to dive deeper, to practice, to pick example applications,
think about what you might want to build and then try to build it with Javascript.
Also you might have a look at some of the libraries like jQuery or any other Javascript library
and of course, it's also a great idea to have a look at some of the Javascript frameworks, like for example
Angular 2 or ReactJS. You might also want to have a look at my ES6 bootcamp which will
teach you the new features introduced by ES6.
Whatever you do, I'll be happy to welcome you in any other future courses or lectures or whatever.
Have a great day,
bye.