What is a function? A function basically is some kind of enclosed code which you can execute whenever
you want, even multiple times.
So remember that before, whichever code you put here was executed immediately by the browser, whenever the
browser finds this code, be that in an imported file or directly in the index.html file, it will
directly execute the code.
Now we can create a function like this, with the function keyword and then the name of the function,
let's name it calc for calculate maybe,
then you have parentheses and then curly braces and now don't mistake these curly braces with the ones
we were using when creating an object. Curly braces generally just mean we're creating kind of a block
here which belongs together, so we can have multi-line statements in here which all belong to this
block,
that's all we do with these curly braces.
So inside these curly braces, we might write the logic this function should execute.
So I'll again write console log inside function here,
now what do you think will happen if I click run?
Nothing,
because even though the code gets executed instantly, functions don't get called automatically, that is
not really what functions are good for,
instead we have to call them, like this, using their name
and then with parentheses here. Now if I click run, you'll see inside function because now the function
gets executed.
Does it also get executed if I leave out the parentheses here?
No, nothing happens.
So the parentheses here are important to actually call a function
and as you later see, we can also do more with these parentheses than just define and call it. An interesting
thing is you can also use a function
if you define it after calling it.
So if I hit run now, you still see inside function
and here again, we have hoisting. Now with functions, unlike with variables,
it's not that uncommon to have function definitions like this one here after the usage,
so that is a fine behavior and you might actually used this in your code as well.
Now I'll put it back to the top anyways and I want to show you another way of creating such a function
.
So you can use the function keyword and then the name here
but another way to do exactly the same would be to create a variable, name it calc and assign it to a
function
but notice that now here, we don't have a name,
we just have function and then parentheses.
So now if I run this, what do you think we'll see?
We still see inside function but we also should now put a semicolon here because now, we're technically
creating a variable and we're assigning this function to this variable.
We can then still call the function with
calc and then parentheses,
so that doesn't change, it's just a different type of creating a function but we may use both types.
Now speaking of this, what do you think we'll see if I log the type of this function?
Notice that I don't have parentheses here, so I'm not executing the function,
I just want to refer to this function variable.
So if I hit run now, we see function,
so this is of type function and is the same true if I use the other way to create a function?
What do you think we'll see now?
This is also of type function.
So it is the same and it has this special function type in Javascript,
so it's a variable of type function here.
Now can I do the following,
create another function and assign the first function to it
but without parentheses here and then I try to execute another function, which should be this function
here, right?
I assign this function to this variable.
So if I now hit run, what do you think we'll see?
Well we'll see inside function because this works exactly in this way.
We're creating a new variable and we're just assigning it another variable and this variable happens
to be a function.
Now what happens if I use parentheses here,
what do you think we'll now see if I hit run?
Well now we get inside function but then we get an error
and the reason is we get inside function here because we're executing the function here
but then we're trying to assign the returned value to this new variable.
Now this function doesn't return anything,
it just executes some code,
therefore another function is now not set to this and therefore we correctly get the error that another
function is not a function, so we can't execute it.
So what is another function
if we log out another function here?
It's undefined because we're setting it to something which isn't there, we're setting it to the return
value of this function and as I said, this function doesn't return anything,
therefore we're returning nothing,
therefore it's undefined
and that's why we could not execute it like a function.