Now I cleaned this all up and I have a simpler constructor function here with a person.
The cool thing is you cannot only pass something like this where we already have starting values but
you might want to have a constructor function where you can pass a name and an age upon creation and you
would set this name equal to name and this age equal to age.
Notice that here of course, I don't have this since I'm referring to the arguments passed to this function
.
Remember, in the end this is a normal function so we can work inside it as we could work in any function.
Here I can then pass Max
and 27 and if I print this object to the console, guess what we will see? We'll see age and name being set because
this was set here in the constructor function
and this of course is a behavior
you'll often need, the chance to have a generic blueprint but fill it with different values for different
objects based on that blueprint.
So you could create a Max object and then create an Anna object here as well, using the same blueprint but with
different values
and then once you print both out to the console, you will of course see the differences but they're based
on the same blueprint here.