So what is this return value I'm talking of?
Well let's say I change this here to not print something out but instead, I want to return a string
and this is a common scheme because oftentimes, your functions will just do something and return a value
for the caller of the function to use,
I can return a value by adding the return keyword.
So now I'm just returning a string,
this is no variable assigned to a string or anything,
it's just a string.
So I'm returning this string here and then I'm assigning this returned value to another function which
now is not a function so maybe I should name it returned to make this less confusing.
So returned is now what this function calc returns, which again is the string.
So now if I print returned, what do you think we'll see?
Well of course we see inside function because now, I'm printing what this function returned to me, which
is this string.
Of course I could also return
a variable defined inside calc,
so return stringVar,
what do you think we'll see now?
We still get inside function because I haven't really changed anything,
I'm just using a variable inside this function which is perfectly fine and I may do that.
Now there is something special about the scope of this variable but I'll come back to this in one
of
the next lessons.
So I'm now returning stuff inside this function and that's cool
but sometimes, I also want to pass something into a function and not just return values,
I can do this by adding arguments here between the parentheses in my function definition.
So maybe, since this function is called calc, I want to calculate something, so I'll pass two numbers let's
say, number one and number two.
Now here, I'm not assigning any string variable but instead, I want to return let's say the addition of
number one and number two
and this is just the addition operator here of course.
So now, if I execute this, what do you think we'll see?
Well this might not have been straightforward but we get NaN,
the reason is we're still calling this function without passing any arguments here,
right, but we try to add the arguments we get and we return the result.
Now we did not get an error which would be the case in some other languages which is because we're calling
a function which expects arguments by not passing arguments
but what gets passed indirectly are two undefined numbers.
So technically we were adding undefined plus undefined which will, since we're doing a mathematical
operation here, result in an error and return NaN because we can't add undefined and undefined,
therefore we are returning this result which is not a number and then reprinting it,
this is why we see not a number here.
So to make this function call here more useful and not get not a number,
I will add arguments to it,
let's say 10 and 8 and I do this by simply specifying them here when I call the function separated with commas
.
If I now run this, what do you think we'll see? We get 18 because we're adding 10 and 8 inside this function
and returning the value which we then print here,
so now this works
What happens if I pass too many arguments, so if I pass one extra 10 here, what do you think we'll see
now? Well we still get 18 and the other argument is just ignored.
We don't get an error like we would get in other languages
but it's not getting used either
and now, what do you think happens
if I change this a bit and here, I create my variable named calculator and assign this to this calc function
but I'm not executing the function here
and then I log out
calculator 15 and 2.
What do you think we'll now get in the console here?
Well we get 17 because what I'm doing here is, I'm just assigning this function here to a new variable,
so
this variable is now also pointing to this function
and then I'm executing this function and I pass two arguments and therefore, I get back the addition
of the two arguments since I'm simply just executing this function here.
So that were the basics about functions and how you can use functions.
Now why would you use such functions?
Well as you already saw, functions allow you to enclose some code and you can of course call functions
more than once,
therefore it's a useful utility for repetitive tasks or more complex calculations or calculations or
code
you don't want to execute right at startup because remember, generally all your code will be executed
once the browser runs through it.