Now you also heard me say that you could use parent node instead of element.
So what's the difference here?
Well basically, all the DOM things you see here for example in the developer tools, in Chrome, are nodes
and the DOM consists of nodes, it's built up of nodes and some nodes happen to be elements as well,
so all the nodes created from HTML elements like these ones here or this one.
So these are then elements and not nodes or they are nodes but also elements.
So here, it really doesn't matter if you use parent node or parent element
since we're interested in the parent element anyways but the difference is parent node can also be some
things in the DOM which aren't HTML elements but if you're working with HTML elements and
you want to select an element, well then of course parent element for example here or whatever element
is the way to go instead of whatever node.