So that's why this can be tricky but it's not that tricky if you follow that key rule, it refers to whatever
calls this function,
so the part on the left of the dot.
You know how to bind a different value to this
but what you probably ask yourself, if I bind person here for example but imagine this function also
takes an argument, like a message and it would log out message
plus this for example, well how could we pass this message?
Well bind takes multiple arguments,
the first argument is always to what this should be bound but all the other arguments are the normal function
arguments
this function here, which in the end will refer to this one, expects to get.
So I could just say Hello there and if I run this,
and I should add parentheses here of course, if I run this, I get Hello
object object here of course because this refers to this object
but this is how I can pass arguments to a function to which I bound with this bind method here.
Another way would be to use call here,
still I would pass what this should refer to
and then my message but here, I don't need the extra parentheses here,
this instantly calls the method on its own.
So if I now click on run, you'll still see hello object object, so the main difference is
I don't have the extra parentheses,
that of course is not just a stylistic thing. With bind, you can bind the this value and use it later because
it's not called instantly, with call,
it is called instantly
and that might be the behavior you want.
You also get another method, apply.
It generally works exactly the same as call, it also calls the function immediately but you pass
the arguments not as a comma separated list of arguments but instead, as an array,
whatever you prefer,
this still works.
So bind, call and apply are the important helpers here which makes sure that your function you call uses
this in the right context and you're not using a this
you don't want to use.