Starting with the libraries, jQuery of course is a very important one and I can't imagine you haven't
heard of it.
It is Javascript,
it uses pure Javascript but it added many convenience functions, helpers and methods.
So jQuery almost is like its own language and it's sometimes mistaken for that but it is Javascript
at the end, just with a lot of helpers
and if you check out the documentation, you'll quickly learn where it helps you.
For example with Ajax which you saw in the Ajax module which makes it very easy to use with jQuery, for
example with accessing the DOM,
so selecting different elements or traversing through the DOM or manipulating the DOM, that is where jQuery
is really strong and where it will really help you
and why is that popular. Now using a library like jQuery is really simple,
one thing of course is learning it but there are a lot of tutorials out on that
and it is enough
content for its own course but installing it is really simple.
You for example on the jQuery homepage here, you would go to the download page and then you simply
download the version you want to use and you dump it into your project folder and then you add a script
import, tag script source and link to that folder
and of course you will see detailed explanations here on the jQuery page on how to do
this
but it is really simple.