Once you set up an object like this, you can of course also go ahead and change a property, for example
to Anna. If I now log this object to the console,
you
see that the name was now updated to Anna. So I can change properties after the object has been
created
and this of course is important because not all the time you have all the data you want to have in your
object right at the point where you create it, you want to be able to edit it later on maybe
and this is very well possible here.
It's time to show another important feature of objects, the greeting function here currently isn't that
interesting, we're just saying hello but we could introduce ourselves here, right?
So we could say Hello, I am and then name and then let's try out if this works,
not this greet. So I'm executing this function here,
now what do you think will show up on the console?
Hello, I'm JS Bin output. So JS Bin output here is basically the name of our global space here
in JSBin, it's the name of our window.
If I do this with age
years old for example and I run this, you'll get an error that age is not defined,
so with name it was just a coincidence that we have this global name variable by default
but age would give us an error because age is not defined.
Now you might say, it is defined,
we have it here, right?
Yes but if we access age like this, it's referring to a variable in the global scope.
Well this is no variable,
it's a property of this object, of this person object.
This is a different thing than a variable,
it's not registered in a global scope,
the object is but age here is only registered within this object, it's a property of that object, it's no variable,
that's important to understand.
If I set up an age here, 30 for example and I run this again, you will see Hello, I'm 30 years old
,
so it's not taking into account this age here.
If you want to refer it this age and certainly oftentimes, we want when having functions inside an
object, we have to tell Javascript that we're interested in a property of this object and not in a variable
.
We do this by adding the this keyword, dot and then age. This keyword is like a person outside of
this object, just inside of it.
So it's referring to the object
and it's this because we're inside the object here.
So like we can reference person.age outside of the object, inside it's simply this.age
and if I now click run again, we now see 27 because now we're referring to this age, to this property
of the object
and that's important to understand
and this allows you to use your functions or properties set up in this person or in this object in general
inside of the object.
Now the this keyword has some interesting things to say this way in Javascript, it has its
problems sometimes
and I'll come back to this in a separate lecture or in separate lectures
but for now, use it like this and this is perfectly fine and this is how you should use it,
don't get me wrong at any point here.
So with that, that is how we can set up an object, how we can use the different properties here and refer
to them internally.
So let's have a look at some other object related topics.