So back in JSBin for this module, I'll use a service named JSON placeholder and
you can find more about it at jsonplaceholder@type.com
and basically what this is it allows you to simulate web requests or send web requests to the server and
it will give you back some dummy data and this is of course great for testing.
Sometimes it has some performance issues, this test service but it's free and hey, just give
it some time and it will work.
So how do we create such
a request?
I'll create a variable and I'll name it http and I'll create a new XMLHttpRequest and that's just the name of
this request object and as already mentioned, it's not only there for sending or getting XML, that's
just an historic name or the name is like that for historic reasons.
So that creates this request
but it isn't sent yet.
I'll next add a variable with URL and here, I'll point to the service I was just mentioning and this service
has several API endpoints you may access,
for example it has these posts endpoint and you can just visit
this webpage and find more information about the available API endpoints.
So those will be the URL
I'll send the request to
and I'll also specify the HTTP method I want to use, get
in this case since I will send a get request.
Now with that, I can wire these things up. I'll take my HTTP object, so this XMLHttpRequest object
here and I'll open a connection.
This open method then requires at least two arguments, the method which should be used and the URL,
you may specify more arguments and you can find out more in the XMLHttpRequest article on the Mozilla
Developer Network,
here where you'll find all the available properties and methods and also explanations on how to set everything
up.
There's also another article on the Mozilla Developer Network which literally describes how to use an
XMLHttpRequest and you of course find both links or links to both articles in the cheatsheet attached
to this module.
So with that, you open this request but still it's not sent,
it's kind of open and prepared but it hasn't been sent yet.
Next, you probably want to do something once the request comes back,
so you will want to listen to that.
Here we have the onreadystatechange
event handler here and I'll add a function here to handle this event and then in here,
I can do whatever I want to do once this request finished successfully or also unsuccessfully and
you could get an error.
So I will check this first,
I will check if the ready state, that's another built-in property here equals XMLHttpRequest.DONE,
that's just a static field
I can use to check because ready state will just be and I can show you this in the official documentation
here, will just be a number 0 to 4
and as you can see, it's either unsent, opened, headers_received, loading or done.
We want to check if it's done, so
we could also just check if it's equal to 4 but XMLHttpRequest.DONE simply returns 4, it's just
a more literal way to describe this.
But it being done isn't everything,
I also want to check if it was successful.
So I'll use a boolean and operator
and then I will check if the status, another property equals 200 which of course is the HTTP status code
code for
OK. If that is the case, then I went to print the data
I got back and I can access the data I got on my HTTP object here
and then the response text,
so this will be the body of my response.
I can also specify an else/if condition here where I want to set up the condition to handle the case that
I got an error.
So I still want to check if it's done
but if it is done, then I want to check if it's unlike status,
so if the status code is unlike 200, in this case, I would simply print out error.
Now with that, what do you think will happen if I hit run?
Nothing does happen because I'm not sending it.
I opened it and I set up what I want to do if I get back data but I'm not sending the request.
So this is the final step I have to do here,
I have to send it. Now if I hit run,
let's see what happens.
You should get back a response like this, these are just some dummy posts
and what you get back here is JSON, so it looks like a Javascript object and it can be used as
such, it's just a string representation of such an object
and this is a common format to send data,
so to take Javascript objects and turn them into strings, you recognize this by the escaping slashes
here for example around the quotation marks.
So to take JSON to send data and this is the data we got back and which we could now use and imagine this
were a real list of posts,
then you could extract the data here and use it throughout your application.
So for example as these are dummy posts here and it is JSON data we get here in the end, so it is Javascript
representation,
what we can do is we can call JSON.parse on our response text here and
let's see what happens
now if I hit run.
Now you'll see it's no longer just a string,
it actually got transformed into Javascript object which you now can use,
so now you can simply access the title or something like that.
So since this is an array of objects, we could just access
the first object or the first element with an index of zero,
so this object here and then print the
ID, so which should be 1,
so like this. If I now hit run, you'll see one.
So this is how this works, how you can use the data you get back and how you can send requests
and as I explained, this allows you to create web applications where you load dynamic content and display
it in your application.