So we had to look at the for loop
but there is another loop built-in and actually, there are two other loops but one loop is something I'll have a look
at when we talk about objects. The other loop
I want to talk about right now is the while loop. The while loop works like this; I set a variable,
let's say number, equal to 5 and then I want to create a while loop with the while keyword and then parentheses
.
Now between the parentheses here, I specify the condition which defines how long this loop will keep
running,
so you can read this like
while this condition here is true, I will execute the code between the curly braces,
so as a condition here, I'll specify that number should be smaller than 7. Inside this loop,
I'll log number and I will increase number by 1.
So it is kind of like this for loop
I created a couple of minutes ago but written in a different way.
What do you think happens
if I hit run? I get 5 and 6 because currently it's 5,
I print 5,
it gets incremented so it's 6 which is still smaller than 7, I print 6,
it gets incremented to 7 which is no longer smaller than 7
therefore we quit the loop.
So you might think, OK that's just another way to write what we already learned.
Well that is just one example of course,
you not only can check if something is smaller than something else but you might check some condition
and you might set condition inside this loop,
well conditionally depending on something else.
So while really is a generic loop which you can use to check any condition you might have to keep running
until a condition is fulfilled or is no longer fulfilled to be precise,
so until this is no longer true.
For example if you write while true and don't execute this, you would write an infinite loop here because
this will never get changed,
it's always true,
this loop will keep running which certainly is not what you want,
of course you can combine multiple control structures here.
I'm setting condition to true here and I'll use condition inside here,
next I'll also create another variable called i which is set to 2 and inside this condition here,
I'll check if i equals 3.
If this is the case, I'll set condition to false,
otherwise I'll print i
and I'll increment i thereafter.
What do you think we'll get if I hit run?
Well we get 2 and 3, 2 is the starting value of course and then we increment it to 3 which is when
we set condition to false
but we're not instantly skipping out of the loop of course, we're just setting condition to false,
we still execute this code
but then when we reach the next iteration, we again check the condition and as it was set to false,
now the loop is finished.
Now sometimes, you also do have a case where your initial condition might be false right from the beginning
but
you nonetheless want to execute at least one iteration of the loop.
So for example if I set condition to false and I get rid of all the other stuff here
and I write log,
execute it here,
what do you think I'll see?
Nothing of course because condition is set to false but let's say condition is not hardcoded to
false but instead set through your program and it might be true
and nonetheless, not depending on its value, you want to at least execute the code here at least once.
For this case, we get another loop, the do/while loop and it's basically the while loop but we add another
keyword, do, then curly braces and then the while condition at the end followed by a semi-colon.
So we're still use this while condition but we specify that we want to execute this code anyways,
so even if it is false right from the beginning.
So if I now hit run, we see executed, even though the condition is false, we only see it getting executed
once
but this one time is executed at least, which is what the do
keyword here allows us to do.
So that have been control structures, if statement, switch statement, for loop and while loop
and how you can combine them, how you can control them with break and continue and setting the conditions
for the while loop for example. Control structures are very important and allow you to change the flow
of code execution or
also of course dependently execute some code, which is something you'll probably need in most of your applications
.