So with the comparison operators and the boolean operators, you're able to write elaborate if statements
or whenever you need boolean statements returning true or false,
for example you could write a statement like this; if a equals b, return
equal and otherwise, print out not equal.
Of course I don't have a and b yet, so I'll quickly create both variables and a should just be 5 and b
will also be 5 for now. If I print this, you'll see equal of course.
Now that is not really a difficult check here but I want to show something else,
I want to show you a shorter way to write short if statements like this one.
You could refactor this like this,
you could console log and then a equals b question mark, then one result,
so a string equal, colon, the else case, not equal.
Before I explain this, let's run it,
you see equal.
So what is this thing here?
It's a ternary operator
and basically this is a way to write a simple if statement with its conditional code and the else code
in one line.
So first comes the check, if a equals b, then separated by a question mark,
we get the code to be executed or to be returned
if this is the case and since I'm in the console log statement, I'm only setting this equal string
here, so this equal string will then be used inside this console log statement or separated with a colon,
I
have the else case,
so if I change b to be 6 and I run this code again, I get not equal.
So this is just a shorter way to write simple Javascript if statements and you may use this when you
find it appropriate,
it's certainly convenient to use it for very plain and simple checks. If you overdo it though, you
might write a very difficult to read code,
so really only fallback to it and use it if the check is really straightforward.