I'll go back to the Javascript code here and I'll start by showing this with one very important
event for example. On the window object,
we have the load event and I can add an event handler to this event with onload property here on
the window object.
I then assign a function, an anonymous function here which should handle this loading event whenever
it occurs,
I will then print out window loaded. If I now run this code,
what do you think will happen?
I get window loaded because it's initially being executed which means this onload handler is being
recognized, is registered and then when the window actually loads,
this code here is run.
So this is an event handler which is always executed whenever the window loads, which is of course an important
event because at this point of time, we know that the window was loaded, the code is available,
we can safely work with it.
Therefore you might sometimes need this onload listener to do certain initialization tasks
as you can be sure that there window was successfully loaded at this point of time.
You can also see very well how events are actually handled,
we use the onload property on the window object and we assign an anonymous function which is therefore
registered as such an event handler
and of course we not only have the onload event handler, we can also listen to other events.
Let's say I add a new button element in my HTML code and this button says Click Me but it doesn't have
any other logic attached to it.
If I wanted to listen to any events on this button or if I want to handle the click event on this button,
I'll first fetch the button with a query selector here, button, I'm just selecting by the tag name here,
so by this name here, button and then I can access my button and with onclick, I can set up an onclick event
handler and I can then print something, for example clicked. If I now click on clear and then on run,
what
do you think will happen?
Well nothing for now because I only set up this onclick handler, so this should only get executed if I
actually click on the button which I haven't done yet.
So now if I click on the button, now we see clicked,
so now this function which is set up as an onclick listener is executed
and of course this function is executed every time I click on this button.
So that's really powerful
but of course you might ask, how do I know which functions are available on a specific HTML element?
The
answer to this is you can either log out the element to the console and then have a look at all
the properties and you will identify the event handlers by the on at the beginning and then the name
of the event or of course and that is no joke but a valid approach,
you simply google for Javascript and then the element name and then events and you should find lists
with all the events and that is a very valid approach to finding out about them because there are a
lot but of course the most common ones like clicking, mouse enter, mouse leave and so on are always included
.
Also note, you can not only listen to onclick on buttons or links, you can add these event handlers on
any HTML element, even if it normally isn't clickable
but in the end, you can click everywhere in the browser right,
so you can listen to it everywhere.
You can even set up an event handler, an onclick event handler on the document itself. If I now hit run,
you will see I get clicked no matter where I click,
so that will work too.
This is how you set up an event handler and I will change this back to button
but there is one major disadvantage of this approach here.
Imagine I want to execute two functions whenever I click this button,
so I have another event handler here which says also clicked. If I now, after hitting run with js, click
on this button,
what do you think we'll see in the console?
We only see also clicked.
So the first event handler here is simply overwritten,
it's no longer there
and that is a problem because oftentimes, you'll need multiple listeners and you don't only want to have
one handler.
So while this approach works fine as long as you only have one thing you want to execute,
it certainly has its problems
if you have multiple functions you want to call. Therefore in the next lecture, we'll have a look at an
alternative.