Besides closures, we also got another special thing about functions.
We can write functions that will immediately get executed when the code runs through our Javascript file,
these
functions are called immediately invoked function executions or IIFES or iifes.
How does this work
and why could we need that?
Let's have an example; I'll create a function and it'll be a function named calc and I will just log
.
Now if I hit run, you of course didn't see anything because this function doesn't get executed automatically
Now however, I can add parentheses around it and add parentheses after it.
Now this looks strange but it looks a bit like a function call where
this would be the name
and then we have parentheses to execute this function if we imagine it like this.
If I now hit run, what do you think we'll see?
We see calc,
so this function here inside the first pair of parentheses gets executed immediately.
Now rightfully, you might say why do I need this,
I could have just written console log
calc, right?
Because all the code here, besides function, gets executed immediately anyways, so why would I do it
this way, this is just more characters and it looks a bit strange.
So what's the advantage of this approach?
The advantage of this approach simply is that we are using local scope here.
Remember that functions create their own scope, the local scope,
so by doing it this way, we make sure that we don't pollute the global scope with our variables and I'll showcase
this. I'll set up a variable here which I will call number and this will be just 10
and then I will simply log number here.
Now I will also try to log number outside of this function then,
so this line here will get executed after this function and we'll see if number is available here too.
What do you think I'll get if I hit run? 10 and then that number is not defined, an error because it's
registered in the local scope of this function here and not on the global scope
and that is the reason why you would use iifes, just to make sure that you're not polluting the global
scope with variables
or maybe you might have variables in the global scope that interfere with some other variables,
maybe
you have a third-party package which uses certain local variables and you accidentally overwrite
them or in your application because it's very complex,
you do the same and overwrite global values,
so by doing this, you make sure that the variable is only available inside this local scope and not everywhere
.
Now I'm not saying you should write all your code as iifes but it might be a good approach
if global scale pollution could be an issue in your application, which of course depends on the
size of your project
and as I said, maybe the inclusion of third-party packages.
Now another interesting thing is you can also pass a value to an iife,
so if I add the input here and I set number equal to input and then I pass 10 here in the second
pair of parentheses, I get rid of this console log function which was throwing the error, if I now hit
run,
we still see 10,
so we're able to pass the 10 into this iife and then use it in this function.
Now what do you think happens if I do the following;
I create an object
and I pass this object into my function
and in here what I do is I'm not logging anything but I'm setting object.name equal to Max and
now I log object.
What do you think I'll get if I hit
run? I get the object with the name because we created the object on the global scope, so it
is registered in the global scope
and then yes I'm using an iife but in the iife I'm only changing this object which is already
existing on a global scope, therefore I am able to print it here and I do see the changes because again,
I'm changing the global scope object, not a local scope variable here,
I'm not creating a new variable inside this function.
So that are iifes
and that is how you use them and why you could use them
and as I said, you don't have to write all your code in iifes, you may do it of course,
it really depends on your requirements and if the global scope should be kind of cleaned up or if
you might have problems with other parts of your app or other packages
or if this isn't an issue in which case you probably don't need iifes for that.