Of course you can not only get data, you know you can also send data,
so let's try this. I'll change the method to post and when posting data, I of course also have to
attach some data.
I'll also turn this back to no longer access any element but I will leave the JSON.parse since I will
get back JSON data here too.
I'll also add one extra thing after opening the request,
I'll set the request header to let the server which gets the request know which content it gets.
So I'll set the Content-Type header to application/x-www-form-urlencoded and that's just
a specific content type telling the server that it's getting data in the form URL encoded format
and I'll show you this format here where I create the data variable and just set up a dummy data here
and
let's say since I'm creating a post, I'll have a title of let's say post title and I'll use the percentage
sign, 20 to represent a whitespace here an
typically you would not type this manually but of course fetch from a form in your project for example
and again, learn more in this using XMLHttpRequest document and I'll also set up body so I'll add an and sign
and body should be equal to body like this and then the data of course has to be attached and
I do this here in the send method which takes an argument,
the data I want to send.
So with that, I'm now leaving the same URL but I'm sending a post request,
I am sending this data here and I'm still parsing any response I'll get back.
I also set the request header to let the server know what it's getting.
I also need to change the status check here to check for status 201 since this will be the status I
get back when I create or when I post something here
since 201 means everything is OK,
a resource was created and that is what I typically want to do when sending a post request.
So here, I'll hit run and as you can see, I'm getting back an object with my data,
of course this is just dummy data, it wasn't created on some server, it's not stored anywhere but I'm
getting back
data I send
and this shows me that this worked
and this is how you can post data, Again, if you want to learn more about how to parse data and convert it
into a data variable which you can attach,
check out this using XMLHttpRequest article and as mentioned in the beginning of this module,
oftentimes you'll use a third-party library which will handle this for you. Nonetheless it's important to
understand how this works
and I sure hope that the lectures here were helpful regarding this aspect.