So other useful built-in functions and methods are some parsers or functions or methods which allow
you to transform certain values. Now I want to explain some of these built-in functions too.
So imagine you have a variable a which is a string of '5'
but it's not a number, it's a string
and then I could print this variable of course
and unsurprisingly, we would see a string of five.
Now I can also call the parseInt method which is also available on the window object, so in the global
scope
and if I now hit run, what do you think we'll see now?
Well now I get 5 as a number,
so this transforms a string into a number or at least tries to.
What do you think we'll see if I have some text which should be hard to be transformed into a number?
We get another number because it's not possible but it'll try it's best to
get your string into a number.
You're not only able to transform let's say something like this but imagine you have a string of
fbb123
so some
hexadecimal string here, what do you think we'll now get
if I hit run?
NaN because still, this is some string it doesn't know but parseInt takes another argument optionally.
Here I can specify the base number of digits, so in which system I'm operating and the default is
of course the decimal system but I can change this to hexadecimal for example
and now if I hit run,
I get a number.
So this is now transformed from hexadecimal to an integer and you will probably not need this all
the time but there might be use cases where you do need it and it's important to understand that Javascript
offers you the tools to transform text in general into integers or even something like hexadecimal
numbers or text here into an intger. Other useful functions would be let's say if we have a real
number here and we want to transform this into a string, we can call toString on that because toString
is a method defined in the Object.prototype
and as explained, this is the base prototype of all the objects, therefore every object by default has
this toString method here.
So if I clear this and run it now, what do you think we'll get? We get a string of 10, so this number
was now transformed into a string.
Again, this is possible on each object in Javascript.
And what do you think I'll get if I have 10.3 and I execute toFixed
and we saw this function being used earlier in this course when we had this problem with the floating
point number.
So what you think we'll now get if it hit run? Well 10, toFixed just basically rounds it
and we have to specify the number of decimal places here as an argument, for example 2 which would give
us this result
but the default if we don't specify any argument is just to round it without any decimal places, just
to in this case 10.
So these were some basic built-in parsers or ways to transform values and there are more and you will
find a more detailed list or a link to that in the cheatsheet attached to the end of this module of
course.