Now I'll clear this and I want to show you something else. I already showed how you can loop through an array
with a for loop
earlier when I was talking about loops. Now on this array object, I can also use another method, I'll access
my array here, so this array variable and then I can call the forEach method on it.
Now this method takes an argument and this argument might look confusing right now but I'll come back
to this kind of function,
what it will be later.
So I pass a function here but this function has no name,
I just create a function without any name.
That's an anonymous function
and as I said, I'll come back to this
but generally, this is something you'll often see if you have a method which expects a function as an
argument, like this method does, that you don't create a new function and then pass a reference to that
function which would be possible too
but instead you create this function on the fly.
You don't need a name because you are only passing it for this argument here anyways,
you're not using it anywhere else in your code and therefore you just generate this function like this
.
Now this function takes an argument, I'll name it element and the name is purely up to you because this
forEach function expect an argument of type function, which in turn also takes an argument and the name
as I just said is up to you. Inside this function,
I can then log element and now this might look confusing, let's just see what it does.
So what could it do if I hit run?
Well you see 1, 2, 3,
so what this basically does is forEach, make sure that for is array, for each element, that's where the
name comes from, this function here is executed and this function only takes the element,
so one then two, then three and prints it to the console.
So that's a convenient way to loop through an array and do something with the individual elements,
of
course you can not only print them,
you can do everything, what you could do in normal Javascript code as well.
Very very convenient to access this.