I want to finish this topic on operators by talking about precedence.
So this means which operator takes precedence over another one.
I already showed this with the boolean operators and I want to come back to this. So I clear this and
I get a and b which is fine
and now I want to still log some thing and I want to log a + b * 2.
Now what will we see if I hit run?
Well we get 17 and this is pure mathematics here,
you have a multiplication which comes first and then you add a to the result of this multiplication
and
of course a way to change this is by adding parentheses round a + b, which would now give you
22.
So that is good but you've got a lot of operators as you saw
and it's not straightforward as with the boolean operators to learn which operators have precedence
over other operators and a great way to find out is by simply and you will find this in a cheatsheet
attached to this module as well, by simply googling for Javascript
operator precedence and this will give you this article here from the MDN, the Mozilla Developer
Network, where you will find a list of operators and their precedents, where the highest or the top element
has the highest precedence here.
So the higher the precedence number, the higher the precedents,
so for example here, parentheses grouping has the highest precedence and we just saw this in action
and if we scroll down, we see that division has this precedence, addition has this one of course
lower than multiplication and division,
that's basic mathematics and so on.
So you may consult this list here to see how the different operators rank and also to learn which operators
exists there.
Now if you are shocked that these are a lot of operators and I haven't covered all of them right now,
well
a lot of them are operators
you're probably not going to use that often
and a lot of them are operators
you will still see throughout this course.