I'll first start very simple, I'll create a new variable which I will just name test and I'll assign a string
value of global scope.
This variable indeed is registered in the global scope since I'm just writing it here and
this by default is the global scope,
therefore I'm of course able to just log it out like this
and it shouldn't be surprising that we see global scope being printed to the console.
Now if I create a function and I name this function local scope, just an arbitrary name here
by the way. If I try to print out test inside this function and I get rid of this printing here and then
I call this function of course,
otherwise nothing will happen for sure,
what do you think we'll see in the console? We see global scope because as I said, you are able to use
global elements inside a function, so this direction is opened but you're not able to use elements from
within the function outside of it
and I'll show that in a second.
So global scope can be printed here since we can access test.
What happens if I create another variable in here, test, where I say local scope? What do you think we'll
now see if I click run?
We see local scope,
I am redeclaring a variable and depending on browser and strict mode, you would even see an error
when trying to do something like this on global scope,
so if I do this here, test and I run this, we would get an error on some systems and with strict mode
enabled, so it doesn't throw an error if we do it inside local scope inside a function
because this is what I meant,
this function has its own scope and it has its own registry
therefore if you want to think of scope like this, where it registers this variable.
Now I am able to use the test variable from the global scope as I just showed but I can overwrite this
and set my own variables.
The question is if I now print test here on the global scope again, notice that I am redefining it in
the function and then I'm calling the function,
so what do we expect to see when I reach this line,
what will get printed to the console? Local scope and global scope, local scope of course comes from this
console log statement whereas global scope comes from here because as I said, this variable is only
available within this scope here inside the function,
therefore test here isn't overwritten
and if I get rid of this first test variable,
so we have no test variable on the global scope,
what do you think will happen now?
Well now we simply get an error
that test isn't defined because again, we don't have access to this variable,
it doesn't flow out of the local scope,
it stays inside it.
Something interesting happens if I remove the var keyword,
what do you think will happen now?
Now all of a sudden, I don't get that error but instead I see local scope here as well
even though I still don't have the test variable outside of this function.
So what's happening here?
Well that's the behavior of Javascript which is possible if you're not using strict mode. When you
are leaving out the var keyword, Javascript will automatically generate a new global variable
and I was mentioning this earlier in this course, that a new variable is automatically generated by
Javascript
if you try to use a variable which hasn't been declared before. Such variables always have global scope
no matter where you use them,
therefore this actually becomes a global variable and therefore can be accessed here.
So by turning on strict mode, you would make sure that this is not possible
and of course always just give your best to remember putting var in front of it.
So that's scope and it's just important to understand that you can use variables inside functions which
are not available outside of functions which is a functionality in turn
you'll often need
and it's also important to understand that local variables however are accessible inside functions, so
you have access to all the global scope things inside a function but a global scope doesn't have access
to the local scope
things or elements.
That's how we can think of it
and that's important to understand.