Now I was also mentioning the modularity which would be great
and with that, I was of course referring to the fact that I already explained.
You want to split up your application over several files, modules and then if you need some module in one
file, simply throw in an import at the top and have all the code from this file available.
The reason you might want to do this is that you don't want to have like 30 imports in your HTML
files with the script tags and then also keep a close eye to the ordering and whenever you
change something, some dependency, you need to change the ordering
and that is close to impossible to manage
and really no fun.
Therefore it would be great if you could import and export modules in Javascript but you can't by default,
at least not with ES5.
The great thing is there are packages or tools which still add this functionality
and what those tools do is they will simply allow you to use modules during development and then for
deploying or running your application, they will manually figure out the dependencies you set up during
development and either import the files in the correct order automatically or bundle them all together
into one file,
still keeping the correct ordering for everything to work.
Now there are a lot of popular choices
and again this is content for its own course but a popular choice is webpack for example and you might
start on its official Github page here which is github.com/webpack/webpack and
there you will find links to the documentation and so on.
And again, this is really something on its own to learn but it's worth it.
An alternative is systemjs, which unlike webpack is less of a tool,
setting up everything,
it's more like a script that you throw into your project and then it will automatically import files in
the correct order for you.
So this allows you to have one import in the end, script
systemjs
and then it will automatically import the rest for you which of course is great and it will figure out
what it needs to import depending on the modules and the dependencies with imports and exports
you
set up in your project.
So here again, the github page, systemjs/systemjs
is a great starting point as well as Googling for it and you might also be interested in something
like jspm, Javascript Package Manager which allows you to easily add libraries to your project and
also use systemjs to load everything together in the right order and also prepare it for deployment
with bundling, minification, so optimizing it by size and so on
and again, here jspm.io is a great page to get started and dive into the documentation.
And once you are there, you will better understand how all of that works, how you actually do import and export
files but as I said, that really is a topic on its own and far beyond the scope of this course which
was about plain Javascript and nothing but plain Javascript
but this is certainly an interesting next step and I just wanted to give you the resources so that you
know where to get started to dive into this deeper.
I'll see you in all the other videos and I wish you all the best.