Well what if I want to find out where a specific element lives inside an array?
So I want to find out which index new has and let's say I wouldn't know. I have a method to find this
out,
I can call indexof on my array and pass the value of which I want to get the index.
So what do you think I'll see in the console if I hit run? I see 0 because that is the index of the
array item here because new gets inserted as the first item of the array and therefore has the index
0.
Of course you can combine things like let's say array, then square brackets and between square brackets
you have to insert the index you want to access and then getting the index with the indexof method
and
I'm now setting this equal to old
and then I print my array here.
What do you think we'll see in the console now?
We got old,
1, 2, 3, 4 because I'm finding the index of new here
and this gets returned and is 0 , therefore here I'm technically calling array 0,
that's what this will resolve to in this case and
I'm setting it equal to old, so I'm replacing the first element with old here.
What if I wanted to extract a part of an array and assign it to a new array, is that possible?
Well I'm pretty confident it is.
I'll create a new array here and I could set it equal to array
but now it would be the same. What if I only wanted to get the last two elements, 3 and 4 in this
case? I can call the splice method for one and I can insert or pass an argument which defines at which position
I want to start to splice a bit of that array.
So remember, I'm inserting a new item here at the beginning,
so technically I will have index 0, 1, 2, 3,
I want to start at index 3.
Now let's see what happens if I print out new array here. I get 3 and 4, the two items I wanted.
Now what if I wanted only a part of the array,
let's say the two and three here,
so in the middle of the array? I would start at index two which would refer to this element
here since I'm inserting a new element at the beginning, don't forget that
and then I can pass another argument to this splice method, which indicates how many elements beginning
from this index on I want to take, in this case two elements, two and three,
so this includes the indexed element here itself.
So if I now print this or run this, here you see that I got two and three. Now however, have a look at what happens
if I now also logout the old array.
What do you think we will see in the console?
Well you see that the old array misses the two and three,
it really got spliced up so we took two and three and pulled it out of the old array and the old array
is therefore only old, 1 and 4.
Now maybe you want that behavior and maybe you don't,
if you don't want it, then the splice method is the wrong method
and you should use slice instead.
However the slice method works a bit different, here
we're not specifying from which index how many items but instead from which index to which index.
So we're starting at index 2
and again, this is only index 2 because we're inserting a new item at the beginning,
otherwise this would be index one of course.
So we're starting at two and then now we would end at two
which of course would give us no element at all,
so I want to end at four here.
Let's see what's now printed if I hit run;
now you see I'm getting the values 2 and 3 and I store them into a new array
but the old array remains untouched and it still has all its values
and again depending on your idea or what you want to achieve,
either splice or slice might be the correct method.
Only keep in mind that you have to change the arguments because slice expect starting and ending index
whereas
splice expects starting index and number of elements.
So there is a slight difference here.