Now there are more array functions available.
I'll get rid of the slicing here or of this new array altogether and let me just print out the array as
we get it now,
so old, 1, 2, 3, 4
and now let's say I only want to logout values which are greater than two.
Now of course, I could create a for loop and loop through all these values and then filter out the ones
I want to print
but I can also use the filter method on the array.
This method also takes an anonymous function, like the forEach method did
and I also pass an argument here which I will name value and what this method will do is it will call
this for all the elements here, pass the value of the element and I can do something with that element,
I
have to return something with my function here
though, I have to return true or false,
so if the value I'm currently looking at should be included in the array returned by this method call
here or not.
So here I will return if value is greater than 2.
If I run this code, you'll see that I only get 3 and 4 because only these two values are greater than
2.
So as before with forEach, this function gets executed on each value
but here it's important to return true or false to let the filter method know if it should include or
exclude the value I just passed into this function.
So that's one function,
another useful function is the map function here.
This allows me to do something with each value often or with each element of an array. I'll again pass
in each element and again, it doesn't matter if you name this value or element or elephant or whatever
you want, this name is purely up to you, it's just important that you pass an argument with which you
can work inside of this function.
So map for example allows me to return value times two
and again it is important to return something because map will also, like filter did, create a new array
and it needs to know what to do with each element of that array.
So here, I'm basically saying with that new array you create double each value.
Therefore if I run this code, you'll see 2, 4, 6 and 8 and at the beginning, we have not a number because I
have new here
and as you learned in the operators module, you can't multiply a string, that will result in not a number
.
Keep in mind that with map as well as with filter, we're creating a new array here.
I'm not assigning it to a variable,
I'm directly printing it out but it's not changing the original array, as you can see if I print this
array right after running map here.
If I run this again, you'll see the old array is untouched, only this printed out new array was changed,
that is important to keep in mind.
Now I get some more interesting methods up my sleeve,
I also got the reverse method.
Now that's a simple one,
it doesn't take an argument but you might be able to guess what it does if I hit run here
and of course it reverses this array.
And now here, please recognize that the array itself was reversed,
this is not returning a new array which is reversed but it's doing this reverse operation on the array
itself,
that's the difference to map or filter where new arrays were created, here
the original array is changed. That is very important of course to know because you might get unwanted
results if you are thinking this would create a new array, it doesn't,
it changes the old one.