So you know the basics about objects and you know that this prototypes thing seems to be important,
let's
have a look at this in a little more detail now.
Here's where I left, with object create and so on,
I'll get rid of that,
back to my basic object and I already mentioned that all objects in Javascript by default have a prototype
which is Object.prototype
and this again also is an object on its own.
So can we check this?
Can we access the prototype of this person here in some way?
Well we do have a property on person, on each object called prototype, though we're not really able to
access this,
if I run this, you see I undefined,
so that's not really working.
Well, some browsers implemented a custom property which we can access to get the prototype but you should
never ever use that in production as it is not safe, as this is added by the browsers and not part of the Javascript
specification.
This property I'm talking of looks a bit strange,
it's __proto__, also sometimes referred to as dunder proto,
so double underscore, double underscore at beginning and end and then proto in the middle.
If I now click on run, you see we get some kind of object and this is the prototype, which is an object
itself, of person.
Now before we get too abstract here because I think this is, yes it's nice, we have this prototype, but it's
more important to understand what is this prototype therefore, what's the sense of a prototype?
We know we can kind of access it with this unsave method here or this unsave property,
but why do we have this prototype in the first place?
I'll show you something,
I'll first call anything as a method here
and unsurprisingly, I get an error.
Next I call toString here and now watch what happens if I hit run,
we get object object as a string here.
So this person seems to have some kind of toString method which basically prints it as a string and
this is just Chrome's way of displaying it for example. toString is not a method we wrote
on this object, we only have two properties,
no method at all,
there is no function inside this object here.
So something else seems to be going on here and the something else is the prototype indeed, the prototype
has some built-in methods which are available to all objects.
That is what the prototype is
there for, we can inherit from it and this is Javascript's form of inheritance to get certain methods
which the object we're creating itself might not implement on its own but the parent object and that
is a difficult term here
but you can think of it as the parent
the prototype has.
So like the name implies, it's the prototype of which we built other object and we can add custom methods or
fields to our objects but they will always have access to the prototypes, objects and methods.
If I now try the following and I go to object prototype and I create a new field, greet which I set
equal to a function
and here I log Hello there to the console and I now try to access person greet,
what do you think will happen if I hit run? We see Hello there because I now added a new method, greet,
to object prototype which as I mentioned before is the root prototype
all objects have in Javascript by default and therefore, we can access greet on person, even though person
itself doesn't have this greet method here
It's set up on a prototype but therefore it is available on person.
So we have kind of a prototype chain here,
we have here our greet call on our object which doesn't have this greet function.
So Javascript will first, when it finds this code, see if object has agreed method which it doesn't,
it will then reach out to the prototype of object and that doesn't always have to be Object.prototype
directly,
we might have another prototype in between for example or we might have set our own prototype.
If it doesn't find it on the prototype of object, it will look to the prototype of the prototype and
so on.
So this is this chain where Javascript will work its way up through all the levels of prototypes an object
might have inherited from.
Now of course, our person object here only has one prototype, Object.prototype
but you will later see examples for objects which have a custom prototype in between.