So you now learned about the basic values you can assign to variables, which data structures and types
you got available.
Now before we dive deeper, let's have a look at some syntactical things which are important
to know in Javascript.
Until now, we had kind of straightforward code here
but let's see what we could change about this code and if it would still run or not.
So I'll change this back to just being assigned to 5
and of course if I print this to the console, we see 5.
Now notice I have semi-colons at the end of the lines,
what happens if I delete those semi-colons?
So I hit clear,
what do you think I'll get now if I hit run?
Well I still get 5,
so the code works without them as well.
Javascript will determine or will infer
where are your lines end
and will still be able to execute this code fine.
So of course, this code here would throw an error because it's never ending
but by simply adding a line break here, Javascript is able to execute this code or the browser running
over your Javascript and actually executing it is able to run it.
Now what happens if I get rid of var
keyword here?
What do you think we'll see now if I hit run?
Well we still see 5, so even though I don't have the var keyword, Javascript still seems to
have this variable because it automatically creates it and assigns it to the global scope
and I'll come back to global and local which is the opposite or the other possible scope soon
but basically for now, it's important to understand Javascript automatically creates this variable and
saves it like it did when we had the var keyword.
So even though this code does run fine, it's not really the best way to write it because it is very
unexpressive
and it'll also decrease the performance when this code gets executed a bit because when the Javascript
engine in the browser runs over this code, it has to do more things than it would have to
do if we explicitly tell it where the lines end, explicitly tell it that this is a variable,
it will have to figure out these things on its own
and that's one extra step which of course also costs performance. Javascript therefore offers us the strict
mode which we can enter to basically tell ourselves when writing the code and browser when running
through it that we have to use strict mode or in the browser's case, that strict mode was used which makes
sure that certain syntactical things have to be considered and won't work
if we're doing it over. So to demonstrate this, I'll head over to plnkr again
and I'll again launch a new editor and then here I'll go to my script.js file here in preview mode.
So I'll go to my script.js file and I'll just copy this code and I'm doing this in plnkr
because I can't show it in JSBin unfortunately.
So now if I open up my Javascript console in the developer tools and I'll clear it for now,
if I hit refresh,
you see we get 5, so this code still executes. If I now enter the strict mode by specifying a string at
the top of the file,
use strict like this,
now you see we get an uncaught reference error,
var1 is not defined.
So now, strict mode enforces us to explicitly tell Javascript that this is a variable by adding the var
keyword,
so now it works again,
also we should use semi-colons at the end of each line.
It work without
but that's also part of the strict mode and depending on the browser, you might need to do this
for strict mode to work correctly.
So it's important now to be explicit with your code, tell Javascript when you create a variable, tell
it where the line ends.
So while this might look strange to just have a string, not assigned to a variable or anything like this,
just some text at the top of the file,
this is a very key thing to make sure that you are writing better code or safer code, more optimized
code at least. Be aware that if you are using some third-party library which might not use strict
mode, you could run into problems here but in reality, most libraries should be written in a clean way
using strict mode as well
but you should at least, well if you get an error, think about this possible error source, that you're using
strict mode and your third-party library is not.