Starting with an interesting or relevant fact,
or personal story.
This is my first visit to your beautiful city.
I arrived yesterday, and I took a walk
through the stunning old part of town.
Many of you recognize this symbol.
It's from Frank and Jimmy's Barbershop at 121 Dundas Street.
I asked Frank why most barbershops have a pole
that's red and white with blue stripes,
and he told me that many years ago,
when you wanted to get surgery done,
in ancient times, Europe or whatever,
you went to the barbershop, and what happened was
after the surgeon, who worked at a barbershop,
would do surgery on you, they had these blue towels,
blue and white towels, and then what they would do is,
they'd use the towel to clean up the surgery,
clean the towels, and then hang them up outside on a pole,
and the wind would wrap them up in those three colors.
That's why it's red, white, and blue.
Anyway, thought that was an interesting story
to share with you all.
Okay, remember the so what thing, right?
Just like Frank and Jimmy's Barbershop,
your company has the same family type,
warm culture feel to it.
Your company is rich in tradition,
and was also founded in 1879.
So starting with an interesting fact,
and then putting it into context
with the purpose of your product,
is a different way to start a speech.
Remember the so what test, too.
It's got to be relevant, and if you want,
go to your success journal, and look at what
you documented as the purpose of your speech,
and the audience exercise as well,
and see if you can start your presentation
with something that might appeal to emotions, et cetera,
some sort of cool story.
And if you tell a story, again make sure to always
make sure it's relevant.
Ask yourself, the so what test.
Here's another example.
This watch is not made of gold or silver,
it's made of stainless steel.
On May 14, 2016 in Geneva, this Rolex
was sold for 2.5 million dollars.
Now if you took apart this watch,
and melted down the components,
the resale value would be very, very small.
It's the sentimental value of an earlier time in history
that makes this watch worth more than the sum of its parts.
Similarly, our customers have valued our product,
and the emotional bond they have with it
for several generations.
Our product is respected and appreciated
by generations of our loyal customers.
Our product is genuine.
It's precise.
Our product has impeccable quality, and it's timeless.
Separately, when you tell a personal story,
it's so natural and much more passionate,
and you usually get hired by a company
if people enjoy your company as they see you as real
in an interview, and not over rehearsed.
So here's how I personalized a speech I gave recently
at Stanford Business School on finance and accounting.
I'm here to teach you about finance and accounting,
but before I get started, I want you all to know
that I got a D in accounting the first time I took it.
What I learned was, I got a D
because I memorized accounting concepts.
You need to understand them first,
and then you will remember them.
And what I wanted to talk to you about today
at Stanford is, yada, yada, yada.
You get the idea.
Just make sure please, that your story is
somewhat contextually relevant.
Separately, this is not a political course, whatever,
but check out the speech from Obama when he tells a story
with no preparation on his life.
His delivery is not as polished in this one
as it usually is because he's very exhausted,
but it's very real.
Check it out.