If somebody didn't introduce you
(quiet music)1
and/or they didn't talk about your bio or your background
then you can consider talking about yourself
when you start a speech.
And the best way to do it generally speaking
is to speak in chronological order
and make sure that there's some consistency please
(Music chords sounding)
or relevancy with respect to the topic of discussion, okay?
For example, and this is a unique approach, okay?
Let's pretend I'm the key note speaker for a finance
or an investment conference, okay?
You must make sure to keep it relevant while making it
interesting, personal, poetic or prophetic,
while being passionate and staying in character, okay?
It's easy to do because it's you, it's you, okay?
So here I go, along with a few images to keep it personal
and relevant, okay?
This piece of cardboard was sold on August fifth of 2016
for 465,000 dollars.
This is a Gretzky PSA10 perfect specimen,
okay it's Wayne Gretzky's rookie card, okay?
10/10 perfect, okay?
There's not many in the world.
I had many cards like this one growing up in Canada.
But unfortunately, I put these cards on my bicycle wheel
so that when I rode my BMX bike around,
it sounded like a real motorcycle.
Okay, clearly I wasn't the smartest kid in Canada.
Now, my first business when I was a kid,
was I would sell enlarged hockey
and baseball cards for 10 bucks, right?
So here's an example, I still have them, right,
I was cleaning out my parents' house.
See that, I used to stick them on the wall of my dorm room,
Right, so I would go to, I think it was like a Kinko's
before Kinko's was around in Canada,
and I would pay five bucks to have them enlarged,
I would stick them on cardboard,
these are comic cardboard backings,
and I'd sell them for ten bucks at school.
So, anyway, that's Wayne Gretzky.
My first business, kinda fun, okay.
So, we all loved Wayne Gretzky growing up,
and one day all Canadians will never forget
is August ninth 1988.
This was the day that Wayne Gretzky was traded
from our Edmonton Oilers to the Los Angeles Lakers.
Okay, in the United States, the combination of the day
Kennedy was shot, or O.J. Simpson chase was on television
or Bobby Thompson's shot was heard around the world,
that's kind of what it meant for us Canadians.
It was a really, really big deal, okay?
And I remember that press conference,
and you know our idol, the great one, Wayne Gretzky
was tearing up on television.
I mean, he was so real, and so awesome to us.
What could possibly make the Great One tear up?
So, what made him tear up was that he was leaving us.
We felt abandoned, it wasn't his fault though, right?
He was leaving our country,
which was an ill thought out business decision
by the owner of the Edmonton Oilers at the time, okay?
And I remember we all teared up, right, I did,
as did my little sisters, and my parents,
and many people in Canada.
You see, to us Wayne Gretzky meant the world,
as he was the combination of Magic Johnson
plus Mickey Mantle plus Pele plus Muhammad Ali,
plus Diego Maradona all in one.
That's how much hockey means to us, okay, and Gretzky.
And it really marked the end of my childhood,
and it was emblematic of, you know,
Simon and Garfunkel singing Where Have You Gone Joe Dimaggio
and Gretzky was really the most real thing we knew
in a pretentious, greed filled eighties decade, okay.
It was at that point that I realized
that sports was a short term focus business,
and no longer a field of dreams,
and that being short term focused in business
had negative long term repercussions.
It marked the end of an era for me,
in terms of athletes being loyal and long term focused.
Gone were the days where a George Brett played
for the Kansas City Royals for his whole career,
or Michael Jordan stayed with Chicago
for what seemed like forever,
or Cal Ripken, Jr. play with Baltimore
for his entire career.
You know, field of dreams no more.
This begs the question, what made Wayne Gretzky great?
Well, he had this epic quote of saying
that he was successful not because he skated
to where the puck is but rather,
he skated to where the puck is going to be, okay?
Years later, when I worked on Wall Street at Goldman Sachs,
and in the hedge fund industry at Citadel,
and then currently, at my own venture capital firm,
I attribute my minor successes in life to that quote
from Wayne Gretzky.
You see, we need to have the foresight of Wayne Gretzky
and anticipate what investors are going to like
in five to ten years.
Instead of skating to where the puck is right now,
meaning, instead of investing in companies
that people already like.
You see, if we buy stocks in companies
that many people already like,
then there aren't that many incremental buyers,
and we are nothing more than tourists renting stocks.
We're not owners.
You get the idea, okay.
Make the introduction personal, please, and interesting,
and always unique, and of course relevant.
(music chords)
Remember the (mumbles) test, thanks.