Let's talk about showing props, meaning bringing items
to show other people as a way to start your speech.
You know, my kids do this in school and it's called
show and tell and it's very memorable for them
and for me.
The classes I remember when I was a kid were show and tell.
I remembered what item I brought in or my other friends
brought in, I don't remember what we learned in school.
I remember the things that people brought in.
It was novel, it was unique, it was different,
and it was personal, right?
It makes you more entertaining, too, as a speaker
as, you know, your audience gets to know you.
So here's what we're going to do.
I'm not going to edit what I'm about to film, okay?
So here I go.
I'll kick it off with, I got a bunch of personal items
I got in the house here.
And, again, I'm just gonna wing it and I'm gonna tell
a story about, sorry if you can't hear me well,
tell a story about some things I have in the house, okay?
This product is very, very hard to get.
And, you know what, I actually got it for way cheaper
than anybody else that purchased this product before, right?
I'm gonna keep going here.
I'm stumbling a bit, it's okay.
This is a Nintendo Switch and it's almost impossible
to find at this point of filming.
So how did I get it?
Well, my kids really wanted it, right?
It's all about the kids, right?
I don't know if I've let them play it yet,
I play a lot, it's pretty cool, just kidding.
So what I did was I went to all the big stores and they
were sold out everywhere, obviously.
So I tried to outthink our competition, right,
and buy this product.
So here's what I did.
I started thinking like other people might, okay,
using game theory.
And I went to eBay with my kids, and this is awesome, okay?
And we searched for it, the Nintendo Switch costs
a lot of money, right?
And I thought what if somebody misspelled the word Nintendo
and so we searched for different renditions of the word
Nintendo and we searched for the word Nintento, okay,
with a T at the end, T-O instead of D-O,
and that's how we bought this for a very, very low price.
Pretty cool.
And I bring this up, I'm back to camera,
I bring this up because we have to outsmart
our competition as well.
We need to use game theory, okay?
Every battle is won before it's been fought
and we need to be preemptive and proactive and think
like they might think and be two or three chess moves
ahead of them at all times, all dimes, times, okay.
Alright, so that's one example, okay.
I'm gonna give you a couple of other examples.
Again, I'm gonna let this film roll,
I'm not going to edit it at all, okay.
And you can skip to the next lecture if you don't have time
but here I go.
This here is a game-used
1987 baseball bat by Andre Dawson.
He was the MVP that year and my mom got it for me.
It's broken, right, as a Christmas present in the late '80s
and I loved it, it was awesome.
And one day I came home from work and my kids were
playing baseball with it in the back yard, true story.
I was mortified!
I was like, you can't do that!
And they were like, why, Dad, it's a bat, duh.
And so what I did was I brought it in to work, okay?
This was in 2007 when I worked
for a hedge fund called Pquant.
And I left it there in my office,
and my boss at the time is a guy named Carson Levitt,
great guy.
Alright, he's my mentor, too, in this industry.
He saw Andre Dawson in town here in San Francisco
because the All Star game was here at that time
and he called me at home one night, right, 2007.
And the phone rang and my wife's like, you know,
Christine said, it's Carson, your boss.
I was like, oh, my God.
A boss never calls you at home, am I in trouble?
And he said this, he was so cool, he said,
"Chris, you're not gonna believe this."
"I just saw Andre Dawson at some MLB alumni event
downtown San Francisco."
"I'm not that far away from the office,
do you want me to go to the office and get your bat
and get it signed?"
Hell yeah, I said!
And he did that, it's signed here, right?
And then I'm gonna make up this next part.
And see, this piece of wood, it might be worthless
to many people, right?
I mean, a wood of this weight might cost you, I don't know,
20 cents max, or much less than that.
But it's actually worth a lot more money than that
because of the sentimental value.
The same can be said for our product.
With the right marketing strategy,
we can create product awareness, an incredible sentimental
thought process with our customers such that the products
they buy from us are worth much more to them in their hearts
than the building materials, okay?
Wasn't perfect, but you get the idea, okay?
And, again, you can just delete, or go to the end
of this lecture if you want.
I'm gonna give you a couple of more examples, okay.
When I was a kid my mom made me read an hour a day, right?
And I hated it, right, but it was during the summer
so my brain wouldn't turn to rock.
And so I do that with my kids as well and Andrew, my son,
he was born in New York City and so he's the only
New York Yankees fan in the house, right?
And, I'm a Blue Jays fan, as you know, right,
from Toronto, but he's a New York fan, right?
Which is not cool but it's okay and here's why.
One of the books he chose to read during the summer
was a book by Derek Jeter, right, from the New York Yankees.
And the book he read was called The Contract.
And I asked him to summarize the book and, oh my God,
this blew me away because now I understand why Derek Jeter
is so successful in every aspect of his life.
Here's why.
His parents, every year, I think it was every January,
they would make him write a one page contract from the age
of nine years old and onwards, okay?
And on that one page contract he had to give to his parents
he would say stuff like, you know, I'll be polite
to mom and dad, I'll get As and Bs in my courses at school,
I'll practice baseball, I'll go to church,
or whatever it might have been, okay?
It's, that's rudimentary goal setting, right?
It's goal setting.
And that's one of the reasons Derek Jeter's so successful,
goal setting.
So, write down your goals.
Pretty cool, pretty cool.
Alright, I got another example but I got to go downstairs
to get this one so bear with me.
(grunting)
Okay, I got it, I got it.
Yeah, there's no downstairs, okay, you know that.
Alright, so I'm bad actor, I know it.
This here is a ticket from the first Blue Jay game
in history in 1977, right, and that was the,
I remember that year was so awesome for Canadians
because Star Wars came out and Toronto got a baseball team.
Right?
1977.
And back then tickets were really, really big
and they weren't very environmentally friendly
because that wastes a lot of paper, right?
But now, obviously, I'm totally kidding, totally kidding.
But what I could do is I could talk about something
sentimental and if I'm presenting in Toronto, you know,
I can talk about, I can talk about this.
And, you know, if it's a marketing convention,
I can tie it into brand awareness and sentimental value
and that sort of thing.
I'm kind of tired because I had to
carry this thing from downstairs.
Okay, alright.
What else do I have here?
Oh, here's one here.
Networking is very important, very important.
It's, I found that by leveraging my background,
and you can do the same thing too,
I was able to get meetings with some very successful people,
people that will be much more successful
than I ever will be.
An example is this.
You know, my mom is Lebanese, here maiden name is Hadad,
and a buddy of mine that works for Morgan Stanley
in New York introduced me to the CEO of New York,
a guy named, a guy named John Mack.
And he's Lebanese as well and, you know, I told him
I'm part Lebanese and I established a great relationship
with the guy just based on talking about
what we have in common.
And it was so cool because I met with him on a Thursday
and I flew back from New York to San Francisco
and by the time I got back, this was sitting on my desk.
Alright, it was a book from him on the Lebanese.
Pretty cool, pretty cool.
Alright.
And so the bottom line here is please make sure to network.
Network with as many people as you can, yada, yada,
you get the idea.
I'm winging it here, okay?
Alright, here's another one.
I had the opportunity to meet Jimmy Carter, right,
along with many, many other people.
He was signing books at my MBA school and I lined up, right,
and I got this book from him and he signed it as well.
And, you know, this is, it's important to me.
I thought he was a really good guy, right,
and he has such an incredibly positive attitude.
But what blew me away about Jimmy Carter was that
there was a guy standing in line, you know, right before me,
right, and he got to the front of the line and he approached
Jimmy Carter and the Secret Service men were looking like
this, you know, everywhere, whatever, that's what they do.
Are they listening to music or something, I don't know.
Just kidding.
And so this guy asked Jimmy Carter to help him
in his home country, right,
with helping to stop civil unrest in a certain region.
And rather than Jimmy Carter just pushing him aside
he talked to him for a while, right, and I didn't care,
I was waiting, I was enjoying just hearing about it, right?
And he actually set up a meeting between this man
and himself later on that day to help him with the problems
in his country.
And Jimmy Carter was so incredibly genuine, right?
And that's probably one of the reasons he became President.
I mean, he was only a one-term President,
but he's just real and very trustworthy and just
salt of the Earth type of guy.
So, you know, I learned from here, from him,
the importance of strength and sincerity, okay?
Okay, I'm gonna keep going here.
And, again, you can just skip the rest of this
if you get the idea, okay?
We're talking about props.
Okay.
This is from my son, okay?
Alright, that's him, Dylan, and that's me, Dad, right?
Because I'm taller than him because he's a kid, right?
And he gave this to me on Father's Day and it touched
my heart so much that a lot of you might have noticed,
I'm making this up, that I actually skipped
our last conference.
And the reason I did was because Dylan gave this to me
and he said,
Dad, you missed my last,
actually, this part is true,
you missed my last Daddy and son,
or child, day at school.
You go into school, right?
It's true, I did miss it.
He goes, can you make sure you never miss one again?
And I said, of course, and I went with him in.
The weird thing is, when I miss Dylan/Daddy day at school,
right, which is once a year,
I don't remember why I missed it.
It was something, obviously, work related but I don't
remember why I missed it.
Of course, I remember skipping his events,
which is selfish of me, but I don't remember
what I did at work.
What could possibly have been more important
than spending time with my son?
Nothing, nothing.
Okay.
Alright.
What else do I have here?
Here's another one.
This is one of the best business books ever written, okay?
It's called The Intelligent Investor and it's written by
a guy named Benjamin Graham.
And Warren Buffet went to Columbia University only because
Benjamin Graham taught at that university, right?
And Warren Buffet and I have one thing in common,
we both got rejected by Harvard Business School, HBS,
2/3 of which is BS, and yes, you can quote me on that.
Thank you, right?
Okay.
Anyway, so I read this book, I marked it up a lot.
And Mr. Buffet came in and he presented to us, right?
And he was there with his late wife at the time.
This was back in, I think it was 1999 when he presented,
right, just a guest speaker.
And he actually said that he brought this book
on his honeymoon, right?
This is what he read on his honeymoon
and it changed his life.
And, the bottom line here is that
if you're a value investor, you're very long-term focused,
right, and Warren Buffet said something that blew my mind.
He said, you know, the longer the view,
the wiser the intention, right?
So, anyway, I brought this and I should have got him
to sign it, kind of like I did Jimmy Carter.
What was I thinking?
He was right there in front of me.
I mean there was a gazillion other people there but,
anyway, it is what it is.
Okay.
Oh yeah, this one, I remember this, okay.
This here is a movie called Keeping the Faith, right?
It was only okay.
It was with Edward Norton and Ben Stiller, who's a good guy.
And I'll never forget this.
I was in New York City with my buddy, Rich Madozow,
and we were in business school then,
and we walked home from a bar at 2:00 in the morning
and we might have, maybe, had too much to drink,
I don't know.
And we walked in to some bar that was closed, right,
in New York the bars closed earlier then I think,
and we sat down and we're surprised it was still open
and the bartender was cool
and gave us a couple of beers, right?
I think I had a Molsen Canadian or something,
'cause represent.
And all of a sudden, Ed Norton walked in and so did
Ben Stiller and Jenna Elfman.
And a bunch of other people walked in as well, right?
I was like, what the hell is going on,
there's like 40 or 50 people here.
And Ben Stiller sat down beside me and he said to me,
he said to me, it was the coolest thing, Ben Stiller.
He said, can you believe we're still filming?
I didn't know what to say so I said this, right?
And you can verify because I'm in this movie, I said this,
I said, I know, I just want to go home, I'm tired.
And he was like, yeah, you and me both, right?
And so what happened was the Director, right,
I think it was Edward Norton I think was directing
at the time, right, he walked in the bar
and he pointed at my friend and I and said,
you and you, and I was like, God damn it, we're busted.
Right?
He said, you and you, you're the lead extras
in the next scene, right?
And I was like, yes!
And so, what happened was there's a scene here in
Keeping the Faith where their coming out of a restaurant
called Carmine's on the Upper West Side of New York City.
And they did about eight or nine takes.
And I walked holding this woman's hand into the bar
behind these three people and I ordered a drink.
So, anyway, that's me taking a risk in my life
and I believe in taking risks, whatever.
Keeping the Faith, true story, pretty funny.
Anyway.
I never got paid for that movie either.
But I think that's, that's, that's it.
Yeah, that's all I got, that's all I got, okay?
And so, you know, the bottom line is just, you know,
try to, when you bring in an item, a prop,
just make sure that it ties into
why you're speaking to them.
Make sure it's relevant.
In some of the examples I gave you,
it was somewhat relevant.
I kind of made up a, you know, a reason why it was relevant.
But make sure it's relevant at all times, right?
It's, I guess just to end it, end it off here,
I want you to watch, there's a George Clooney movie,
right, and he did an amazing job of discussing a backpack
as a prop in his movie called Up in the Air,
I think was the name, right?
And how much does your life weigh
and what's in your backpack?
So, check out this video as a way to wrap up this lecture
on bringing props to your speeches,
as a way to start your speech.