Alright, now it's time to structure
your brilliant contents.
We are done discussing the silver cap bucket,
it's now time to fill up the gold structure buckets
with our outline, okay?
And I'll explain how to do this soon, okay?
Just stay with me, please.
But in this lecture
I wanna talk about a more generic structured process
for your speech plus an exercise
to really help you structure
and order your contents, okay?
Now, you already have a decent idea
how to start your speech
as we covered this in your journal exercise number four,
Starting Your Presentation.
And in the next scene called Act Three, Scene Three,
we're gonna cover how to end your speech,
including thinking about how to reinforce
the bottom line message, and thanking people,
and the next steps if there is a call to action
from your audience, okay?
Okay, let's just talk about the middle stuff in your speech,
meaning not the start and not the end, okay?
When you write an essay
you have an introduction paragraph,
and a concluding paragraph, okay?
Everything in the middle, right, in-between
is used to discuss the supporting arguments or ideas
or stories or general descriptions, okay?
So, here's a very basic essay outline
that is also applicable to speeches, okay?
And you can even consider
visualizing the outline of your speech
using a similar bucket-based process,
and showing them to your audience
when you start your speech
if the speech is really long,
and if your audience is expecting an outline, okay,
meaning if you work at a company that appreciates
outline and structure all in itself.
Your call, your call, okay?
My job is to give you a menu of items,
and then you select what option is best for you, okay?
So, each topic
can be a business idea,
a recap of our progress,
an option to consider implementing.
I don't know.
A story about the groom about to be married,
a story about a family member,
a small part of a short toast.
We can then add another layer of structure
to our speech as follows, okay?
For each topic
we can discuss W5, right.
W5 means what, why, where,
when, who, right?
And then the next bucket is called how, right?
And then just to be objective,
you know, we can think about discussing
the risks with our presentation topic
because during the Q and A session
somebody might ask you about risks, right,
or holes in your logic, right,
and you can reiterate what you think
the biggest risk is to topic number one etc.
Okay.
Again, you don't have to use everything I'm showing you
but I need to introduce this concept
as it will make our next exercise
of structuring the content easier for you, okay?
Don't worry though
because we can add more structure
or more sections later on.
You know, I just want to help you
organize your contents, okay?
Now, please watch the next lecture
called Journal Exercise Number Seven,
Structuring and Ordering the Content,
and I will show you an example of structuring,
and then sorting the content.
Thank you.