Business presentations usually end with a conclusion,
next steps, or a call to action.
Personal or award receiving presentations
often end with thanking people,
which we'll cover in two lectures from now,
not the next lecture, the one after that.
We will also cover the presentation Q and A strategy
in Act Seven.
So in the next few lectures,
I'm going to explain many different ways
to end your speech,
and please feel free to use one of the strategies I mention,
or combine a couple of them.
For example, instead of just ending with a conclusion,
you can also end with thanking people,
giving credit to others, asking for the sale,
or networking by asking people
to connect with you on LinkedIn, et cetera.