Let's talk about minimalism.
Less is more.
Simplicity works best.
Making slides that have minimal detail on them
is not for every occasion
as complex software program
or engineering related presentations
can be tough to minimalize, okay?
But you can do it and it's actually less work.
It's easier to understand as well, okay.
And just as a side note.
I'm gonna explain how to articulate more complex topics
in the case study section of this act
when we talk about using animation to build upon
and explain very complex topics.
But when it comes to minimalism,
I wanna stress that I really believe that less is more
in business communications
and I want you to really try hard
to never have more than three bullet points on a slide
because we just can't retain more than three things
at a time, right?
It is what it is
and so try to experiment with even less than three ideas
on a slide if you can.
Simplicity works extraordinarily well, right?
And we're conditioned
to not read instruction manuals anymore
or to hit that F1 key on a keyboard for help, right?
My kids don't even know what that means F1, right?
The way it works now is if it's not intuitive
then you gotta rethink it please.
Just keep it simple.
Kinda like this device that Steve Jobs pioneered.
It's just got one button, right?
There's no instruction manual on how to use this.
And I used to be a software programmer for years
and we used to create these complex
client server-based applications, right?
But what's happened is in software,
all you gotta know how to use is a browser.
Forward, back, home, stop, refresh.
That's it, right?
You never really have to learn how to use a website, right?
If it's not intuitive then people won't pay attention
so if it's not intuitive,
please rethink your slide structure.
Just keep it simple, right?
And use simple language as well, okay?
Steve Jobs was amazing at this, right?
He used to use words like insanely great on his slides.
And one online magazine company that I wrote for
actually asked me to write at an eighth grade level.
I know it sounds out there,
but I guess minimalism works, right?
And you wanna cast your net as wide as you can.
And so minimalism on slides is very effective too
when it comes to showing contrast
like in these sample slides.