The last letter in PIMCO is O for Original.
Right, I try to be original with this.
I know that we mentioned the word "different"
in our content creation strategy earlier in the course
but I really, really want you to be different, okay?
I included a synonym for it,
O, Original, same thing as different
because I want you to think different,
kinda like Steve Jobs did, and if you think different,
then you'll really stand out and you'll give this incredibly
passionate and memorable performance.
Right? Just be different.
Be you. Okay?
Okay, so being original makes people remember you.
And conforming for presentations
doesn't really have the same effect.
How boring is it if you use the same structure
that everybody else uses in your company?
You'll never stand out, right?
And if you wanna move your way up the corporate ladder,
there's fewer people at the top
than there are at mid-level management,
you've gotta stand out.
Or, if you want to be a very successful entrepreneur
you gotta be different
and the most successful entrepreneurs I've ever met
are the ones that are just really, really different
and they don't care what people think about them.
You know, I'll never forget when I saw Marc Benioff.
I worked in this building, I think it was One Market Street
in San Francisco and Marc Benioff,
the founder of Salesforce.com worked there as well,
and sometimes I'd see him walking his Labrador,
his beautiful dog, in bare feet
on the main floor in the building.
He just doesn't, he's just him.
He's different. He's awesome.
Kinda like Steve Jobs was different.
You think different and that's why you become successful.
You're just different, right?
And the same thing goes for musicians, right?
Madonna's different, U2 is different,
Jay Z is different, and they don't try to be somebody else.
And nobody is successful in music
because they're just like somebody else.
There's not somebody that's successful because,
hey, that dude's kinda like Jay Z
or that guy reminds me of Drake or Adele.
No, there's only one Adele.
There's only one Jay Z. There's only one you.
So, conforming for presentations
doesn't have the same effect, okay?
And I know that some people might not want
to stand out from others when they present,
but I humbly disagree and I think that taking
calculated risks can really help to advance your career.
And I don't think that you can achieve
all of your dreams in life without taking risks,
especially when you present.
Here's a great quote from Mark Zuckerberg.
He said, "The biggest risk is not taking any risk.
"In a world that's changing really quickly
"the only strategy that is guaranteed to fail
"is not taking risks."
And there's this amazing Chinese proverb which is,
"Pearls don't lie on the seashore.
"If you want one, you must dive for it."
Dive and take a risk.
And Deepak Chopra said this,
"The universe has no restrictions.
"You place restrictions on the universe
"with your expectations."
You know, the biggest critic you have is you, right?
And if people try to make you conform when you present
and you feel almost claustrophobic,
then keep this in mind from Steve Jobs, please.
"Your time is limited, so don't waste it
living someone else's life."
So, risk-taking and being different
is really important in the arts as well.
You know, concept albums like "Pet Sounds" by the Beach Boys
or "Sgt. Pepper's" by The Beatles
were risks at the time, right?
But because they were so different, they were successful.
You know, many of these people on the cover of
this album by The Beatles were different, right?
It's a beautiful album, "Sgt. Pepper's."
Listen to it if you haven't, please.
And if you have, listen to it again.
It's prophetic, it's poetic, it's amazing.
It's a masterpiece of art, kinda like your presentation's
going to be and your slides will be.
I want you to be different and just take a chance
and be different when you present.
You know, life is too short to conform.
You know, just be unique and create an
Oscar-worthy experience when you present.
And dammit, have fun doing it, too.
Thank you.