Let's talk about customizing and adding images
using PowerPoint.
So first of all,
let's go and get an image.
So I'm going to my favorite image website,
which is GraphicStock.
And let's just type in the word minimal.
So let's grab this one here.
Okay, so we'll download it.
It's a very small file.
All right.
Great.
We'll insert it,
we'll go to downloads here,
and this is the image.
Okay.
Very simplistic.
We can change the size.
We can manipulate it quite a bit.
Okay and so first of all, let me kick it off with borders
and then I'll change the colors and what not.
And very soon, in a couple minutes,
I'm gonna show you how to get rid of
what's in the background
for making an image transparent
which adds a nice pop effect.
So first of all, we can customize
the background of our image using all of these.
I won't spend too much time on this,
but it's a lot of fun.
And Keynote, you can do the same thing as well.
Okay, great.
Now if we click on picture format,
let's change the transparency, right?
You can make it hardly visible
or you can make it much more visible.
And you can always go here
which is resetting the picture, okay?
We can change the color as well right here.
And that is that for this one.
Let's do another one now, okay?
Delete.
Let's get something that's a little bit more advanced.
Okay, let's get the sun.
And say we wanted to use this one here,
but we didn't want that background, right?
So I'll show you how to do that.
We go again, insert, picture, from file,
there's the sun.
Okay cool.
Say we want to get rid of the black background
around the outside.
So what you do is you go here to remove background, right?
Microsoft it makes it pretty simple to do.
Okay.
And whenever you see purple,
that's what's gonna be removed, okay?
But I want to remove everything around the side of it
and not forget about that little corner piece there.
Let's go here,
and then click here,
and you're done.
And it looks a little bit,
I don't know, it doesn't look like there's a
clean outside portion to this.
So what you could do is
you could actually crop it, right?
And so cropping basically allows you to
change the size of the image
or what you wanna see, that sort of thing.
Let me just get out of there.
I'm wanna show you how to crop a circular image as well.
Okay?
You can go crop to shape.
Okay, then you can resize it,
do whatever you want to artistically as well, right?
And because it's color,
you can do a lot more artistic effects here.
So let's click this guy here.
Looks like if this sun was in the movie The Matrix
it would look like that.
Then let's say we don't want the green Matrix sun anymore.
We go here to color
and we can alter it a little bit.
Say for some reason,
you want to have, I don't know, a blue moon.
And then if we go to artistic effects,
we can change it to look a little bit more grainy
or whatever that is.
And then if you wanted to resize it,
throw it in the corner,
you can do that sort of thing.
So it's pretty powerful.
There's a lot of really cool basic things you can do here.
Again, PhotoShop is much more advanced
but I want to keep it simplistic
and just have you work smarter but not harder.
Now let's grab another image
to see if we can layer on top of that one.
So we'll go back here.
We still have the keyword search sun.
Scroll down,
let's just grab any random image.
Let's grab this guy here, okay.
And then we'll insert it,
pictures,
here we go.
Let's say that, I don't know,
we want to put the sun right on top of that.
But you see how it's in the background, the sun?
So what you do is,
and all Microsoft applications
and programmers on Microsoft platforms
try to anticipate what you want to do
when you right click on something.
So let's right click on this. Right?
And what you can do is you can say,
hey, bring it to the front place.
Okay?
So there is is there, okay?
And then you're like,
well I kind of want to see
part of that background image, right?
So what you can do is you can go to transparency here, okay?
And make it somewhat transparent.
Right, you see that?
It's kind of a nice little touch.
All right.
So let's resize this,
make it the size of the sun there.
I don't know why you'd want to do this,
but whatever.
It's kind of cool.
Looks like the moon is on the sun now.
Okay, and then for this image here,
let's say we want to manipulate this one
a little bit as well.
So you can go here to remove background.
And whenever you see purple,
that's the stuff that's going to be removed, okay?
So let's say for fun,
I don't know why you'd do this,
but we just want to have a couple
of these green leaves shown, right?
But for some reason,
we don't want to have any blue background.
Okay.
So very high quality images,
meaning ones that take up a lot of space,
can be more manipulated than others, okay?
And when you do what I'm about to show you,
you're gonna make a lot of mistakes, right?
So it's never perfect.
So you hit Control+Z and you keep doing it
until it looks perfect for you.
Okay?
So let me just take a second here to make these changes.
And it takes a while to make it perfect.
What I'm gonna do now is
I'm gonna go on fast forward,
and I'll show you the final product.
Okay and let's say we're done.
You click outside here
and there you have it.
Just the leaves.
Okay, and that doesn't look that great,
so let's get a different backdrop
to throw in the background just for fun.
Okay, so let's go here
and we'll search for, I don't know,
sky.
Okay, sky, and then we'll insert it.
Insert, sky,
here you go.
Cool.
Okay, now we want to add this sky to the back.
So again, you right click
and you go send to back.
Okay it's looking better.
Let's say we want to add some birds there as well.
So let me go here to birds.
And this won't look that realistic.
But that's okay.
And let's say we want to add a shadow.
There you go.
So you know, PowerPoint is pretty powerful
when it comes to this stuff.
Lot of people don't give it enough credit for this,
but there you go.
There you go.
I mean it's not an amazing image,
but I showed you how to get rid of a background, right?
It's pretty cool.
So let's say that you have a lot of images
and you can't remember what's the very back,
what's the beginning.
And say you want to bring this blue moon
in front of the birds for whatever reason.
So you can go here to arrange,
and then select reorder objects.
And this is pretty cool.
Okay, so and I showed you this before really quickly.
So say we want to throw the blue moon in front.
You could do that.
You click okay.
Now let's say I wanted the birds and the moon
to stay together
because I always want them to stick together
when I'm moving images around
and it gets kind of complicated otherwise.
Control+Z.
Here's what you're gonna do.
Now if I just click on the birds,
watch what happens.
It gets confused,
it's like no, I'm choosing this.
So what you have to do is
you have to kind of zoom out a bit.
Go down here, zoom out.
And then you highlight around it
by clicking there and highlighting what you want
to group together.
There they are.
Then you right click and you say group,
and those are together now, okay?
Now let's say I wanted to export this image
and maybe throw it into an email or something, whatever.
So what I can do is this.
You hit Control+A,
Copy,
and then what you do is you say
Paste Special, okay?
And you paste it as a picture, okay?
Now.
This item here is a picture.
All that stuff is together, okay?
And let's say I wanted to crop it a bit.
Okay, so you go up here to picture format,
crop,
and then we can crop it.
So we want to have kind of a nicer, neater look.
And then you can right click on it
and say save it as a picture, right?
And you save it as a picture,
many different formats,
and you can insert in email
or do whatever you want to do with that.
Now let's say I wanted to have a shadow on this.
We copy it,
throw in a new slide.
Remember you gotta right click, okay?
And then I'm gonna hit paste,
and then I go here to picture format,
and I can add a shadow like that,
which is just the style that I personally like.
And then if we were to play it,
it would look like this. Right?
It's kinda neat.
Kinda neat, let me go up a screen
and see what the previous image looks like.
And play around with the picture formatting here.
There's so many cool things you can do, right?
It looks really, really awesome.
Now you can only apply one of these things at a time, right?
It's a little bit limited.
But hey, it's so easy to use.
Sometimes I like to have this here
where you can see the reflection.
And let's just delete this.
And say I wanted to have kinda more cool effects
with the leaves here.
Corn, or whatever that is.
I go here to artistic effects, okay?
Looks neat.
And say we want to change the birds around,
but this is already grouped, remember?
So we're gonna have to ungroup this.
Group,
ungroup.
And say for this background here,
say we want to change that around as well.
Let's go to artistic effects here.
Let's try another one.
Isn't that wild?
Let's take a look at it.
Pretty cool, huh?
That's from layering.
Amazing, amazing.
If you have any questions about
manipulating pictures with PowerPoint,
please let me know.
There's a lot of cool stuff you can do.
Thanks.