(upbeat music)
Let's talk about creating off the charts confidence
by studying elite professional athletes.
In my very humble opinion,
baseball pitching great Bob Gibson
had arguably the best season of any professional athlete
in the world in 1968.
Nobody's more fearless or more competitive
or more confident than Bob Gibson.
He said that he wasn't just in the zone
on one or two occasions in 1968,
he was in the zone for the entire year.
And if you have time, check out this interview with him.
It's amazing.
He had the best season in baseball history.
He was a pitcher.
For those of you not familiar with pitching,
some people say that it's a primal battle
between a man with a stick and a man with a rock.
Without confidence, you can't shine.
How is there not a movie
about this baseball legend, Bob Gibson?
I want you and I, you and me,
not sure which grammar's correct,
I want us, how's that? (laughs)
I want us to be in the B.G.Z.
I want us to be in the B.G.Z.,
which is the Bob Gibson Zone.
In 1968, he dominated baseball.
And in that interview that you can watch if you want to,
he said it never felt like work.
That's that way you gotta be.
It's gotta feel like you love what you're doing
when you're presenting, otherwise you won't shine up there.
It's tough to act.
You gotta kind of just be you up there and have fun.
When you present and when you prepare to present,
again make sure it feels like
something you absolutely love doing,
or you won't be really confident.
And I'm talking to you right now,
and I'm so passionate about what I do
that I don't have a job.
I'm successful if you're successful.
If you're not successful presenting, I'm a failure.
We're in this together.
Together, we're going to get into this zone
where we can passionately create our speech
and deliver not a presentation, but we will deliver
a passionate and confident experience.
There's nothing better than watching somebody
who's incredibly passionate about their profession.
Like Jodie Foster, for example, in the movie Contact.
Check out this clip if you have time.
She's so passionate.
You gotta respect that.
And I really respect professional athletes
when they're really passionate about what they're doing,
or anybody, for that matter, that's passionate
about their trade.
I love watching movies about people
that are really inspiring and confident
and believe they can change the world.
Another example is Jeff Bridges in Tucker.
Great movie, great movie.
Please condition yourself to know that you love
what you are doing.
If you love what you do, then you'll be even more confident,
and you can condition yourself to believe that.
Most people that are at the top of their game
see it as a game and not work,
and they're incredibly confident because of that.
It's interesting, because you watch professional athletes
and sometimes they get upset on TV,
and they don't really care
that the whole world is watching their emotions.
They're just them.
It's interesting.
So I want you to have the focus.
I want you to have the confidence.
I want you to have the determination of an elite athlete,
not just for your presentation event day,
but for the whole preparation stage.
I want you to put it all on the line.
This is all that matters.
So confidence is like a light switch,
and it comes from within.
Only you have the power to turn on that switch.
Whether or not you think you can do something, you're right.
I'm gonna say that again.
I don't personally know what your favorite sport is.
But whatever it is, please study the best athletes
in that sport and watch interviews with them on YouTube
and highlight reels of their accomplishments
as confidence is incredibly contagious.
And not all athletes are very well-spoken,
but when they interview, they don't really care.
They don't care, they're just confident.
They're in that zone, and I want you
to be in that zone too, please.
These elite athletes also don't care what they look like.
A lot of them go out in the field
and they put that black stuff under their eye,
and they just don't care.
And then baseball, it's interesting,
a lot of them have beards now and long hair, whatever.
It is what it is.
They don't care what others think of them.
They're in the confidence zone.
And if they cared about what other people thought,
they would be distracted.
They are money, and so are you.
Please use your own unique style
and don't be influenced by other people,
especially those people with a dangerous combination
of being arrogant and ignorant.
You know exactly who I'm talking about.
Again, you be you and ignore what others think.
This is the winning, confident athlete attitude
that I want you to use.
Use their philosophy.
Separately, thank God for these people.
Thank God they were very confident,
or the world would be a different place today.
By the same token, if you become more confident
and present better, think of how you will make
the entire world a better place.
I have to repeat that again.
If you become more confident and present better,
think of how you will make the entire world a better place.
You can make a difference, and you will.
By the same token, if you become more confident
and present better, think of how you will make the lives
of everybody around you better.
Anyone that hurts your confidence,
I want you to please write them off and never see them again
if you can, because they are standing in the way
of you and greatness.
And separately, unjustified criticism is nothing more
than a disguised compliment.
I have to say that again.
Sorry I'm repeating things,
but this quote means so much to me.
Unjustified criticism is nothing more
than a disguised compliment.
So bring it on, doubters.
As you get even more successful in your life
and in your career, you can get criticized more.
But again, just think of that quote.
Unjustified criticism is nothing more
than a disguised compliment.
So bring it on, doubters, because when you criticize me
and it's unjustified, that's a compliment.
I love it, and so should you.
Confidence comes from within.
Turn on that switch and get in that zone
when preparing for and when delivering your masterpiece
of a speech.
Whether or not you think you can, you are right.
And the only thing that matters opinion-wise
is your opinion of yourself.
(upbeat music)