I used to be absolutely terrified of public speaking
much more than you are or you were.
And it really held me back in my career
for a lot of my life.
I actually remember in business school
at Columbia University, and even during
the training program at Goldman Sachs,
I would always ask way more questions than my peers did
as I was really scared of being cold cocked.
I was scared of being put on the spot to present.
I was even "sick" when I was supposed to give a speech
when I was in high school.
I'll never forget that on a particular day.
And I found every reason not to do public speaking
for many many years.
And I eventually realized that you really
can't achieve all of your goals in life if you can't
confront your fears and master public speaking.
It's important.
And so finally I decided that enough is enough
and I needed to confront my biggest fear.
So what I'd do is I thought,
"How can I?
"How can I confront this fear?
"How can I confront this fear and eventually
"turn that weakness into a strength and enjoy it?"
And I thought, "That's crazy, Chris.
"You'll never enjoy something fearful."
A lot of people are just as fearful of public speaking
as they are getting really really hurt physically.
So I thought, "What can I do to confront my fear?"
So I actually do a lot of charity work.
I've always liked helping others,
so what I did was I volunteered in the prison system
here in California through my church.
And the reason I did this is because I wanted to
help these poor kids that were about 20 years old
that didn't have the luxury of having two loving parents
growing up like I did.
A lot of them had deadbeat fathers.
Never a deadbeat mother, it was usually the father left.
It was sad.
Many of these kids were put in prison
for ridiculously minor incidents.
And that could have been me if I were in the wrong place
at the wrong time, or without two loving parents
that watched over me.
And you know exactly what I mean.
If you got caught for doing something at the wrong time
you could have got in a lot of trouble.
You know maybe your parents pushed you back
on the right path, but these poor students,
or these poor kids I should say,
in jail, they didn't have that.
They didn't have the luxury of having two loving parents.
So here's what I did.
I volunteered at a prison in Redwood City, California,
called the Maguire Correctional Facility
which is right here.
You can see in this video.
I'm zooming right into it.
So I started giving speeches there to kind of help
those poor kids that were incarcerated.
I wanted to teach them life skills and mentorship
and really inspire them to turn their lives around.
Right, it's never too late.
I was only supposed to present to a couple inmates
at a time, and they gave me a police pass.
They did a background check and everything
to get me to go in there.
And then something absolutely terrifying happened to me.
I was actually scared.
I showed up at the prison on a Sunday morning,
or Sunday, actually it was around 1:00 p.m.
that day on a Sunday which is the usual time
I would show up.
The priest that was supposed to conduct mass
didn't show up that day.
This is not a religious thing.
I would help anybody, okay.
But the priest that was supposed to conduct mass
didn't show up that day, and the warden said to me,
"Well Haroun, it's up to you.
"You have to conduct mass."
Oh, my God.
I seriously thought about coming up with an excuse
like I did in high school.
I thought about turning around and walking away
and just finding some excuse not to do it.
This is kind of like a personal intervention.
I had to force myself to follow through.
And I said, "Screw it, I have to confront this fear
"of mine right now because it's holding me back,
"and I can't take it any more."
And when you go to religious service, quite often
what happens is you read a passage
from say the Old Testament or whatever it is.
And then the priest or the religious leader
gives a speech based on that passage.
And of course they have many weeks
to prepare for each speech.
And they've spent their whole life doing this as well
citing whatever book it is that they read from.
And I thought, "How the heck am I going to
pull this off without any preparation
and, more importantly, without passing out?"
So, I got to get some water for this one. Sorry.
Alright, so I cleared the security doors,
cause you have to go through a lot of security checks.
You have to go, there's two doors closed,
one behind you and one in front of you,
and there's a camera and you have
to say your name and look up.
Anyway, a lot of checks.
And then the officer there escorted me to the breakout room
where I was to present to these inmates,
many of which should not have been there.
And so I stood in front of them absolutely terrified.
My knees were shaking.
Many of them were crammed and seated in this small room
and they had these orange jumpsuits on.
And when you go, you're not allowed
to wear anything orange for obvious reasons.
And a lot of them have their arms crossed like this.
And some of them had tattoos on their heads
and right here with profanities.
Tattoos, right, it was really intimidating.
And again many of them didn't deserve to be there.
And that could have been me if I was caught
at the wrong time in my life.
And so I read that the pamphlet, right,
they give me a pamphlet that was given by the church.
Remember the priest wasn't there so I had to fill in.
And that particular gospel passage that I read from
was all about hope and faith and all that good stuff.
And so after I finished reading the passage,
I was supposed to give a speech about the topic
that I just read
which was about hope.
And so I stared at the inmates.
They had their arms crossed.
They were staring right back at me.
Some of them had these really negative looks on their face.
You can imagine.
So I started giving a speech that I made up on the spot.
I had no idea what I was going to say.
So I said this, "Do you believe in God?"
And a bunch of the inmates kind of went, "Yeah."
I then paused.
I said, "Does God believe in you?"
And a couple more inmates said, "Yeah."
Then I said this, "Well if you don't believe in yourself,
"then you might have to question your faith."
I paused again for a few seconds.
And I felt a sense of calmness and peace
and love in my heart.
Almost like this public speaking handicap
that had been holding me back for so many years
had been lifted from me.
I'm getting shivers just thinking of it right now.
My knees stopped shaking as I saw many of the inmates
uncross their arms.
They opened up.
A few of them I remember took deep breaths.
And I saw one man's angry eyebrows rise.
I'll never forget that.
Another one smiled at me.
Actually it was the one with the crazy tattoo that said,
I can't say it, okay.
And another one looked up at the ceiling
as if there was some kind of sense of temporary relief.
It was a eunuch experience for me.
The only thing I can remember saying is,
"Thank you."
I paused and my heart opened up.
I actually said this too, "You need not worry
"as God already knows what's gonna happen.
"And that should really give you peace of mind
"and instill a sense of self-worth and confidence
"and happiness and hope in your heart."
So since that day,
my biggest fear has become my biggest sense of joy.
And I only wish that I had the guts
and that I had that revelation and sense of love
and humbly empowering the empowerers events
occur earlier in my life.
So whether or not you think you can do something,
you're right, and quite often you
are your biggest enemy.
I think of those prisoners staring at me
with the negative looks.
That might be you staring at yourself in the mirror.
You got to change your perception.
So now I love to teach.
I love to teach many classes and seminars
on how to give presentations.
And many students open up and feel that
they can accomplish anything.
And one of my proudest moments when I was teaching
was there was this guy.
His name was Yon.
And he approached me at the very beginning of class.
I'd teach for a couple of months in a row.
And he said, "Chris, I'm really scared of public speaking."
And I said, "Okay, okay, halfway through this course,
"you're gonna present to the entire class, right."
And he was kind of scared and I got him to do it
and he aced it, and then at graduation
I had him speak as well.
And I literally had a tear in my eye.
It was amazing.
So I want you to embrace this fear right now if it's a fear.
I want you to turn your biggest perceived weakness
into your biggest strength, okay.
And people might forget what you say,
but they'll never forget the way you made them feel.
They never forget the way you made them feel.
And when you put your heart into anything
your mind stops caring what others think,
and you become more confident when you speak
in front of large groups of people.
A little cheesy, but here I go.
Confidence is key.
So just like Bob Gibson in pitching on the mound.
And when I was younger it was.
This is too tight.
Let me undo this a bit.
When I was younger, for some reason
people left the tags on their baseball hats.
So I'm gonna try and act cool and do that as well.
Official, MLB.
Okay, here we go.
Okay, this is actually a Saint Louis hat
that Bob Gibson used.
Not the exact same one, but the same style.
So just like Bob Gibson on the mound pitching,
we have to revisit this chart.
Let me draw it for you.
I'm gonna step over here.
Hopefully you can still hear me without the microphone.
So here's the chart, okay.
On the x axis here is your age, okay.
And then on the y axis is give a shhh darn,
give a darn, okay, okay.
So stay with me here.
In the middle here is what I call the triangle of despair.
And when you're younger, you are here
cause you don't care what people think.
Right, my kids are like that.
I was like that too.
Then when you're older, like me, you're here
and you don't care what people think.
Cause I'm old and I'm here.
Old people don't have confidence problems.
Young kids don't either.
Otherwise they wouldn't have meltdowns at restaurants.
And so most people are stuck in this triangle of despair.
And the key is I want you to remain
at this low level here like when you were a kid.
Remember when you were a kid and you were really creative
and you didn't care what people thought.
So I want you to stay at this level.
I want you to skip this stupid triangle here
cause it's holding you back.
It's holding you back when you care about
what other people think of you, within reason of course.
So Bob Gibson is an incredible pitcher.
Good, I didn't hit the camera with that.
I don't want you to be in jail,
(prison bars slamming)
this triangle of despair, okay.
I want you to break out of this jail.
Successful, confident people are never in this prison,
this triangle prison, right.
We need to break out
(prison bars opening)
of this prison
and only then will you be confident enough
to present from your heart and free your mind
of despair and be confident by being you.
(music from The Lion King)