Warren Buffett and I have three things in common.
The first thing is that we both got rejected by HBS
which is Harvard Business School,
two thirds of which is BS.
I know I've used that joke a lot before
but hey, they rejected me.
Okay, the second thing that Warren Buffett
and I have in common is that we were both
absolutely terrified of public speaking, right,
and we both took the Dale Carnegie public speaking course
at the age of 20, right, and I've got proof.
He took that at 20 as well, right?
So here's the course I took.
Back then, books looked really old like this, right?
Yeah.
So anyway, I took it and just to prove to you
that I took it,
I got the actual receipt here
and if you want, you can zoom in if you can
and you can calculate my age as well, okay?
I took that at 20.
Alright, put that away.
Okay, so I didn't know who Warren Buffett was obviously
when I was 20.
I didn't know much then, right,
but we both took that Dale Carnegie public speaking course
when we were 20, okay,
and my mom and my wife hate the fact
that I don't throw anything out at all, right?
You'll see from a lot of the props I use in this course
I keep everything, right,
except for my Wayne Gretzky rookie cards.
I use those on my bike so it sounds like a motorbike
'cause I'm an idiot.
Okay.
Okay and so, oh, by the way,
if you get a chance,
I want you to read this book here, okay?
It's a great book.
It's timeless.
It was initially published in the 30s, right?
It's published by this brilliant man named Dale Carnegie,
right, and so Dale Carnegie wrote this book,
How To Influence People.
That's the book I read, just kidding.
How To Win Friends and Influence People.
And it's timeless and Warren Buffett loves it as well
and he actually wrote this other one too.
It's kinda old school but people don't change, right?
So there's been six million copies
that have been sold of this version.
It's called How To Stop Worrying and Start Living
and Dale Carnegie talks about living
in day-tight compartments which means one day at a time.
Right?
So check it out if you can.
I think they're both great reads
and Warren Buffett loves it as well.
It's really timeless, it's really timeless, right,
and without Dale Carnegie, you wouldn't have
all of these great motivational speakers out there.
He was the first, okay?
Okay, so why are you mentioning Dale Carnegie, Chris?
So what?
Okay, well, on Warren Buffett's wall
is not his business degree from Columbia University, right,
or University of Nebraska, right?
He has two degrees.
On his wall is actually his public speaking certificate
that he earned from Dale Carnegie.
It's pretty amazing.
You see, Warren Buffett was terrified of public speaking.
He's just like us, right?
He was terrified of public speaking, right,
and he said that if he didn't confront his fear,
he would not have been successful, okay?
Now, the third thing that Warren Buffett
and I have in common is a huge admiration
for Dr. Martin Luther King,
not just what he stood for but his prophetic ability
to inspire a crowd, right?
He's amazing, he's amazing.
Dr. King's epic I Have a Dream speech
is still the best speech that I've ever seen
that's been filmed, right, and that's saying a lot
as his I Have a Dream speech was given by Dr. King
more than 50 years ago, on August 28th 1963.
Incredible.
Nobody comes close to delivering a speech like Dr. King did,
right, and it's not just the brilliant content
of his message but it's the prophetic,
perfect and passionate delivery that he has, okay?
It's genius.
So please watch it here, right,
if you haven't seen it in the past few weeks,
months or years, okay?
The way he changes his tone and his voice
really touches your heart, okay?
Now, Warren Buffett's favorite line from a Dr. King speech
was when he said, "we shall overcome
"and that scaffold swayed the future", okay?
"We shall overcome and that scaffold swayed the future."
Right, so it's really poetic and prophetic
and I'm actually getting butterflies
just thinking of this, okay?
And so Dr. King's delivery and confident
changing tone is really a work of art.
It's a masterpiece, okay,
and so this next speech here by Dr. King
is really worth listening to as well
and you'll hear him use those powerful words
that he created the epic
scaffold swayed the future quote here, okay?
And there's so many incredible parts to his speech
just like "the arc of the moral universe", right?
That's what he says as well, right?
It's amazing, it's amazing.
So I mean, I personally forget about citing poets
like Robert Frost or the writings of Shakespeare.
We should all spend more time
studying Dr. King's speeches for some many reasons, okay?
Now, Warren Buffett was so scared, this is funny,
he was so scared of public speaking
that he didn't wear glasses at his wedding
when he gave his speech
so he wouldn't have to see the crowd, right?
You see, Warren Buffett ran to his fear and confronted it
and if he didn't, we wouldn't know who he is today.
So you have to please run to your fears
and confront them right now
and turn any perceived weakness into a strength.
Why?
Because your competition certainly won't, okay?
This is holding you back, okay?
This is holding you back between where you are now
and greatness, okay, and Warren Buffett said that
learning how to embrace public speaking
and not fearing it changed his life
and Warren Buffett's really interesting
from a public speaking perspective
because he's so likable when he presents
and when he's being interviewed
because he is number one, personal, right?
Number two, he's self-deprecating.
He makes fun of himself, right,
and number three, he talks about what scared him
which is public speaking, right?
He's human.
And I suppose if somebody showed the opposite
of those three items I just mentioned
when speaking in an interview,
they wouldn't be nearly as likable, right?
So should you take the Dale Carnegie course?
Well, if you want to practice in front of people, right,
lots of people then yes, take it
'cause I always humbly believe
that an investment in yourself
is the best investment you will ever make, right,
and I cut a lot of lawns when I was a kid
to pay for the course, right?
It was a bit pricey when I was 20.
I remember it took me a while, okay, it took me a while.
It's worth it though and if it's available in your town,
it's available all over the world by the way, right,
and you can also search online
for what's called Toastmasters
or other public speaking in-class courses
where you live if you wanna practice
in front of a lot of people, right, but here's what I say.
I say challenge yourself.
I want you to dare yourself
and run to your fear by volunteering
to please speak at work or at religious events
or whatever, at school events
or other organizations, charities, et cetera, okay,
'cause that's really a great way to practice, okay,
and I wanna end act five, right,
with you watching these four very short videos
on Warren Buffett talking about public speaking
which should really put a smile on your face.
I wanna congratulate you on completing act number five.
Thanks.