When you present,
you can almost never have enough passion, okay?
When you practice your presentation
and you record yourself with your smartphone,
computer, or other video recorder,
watch to see that you have enough passion in your delivery.
I want you to speak from the heart,
like you're having a conversation
and not giving a stale delivery, okay?
Do you ever flip through many TV channels
and you stop for a second,
and somebody is speaking in a really boring, monotone way?
Well obviously you immediately change the channel, right?
You know, quite often when you stay
on a certain TV channel, when someone
is speaking right from the heart with passion and emotion,
you stick it out for awhile and you kind of watch to see,
what are they talking about, right?
Now, I'm certainly overdoing, you know, this, a little bit.
But I'm doing it on purpose just to get my point across.
And I humbly believe that you can almost never be
too passionate about life and almost everything, okay?
And so, when you speak on stage, take it all in.
Savor and enjoy every single word.
What are we here for, okay?
Just think about how great actors like,
like Liam Neeson, speak with passion, right?
These great actors can make something
incredibly boring sound amazing, right?
And Morgan Freeman does this, too, right?
And when you make something boring sound exciting,
like cloud computing, like Mark Benioff does,
then you can sell anything, okay?
And for those of you that have taken my previous courses,
you know how passionate I am about networking
and using LinkedIn to network.
You know, I have to hand it to guys like Liam Neeson,
as they're, they're better than I am
at presenting networking concepts, like LinkedIn,
better than I am, right?
So, check out Liam Neeson here kind of
talking about LinkedIn, and he does it
much better than I do.
Okay, so, all the world's a stage.
Please watch this next video, which was a trailer
for an HBO show that was canceled, called Vinyl.
The trailer's outstanding, right?
And Martin Scorcese and Mick Jagger actually produced this.
Right, it's too bad it was canceled, right?
Watch the passion in this delivery, right,
from this record producer, and then try to feel
or understand what is being said
when the record producer in this video says,
"Do you remember the first time you heard a song,
and it made the hair on the back of your neck
want to stand up?"
Check it out.
Okay.
You want to deliver a passionate experience, you know.
I kind of say this again and again and again, right,
as repetition is really the mother of all skill
but people might not remember what you said
but they'll never forget the way you made them feel, right?
And that trailer that you just watched
from that canceled show called Vinyl,
I don't really remember what they were talking about
but I remember the passion that was being said, right,
and I love it because that trailer we study musicians,
and musicians that sing with passion are the ones
that are successful, right?
It's not usually about the stuff they sing about, right?
Just think about the most memorable Oscar speeches ever,
right, you probably remember how this person made you feel
and not really what they said.
Delivery is everything.
The medium is often more important than the message.
And so, please have fun up there, right?
This is your time and your moment to shine, okay?
And don't be stale and boring, you know?
That's not who you are anyway, be you.
Who gives a damn what people think when you are yourself,
passion kicks in, okay?
You can't have passion unless you are you, okay?
Be the you that your friends and family love.
Just let the audience get to know you, okay?
And again, have fun doing it as well.