I always enjoy a speech
when I notice the presenter goes off script,
even if it wasn't polished.
And I love it because it's so authentic,
it's so genuine, and it's so real.
We all know how popular reality TV is these days
and these great YouTube stars
that younger generations love.
They're real, and there's no acting.
And I really admire when people go off script
or they just keep it real.
And it can be something as small and innocent
as saying the word, God bless you,
a microsecond after somebody sneezes.
Or it can be during the presentation
when the speaker mentions something relevant
that occurred during the previous speaker's presentation.
Or something in the news,
like a sporting event or the Oscars
or something that almost everybody is aware of.
When I have my many in-class business students
at universities present a presentation
and they prepare a lot,
my favorite part when they present is the Q and A
because when they have their Q and A sessions,
they don't rehearse for it of course.
And they don't sound nervous.
They're just relaxed and natural during the Q and A session
because they go off script
and they just give a lot of examples from their own lives.
And so, when you go off script,
you'll be authentic and unrehearsed of course
and even more likable than you already are.
It's like when you're watching a live comedy in person
or on television and one of the actors laughs
when they shouldn't.
And you remember that
because it was so likable and authentic,
like when the late great Chris Farley,
God bless him, he was great,
but when he made David Spade
and I think it was Christina Applegate laugh
on live TV when he was doing that
motivational speaker, "In a van down by the river."
Anyway, there's many famous movie scenes
that were unscripted but they were so authentic.
And here's a couple examples.
In the movie Pretty Woman,
this scene is not scripted,
and the director left it in as Julia Roberts' laugh
is completely genuine, authentic,
and really right from the heart.
Check it out if you have time.
Another example is Ben Stiller in Zoolander
when he forgot his line,
and he said the word,
he was supposed to say the line,
"But why male models?"
And he repeated the same line again
because he didn't know what to say.
And sometimes the blooper reel is the best part,
and it's so real, it's so authentic.
And this is why people love watching blooper videos.