Move around if you can while you present
as energy makes people pay attention
and not enough people do this.
Okay, so, I gave a keynote once
at the University of Tulsa finance event,
it was called Friends of Finance.
It was a luncheon in 2015
and they were really, really nice.
They were awesome and I really enjoyed it.
It was cool.
Actually an article was published about me presenting
in a couple of local newspapers,
you can google it, whatever.
They called me "a techie venture capitalist
"wrapped in a perpetual motion machine with arms,"
or a motion machine with arms, whatever it was.
I think that was a compliment.
Not sure, whatever.
But I love to move around when I present
as I get really excited and even more passionate
about what I'm saying.
You know what, 99.99999% of people stand still
when they present, and here are some examples
of me presenting at other events, like my TEDx talk
or when I presented in front of other companies.
I just love to walk around.
I love to move around a lot.
It's just what I do,
and it gives me a lot more energy as well.
And I've found when I do that fewer people yawn,
and it's just, I don't know, it's just me being me.
And when you go to a concert, if the performer
stays in the same place the whole time,
that's really boring, right?
The highest-grossing concerts have a lot of movements,
and the worst concerts ever have the artist
just kind of stay in there.
I mean what's the point of going?
I can just kind of listen to them on Spotify, right?
How boring is it just watching them sing
or watch a presenter just stand there and talk.
You know, I can just listen to radio instead.
It's hard to lose interest if someone moves around a lot.
It shows they have energy and that they're passionate
and that they're different than other people.
Motion creates emotion because, you know,
staring at someone for a while is lame, it's boring, okay.
Now think about a time when you went to a concert
and this singer walked into the audience.
You remember that, right?
Or close to the audience, okay.
But do you remember the song or the content they sang?
Probably less likely, okay.
Remember, the medium is more important than the message.
The way you present's more important than what you say.
And I want people to remember your speech,
your performance, your experience,
and I never want them to forget it.
Okay, and if you do move around,
without overdoing it of course,
then people will never forget it.
Powerful effect when you present is to stop walking
when you want to say something really important.
I did this when I was doing my TEDx talk
and here's a little clip.
And also, please make sure to wear soft bottom shoes,
when you're walking around the stage.
Especially if it's, it's usually not a carpeted stage,
it's usually, it's hardwood or whatever,
concrete, whatever.
But just people hear the sound of you walking,
and that's all they'll remember, right?
And so, sometimes I'll move,
sometimes I'll move to a different spot on the stage
when I talk about a new topic.
Okay.
Or, think about how rock stars move around the stage
to address or sing songs to people
that are in different seats.
They want to engage the entire stadium or coliseum, right?
Why can't we do this when we present as well
if it works in concerts?
I'm not telling you to run around like 1872,
Mick Jagger on the stage at Wembley Stadium,
I'm just telling you to kinda, you'll mix it up
because motion creates emotion.
And sometimes use a catwalk,
where these singers will walk on
to get closer to the audience.
And if you've got a really big stage
I want you to mix it up and move around.
A lot of times I'll actually enter into the crowd.
I love that.
I do in my class as well,
I think I might drive my students a little nuts.
But they always pay attention.
I walk around the class sometimes when I teach,
just to kind of mix it up,
and I'm challenging myself, too, to make it different.
Now, I always check to see if the microphone will work
that far away meaning off the stage, the day before,
when I test the equipment,
or if it's the day of, I'll ask the technical person
setting up the presentation, if available,
if the microphone or the wireless headset
can work anywhere in the room or not.
No, I'll actually, I'll test it out.
Sometimes you'll hear feedback
if you walk too far away or certain areas.
Microphones are like that, and sometimes you don't know why,
it's like your barbecue, they work really well
in certain spots and not others.
So you've got to test it out beforehand.
You know, microphones are usually used during Q&A as well,
so just make sure you test all this stuff out.
Ask a technical person, again, if they're available,
if the microphone works everywhere on the stage or not.
As a side note, please, please know
that if you're wired up with a wireless mike,
it can work in many different places, okay.
Just watch this video and you'll know what I mean.