I've always been a risk taker, right.
It hasn't always helped my career
but it's just the way I am,
and I want to please challenge you to be different
especially when you present
as it will help your audience remember your presentation
years later, okay?
And I mentioned Roberto Benigni's Oscar speech earlier
which was amazing.
It's way over the top, right,
but I remember it really well, and I love it.
I love his passion, okay?
And in the business school classes that I teach at
in universities I sometimes I'll stand on a chair
or a desk during one part of my classes.
Here I am, I'm still here, okay?
And I'll do this because
I'm talking about the importance of seeing the forest
from the trees, right,
and how when you look at the total adjustable market
for a certain industry you're considering investing in,
you have to understand the size of the market,
and see the trends higher up,
and focus on the forest, and again, not the trees, right?
So, anyway I do that
and think it's a class that
my students don't forget, right?
And they all remember what TAM stands for
because of that class,
which is total addressable market, okay?
Everyone pays attention when I do that
because it's unique, it's different, it's unconventional,
and I don't care what anyone thinks, right?
So, just kidding, sort of, nevermind, right.
Please dare yourself to do something radically different.
And Apple actually had an advertising campaign
that aired first in 1997 called Think Different,
and not only did this campaign help to rescue
the company from bankruptcy with the help of Steve Jobs,
of course, but it also redefined the company,
and it put it on a long-term trajectory
to becoming the most valuable company on the planet, right?
And I want you to also please think different
when you present, okay?
And this commercial was aired on the 28th of September 1997
during the television premier of the movie Toy Story,
you know, which was creative,
by Pixar, of course, of which Steve Jobs
was the largest shareholder.
Check it out.
I want you to please take a chance in your life,
and in your career and present differently
as one speech can change your life
and touch the hearts of so many people around you.
Life all comes down to a few short moments.