(dramatic music)
Welcome to the second of three intermissions.
In each of the intermissions we're going to have
a presentation by you and then we will critique it,
to make sure it's absolutely perfect,
so that you're ready on game day.
I strongly recommend, please,
completing all three intermissions
as you work your way through the courses,
because I want you to please notice
how you're progressing and how much better
your presentation becomes throughout the course.
And so the first part of this intermission
is a presentation exercise, which is the very next lecture.
The second part of this intermission
is an exercise critiquing the presentation that you gave.
And the third part, of this intermission
is comparing how you just did
on your second intermission presentation
with how you did during the first intermission presentation.
Okay?
And the fourth part here is going to be a discussion
and a critique of one of my presentations,
which I gave to a company.
And don't worry if all this stuff sounds complicated,
as I'm gonna walk you through every single step.
I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thanks.