I'm not a PR or a public relations expert by any means.
But I've seen a lot of executives answering questions,
when there is a crisis or potential crisis
occurring with their company, or their product,
or their service.
And there's definitely an art to this.
And I've seen CEOs turning a crisis weakness
into an incredible strength.
Or at least a less bad situation, right?
It, for example,
if the question is about a product that had an issue
the CEO could respond by saying this.
Thank you for the question.
Here at XYZ Company,
we have always had the highest quality products
in the industry, as our products are tested three times each
before we sell them.
Unlike the competition that only test the product one time,
et cetera.
You get the idea.
And you'd never mention the competition's name, right?
You don't mention the company.
It makes you look bad, okay?
Okay so I want to discuss a real life example
of this in action.
Okay.
When the late great CEO of Intel, Andy Grove,
answered a crisis of an issue question,
about Intel's Pentium Processor.
Which at that time, back I think it was the early '90s,
or '94 whatever.
The Pentium Processor actually miscalculated
certain incredibly complex calculations, okay?
And Mr. Grove, Andy Grove,
went on all of the major news programs
to discuss the strategy for dealing with this issue.
I remember this was back in 1994
and I searched online everywhere
and I can't find that video otherwise I'd show you, okay?
It, you know what this was actually,
it was interesting, right?
Because this was the first time many people
ever heard of Intel, right?
Who made you know chips inside a PC
you can't see, feel or touch, right?
So he ended up unintentionally
using this
as an unintentional,
brilliant, free PR campaign.
Kind of like when Apple introduces a product
the media's all over it.
It's free PR, right?
Separately,
Andy Grove wrote about this
in one of my favorite business books ever.
Which is called Only the Paranoid Survive.
Read if you get a chance.
It actually deals with the Michael Porter Five Forces model.
But it adds
one more force which is a strategic inflection point, right?
Like when an industry changes.
And the example he gave in this book,
I'm sorry I'm going off topic here
you can skip ahead in the next section if you want.
The example he gave in the book
was the Japanese companies that were competing with Intel
you know back in the '70s and '80s.
In the RAM market.
DRAM market.
And Intel couldn't compete,
it was a strategic inflection point on price.
So Intel transitioned to make processors
which is the brain of the computer instead.
Anyway read if you get a chance.
It's a great read and God bless Andy Grove.
Thank you.