If you want, you can download
the very big PowerPoint file
that we are going to discuss in this lecture.
And it was actually the PowerPoint presentation
that I created for my TEDx speech.
And it's the first lecture of act four, scene four.
Or just go to the resources section
and download the file called,
"Case one TEDx slide Chris Haroun PPTX"
PowerPoint file, I don't know what the x is for.
Okay, the caveat here is that it is
an enormous, enormous file.
You don't have to do it, okay?
You don't need to download the file,
but I just wanted to show you
how I practiced my TEDx presentation, okay.
I memorized a 15 minute,
and put this video here, speech,
and you can see the note section within PowerPoint, right,
that I use.
And you can enter your notes in here, as well.
Right, do the same thing and Keynote as well
and to figure out how to do that, if you want,
go to case study number six and act four, scene four
for an example of writing practice notes in Keynote.
Okay, let's move on.
But per this video,
you can see that I wrote all of my notes
as I had to time my transitions, as well,
which was a lot of fun.
It wasn't work, it was fun,
otherwise I would not have enjoyed it, okay?
Now, you can also do the exact same thing
on the iPhone or the Android version of PowerPoint
which is a free download, okay.
So here's the video, here.
And here you can see, right,
that I have my entire presentation
and the exact same one or version of the one we just saw
on the desktop version of PowerPoint, right,
so what you can do is save it on Dropbox,
iCloud, OneDrive,
or locally on your smartphone,
whatever works for you,
and Google Drive, as well, okay.
So I love to have one file up in the cloud,
one PowerPoint file, and then I write to it
from many different devices.
And so the PowerPoint presentation that I'm reading, right,
in this lecture, right,
all of these, I made using PowerPoint on many devices.
I didn't just do it on a Mac,
I actually did it on my Windows device, as well.
I did it on iPad, on an iPhone, etc., okay.
So I practiced this speech, right,
when I went on very, very long walks with my iPhone, okay,
and while looking at the slides, right,
that you can see in this video on my iPhone screen.
I kept doing this until I had it memorized.