(waves crashing)
It's up here, you wanna walk in the water then.
We're shooting a profile shot,
with the sun in the background, glistening on the water.
What's up guys?
Hey, dude! How are ya?
What's going on, man?
How's your first day?
This has been amazing, thank you.
Thank you, you're awesome!
You too, man, you too.
Everyone here has been amazing.
Beautiful day.
(Cameraman chuckles)
What a great experience.
Alright.
I can't wait to see it, man.
This is great.
Yeah.
Looking forward to day two.
Awesome, thanks.
Hey, Fred, you good?
Alright!
(Cameraman chuckles)
Out of the sun.
What are you saying?
Well we're setting up our last shot here.
It's pretty nice out here at Baker Beach.
Oh, we're getting the bridge right over there,
the sun right over here, and our day crew
and it's been going really good.
Good.
(Cameraman chuckles)
How do you guys feel about the first day?
Yeah!
(Cameraman laughs)
Oh, is this video?
Yeah.
(Cameraman chuckles)
You, Tom?
Good day?
Yes, excellent day.
(Cameraman chuckles)
Beautiful day!
Nice.
Friendly neighborhood.
Excellent, perfect day.
Couldn't ask for a better day.