Now we're going to create the deployment,
then test the app running on your Kubernetes cluster.
The YAML file will be in the deploy directory.
From here, run kubectl create -f demo.yml.
The deployment and service were successfully created.
Let's find out where it's running so we can try it out ourselves.
The load balancer is created,
but the external IP is still pending so we'll give it a minute.
Here's the external IP where the application is
running on the Kubernetes cluster.
Let's pull up a browser and try it out.
Here we see the expected output.
Let's hit this service in a loop and observe the output to understand
how traffic is being routed to the different pods.
The load balancer service will route traffic to all three pods.
The simple demo application only keeps a local copy of the counter.
It's not coordinating across the pods.
This is why we see multiple of each number and the number sequence out of order. We can also run kubectl get pods to see that all three pods are running.