Let's take a look at the specific information you will
need to perform the Docker login, Docker tag,
and Docker push commands in order to get your image into your OCIR repository.
The server you log into is different,
depending on what region your registry is in.
Each region has a region code, which is usually a three-letter abbreviation.
I've included a link to the documentation in the exercise files for this course,
where you can look that up for your region.
If your registry is in the US West Phoenix region,
you would use docker login phx.ocir .io.
The username you need to provide is a combination of the tenancy namespace,
slash, your Oracle Cloud username.
Tenancy-namespace is the auto-generated Object Storage
namespace string of your tenancy,
and can be found on the Tenancy menu in the Oracle Cloud console.
You'll see exactly where to find that in the demo.
Finally,
the password you need to provide is the auth token you generated in the
Oracle Cloud console and will look something like this.
For docker tag,
the image-identifier is either the image id or the name:tag on the
source system that identifies the image you want to tag.
Target-tag is a combination of several different things.
First,
the region-code and tenancy-namespace are the same as what you used in the
Docker login command that we talked about on the previous slide.
Next, repo-name is an optional parameter,
which indicates the repository in your registry you want to push the image to.
If the repository doesn't already exist,
a new private repository is automatically created for you.
If you don't include a repository name,
then the image name is used to identify a private repository for the image.
Image-name is the name you want to give the image in the
Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Registry,
and tag is the image tag you want give the image in the OCIR.
Here's an example of what that would look like with the values filled in.
Docker tag, image identifier, region code,
.ocir .io / tenancy namespace, slash repo name,
slash image name, colon tag.
For Docker push,
note that the target-tag format is the same as what you used for Docker tag.
Now you'll simply push the image that you tagged.
For example, docker push, region code, .ocir .io / tenancy namespace, /repo name, /image name:tag.