You're going to need a few things to connect to your cluster with kubectl.
First, you'll generate a private key that will be used to sign requests.
Next,
you'll need to upload a public key to your account that will
verify those requests and install and configure the Oracle Cloud
Command Line Interface or CLI on the machine that you want to
use to access your cluster.
You'll creates a kubeconfig file,
then finally you can verify your kubectl connection to your cluster.
We're going to walk through how to do each of these items so feel
free to follow along with your own cluster.
You'll to generate and upload a key to your account.
Then open SSL commands that I'll use are included in
the downloads for this course.
First, generate a private key,
then change the permissions so other users cannot read it.
Next, generate a public key from that private key.
Your public key should look something like this.
Use your favorite way for your operating system to copy it to the clipboard,
then open your user profile and scroll down to API Keys.
Select Add Public Key, and paste your public key in the box.
Notice the fingerprint that is generated from that public key.
Go ahead and select that so you can make sure that it was uploaded correctly.
From your local machine, generate a fingerprint,
then compare it with the fingerprint that was shown when you uploaded the key.
If they match, you know that your key was uploaded correctly.
If not,
you may need to repeat the steps to upload your key and make sure that
it matches the key that you have on your machine.
Now you can install the Oracle CLI on your machine.
I've included the relevant commands that you can download in
the Exercise files sections of this course.
The Oracle CLI utilizes Python so you'll need that on the system.
This command will download the install script,
and I'm going to just accept the default locations to install everything.
You can choose whether you want it to modify your path or not.
Then to verify the install, simply run oci -v.
You should see the version of the OCI CLI that was installed.
There's a few pieces of information you need to
gather from our Oracle Cloud console.
First, we'll get the tenancy OCID.
Under your user profile, click Tenancy,
then the OCID is listed under Tenancy Information.
Use the link to copy this, then set it aside while we gather a few other items.
Next is the user OCID.
On your user profile, click your username,
then under User Information, the OCID is listed.
Now that you've gathered all of those IDs, you're ready to configure your CLI.
Run oci setup config,
then it will ask you where you would like to put your config.
I'm going to accept the default,
then provide the user and tenancy OCIDs that you collected earlier.
Next, enter the region where your cluster is located,
then here be sure to select No.
Let me say that again.
You already uploaded your key that you will use to sign the requests.
Put N for No, then provide the path to your private key.
Note that it reminds you to upload the public key through the console,
but that's already taken care of so let's move on to the next step.
Go to your cluster dashboard by navigating to the Clusters menu,
then selecting your cluster.
Select Access kubeconfig,
then it will provide you some information on how to create the kubeconfig file.
If you don't already have one,
you can create a .kube directory in your home directory.
Next,
you can run the CLI command to create a kubeconfig for you
with the appropriate values for your cluster.
You can open that config to see what was created.
Now you should be able to run a kubectl command like get nodes and see the nodes that are running in your cluster.