Hey, what is going on, everyone?
Welcome back to chapter number eight.
In this chapter, I will take even deeper into the concept of the context, talking about how it works
inside flutter and therefore how it is used by the Block library to provide different blocks or cubits
across the widget.
This is a really, really important tutorial.
So make sure you don't skip it.
We will be going to tackle up different scenarios to see how build context can cause the unwanted block
provided a lot of ways to find the context containing a specific block or cubitt error.
So if you encounter this issue too often, it's a great idea to watch this tutorial in depth.
Remember from my third story of the series regarding floatable block concepts, when I told you that
everything in Flutter is mainly a widget and that flutter uses what's called a widget tree in order
to organize and structure the widgets you want to set up and use inside your application.
But how is this widget restructured at the end?
What links everything into place in a perfect Armony?
You guessed it the build context.
So the build context is somehow a tool which helps handle the location of a widget inside the widget
tree.
So you may ask ourselves, well, that means every widget is built within a context, right?
Absolutely correct.
In fact, every widget has a build function of function, which gets called whenever the widget is being
built in your application.
Inside that builder function, you will often see a build context e as best that lets flutter know where
the widget will sit inside the widget.
You must know that not all widgets have a user accessible context.
By default, for example, a text widget will be built within a context, but that context will be anonymous
by default.
On the other hand, when you're creating a block provider or whenever you're building a new screen inside
the build function parameters, you will see that there is a build context eason's that you can use
later on in order to access the context inside your page.
To better visualize how context actually works.
Will watch how the widget three of our current app is created.
Widget by widget to App Code Base will be using is the counter app from my last tutorial regarding block
to block communication.
You can find the source code for that in the video's description.
Let's start with the beginning of every application must start at the point in flutter.
This point is actually the required main function from inside the main that dart file, the run app
method inside will start building the app.
Therefore, our widget tree.
Every tree must always have a root node, a node where everything starts and develops from there for
every widget, tree must always have a root widget.
In our case, the root widget is actually the first widget created more specifically the My App Widget.
As I previously said, since every flutter widget is built within a built context, the map widget will
also be built within a build context.
Now, please be a little bit more attention because I'll tell you the relationship between different
build context.
I'm going to tell you three completely wrong assumptions you might make during the development of your
app.
Firstly, you might be tempted to say this.
All this build context instances have the same name.
Then that means we're talking of the same build context over and over again.
Secondly, you might be tempted to say that since there is no build context instance mentioned as a
parameter to a widget, then the widget isn't built within a build context.
Last but not least, you might be tempted to think that the context in which the next widget will be
built won't be related at all to the previous context.
Inside the widget.
Three.
All of these assumptions are terribly wrong and let me explain why in detail.
We'll start with the first wrong assumption.
Even though the names of the build context instances are the same here and here and here, this doesn't
mean they're identical by any means.
This context is completely different from this one and completely different from this one.
This is crucial to understand.
Context in this case is just a name for a build context, for instance, which is best as an argument
to different functions.
It's like having three different functions, both having the same name arguments.
But when called the past arguments, values will be different, even though the arguments are named
the same.
In this situation, when there is a built context, context, for instance, task to a builder function,
you need to start imagining the name context as being the build context in which the current widget
is being created.
Therefore, in order to make things even more understandable for learning purposes, I'll rename.
This context, the following, the context in which the MIT, which is billed, will be called by up
context, the context in which the block provider of type enter and Cubitt widget will be created will
be called Internet Cubitt context.
And finally, the context in which the block provider of type counter cubitt widget will be created
will be called counter cubitt context.
I rename them this way so that you will see better that they are completely different.
When you fully understand this, you will find it easier to name all of them context since you'll know
which context goes where immediately.
Now that we figured out the first wrong assumption, let's move to the second one.
As I told you before, every widget inside flutter has a build function which will require a build context
instance in order for it to be built and most importantly, placed correctly inside the widget.
So if you are seeing the material up here alone, this doesn't mean it was built without any context.
It has an anonymous built context, but it's still a build context like every other widget, and will
be placed correctly inside the widget.
Finally, to discuss the last wrong assumption regarding the relationship between build contexts, you
need to know that the build context of a widget keeps track only of its direct parent and nothing else.
So in our case, our widget build within its next context only knows that its parent is the widget built
on the previous context and nothing else.
So to sum up, the relationship between build context is a bottom up relationship because the only way
to know what's at the top of the tree is to start from a bottom child and work your way up asking at
each step for every parent that is above.
Until you reach the top build context only cares about its parent context.
It won't record any information about its child or children.
This is crucial to understand because this way you will know that the only way to move inside the widget
tree is by choosing a context and then navigating up from there.
The only way is up.
No left, no right, no down, just up.
This is the only way.
Build context, navigate between each other.
Coming back to our widget tree.
Every time you see the build function, returning a widget, that widget is going to be a child of your
current widget.
In our case, the my returns in its build function a Mutai block provider.
So this widget is going to be built in a new context, this time anonymous.
Therefore, the multiple provider widget will be the child of the app widget inside the widget tree.
Now to continue, we need to understand what multiple provider really does.
Remember for my third flutter block concept tutorial, when I talked about multiple provider, I mentioned
that this widget was built to facilitate providing multiple blocks or kibbitz so that instead of nesting
them one inside another, you can create a list and mention them inside it to understand that behind
the scenes, multiple provider will be still nesting each block provider from the list.
Multiple provider is just a way of making the code look more readable and organized.
So having this in mind, we can deduce that the provider of type Internet cubitt is going to be the
next widget in our widget.
We did own Internet covid context bill context.
Then in a new countercoup context bill context, another child will be linked to our widget tree, the
block provider of type counter cubitt.
Let's continue for whenever you see a child parameter, the widget test will be a child of their current
widget.
So material up goes.
Up next, inside the widget of our app, be aware that team data glass is not a widget since it does
not extend any type of widget glass.
So we won't take it into consideration inside our widget tree.
In my six tutorial from the series regarding block access and navigation, one of the resulting options
we tackled was a generated routing.
So by default, our application will pushing the default home route into the navigation stack, which
is linked to our home screen.
Therefore, the next widget inside our widget tree is going to be the home screen widget again.
This widget comes with a built method and the new context which will call home screen context for learning
purposes.
The return widget is the Block Lisner, which will be placed right out the registry.
As we have previously done.
It's build context will be called Internet Cubitt listener context.
The Block listener also comes with a child parameter the scaffold.
So this will be the next widget inside our widget tree.
Now please be a little bit more attention.
As you can see the scaffold in our case.
Receives two widget parameters, the Apapa widget inside the abar parameter and the central widget inside
the body parameter, when you see this kind of scenario with multiple parameters filled with different
widgets inside the same widget, you need to know that these will be children of the same parent widget.
So in our case, we have two widgets building from the scaffold widget.
One will be the Abre child widget and the other one the center child widget will need to see for each
of these two widgets, which are their children.
In the case of the Apple widget, there is only one child, the text widget.
On the other hand, the center widget has a column widget child with multiple children.
Those will be again direct children of the column widget.
So they'll be on the same level inside the widget.
Let's write them one by one, the block builder, the divider, the block consumer, the material button
and again, the other material button.
The block builder returns text widgets within a new counter cubitt builder context.
Depending on which state is receiving block, consumer is almost the same scenario.
It will return the counter text widget within similar naming style context.
Now, please pay more attention to what I'm going to introduce right now inside the material button.
You might remember from my tutorial regarding block routing and navigation that we have an unpressed
function from where we're calling navigator that ov push named to push a new screen inside the navigation
stack.
This is the moment when you will finally encounter why it is crucial to understand how context works
inside flutter.
You might think that this line of code is simply a default way of navigating inside flutter.
Well, it's not like that.
Let me translate to you, Navigator.
That of context that Bush named is equal to search for the closest navigator widget inside the widget
tree starting from the past.
Build context instance and then add to the navigator widget is found at the new screen widget as a child
of the navigator widget.
So let's take this easily.
One piece at a time search for the closest navigator widget inside the widget tree.
This means Flutter is going to do a lookup after the closest navigation widget starting from the past
build context instance.
As you can see, there is a built context.
Easton's past inside of Navigator State.
This is done to indicate flutter from which exact context inside the widget read.
The lookup should start.
As I told you before, in order to find a specific widget in the widget tree, you need to choose a
starting context and then proceed upwards parent by parent until you find it.
So in our case, Futter will start searching for a navigator widget right from the provided bill context
instance, which in our case should be the context of the material button widget.
The thing is that since the material button is built within an anonymous context, we can't access it.
So we cannot mention it inside the navigator, that of line of code.
But can we transform an anonymous context of a widget into a normal, accessible one?
Yes, we can.
And this is done by wrapping the widget inside a building widget.
The Builder widget was created to be able to specify a built context insert name in which a widget should
be built.
So in our case, all we need to do is wrap the material button inside the builder widget and specify
the name of material button context for the bill context instance in which the widget should be created.
Now we can pass the material button context to the navigator, that old line of code for the second
scenario, when we want to start searching for the navigator widget from inside, the context of the
home screen will need to pass the homescreen context instance to the navigator, that of line of code.
So we'll have two scenarios to test.
One starting from the context of material button widget and the other one starting from the context
of the homescreen widget.
OK, so let's simulate how Flutter works with both scenarios.
In the first scenario, we want to push the second screen onto the navigation stack right after the
navigator widget is found inside the widget.
We're starting to look up from the context in which the material button was created, which is the material
button context, and then Flutter will ask for the parent widget of it.
It will go right to the column widget, then to center scaffold and block Lisner Widgets.
Finally, Flutter will search inside the homescreen context for the Navigator widget.
None was found there, so it moves again to the parent widget of the home screen widget, which is the
material app widget.
Even though there is no the Navigator widget inside our material app widget.
You need to know that.
Material app has it inside its core functionality.
This is where the Navigator feature starts.
So if you are always wondering why the material app widget contains all the parameters for setting up
the preferred routing option, well, now you know why?
Because it contains the Navigator Widget core, which manages the navigation feature of your app.
OK, so right now Flutter found the navigator widget it was looking for.
Now it's time for a navigator to pull the second screen onto the stack.
But remember, it will push it from the context of the navigator widget and that's the context of the
material app.
So the new second screen widget will be placed as a child of the material app widget.
So the new mediatory following our previous rules will transform into this node that if you click the
big button, the second screen widget will pop from the navigation stack and will no longer exist inside
the widget.
In the second scenario, the same procedure applies inside flutter.
The only difference being that the lookup starts from the home screen context instead of the material
button context, and that instead of building the second screen as a child of the material app will
build the third screen.
You need to understand that the translation of the navigator, that of context, line of code works.
Also, when you're writing block provider, that of context team, that of context, scaffolded not
of context or any similar sequences, therefore block provider.
That of context means that will search for a specific provided instance of a block or cubitt inside
the widget, restarting from the provided context since there might be multiple providea blocks or kibbitz.
That's why we're mentioning the type of ID between angle brackets.
I hope you understood how context work and interact with each other overall.
If you have ever wondered why wrapping the material up with block providers cards, the blocks are kubis
to be provided globally to the entire widget tree.
Now you know why?
It's because all the screen widgets from inside your app will be children of the material app widget,
therefore creating and providing them before the context in which the material app is created, which,
by the way, contains.
Also the navigator widget means that whenever a new screen is Bouchet searching for the Block or Cubitt
unique instance by calling block provider out of context from the context of that screen, we'll go
and search for the instance until it finds it above the material app widget.
That's also why if we wrap the homescreen widget inside the block provider and then we push a new screen
widget, which is going to be a child of the material app, you won't be able to access the block or
Cubitt instance provided from the home screen inside that new screen widget y because this is the nature
of how context works.
Searching for a cubit or block and started from the context of the new screen widget will drive flutter
to the material seized as the parent of the new stream.
Then Flutter will go to my approved widget.
And since it wasn't able to find any instance of the block or cube down the road, it will throw the
well known area of block provider that fails to find the context containing the specific block or cubitt.
Another thing you need to understand is that you cannot access a block or cubitt instance from the same
context in which it was provided.
So you must ensure block provider that is called Within a Child Bill context to analyze the series in
more detail.
Here's three examples you need to understand.
So first example, this code for a bit.
And let's apply what we learned so far.
Can you access the unique instance of Block AI in this specific case?
Pause the video for a moment and think of it, then come back for the full explanation.
OK, so the answer to this example is yes, you can access the unique instance of block AI by using
block provider of block AI of context.
Now let me explain to you why the first widget is built in a context built context.
Then it's child.
The block provider is built in an anonymous context right below it.
Bear in mind, whenever you see an underscore past as a parameter to a function, it translates to it
doesn't matter which parameter it's passed there, we don't care about its name.
So in our case, we don't actually care about the name of the context in which Block AI is created.
Then we have a child called My Child, which is also built in a context context.
Remember that even though these build functions have the same parameter names, they're not the same.
This is a completely separate context from the context above.
We also have a race button built with its own anonymous context at the end of the widget tree in which
we're asking Flutter to find us the first block provider of type block AI.
So the context for.
Which will start searching east, as you can see, the context of my child, which it will start going
up from there and voila, my parent is actually what we were searching for.
The block provider of Block A, which contains the block, a unique instance, success.
Let's move to the second example.
Here's the code again.
I want you to take a look and think whether the unique instance of Block eight is accessible or not.
So what do you see?
If you think the Block A is accessible there, you are wrong.
And let's investigate why we have a widget built in a context Bill context at the top.
Then right below it, a block provider will create the block a into an anonymous context.
The race button will also be built as a child.
Within an anonymous context, we're asking Flutter to find the closest block provider of type block
a starting with the best context.
If you pay attention, the best context is actually the one in which the top widget was built.
Since the other created widgets have anonymous context, which we cannot access.
So in this case, a flutter won't be able to find the block provider of type block A, therefore throwing
the well known error of block provider that of fails to find a block or cubitt.
So do you think there is a way on how we could adapt this specific example in order to make it work?
The widget tree looks rather good.
If we only had an accessible context in order to start to look up from there, we can now start to look
up from this context.
And since the block provider is actually above this context, we know for sure that the unique instance
of the Block A is accessible.
This was the example number three, and I hope you understood why knowing how Bill context works is
crucial.
We're almost at the end of this important tutorial.
What's left for now is for me to tell you a trick on how you can easily visualize the widget tree of
your app without having to manually write it down every time.
So first of all, inside this code, you need to build and run your application, then heat control,
shift P and search for the tools, then open it in a new browser tab.
If you go to flutter, Inspector, you can notice the entire widget tree which is currently built inside
your app.
As you can see, it's actually the same widget tree we manually built.
How convenient.
So whenever you have doubts in which context a specific widget is built, you can now double check it
inside.
Flutter Inspector.
This was definitely a long but really, really, really important tutorial.
Bill context is actually one of the key concepts of flutter.
So understanding how it works underneath will win you big time in the long run.
We have successfully covered about two thirds of this amazing blog.
First, congratulations.
In the next chapter you'll learn what are the new additions of Flutter Block Version six point one point
zero.
It's a really nice update, so make sure to check it out.
With that being said, I'm looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in the next chapter.
Stay tuned and let's get wicked.