What is going on, everyone?
Welcome back to chapter number six.
In this chapter, I'll introduce you to Block Access, more specifically, how you can access a block
instance across various scenarios with block provider and block provider that value.
It is going to be a long but highly important tutorial.
So make sure you buckle up and grab some popcorn at first.
Remember that in my third tutorial of this series regarding block concepts, I showed you how to provide
a single block instance, the counter cubitt to the widget tree of a single page by using block provider.
Well, in that video, we only provide it locally to a single screen.
But what if we want to provide it to another screen, to multiple screens or even globally to all of
our app screens in order to follow up?
We will also need to close my repository from GitHub and open the third block concepts folder inside
the code so that we can continue right where we previously left.
OK, so let's dive into our first scenario, which we have actually discussed in program before locally
providing a single instance of the counter cubitt to our default home screen.
If you remember, if we wrap a widget with a block provider, a single instance of that specific block
will be provided to all of its direct children.
We can provide it this way across the widget tree, thanks to the build context, which is a way Flutter
knows which is actually the parent and which are the children across the widget.
Since most apps nowadays benefit from more than one screen, flutter also comes with the navigation
stack, which organizes the routes and their specific screens inside the app.
So every time the app displays a new screen, we should know that Flutter pushes a new route with the
new screen inside the navigation stack.
Every time we click the back button on our phone, we should note that Flutter pops the current screen
out of the stack.
There are many other actions besides pushing and popping, which can be executed on flusters navigation
stack.
But these are beyond the purpose of this video.
You must know that every application must have a default home route, a route which is automatically
pushed by default when the app is started.
In our case, inside the navigation stack, Flutter only pushes the default home route, which is the
home screen containing the counter feature.
Coming back to our block access discussion, you may wonder Wicked, you showed us that you can provide
a single instance of the counter QB to our home screen.
Why do you call it local access?
Well, it's called local access because as the name is implying, the cubitt will only be available
locally inside the widgets of that screen.
So you're saying that if we push another screen inside Fata's navigation stack, the counter Cubitt
won't be available there, too?
Indeed, that's absolutely correct.
If we push a new screen into the navigation stack, Flutter will add its widgets to the already available
widget tree.
But since this, we just are part of a new screen from when you wrote the bill, context doesn't know
how to indicate block provider, where to provide a single instance of the counter cubitt up next.
So here comes the major break up with local access.
Local access means providing a single instance of a block to only one screen, thus to the entire widget,
which is part of that screen.
Let's test this theory for now inside our code so we know that currently locally providing our counter
cubitt to our default home screen works perfectly.
Firstly, let's do some refactoring with the structure of our folders and go this way will also be testing
the block architecture layers.
We learned a couple of tutorials.
So in order to stick to the architecture, we must highlight the business logic layer by creating a
business logic folder which are simply call it logic and in which will move the cubitt folder with our
counter cubitt.
Then, as we know, the UI should be part of the presentation layer.
So I'll create a presentation folder along with the screen subfolder.
Inside this folder will place all of our different screens from inside this tutorial inside the main,
that dirt file.
You can notice that, as I told you previously, Flutter has a separate feel inside material which is
named home denoting that this is the screen which is going to be pushed up first onto the navigation
stack.
In our case is the my home page on which will press F2 and rename it to homescreen will move the entire
implementation inside the separate home.
Underscore screen that dirt file inside the screen folder.
I have also modified the homescreen class a little bit so that it will take a title and a colour as
parameters in order to make it stand out compared to the next screen will create will also need to add
a material button inside our home screen, which will push a new screen on the navigation stack.
When we press, it will leave the unpressed function empty for now.
To demonstrate that the counter block won't be accessible to a new push screen, we would obviously
need to create a new screen called Second Underscore Screen that d'arte.
In order to speed up the process, I'll just duplicate some of our existing home screen code.
Inside our second screen class, this is not really recommended in programming, since we shouldn't
have duplicate code, but for testing purposes, it's OK.
Now we need to go back to our home screen because we need to write the code to push the second screen
onto the navigation stack.
We'll do this by using navigator that out of context that Bush and Material Page are out to easily differentiate
between the home screen and the second screen for the home screen.
I'll use a blue X and color and for the second screen a red X and one.
Finally we can run the project and as you can see, everything is running fine.
The counter block is provided locally inside the home screen page.
All the functionality is working as it should.
But if we press the go to second screen button, you'll see that the application will crash with an
error to be expected.
Block provider that you've called with a context that does not contain a cubit of type countercoup.
As you can see inside the second screen, we're asking the block provider for the counter cubitt instance.
But since the new bill context doesn't know either where the instances or how to find it, it shows
an error making the application crash.
You may be asking yourselves now, well, how will we provide the Cubitt instance to a new screen that
the answer to that question will be by using Routt access?
Until now, we only provided the QB to a single screen.
Providing an instance of a block or cubitt to only one screen is called local access.
Providing an instance of a block or cubitt to multiple screens is called route access.
We're calling this route access because we need to profit of the routing navigation feature of flutter
in order to provide the instance to the multiple screens.
You don't need to think of local and remote access as to complete different scenarios because you will
see that in the following part of the editorial.
Some parts of the remote access are linked to the local access.
OK, so as I told you a couple of moments ago, route access is related to the routing navigation feature
of Flutter because it's so strongly related.
I need to make a short introduction on how Flutter manages its routing feature.
Usually in routing feature, you'll need a pair of data containing both the routing name or tag and
the page or screen you want to be displayed when you enter that scrutiny.
Think of this as the way Web pages work when you enter five hundred pixels dot com, which is a popular
photography website.
If you want to navigate to the most popular photos you can append slash popular to the website.
The Slash Popular is the road name and the popular page is what is gets loaded up.
After having this in mind, you need to know that in flutter there are three major routing options available.
Anonymous routing named routing and generated routing.
Anonymous routing is at his name is implying routing without a Rosny.
Anonymous routing is what we've been doing so far in our counter wrap.
So by default we provided only the name of the homescreen class to the home parameter inside the material
app.
Also, when we navigate it from the home screen to the second screen, we used the material page route
without having to provide a name.
On the other hand, name routing is routing with a provided name.
This is the routing method I explained a couple of moments before when I mentioned the example with
the five hand pixels that come website.
All the routes you want to provide have to be set inside the roads parameter of the material.
App Widget.
Here's a quick example on how they will look like if you're building a small to medium sized application,
this named routing is recommended as opposed to the anonymous routing which might get really cluttered
and unorganized.
However, when you're working on a large project is recommended to user generated routing, generated
routing has almost the same structure as the named routing.
The only difference being is that you need to have a separate function in which you have to set up all
our routes.
This is a more professional approach since it will be cluttered the material map of the parameter,
a parameter which might get really cluttered while working on a huge application.
You will see from the code that it's actually pretty simple and self-explanatory since there are three
major routing options.
We'll tackle up each one of them to see how easy it is to provide an instance of a block or cubitt across
each page in every of the above scenarios.
We'll start up with the anonymous routing since is the one we really close to right now.
Providing a block or a cubitt instance across different anonymous routes is a key functionality.
So make sure you pay a little bit more attention to this topic.
Currently, we provided a counter to locally to our home screen, therefore to all of its children widgets.
We know that when we press the go to second screen button, there will be a new anonymous Routt pushed
on the navigation stack, loading up our second screen.
Unfortunately, due to the fact that the second screen has a different built context, the block provider
isn't able.
To continue providing the counter cubitt instance to the second screen, thus making the application
crash so there is a working instance of the counter cubitt available in the entire homescreen widget
tree.
How can we provide this working instance up next to the entire widget Tree of the Second Street?
That's the big question.
The answer is by using block provider, that value widget block provider, that value takes an existing
instance of a block or cubitt and provides it further to its widget.
In our case, the second screen, let's switch to the coding part so that you understand the concept
better.
So we're inside the homescreen class right where the second screen anonymous root gets pushed on the
navigation stack.
This is done by using material page.
The second screen is being written by the builder function.
So right before that we need to wrap the second screen widget with the block provider, add value widget
so that we provide a counter block instance further.
Now please pay the most attention you possibly can because I'll be telling you some important information
you'll definitely forget if you are paying much attention.
There are two important steps you really need to pay attention to.
Remember that I told you that the block provider that value widget takes in an existing instance of
a block or cubitt and provided farther down the next screen widget tree.
The existing instance will be passed right inside the value parameter from the block provider, that
value widget.
This is where most people, including me, make a huge mistake at first.
The right block provider that value and they provide the value of counter cubitt.
If you save this project now and run it, you'll see that everything works fine.
The error is gone.
All the functionality seems to be working smoothly now.
Well, being on the home screen, let's increment a counter to five and then go to the second screen.
You may notice that something isn't quite right.
The counter is zero, but if we go back, the counter is still five.
Why is this happening?
Take a look at what we actually provided to the value parameter.
A new instance of counter cubitt.
What should have we provided instead?
An existing instance of the counter cubitt.
So what happens is that every time we push the second screen, we wrongly provide a new counter cubitt
instance.
This is really bad because not only the instance won't close automatically since it was not created
by a block provider, but it will also have a completely different state than the existing instance
from the home screen.
And it will defeat the purpose of having one unique instance of the counter to beat around our app.
What we should do instead is provide the existing instance of the counter cubitt to the second screen.
If you remember back from the blockhouses view, we can access an existing instance of a cubitt or block
by calling either block provider of Cubitt context or context that block cubitt.
This was one of the two problems that may encounter.
If you're not careful when you're providing blocks or qubits to new pages, let's say that this one
can be avoided, but the next one is simply too easy to mess up.
You may think that if you save and run the project now, everything will work.
That's what I also thought multiple times.
But surprise, you'll see the previous error popping up again, this time arising from the builder function
inside the material page instead of the second stream.
How could and flutter find the existing instance of the country?
Cubitt in the context, we know for sure that's available inside the context of the home screen.
But is the context from which we're searching for the counter cubitt the appropriate context?
No, it's not.
If you look closer, the context in which we're searching for the counter Cubitt is the new context.
The second screen is being created.
So instead of searching inside the homescreen context, we are wrongly searching inside the new context
of the second screen.
That's because we have the same name for both context.
Imagine having to debug this.
It would have been a nightmare.
That's why I told you to pay as much attention to these two major issues that may arise.
In order to fix this, we have to rename the second screen context, the new context, or maybe replace
it with underscore since we won't use its value now, after we save and run the application, we can
see that everything works as it should.
We successfully provided the only instance of Counter Cubitt to the second screen's anonymous routt.
If we're developing a small application with a few screens, this is how you can provide an instance
of a block or cubitt through all of your anonymous screen routes one by one on multiple screens, though
you may need to take a look at named or generated throughout access.
And that's what we'll tackle up next.
But first, let's create a third screen for the next topic.
We'll duplicate some parts of the home screen again just to save some time.
OK, so name Drought Access is basically referring to providing an existing instance of a block or cubitt
to the screens while navigating with Nimrods.
Since we're currently navigating with anonymous routes, we need to completely refactor the navigation
part of our app in a.
Application refactoring the navigation feature may take a huge amount of time, so that's why it's important
to stick to navigating technique from the start, depending on how big your project it is going to be.
We will list all of our routes inside the perimeter of our material app class.
Any application should have a default home route which will be pushed in the first place when the application
starts.
This route must be named inside the routes list, since Slash is the universal sign for home in programming.
Let's get to the coding part.
Since it would be easier to explain what's going on, let's start refactoring the entire code in order
to integrate name droughts.
Since we have already created the screens, we need to decide which one is going to be the home road
and then associate the rest of them with an alternate.
As I told you, the material app class comes with a route's parameter, which takes in a map of pairs
pairs which contain both the root name and the screen objects we want to assign them to.
OK, so first and foremost, we need to set up our home front by routing its route name, which is slash
and link it to the screen we want to launch when the route is pushed down the navigation stack.
Since the screen we want to push is the home screen will write down a function taking the context as
a parameter and returning the home screen.
The same procedure applies for the rest of our screens.
Let's name slash second the wrong name, referring to the second string and slash third the route referring
to the third screen.
Of course, in order to easily differentiate between them, I will set them different colors and titles
so that a second screen has red X in color and the third screen has a green accent color.
These are all our roots and screens will use inside our app since we have our roots attribute with an
already defined home wrote.
We can delete the home parameter since we won't need it any longer.
Now for this name, not access topic, we're interested in how we can navigate by using name routes,
but most importantly, how we can provide a unique instance of a block or cubitt across all of them.
You might notice that right now we don't have any block provider widget wrapping any of our screens.
Can you guess why?
Well, if we had, we would have to provide a new instance of our country.
Cubitt for every screen.
Again, we definitely don't want this.
We want to provide a unique instance of our countercoup cubitt across all of our screens.
So this time will create the instance manually.
Here at the top, we will prepare the name of the variable with an underscore to make the field only
available inside this class.
Note that we have a unique instance of Kountry.
Cubitt can be provided with block provider across every screen.
Well, yes, you could, but it's not really worth it, since the only advantage of using block provider
is that it automatically closes the counter cubitt, but only when the counter cubitt is created inside
the block provider itself.
We created it at the top of our my app class, so using block provider would be nonsense.
Then what should you use instead of taking my what I have already told you, when we want to provide
an existing instance of a block or Cubitt, we will use block provider that value widget when we want
to create and provide a block or cubitt in the same place.
We should use the standalone broke provider widget here.
We can create and provide the counter Kebede for every screen because that would lead us to having three
different countercoup instances.
I have told you multiple times that inside any app we should only have one unique working instance of
a cubitt or block.
So that's why we created only one here at the top, and that was it.
Hence, we need to wrap all of the screens with a block provider that value widget, and provide them
with our existing single instance of counter cubitt.
Remember that block provided that value won't close the PROVIDEA block automatically, we will need
to close it manually where we created it.
More specifically, where the my app class gets this post.
My app is a statelets widget which doesn't have a disposal method, so we'll have to convert it to a
stateful widget.
And then inside of this method we will need to call the closed function on our counter.
Cubitt, we're almost done.
All we need to do now is to modify the buttons from where we pushed our name roads into the navigation
stack for that.
Firstly, we need to visit the home screen from where we'll have two buttons, one navigating to the
second screen and the other one navigating to the third screen in order to push a name brought down
the navigation stack.
We need to use the navigation that of context, not push named function and write the specific name
as an argument.
Now, if we run and save the project, we can see that everything is working perfectly as expected.
The navigation feature.
It's fully functional, the counter works flawlessly, and this is how we can provide a block or Kubi
to multiple screens of your -- by using named routing.
Now we can finally get to my favorite way to navigate seat flutter, which is by using generated routes.
So what is generated routing?
My top choice when it comes to navigating in flutter you mask?
Well, mainly for two main reasons.
One is that it mainly looks the same as the name routing, which means it borrows its advantages, thus
being organized and properly structured.
The second thing is that everything relates to the navigation cannot be separated into a single file.
OK, since we're going to change the navigation feature again inside our app, we need to refactor the
navigation part again.
Will begin by creating a separate router folder inside the presentation layer since overall navigation
is related to the UI.
Inside the folder will create a file called App Underscore a router that dart in which will set up all
the logic for navigating to all of our screens.
The main idea here is that we want to create a function which takes in mainly the name of the route
we want to generate and returns the generated screen accordingly.
So we'll create a function called own generator result, which returns the type of route and this is
going to accept a settings parameter inside.
This function will create a switch statement which will contain our three root names.
The own names can be accessed from inside the root setting parameter by calling settings that name.
So we'll have three main cases, one for the home screen, one from the second screen, and finally
one for the third screen.
For each case, we will return a material page result which returns our specific screen inside its builder
function.
Since this is a switch statement, we also need to mention a default case, which will be called whenever
one of the real names is not equal to any of the mentioned cases.
OK, so again, we set up the navigation feature, but what we want now is to know how we can provide
an existing instance of a block or Kubi to each of our screens.
Creating a new instance for each screen is again not an option.
So instead we will create the unique tumed instance right at the top, as we did with the name routing.
Then, since we need to provide the existing instance of Cubitt we created to all of our screens, we
need to wrap them inside a block, provide that value widget again.
Since we created the Cubitt manually will also need to manually close.
It will do this by creating a display function in which will close the cubitt.
We're close to finishing the scenario.
Our approach to class is really to manage the navigation feature of our app.
But now we need to go inside the main Dadda file and in the material app we can delete the parameter
completely since we don't need it anymore.
Instead, we'll use the own generator parameter, which takes in our own generator function from inside
our operator class.
So first of all, we need to create an approach, for instance, at the top and then pass the on generator
function of it to the own generator parameter.
Pay attention because we need to pass the function as an argument and not as a result of it.
Finally, inside of this function will close the counter cubitt by calling app router that disposer.
I want you now to observe how organized everything is.
Every feature is placed in its own folder and is structured nicely and easy to read and understand.
If you run the project now, you can see that everything is working as expected.
Now think of this fact for a moment.
Inside your application, you'll definitely have multiple blocks and Cubitt.
Each one of them will have their own functionality and will work on a specific screen or part of your
app.
Now you know how to provide our block instances locally and specifically to each of your multiple screens.
But what happens if you have one hundred screens and you want to provide a block to all of your screens,
will you have to provide it one by one?
Think a little bit about an altercation block.
You need to know the state of it around the entire app, not only inside the login or logout page.
Why?
Well, what if the authentication session expires?
You will want to keep the authenticate user out of whatever the screen he's browsing at.
The moments right in this case will need global access.
But how can we provide a single instance of a cubitt or block to all of our screens?
You wouldn't believe this, but if you wrap the material app inside the block provider or even inside
the multiple provider, every block or cubitt you provider will be globally available inside every screen
of your app.
What it is possible is beyond the purpose of this video, but it will be addressed in detail in future
tutorials.
Let's tackle up the coding part.
So right now we're manually providing an existing counter QB to all of our screens.
One.
Buy one because we need it in all our streets, but what we can do instead is provided globally, as
we discussed.
Let's refactor the code for the last time in this tutorial.
We don't need this instance anymore here.
And none of the block provided that value widgets.
We can also delete the dispose function since will create the instance of the block inside the block
provider.
Therefore, the block provider will automatically close it then my app class does need to be a stateful
widget anymore, so we convert it back to a statelets widget.
All we need to do now is to wrap the material up inside the block provider and create the only instance
of the counter cumi to be provided globally to all of our screens.
As you can see, if you save the project and right right now everything will work as previously, but
this time having the counter to be provided globally accessible from every screen inside the app.
OK, I know it's been a long tutorial for you guys and I hope I didn't lose you on the way here.
There is some important information you need to have in your mind before you leave the tutorial.
I recommend you to watch it multiple times and practice as much as you can.
Here goes a list of what you need to briefly understand as you watch this tutorial.
So by default, you can navigate in many ways inside flutter by using anonymous routing, named routing
and generated routing.
Remember that the key here is to provide a unique instance of a block or cubitt to one or multiple screens.
You shouldn't create multiple instances of the same block because that might cause unexpected behavior.
Take in mind that block provider creates and provides a new instance of a cubitt or block.
On the other hand block provider that value takes on already created instance of a block or covid and
then provided far more.
Depending on the navigation where you chose.
You can provide your block or cubitt instances the following ways locally when you want to provide the
instance to a single screen, specifically when you want to provide the instance specifically across
one or multiple screens and globally, when you want to provide the instance across all of your screens,
remember to always double check in which context you're searching for an existing instance of the block
or Cubitt, because that can also cause a lot of problems.
Wow.
We have finally arrived at the end of the six chapter.
I hope I didn't lose you along the way.
I admit it was a long and difficult one, so please feel free to watch it as many times as you want.
However, in the next chapter will relax a little bit and talk about how two or more cubits or books
communicate well with other ones.
We'll definitely like this one.
With that being said, I'm looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in the next chapter.
Stay tuned and let's get with it.