What is going on, everyone?
And welcome back to chapter number seven.
In this chapter, I will introduce you to block to block communication, especially how books or kibbitz
communicate between each other in this material will also cover up some further block architecture tips
and tricks.
And to general recap of everything we learned so far so that you'll be able to practice and structure
code even better.
Also, if you want to follow up by practicing this tutorial, you need to clone my block from zero to
hero repository from GitHub and open up the sixth block access folder.
That's where we left last time.
OK, so in order to start this lesson with the motivational purpose, you need to know that sooner or
later you said your application, you will have one or multiple blocks or qubits which may need to communicate
with other blocks or cubits.
By communication, I mean that one may do something in response to a state change over another.
Remember, from my third and second story on the series that both cubits and blocks emit a stream of
states.
Well, because of that, other blocks can listen and receive those states and then act appropriately
in response to them by perhaps adding an event or by calling a new function.
So the main question here is how can a block or Cubitt listen to another block or cubie?
To be fair, there are two possible scenarios you can tackle in order to achieve this.
Both have their own pros and cons and can be equally good.
So the method you'll be choosing in the future will be strictly a matter of taste.
Today, as an example, will learn how to communicate between two cubits by adapting our existing app
a little bit so that whenever the phone is connected to Wi-Fi, the counter will be incremented by one.
And whenever the phone is connected to mobile data, the counter will be documented by one.
So we'll have an internal cubitt and a countercoup, both communicating one with another.
Let's start by discussing the first method on how to blocks or qubits can communicate one with another.
If you remember back in the trial, number two, when I talked about streams, I told you that in order
to listen to a stream of data, you need to subscribe to a stream subscription.
A stream subscription is the foundation object from which you can listen to a stream.
So what would stop us from using it as a method to listen to a block cubitt?
Well, nothing.
So currently we know that blocks or qubits start to emit states right after the unique instance is created.
Most of them will admit an initial state right after they were created.
So it's important to understand that the stream subscription object will use to listen to a block or
Cubitt should be listening right from the start and actually before the first date is emitted.
How can we do that?
Well, by initializing the Stream subscription inside the Block or Cubitt constructor.
So in our example, we set up an Internet Stream subscription object inside the countercoup constructor.
Since this is where we start listening to the Internet, Bloks emitted states.
However, you need to understand that since you created the stream subscription manually, you also
need to close it manually somewhere so that you won't listen to the stream forever.
You can do this inside the overridden close method from inside any block or cube.
OK, so we established the connection between the two bits, but what's the purpose of it?
The purpose of it lies in the listener function.
There you'll have a stream of internal states coming from the Internet cubitt.
So since we want to counter incremented by one every time the phone is connected to wi fi, all we need
to do is checking if an incoming state is the one corresponding to when the phone is connected to a
fight and as a result will come the counter kibbitz increment function right away.
This is how you can stream subscription in order to establish a block to block connection.
Let's dive ourselves into the coding part.
OK, so after opening project number six inside this code will start by browsing the perspective of
the file here.
We need to add the latest connectivity underscore plus dependancy to our project.
This dependency will help us find out when the phone is connected to either wi fi mobile or to nothing.
Know that on Android.
If the plugin reports a wi fi or mobile connection running on your phone, that doesn't mean it has
Internet connection.
For now, we're only interested if the phone is connected to a network or not and we don't care if that
network sends or retrieve data from the Internet.
Now, let's start by creating our Internet cubitt and move it inside our Cubitt folder.
The first thing I always go after creating a block or Cubitt are its dates, because first and foremost,
you need to know the purpose of your block or Kubi and also what are the possible cases.
It will return as a stream of data.
So by analyzing the documentation of connectivity plus package, we can deduce that the first possible
states are connected to wi fi, connected to mobile and disconnected.
Since there are two almost identical states will create an enum for the type of connection we were using.
There are two types, so we'll have two members for the connection type info, wi fi and mobile.
Now here's an architecture tip number one predefined types enum constants and generally call that.
Doesn't change at all during the life cycle of Europe can be moved inside, the Konstanz folder will
create one inside the folder.
We also need to create an Enum Stoddart file, since every enum you'll create inside your app must lie
down there for easier access.
Therefore, the code will be more organized.
OK, coming back to our Internet states, we have decided to have an Internet connected and internet
disconnected.
State will focus on the Internet connected for a moment.
We know that our phone can be connected to the Internet by using either Wi-Fi or mobile data.
Therefore, the type of connection needs to be specified inside the state.
This can be done by creating a final variable of the connection type will assign it as a required parameter
inside the constructor.
So whenever the Internet Cubitt will meet, a new interconnected state will have to mention the type
of connection we're using, whether it's Wi-Fi or mobile.
By default, every block or cubitt comes with an initial state.
This state is emitted when the block or Cubitt instance gets created.
We know that will instantiate the Internet cubitt when the application starts.
And since the plug in may take some time to detect whether the phone is connected to wi fi or mobile
or to nothing, we'll need to show a loading animation in order to let the user know that something
is actually happening in the background.
So instead of showing an Internet initial state will show an Internet loading state.
Now, if we switch to the Internet with glass, we can notice that when the Internet KUBIS constructor
gets called, the first and immediate Internet state down the stream will be Internet loading.
OK, so we finished coding our internal states successfully.
From this point, I'd like to continue by creating the specific Cubitt methods which will the states
we created previously.
The Imit Internet connected function will take a connection type as a parameter and will emit an Internet
connected state with the same connection type so that we know whether it's the wi fi or mobile data
we're connected to.
Last but not least will create an Internet disconnected function that will end the Internet disconnected
state accordingly.
So to recap, the purpose of this Internet Cubitt is to emit different Internet connection states based
on what is written by the connectivity plus plugin.
Therefore, somehow we need to react to do something in response to the connectivity plus plugin.
So we need to add a dependency of it into the Internet cubitt class.
We can do this by creating a connectivity variable and passing it as a required parameter inside the
constructor.
Let's take a look again at how the plugin returns, the type of connection of your phone, as you can
see it can either return it a single time when we call the check connectivity function or multiple times
through a stream that is internally managed by the plugin.
We're really interested in the latter scenario since we always want to know the state of our connection
as we want to listen to every possible connection type the plugin sends down the stream.
How convenient.
So today, not only will learn how a block can listen to another block, but also how can a block listen
to a specific stream of a plugin?
Both have the same stream subscription approach, so it's amazing that we can tackle out both of them.
OK, since we need our internal QB to listen to the connectivity plus stream.
First and foremost, we need to create a stream subscription so that we'll be able to subscribe to the
specific stream.
Then we'll need to initialize this connectivity stream subscription inside the constructor by subscribing
to the on connectivity change stream and then by listening to it.
So to recap, every time a new connection is noticed by the connectivity plus plugging this on connectivity
change stream will send the connectivity result down the stream.
Currently, our Internet cubitt is just listening to the connectivity results emitted by the plugin,
but we also need to do something in response to them.
We need to meet new Internet states accordingly to what the connectivity result is.
So every time a connectivity result is received down the stream will verify if it's of type connectivity
that wi fi, mobile or not, if it's of type connectivity that wi fi will call the imit.
Internet connected function from inside the cube in the mobile case will change the connection type
to mobile.
And finally, if the connectivity result is of type connectivity result that none will amidst the Internet
disconnected state.
Not that we don't need to meet the Internet loading state since it will be automatically emitted when
the Internet cubitt is created.
If you hover on the connectivity stream subscription variable, you can see that DART is warning you
because the created stream subscription hasn't been closed yet.
We don't want you to be listening forever.
So we'll close the subscription right when the block is closed.
So let's have a little overview of what we did until now.
So we added the connectivity plus dependency in our project.
We created the Internet Cubitt.
We did the respective Internet states inside the Internet Cubitt.
We created the methods from which we can admit our created internal states.
And then we learned how to be can communicate with the plugin by subscribing to its stream of data.
The stream contains the type of connection.
Our phone records during the lifecycle of our app, depending on whether the phone is connected to wi
fi mobile or to nothing, we called our cubitt functions accordingly.
Nice.
We're really making a ton of progress.
What's left for now is how our well known counter cubitt can communicate with the newly created Internet
Cubitt.
Remember that our goal is that whenever the phone is connected to Wi-Fi, the counter should increment
and whenever the phone is connected to mobile, the counter should dichromate.
So let's switch our attention to the counter cubitt since we need a counter to be incremented or decrement
it as a result of a new Internet state, the counter cubitt will be dependent on the Internet cubitt.
So we need to have a final field of type.
Interent Cubitt ready to be initialized inside the counter cubitt constructor as a required field.
Then, in order for the counter to communicate with the Internet, Cubitt will proceed, as we did previously,
by creating a stream subscription which will subscribe to the Internet Cubitt stream of states.
Remember that each block or cubitt has a stream of states you can subscribe to.
Therefore, Internet Cubitt has one too, and will subscribe to it inside countercoup so that whenever
a new Internet state is retrieved down the stream, we can do something in response.
In our case, we need to check whether the received interstate is a type of Internet connected and the
connection type is either wi fi or mobile so that we can call either the increment or Dyckman functions
respectively.
Again, we need to cancel the Internet stream subscription inside the closed method of the cube so that
we won't listen to it forever.
And now here's architecture.
Tip number two.
You have to agree that the code looks a little bit messy now.
So let's refactor it a little bit inside the Internet.
Cubitt, you can see that all we do in the constructor can be extracted to a method.
We can call it monitor Internet connection.
Since this is what the function actually does, we can do the same with the counter cubitt this time
we'll call it monitor Internet Cubitt, since according to the states emitted by it will increment or
decrement our counter value.
All we need to do now is to provide both our internal cubitt and counter cubitt globally to our pages.
But the reality is that the counter cubitt is dependent on the Internet cubitt and the Internet.
Cubitt is also dependent on the connectivity plus plugin.
So what do we do in this case?
What I usually do is instantiate the objects by following the order from the least dependent one to
the most dependent one.
We know that our connectivity plugin doesn't depend on anything, so we'll create it firstly.
And now here's architecture.
Tip number three, a good practice.
When you want to create a standalone instance, which is an instance that doesn't depend on anything,
is to create it at the top inside the main function and then inject it into the app.
In our case, within the app glass.
This way, our dependent cubits, blocks or repositories can use their specific methods like block provider,
repository provider to create and also inject themselves into the rest of the app accordingly while
also having access to the required dependencies.
Of course, this varies on the way you chose the provider blocks.
As we learned in the previous tutorial, all you need to do is to adapt to your needs.
Now we need to modify the UI of the home screen a little bit just to double check that everything works
will also place a block builder which will rebuild a text widget accordingly to the current internal
state.
So whenever the interstate is Internet connected, will display either wi fi or more, but also when
the interstate is Internet disconnected, will display a disconnected text widget on the screen.
Finally, when the interstate is Internet loading, will use a circular progress indicator to let the
user know that some process is actually running in the background will also disable the plus and minus
buttons since we won't use their functionality anymore.
I also need some refactoring to the UI code, which only beautifies our app.
You don't need to do that since we only care about the functionality right now.
We can finally save and run the application.
And as you can see, when it finds out that the phone is connected to wi fi, a new Internet connected
state is emitted and the UI rebuilds accordingly.
You can also notice that the counter cubitt successfully retrieved the new internal state, too, since
it incremented the value by one.
And if we turn off the wi fi and connect to mobile data, you'll see the same behavior.
This time, though, the counter will decrement when no Internet connection is available, though the
application displays it properly and the counter doesn't do anything.
Since it wasn't programmed to do anything as a response to the state, we finally succeeded tackling
up this block to block communication scenario by using stream subscriptions.
I hope that from the above code you learned even more than that, since we also improved our block architecture
structure even more.
Let's have a minute and talk a little bit about the pros and cons of the stream subscription way of
communicating between blocks.
Well, for me, the advantage is that the code looks really understandable, readable and easy to structure
and maintain.
This method will also help you practice your stream skills.
Stream subscription is the foundation of subscribing and listening to the stream flow.
A disadvantage may be that if you have lots and lots of block to block communications, you may be overwhelmed
by the number of stream subscriptions you need to create.
But most importantly, close things can get pretty cluttered in a big application, and huge memory
leaks may appear as a result.
So if you're not really ready to manage the stream subscriptions, you need to take a look at the next
method used to communicate between blocks and.
Remember that in my third Flutter Block concept story of the series, I specifically introduced you
to a widget called Block Listener.
If you remember, this widget was meant to be used only when you want to do something in response to
a block or cubitt state change.
For example, we use block listner to show an increment or decrements snack.
But so what prevents us from using the block listener in order to do something in response to a new
state?
Absolutely nothing.
But why would we do that?
What is the advantage of this over the stream subscription method?
Well, the advantage is that you don't need to create a stream subscription anymore since the Block
or Cubitt manages it internally from the start.
So in having many blocks communicating with each other, you don't need to think of which subscription
you should cancel or create.
Everything is being taken care of under the hood at the first glance since the Block listener is a widget
and must be placed inside the widget, you may feel like doing something in response to a state change
inside the UI introduces logic inside.
The UI therefore violates our architecture principle of isolating the logic from the UI.
This is wrong because calling a new Cubitt function or adding a new block event isn't related to the
logic of the app.
It's just a notifier on what the block or kibbitz should do is just notifying the block what to do,
not how to do it.
Hence by using the block listner widget in order to do something in response to a state.
Change isn't related to logic.
OK, let's get into the coding part of this method.
So definitely the most important advantage over stream subscription is the fact that we don't need to
create or manage the stream subscriptions manually.
So that's reflected the code and delete the subscriptions from inside the counter.
Cubitt, we don't even need the Internet blog dependancy anymore since we'll just listen to it by using
block listener inside the widget tree.
So the counter cubitt class will actually be having just its plain functionality in there.
But now inside the homescreen page we can add a block listener somewhere here.
Doesn't really matter where.
As long as there is a context containing the block or Cubitt, you want to react to the incoming status.
So in our case, the context should contain both the Internet, covid and counter cubitt unique instances.
We provided them globally, so they're available everywhere inside the app.
I like to wrap the top of the widget three of the page with the Block listener so that it looks more
organized.
Remember that Block listener is different to block builder.
Block listener just listens to a stream of data while Lochbihler listens and rebuilds the UI based on
a stream of data.
So it's safe to place block listener at the top of the tree since it won't rebuild anything inside the
block.
Listener will listen to the Internet covid and act accordingly by calling the behavior that we want.
If the internal state is of type Internet connected and the Internet type is wi fi will call the increment
function of the countercoup.
If it's of type mobile will call the Degremont one again.
We can access the countercoup unique provided instance by either calling context that block or provider
that of.
Now, if we save and run the project, you will see that the application has exactly the same functionality
as with the stream subscription method.
So what about the pros and cons of this block listener approach compared to the stream subscription?
Once Inside Block Listener Block Library takes care internally of all these streams subscriptions,
so we don't need to spend extra time verifying where they were created or closed in the first place
in the same time.
Adding Block listeners inside your UI may also create some readability issues if you have a lot of them
stacked one over another.
So at the end of the day, it's up to you.
What's the method you'll be approaching?
More or less?
Let me know in the comments section which one you actually prefer the most.
I hope you enjoyed this chapter in the next one.
I will get really in-depth on how to context works.
This is an important topic.
I noticed most of the tutorials failed to explain properly.
Will understand together how Futter builds the widget tree in the background and help build context
helps towards organising and structuring it.
Believe me, if you have any doubts on how context works along with Flutter and Block, after watching
this next chapter, you won't have anything more to worry about.
With that being said, I'm looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in the next chapter detuned
and let's get wicked.