What is going on, everyone?
I'm wicked.
And today I'm going to show you how easy it is to maintain the state of your block build application
with dehydrated block package.
This is a topic that is often omitted, but to be honest, I think it's one of the most important pillars
of a flutter application.
By default, every application you'll build inside Flutter won't be able to maintain its state after
rebooting.
As an example, we'll take a look at our current counter app.
If we increment the counter to five and then hit the restart button, the state of the application will
revert back to its initial state.
So in order to avoid this, we'll need to somehow store the entire state of our application so that
whenever the application reboots, it will be able to access the already stored data.
Okay, so states we've all been talking about them since the beginning of this tutorial series.
We learn that a state is a group of data that is stored inside the application at a moment in time.
Right.
Remember, BLOCK Library is a powerful state management solution.
BLOCK Library helped us create the state, but now it's our duty to help its store, therefore maintain
them.
The way we're going to do this is by using the hydrated block package.
In order to understand how hydrated block works, we need to see where and more importantly, how it
stores the data of our app.
So where are we going to store all of our data?
This place needs to be fast and close to the application.
Therefore, the most intuitive solution would be actually the local storage of the device the application
runs on.
You may have heard that every app running on an Android device will benefit from its own internal storage
where it can store some of its data.
So this is where hydrogen block will also have access to store our application state.
Let's start with this.
First, I'll open up my previous project Inside the Scope, a project that can be found on my GitHub
page, which is listed into description.
Then we'll need to add dehydrated block dependency.
So we'll open up the box, pick that YAML file and list it.
Right there will also need a path provider dependency because this will help flutter retrieve the path
for the storage of different devices the application may be installed on.
Now we'll let you tell a hydrated block what will be the accessible storage area required to store our
data onto.
To do that inside the main function from our main dart file, we need to set up its storage.
This hydrated build function asynchronously creates the connection from the hydrated block to the storage
on where it's going to store the data by default.
If we're not mentioning anything to the storage directory parameter of the function, the data will
be stored to a temporary storage which can be easily removed by the operating system at any time.
So it's not really recommended to store anything there.
Instead, we could set the storage to the one provided by Android for the current app.
This entire line of code will call native code to initialize the required storage and link it to hydrated
block.
But in order to do that, we need to initialize the widget bindings before we start building our app.
Otherwise we wouldn't be able to call the native code, so keep that in mind.
Okay.
So currently we establish the connection between the hydrated block and the app storage layer.
Now all we need to find out is how hydrated block will interpret and save the data.
We want to be stored inside that storage layer.
And the answer is Jasons.
You must have heard about Jason before.
I talked about them in my full tutorial in block architecture when I say that the data fetched from
the outside of the app may come in adjacent file format, so similar to how the app can import the data
from adjacent format, the same thing can happen vice versa.
The application can also export the data to a JSON format.
What's left for us right now is to decide which data we want to save in the storage.
So let's start by maintaining the state of the counter qubit.
The state of the counter qubit is found in the counter state class.
So let's code that first.
As I told you a couple of moments ago, we'll need to export the data of this class into a JSON later
on.
Hydrated block will take the exported JSON and store it safely into the storage.
You can easily create the to JSON and from JSON methods of an already existing class by clicking control
plus period and then by selecting JSON serialization.
This is only available through the dark data class generated via Xcode module.
I know a lot of you asked me what this module was, so here it is installed on my VTS code.
As you can see, the module generated all the functions we needed for our counter state class implementation.
Now I want you to understand why it created four methods to map from map to JSON and from JSON.
A JSON is a file having the json.
An extension appended to its name.
This is mostly how an API will reply to your HTTP request.
Dart language can only understand its own types of data like integers, doubles, booleans, maps,
lists and so on and so forth.
It doesn't have a special type called JSON, so we need to take the JSON file, which is mainly a really
large string and decoded to a type that is familiar with the type that is similar to the structure of
a JSON.
Is the map similar to a JSON?
A map keeps multiple key value pairs inside it.
So we have the JSON file.
We'll decode it into a map variable using the from JSON method.
Then we'll use the map to create a class instance with the from map method.
Vice versa.
If you have an instance of a class with some data inside, it will use that to map method to create
a map out of that specific instance, then use the to JSON method to create a JSON file out of that
map.
And that's the entire process of converting an instance of a class to a completely storable JSON and
vice versa.
That's the purpose of all these methods, and that's how helpful this dark data class generator function
is.
Imagine how much time it would take to manually write this function.
So at this point, the counter state class can be fully exported and imported to and from JSON.
Now we want to find out where and when hydrated block will come into action.
So let's switch our attention to the counter qubit class for a block or qubit to become hydrated.
That is for the state of a block or qubit to be saved and retrieved from the storage.
We need to use the high rate in mixing to the class.
Note that we can also use the hydrated qubit or hydrogen block extension of the counter state class
instead of using the hydrogen mixing.
As you can see, that warns us that we need to override the two methods of the hydrated mixing from
JSON and to JSON.
These two methods are the pillars of storing and saving the state to the storage while also being able
to retrieve it back when the app is rebooted.
Take in mind also that these methods should have been called from map and to map, since all they do
is import and export a map type from the storage.
Since the JSON is most of the time translated into a map, it is acceptable to call them from JSON to
JSON.
But you have to keep in mind the difference.
All we have to do now is to implement those functions.
You need to take in mind that the to JSON function is called for every state emitted by the counter
qubit and that the from JSON function is called every time the application needs the locally stored
data.
Let's go the to JSON method first.
So every time there is a new counter state emitted with the new counter value, we want to save its
data to a map and then send it to the hydrated block to store it onto the local storage.
When we want the app to access the last safe data from the local storage, high rated block will call
the from JSON function and retrieve the JSON, which is already converted into a map.
As I told you before, we need to return a new instance of the counter state populated with the data
from that map.
So we'll use the counter state from map method for that to happen.
If we finally save a run the project now you'll see that after we increment the value to five and then
restart the application, the value will still remain five.
And that's the exact behavior that we wanted to understand this tutorial much more in depth.
Let me get the whiteboard one more time and simulate every step of the process.
So we have the app, the counter cube with its hydrating block plugin attached, the counter state and
our storage components.
We have a counter value of zero, the initial value of the counter qubit.
When a user presses the plus button, the increment function from inside the qubit is triggered, causing
the counter cube to emit a new counter state with an incremented value of one.
Here, the hydrated block is notified that a new state has been dispatched and calls the to JSON function.
The to JSON function will call the two map method from inside the counter state, which takes all the
attributes of the class and their values and puts them into a map.
So right now we'll have a map which looks exactly like this.
This map is then being taken care of by the hydrated block plugin, therefore being stored on to the
storage.
Now let's say the app got killed or has been restarted by the user when it will be opened again.
High rated block will retrieve the last known data from the storage as a map of data.
Then, with the help of from JSON method of counter qubit and with the help of from map method of counter
state, it will create a new instance of counter state with the previously stored values, thus ending
the cycle and maintaining the counter state.
You might be wondering, well, what if we have a ton of read and write operations from the storage?
Won't that slow down the application?
No.
Hydrogen block is not only a real.
A useful plugin, but it's also really optimized and that's thanks to the high package that it used
under the hood to store the data.
Hive is the most efficient way of storing data.
Take a look at these benchmarks.
It's absolutely blazing fast.
So to sum up, every state from your blocks or qubits can be maintained and saved to the storage.
All you need to do is to decide which ones you want to keep in storage and which ones you don't.
For example, inside this application, you may store the state of the counter qubit and the state of
the settings qubit.
But you won't need to store the state of internet qubits since the state of the Internet connection
must be retrieved constantly, even when you reboot the app.
This was chapter number 11.
You are one chapter away from becoming a block hero.
Isn't it exciting?
In the final chapter, we're going to buckle up everything we learned and play with all the debugging
methods of a block or qubit.
So in case something goes wrong with them, we'll be able to successfully track and debug them at a
glance.
With that being said, I'm looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in the last chapter of
this course.
Stay tuned and let's get wicked.