What is going on, everyone, I'm wicked, and today I'm really happy to present you the last chapter
of this amazing block, complete course in this chapter.
I'll introduce you to debugging blocks and cubists code facilitating via code extensions and the some
of the most important naming conventions you should follow when working with Block Library on a large
project.
OK, so until now we kind of understood in big words how book library works, what are the main concepts
and how to structure the code of a blog driven app.
But what if something is wrong with one of our kibitzer blocks?
Is there a way we can specifically debug them?
Yes, there is both blocks and you have specific debugging methods you can override so that you can
observe their behavior while the app is running.
Remember, if that's a block is just an advanced type of cubitt block extends Cubitt.
Therefore, every debugging method found inside the cubitt will also be available inside a block.
At the same time, a block will benefit from some separate specific functions, thanks to its special
ability of being triggered by a stream of events.
So let's start with the Cubitt first.
Remember this diagram we discussed way back then?
When a cubit emits a new state, we say that a change occurs.
Therefore, we can deduce that a change contains only two pieces of information the current state and
the next state.
But why are they called current and next state instead of current and previous state?
Well, you need to understand that this unchanged method is called right before the state will be emitted
down the stream of states.
So at that moment in time, it makes more sense to call them current the next state.
So to sum up, with the help of this overeaten own change function, we can observe all changes for
a given Cubitt.
In order to see this in action, I'll open up my last project inside the code.
You can find it on my GitHub beach as always in the video description.
Then I'll simply navigate the counter cubitt and override the own change function.
As you may notice, this function takes a change instance of type counter state parameter.
So every time a new state is emitted down the stream of states, this function will be called with a
change instance containing both the current and the next state.
Obviously, this will help you track and debug the stream of omitted states, which is really important.
Inside this function.
You may adopt two approaches.
You can either manually code what you want to be printed by accessing both counts values of the current
and previous state.
Or you can opt for a much faster and efficient approach.
You can simply print the past change instance as a parameter to the O change function.
But how does Dart know how to print an instance of the counter state, you may ask?
Well, at the moment it doesn't.
But if we go to the counter state class, we can override the two string function, which is mainly
called when DART once a string representation of the object instantiated from the country's state class.
This is exactly what we want.
If we save and run the project right now, you'll notice how simple it is to track and debug a cubitt
whenever a new state is emitted by the counter cubitt either by incrementing or decremental the value.
A new change is printed in the debug console, letting us know what the current state is and what the
next state will be.
Another important method which you can override inside a cubitt is the on error method.
This is triggered whenever there is an exception inside a cubitt.
An application is most likely to have some exceptions during its lifetime.
But whenever we write something to the internal storage, something may go wrong with the operation.
If something goes wrong, then we may want to dispatch an exception with a specific error message.
We can do that by using the error function from inside any cubitt.
This function takes into arguments the exception you want to dispatch and the stack trace to where the
program ran until it retrieved that exception.
Let's add this function randomly inside the to Jason method to simulate something that may go wrong
with it.
So whenever that adjacent method is called, that is whenever a new state is being emitted by the Cubitt,
a new error will be added at the same time, due to the fact that we override the on error method inside
the cubitt, the app will print the exception and it's territories so that you'll will be able to understand
what went wrong with the application.
OK, so we finished with how we can debug and trace a specific cubitt.
But what about the block?
By extending Cubitt block is actually a more advanced type of cubitt comparing both of them.
We learned in the past that the only difference between a cubitt and a block is that the block is event
driven.
That means a block does something in response to a stream of events dispatched from the UI in comparison
to those things whenever.
One of the predefined methods is called, therefore, due to the fact that Block reacts as a response
to a stream of events, there must be a way to debug and trace this stream of events to.
And indeed, it is the first method that can be overridden, which is only available to a block is the
on event method, as name is implying.
And similar to the own change method on event is simply a method that is called as soon as the new event
gets dispatched to the stream of events.
Another block specific method that can be overridden is the own transition method on transition.
Method is kind of a combination between own change and on event.
Since you displace the current state, the next state and also the event that triggered the block to
dispatch a new state over the current state.
So by calling on change, you'd get this output and by calling on transition you also get this.
But in addition, you'll also retrieve the event that caused the states to change.
So to sum up, along with the only change and on error methods, methods borrowed from the covid a block
also comes in addition with its specific ones, like on event and on transition.
Now another important question will arise.
In a huge application, you'd have maybe more than 20, 30 blocks and qubits altogether doing different
tasks.
What if you want to track each and every one of them?
Will you have to manually override every function inside every block or cubitt?
Well, you could do that, but it will be obviously time consuming.
Instead will use a block library internal feature, which manages everything related to observing and
debugging cubits and blocks.
I'm talking about the Block Observer.
The Block Observer is a utility class from Inside the Block library, which contains every previously
mentioned methods like own change on error, on event, on transition, and also two extra ones on create
and one close.
These last ones are called Whenever A Block or Cubitt has been created or closed.
We'll take a look at those in a couple of moments in order to test block observer first and foremost
and erase the already overridden methods inside our country.
Cubitt, of course, to avoid multiple identical outputs.
Remember, Block Observer will take care of every cubitt and block inside Europe.
Then let's create a new folder called Utility inside our Logic Folder, inside of which I'll create
an app.
Underscore, Block, Underscore Observer that dirt file here.
I'll create an app block observer class that obviously extends the block observer managed internally
by the Block Library after that, and they sure to overwrite every method we discussed today.
Most of them I won't be able to test since we're only playing with bits at the moment.
But the key of this material is to understand in big words what they're exactly doing.
So if we take a look at the own change method here, we can print the change exactly as we previously
did in the tutorial.
This unchanged will react globally right now to every change from every cubitt.
Therefore, the change parameter can be a type of counter state, internal state or setting state.
We need to make sure that every one of them have their two string Mesan overridden so that we can easily
print their values.
Let's switch our view to the uncreate and unclosed methods.
If you've ever been curious on how and most importantly, when our kibbitz get created inside our app,
now it's the time to learn one important key factor.
So let's print whatever kibbitz gets created here and observe a really important difference.
One thing that's left to be done now is to navigate inside the main dirt file and set up the block.
That observer to our newly created app Block Observer instance.
If we save our run, our app will notice an interesting fact.
Even though we have set up three block providers to get three cubits provided globally, only two of
them were created when we opened the app, the counter covid and the Internet covid.
But what about the settings covid?
Why wasn't it created?
Is there something wrong with it?
If we click the settings icon, we can observe that right after we pressed it, the settings Cubitt
got created.
So why exactly is this happening?
Well, let's switch our view to our block providers.
If you have ever wondered what these boolean lazy variable was designed for, now you'll understand
by default the lazy parameter of a block provider is set to true.
That means the providers block or Cubitt will be created only when the app really needs it.
In our case, the settings Cubitt was created when the app needed it in the settings page.
So this is a really cool optimization technique.
As a result, if we said the lazy parameter to force the settings cubitt.
Will be created right after the app runs, another fact you may have observed is that the first change
occurring in our app is actually the one where we're checking for the type of Internet connection then
whether we're incrementing or discriminating our counter value, other changes occur into the bug window.
Last but not least, if we modify the notification settings will also see a change with its respective
values.
So we're finally done discussing how we can debug and trace all of your blocks and qubits inside your
app.
I hope you understand how everything works.
Now it's time for me to continue showing you some of the tips and tricks that will make your development
life easier while working with Block Library.
I'll talk a little bit about some of the most frequently asked questions I got from you guys.
First question, how do you know when you should create a cubitt or a block?
The general rule is that you should create a cubitt or a block for every feature of your app.
As I said multiple times, and as you noticed in my tutorials, for every feature my app had, I created
a new cubitt.
Whenever we're talking about the counter feature, the Internet feature or the settings feature.
So that's the main rule.
If you want your app to be able to log in and create user accounts, then you should have an authentication
cubitt or a block.
If your apps work with different models like a country's fruits, weather planes, etc., then you should
have a block or cubitt for each and every one of them.
Then the next question would be when should I create a cubitt and when should I pick a block instead?
The general rule of this is that you should start by designing a cubitt for your feature and then if
you need the advanced features of a block, you can easily refactor the code and switch to it.
You know, the only difference between a block and the cubitt is that a block is event driven.
So you must think in which scenarios of your app it will be better to have events triggering a block
to do the job instead of having a method to trigger a cubit to do its job.
Remember, Cubitt works with simple and plain methods.
It's not a stream of methods.
Block, on the other hand, works with a stream of events, so you must take advantage of what operations
you could perform on that stream.
Another question I frequently get is what's the naming conventions you should follow when designing
a block or cubitt?
The answer here is not really a general rule.
You can name the blocks, cubits, events, methods and states.
Whatever you feel, it makes sense for your app.
There are, however, some naming conventions that will make your code look more organized and straightforward
for the state.
It recommended that you name them after this pattern, a block or cubitt subject, plus the action,
plus the state of the action.
For example, if you have a weather block, some of the weather states may sound like weather.
Fetch success, weather, fetch in progress or weather fetch failure.
If you have another user QB, some of the other states may sound like user creates success, user create
in progress, user delete, failer use their fetch success, etc..
You can see where I'm going with this for the events.
It recommended that you name them after this battered block or cubitt subject.
Plus the action.
The event itself in past tense events should be named in the past tense because events are things that
have already occurred from the blocks perspective.
For example, if you have one user block, again, some of the user events may sound like user fetched,
user deleted, user created, user modified, etc..
Now what about the methods of a cubitt?
Methods of a kibbitz should be named so that they denote exactly what a cubit is working on.
For example, if there is an user cubitt the method inside it should sound like Thach, delete, create,
modify and so on and so forth.
As I told you, these are only recommended conversions.
Feel free to modify them as much as you want, as long as it makes sense inside your own app.
One last question I receive in the comments is what we the extensions do I frequently use.
So here's a list of every viscose extension I use.
The first one is better comments.
I use this to highlight some of my code in a brighter color.
The block extension is a must when working with Block Library just because it offers you many timesaving
options like wrapping widgets and useful code snippets.
Bracket eyes are, on the other hand, is also an awesome extension.
I used to keep track of some of my brackets.
You'll find a dozen of brackets inside darte, so this is really efficient.
That extension adds support to the code for the DART programming language and provides tools for effectively
editing, refactoring, running and reloading apps.
Now, maybe the most popular one I used my tutorials.
The Dart data cloud generator is one of the best.
You can have four first class cogeneration like generating class constructors to string to Jason and
from Jason methods and many, many more, that import is a plugin I often use to refactor and optimize
my imports inside my app.
It's an amazing timesaver extension.
Flutter like the dart extension is also a really must have plugin for viscose, adding support for effectively
editing, refactoring, running and reloading flutter and mobile apps as well as support for the dart
programming language gradle.
Language support is a very useful extension to manage and code the dart griddled files found inside
the Flutter project now above the streaming of skilled material I team and Vaskov icons are the Vasko
extensions I use for personalizing my folder icons.
And last but not least, Bob's big assist is one of the most amazing extensions which will help you
add the latest dart and flutter packages from Pop that live right inside the pop spec that will file.
This is a plugin I really use a lot, so I definitely recommend it and I think disrupts out everything.
I wanted you to understand not only for this tutorial but also for this entire block from zero to Hero
tutorial series.
It is finally time to end this tutorial series.
I have spent so much time making every tutorial and I really hope I could help you in learning the really
popular blog library.
If I did, I would really appreciate if you could support me by subscribing to this channel and by liking
and sharing the entire tutorial series.
We learned everything about Block, but now it's time to put everything to practice by building real
world apps.
This will be the next tutorial series.
I invite each and every one of you to join.
Until then, as always, take care.
Stay safe.
Work.
It is out.
Bye bye.