Hey, what is going on, everyone?
Welcome back to chapter number nine today.
I'm going to show you some important changes introduced in the new stable version of Block Library.
We will tackle up newest additions like context, that watch context, that select and context, that
read additions which cause context, that block and context that the repository to become deprecated.
This video is going to be an extension of my third tutorial on Flutter Block concept since the changes
from six point one point zero are strongly related to some of the concepts we discussed back then.
OK, so in order to understand the changelog of clutter, block six point one point zero, we need to
see what was wrong with the previous six point zero point zero and lower version.
Remember when I introduced you to the Block Builder Widget concept?
Back in tutorial number three Block Builders duty was to rebuild a widget as a response to a state change
coming from a block or cubitt.
Of course, the obvious limitation of this approach lies exactly in the definition of more specifically
in the fact that block builder only reacts to a state change emerging from only one single block or
cubitt.
As a consequence of this limitation, some users wanted more granular control.
And since there is already a multiple provider and a multi repository provider that accepts multiple
blocks, cubits or repositories to be provided throughout the widget tree, they also wanted some kind
of a multi block builder, a tool which can rebuild a widget based on multiple blocks or Cubitt states.
This is where the newest concept named context, that watch was introduced.
In order to understand exactly what the context that watch function does, I need to translate it in
depth.
So context that watch of block a function translates into from the widget that was built within the
context built context starts searching for the unique instance of Block A provided above in the widget
tree.
Then after it's found, watch or subscribe to its stream of emitted states.
And whenever a new state is emitted by Block A rebuild the widget from which the lookup was started.
This was a surprisingly long translation for the code sequence, right?
So currently you might be tempted to say that the translation seems to be familiar to the definition
of block builder, yet there is still no multiple blocks or cubits mentioned inside it.
Then how can we watch state emitted by multiple blocks or qubits simply by calling context that watch
on the blocks or cubits you need to watch.
For example, if you want to rebuild a specific widget as a result of the states emitted by Block A,
block B and block C instances, all you need to do is 30 states in three different variables like block
A state, block B state, block C state and then return a widget.
You want to be built with the information from those three states.
Bear in mind that the return widget is not the only one that will be rebuilt whenever at least one of
these three status updates, but rather the entire widget built within the context from which the watch
method was called.
In our case, the entire building widget will be rebuilt.
Therefore our return widget too.
I hope this makes sense.
And if it doesn't, I invite you to watch my in-depth video about Bill context to see the context that
watch function in action will obviously need to blocks or kibbitz, so that will rebuild a specific
widget based on their separate states.
So I'll open up the project from my latest tutorial inside the code.
And right away you can observe that Flutter warns us we are using a deprecated version of Block.
So first and foremost, we need to update it to six point one point zero will do that by going to pub
spec that Yamal and rename the version of the flutter underscore block dependency from six point zero
point zero to six point one point zero.
If you have forgotten what our contract does every time the phone is connected to wi fi or mobile,
the counter value will either increment or decrement by one.
Therefore, currently our counter app is dependent on the network state.
But in order to test if a specific widget will rebuild based on at least one of the two separate states,
we need to make the cubits independent again so will delete the block listner which caused the counter
to to increment and decrement based on whether the Internet Cubitt was connected to wi fi or mobile,
then will uncommented the lines of code containing the plus and minus floating buttons that caused the
counter cubitt to manually increment or degremont.
Now both of our qubits are independent.
They won't do anything one as a response to the other in order to demonstrate our.
That watch works will have to create a widget which will rebuild whenever at least one of these two
cubits meets new states.
So let's create a text widget containing the current counter value.
And the current state of the Internet connection will need to wrap this widget with a builder so that
we get access to its closest context above it, after all.
All we need to do is to write the context that watch that state for each of the two cubits we're interested
in, then use them appropriately to return reserve text widget.
We can now save, build and run the application, thus observing that whenever I press the minus and
plus buttons, the builder widget built within the context from which the watch function was called
rebuilds.
Therefore the text widget rebuilds as well.
Then if I switch from mobile to Wi-Fi connection, you can see that the widget rebuilds again, leaving
the counter unchanged.
I hope you understood what the purpose of context that watch is and why it was introduced as an addition
of blog six point 1.0.
Now it's time to move on to the next edition.
The next feature was added as a response to those users who wanted a much simpler build and function.
So let's say, for example, you wanted a specific widget to be rebuilt only when the name of the user
changes.
How would you do that inside block six point zero point?
Oh, well, you would have created a block builder then you would have set up the building function
so that the widget you want to rebuild will rebuild only when the previous day that user that name is
different from current state, that user, that name.
But what if you wanted to do this in a simple manner?
Well, this is where context that select function comes into place as a new addition to block six point
one point zero contact that select similarly to contacts.
That watch is still linked to a build context, so it will still rebuild the widget built inside that
specific context.
Build context.
Remember, this select function is useful only when you want to rebuild a widget based on only one simple
select condition for more advanced conditions.
The recommended way to do it still remains the builder, along with the buildout and method.
Again, to test this, all we have to do is to wrap a text widget inside a building widget to access
its closer, build context and then retrieve the new counter value inside the variable while also updating
and rebuilding the builder widget.
If we save and run the project, you can see that context that select is working as it should whenever
the current counter value is different from the previous counter value context that select returns the
new value and rebuilds the builder widget and to move on to the next added feature.
You may have noticed during this tutorial that I have ignored some of the warnings from inside.
This is the most crucial one to understand.
Block is deprecated and shouldn't be used.
If we click on it, we find out that context, that block function got deprecated and that it will be
completely removed in version seven point zero point zero of block.
But why exactly is that happening?
I remember from my tutorial number three on Flutter Block Concepts when I explained that you can access
the unique provided instance of a block or Cubitt by either calling block provider out of context or
context.
That block from the feedback Felix Angelov retrieved from its block users.
He realized that people misunderstood the purpose of context that block.
Some of the users were using context that block to get the current state of a block or covid inside
the build function of a widget.
Then they would use the retrieved state in order to make further decisions on other widgets.
This is terribly wrong and should be avoided at all costs because it can cost unpredictable behavior.
Whitewell Because there is nothing that guarantees at what moment in time that build function will be
called within flutter engine.
Thus, what will the state of the Block or Cubitt be in that situation?
Remember, state is a stream of data, so you should be listening to it and do something in response
to each value of the stream rather than asking randomly for a value at a random moment in time.
But wait, you said contact.
That block will be removed.
Then how can we access an instance of a provided block?
Well, you can still access it by using block provider that of context or from now on by using the last
addition of blocks six point one point zero, which is context that read function context that read
is as the name is implying a way of accessing or reading a block or covid instance provided in the widget
context that we won't rebuild the widget from the context in which it's called, as opposed to context
that watch and context that select.
Functions at the same time, you need to understand that you should be asking for a block or Cubitt
instance only when you need it and only where you need it.
For example, asking for the Easton's bill's method of a widget will start a lookup every time the widget
will rebuild, which is not optimal at all, especially when you only needed to call a function or add
an event from inside a button.
Keep in mind that we don't know when Flutter will automatically build or rebuild its widgets, except
in the cases when we're using block builder contacts that watch or contact that select cases in which
we're manually telling flutter to rebuild them based on different states from different blocks or qubits.
All it's left to be done now is to modify all context that block to context that read right where it's
needed, save, run.
And as you can see, the app still works perfectly as it should.
Hope you enjoyed the newest additions to the Block Library.
We are kind of done with understanding and learning the block concepts.
So in the next chapter will focus more on understanding and fixing one of the most frequent issues some
of the new blog developers encounter while working with the Block Library.
Chapter 10 will definitely be a chapter worth watching as it will test all the knowledge accumulated
until now.
With that being said, I am looking forward to seeing each and every one of you in the next chapter.
Stay tuned.
And of course, let's get wicked.