Hello, everyone, and welcome to the second chapter of this amazing course in which we are going to
dive into the core concepts of Block, and I have to tell you that it is critical to understand them
before trying to use block.
So, Mark, as an important lesson, because you may need to revisit it multiple times in order to understand
every concept.
So without further ado, let's get right into it.
The first major concept you need to get familiar with is the concept of a stream.
This is the foundation of block.
So please pay as much attention as possible because I will try to make it as simple as possible to understand.
Imagine the following scenery.
You are with another friend in a beautiful mountainous area and you spotted a nice river flowing from
top to bottom.
You decide to take part in a recreational activity.
You will go uphill to where the river starts flowing and your friend will wait down here.
You are not able to see each other since the river swim left and right multiple times.
Now, the task of this activity is that you will said no more than 10 boats down the river containing
multiple numbers inside them corresponding to the order they were dispatched.
The first boat will have no one.
The second will have number two and so on and so forth.
The purpose of this activity is for your friends to shout out the number he will receive at the end
of the river.
So lets him lay this activity for a bit.
You will send the first boat with no one in sight.
Your friend is waiting patiently for it to arrive downhill.
It eventually arrives after a couple of moments and your friend shouts one.
After two seconds, you send another boat, your friend receives it, a shout outs to and so on and
so forth until there are no more boats to arrive.
If you understood this little activity, then you understood what a stream is.
A stream is at its foundation, mostly a river, which transports some data on a boat from the sender
to the receiver.
The transported data is asynchronous, which means the receiver doesn't really know when he'll receive
the data.
He just waits or listens to it.
Now let me attach the codes to every component of this entire recreational activity.
Just take a look and observe how natural everything goes into place.
So there is a bowstring function which returns a stream type of integer numbers.
This will be a function designed by you, the guy who is sending all the boats down the river.
In this function, all you are doing is iterating ten times in a for loop in order to send the boat
with the corresponding number.
You may notice that there are three keywords that we have not discussed yet.
Async start a wait and yield.
I told you before that the data or the boats in our case that are being dispatched are asynchronous.
Well, the function from where all the magic happens needs to be an async generator function because
it generates asynchronous data, hence marking it with the async star.
Koeberg in an async star function.
The keyword Hield pushes the boat to the Dreamweaver.
So every time we use something in an async star function, we are sending that piece of data to the
stream.
The await keyword helps waiting for a process to finish before proceeding to the next step.
In this case, we are waiting for two seconds gap between both dispatching.
OK, so we took care of the guy who sends the data, but what about the guy who receives it again?
Will notice how natural that code sounds like.
In the main function, all there is to be done is initializing the stream.
Then we will listen to the stream by analyzing whether a boat is approaching or not.
Remember, your friend doesn't know when the boat will arrive down the stream, so he needs to listen
to it or practically watch for it.
But eventually you ask yourself a question why streams?
Why do we need them?
You might remember from the last video on Why Block when I mentioned that for every interaction inside
the app, there should be a state emerging from it.
Right.
Can you see where streams will come in extremely handy in this situation?
So you will have interactions emerging from the app which needs to be listened to in order to meet state
based on the sequence of code which changes the app.
Take a look at both of these next concepts so that everything will be more clear on the video and have
a couple of seconds to properly read them and try to understand what's going on.
Both cubits and blocks can also communicate with the outer.
Detail here, but this part is beyond the purpose of this video and will get covered later on, so let's
remove this part for now.
What can we observe here?
Cubitt and Block are two really important concepts which you will need to understand.
The only difference you should have in mind for now is that a cubit is a minimal version of a block.
So Block actually extends Cubic.
To understand why is that, we need to dive into what is a cubit and what is a block.
Let's start with a cubit first.
A cubit, as you can see from the picture above, is a special kind of a stream component, which is
based on some functions which are called from the UI functions that rebuild the UI by emitting different
states on a stream to make the understanding process simpler.
Let's associate the concepts with the default counter app from Flutter.
So question number one, what is the initial state of the app when you started in this case, the default
counter value default at zero.
Question number two, what is the main interaction the user can have with the app?
Well, and user can click one of those plus and minus buttons.
And question number three, what are the functions which need to be listed in the Cubitt component in
order to describe the actions defined by the minus and plus buttons will have two functions, one called
increment and the other called decrement, which will logically add or subtract one to the current state
of the counter.
Now let me show you the implementation of the Cubitt to the screen so that you completely understand
every question and answer from above.
Here we're declaring the Cubitt responsible for managing the counter feature of the app.
As you can see, we are setting the default state of the counter to zero right in the constructor.
Then we are creating an increment and decrement function so that when we call it from the UI, then
you increment its decrement in state will be omitted.
The main function acts like the UI currently.
So don't worry if you don't see any plus or minus buttons to play with.
Right now, the function was just designed for educational purposes and ease of understanding will get
you further user interface and widgets in the next tutorial.
So inside the main function are declaring the counter cubitt.
Then we can observe how we can update the state of the counter value easily by calling the specific
functions we created earlier.
And this is the cubitt is actually a type of stream mitting states.
You can listen to it and observe the state change.
You take in mind that as you can see, compared to block, the cubitt functions are not part of a stream,
but rather of a predefined standalone list of what can be done inside the cube.
It's actually the important difference is highlighted by the lack of these blue points on the schema.
The one and only stream existing in a cubitt is the stream of empty states.
So you may not ask what advantages could block bring into the game?
Is an cubitt enough?
Remember that Cubitt is a component which based on some functions, I repeat, functions that are not
part of a stream and meets a stream of state which modify the UI.
Block, on the other hand, is more advanced since not only emits a stream of states but also receives
a stream of events.
So think of block as being the brain of an advanced and complex component from your app.
Depending on the interactions the user has with the app, there will be an event emerging from it which
comes as an input to the block.
Then inside the block there will be a required mapped event to state function, which will take the
event and convert it into a state so that the UI can successfully rebuild.
Let's take a look at the same counter app example and turn the previous cube it into a block.
So here, as you can see, instead of having a precooked increment function, we have an inner called
counter event which contains two events the increment and decrement ones, which can be entered as an
input into the map events, the state functions, and then a new increment is DiClemente state will
be yielded into the output state stream as we the cubit.
In order to use block, you have to declare it whenever there should be a new event dispatched.
We call block that ad and the event we want to.
For example, when the plus or minus button is pressed, there should be an increment or decrement event
dispatched, the blueprints will listen to the event stream, receive the event just how your friend
was receiving the boat on the river, actually, and then calculate the next value and Hield it on the
State Street.
Knowing that we've covered the basics of the cubitt and block classes, you might be wondering in the
first place when you should create a cubitt or a block in your app, in the second place where you should
use Cubitt as opposed to when you should use block and what is actually the real big difference, setting
them apart from each other.
So let's get right into question number one.
When should you create a cubitt or a block in your app?
This is a really important question.
You ask yourself when you will finally understand the concepts of these two.
Technically, there should be a block slash cubitt component for every feature of your app and by feature
you should understand a key functionality your app offers.
For example, you have a customer step where you can create show delays some people from a list.
Then you will need either a cubitt or a block to manage the events of creating, deleting, showing
a customer and the states emerging from them, which will change the UI accordingly.
Another example can be the type of Internet connection you have.
You need a block or a cubitt to keep track of what is going on with the app when there is no Internet
connection or when there is a poor one, or when you're connected to wi fi rather than mobile data and
so on and so forth.
So I hope it's clear for now.
And now here comes question number two.
Where should you use Cubitt as opposed to block and what is the real big difference, setting them apart.
So as I have previously said, the main major difference between a cubitt and a block is related to
how each one of them receives input from the UI.
So you may ask why this difference?
Why is there a cubitt in the first place?
Is a block an already amazing and powerful solution for everything?
Well, technically it is.
You can use block as opposed to Cubitt everywhere in your app.
You don't even need to care about Cubitt if you ask me.
But you see, there is no real need for a stream of events when you want to implement a simple counter
feature using a stream for events to do this is like getting a bulldozer to dig in a fifty centimeters
hole in the ground where you can simply use a shovel to do it.
So when the stream advantages come into place, then we'll think about searching for a weather location.
For example, you're typing each letter and for each one there is a new list of locations displayed
from work and choose from.
What would the cubits do in this situation?
Let's think a little.
It will call to get locations list function, for example, for each letter you type into the input
field.
What would a block do?
Well, you can set the block to call to get locations, list function once every four letters, for
example, or maybe once every two seconds, or maybe when the user stops typing.
And that's because the input events can be delayed and manipulated thanks to them being dispatched on
an actual stream.
OK, so having that in mind, we can deduce that block is the big brain of the project, whereas Cubitt
is a smaller part of it, which can be used to optimize code workflow.
The advice I can give you right now is to start with a cubitt and modify the cubit into a block when
you really, really need the extra streambed use.
Having all of this in mind in the next chapter will discuss another really important topic, the flutter
block concepts.
Maybe you heard about blow provider, block builder and block listener along the way.
These are some of the floatable concepts.
Will Dekel up next.
With that being said, I'm looking forward to seeing each and every one of you.
Up next.
Stay tuned and let's get wicked.