In this section, we will discuss the Agile foundation and the participants.
In business,
a lifecycle is the process of managing the entire lifecycle of a product,
and in our case, software, from inception through engineering,
design, and manufacturer.
First, Agile delivers software incrementally and iteratively.
Incrementally means we have an incremental process in which
software is developed and delivered in parts.
Each part, or increment, represents a completely working piece of functionality.
The size of the increment is not really important,
but an increment is a fully coded and tested piece of software.
Now an iterative process is one that makes progress
through successive refinement.
For example, in the first iteration,
we have a web page that you can search for courses at a university with
maybe only three filters and four columns of data returned.
And maybe in the next iteration we have a few more complex
filters and more course attributes that is columns.
Value-driven verses plan-driven.
Agile is often referred to as a value- driven approach as opposed to the
traditional Waterfall approach that is plan-driven.
Hence,
iterations need to provide value verses an arbitrary planning day
forcing features that may not provide needed value.
Also with Agile,
the value of features drives the order of work to be developed and delivered.
Items with the most value, as determined by the business,
are prioritized the highest.
And the Agile values, based on the Agile Manifesto,
drive the way the work itself is performed.
Most importantly to me is for you to be flexible and adaptable at all times.
Nothing that I'll be discussing in this course is cast in concrete.
Life and software development is not that simple.
With these foundations in mind,
they will act as the underpinnings of an Agile project.
And as with all projects, they have a lifecycle.
Let's explore.
A process group denotes a collection of one or more processes.
With traditional project management, we had five process groups: initiation,
planning, execution, performance and monitoring,
and lastly, closure.
Now let's check out the Agile/Scrum process groups on the next slide.
With Agile, there are four process groups.
The first is the project, the overall container,
if you will, of the activities of this Agile effort.
Next, projects have releases.
That is a project we've made up of a series of product releases.
Next,
there are multiple iterations per release just as there
are multiple releases per project.
Also in Scrum terminology, an iteration is known as a sprint.
I will use them interchangeably in this course.
Lastly, daily work,
which is what the team does every day with an iteration or a sprint.
Several days of work make up an iteration or sprint. Now let's check out the participants and their roles and expectations.