If you plan your sprint where the velocity equals the number of story points,
I think that's just cutting things too close.
Give your team some slack, that is some breathing room.
So what is slack?
Slack is time earmarked within an iteration that'll be
used for unanticipated activities.
Basically, you're setting aside time in reserve.
Slack is your team wiggle room in each and every sprint.
As I said at the beginning of this slide,
if the number of story points in your sprint is identical to the velocity,
you will likely be overcommitting your team.
If you have a consistent number of hours per sprint where you are
handling problems rather than pure user stories,
then, of course, your velocity perfectly handles that.
In other words, your velocity will remain where it is,
albeit not as productive as you would like.
But if your problems vary somewhat widely per sprint,
your velocity will bounce around as well,
so you may want to ensure you leave some slack by reducing the
number of story points you want to tackle.
Lastly, if your velocity is rock solid,
then you might consider reducing slack by instead committing to a small extra user story in the next sprint.