Backlogs are the fuel driving Agile projects forward.
I want to impress on you that you need to ensure you
have a healthy backlog process,
which means having quality backlog items and a
quality backlog management process.
This course will provide you with what you need to know.
Now let's define the product backlog.
In the simplest definition,
a backlog is simply a list of all things that need to
be completed within the project.
It replaces the traditional project management
requirement specification documents.
These items can have a technical nature or can be user centric,
for example, in the form of user stories or epics.
It is a single source of requirements for any changes to be made to the product.
The product owner is responsible for the product backlog,
including its content and ordering, that is its prioritizations.
Please note the backlog items will typically still
have a reference to a document, a wiki,
or something that would further clarify the business rules.
Agile still needs documentation,
albeit of a lighter weight and written over time and not all at the
beginning like in traditional Waterfall projects.
Okay, now let's talk further about backlogs.
To be clear, there is really just one backlog,
but at times, there are other monikers for different views of that backlog.
So we have the product backlog,
the total list of all product features we would like.
We may also have a release backlog.
It's a partial list of the product features slated for
this release or a particular release.
And we have the sprint backlog,
partial list of the release features slated for this sprint or iteration.
There is always truly just one backlog per se, but it can be partitioned.
And also, they're not in concrete.
Backlog items can be moved, added, removed, as required.
More on that in the next module.
Now let's look at where backlog items come from.
So how does a backlog get started in the first place?
Typically, there's a kickoff meeting,
which is the Agile project planning meeting,
the participants or the product owner,
and possibly a sponsor or other key business person,
also the technical lead, and maybe another technical subject matter expert,
and the Scrum Master.
And if we are not in a Scrum shop, possibly a project manager.
There might be a few more people.
Some may be excited for the project, and also,
you might need to pull in a few more qualified people to get
everyone's viewpoint and expectations.
Of course,
the product owner shows up with the prioritized product
backlog and describes the top items to the team.
Not all items should be discussed,
but only the top most value-based items to help the
team get a good understanding.
Now let's see what an item in the backlog may look like.
Though most items in the backlog will be items that
are software development tasks,
they really can be anything whatsoever that is required to
deliver the product for this Agile project.
User stories and features.
By far,
the main way for a team to specify features on an Agile
product backlog is in the form of user stories,
which are short,
simple descriptions of the desired functionality told
from the perspective of the user.
We will go into detail about user stories in the next section of this module.
Bugs.
Because there's really no difference between a bug and a new feature in a sense,
each describes something different that a user wants.
Bugs can also be put on a product backlog.
Research.
There could be many research activities that requires you to
understand and/or help determine the product.
For example,
a research item may be determining the best cloud
platform and how to configure it.
The product owner was not likely the source of that backlog item,
but instead the development team.
The product backlog may be mostly user- oriented
features written as user stories, of course,
but may also have other items.
Analysis items.
It may be that a feature really needs more analysis in order to
create quality user stories or even if some feature is worthy of
being in the backlog in the first place.
So there is nothing wrong with having analysis items.
An example of analysis related to knowledge acquisition could be a
backlog item about researching various JavaScript libraries for
the user experience such as Angular, React,
or Vue.
Environmental items.
There could be items that are required such as software licenses,
computers, office space, who knows.
An example would be to upgrade all developer's workstations to Windows 10.
All this is still part of the overall backlog items that must
be in place for the success of the project.
There's no point in having another list that would not
be visible to the product owner.
Technical debt, which means your code base has,
well, less than perfect design and coding in it,
so you may need to shore that up a bit for the long-term quality of the project.
Now the life of a backlog may not be so perfect.
Let's see why.
As you know,
a product owner is a person from the business who typically represents
their business community and represents their needs.
As you'd imagine,
product owners come in all makes and models with various
backgrounds from purely business to highly technical.
Therefore, the nature and quality of the backlog may widely vary.
The items in the backlog may be unclear.
The English language can have a lot of ambiguity,
plus,
the team is learning about the domain and its
terminology for the first time possibly.
So discussions may ensue; all good.
They may have multiple styles.
Many times,
a product owner is gathering requirements from all over
their department or organization,
hence different people wrote different items
resulting in different writing styles.
It is the goal to refine those writing styles and try to standardize them.
We will discuss that in the next section of the module on user stories.
Very high level.
Sometimes the backlog item is at such a high level it
would require additional refinement.
Very low level.
And on the flipside of that,
some items can be way too detailed to be on the backlog.
Maybe they're more like a task in nature.
Product owner still learning.
The product owner may be learning not only about their business domain,
but also about backlogs, Agile, and other things,
so please give them the time and respect they need to come up to speed.
Prioritize based on need.
Now, need is interesting and can be tricky.
Initially, you might be presented with an item of high need,
and you believe it just is not that important.
For now, please just sit tight.
Don't presume you know everything.
Now you might be right, but give it time.
Listen, seek to understand, and show empathy for your product owner.
They don't need the new system for fun.
They have a business to run.
So it'll be up to you and your team to normalize them,
if you will,
the originally presented backlog into more
actionable material such as user stories. That is what we'll be doing in the next section.