Step 0 - Preparing for Sprint Planning.
First, assemble the team of the product owner,
Scrum Master, or dev lead, and the dev team.
Next, you need access to the backlogs, of course.
In this example, we are in release 3, and hence,
the release 3 backlog would be available for the planning team,
but you will need to have the entire backlog available in
case you need to move things around.
Business is dynamic, and so priorities and stories are bound to change.
It is very important to review the outcome of the last
sprint's retrospective and review.
And if the last sprint was the last sprint within the last release,
then also review the release retrospective and review the release feedback.
So now we have the three main elements to move forward with our planning. Now let's look at the next step.