Now let's move deeper into user stories and epics and what
characteristics make a good quality user story.
An important point: The better the user story,
the better the sprint planning, and therefore,
the better the overall success of the Agile project.
Product backlog and user stories.
As mentioned earlier,
the nature and quality of the backlog may be inadequate initially and may
take a little work before the project is off and running.
We want to transform the initial unstructured backlog received from our
product owner and rewrite it or transform it into user stories.
Also, we don't want to be too detailed and list developer tests either.
So we want to take the initial backlog, which may be fuzzy,
unclear, and have a variety of content and authoring styles,
and transform it into user stories.
Typically, we call each requirement or feature a user story.
We want our user stories to be succinct,
clear, and with a single writing style, maybe multiple authors,
but a single writing style.
Hence, we want to write the user stories in a common way.
More on that later in this module.
Now let's define a user story.
Here's the basic definition of the user story.
A user story is a high-level definition of a requirement.
User stories contain just enough information so that the developers can
produce a reasonable estimate of the effort to implement it.
Another way to phrase it is that the user story is generally
understandable by the development team and therefore can,
in fact, make a reasonable estimate.
Now, as the backlog meeting proceeds with everyone discussing user stories,
be sure to observe the level of understanding,
the level of confidence, and the quality of the discussions.
This will help you assess the degree of knowledge being
transferred from the product owner to the team.
This is important.
Now let's look at some good traits of a user story.
Let's discuss what attributes make a good user story.
These are known as INVESTs since each of the words I
will discuss spell out the word INVEST.
Independent.
Independence means that a story can be coded,
tested, and even delivered all on its own.
That is, it's not waiting for another story to be completed.
And what also makes independence important is that
it can be independently valued.
Negotiable.
A user story is a placeholder for requirements to be discussed
and potentially accepted for development.
In the traditional Waterfall approach,
requirements were basically contracted to implement.
End of story.
So a process of negotiation is conducted between the
product owners and the development team,
and very important here,
each respects and jointly collaborates to arrive at
the best approach and solution,
aware of each other's potential limitations and strengths.
Valuable.
The full team's most important goal is to deliver the most
value given their available resources and time.
Therefore,
I will suggest to you that this is the most important of the INVEST traits.
Remember, the backlog is prioritized by value and value alone,
hence the importance of these traits.
Estimable.
A good and well written and discussed user story is estimable.
Backlog items can be any size really, but let's face it,
more decomposed user stories are much more likely to be estimated with accuracy.
In the event you are facing a challenge of coming up with an estimate,
that it is quite likely you need to decompose or break down
the user story into smaller user stories.
Next, small.
So what do we mean by small?
That is something you can finish in one iteration.
Most iterations that I observe are two to three weeks.
That gives you an order of magnitude from an elapse time perspective.
Smaller stories and process of your sprint are more likely to come out faster.
Testable.
In the Agile world, all code is tested code.
But if you think that the user story cannot be tested in the sprint iteration,
then it is quite likely that the story is not well written,
maybe linked to other user stories, or just too complex.
Vague and fuzzy words in user stories will usually get better
revealed when discussing if something is testable,
so look for that.
Use the INVEST convention as a checklist against every user story you write,
and it will greatly improve your team's ability to write them.
Better stories result in better outcomes,
yielding value to the business earlier.
Here's an important point: Writing the code for a well-understood objective is
not necessarily the hardest part of software development.
Instead, what is hard is understanding what the real objective for the code is.
Therefore, teams who spend a meaningful amount of time reviewing,
refining, and understanding user stories will be the most successful in the end. Okay, now let's check out some examples.