If the team composition is changed, then the velocity will change,
and there are many factors that can cause this to happen.
People can be sick, on vacation, or paid time off,
and that will certainly drag velocity down.
Temporary reduction in team size.
Maybe management had to move some of your team to other temporary assignments.
People issues.
Life happens, and life can have an effect on people.
Be sensitive to your team's personal issues as much as is feasible and within
the norm to view human resource policies and procedures.
Being cognitive of your team member's issues and address any
issues will help keep velocity on track.
Turnover.
If you lose a team member, you will have less velocity.
Yes, right in the middle of a sprint, someone may leave your company.
Ouch.
With a new hire, there may be skill set differences,
and it may take time to bring them up to speed.
Also, a new hire to the team or someone who transfers into the team may,
in fact, reduce your velocity, hopefully temporarily,
as they become familiar with their teammates,
Agile, technology, and the business domain the velocity will increase over time.
Organizational issues such as a company reorganization,
new bosses,
new relationships can reduce your velocity because people can be
distracted or concerned about what is going on within the
organization and how it will affect them.
The most effective Scrum teams that I have witnessed
have worked together consistently, at least as a core group,
for some time.
If your organization is having difficulty keeping teams together,
then there is an organizational impediment that must be addressed.
Organizations that can give work to teams rather than reconfiguring teams to
match the work will have more success with Agile and Scrum. Your velocity will rise and stabilize with a solid, consistent team.