The daily standup, or the daily scrum, as it known within the Scrum methodology,
is an important and vital event within the Agile and sprint frameworks.
The daily standup, or scrum,
is a 15-minute timeboxed event for the development team.
The daily scrum is held every day of the sprint.
And also, in extremely critical times, there could be a second one midday.
When it is crunch time, I like a midday scrum,
and I might timebox it at just maybe 5 to 8 minutes.
The daily scrum is held at the same time and place
each day to reduce any confusion.
The daily scrum optimizes team collaboration and performance by reviewing,
checking, examining their work since the last daily scrum,
and forecasting upcoming work for that day.
This activity enables open, honest,
and safe discussions and communicates to ensure that
everyone knows what's going on, or for that matter,
not going on.
Next,
the development team uses the daily scrum to inspect
progress towards the sprint goal.
Every day the development team should understand how it intends to
work together as a self-organizing team to accomplish the sprint
goals and create the anticipated increment,
that is working software by the end of the sprint.
This is a key meeting to inspect and adapt.
Through communication and collaboration,
the team will be able to adapt, that is make adjustments,
maybe switch assignments, brainstorm any blockers,
seek help,
or have any questions answered by later reaching out to the product owner.
Remember, the product owner is typically not at the daily scrum.
But if it works for you occasionally, well, do it.
Cadence or pace, if you will, of the daily standup.
The structure of the meeting is set by the development team and
certainly can be managed in different ways as long as it focuses
on progress towards the sprint goal.
Here's how it would typically go.
What did I do yesterday that helped the development team meet the sprint's goal?
For example, I completed user story X and began user story Y.
What will I do today to help the development team meet the sprint goal?
For example, I will continue working on user story Y.
Do I see any impediment that prevents me or the
development team from meeting the sprint's goal?
For example, at this time, no,
as long as Mary completes the database design task.
Note that I ended my statements with a phrase to meet the sprint goal.
It may sound redundant,
but this is important since it reinforces and focuses
the discussion on the sprint outcomes.
If any issues or questions are identified that would not
fit into the daily standup's timebox,
the development team or team members may meet immediately after
the daily scrum for more detailed discussions or to adapt or
re-plan the rest of the sprint's goals.
So, as we work through our sprint, how are we doing towards our goal? How do we know?