Here are some resources you might want to consider.
Agile tools are project management tools designed
to support an Agile methodology.
Whether it's Scrum, Kanban, Scrumban, or other hybrid agile methods.
Scrum certification.
You may want to consider getting certified in Scrum.
But which certifications should you take?
Well, we'll touch on that soon.
And lastly,
consider joining professional organizations like user groups and
certainly taking more Pluralsight courses.
Now let's go a little deeper into each one of these resources.
Here's a partial list of Agile tools.
And there are a ton of them out there, and I will not promote any one of them.
You need to pick the best for your needs certainly.
So figure out your key requirements, and pick the best one for you.
These seem to be the top 10 at the moment,
but this is a dynamic world, and vendors may come and go,
but this gives you a good place to start.
You might consider getting Scrum certified.
During the past decade,
demand for Scrum Master training and certifications has increased substantially.
There are many sources of certifications, and here are some examples.
Scrum Alliance, scrum.org, PMI (Project Management Institute),
the ICAgile (International Consortium for Agile),
and lastly, Scaled Agile Academy.
Professional organizations and Pluralsight.
Now, professional organizations, there are dozens and dozens of them out there.
Do some research, and maybe first attend several,
but maybe pick two or three and focus on those.
Try to also find local user groups so they are easy to attend.
I think face-to-face activities will help you make more connections with others,
and you can learn from them.
Meetup.com and other sites allow you to search and find great forums to try out.
And, of course, conferences.
Now, they usually will cost you some money,
but maybe your company will pay for, or maybe,
if it's important enough for you, you might want to pay for it.
It may be a great investment in your future.
And, of course, Pluralsight.
Just log on, and go to the search screen, and enter in keywords like Agile and Scrum to find the best courses for you.