The sprint retrospective is a self-audit team exercise.
This is the time for the team to inspect itself and create a plan for
improvements to be enacted during the very next sprint.
Remember, I mentioned that this activity is qualitative.
Well, inspect how the last sprint went with regards to people and relationships,
you know, the fuzzy stuff such as, well,
what worked well?
For example, moving the Scrum time from 9 A.M.
to 7:30 A.M.
worked best for everyone's schedules.
What didn't work well?
Well, the location of the Scrum meeting was in a too noisy of a location,
and we moved it to a conference room with more privacy.
Any recommendations for change?
Yes.
For example, we added a new person to the dev team,
and they requested some additional training on Angular and React technologies.
Also,
I would like to consider feedback from the previous retrospectives and review
the success or progress of those actions and recommendations.
So now, agree on new changes or actions as a team with full consensus,
if possible.
Then, implement those changes or actions in the very next sprint.
Again, if possible, but the sooner you make them, the better.
Now, as necessary,
you can change up the attendees if it makes sense to you and your team to do so.
You may even consider having one meeting with two major agenda items,
the review and then the second part of the meeting,
the retrospective, rather than separate meetings for each,
thus saving people's time.
I would suggest that the product owner is only in the demo meeting and not
misuse their time with the review and the retrospective.
Let's talk about how sprint outcomes impact sprint planning.
The demonstration of working software provides
valuable insight on backlog stories, estimates,
and priorities.
The review provides feedback on velocity,
team capabilities, and estimation quality.
The retrospective provides team self- reflection and
improvements for the next sprint.
All three outcomes work together collectively to improve team dynamics,
process improvements, and, of course, ensure the highest quality software product that you can deliver.