Hi, my name is Kevin Jones.
And this is the introduction chapter to the Understanding the
Java Virtual Machine: Memory Management class.
In this class,
we're going to take a look at various aspects of garbage collection
and memory management in the Java virtual machine,
including how the GC works, how we can interact with the garbage collector,
both from an external point of view, i.e.
using some of the tools that the Java virtual machine provides for us,
and also how we can interact with the garbage collector
internally using some of the classes within the VM.
Before we do that,
I think it's good to understand why we need garbage collection at all.
So in languages before Java, such a C and C++,
whenever we allocated memory, so in this example where we allocate an object,
at some point,
we need to remember to delete that object and to free up that memory.
If we didn't do that, we'd end up with a memory leak.
In Java, that's not the case.
So in Java, we can allocate an object, we can use it,
and then when that object is no longer being referenced,
the garbage collector will release the memory used by that project.
There are also issues around who should delete an object.
So here we call a method called getAccount that returns an account object.
Who actually owns that object?
Is it the receiver of the account object, so am I responsible for deleting it?
Or is it the giver of the object, the thing that implements getAccount.
If we're not clear about that, and neither side deletes the object,
we end up with a memory leak.
If we're not clear about that and both sides delete the object,
we'll end up with some null pointer exception later down the line,
which will be very, very hard track down.
Finally, we can use objects with some confidence.
So so long as I have a reference to an object,
there's no way the garbage collector will free up that memory.
I will always be able to hold onto that object and use it.
In other environments,
such a C++, a thread in the background may take a reference
to that object and delete the object.
When I then come to use it,
I know of a pointer that's pointing at nothing, and I end up with either
memory corruption or with the null pointer exception somewhere later in
the code, again something else that's very,
very hard to track down. Garbage collectors make a promise, and
that promise is they claim no live objects.
However, garbage collectors make no promise about dead objects.
They may collect them.
They may not that. If they do collect them, you don't
know when they're going to run,
i.e. when that memory is going to be reclaimed. So here,
for example,
we allocate an account object, we do new Account, and we have something that
references a block of memory that contains that account object.
If it's some later stage, we take that same variable, point it at a new account,
you're now referencing a new piece of memory and a new Account object.
The only guarantee that we have, and it's a good guarantee, is that that
second account object will be live forever. So long as we have a reference
to it, the garbage collector won't collect it.
We have no guarantees about the old account object.
It's no longer being referenced, and it may be reclaimed, but it may not.
Even if we have an environment like Java where the garbage collector
will run, we don't know when it will run, and we don't know that it'll
run before the end of our application.
So a quick note on Java versions for this course.
So the world still runs on Java 8.
Well, at least Java 8 is still widely used.
However, this course is written on Java 11, but that's fine.
I wanted to make sure that with this course, whether you're using
Java 8 all the way through Java 11 or beyond, the course is still
relevant for you. So certain things change.
So, for example, in Java 7, the G1 garbage collector was introduced.
It was actually produced in Java 6, but in Java 7, it was made official.
In Java 6, it was just experimental. And then other things changed in Java 9.
So in Java 9, the CMS garbage collector was deprecated,
finalizers were deprecated, and something called the cleaner was
introduced. But I still cover all of these things in the course. So
I'll still mention finalizes because they're still widely used in
Java 8. I still mention the CMS garbage collector because that's
still widely used in Java 8.
I talk about the G1 garbage collector because that's used from Java 7 onwards.
And I talk about the cleaner because that's used from Java 9
onwards. So hopefully, whichever version of Java you're using, you'll find many useful things in the course.