Hi, everyone.
My name is Kevin Jones, and welcome to my course, Understanding
the Java Virtual Machine: Memory Management.
I am a developer and owner at Rock Solid Knowledge, a software
development company based in the United Kingdom.
One of the core aspects of the Java virtual machine is memory management,
and it's important to understand how memory management works in Java if you
want your applications to perform as well as possible.
Java has different garbage collectors, and each behaves
differently and has different characteristics.
Some of the major topics we'll cover in this course include
understanding how the different garbage collectors work, understanding
Eden, survivor, and tenured spaces used by the garbage collector, see
the tools that you can use to monitor the garbage collector, and learn
how to interact with the garbage collector using reference classes and
the cleaner class.
By the end of this course,
you understand how the different garbage collector works in Java
and how to interact with the garbage collector.
Before beginning the course,
you should be familiar with the Java language. I hope you'll join me on this
journey to understand garbage collection with the Understanding the Java Virtual Machine: Memory Management course at Pluralsight.