I wanted to take a brief look at each of these forms of garbage
collection in turn. Here we're showing the idea behind a
reference counting garbage collector.
So we have two objects here.
The object on the left has a reference count of 2, and the object on the
right has a reference count of 1. These objects are referencing each other,
and that raises each other's reference count.
This is called a circular reference, and this is one of the issues
of the reference counting garbage collector.
It's very hard to get rid of circle references.
So, for example, once the reference on the left goes away,
the count of both objects is now 1.
Well,
both these objects are actually garbage as there's
no external reference to them, and this can be a very difficult problem to solve.
The way reference counting works is that a given object once its been
assigned will have its reference count incremented. And when it's being
dereferenced in deassignment, it'll have the reference count decremented.
When this reference count goes to 0, as in the first object here,
the object is then freed.
While the reference count is non‑0, then the object
doesn't get freed. And also there are issues with this.
People might forget to call AddRef,
for example, i.e. to increment the reference count. They might forget to
deref the object and decrement the reference count.
So we can up with memory leaks.
We can also end up with scenarios where somebody decrements the
reference count, but the object is still in use. It's not the ideal situation.