So now that we've seen some code,
how are these things actually used? Well a WeakReference, this is
often used in conjunction with something called a WeakHashMap, and
we'll see an example this in a moment. And we use this to associate
metadata with another type.
Now the metadata here could be just some data we
want to associate with that type.
It doesn't have to be really metadata.
It might just be extra data we need to add to the type.
For example, if we have a type that's marked as final, so we can't extend it.
But in certain circumstances,
we'd like to extend it and add extra fields to it, then the WeakHashMap
and the WeakReference provide us with a way of doing that, and we'll see
that in a moment. As we said to do that,
we use something called a WeakHashMap. The SoftReference,
an example given for this is caching.
People often say that you can use a SoftReference to cache things in memory.
The idea here is I load into memory some large object,
maybe an image or some object that's expensive to create,
maybe something I need to go to the server to get.
I have a strong reference to it, and I create a soft reference to it.
When I no longer need the object, I can set the strong reference to
null, but the soft reference is still around. And what this means is I
can easily retrieve this object if I need to by going through the soft
reference. If there's any memory pressure, then this object will go
away, and the SoftReference when I call get on it will return null as
we've seen with the WeakReference. And finally, there's a
PhantomReference, and this is probably the least used of these reference types.
This allows us to interrupt the garbage collector,
and we can use this to monitor when an object's being collected and to
do something when that object has been collected.
And if this sounds just like the use of finalize in Java,
then essentially that's what you use a PhantomReference for. In
places where you might use finalize, instead,
you could use PhantomReferences. And again,
we'll see an example of that towards the end of this chapter.
So before we go on and take a deeper look at WeakReferences. So we have a soft
reference to an object, as well as a strong reference. Once the strong reference
has been cleared, the soft reference is still available. So the object can be
retrieved by calling get through the soft reference. And people promote this as
a way of doing caching in Java.
Be aware, however, in many circumstances, this is not a great mechanism.
The problems with this are that we have no control over the
cache. You have no control of the cache aging.
You have no control of when anything leaves the cache.
You have no control over caching with at least recently used
write list or a most recently used list.
It's all managed by the garbage collector.
So while soft references can act as a simple cache, they're not great as caches in general.