We also have the idea of generational garbage collectors, and the idea here
is that once an object survives a garbage collection,
that object is promoted to a different generation.
The garbage collector will sweep through the young
generations more often than it sweeps through the older
generations. And depending on the environment,
there could be any number of different generations.
So in Java, for example,
there's two. In .NET, there are three. Again. in different environments, there
might be two or more generations where the garbage collector manages to collect
memory. So with the generational garbage collector, again similar to before, we
have a block of memory into which we're allocating our objects. And again, that
memory has become full.
This is now our first generation or young generation.
In that generation,
we've allocated memory. Notice we also have an old generation where
there may be objects that may be alive, may not be alive. Once the GC
runs, all the objects, in this case 1, 2, 3, and 4, that survive a
garbage collect will be moved to the old generation. We can then clear
the young generation and then carry on allocating objects inside the young generation.