So as well as the reference types, such a soft reference,
weak reference, and phantom reference, and the WeakHashMap, we also, in
java.lang.refs, have this type called a ReferenceQueue. ReferenceQueues are
passed through the constructor of a reference object.
When I create a weak reference or a soft reference,
we can also create a ReferenceQueue and pass this along inside its constructor.
When I create a PhantomReference object,
we must pass a reference to a ReferenceQueue. So ReferenceQueues are
associated with a reference object, and its these reference objects
that get enqueued to a ReferenceQueue.
So if I create an object, and I have a strong reference to it, and I wrap that
object in say a weak reference and I've associated a ReferenceQueue with that
weak reference, when this object no longer has any strong references to it,
the WeakReference type gets enqueued to the ReferenceQueue, and we'll see an
example of this in the moment. These are useful when you want to associate
some sort of cleanup mechanism with the object. So we create them something
like this.
So here we create a new person object. We then create a ReferenceQueue of type
Person. And then we create a WeakReference around the Person.
And when we create this new weak reference,
we pass it the Person object and the ReferenceQueue. So the way
ReferenceQueues are used is this. When all strong references to an object
are cleared, any reference object that wrapped up that strong reference is
now added to the ReferenceQueue. So from the previous slide, I had a person
object, I had a weak reference to that person object. When all strong
references to the person are cleared, that weak reference will be added to
its ReferenceQueue.
We can retrieve these references from the ReferenceQueue by using
the ReferenceQueue's poll and remove methods.
The poll method returns immediately, so we're polling the queue. We're
asking the queue, do you have a reference type for me?
If there's a reference type on the queue, it's returned to us.
If there's no reference type on the queue, then poll
returns null. The remove method will block.
So when I call remove, it will block until there is a reference on the queue,
and then it'll return that reference back to me.
The remove method also has a timeout, so we don't have to block forever.
We can has block for a second, 2 seconds, whatever our timer is. And
then remove method will either return a reference within that time, or
it will return null if the timer expires.
Both of these methods remove the object from the queue.
So once poll returns and remove returns, if they return with a reference object,
that reference object is no longer on the queue. The way we use
these is to attach some sort of cleanup mechanism to our types.
So we don't extend our type directly.
Instead, what we do is extend the reference type.
When all strong references to our type are cleared,
the reference object is added to the queue.
We then deque the object from the queue by calling poll or remove.
And then we call its cleanup method or whatever we call
this method to cleanup on our type.
So this time we know the object's been garbage‑collected,
and we know we can now clean up any data we want to on this type. So again, let's take a look at a demo of this.