Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning I hope you're as excited about this section of
the course on recurrent neural networks as I am.
We're slowly venturing into the very complex very forward looking and cutting edge areas of deep learning
and this is going to be very very fun.
So today we're going to talk about how we're going to approach this section which contains so many different
complex topics so many concepts that we need to get our head around.
All right so in this section we will learn first of all the idea behind a recurrent neural networks.
We'll see how they compare to the human brain will understand what makes them unique and special as
compared to regular artificial neural networks.
Then we'll talk about the vanishing gradient problem something that has been a major roadblock in or
had been a major roadblock in the development and utilization of recurrent neural networks something
that prevented them from being what they are now.
And then we will move onto the solution.
One of the most popular solutions to the vanishing Green problem the long short term memory or ellis
T.M. neural networks and we'll talk about their architecture.
They are very exciting tutorials.
One of my favorite topics and we will find out exactly how they work and what what that complex structure
is inside them.
We'll break it down into simple terms and you will be able to walk away with a pretty solid understanding
of LSD.
And then we'll talk about the practical intuition.
So in that Prius we will have a practical example of using LACMA.
But in this practical intuition trail we'll look at some great examples posted by one of the researchers
one of the most well-known researchers in the space and will understand even better on an intuitive
level how Ellis teams actually work how they think will be like.
Neuroscientists trying to understand what's going on in the brain of an Ellis team is going to be very
exciting as well.
And then at the end we'll have an extra tutorial on him variations something special something you don't
really have to take this tutorial but it's very quick just to get you up to speed on what other options
of LACMA exist out there in the world what other architectures you might come across in your work.
So hopefully you're excited and ready to get started.
And I can't wait to see the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy deep learning.