Hello and welcome to this new very exciting tutorial and this one we're going to start creating the
architecture eventually of our set to take model.
This architecture is twofold.
We'll first create the encoder Arnon layer because this what comes first in the architecture of the
sect to morrow and then we'll create the decoder Arnon layer.
So you got this right.
We have the neural network for both the anchor and the decoder will be an Arnon.
It will not be a simple iron and rest assured it will be stacked episteme which reply drop out to improve
as much as we can the accuracy and we'll create all this in the next tutorials.
And today we're going to start with the encoder Arnon there.
And so we're going to make a function that will define in some way the architecture of this anchor RNA
layer.
I hesitated to include either LACMA or Recker and unit.
In fact I first implemented a child in PI torch and this implementation I included BGR you get redirector
in the unit I will share with you this model at the end of this course.
But in this one with tons of flow we are going to include an LSM instead of a jar.
And for this we're going to use the basic LACMA Cell class by tens of flow.
So let's do this.
I can't wait to start.
Let's make this function happen.
So as I said it's a function.
So we start with Def to define it.
And now we need to give a name to this function and still in the spirit of making everything crystal
clear we are going to call it and coater are and then later and coureur aren't in there and now be careful.
Get ready.
This function is going to take several arguments.
The first one is the Arnon inputs so that corresponds to the model inputs.
Remember we made this function that prepare the inputs of the models not to be confused with the questions
inputs but inputs like the input questions the target answers the learning rate to keep prob..
So that's the model inputs for the oron and basically then the next argument is going to be the Arnon
size and the arland size is not to be confused with the number of layers in the Arnon the arland size
is the number of input tensors of the encoder are in and they are we're making right now.
So arland size then the next argument is this time the number of layers which I'm counting.
None of those core layers.
All right then the next argument is going to be our keep problem parameter and that we need to do that
because we are going to apply a dropout regularisation to our Ellas GM will first make an industry and
then we will apply dropout.
So we will have a stacked LACMA with drop about.
And this again is to improve the accuracy.
So keep that control the dropout rate and then a final argument sequence underscore length which is
the list of the length of each question in the batch.
All right so that's the list of the lengths of the questions.
Inside each batch and that's it our function is ready to be defined.
OK so first we will create the LSD.
How will we create it.
Well thanks to a sense of where we have an amazing class that allows us to create it in a flashlight
and actually only one line of code and that's the basic LACMA cell class.
Therefore what I'm going to do right now is introduce a new variable that I'm going to call t m but
that will actually represent an object that will be an object of the basic stemcell class and therefore
I'm going to do right now is get this basic LACMA cell class from tensor flow.
And so we need to start by getting tensor for here which has a shocker T.F. and then from terms of flow
well we can directly get the class in terms of flow we need to go through first the contrib module then
the Arnon submodule and then from there we can get the basic LACMA cell class.
So let's get it.
It is felt this way.
Be careful with the capital letters.
Capital B.
Basic LSD em all in capital and capital C D L L bezique LC himself.
And in parenthesis we need to put just one argument which is our Arlen's size which I remain corresponds
to the number of input tensors in the layers.
Let's put this r n n size as we called it.
This is one of our arguments arland size and there we go.
We now have our LACMA perfect.
So now we're going to apply dropout to this.
So busy going on what we'll get is the same but on which drop out was applied and therefore the new
variable I'm going to introduce here is T.M. underscore dropout.
Well you can call it however you want but with this name of the variable it's quite clear that we are
just getting the same re-use as GM but with drop out applied.
So I left him drop out and to apply rappelled.
Well again that can be very simple.
We're going to use another class which is a drop out wrapper class and which is some kind of wrapper
that can wraps an already existing LACMA which is the one we just created.
But with drop out applied.
So I remind that dropout is the technique of dropping out.
That is deactivating a certain percentage of the neurons during the training iterations.
So the usual dropout rate is 20 percent which would mean that during the training iteration 20 percent
of the neurons are like nonexisting their weights are not updated.
That's why they are in some way deactivated so that's to drop out and so to apply it well we'll create
a new object of the drop out wrapper class which will of course get as one of its arguments.
The elist object we just created.
So let's do it.
Let's get it from sense of flow of course.
Sense of flow.
Then again we need to go to the module contrat.
Then Arne again.
And from this Arlon module we get the drop out there with capital D and then capital W wrapper class.
Right.
And this class takes several arguments.
The first one is the record a neural network you want to apply dropout on.
And that's of course our LACMA object that which is created here.
So LCN and then the next argument is going to be our key prob of course because keep drub remind us
to control the dropout rate.
And since now we're dealing with drop out.
Well that's the time to use it because it will control the dropout rate.
So I'm adding here keep track but I will specify that keep prob is the input underscore keep prob parameter.
So that's the name of one fixed argument of drab wrapper.
This is not an arbitrary name I'm choosing.
This is part of the class.
But this argument should be held to that keep from argument.
That is the argument we will put later of our encoder Arnon layer function.
So keep this core prob here.
Perfect.
Now we have our LCN with drop out applied.
Great.
Now next step the next step.
Now that we have our LSM with drop out applied and I see him drop out we are ready to create the encoder
cell and we can only create it now because we are going to create it through again a very useful class
by sense of flow which is the multiday Arnon Cell class and which takes an argument.
Well of course the LACMA with drop out applied this LACMA drop out object by the drop out wrapper class.
So what we need to do now is introduce a new variable and call your cell.
And this core cell that will be the cell of the encoder not to be confused with the state that will
create right afterwards.
So that's the cell.
And to get it.
Well this will actually be an object of this Mahlzeit Arnon cell which we'll get again from sense of
flow and then from the contrib module and then from the Arnon submodule And then there we go we can
get the non-Thai are and and sell.
Be careful with the capital letters.
And then this class is going to take several arguments.
Well first to asked him drop out later we created year times the number of layers to specify how many
layers we want and our encoder Arnon and therefore how do we put this.
Well we first need to put our as Jim drop out later in square brackets like this.
So in square brackets I'm including our previews LSD and drop out object and then to make it several
layers.
Well I multiply that by another argument that we have and that gives us exactly the number of layers
we plan to have in our encoded Arnon and which is none on the score layers underscore layers which will
create the anchor Rousselle I remind If you have not followed the intuition lectures or if this is pretty
new for you.
Well the encoder cell is composed of several layers.
And besides we applied dropout to each of these and I asked him there's that Sinco to sell.
And again if this is pretty new for you I highly recommend to have a look at the annexes and especially
the second annex at the end of this course because we explain the whole theory of Arnon and that will
help you understand the difference between cells and states.
All right so perfect.
Now we have our ankers cell and now of course we'll take care of the anchor state and to get it.
We're going to get it from the bi directional dynamic Arlon function by the end and the Mudgal this
time it's a new module I a torch to an end module.
I tend to flow and this will get us exactly what we want that is the output.
One of the output of the Arnon which is the state.
And so we are going to call this state and coater state.
So we again for the long names of the variable.
But that's because we will have then the decoder cell and state so I just want to make the clear difference
between those two and go to state.
However the interstate is going to be returned by the directional dynamic Arnon function by tens of
flow but which returns two elements one of them is and go to state but any state is the second element
returned by this bidirectional dynamic Arnon function and therefore to only get it because we only need
it we have to add here underscore and then come to specify We only want the second element returned
by is future directional dynamic and function of tensor flow.
And speaking of tons of flow that's what we need to get first to get function.
So the TFT out there remember we get it from the end and Mudgal inside the tent of the library.
And then from this and then Munjal we get the B D Rex no underscore dynamic underscore our end and function.
And this creates a dynamic version of a bidirectional record renewal network.
Remember I told you we're not going to make a simple record a neural network we want to make our job
but as powerful as possible and creating this dynamic version of a bidirectional record Renu and that
work will definitely help.
So this dynamic version of directional Arnon basically takes your input that we're about to answer right
now and will build independent forward and backward Arnett's but be careful when you build this this
kind of bidirectional dynamic Arnon we have to make sure that the input size of the forward cell and
the backwards cell must match.
That's the first thing we'll make sure of when entering these arguments.
So let's do it.
Let's take your first of the four Arnon.
The argument for it is cell underscore f w forward.
And this will be equal to r and code hersel object from the not Ireland cell that we just created in
the previous line.
Therefore the cell forward here is going to be equal to and Khoder cell then next argument is going
to be for the backward Arnon and the name of the argument for that is sell underscore B.-W backward.
And this one is going to be equal to again the encoder cell because it's like a B directional Recker
a neural network that we're making meaning we have both directions.
But on the same encoder cell.
All right so the cell backwood here is going to be equal to the encoder cell again.
Then the next argument is going to be the sequence and the score lengths which I remind is the list
of the length of each question in the batch.
So sequence length which this one is the name of the argument inside the existing bidirectional dynamic
and function.
But we have to set equal to the sequence argument which is one of our arguments a VAR function that
we're making.
OK then next argument is going to be our model inputs which are one of the VAR arguments here that are
in an input.
So inputs which is the name of the argument of the bidirectional dynamic or in function are you going
to be equal to or are an input argument.
And then finally one last argument to decide and this has to be equal to the float 32 type.
I tend to follow T.F. that float 32.
It's important to include it to make sure we are dealing with floats.
All right.
So congratulations you made the first pillar of this sector sic architecture to anchor the Arnon and
so now of course we simply need to return the output of this and Goodere which is of course I remind
the state and not the cell the cell will be part of the loop in the Arnon but will not be the output.
The output is the.
And go to state that we got in our last line here.
So we have to return it and return it.
There is nothing more simple we simply need to add return and coater on this core state.
And there we go.
We have our first function created that creates the encoder Arnon layer.
Perfect.
So now we're going to move on to the decoder and it's not going to be that simple.
Will do it in three tutorials because we're going to make some cross-validation to separate some training
data and then some Krus validated data so that cross-validation that's very important to reduce overfilling
and improve the accuracy of new observations.
So we're going to start by making that separation between the training data and the cross validation
data and then we'll be ready to create our decoder Arnon layer.
So let's do that in the three next it's.
I'm going to execute this.
And until then and then I'll be.