Hi everyone and welcome to this lecture where we will be focusing on Ripl also known as X R.P. as is
one of the most prominent and popular forms of crypto currencies today.
And due to its impact in the banking sector can also be seen as one of the main disruptive technologies
currently shaping the industry.
But let's start off with a bit of historical background before we jump into some further details for
Ripl the company building the protocol open coin was founded by CEO Chris Larsen and CTO Jed.
Originally released in 2012.
It was written in C++ and one of the most interesting aspects is that the network can operate without
the company entirely but it can even claim to go back to 2004.
With the ripple project the founders had extensive experience coming into this with digital currencies
including working with companies that handled Bitcoin trades and online financial companies.
Although Ripl does attract less attention than some specific other cryptocurrency currencies report
has the second highest market cap.
One of the huge benefits is that ripple can be used for any currency exchanged ranging from traditional
currencies commodities or even frequent flyer miles.
The ripple network was originally created with a 100 billion units.
Rebel was intended to be more efficient.
Such as not utilizing large amounts of electricity to mine so you can exchange anything of value in
an efficient way.
And we did mention earlier that we could see here in a brief example how it works.
From the following brochure if you get the chance take a look through it because it has some great information.
And keep in mind that these terms here.
The liquidity it's going to come more to play later with a huge attraction of ripple related to liquidity.
But we could start getting an idea here of this schema how it works and who uses it.
Think of the banking sector and keep liquidity in mind.
We'll get to that in a moment.
So you may be thinking what are some of the benefits of ripple ripple benefits include speed.
And then is that X is over 1000 times faster than bitcoin in terms of confirmation time.
The transaction cost is also much lower.
It has a higher quality of validators and processing and it's also ready for enterprise use which we
can see when we discuss the financial sector picking up rubble.
It's also open source software and anyone can run a server validator.
And as we've mentioned earlier as an example if the ripple company disappeared it would still function.
So those are some pretty crucial benefits you're talking about speed and lower transaction costs.
Those are two key elements within cryptocurrency.
In addition if you are worrying about more SRP being created the transaction rules are deterministic
and software is open source so there's no way to create more Ripl currently holds about $60 billion
SRP or 60 percent of X R.P. that will exist with 55 billion locked in escrow to be released over fifty
five months and that's intended to provide supply predictability over a set length of period of time.
The Leger's are public adding increase transparency.
And David Schwartz who is the chief cryptographer at Ripl mentioned that through 2018 the company plans
to focus on adding additional validators for decentralization.
And you may be wondering how Ripl compares to bit coin or how Ripl sees themselves.
But Ripl actually has positioned itself as a compliment to Bitcoin because you can use it for any currency.
Remember we talked about earlier the currencies commodities you can exchange Ripl for any type of currency.
And of course we have to mention blotching ripples payment network ripple net uses the block chain technology
but Ripl is in mind.
The company has control.
We talked about the distribution in the earlier slide.
And to reiterate a block chain is a public ledger containing transaction data for anyone who uses the
service.
Transactions are added to blocks orderings of code that make up the chain and each transaction must
be recorded on the block.
Blotching one of the most crucial if not the most crucial components of crypto currencies.
And here we arrive at the financial institutions and I mentioned earlier to try and keep liquidity in
mind.
And one of the most interesting aspects about Ripl and what makes it highly attractive is that for financial
institutions it has that such appeal related to liquidity.
And we see with a quote from Ripl CEO Brad Garlinghouse that he mentions liquidity needs of banks that
is managed with literally 10 trillions of float that sits in these no show and offshore accounts.
We believe very strong this is an inefficient model you can use digital assets to fund liquidity and
Ripl is uniquely positioned to capitalize on that.
Bitcoin takes four hours to settle a transaction where SRP takes 3.6 seconds.
You can imagine the benefits of financial institutions being able to make these transactions in such
a decrease the amount of time 3.6 seconds is almost lightning fast for a transaction time.
And if you get the chance you can visit the brochure mentioned here.
And we had it earlier.
We could jump over to that really quickly.
If youre able to scroll through it take the time to look at some of the information and how Ripl presents
itself and ripple in the SRP it is one of the main crypto currencies and its definitely here to stay
with its appeal to financial institutions all along with its speed lower transaction costs.
Those are some crucial components allowing people to succeed within the cryptocurrency environment.
In addition keep an eye out for what Ripl is doing within the next few years of the company.
As we mentioned earlier are working on implementing some additional decentralization options and I still
think we have much more to see to come.
Related to report and its impact in the cryptocurrency market and also in the financial market especially
related to currency exchanges and financial transactions.
With that we can wrap things up if you have any questions.
As always please feel free to share them and I will see you in the next video.