Hello welcome to this new tutorial and now lead by our actions.
So as a reminder we're now making a function so that we can get the by at coin's action in my wallet
and exactly as what we just did for getting the equity in at coin's an investor.
We going to make a new function here which we'll call by at coins and which this time will not return
anything but we'll update three variables right after the investor buy some Atkins and the three variables
are first the equity in Adkins of the investor.
Second the equity in dollars of the investor.
And third that all at once but which is I remind the total number of coins that have been bought by
the investors because indeed as soon as an investor buys them at coins Well this variable is a dated
and that is increasing because some you add coins were bought.
All right so buy at coins.
Let's make this function and we start with a function function then we need to give a name to this function
which will go by at coin's very simply and then this function will take actually two arguments to sign.
First the address of the investor because it's actually the investor that will call this function to
buy some coins.
So we need to specify here address of the investor.
But keep in mind that address here is the type of the variable and investor is the name of the variable.
So that's the first variable and then the second variable will be well how much dollars the investor
wants to spend to buy the coins.
That is basically how many coins does he want to get.
But with US dollars.
So the second argument here will be the USD invested but again we need to specify the type just before
the name of this variable and the type of this variable is an unsigned integer int and investor is not
going to spend billions of dollars to buy at coins so we can take the simple You end with 32 bytes.
So you and you as invested we have our two arguments perfect.
Now we're just going to specify exactly like before that our input variables are external because indeed
these are not intrinsic to the contract.
And now guess what we have to do.
Do we have to open some new brackets here.
No that's the trick.
There is a tricky thing to do here.
We must apply the modifier because remember we need to check first if this investor here can buy the
at coins with the money he wants to invest that is with his US dollars and to check this well we'll
of course apply or modify.
All right.
And so now the question is how do we apply this money if I hear how do we link it to this function.
Well that's exactly the next step here.
Just before we opened the brackets we need to call our modify here just this way can buy at coin so
that I might if I remember we got it can buy at coins and of course we can put what this modifier is
expecting as argument which is exactly the U.S. invested by the investor which is already an existing
viable dysfunction because indeed is the argument of the buy at coins function.
So what I can simply do here is just take this USD invested without taking the time because the type
is just use when you declare a new variable.
But this was already declared and therefore we just need to pay that here.
You as the invested and now we are allowed to start implementing the function.
So pressing enter.
I get my closing bracket and now we're definitely ready.
OK so as I said at the beginning of the Statoil this function is not going to return any value.
It's just going to modify some variables.
Remember these are the equity in us the investor the equity in coins and the total Aitken's.
But all right so let's start with the equity in at CUENTA.
So to date this equity in at coin's well simply we must increment we must add to the current equity
and at coin's of our investor.
So here I just took my mapping again this is my mapping and this is the argument of the mapping which
is the address of the investor.
So that basically gives me the equity in coins of our investor here.
And so that's exactly the variable that we need to update right now and to update it.
What I want to do is add to this equity and at coin's Well the at coin's but by this investor when he
pays this amount of US dollars that is this you as the invested amount of dollars.
And so what we exactly need to add to the equity at coin's of the investor is this amount of at coin's
this investor could get by spending this amount of US invested.
And so let's call this number of coins and coins but and now we are going to define exactly what this
variable will be equal to which is of course the USD invested by the investor that is the amount of
money paid by the investor times.
Remember we have our USD to add coin's conversion rate the USD to add on conversion rate allows us to
go from USD to add coins.
And therefore since here our investors spent USD investor dollars well to get the number of at coins
this investor could die with his dollars.
We simply need to multiply this by this rate here.
You get it at once and therefore let's just take this USD at coin's copy it and let's face it here so
that we get our ad going.
But and here the equity and at coin's is well incremented.
However let's not forget that at Cone's.
But here is a new variable that wasn't declared anywhere before and therefore this is the first time
we declare it here.
And when you declare a new variable and solidity and that comes from C++ because solidity was inspired
from C++.
Well we need to declare the type here which is an unsigned integer.
And again and there we go now to get rid of this.
We simply don't add the semi color.
All right.
And that update our first viable equity in at coin's of the investor.
Now let's update the other variables.
So the second one was the equity in dollars and the third one was the total at but.
So let's start first with the equity in USD.
So that's why I'm coupling this because the equity in USD is simply the knapping equity USD taking the
investor's argument investor address.
So that gives us the equity annuity of the investor.
And now how do we update the variable.
The right way after the investor buys the coins well simply what we can do is update it this way we
can take our equity in at coin's of the investor which is exactly this and paste it here and then divide
it by the U.S. at Cohn's conversion rate that is 1000.
Because indeed since one dollar equals 1000 at.
Well in order to convert your coins into dollars you just need to divide your actions equity by 1000.
And that's exactly what we did here.
All right.
And let's not forget the semicolon.
And there we go.
We have our second variable updated.
Good.
Now let's update the third one.
That is the toll at coin's but so try to guess how we have to update it.
It's actually very simple.
Well very logically the total Aitken's But is the total number of coins that have been bought by all
the investors.
Right now we're dealing with one investor which is this one and therefore right after this investor
had but his coins with this amount of dollars.
Well that means that some new head coins were but and this number of new actions but is exactly what
we got here with this variable at coins.
But so that's why I'm selecting this and copying it because now I'm going to use it to update the total
number of coins.
But by the investors the following way by simply incrementing it by this number of actions.
But by this specific investor.
All right.
We just add up some new Atkinsons which is but to the total number of coins that were bought by all
the other investors.
Great let's not forget the semicolon and we are done with the function the red flag just disappeared.
All good we're ready to move on to the last final function of this implementation which is the function
that allows the buyback option or in other words allows us to buy actions back.
All right let's do this in the next tutorial and then I guess we'll be ready for the demo.
Until then and good luck.