Let's get into specifics in this video you'll learn how WordPress websites fit with domain name registration
and hosting on a server and get all the other pieces together on your computer outside of Wordpress
You'll gather all the tools you need for this course including setting up your students sandbox at W.P.
of course dot com giving you access to premium tools you can use in your business.
from the ground up.
Let's start with hosting.
It's a Web site needs to have files and a database that are accessible to the public through their Internet
It needs a physical place to be.
This is called a hosting account.
There are lots of different levels and types of hosting and we'll go over these in detail in the next
For now just know that a hosting company provides a server connected to the Internet in such a way that
a Web site.
They either click or type an address or a URL to get there you are.
L stands for universal resource locator and it's just a quick way to say web address or domain name
an example of a r rl is Google dot com.
One of the requirements of having a public Web site is ownership of a domain name which has a specific
URL that you or your clients can register using a company called a domain name registrar.
Network Solutions dot com and many others you rent or register a domain name for a specific period of
its own L or web address.
When we are developing a web site locally or before our client has a domain name yet we can use a temporary
real domain name.
During this course you can use real domain names that you register yourself or just use testing yourself
to create the Web sites will make during the learning process.
If you do use a real domain name you'll have to have a paid or trial hosting account to which you can
the next section.
In the last section you learned about how WordPress works with a file structure and a database to output
You also saw how themes and plugins can be added to design a look and feel as well as provide specific
In this course you'll have an opportunity to use a whole bunch of premium themes and plug ins to create
your development sandbox and all the premium tools will be learning in this course.
After this video go to W.P. of course dot com and click the student's button to get your sandbox site
ready.
There's an exclusive code for students of this course.
You'll need to use to gain permission and set up your sandbox environment.
It's located in the resource document in the next section.
Let's compile all the other tools you need for building websites for clients.
First go get a text or code editor you can use the simple text editor that comes with your computer
notepad on Windows or text it on the Mac.
But as I said in the last section you'd be better served by getting a code editor that formats the code
You can try notepad plus plus or atom that IO but don't rely on word pad that comes with Windows or
These don't do the same thing and can insert formatting characters that aren't part of the code you
There's text Wrangler and Adam works as well.
Here's what the Wordpress config file looks like in ADOM and here's what it looks like in Notepad plus
But here's what it looks like in Notepad itself not formatted and not as good looking or easy to edit
as it looks like an atom.
Download one of these code editors now and install one on your computer.
You are L's to all these code editors are in the resource document in the next section to set up an
FPP program.
One of the best ways is to choose an add on for the Firefox browser called Fire FGP install Firefox
If you don't have it already and open it up at the top you can click Tools and add ons and Firefox will
Fire FGP and hit enter and you can install the add on.
You can get to the fire FGP add on by clicking the menu dropdown at the top right here.
But I've already dragged it up into my toolbar.
So if you click customize on that menu right there you'll be able to drag and move your toolbar items
to and fro.
This is where it probably starts and if you drag that up somewhere on your toolbar that will provides
That way anytime you need it the FCP program is right at your fingertips and it will open in a new tab.
There it is the left side or the files on my computer and I can set up accounts here connect to them
Another option is to use a standalone FDCPA program like files Zilah available at files Zyla dash project
dark
go ahead and get yourself set up with an FPP program on your computer.
Let's take a look at two of them and try optimizing an image for the web yourself.
If you have Adobe Photoshop follow along in the next section and if not open up pick seler dot com and
First let's get a large image that's too big in terms of both file size and image size and place it
There's one you can download and use at WP dev course dot com slash big image dot J peg.
If you don't have one of your own ready you can just use this right click the image and say save image
as find a place on your computer where you want to save it and there you go.
This image is straight out of my camera full of 3.6 megabytes in size and more than 30 400 pixels wide
for any image on a Web site.
The file size should be at largest less than 300 K or kilobytes and less than 2000 pixels wide even
I like to make my web images 6500 pixels wide and I try to get them as small as possible under 200 K
Image editing programs can do this with most photos without losing any image quality.
These smaller compressed images will load faster for web site visitors making for a better web site
Watch as I open this image in Photoshop and if you have the program follow along and do this to your
Once I have the image opened in Photoshop or click image image size and under the width I'll put 6900
and just hit OK.
Now as showing it to me at 25 percent.
Now I'll click file save for web and devices.
This will optimize the image and show me an optimized version if I like.
I can go up here and click JPEG you'll show me the image at full size so I can browse around to the
If I hit medium I can see that that will be an 84 K image and the quality is very good.
I might go up to high and that's 2:21.
In fact I think it looks really good.
Right here and then I'll click save when I save this file on my computer.
Photoshop but opens within a browser window instead of being a standalone program.
If you navigate to pixel or dot com you can launch the web app under Pichler editor you can use the
it does in Photoshop.
That's fun my image here.
Big image
click image and then image size right here I can put 6500 pixels as I did before and leave the constrained
That means that it won't distort or stretch the image at all.
It'll keep it in the same proportions.
Now that that's a smaller image in pixel or I can click File Save and in the dialog box it'll give me
I can see that this will be 211 kilobytes if I pull it down just a little bit.
I get 158.
Let's go ahead and save that in this web folder and we can go and see what it looks like after it's
And here it is.
Let's take a look.
Unlike Photoshop it doesn't give you a live optimized version that you can look at but you can experiment
If you use Microsoft Office with Excel spreadsheets you can use existing templates for quotations and
you can see I can open just a blank splodge spreadsheet or some other templates here under business.
It's searching office dot com since I'm online.
Or you can use the search bar and you can see that there's a whole bunch of templates that you can choose
If I search for invoice I can find the one that I usually use invoice that calculates total.
And then you can download it and it'll save it as a template in Excel.
I use one called price quotation without tax.
to find what works for you.
But either of these can use a logo and can be customized for your business.
Once I've created an invoice for a client I just click File Save As and save the document as a PTF
then it can be edited and the class can open it up and pay using the methods I specify.
You can also do this using the free Google Drive documents navigate drive at Google dot com and log
If you go back to their welcome page after signing in.
Click the menu grid at the top right and then click.
Dr. click new at the top left and open up a new Google sheet.
You can do a google search for invoice for Google sheets and there are lots of templates that you can
when you need to make a new invoice.
Once you have a new one finished you can click file download as and choose PTF to download a finished
I receive a lot of payments from clients via check but at times you'll want to be able to take a credit
It can feel like a big step to accept credit cards through a merchant account at your bank.
And if you research it it's pretty expensive and complicated with applications and credit checks to
available to everyone without a hassle or any upfront fees.
You can set up PayPal to take both one time and recurring payments very quickly and easily.
They charge the seller.
That's you.
A small fee for processing the credit card and they take that percentage out of the payment after it's
They don't charge the buyer at all.
at a bank.
Plus your clients can feel comfortable with the security of their information as PayPal keeps it secure
and you can't actually access their credit card information at all.
Paypal takes care of it.
You can also send invoices via email through paypal allowing your customers to just click a link in
the top right choose a business account and then click continue and choose Pay-Pal payments standard.
set to take credit cards paypal payments standard is all you need to take recurring payments for website
maintenance or hosting for your clients as well as onetime payments for web design and implementation.
In this video we went over and compiled a lot of the tools we'll need to create our complete WordPress
sandbox resource and lots of free tools.
We've assembled everything you need for your website business.
Next we'll dive deeply into how to host client web sites.
and get your students sandbox set up and running for coursework.