Every server including local environments and live hosting servers on the internet works a little bit
And so this is an example of how WordPress could be installed manually using local by flywheel.
Coming up in this chapter I'll show you how I installed WordPress manually using another local environment
But you should follow along in whichever environment you have.
You can refer back to this video later or follow along now.
And in doing this you'll get a feel for how WordPress works and the way it connects the core files to
Let's go now I'm going to create a new WordPress installation in local by flywheel and I suggest you
So I'm going to go ahead and log out of my practice site one close the tabs and I'm going to close that
on this site instead I'm going to turn this site off.
So practice site one is now turned off and I have a second one called practice site 2 that I've just
And I did a very default installation with no changes at all and I called it practice site too.
So stop the video if you like and hit the plus sign and set up a second site that we're going to do
Or you can just follow along here.
The reason I use local by flywheel to create the installation first and then go ahead and change it
by flywheel sets up the config file so that it's already connected to the database.
That way when we install WordPress manually We know that all the credentials are correct.
Now let's first take a look at the file structure for this practice site to give you an open file explorer
again and I'll go back to my local sites folder in my username under users on the main hard drive and
You can see that these are the files that are the Word Press Corps files.
And like I mentioned in the last video if we go to WordPress dot org and we download this zip file and
These are the exact files that will end up with from that zip file with the exception of the WP config
file that was created from the sample.
Let's open the WPE could fig dash sample that ph file in a text or a code editor.
Now I have it open in my Adam code editor right here.
And you can see that it's just got some default data for the database name and the user and the password
and what the host name is which by default might be localhost.
has been created by WordPress when local by flywheel installed it.
So you can see the difference.
The password is root and the host name is localhost.
And also there are some salts or unique keys and phrases down here that we will set up in a later video
when we do a manual installation in the next section.
That's just to show you what you would get if you downloaded WordPress from WordPress dark instead of
I'm just going to make the assumption that this is the file these are the same files and the W.P. config
file is already set up for this server.
However the main change that we're going to make so that we can go through the Wordpress installation
database as we did in the last video.
Click the database tab here and click add Mynor for this Web site.
Now you can make sure you're in the right Web site up in the address bar of your browser.
This one is my practice site to local and so I know I'm in the right database and what I'm going to
There's 12 in total.
And then after that I'm going to come down here and click drop when I click a drop gives me a window
to leave the database intact.
We're just erasing an existing database.
OK.
And now the message in admen or tells me OK.
In this database there are no tables.
So how are we going to get the tables back and get this working.
If I go right now to local buy flywheel with the empty database and I click say View site and I click
Now the Wordpress files are in place and the Word Press W.P. config file is correct.
It's actually communicating with the database correctly.
The reason I know that is because this is the first step of setting up WordPress manually.
So now I'm going to go through this process which is a script they use called the famous five minute
Now so many hosts and local environments install WordPress automatically that you may not have to go
And now since we're already connected to the database it just needs a little bit of information about
what the word press is going to entail.
And this is the welcome message Welcome to the famous five minute WordPress installation process.
And so let's see.
I use my standard username and then I'm going to choose a password that I know I'll be able to remember.
It doesn't have to be that
difficult or that strong of a password since this isn't a public facing Web site.
Nobody can access this on the web.
And then there needs to be an email address
for each user account.
And then you can choose discouraging search engine visibility on a live server.
You might do that in order to develop the site or hide it behind a maintenance screen.
In either case you don't need to check that box and I'll click install Wordpress and I can save that
And that was it success.
WordPress has been installed so I can click the logon button which brings me to that standard log in
And here we are our practice site 2.
And I can right click.
Visit site and open that new tab and I have my standard default fresh and clean WordPress installation.
Ready to go.
Now let's take a look at the database that's still open and let's just refresh the page and you could
Let's just verify under W.P. options and select data.
Yeah.
There's the practice site to local same Yoro that I have up here and so that worked for me.
The quick quick quick WordPress five minute installation process and that's how we do it in the next
You'll see that I teach you how to install WordPress manually using the map local development environment
and I've added this local by a flywheel system in ahead of that because I find that it's much easier
But follow along if you like you can continue to use local by flywheel instead of map and in the next
In this lesson I showed you how you can use local by flywheel to experiment with installing WordPress
It's a good exercise just to get familiar with how WordPress works to connect the files to the database
in the future.
automatically in the next video.
We'll explore different types of hosting environments for Wordpress including another local development
Feel free to just follow along with the map lessons but keep using local instead.