Let's set up your W.P. of course exclusive 90 day free trial at site ground where you can easily install
and they have inexpensive shared levels all the way up through managed WordPress plans you can use to
In this video you'll set up your free hosting account with site ground.
By the end of this video you'll have your first live internet hosting account and a place you can use
Start by visiting the student site at students dot W.P. deaf course dot com and scroll down to see the
You can hit this resource page button or the resources button at the top or the bottom of the site and
different places that we will use in this course.
If you scroll down near the top click the site Ground link and it will open up a new tab where there's
a three months free hosting sign up page and you can just click sign up right there.
Fill out the small amount of details on the form and what you're getting here is a start up hosting
of time you sign up for at once.
So this is a special exclusive offer for students of the course and just go down and the last choice
If you do own a domain name that you'd like to use with this hosting account during the course you can
activate it with an existing domain you could purchase a domain name right here if you like but I don't
And it's easy enough to activate an account without the domain and you'll be given a free domain to
The hosting account for.
So just click the box that you've confirmed and click pay now which will be zero dollars.
And let site ground set up your hosting account for you.
log into the customer area right here to log in to your site.
You are ELF from site ground it's you a for user area dot site Ground dot com and that's what I've done
You can see that I've received an email from site Ground Kinglet your and you are now a sacred client
and they've assigned me a username and the password is the one that I chose during the sign up process.
So make sure you remember that password that you used and use your username that they've assigned you
Control-C to copy and I'll go back to the log in form and I'll go ahead and log in with my username
And now I get to choose whether I want to start a Web site transfer an existing web site or thanks but
It's important that you choose this third option because we are going to be installing WordPress using
So now that you've chosen the third option thanks but I don't need help.
Click proceed.
This is the site Ground user area and whenever I log in to site Ground I'll usually go right to the
I have a primary domain here which is Greg one dot SAGD you dot site and we can use this domain throughout
the course to build web sites and do all of our coursework.
And there's some other information that you can look at as you go down here.
These are your name servers if you do own a domain name and you'd like to point a domain at your site
But we don't have to do that during the course next let's click the red button go to see panel and see
button checked.
And then remember your selection and click proceed once the see panel is loaded.
You can explore by scrolling down a little bit all the different utilities that we have as a part of
Let's finish up this video by installing Wordpress and activating it for our testing domain whatever
So if you see near the top there's an auto installer section and you can just click the word press button.
companies accounts and you can just go to the install tab and let's choose where to install WordPress
inside of our domain right here.
Now we'll leave HTP colon slash slash for now as opposed to setting it up under a secure HTP s which
a separate directory here in the directory place.
We could just leave everything else as the default except what I'm going to do is choose a username
that's easy for me to remember along with a password that I can remember as well.
So I'll just choose that user password that I can remember and I use a valid email address so that I
there.
We can just choose whatever we need down here.
Let's just leave all of the defaults and we can go down and click install should only take a couple
That just took about five or 10 seconds and it says congratulations the software was installed successfully
and it gives me a U R L which is my regular site Ground educational site you Arel that I'm using along
account slash W.P. Dasch admin.
We don't have to save or remember that we're going to be using this u r l a lot in different places
in this course.
you back to the seat panel.
We don't really need to go back there again because we're going to be managing WordPress through its
admin you are l.
But let's go ahead and open up a new tab in your browser.
And let's go to the you are l where are your wordpress site is set up.
If you're in the C panel that's at the very top here and I'm just going to hit Control C and it's also
I don't want to open up my new tab and just paste that you URL right into the address bar.
And I've got a new WordPress site set up.
This is a default page.
That site ground creates for you with a little bit of links to some resources.
And if we want to get to the admin page we can go to this log in button right here in the sidebar and
I'm going to right click that and click Open link in new tab.
That way I'll have the log in an admin area open at the same time as I have the actual site open in
Remember I used a certain username right there and typed my password that I made sure and remembered
and I'll click log in and I can ask Firefox to remember that password for me so it's easy for me to
Here's my wordpress dashboard.
And boy doesn't that feel great.
There's nothing like getting a nice fresh WordPress installation installed and ready to go on your news
Remember it's my you Arel here that I'm using with my site Ground free account.
WP admin is where my web site lives.
We can use this site Ground account to create multiple WordPress environments for all of our course
Lastly lets configure the Wordpress dashboard and our WordPress installation just a little bit from
That site ground gives us first off there is a welcome to WordPress area right here that you can dismiss
up here on the right hand side if you like and we've got a default plugin from automatic.
For now I'm just going to go into plugins installed plugins and take a look at our plugins lists that
I'm just going to deactivate jetpack for now and we'll leave the other to default WordPress plugins
deactivated as well.
line and I'm also going to choose my own time zone as well as the what I want the week to start on and
So go ahead and do that and I'll pause the video and be right back.
I changed my site title to site ground testing site made a tagline experimentation for WP dev course
and then I just wanted to show you as you go down here to time zone if you open it up you can get a
But there's also a number of different cities here.
But if you just start typing a letter you can go to a city that's near you.
Then I'll click Save changes usually get a green line when your settings are saved.
Like I just did and then the second and third thing I always do is I'll go down to the media settings
and I like to uncheck the organize my uploads into month and year based folders just so I keep all of
I want to.
So I save those changes and then finally I always go into Permalink.
And I'll choose post name.
The best permalink structure for MCO for the search engine optimization and it's the simplest gives
Then I'll just go down and click save changes once again.
And now I have a fresh WordPress installation that's ready to go and I can start building sites in the
We'll set up a free managed hosting account at flywheel.
One of the fastest and most secure managed WordPress hosts available.
Let's go