Managed WordPress hosting provides the fastest loading websites takes care of security and as easy to
your hosting account and create managed WordPress sites with pass it on billing transfer or bulk accounts
But for W.P. of course students they've provided a 60 day demo site for coursework and testing.
an exclusive W.P. Of course student discount if you want to continue with flywheel.
The coupon code on the student resources page gives you at least hundred dollars off an annual ball
If you want to get set up to resell hosting to your clients Let's check it out.
Just like in the last video.
Let's start by going to the student dot W.P..
Of course dot com resources page and that's available if you click the link at the top or the button
as you scroll down from the home page down here.
Just click resource page and on this page as you scroll down just a little bit there is a link to the
You can use that later click the flywheel link and you'll go to a flywheel Sign-Up page exclusive to
I've already filled out some of the fields right here clicked the Agree button and then I clicked sign
I was taken then to a page with a welcome video where I already had an active account.
Go ahead and take those steps for yourself and once you have an active account at flywheel you'll also
with your username and your e-mail you've used and a log in page.
Again like the site Ground account I'll bookmark this log in page which is app dot get flywheel dot
Back inside of the browser there's one more step you need to take to activate your site and be able
If you just click new site you'll see that you'll get to a create a new WordPress site page but don't
right here.
There you'll be able to go and verify with a text message to your phone or you can enter a credit card.
I'm going to verify with a text message and you can do the same.
Just place your phone number right in there and click send code and it will give you a message.
And then you just enter the six digit code that they send to your phone.
Straight in here and click verify I'm going to enter my six digit code.
It came in about two seconds straight to my phone and now my accounts been verified.
So that means if I want to roll over and click the new site button I'm right here on the create a new
I'm just going to enter a few details in here.
Pause the video and I'll start it back up when I'm ready.
I chose a username for my wordpress site that I would remember and a password that I put in twice that
Also you can choose your own temporary domain and it'll be whatever you put a place here.
Dot flywheel sites dot com.
pointed to the site.
As you scroll down you'll see that you can pay now or you can add it to a book plan if you have one
where you can click.
My client will pay later.
I'll just scroll to the bottom and click launch a demo site
and it really only took a few seconds for this site to be created for me.
You can see that it says I have 61 days left at the top of my dashboard for this site and it is password
be asked for a username and password and they use an interesting memorable password system.
News at this point and that can be changed.
The user name is always flywheel and so all I have to do is go up here and click WordPress log in and
that will open up a new tab.
And this is a browser authentication that flywheel places just as an additional layer of protection.
Or so you can hide your development site while it's being made from clients or anyone else.
I know that the user name is flywheel and this is where that memorable password comes in handy
because if you don't remember it you can't go back to a previous tab when you're using browser authentication.
And so I remember that password and it all hit.
OK I can have my browser remember that for future use.
And now I'm at the standard WordPress log in page.
I can put my user name that I chose along with my memorable password that I picked and click loggin
I'll have the browser remember that password as well.
And there I am that great feeling comes over me when I get a new fresh WordPress installation started
again.
We've got the welcome to WordPress standard message that I can dismiss by clicking at the top right.
And if I go over to plugins installed plugins just like we did before.
There's no standard plug ins loaded inside of your demo sites but I will take those couple of steps
And if you'd like Pazz the video now and go ahead and make those steps yourself.
I hope you could remember those little changes that we made to set up our site for development in the
But I'll show you what I always do.
I'll go into settings general and then I'll just name the site if I want to.
and I'll just type experimentation as I usually do and the addresses are there.
We'll scroll down a little bit further and I'll choose my own time zone and I'll go to the bottom and
Then I go to the media settings and always uncheck this organize my uploads into month and year based
Grade the last one is permalink and I click Post name because that is the best Ezio.
And it's just a habit of mine to create that from the very beginning and I'll click save changes.
Now there's one more plug in that's permanently installed inside of flywheel sites which is called limit
Let's just check it out.
What we'll do is look at the limit log in attempts settings just so we know what they do.
and slowing down your sites that are at a managed WordPress host like flywheel.
So it only allows four times before the 20 minute lockout occurs.
And then you can only have four lockouts and then you'll be increased to 24 hours of lockouts.
You don't have to change the options right here.
But it's good to know that this exists in the flywheel sites.
Well that's it.
Let's check it out.
The title of the site and right click visit site and open it in a new tab.
Now if I look at it this is my site.
Great.
One of the things I like to do as well that we didn't talk about in the last video is to get rid of
that loggin admin bar at the top here.
To do that go back into the Wordpress dashboard and under users click your profile.
You can also get there from rolling over your name up here and clicking at it my profile what I'll do
Now when I go back to the live site and click refresh or reload that's what the site really looks like
to visitors at this point.
In this video you sign up for the excellent managed WordPress host flywheel where you get an exclusive
you can use your flywheel account for no charge as part of your coursework or to develop websites for
You can also set up your business to host your sites in one of their bulk accounts and resell the hosting
You'll install a map to set up a complete server on your local computer and you'll be installing WordPress
manually by hosting WordPress on your local computer.
You'll be able to develop Web sites privately.
Experiment with Wordpress and create projects without relying on an external server or needing an internet
See there