In this chapter we're going to be building a new website from scratch a simple brochure type site that
We'll start fresh by installing WordPress again locally or at your site Ground server and preparing
You'll be working on your local computer as a staging environment as if you were going to transfer the
You can also use your live environment at site ground for this developing of the site at a new staging
Here's your challenge for this first video of chapter 3.
Make sure you've downloaded the latest version of Wordpress and then start map and install WordPress
in your local development environment.
Pause the video now and get it set up.
If you're using the site Ground server instead.
Your challenge is to set up a fresh WordPress installation manually instead of using the auto installer
to do this.
folder that you'll create under your student domain.
Use the file manager and your code editor as well as the database section of the panel to manually install
WordPress paused the video now and I'll show you how to do both processes.
Good luck OK.
The first thing I'm going to do is make sure that I have the latest version of Wordpress by going to
and if I open windows explorer and open my wordpress folder you'll see that I do have WordPress 4 5
1 and I did download the zip file and then unzipped it.
And here are my wordpress files.
Now I'll go into Seacole and map in another Windows Explorer folder.
open data.
Select all the files and hold down control and copy them over
all right now that those files are copied over.
I know that they're in a folder called brochure Dasch site and I'm going to go ahead and start map and
get myself ready to look.
That's going to open the map start page in my browser so that I can easily connect with the database
DHP my admin is available up at the top menu or down in the content area there and I'm going to create
I'm going to call it brochure site
and hit create.
Great now that that's been created I can go ahead and connect the Wordpress WP dash config file
and we are ok inside of brochures site.
and then if I double click that it will open inside of my text and code editor there it is right that
I know that database name is the same
if you remember the user name and the password are both in our local installation and the local host
needs to identify the port.
And so let's go back.
Let's see we go back into the start page of map I can see that the sequel port is 33 0 6 and this is
So I can define the host inside of the W.P. config file as localhost Colan 33 or 6.
Just going to hit control as to save it and now I can just open a new window new tab in my browser localhost
slash brochure Dasch site.
If everything is connected properly it should recognize that WordPress isn't quite installed yet and
And go ahead and set up the Web site.
If you do use a password that you can remember for your local computer you have to confirm the use of
great.
of the Settings tab.
The last few things that I want to do is under settings general
set up a few things like the tag line or else the same email address lets choose my time zone those
I can leave as the default and save changes.
Next under writing I don't think I'll have to change any of these for now but under reading I am going
under discussion in media I'm going to leave that as is for now and under Permalink.
I'm definitely going to choose post name and then save changes.
Nice job.
Now I'm going to open them to the new site.
In a new tab.
Take a look.
One more thing.
I still got the admin bar up at the top of the site here.
I'm going to remember to go ahead and go back under my profile and turn that off so that I can look
as the public will see it.
Great.
like.
Now for those of you that are using site ground and your live server environment let's manually set
So log in to your site Ground hosting account and then click go to see panel up at the top left.
First we have to go into the file manager and create a fresh clean folder and we can call it brochure
Usually I'll dismiss this button for the file manager by clicking show hidden files and also skip this
So here I am in my public HTL mail original WordPress installation area.
What I'm going to do is add another folder right inside of public h DML by going up here and clicking
new folder.
I'm going to call it Rosher dash site and I'll create new folder.
So now I have a new folder called brochure site.
If I double click that folder you can see that the directory is empty.
But what I'm going to do is just go to upload and I can hit browse at the top here and here is where
I have saved.
So that will click that folder I had and open up the folder that I had unzipped and inside the Wordpress
Now one thing you may have found is by uploading using the file manager.
You can't select multiple items and upload them all at once and so there is a solution here.
I'll cancel out of that for now and I'm going to open the windows explorer.
I've navigated to that WordPress folder and one way to do is select everything inside of it right click
anywhere in there and I'm going to go send to compressed or zipped folder.
file manager and then I can unzip using the file manager right on the server.
So now I have a zip file which is named whatever I had right clicked up here.
If you are on a Mac it'll be called archive.
Zip.
By default.
I'm just going to click that once and then a second time and I'm going to rename it w.
Doesn't matter what we call it just so that we know what it is and so it is a compressed zipped folder
and when we go back to the uploading screen for the file manager we can go over there and find it and
upload it as one file.
There we go a pause the video while this uploads gives me a success message down at the right hand side.
If I just click go back it closes that tab in my browser and I go back and see it right here in the
If you highlight that file you can click the extract button up at the top right and then extract files
and it quickly extracts everything.
Then you can say reload right here you can see that I got all my Word Press Corps files right inside
of my folder which is called brochure Dasch site.
It basically made a copy of all the files that were within the zip file.
So if I highlight that zip file I can save a little bit of space by deleting that file.
Now I can highlight the WP dash config dash sample that PSP file and click rename.
And just rename it W.P. dash config dot ph P and click rename file and now we have the WP config file
ready to go.
If I double click this file I can download it to my computer edit it in my code editor and then upload
However there's a feature directly inside the file manager where you can open up a file inside of a
browser based code editor you click code editor with that file highlighted and click Edit.
Now I can see my whole W.P. the ash config dot ph P file inside of the browser and I can go up here
I know I'm going to need a database name a username password and a host name however.
I'm going to create a new database and I'm just going to call this one brochure and the whole name is
And then the name that I place here.
So I create the database and it's added the database so I can click go back and you do need to create
And so here are my current databases and if I go down a little bit further you can see I can add a new
So I'm just going to use the same name for this user.
It only lets me use 7 character so I'm missing the E on the end for the username and I'm going to type
and type it again so that it knows that we are using the same password and I can click create a user
could go back one more time.
And now there's one more step I need to give this user permissions to use the certain database so if
and I want to click the all privileges button click make changes and now I've granted privileges to
So if I just clicked go back here and I can actually get right back to the see panel home.
Now I know what those credentials were.
So I can go back into my W.P. config file and enter them here.
Now I've entered those three credentials and I know that when we're creating databases using the C panel
we use localhost as the hostname.
And so I can go up and click save at the top right and then I can just close that code editor and I
go ahead and close that.
And inside of the C panel I can just grab my main domain and then hit control-C to copy open a new tab
But I'm going to add the name of the folder that I created right at the end there and it looks like
No worries this is very common.
I can tell that WordPress is trying to see the database and so something is working.
So let's look at the databases section of the C panel and it looks like it's Greg D 11 not Greg.
Very common error which may have happened to you as well.
W.P. config Doppie HP and I'll go up and click the code editor and click Edit.
Now as I look at the database credentials I can see that I'm just missing a number one here and a number
I'll just click save and then close and I can close the file manager now.
Now if I go back to this address and hit refresh great.
I can click continue and now I'll fill in my credentials and set up my wordpress site.
I filled in all my credentials here.
I used a password that I could easily remember which was a weak one.
So I had to click confirm use of weak password again.
But in my email address and I'll click install WordPress.
I love that success message.
I'll click log in just to go ahead and make sure everything is working.
I think my is remembering my password.
It's one I often use and great.
got a beautiful new WordPress installation that I installed manually.
You can see that that takes quite a few more steps than it does to go into your C panel and use the
Wordpress installer.
But hopefully that gives you a good understanding of how WordPress works and connects to the database.
In this video you set up a new WordPress installation either on your local computer using map or your
Maybe you even did them both in the next video.
You'll make one more edit to the WP dash config file to make sure your site is using best practices
Plus you'll install for plugins that will be using to customize the site see their