The word assault or a series of encryption codes that keep the Administrator account and dashboard area
secure in this video you'll learn how to add these security codes to the W.P. config file and you'll
Let's get started.
As you remember to set up this WordPress installation we went into the map area opened up the database
And we also had to customize the WP dash config file in order to attach the website installation to
If you've got your site Ground manually installed site open you can go to the see panel and use the
When that opens you can see that I have the core installation files here and then of course the brochure
Let's just open the W.P. config file right here in the auto installed WordPress installation.
That opens the W.P. config file inside my code editor here and down below the database information you
The auto installer has taken care of using specific Salt's that it got from the wordpress site automatically.
If we go back I'll just close that in the file manager.
in the code editor.
This is the same thing as looking at it in our text editor like Adam.
If I scroll down a little bit you can see that it just has a blank statement puts put your unique phrase
So like in our local environment we can do the same thing inside the code editor here at Control-C to
Paste it into there and now it's loading me up a nice fresh set of keys.
I hit control-C to copy that and back into the document and code editor I'll select it again that whole
Great.
Now I can close that editor and everything is done.
We can go through that same process in our code editor on our local machine to edit the WP config file
in our local installation.
Go ahead and make that edit of your WP config file in both installations puzzle video now and give it
Did you get that done.
Great.
The control as to save and to prove that it worked.
If I go back to the dashboard try to refresh the page.
Oops.
That proves that the secure keys are working.
And if you ever have any fear about the security of your site or your dashboard you can go ahead and
And then you'll be forced to log back in again.
The reason we didn't set up the assault and authentication keys inside of our flywheel sample account
is that the managed WordPress hosting at flywheel manages your W.P. config file privately.
They don't let you access it yourself to make changes because they're editing it for best practices
and security within their hosting system.
in the W.P. config file but flywheel keeps it secure and manages it for you.
sites that camp is right here and as recommended in the previous chapter I can open up Firefox and fire
So I'll go up to the top of my list here and click Create an account and paste that host right in here.
And I'm going to use my username and my password.
choose security as FGP which is secure FGP and hit OK.
And now that I have done that I can click connect and it will connect to my Web site files at flywheel
via my FCP program over here on the right hand side I can use the little arrows to click below my site
side as it opens up on the server.
Now if I click that W.P. config file and I go over here on my computer side under users there is my
it on the right and clicking that left arrow button gives me a message down here that it's place it
Great.
Now over in Adam my code editor I can open a file and navigate to the desktop where I just save that
under a brochure site.
There's the W.P. config file there click open.
And here's my W.P. config file at flywheel.
It says this is automatically generated by flywheel and you will not be able to edit this file yourself.
And if you make an edit of this local version of the file for instance to choose new songs and keys
It won't actually replace the flywheel generated W.P. config file.
We'll be setting for plugins up in order to give some functionality to this brochure site and for all
life server.
So under plug ins add new I'd like you to go in and look for for free plugins from the repository.
Go ahead and search around the plugin repository and see what you can find.
All right what you may have done is gone into the search window on the top right there and perhaps you
one you choose.
and choose from the plug ins and themes in the repository to make sure you're getting one that's going
Now there's so many contact forms here.
I know the one that I like is called Contact form 7.
It's probably the most popular and most well used contact form plug in inside of wordpress.
So I just click Install now.
It'll give me a message after the plug it has been installed.
And I can hit activate plug in right from that installation screen if I want to.
And just to verify that we know what's going on under the folders of this brochure site.
and we've downloaded it off the Internet out of the Wordpress darg plugin repository.
So under what WordPress darg under plug ins Here's a very similar screen to what we find inside our
And if I search for that same plug in it should come right up.
If I open the page for that plug in I can get a lot of information here across these tabs.
You can download it directly and then upload it into the plugins directory of your Wordpress installation.
But all this information here is also available inside of the installed plug in screen which is right
And then if you hit view details on any of the plug ins that's going to pull up information directly
different information that the plugin authors give to you.
One of the things I always look for is that I make sure that this plug in has been updated recently
it's compatible with the version of Wordpress that I'm using.
know that the developers support the plug in that I want to use.
Now when I said an email protection plugin you might not have known exactly what I meant there but one
by spam bots across the Internet.
In the case that they actually type their email address into a page or a post or place it on the Contact
from being harvested by spam bots.
But I appreciate this one.
Plug in
ah here it is email address and coater by till Kreutz.
It is a lightweight plug in which means it doesn't take any bandwidth or space at all inside of your
All it does is it converts the e-mail address when it recognizes it to a hexadecimal so that the bots
can't harvest it.
So I usually click Install now and activate the plug in the e-mail address and coater doesn't take any
It automatically recognizes e-mail addresses inside of the Web site and converts them to hexadecimal.
Let's take a quick look at how that works.
I'm just going to go ahead and put an e-mail address straight into the front page of the Web site and
it won't be harvestable by spam bots.
Even if I were to make it and link and have it be clickable it won't be harvestable.
So let's go ahead and update this page
great a real email address that's visible on the front page of the Web site.
There it is.
Let me open my web developer toolbar and then click view source
and if I scroll down to the source of this page let's see if I go into the body and I can see the site
header header.
And here's the entry content.
The first line look at all that hexadecimal code.
It basically converts every few letters or many of the letters in the email address to hexadecimal codes
instead of the actual lettering.
So it makes it readable by the browser but not readable by the spam bots.
At the same time if that e-mail address potentially I want it to be a mail to link like that
that would make an email address clickable.
So let's see I refresh the page.
That means that it will open up my email program and send an e-mail to that web address.
When I click the link.
But if we do the same thing
look at the source of that page even when it's a clickable link I can see that even inside of the link
as well so that it's not harvestable by the spam bots.
I'm going to go ahead and take that e-mail address out now.
Update the page there's plenty of Google Analytics plug ins and you can actually depending on the way
But it's easier to use a plugin in this case perhaps you were and found a number of Google Analytics
their web site.
Well there's a lot of Google Analytics plugins.
One of the best ones is the Google Analytics Hayter by sumo me I often use that Sukhumi as often a free
service that I use for social sharing and networking which we'll get into in a later video as well.
But you can activate that plug in right away and then set up the code directly with your clients.
Google Analytics account
one more to go.
Let's search for Google Maps plugin
great.
First thing I'm looking at is the number of active installs and the number of positive reviews.
300000 active installations as I scroll down I don't see anyone quite as popular.
Here's a good one.
Looks like compatible.
Updated four days ago 100000 installs.
But boy this one updated six hours ago.
That one looks good.
Great.
I'll activate the plug in
and later in this chapter will configure each one of these four plug ins and customize it for the brochure
In this lesson you used the word press encryption keys and salt's generator to paste security codes
into the WP config file and saw how it logged you out of wordpress.
Then you went and found for free plug ins from the Wordpress plugin repository that will be using in
Next will customize the home page of the site choosing the layout will also look at the difference between