Like category's tags are a taxonomy or a way to place content into a group or a type tags are generally
And this video will experiment with them and set up a navigation convention called a tag cloud.
By the end of this video you'll understand how and why to use tags by setting them up in your own local
Let's get started.
We'll first explore how tags are displayed in our existing 2014 say in the photography site.
So make sure that map is running and you can open up the Wordpress dashboard and the site in a different
Navigate to the home page and if you scroll down some of the posts that we imported using our ex-MIL
And these are down here at the bottom of each displayed area of each post.
They have a slightly different looking little graphic background like a little tag on there.
And if I roll over one of them and you look at the bottom left hand side of the screen you can see that
it's the R L slash tag slash alignment to is what this one is called.
Sometimes if you have a category for example by the name of alignment and then after creating that category
you create a tag called an alignment.
It will make the u r l have a dash too.
So there's no conflicting yourselves.
If I click on one of the tags here this will show me an archive page of all the posts that are tagged
image horizontal so it looks like I have.
Well it shows me 3 on a page and I have 3 pages so I'm up to nine different posts are tagged with the
Now let's go back into the Wordpress dashboard and look under the posts menu item and click tags.
We imported a bunch of posts that are tagged through our sample SML import so we can use these existing
This on the left is an example of a tag cloud.
They use font size as a hierarchy with the larger fonts for tags with more posts.
will place a tag club like this on the sidebar of our Web site.
Similar categories.
A tag is added through this add new tag field right here.
The real name for the web address and they can also have a description one of the general differences
You can see that there's a hundred and eleven items here.
content within a post.
Generally posts that are tagged will have a whole lot of tags that describe very specific types of content
about the posts that they describe and post will also be categorized in one or maybe two categories.
So if we look inside these existing category tags you can see that some of them have one two or three
posts.
And as we go down you can see that there's just a whole lot of different tags.
And once you begin to tag posts you can really start to use existing tags to tag other posts that you're
Or if the client is using a blog it's a really good way to provide a different intuitive reference as
or does not have some tags let's just go ahead and open one that doesn't.
The HELLO WORLD post that we have on the front page of our site and under a post editing page tags are
And this one does not have any tags but it has a couple of different conventions that allow you to choose
You can click Choose from the most used tags.
Now that'll give you a tag cloud of some of the most used tags just like was on the tags page at the
And if you click any of these it will go ahead and use that tag.
Go ahead and say OK this one is in the content tag and it's also in the love tag are tagged with the
And if you're looking for a specific tag it may not be in this list if there's a whole lot of tags in
But if you just start typing a series of letters if there's a tag that starts with those letters it
will show you.
There we go.
And you can separate tags with commas or you can just click add.
And here's this group of tags for my post.
Hello world.
world post here can see that now.
It's populated with these tags.
I can see what other posts have been tagged with the word love and that can help users to you to be
Again tags are a taxonomy that are navigated in a certain way and it's another way besides categories
to put each of the posts in a web site or a blog into a certain type.
I do have a challenge for you in this video.
What I'd like you to do is populate this content sidebar with a tag cloud see how you get on and I'll
How do you do with your tag cloud.
Well you may have found that there's actually a widget type built into WordPress called tag cloud.
You may have actually seen it in earlier video but if I just go to appearance widgets I know that that
sidebar is called the content side bar and look and see that that's where I have the photo categories
widget and right over here is a tag cloud widget that I can drag in and place below the categories widget.
I can give it a title maybe I just call it tags or if I don't want to do that I might even just call
Now the taxonomy when you use a cloud you can actually choose from tags categories or link categories
and tags is what we're going to use now.
But you could arrange categories if you had a lot of them into a cloud like font size type of display.
And if I refresh the page as you know these these sidebars show on every page of the Web site and so
There it is.
Let's see how it looks on the home page as well.
Great.
Now it doesn't give you that many choices for how many tags that it's going to display and which tags
You can find plugins that manage tags and display of tags in some different ways.
We're going to get into some more of that advance stuff later in the course.
Also by rolling over the tag and letting the little tool tip come up it'll tell you how many topics
are tagged how many posts are tagged with that word.
So the small font only has one largest post formats has 16 medium one is to this one over here is 6.
So you can see how that works.
And if you click one of the tags it of course brings you to the tag archive's as I mentioned before
and it'll show you a list.
And of course in my settings and previous video we chose to show no more than three posts on a single
and I've got.
In this video you learn how tags are different from category's even though they are both taxonomies
within WordPress for displaying and navigating to different types of content and you place your own
In the next lesson we'll wrap up this chapter and this website by adding two more footer widgets to
We'll finish with a discussion about what to do with all that extra stuff we brought in with the content
Once the Web site's done