In this video we'll finish up the photography site by populating the last two footer widgets.
We'll also explore post formats in the 2014 theme.
process so we can deliver a clean website to the client by the end of this video.
customizing with it later in the course.
Post formats are another standardized way in wordpress that you can place posts into certain types.
list of formats that are available to all themes that support the feature.
the format of image and the only change that does is it displays the post in almost exactly the same
Post archive if you looked at the bottom left there it's the URL slash type slash image a theme can
post type the person has defined.
If you look in the Wordpress dashboard I've got this hello world post open and over on the right hand
doesn't use the post format types.
actually nine different kinds of formats and theme developers and developers on WordPress can't change
As I said there are standardized lists that are available to all themes.
If I click image under hello world you can see that that's going to show me a list of posts that are
or a list of tags on a tag archive page the other thing that 2014 offers is a widget that you can use
And it's called the 2014 ephemera widget just to take a look at it.
It would be a listing of a certain post format.
However many posts you want to show and then you could say I might call this one images and it should
images.
So if I just refresh the page any page again I'm on the image type page but if I go down and look looks
name and the date the author and how many comments.
And then it actually shows the the actual image and then a more button which would show this image is
post format archive.
Now you can see that the hello world post is not showing an image.
And this post format image has this one.
And the post format image with a caption is showing this one we can fix that by going in and opening
And then we can just take a look at what that looks like.
and I'll add the same image.
As the one that I was using Let's see how should I display it or display it with a large size and no
great if I update that post.
And then I can go back and refresh the page I might go and just look at the home page
let's take a look.
Great at showing the image and then the titles clickable through to the post.
And these images are also right here.
Another way that these put post formats and enable you to organize your posts a little bit is in the
it shows you a little image link right here and if you look at the bottom left hand side of the screen
So if I click that inside of the post list inside the Wordpress dashboard I'm going to get a list of
all the posts that are inside that image post format for now I'm just going to go ahead and revert back
and not use the post formats for now on our 2014 site.
But I wanted to make sure that you saw what that was inside the editing window and the types of things
One more thing I'm going to go back to a perience widgets and just get rid of that widget in the content
Great that should revert my site back to the way that it was.
And let's do a couple of more things to finish up.
We'll check that everything is working right.
Will fill these two footer widget areas with some more appropriate content and call it good.
There's two slight issues I've noticed as I've been working on the site.
One is that I do have this search bar in side of the primary sidebar but I also have this search area
It's a nice looking magnifying glass search icon with a green bar that opens this nice search window.
I've noticed that sometimes when I click this home button it's actually taking me instead of taking
Now this used to be the home page when we were creating our brochure site and we made the navigation
time which was the sample page.
Now the logo or the title of the site name over here always points to the home you are l.
But over here I've got the wrong menu navigation and so let's make those two changes right now.
Go ahead and stop the video.
Get those changes done if you haven't already and then come on back.
We'll have that work.
Secondly I'm going to go into menus under appearance and I want to go to manage locations just to find
my Hederman you here.
And then I can get at it.
I also could have gotten there by opening this one and clicking the header menu but instead of.
Now this is a page called home.
area.
So I'm actually going to make a custom link I can go back here to get the URL just Control-C copy.
Now I don't want at the very end so I'm going to drag it up to that original spot and click save menu.
Let's take a look.
Here's the home page of the site.
If I roll over home it's taking me the home page it also shows that it's green instead of white showing
Also I've gotten rid of that search bar here because it was a duplicate search bar that was available
up here.
Now there's a lot of different things that you could do with the two remaining footer widgets.
Let's go ahead and go over to the customize or and let's see what appropriate content we could put in
We already have a map with our location and the name address and potentially you could put the phone
It's there already.
But we just have to text widgets over here for now let's see what else we can use.
We're going to go ahead and remove one of the text widgets and let's just click Add a widget.
maybe they've gone to the bottom of a long post.
in the site from down here without having to scroll all the way back up.
Now in this theme the header navigation actually stays at the top of the page no matter where you're
We don't want to necessarily duplicate these pages down here in the footer but one of the things we
a different category page there.
So it's like add a widget and I'll just click a category's widget as it is.
Each one of those clickable.
And if I remove all the posts from the Uncategorized category then that one won't appear there and we
So what are we going to replace this text widget with.
I was going to go through and remove it.
And let's see what else we can choose
the pages we already have appear in the regular navigation so I don't want to replace that.
But for now I think it's a good idea to place a little detail from the about page just down here at
So I think I will use a text widget here and if we just have an About Me section over here on the right
go ahead and get some of the content.
maybe just the first say two sentences something that's appropriate for someone to see at the footer
of the Web site that's going to be on every page of the Web site.
Maybe I'll do a sentence and then there's a hit enter and then enter here too and automatically add
Nice maybe I want to put another space in there.
I can lay it out how I like.
That looks great.
One last thing though.
Let's just.
Well I have to hit save and publish Of course.
But let's talk about within the site you know that we imported that SML file which gave us a lot to
It gave us a bunch of menus give us posts a lot of media in the library that we've been using to arrange
There were comments in there.
There were categories and tags that we've used and I don't often bring in a whole slew of sample content
in that way unless it's the first time that I've worked with a certain theme for many client sites.
All I need to do is make a couple of sample posts sample pages.
Bring in a few pieces of media and I've got what I need to make the site look great.
So when you're done doing the site build How do you get rid of all that content.
One of the things that you might consider doing is just going inside of Wordpress and going to each
they're using the bulk actions dropdown here's a challenge for you go in and delete all the extra posts
And then under Post's tags let's get rid of all the tags except for the one called featured that we
And just go in and remove the tag cloud widget from the content sidebar.
Pause the video now and get rid of all that extraneous content and then come back and watch me do it.
How to go I hope you were able to get rid of a bunch of extra stuff that you didn't need.
One of the things that we did in a previous video that I hope you're able to do is instead of going
seeing them all on a single page.
So in terms of pages there's only six pages that I want to save here and I want to get rid of all of
I don't need them now.
So what I'll do is check all of them and now I don't want to delete all of them so I'm going to uncheck
And then in book actions I could say move to trash apply.
I've sped up the video here while I delete all the posts and then all the remaining tags except for
When I deliver a site to a client I normally delete all the posts and pages that I used in design out
One more thing to clean up the site.
I've got to get rid of that tag cloud widget that we had in the sidebar because I've got no tags.
Great.
I have a lot less posts.
I still have post one two and three.
I still have the three posts for the home page that I saved the tag clouds gone gray and my footer content
as well.
Nice job in this video.
You finished up your client site by cleaning up the extra Post's pages and tags and using two more widgets
You also learn how post formats can be used as long as the theme supports them.
Congratulations you made it to the end of chapter 4 in the next section.
We'll do some technical work with the site we just created.
Migrating it from one server to another.
for staging a site to make changes without affecting the live site.
Let's go