In this video you'll download and activate a new theme for the site completely changing the look and
You'll see that while the content of the site stays exactly the same we can change the theme and make
This is the beauty of using WordPress.
It's a content management system which lets us separate the core information from the style and manner
After this video you'll have a handle on what it takes to work in a staging environment using best practices
for backups as well as seamless migrations.
It's a free theme that's pretty modern and looks great and it's actually available first at Wordpress
But if you go to the homepage of Wordpress dot com you can download a theme copy for your Wordpress
So go ahead and go to WordPress dot com slash themes slash affinity and you can download a copy for
I'll just go to appearance theme's and since it's a themed zip file we can click Add new and just upload
In my downloads folder there it is.
Here's an error that sometimes might occur.
The uploaded file exceeds the upload max file size directive in P.H. dot.
I and I that means that the maximum allowable file size via the HP settings is less than the amount
If you search for something like P-H BMX file size you'll get a lot of different tutorials on how to
Basically there's two ways you can edit the HD access file or you can edit the HP Dot and I file both
If I go to the downloads folder and take a look at it right it's 5 megabytes 5.3 megabytes in size.
And so here's how we're going to get around that.
First I'll just head back to get back to the dashboard
and I can actually check my settings there by going to add a new piece of media add new maximum file
is to place a code directive with HP inside the HD access file.
Now if we look at the file structure just a little bit under the live site folder with all the core
now because it's starting the filename starts with a dot a dot preceding the filename defines it as
structure.
And if you open up that file within your code editor or Adam as I have here you can see the file name
Dot H.T. access is the name of the H.T. access file so there's some code that you can place and we're
And this works inside a map server and it may or may not work the same way at a live server but if we
define a PH p value and then a space and then type upload underscore Max underscore file size.
That's a directive that's accepted in the Apache server and in wordpress.
This means eight megabytes.
So if I control S and save that file now my H.T. access file is newly defined and if I hit refresh
that BHP directive will tell WordPress.
OK go ahead and accept files that are up to eight megabytes.
So now I can go back into appearance theme's and click the Add New and then the following button upload
great.
Now if I just click activate on the affinity theme
great now let's go ahead and refresh the page you'll see that the look and feel has changed drastically
but everything still makes sense within the theme.
You can scroll down and there's the Post's three two and one with their featured images everything looks
Even my footer areas I might lay that out slightly differently for this site but for now I've changed
Let's see what our portfolio page looks like.
Great it's got a large header image and I might change the layout because of this wider column width
even though I have some edits to do.
I have to fix that menu item to say home instead of number two.
That's the sample page
great.
So your task is to upload this affinity theme and activate it in your local environment.
And then go ahead and make a few edits like this menu button and maybe arranging the gallery in the
it.
So then we'll have a new site up here.
Now before I do that I want to make sure that I take a backup so I already know that I have an export
I brought it into my computer under live site and then I imported it into here.
And what I'd like you guys to do is download affinity activate it and then make those theme edits and
Did you get your say edited and then uploaded and replaced the live site with no downtime.
I hope so.
Check out how I would do it.
First I'll change this menu item.
But what I discovered when I went into menu in the dashboard is that this is just the default menu that
is all the pages on the site that was set as default as part of the theme.
portfolio so when I went in the menus you could see if I managed the locations that this team offers
there's one location just tap and there's no menu assigned to it right now.
So I'll go ahead.
Go ahead and sign my head or menu and save the changes.
And then I shouldn't have to edit anything.
Yeah that's good.
Great.
As I scroll down to the footer that's where all my footer widgets.
Here's the four on the right hand side.
And this was my other sidebar which it will have to go into widgets and see what widgets are populated
with what content looks like I have three footer widgets available to me and one side bar.
This is shown in the recent posts.
That's fine and I think I'll move there.
One of the footer category widgets just up there let's see if I refresh this page I'll move it up alongside
the content in the sidebar.
That looks great.
OK so now I have four Let's see where those are at.
I might have all those widgets.
Yeah I do.
categories widget which is a duplicate and the about me text I'll put in the third footer widget area.
It saves them like that.
here and a great one to three.
That looks nice.
Now let's take a look.
Great.
This is too big of a font.
I was using H-2 I think there but in in this theme the fonts are displayed a little bit differently
much better.
That looks nice.
All right.
So now that I have all of my edits done oh there was one more at it actually the portfolio page.
I think that these narrow 150 pixel images you know they're a little narrow there for the gallery.
If you click once inside the photo gallery there's an edit button.
And over on the right hand side let's change it to the medium size and update the post and see what
Nice.
normal sized captions will look better I think
nice.
And when you click it opens the attachment page
Great.
And now with the attachment page we might have a problem with these pages all having a full featured
image on them.
I mean have it linked to the media file that way when someone clicks the image it will just open that
There we go.
And when you click the image it opens the full size version inside the browser.
Nice.
OK.
Now I've got a complete site ready to go.
I can go into my local host development area go in on one and export a file that represents this entire
around is finished making the archive and now I'll download it and it will come into my downloads folder.
I'll pause the video while it does that.
All right.
That's in my downloads folder.
You know I know it's the last one there.
The last thing to do is to go into my live site and go ahead and migrate the imported in using the all
Now if this is the live site this is a live domain name I can refresh the page make sure we can see
what someone would see out in the internet that had access to this site right now.
There's the old style.
I know I have a nice one prepared that as soon as I upload it.
If someone were to navigate to the site or hit refresh the new site will load with no break in service
So I'm going to go ahead and import and do I have a backup of this before important change anything.
But I'll import it from the file.
There it is right there hit open.
Now since this is uploading to the Internet live it's going to take a little while to upload this many
Now that's uploaded.
Great.
Nice.
Oh let's change the general settings away from the word live.
Let's see what our new live site looks like if someone were to be browsing now.
Comes right up.
in this video.
You changed the theme and made a brand new site out of the same content all in your local staging environment.
Then by uploading the completed site you kept the live site active while making changes in the background
and avoiding any downtime or the need for a temporary main screen.
Great job.
Next chapter will delve into the topic of premium themes frameworks and child themes.