In this lesson you'll create your own child theme using the standalone theme we used from Automattic
as the parent theme by using your code editor and a few snippets of code you'll manually create your
Here's where you'll make any code edits to customize the site using best practices by editing the child
Let's start by just reviewing what a child theme is here from WordPress dot org a child theme is a theme
the recommended way of modifying an existing theme.
Now we went over that in the last video.
But if you scroll down on the same page there's a little bit of instruction about how to create a child
You can also find a lot more detail if you Google something like how to create a child theme in wordpress.
You'll come up with a lot of different tutorials to do it.
You do need a code editor like Adam that we've used in the past and I have a favorite tutorial that
Inside their blog and it gives you a lot of good little code examples and tells you exactly the steps
Just like the word press Darrig this article tells you that you just need three things and it's true.
First you need a child themed directory which is basically a folder called Something child.
And then you need two files inside of it style that CSSA and functions dot THP each one needs to be
And then you can add your CSSA styles or your functions dot ph peacoat code snippets that you might
Here's a challenge for you.
Go ahead and open up.
Start map or whatever you're using for your local development environment and open up your fire weed
Open up the Wordpress dashboard and look at the themes and then go ahead and look at the Wordpress Codex
at Kodak's dot WordPress dot org slash child underscore themes or Google one of the tutorials maybe
of this one called affinity and activate it plus the video now and see if you can do it.
I hope you did well with that if you did create a child theme correctly.
You should have a nother theme available here.
Probably with just a blank screen shot and the name of your child theme.
Here's how I would go about it.
First I'm going to go to a Windows Explorer and open up the folder that contains my wordpress files.
If you remember this one is called Live site.
So there's my wordpress core file structure and within the content and themes.
As a new folder and I'm going to call it exactly the name of the theme that I want to create the child
So I call it affinity W.P. come dash child
create.
Now within that folder I've got a place to files if you remember back here at the child themes how to.
I need a style that CSSA and a function's dot BHP so I'll just go to my code editor called Adam and
I can actually go to the content themes and in this folder I could right click and say I want a new
going to be within the child themed folder and I'm going to call it style dot see SS
in order to find the code I need to place inside style.
Thus VSS I can go back to WordPress data work and just copy and paste this.
This example code Control-C for copy and I'll just paste it right at the top there and I'll just edit
There's really only two if you actually do go back here.
There's two that are required for a child theme out of this style that CSSA code at the top.
It's the theme name and the template but you can go ahead and use the whole amount of code and just
WP SEO and.
Now how do I know that it's the name of the folder where the theme files reside affinity dash W.P. come
great.
Otherwise I can leave the leave it the same.
theme you are I everything else doesn't really matter I could put my own name if I want to on the description
The way this control asked to save.
OK so that is the first file.
The second one I need is called functions that ph p.
Again I'm going to go into affinity W.P. come child.
All right click on that folder and click new file and it's going to be called functions a dot ph P and
Here it is right here and you do have to place a certain piece of code in the functions up DHP a file
that your child theme has to enqueue the styles from the parent theme.
Now where am I going to get that code again.
Back at Wordpress dot org.
I could go down and find the queuing styles.
You can read a little bit about more detail here.
In this case this is going to be enough because there's just one style that CSSA file in the parent
So if I hit Control C from here and go back into my code editor paste that directly into functions dot
ph P Now you just need the starting ph p tag.
But you the finishing when you can keep adding other functions that BHP style snippets or code snippets
editing the parent theme.
It functions up HPL just had control S for Save make sure both of these are saved.
And now I can go back and activate my child theme.
There is a bit more to understand but that is enough to get us going.
If I go back into my themes page and hit refresh in my local installation I should see my second theme
And because I've defined it as a child theme of this affinity theme everything should work perfectly
great.
That theme has been activated and let we hit refresh on the live site
It works exactly the same way obviously and you've probably noticed the way this theme with the default
images is set up as it has a random image that comes up for the home page and for some other pages every
let's finish up by making one more change within the style does CSSA file of our child theme and we'll
Maybe we could choose something down here on the footer.
Maybe I can make those a bright white instead of this low gray the way I'd find out what the CSSA styles
inspector the inspector something when this is activated inside of this Firefox utility that when I
Here's the actual markup code on the right and down here at the bottom are the CSSA styles.
So I can see that there the let's see this is defined as a border that's one pixel that's solid and
So if I take this whole style element called Dot widget title that's a class along with the first bracket
I'm going to start out the code block by doing that and then I'll hit enter to the next line.
I'll go back over here and inside of the brackets.
Copy that and place that in my code here.
Then enter one more time and I just need a closing bracket.
And great.
hexadecimal codes.
You can go to Photoshop or Pichler one of those image editors and pick a color and find out what its
So I hit control as to save and just a check.
Nothing has changed within the style sheet of the parent theme.
because we were able to cue the styles in the functions up DHP Well let's go back to our website and
If I just close the inspector and refresh the page since I saved that style that CSSA file.
Well sometimes you might have to do a little bit of experimentation because I can see that didn't change
So I did go back into the web developer toolbar and open the inspector actually.
And when I look at this area I also see that there's a dot footer widgets there's a footer widgets its
So if I take that footer widgets class and paste it right in front with a space for widgets and widget
So I get control S and save it.
Turn off the web developer and let's see if I refresh.
What that does to the border of the footer titles.
Nice nice and white.
And we can see that that's only been done to the child theme not the parent theme.
So when they release affinity 1.1 or 1.5 or 2.00 I'll be able to update infinity.
Still get all the newest stuff when they update the theme but my changes will still be preserved because
In this video you created your own child theme using the affinity theme as a parent.
Then you activated it and made a change to the style that CSSA file to change the web site without touching
Nice job in the next video you'll create a child theme using a plugin which can make it slightly easier.
again without touching the parent theme.
So either