In this video we'll look at a large proven marketplace for premium plug ins called in Vado the Advento
market has lots of different resources for sale by experienced designers programmers and developers
and wordpress plugins and themes make up a big part of the products their themed Forrest is enviro's
We'll explore the and Vado market and I'll show you how I've used in Vado to enhance my business with
First let's just take a look at the and Vado Web site.
It's NVI a teow dot com.
And over here on the right if you open up the little button it'll ask you what you want to do in Vado
the enviro market is what I'm talking about.
They have a theme provider called theme forest and code Canyon is where I get my plug ins for wordpress.
Here's the code Kenion page.
At the end Vado market and I'll usually roll over WordPress.
If you click the Wordpress tab it'll open up 4400 WordPress plugins are in the repository.
They all cost a little bit of money and you can rate them just like you'd go through and rate a plug
You can look at how many downloads and look at the comments and some testimonials and how long the company's
been around and make a judgment whether the developers will be around in the future to support the plug
Now I'll usually narrow down my search within the Wordpress plugin results using this search bar right
For example maybe I want a fancy pop up because I've got a client who wants to build an email list and
form as a pop up for someone that browses to the Web site.
Looks like there's quite a few here and I can spot one in the top few that I've used before.
particular because I have experience with it.
One thing I like about the Vado market is your ability on any products page to look at the details very
There's always a live preview button that opens up a new window or a new tab where you can get a demo
provided by the developer of the plugin.
That was a cool one.
an animated fashion comes in maybe from the sides or from the top.
There's some animation which makes it quite interesting.
Here's a real cool one that I like
nice fill it out and if you close it or subscribe it drops off the bottom within this plug in a lot
pop up for a client or for your own sites.
Inside of a site that I made for a client I'm inside of the layered pop ups settings window with all
these choices.
And you can see that it comes with a whole bunch of sample pop ups the same block over here because
The one that I have activated is here and I went through and customized it with these settings.
here where you can have a lot of different settings for the pop up that you're making.
Back at the layered pop ups and Vado market page at Code Kanyon let's look at what we've got here.
It says five stars with a little bit of testimonial and they're able to do all these kinds of different
pop ups.
I look over here I've got almost seven sixty seven hundred sales with 4300 comments.
The overall rating out of 428 ratings is five stars.
That's making me pretty confident created in 2013 and updated not long ago and it it always tells you
give you some advertising about what it does.
And these are different e-mail servers e-mail providers that it can work with.
And I've just found that it's a really great product for not that much money.
So what if I wanted to shop for a different type of Wordpress plugin maybe I need.
Recently I've done a search and researched plug ins that I can use to make a contract in the if I search
And that's what I did search for before.
Here's one called W.P. online contract and looks like they've got a couple of add ons for some payment
I really just needed to have my client actually needed to have his clients be able to sign a contract
online downloaded as it PTF and have it keep inside his Web site on file so that he could access it
WP online contract was an excellent solution and I went through the process of just going through and
Looking at the buyer rating looking at when it was created and when it was last updated and I went ahead
I've said it before regarding WordPress themes.
But one of the best things about purchasing a premium product like a premium plug in here is that the
Keep it updated as Wordpress updates and give support when needed.
One of the things I looked at with this plug in before I bought it was that I was able to go down here
and see some recent comments and they were all positive comments six days ago eight days ago 11 days
And so that gave me confidence that I can go ahead and give it a try and make it work for me.
Don't forget I've covered this in an earlier video but they are responsible for the theme for us to
And Vado market has.
and then you can search within these results.
The team that I went over earlier in the in this course and some other themes that I've used are excellent
And I've always had excellent service with and Vado and theme forest.
a newsletter every so often and an access to a monthly list of free files.
I've used these to great advantage and they're always doing holiday promotions and giving away free
pieces of design and plug ins and code and themes from different providers on an ongoing basis.
And so if you look at this and Vado market email I got last March I've got a response of Wordpress theme
panel WordPress plug in some audio and I don't use 3D modeling but if you did free files every month
they also do a lot of promotions where they'll do holidays and celebrations of new things coming up
once a month.
There's always some WordPress goodies in there and I think it's great to be on the Vado mailing list.
I think the best way to get on that list is to visit the resources page from students dot dot.
Of course dot com or from the link at the top left of your site dashboard in your sandbox and just go
If you create an Vado account then you'll get on their mailing list and you'll be able to get that free
Another way to find their monthly free offerings is to go to any of their major brands theme forest
or code Canyon or any of the others.
And on the homepage of that brand you can scroll down.
And then here's the free months stuff from code Kenion graphic river theme forest.
Usually a lot of Wordpress themes there and I've used video hive projects as well.
In this video we checked out the end Vado market where plug ins themes and other great resources are
Sometimes however a free plug in might exist.
That's just the thing you need in the next video.
We'll go over how to decide on and rate plug ins and find the one you need in the free WordPress Dorward
plugin repository.
See their