In this video you'll use the themes built in scrolling home page navigation tags and build the footer
pages of the theme using the Genesis theme settings and sidebar widgets.
We'll also check out the inner workings behind the scrolling home page navigation in our local environment
You'll understand how anchor tags can provide a beautiful and useful navigation structure for scrolling
For starters make sure you have the caf theme site open inside the student's sandbox.
Make sure that when you roll over the site it's your cafe themed site and you can see your list of sites
First let's take a look at the menus that were imported using our X-amount import that we got from the
If I click appearance menus usually the edit menus tab is the first one selected but if not go ahead
the menu is the menu that I created and was part of the default parallax installation just to give an
As you remember all of these were just a custom link with NO YOU Arel except a hash tag they didn't
The other two menus that came in with our SML import are called primary navigation that one has an about
with a dropdown with a bunch of different sub items that came in as pages as a part of our import.
And then there's a few custom links menu mission mantra location.
dot com slash Cafe site dema.
And if you remember we looked at these menu items before they they have a standard you are l and then
Front Page 1 from page 2 from page 3.
So if you look at the navigation menus page for cafe inside of the studio press member area I'll just
We've got a primary navigation menu that goes after the head menu and then there's also a footer menu
further.
You'll see that they recommend that you use a custom u r l for these menu items and you call it your
dash widgets back inside the student's sandbox.
You'll see that these custom you aureoles are actually populated with relative Your else rather than
the absolute you are else here.
Absolute just means they go all the way from the HTP and include it for using the whole domain name.
A relative you are l is just a slash and then the ending part of the inside of Wordpress menus.
You can use relative you or else like this but because this was part of the cafe demo the way we imported
each page.
So to make these work we'll have to edit out that slash cafe and for each of these menu items go ahead
and take out the slash cafe but leave slash hash tag front page 3 and all the other appropriate or else
go ahead and pod.
Pause the video now navigate to the menus area and make that change.
Don't forget to scroll to the top and click save menu at the right hand side when you're done.
OK don't forget to go up to the about link as well which is pointing to the hash tag.
I click save menu on the right hand side and then what I'd like to do is push put this into the primary
If I scroll down to the bottom of this menu I can check the primary navigation menu box and then click
As you remember you can also manage the menu locations using the tab up here.
We've already set primary navigation menu to the assigned menu.
Primary navigation.
Let's go to our site and refresh the page and see how our relative your L's are working inside of the
Great now if I use the scrolling wheel or the scroll bar at the top I can see that the menu comes to
Now I scroll back to the top I can see that if I use this menu item about I'll go to this about section
and there's front page 2 Front Page 3 etc..
Nice.
Your next challenge is to populate this bottom footer menu with the menu that was imported with our
If we look at a site demo again and scroll all the way to the bottom you can see that it was a social
Go ahead and go back to the menu page and populate that menu into this footer menu area.
Good luck How did it go.
Did you get the proper menu populated into the right place.
Well here's how I would do it.
OK there's the footer navigation menu and if I open it up I think the secondary menu is the right one.
I'll save the changes and we can look at it.
But if we were sure you might have gone back to the edit menus tab and looked at that secondary navigation
contact page menu and it's the right one.
So if I go back to the Web site in the other tab and read and refresh rate I've got the menu down in
Now you may have found that you tried out the secondary navigation menu as a location and in fact when
tell you the secondary menu location is not used inside of the theme demo.
If I scroll to the top you may have found if you tried to activate that menu that your social menu came
You may have found that.
But just to show you if I do activate say that secondary navigation into the secondary navigation menu
and click save changes you'll see that that puts that menu at the top below this widget which is that
But above the header image here and it scrolls away and disappears when you scroll unlike the primary
So I go back and just deactivate that secondary menu location by clicking select a menu and then saving
Now my site doesn't use that secondary navigation menu location back inside of our live site tab.
Let's scroll down a little bit and look at a sample page.
that these pull images aren't working the same way as they were inside the parallax theme but they do
There's also a menu inside of the primary side bar widget location.
Let's go back and look inside of appearance widgets.
And we can see that this custom menu which used to be populated inside of the head or widget area it
Well when we change the theme from parallax to Cafe pro that widget got stuck inside of the first widget
So that is a custom menu that I brought from over here this custom menu widget that we can use and the
header menu is the one that was selected.
I can delete that or bring it over and place it down here in the inactive widgets if I like.
If I don't have a primary sidebar item and I refresh the page you'll see that it just gives us a default
we wanted a full screen layout instead of using the sidebar area on interior pages.
width layout instead of using a content and a sidebar column plus a video now and give it a try.
I hope you did well with that.
Here's how I would go about changing from the two column layout to the full width single column layout.
I go back to the Wordpress dashboard.
What I'm looking for is under Genesys theme settings because we're using Genesys we've got this default
layout selection under Genesys theme settings.
Let's check it out by opening the site again and refreshing the page nice.
but they do enable a nice lay out with align left and align right in a single page.
I'm going to finish this lesson with posing a challenge for you.
If you remember in our local site which I had called Live Dasch site and we built out as a photography
on the home page as we scroll down past the featured image on the home page we have recent posts three
two and one on the home page.
However the affinity theme has a home page design with Page panels.
along with scrolling navigation using diamonds on the right hand side.
Your challenge is to go find the Wordpress dot com affinity theme.
It is at Wordpress dot com slash themes slash affinity and also use map to activate your local development
Open the Wordpress dashboard so that you can go ahead and use this to make your changes.
But what I'd like you to do is to activate the panels inside of the affinity theme here and you can
and following them.
It might help to take a look at the theme demo using this link at the top right and have it open in
You can see that on the right hand side.
page there.
They're scrolling navigation works a little bit differently as you scroll down the different and Dimond's
light up or become gray as you scroll down and you can also use them as clickable links.
Good luck in this lesson you added navigation menus to the scrolling home page web site.
We've been working on by using the appropriate relative you or else you were able to make the anchor
You set the site to use a single column layout for interior pages and then open to your local development
I'll reveal how I went about modifying the affinity theme to use their scrolling home page and anchor