In this video we'll check out all the stuff that comes with the author pro custom post type plug from
in comes ready to organize and display customized information.
You'll see that by using the author pro plugin which works with any HDMI L5 Genesis theme.
It can save you a lot of work trying to get that custom post type information to display nicely.
Let's start by looking at the Genesis author pro plug in page inside of Wordpress dot org.
it's called Genesis author Pro.
You can open this up and look at the plug in in more detail if you like but I'm just going to show you
One of the things we have is that there are a there's a library created when you activate this plugin
that uses custom post types for information that is covered in all of these bullet points.
So there's all these free set up custom fields where you can place information that gets stored in the
There's a little bit more to this custom post types.
Plug in there's output from a widget a featured book widget that comes within the Wordpress dashboard
Once you activate the author pro plugin now within the featured book widget it's very much like the
pro-team inside of Genesis and it gives you a lot of options with which to display the different custom
As you scroll down there's also some fields designed for authors who can have multiple authors within
of these are independent of a WordPress user as an author and it's independent of the date that a post
So it's a published date that's independent of that.
Finally there are these five templates built into the plugin and this is where the Genesis author pro
plugin gets really powerful and prevent you from having to program templates like this yourself while
using something like the custom press plugin.
You can list a single book page a list of books which is an archive page and you can list the books
of these taxonomies is independent of the categories and tags.
Taxonomies built into WordPress.
Now it should be mentioned that this author pro plugin works with any Agena HCM L5 Genesis child theme.
Any studio press theme that has the word pro in it like Author pro and all the themes that are present
within the student's sandbox are HVM L5 themes so you'll see that the author pro plugin will work with
And one last thing because we're in wordpress dot org you can see that this Genesis author Pro is a
However it only works with a theme that's running.
Genesis back inside the Wordpress dashboard in the author pro sandbox site that you've set up.
Let's take a look at the Customize her.
What will be doing is looking through the author pro theme.
After making this content import that we've done and will look at all the different pages and custom
themes to display the content.
As we've seen before the home page doesn't look exactly the same or as it should because I had it set
of course dotcom students sandbox area will deal with this home page later but for now let's open up
menus.
And you can see that there's three menus created already.
Follow me is a menu that came in with our SML import and has some social networking follow buttons Hetter
However these items here menu one menu to three and dropdown are the ones that I had but by importing
of these navigation items that we can use to check out the author pro plug in content and how it's played.
So we'll be using that hetter menu.
And then there's also a secondary menu that appears within the author profe theme and is control with
That shows I'm a book author page and some book tag pages.
menu location and under secondary navigation menu location.
Let's set a secondary menu great so now what we have is a set of menus one across the top and another
Now I'd like you to make one more change so that this hetter menu isn't so large it has too many items.
to go ahead and remove menu one two and three.
Go ahead and follow along and do the same as well as the dropdown menu item and then items 1 2 and 3
that I had created when you created your sandbox at first and we have the standard Hetter menu that
So now click save and publish.
And now I'm ready to close the customize or I'll get back to the Wordpress dashboard here and I'll just
Visit site right click and click.
I still have my old front page and will be editing later in this chapter.
But I do have my menu items secondary menu right here and the header menu which has a few different
custom fields and custom taxonomies that are available here within the author pro theme and plug in
most of them are available under sample page with the dropdown right here.
like a traditional post it's got a title it's got an author listed here which is not actually the user
within WordPress but actually an author listed as the author taxonomy.
There is an image on the right hand side.
And we'll talk about how this image looks like a book with this little bit of overlay on the left side
and it's got some information in the body text area down on the left side.
And then here are some of the custom fields over here on the right.
There's a price and then there's a publisher how the item is available.
There's an is vin number custom fields and there's two buttons that you can use for any link and there's
It's also got a tagged listing right here for any book tags that are associated with this particular
Now let's go back into the Wordpress dashboard and under our new custom post type area code library
lets look at all books and we'll open that same book it's called across the bridge.
And let's see how this is different from a traditional post within WordPress.
It looks very similar.
It's got your traditional editing area here at the top the ADD media button etc. and you can see that
the title or name of the book itself as we scroll down a little bit you can see some of the taxonomies
on the right hand side book authors is set up like categories in a traditional WordPress post.
So it's like each book can have two different types of categories.
One is for authors and one is for a book series.
And then finally there's a nonhierarchical taxonomy like tags.
And this one is called Book tags and it's independent from the tags that are available under posts because
it's set up separately inside of the custom post type called books.
As we scroll down a little bit lower There's the traditional featured image and it's designed to be
It places it on the right hand side.
And it also has a certain size and a certain thumbnail image size associated with it.
Back to the Wordpress dashboard as we scroll down we've got a few more items.
Now these are all the custom fields under book details.
There are a whole bunch of custom fields that we can use feature text is interesting.
What if I say that let's see this one is featured text and if I update that now there was nothing within
the bridge it shows featured text as kind of a banner across the right hand side in an angle that lists
An interesting display of a custom field inside of wordpress.
Now further down like we listed on the book page here we've got price is bin number publisher.
There is a publication date that can be listed available in certain types of formats right here.
And then a place where you can have three up to three different buttons.
two buttons one for Abai on Amazon and one to download the e-book can point these wherever you like
to have the customer go ahead and link through to either the publisher or Amazon or wherever they can
Well that shows us within the book custom post-time a lot of the stuff that's built into the Author
good on any Genesis powered theme.
Now there's just a couple more things to look at here.
Let's look at what a series page might look like.
Now within the travel series you can see that the URL is the the the L slash series slash travel which
We've got a three wide way of displaying a grid so that it's a nice display in and it shows the featured
image the title which both are clickable through to the single book page.
You can see that this one has that feature text says Award-Winning on it.
If I hit back we're on a series page which is like an archive page here.
Now you might be able to put some information at the top to announce that this is actually the travel
Let's look at that option quickly inside the Wordpress dashboard.
If we look under series I've clicked the series menu item and I have one series in here so far called
And when you click that the author pro plugin has provided us with a book series archive settings section
which gives you an opportunity to place a title as well as the archive intro text above that grid format
So if I just turn a travel travel series and then anything I might put in here you can put images anything
You could put right here.
So I'm just going to put a placeholder word called content scroll that about to the bottom and click
update and then look at this travel page.
And this is the real advantage of using the author pro plug in with Genesis themes.
You can place anything you like up top here on any archive page for example on an author page you can
Let's go back and look at tag's which is one of the taxonomies inside of the library or books custom
If you have say Award-Winning there's one book inside of the award winning tag.
There is a tag archive's settings section where you can have a headline and whatever text or images
Above all the items that fall under that tag.
Now having these archive page settings areas where you can have a headline and some intro text or even
This is unique to Genesys or at least it differs from the standard WordPress way that they treat taxonomies.
powered theme.
And if I go under posts and look at tags for example and choose one of my tags you'll see that it only
your theme but you don't have an archive page setting a place where you can put intro text or anything
else.
The last thing I'd like to show you has to do with menu items here in the author pro theme as well as
hand programmed into templates if you were to use a simpler custom post type plug in in the secondary
Here we have traditional items that are floated left but then a special highlighted item that you can
I have the appearance menus area open and I also have the secondary menu selected here so that we can
I don't see any differences here but if we look at the top we open up screen options we can see that
we can check CSSA classes and that gives us an additional option for our menu items now built into this
author pro theme.
You just put the word highlight there and it will float that menu item to the right and it will highlight
And the last thing is that for menu items you can see that there's not just Pages posts and categories
as in and custom links as well that a traditional standard WordPress installation has.
But we also have lots of different menu items provided by the custom post type plug in.
We have libraries.
You can make a menu item out of any of the book custom post type items.
We also have book authors book series and book tags that we can make menu items with and that makes
the author pro theme or with any studio press Genesys theme that's using the author pro custom post
You explored the author pro theme within your sandbox site powered by the author pro Plug-In with content
You can see that the custom post-time taxonomies and custom fields provided by the author pro plug in
gives Genesis themes easy display of all that custom content.
In the next lesson we'll build out the home page of the site by using the author pro layout configuration