In this video we'll finish up some specific customisations to the author pro-side.
We've been working on will populate the footer widget areas with content and explore the use of the
By the end of this lesson you will have explored all the author pro plug ins custom content display
Let's start by opening up the dashboard and again going into appearance widgets we'll be looking at
Each one can have whatever we want in there and in the first one.
Lets open up and looked look at this one is just a title that is a text widget that has something to
And then secondly there is the genesis simple social icons a plug in that is free and the repository
parallax pro sample inside your students sandbox.
Lets open up the site inside another tab and take a look at what we have going on.
nice blue color which is a secondary color or alternate color that weve got set inside the author proceeds
theme at the moment.
So the first thing we want to do is basically arrange these icons so that they'll fit all in one line
or in two lines we can control the size of these icons and the color of these icons.
So that's your first challenge for this video.
or larger to make them lay out in a nice layout.
The first thing I look at is how are these icons going to display at the widest size.
You're looking at my screen here on my large 22 inch desktop monitor.
So I know that if I drag my window across and make it smaller I can look at how the mobile responsiveness
works within this theme.
So I don't like the way it looks with the single icon below the 4 in the first or the second iteration
and two.
And as I get smaller Yeah that's going to look good.
a row so I'll either make this a little bit larger so that it shows in two rows in my larger screen
or I can make them smaller so that it shows in one row.
Well how go about that.
and you can see it under simple social icons.
I've got both a size and a radius some information that I can choose to to work on the size and the
colors what color it's going to turn when I roll my mouse over it.
And then each time I put a link or in this case a placeholder I can choose how many social I kind of
So for me I'm going to leave it at the number 5 5 items and I'm going to make those I think a whole
I've got plenty of room inside of my footer widgets and really let's see what happens if we double the
look.
Now.
OK.
I don't want my footer widget area to get too tall.
90 pixels.
Hope this was the process that you went through just trying to make your layout look good.
I like that.
I like the five different ones.
Now let's find out what this blue color is and let's make the roll over of our social sharing icons
that same blue color.
So how am I going to find that out.
One thing I know is that under a perience customize inside of the customize or I'll have some controls
Here's the site colors and there's my accent color and that's where it is being used for the menu items
So if I just select that I'll choose the color number without the hash tag symbol and that's just close
Let's change the color
in my simple social icons widget.
So I get to select that and hit Control V to paste that color and then I'll save it
great.
And I don't need a second text widget to push the size up.
Boy I like the way that blue looks.
So I'm going to go and see.
I mean the title the simple social icons widget
and I'm going to get rid of that second text widget that I had over here just by dragging it across
and letting it go by deactivating it over here.
Right.
Let's take a look at our results and then we'll go to the next stage.
It looks great.
Let's use one of the Genesis featured book widgets and placed them here with a link and maybe just a
that a try.
How did it go.
Should've been pretty simple for you.
I would think here's how I'd go about it.
I'm going to play a Genesis author pro featured book widget and again this is pretty easy to do.
And this widget is provided by the author pro plugin which gives us a real easy way to go ahead and
So if I just pick one of the books we have that one featured above on the homepage so maybe I'll choose
a different book.
I use the author pro image thumbnail size leave it none and then it'll be just centered within the widget.
I want to show the featured text if it has it and show the title.
any content and just have a button that says View book it's time let's show the price to see what that
Click save and then I'll refresh the page over in my other tab.
Great now that's pretty large.
And here is the view book.
Maybe the 150 by 150 thumbnail and click save
that looks a little bit better.
That shows only partially the book cover but it does give me a nice small widget to go alongside my
Now what if I wanted to have that thumbnail instead of a square thumbnail actually have the proportions
of the book itself and show the title of the book the entire book cover that would be a good challenge
And if you can remember how to regenerate your thumbnails you can change the thumbnail from being cut
Plaza video now and see if you can figure that one out.
How'd it go with changing the thumbnail size.
Back inside the Wordpress dashboard.
I'll show you what I would do.
First I'm going to check my settings media.
You know I look like I want to see it says Krop thumbnail to exact dimensions and leave it proportional
But then it's the right size.
This is only for newly uploaded images.
to plug ins and activate it.
in.
the video here and let that finish.
OK.
My message is success.
All 45 images were so successfully resized.
So what happens when I refresh the page.
It will be pulling the thumbnail in and there it is a nice book cover that shows the entire book cover
and it's not cut off at the top.
Now if I wanted this to be slightly larger I think 150 pixels is a little bit small for this.
So I might just quickly go in and change my media settings once again and it's OK to regenerate your
I'd like to see this it 200 pixels instead of 150.
It save changes undermine media settings and then I can just go into tools and regenerate the thumbnails.
Once again I'll pause the video here and let it finish.
Great.
That just took a couple of quick seconds and I'm going back to my live page and refreshing it.
And that looks like a better size to me.
What happens when I go back to appearance with it's just one more thing I know that that's justified
I'm going to take my image alignment instead of none and make that centered and click save and let's
That looks better.
Now this footer is going to appear on every page of the website below whatever content we're working
So let's place a recent posts with you here that will update when the author or authors create a new
and lay it out so that the number of posts showing fits with the height of these other widgets in the
Give it a go.
I'm sure that was super easy for you.
Let me show you I'd go back into widgets here.
Close up footer number two and under footer three.
I'm just going to bring a recent posts widget over here.
I think maybe I'd be able to show 10 and if I don't have a post title here I'll just use the default
recent posts and that's fine for now.
So as I save that widget and give a refresh or was it laid out.
Great.
Nice links that over with the beautiful blue color.
Now if I look at a single post behind Iceland eats as I go down here the next thing after the post is
The last thing will do in this lesson is to use the Genesis powerd after entry widget area and what
In this case and the author pro-team and it shows some content that we might want after every blog post
web store or something like that would be a very appropriate piece of content for this widget.
entry and most Genesys powered studio press themes there's an after entry widget says right here widgets
Now just quickly inside of this after entry widget I'm going to drag across a special Gensis widget
Very useful for this area.
You can just say about the author or something similar and then what it's doing is it's pulling data
from the user's account within Wordpress and so which you can choose whichever user you'd like to use
and then it's using a Gravatar which is a visual account which brings an image in Gravatar as a company
and it's a good place to associate your email address with an image so that you can use that same image
But you can choose the size of the Gravatar of course if there is none it will show the little mystery
You can use the author bio which is one of the items inside of your profile here.
Or you can use custom text below and then you can use one of your pages as a linked page within this
widget here.
Read more perhaps about the author.
I'm just going to use this is about me.
Just as some sample text right here and then we can click save an author archive link we'll link to
So let's go down and see what that looks like if I open a particular blog post like this one.
When I scroll down to the bottom and I've got yes there's the Gravatar image and a read more link goes
In this lesson it used existing content to populate the footer and after entry widget areas some of
Some of it provided by the author pro plugin like the featured book widget and some conditional like
post pages in the Web site in the next video.
You'll use the book cover Photoshop image that's provided by Studio press with the author pro theme
and learn how it uses an overlay within its layers to make the left side of the image look like a bookbinding.
Let's check it out