In this video you'll select a different genesis theme and check out how the custom postdated created
We're not tied to a particular theme forever nor do we have to re-import the data created around the
You'll get a sense of the versatility of not only the author pro plug in but all custom post type plug
Let's start by going back to the Wordpress dashboard on the author pro theme that we've been working
our existing content.
Let's all do interior Pro.
The reason I'm picking interior pro and I'll just hit activate is that in terms of the home page and
for book which is again across one of the widget areas and it'll show for across just like the author
Let's go back and look at our interior pro powerd site now.
OK I've got my my site open in another tab octaves right click and hit open in new tab.
OK you can see that I've got the interior theme look right here.
It's actually also have the interior theme demo open in another tab.
So we can compare our site to what the demo is supposed to look like Don't forget it's at Demo dot studio
And then the theme name.
This one is interior.
This is the site name.
And then here's a widget area that can have we have a widget area here it looks like here's a widget
And then there's a couple other areas.
And this one is the footer which contains three widgets.
And so we're going to customize the interior theme for our author pro web site.
Let's just take a look at what we have.
We've got this is one of our widget areas where we had a single widget I think that was down in the
And here's our books for widgets in the area across.
Looks great.
I think I can see that the plug in is taking care of some lay out items and fitting it into the interior
pro theme look and feel you can see the buttons look a little different.
Let's go down and look at the rest of the home page.
Here's our little about the author that we had put in the after entry area so we're going to rearrange
But let's take a look at a single book page as well and see that the plug has taken care of some of
It puts the image to the right hand side and this looks really good.
As you scroll down you can see that it's got the different custom fields data present Also and here's
one of the by buttons.
Looks great.
And then you can see these two areas the above the footer and the footer area are visible on every page
So there's a little bit to change here.
And here's your challenge for this video.
Back on the home page you can rearrange your home page or front page widgets into the widget areas to
widget area and the footer widget area.
You can go back to the interior pro theme demo to look at what that looks like.
Also you may want to take and make a change within your own site.
to keep that at the very bottom but somehow arranged that that is visible at the top along with this
So your challenge is to arrange your site with the existing content.
The home page and the footer and before footer widgets and see how you go puzzle video now and then
OK how how'd you do with that challenge.
That might have been a couple of trial and error items that you need to do there.
But if I go back into the Wordpress dashboard one thing I know is that because I need to move these
items that I've already created between widget areas the custom.
Isn't that great at that.
and I can just drag them around and put them where I need them to be.
front page one from page 2 and front page 3.
And then of course I have the before footer and footer areas.
So if I have the footer Let's see I can just oh also this simple social icons that had been missing
So I'm going to go ahead and do that into the footer along with the recent posts widget into the footer
and I'll figure out a third widget to put into the footer area as well to make it like the demo.
I think this front page 2 widget area with its four featured book widgets looks good so I'm going to
This one is the about the author user profile which has the Gravatar and the connection to their bio
So I'm going to use that Genesys user profile widget.
Except this time I'm going to put it in the before footer.
Instead of having this text widget which I am and I just bring down and get rid of over here I'm going
feature posts.
So if I bring agenesis featured post widget over the front page three now just to show the most recent
of different thumbnail sizes to choose from.
And that reminds me.
This may have occurred to you hopefully you thought of it during your process but because we've changed
once again.
So for this one because this is part of a widget here we're going to show just the most recent blog
I want a nice big square front page square eight hundreds.
We know that from author pro 800 by 800 was one of the thumbnail images but these ones ape 800 by four
So I'll choose this one nonetheless.
Let's leave the image to the left and then the text on the right.
And let's show the content and we'll do the same we did before limit it to 300 characters and we can
That's fine.
And our Click Save Let's see in front page one I have just a single featured book.
Let's go and bring that over to the middle of the footer section.
That's where we had it before in our author pro theme.
Let's see if I go back to the sample you can see that in front page one this is like a big hero image
There's a button that links somewhere to the Web site.
Some large text and the title is right here.
So I'm just going to imitate that with a text widget back in my sample site here or the online version
So if I don't have a front page one widget in there it just uses the header image and goes straight
But I want to use from page 1.
So I'll place a text widget in here and I know that this theme is program to format the content a certain
and put that inside of that content.
The author's name that was brought in as a part of our ex-MIL import originally and have a scholar author
that's just going to be a small title at the top.
And then let's put that little button in there so we know that we need we need a link.
And this one is just connecting to us a page within this site.
Now back at the site the home page I know that if I go to the URL slash books I'll get the library grade
it shows three across and then it's paginate so that we can go to the next page.
Great so I might create a button that would be that you are in control C for copy and I'll just paste
OK.
So if I want this to be an anchor tag which is a button or a link I have to go a for anchor and the
a button.
So if I just do a space class equals quote button unquote and then the next thing I need to define in
This is the hyperlink reference equals quote.
And all I have to do is close that beginning tag and then right here I can type whatever I want.
Let's see this is going to be all books.
How about.
and greater than symbol so I have automatically add paragraphs and actually I mean to take out one of
I've hit save.
Let's see what our site looks like now.
Oops I'm not on the home page so we can see that it's using a any cursive font for our page title.
And great.
open that page.
Awesome.
And now I've got the content showing up.
So I have a little thumbnail image inside of the behind.
Let's go back and edit that widget just a little bit make that front page look all that much better.
We've got one featured post and they're showing the content.
That's where I had my error and I need to put 300 right here and I'll just say if Now if I go back and
That's quite huge.
and then see how it affects our page.
First of all I'm going to region thumbnails regenerate all the math and it will look at the theme and
OK now that all my thumbnails have been regenerated let's just go back to the home page and refresh
to see how that affects our home page especially where I have that featured post.
It's still quite a large image.
See if I just look at image info in Windows.
page.
featured image size thumbnail that's been created for me.
I need to go to front page 3 and featured posts that featured image from page Square.
What else do we have here.
That's a large one.
a nice size 400 tall but 800 wide
refresh the page here.
Oh that looks really nice with 300 characters and then the read more link that blog post looks good.
I've got the four footer area with my author information and three widgets in the footer.
Go back and address this primary sidebar and then maybe I'll go and edit this menu so that these are
So if I go into first of all check Genesis theme settings you know see it looks like yes I have sidebar
It's like I had in my last design.
All right.
So if I do that and refresh that page there you go a nice full with blog post.
hand side and buttons.
If I have them great.
All right.
Let's go over and go to appearance menus.
I can see that that Hederman you.
Is that upper menu at the top.
And then there is the secondary menu which in this theme is called the footer menu.
People can get to them.
We don't want it to go too wide.
What I have here I might use a dropdown.
I think that's a good idea.
I could get rid of say this item on the right hand side and replace it with a dropdown item.
page there are all these items.
I just want to go in here and create a custom link and I think what I'll do is go to the see it's good.
Copy link location I've right clicked on all books and I use that link as the custom link at the top
But now I also want oh I don't have a title for it.
Area
call it all books.
I was missing from the footer menu.
And when I place him here I pull them to the right until there are some items of the one that I want.
There are also a couple of book tags that were on that footer menu.
Keep them on the same level and they'll be all part of the single drop down there.
I could even put a specific book if I wanted to as a menu and that one if I wanted to highlight a book
that look to the menu
and place it over there.
All books.
And there's my drop down.
Nice.
In this lesson you completely change the look and feel of the website but kept all the content intact.
This is a good example of both how separating the custom post-date content into a plugin preserved the
This illustrates the power of Wordpress as a CIMS or content management system that wraps up this chapter
in the next.
for your Wordpress Web site Business.
We'll be working with live web sites either with a free trial account or one that you've purchased because
Let's go