Hello and welcome the course in Python programming in today's tutorial we start our epic journey into the world
of Python.
And today I'll show you how to install Python on your computer.
Whether it's a Mac or a Windows computer we will learn how to do it.
In either case.
So let's dive straight into it.
So installing Python What does it involve.
Well of course it's all about installing the programming language Python
However this can be done in many different ways.
So you could install Python just by itself onto a computer and then install an IDE an integrated development
environment such as pi charm or Eclipse onto a computer as well and use Python through there.
But what we're going to do is we are going to install Python through the Anaconda distribution so Anaconda
is kind of a pre-packaged solution that already includes Python and it also includes Jupiter.
And it includes which we'll talk about just now it also includes other IDEs already inside Anaconda
and it actually also includes a lot of packages like NUMP pie and Pandas and some vizualization packages
so you won't have to then worry about installing them separately so basically Anaconda is a very convenient
way for data scientists and analysts to get Python up and running very quickly and I'll demonstrate
how to use how to install Python using Anaconda and get it up and running on your machine very fast.
And also we will be using Jupiter so Jupiter notebook's is a solution which used to be previously called
IPython notebooks but then they expanded and now they you can you're able to code in Julia in Python
and in R among other languages in the Jupiter notebooks and that's where the name comes from.
So Julia Python and R it is a solution that works in your browser so instead of installing an integrated
development environment and install in python there.
So like a separate program that you would be coding in Python and there you can actually do it through
your browser and you'll see how it all runs.
I know it might sound a bit dodgy even that it's running through a browser but it's actually a very
very powerful solution especially for data scientists because it allows you to get results very quickly
.
All right.
So let's get started.
How do we install all of these things on to a machine.
It's actually not a very complicated process.
There's a few steps as just three basic steps that we will go through together and you'll see that it's
very straightforward.
So first step is installing Anaconda
Second step is open the command line or the terminal on your computer.
And the third step is a run Jupiter notebooks and that's pretty much it.
So as soon as we get through these three steps you'll be able to start coding in Python is pretty exciting isn't
it.
All right.
So let's get started.
Step one.
Installing Anaconda, so to get Anaconda.
I'll show you which website to go to.
But basically you can just search through Google just google Anaconda Python and then you will need
this version on the right you'll need the python 3.5 either for Windows or for a Mac and it will do
all these steps together just now this is just like a summary of the steps.
Step two open the command line.
There's two different approaches one for Windows one for Mac.
So if you're on a Windows machine then in your Start Menu in the search bar just start typing Anaconda
.
This is after Anaconda's downloaded installed.
You'll be able to bring up the command prompt So as you can see here we started typing in Anaconda and
that brought up this option.
And we need to just click and icon the command prompt.
By the way if for any reason you're having trouble finding the Anaconda command prompt then you can
just use the standard command line.
So in the search.
Just type in C M D those three letters and it'll bring up a similar window to the Anaconda command
prompt and you'll be able to use that as well.
So this is what the Anaconda command prompt looks like it's just a black screen or a black little window
where you can type commands so you don't need to type that command that's in there right now.
The one you will need to type in is Jupyter notebook so if you just type in Jupyter notebook after an Anaconda
is installed then Jupyter notebooks will be brought up in your browser and the browser I recommend is
chrome.
And also you will notice that the Anaconda distribution actually already includes Jupyter.
You don't need to install Jupyter separately as long as you install any distribution.
You will have Jupiter and you'll be able to run it through this command line.
Here and will go through these steps just now.
And if you're on a Mac you just need to bring up the terminal if you press command space on the keyboard
.
That will bring up the search and then you start typing terminal.
This will bring up this terminal option if you run terminal.
You will get a box like this or a window like this.
And inside this window once again all you had to type in is Jupyter notebook.
All right.
And then once that's done what you will see is Jupyter.
So this is Jupyter it's running in my browser which is chrome.
And basically you can type in Python code in the cells and then the code will be run underneath.
So this is actual code from our tutorials.
This is from one of the sections in this course and this is one of those visualizations that will be
creating some very powerful analytics around basketball players that will be conducting.
All right.
So those are the steps.
Let's now go through them in practice.
All right so here I'm going to Google to get Anaconda all you have to type in is Anaconda Python.
So just search for that.
And then the link that takes you to Continuum dot I O.
Slash downloads.
So when you want and continue analytics provider the Anaconda distribution so you can read about it
a bit here and there is an icon for Windows.
The one you need here is Python 3.5.
So get the graphical installer and be careful that it is quite large is 350 megabytes.
Also if you're on a Mac.
So I'm doing these tutorials on a Mac.
You'll see that I'm installing the Mac OS version here so once again graphical installer.
And there isn't a big difference in terms of how they're running because it is going to be running in your
browser and we're going to be typing up all the same code as just this installation part that is different
.
So go ahead and pick the one that's right for you.
And just remember we don't need Python 2.7.
We need Python 3 point something.
So your version of Python might be more at the time watching this video it might be higher than 3.5
.
Just go ahead and install that one as long as it starts it doesn't start with a two as long as it's a python
3 point something version or later.
So go ahead install that and once that is installed it might take some time.
Then we will proceed to the next step and the next step is to bring up that Anaconda command line or
on Windows.
So remember you need to search for Anaconda in your search bar in the Start menu or on a Mac.
I'm going to type in it's already typed in here so what we need is typing in the spotlight search is
terminal.
So just press command space on your keyboard and then type in terminal and then brings up the terminal
and once again whether you're on Windows or Mac you just need to type in the same thing.
Jupyter notebook.
Cingular and then just click enter.
And so what that does is it starts launching Jupyter notebook, Python and everything is launched and
then you are presented with Jupyter notebooks inside your browser.
So here all you need to do is select a folder where you want to run all of your Jupyter notebooks or create
all your Python code.
So I recommend creating a folder maybe somewhere on your desktop or somewhere so all of your notebooks
are in one place.
I created a folder called Python programming course for this course.
And if you just go inside you can see already here that I've got some code prepared here.
So, for instance, I can open Basketball analysis and this is a program that we were going to be writing
inside this course already so you can see there is already code in here if you want to create a brand new
program again.
So once you're open you've opened the folder that you want.
Just click here new and then select Python so because you installed it through Anaconda and for Python
you will have this option to start a python notebook and there we go so we can start typing in code
here we can say print Hello world.
Exclamation mark.
Very classic.
And there it is.
It's running as you can see that's where we type the code.
That's the result of our code Jupyter notebooks might seem a bit different at first to what you might be
used used to too.
Working in integrated development environments with programming languages but at the same time will
get used to them very quickly and they're a very powerful solution to not only learning programming
language but also actually performing real life analytics and data science as you will see in this course
can't wait to see in the next tutorial.
And until then happy coding