Hello and welcome back to the course on Python programming.
I'm super excited about this section.
We've got some very interesting tutorials and some outstanding visualizations coming up and I can't
wait to show you them.
And to walk through them and to learn how to create them together.
But before we do proceed there's one topic that we need to cover off and that is categorical variables
.
It is quite an important topic.
As you'll see we'll be dealing both with Gnumeric daughter and categorical data in this section and
is valuable to get this topic out of the way from the very start so that we're on the same page going
forward.
So that's why we're going to dedicate this tutorial to categorical variables.
And let's dive straight into it.
All right.
First things first we're going to import pandas as PD as usual so that we can load our data set and
we're going to import os so we can change the working directory if we need to.
So now we're going to just quickly check the working directory.
As you can see my working directory is correct that is where I put my data said make sure that you downloaded
the data set and placed it in the working directory where you're working or if you need to then change
the working directory and by now you should know how to do that.
In my case I'm just going to proceed with loading the data set I'm going to create an object called
movies and I'm going to use a read CISC function to read movie ratings dot Yes V.
There we go.
So now if I quickly check from our standard while something is becoming our center check the length
of the file we got 559 rows.
OK great.
And if I look at the top couple of rows I go movies head.
And then you can see here we've got the top five rows.
That's what they look like.
We've got one two three four five six columns films honor roll and tomorrow's ratings.
That's the audience ratings.
Oh that's a critical ratings.
Audience ratings budget in millions of dollars and a year of release.
Now the next thing we would we can always check is a movie.
COLMES Now we can see the columns in this case but it's always a good idea to be in have a habit of
doing these checks so that you don't forget next time you have a larger data set we cancel the columns
for example.
OK.
So and another thing we noticed is that the columns have kind of like weird names as a percentage size
lots of spaces and remember what we talked about previously that spaces can be inconvenient if you want
to access columns through the dot operator rather than using the square brackets.
So what we're going to do is we're going to rename I'll call them saurians and movie columns equals
and here we're going to just parse the list.
So first one is going to be Philonous no change.
And I'll say genre no change again.
And also a critic rating is faster to type than audience.
So just for a long audience rating so that we have the same names and just I'm going to keep the singular
audience rating critic rating.
And then we're going to have budget millions.
What did we say about a new line in.
You don't have to put the backslash in other IDs.
A good idea.
And here you can say you're so far on this line.
And now I look at movie movies that head or read the square forget the brackets.
If we look at that now you can see that it's nice and neat and tidy film janitor degrading audience
rating budget millions a year.
Beautiful.
So that's us preparing our data set.
Let's quickly proceed with the exploration.
So what we've learned to really to explore data said we're going to say movies dot info get some information
and so we see here our columns are six columns.
We've got to show them are objects or recognizes objects and four of them are recognized as integers
.
So this is where everything gets started it's getting interesting.
You'll see that critique creating has been recognized as an integer this column or here that's 0 to
100.
What is the rating in percentage terms that the critics gave to that movie the audience rating.
Again zero to 100.
The budget in millions.
That's from zero dollars to some huge amount as you'll see.
There are some movies as a movie with over 300 million dollars in budget.
So these are fair enough.
But then we've got a column called The Year here and it is also recognized as a number.
Right.
Fair enough it is a number but is it really a number.
Is it do we want to treat each year as a number.
That's a question we should ask ourselves when are we going to be working with this data set.
Are we going to be treating year in a similar way that we're going to be treating these three columns
for instance here we can add them take the average take the maximum take the minimum subtract these
these numbers from each other and work with them as normal numbers do we want to do the same of the
year.
And to answer that question we can just use one of the functions that we read you know and it'll make
things a bit clearer.
So let's go and type in movies dot describe.
Remember that a function that tells us some stats around our numbers.
Well if we run that you'll see that we've got the count I mean the standard deviation the minimum first
quarter all the median Segre third quarter and the maximum.
And so these numbers make sense for Kritik creating audience rating and Budget in millions.
Right.
So it makes sense to take the average of the critic rating audience a budget million.
But as you can see for a year it makes completely no sense it says 2009 1 1 5 2.
What does that mean.
What does the average of the years that we're dealing with or let's say the minimum low minimum and
maximum can kind of make sense.
But these quartiles really don't make sense or so.
So does the just as a standard deviation so there is no not much point in these operations.
In fact they don't make sense and that is because we really don't want to treat year as a number.
That's not our goal here is more of a category for us.
Yes indeed years are now presented as numbers there resos 2009 2008.
But for all we know they could have been named in a different way these could have been months.
January February March April and so on and we could have still conducted our analysis so this just stands
to show that in reality year is not meant to be on Americk favorable for us.
It's meant to be a categorical variable.
So how can we fix all of this.
Well first thing we want to do is let's learn how to convert variables into categorical variables because
even these two variables that are currently recognized not recognizes numbers.
They aren't really recognized as categorizing recognizes just objects.
So how do we turn them into actual categories.
Well the correct way of doing this is you call the variable so in our case film and let's remember that
we can run it like this and I will get films like that or we can even just put that dot same result
because it is it doesn't have spaces in it.
So we just call this a column and then we type in dot as type.
So we want to change the type.
I don't want to say category here.
So if I run this again you'll see that it's printed out.
Nothing has changed but what we'll do is we'll take movies Daut film equals I will override it because
this is just returning the result although oppression is not actually changing the column itself.
What are we going to do.
We're going to set it as a category and then we're going to overwrite the column that we already have
.
So if we run this now if we look at movies on hand you'll see that really nothing has changed.
But if we go into movies dot info you'll see that now film is recognized as a category and that's exactly
what we want.
Now if you've already studied Aroer if you've taken my course in our programming then you'll remember
that in our categories are called factors and in our it is a bit more detailed you get more information
on the carry on factor and what unique values they are in that fact call them.
But we'll learn to do that in Python as well.
So basically categories in Python are very similar or like two factors in our.
And now what we're going to do is we're going to perform a celebration for the other columns.
Let's make two of these.
And here we're going to say genre and here we're going to see Year.
All right.
So let's run that.
And now if we look at movies dot info you'll see that both of these genres and year are now categories
and that's exactly what we wanted.
And in terms of what we just discussed if you'd like to know what are the unique values in that category
.
It's very simple.
All you need to type in is movies genre for example than say cat and categories.
Yes.
If you're on this you'll get the unique value so it's a very quick way to assess what levels are in
are these would be called levels of a factor.
And these are levels of a category in Python.
What levels or what unique values that category holds.
As you can see we've got seven different genres on movies.
And finally now if we call movies and describe you'll see that a year is no longer here so Python has
learned that the year column should be treated as a category and not a number and therefore it's not
including it in this describe or in the statistics that it's outputting for our doorframe.
So there we go that's how we prepare our data set.
That's how we are.
Once again we learned how to we revise how to explore data set.
And also we learned how to prepare our data set in terms of dealing with categorical variables and specifying
them manually where Python has and recognized variables correctly so for instance where years have been
recognized as numbers Popinjay this is Tauriel and I can't wait to see you on the next one.
Until then happy coding.