Hello welcome back to the course of the program.
Today we're continuing to explore matrices.
And here we've got the data that we loaded into our jugular notebooks last time.
And now let's have a look at some of the matrices that we have here.
For instance we've got field goals minutes played games.
Let's have a look at a couple of them.
So that's Taipan games and press shift enter.
So there's our games majors.
OK.
Interesting.
Let's have a look at let's see what else do we have points for instance.
Those are good points.
OK.
So there's another matrix of points.
Let's have a look at how these matrices are constructed.
Where do they come from.
What do they mean.
So let's go to the top and we've got some Commines here and here.
What do we have.
So a package has been imported.
And by then we've got a list of seasons.
OK that's interesting.
Then we've got some other object.
This is actually a dictionary so we'll talk about these further down.
OK.
And so here is the salary matrix for instance.
So it is created using a function NPR-A.
And what is it using to create this matrix.
I know this is all alien right now but we're kind of working backwards we're trying to see what's going
on and then we'll talk about the specific ways that you can create matrices.
So what is happening to here to let's look at the specific metric.
So we've got some lists over here Kobe Bryant Sellwood Joe Johns S.R. and looks like it's their salaries
starting from 2000 thousand five all the way to 2014 because you can see that is increasing quite substantially
.
So for the last year or here for Kobe Bryant.
So these are salaries for each one of the players and then they're being put into a list so you can
see the square bracket here signifies a list.
So all of these lists are being put into another list.
There we go.
That's the list of lists and then that list of lists is being passed to some sort of function which
is called NPR-A and somehow it turns out that list of lists all this information into a matrix full
salary and then same thing happens for games.
The same thing happens for minutes played and so on.
OK.
So now that we can see how it is coded let's try to understand what's going on and I'm going to jump
to a presentation about how you can possibly build on a couple of ways you can build matrices in Python
and then we'll come back to the code and practice a bit.
So I think it will be an interesting approach to today's tutorial.
All right.
So let's go building your first matrix.
So how can you build a matrix in Python.
Well as we know a matrix is like a representation of a table of data.
And here we've got an empty matrix How can you actually create a matrix in Python so one of the common
ways one of the ways we'll explore it is using the pi function called reshape and it basically takes
some data.
So for instance a list of data and then it's reshapes it into certain dimensions that you specify.
So the first start there would be the data that you're reshaping.
Second the star is the dimension and then the third parameter which is c in this case.
We'll talk about it just enough.
So there this is how this function works as you can see it creates a matrix.
If you give it letters to 0 and you say that you want a matrix of the dimensions 3 by 5 it will put
these 15 letters into the matrix in this manner.
Now why do we have this parameter C so did you notice that the Matrix got populated.
Row by row.
So I'm going to go back and I'm going to go have a look at it again.
So let's run it.
You can see that the rows of first being populated.
Then it moves on to the next row and then onto the next row.
So this behavior by the way you've taken our programming course then you'll notice that this behavior
is the opposite of what happens in our in our by default.
First the columns get populated.
And this is what the parameter C stands for.
And sometimes people can get confused thinking that the C stands for columns actually C stands for the
programming language C which had an influence on python.
And so this is like the C-like population of the matrix.
We have another approach which is empiric shape with the parameter F..
And in this case it's like the Fortran language that the population is Fortran like.
And therefore you could see that the data got populated into the matrix column by column and the resulting
matrix as matrices are different.
So the default behavior is the C version.
So if you've called the reshape function by default and we'll see this you will get your matrix populated
row by row.
So just be careful of that especially if you're coming from our programming into Python or if in the
future you will be moving into our programming from Python.
Then also keep that in mind so that behavior is different.
And finally there's a third method which will be using quite a lot.
It's called the NPR-A.
So my function called area and what it does is it puts rows into your matrix so it combines data elements
into Matrix and that's exactly what we saw there we saw that lists were combined into Matrix row by
row.
So each player had their own role in the resulting matrix.
So that's how the NPR-A function works.
And now let's have a look at all of this in practice.
All right.
So I'm going to jump back here and then scroll down to the bottom.
The first thing that we want to do is we want to create some data that we going to be playing around
with.
So first of all let's import some PI as and P even though it has already been done for us of a here
in the code actually because it's been used as you can see it's been used in these functions but we'll
still do it just in case it doesn't hurt.
So that we remember that we were using it as well.
So we click enter here and then we'll say my daughter equals and we arrange 0 to 20 so it's a range
function.
And what it basically does is it's going to give us some data to play around with we just let's print
it out so we can have a look at what we're working with my daughter.
So if you run that you'll see that we've got 20 values remember that and arrange it starts with this
value.
And it goes up to the 20th.
Love the last value specified here but not included.
So that's where it goes up to 19.
So in total we've got 20 values of 0 219 and therefore 20 is not included.
All right so what can we reshape this data as well we can reshape it into matrix right.
So let's try the reshape function let's say N.P. reshape from the non-pilot package and then I'll say
my daughter coma.
And the way you need to parse the parameters to reshape is here it needs to know what dimensions you
want to specify and they need to be passed on as a tuple.
So here we're going to say 5 4 so we want five rows and four columns so the first Tramadol stands for
how many rows or one second one is how many columns.
All right so let's run that.
And so here you can see we've got a matrix of five rows and four columns and a got populated in this
manner.
So first the first row then the second row.
And the third row and so on.
So we're going to make a note here just in case because a lot of time we use different tools.
So we remember the default is opposite to our right because in Our it would get populated downwards
by default.
All right you can see that we didn't specify either FC So that's a default behavior.
Great.
So now let's save this reshaped data of words first let's check how the behavior will look like if we
actually say that we want special special prime minister or say order the parameters name is order.
And then in single quotation marks or in double doesn't matter we're going to say C..
So if we run this you will see that we've got to the same exact result.
So that's.
That means that the default behavior here when you don't specify a parameter it means it's like the
C like behavior.
And here let's just go ahead and save this matrix matrix one equals and maybe that is printed out as
well.
So we can work with it as well.
There we go.
Now why we saved it.
I've got a little quick exercise for you just in the code exercise.
The challenge is to get to the number 10.
All right.
So here we've got a matrix and here's the number 10.
How would you get to it using what we learned about indexation of matrices just for this video very
quickly and try type in that line of code that will get you to that number 10.
All right.
And now I'll show you how I would do it.
I would say a matrix and then Herodes say so this is zero.
This is the listicle of the rows rows 0 1 row 2 so it's in the second row and the column 0 column one
column two.
So it's in the second row and the second column columns for on that I get 10 beautiful.
So now what I wanted to do is I wanted to look at the opposite behavior so let's look at this line or
just copy this line or actually copy this whole cell and just create matrix 2 here instead of order
is sort of the C-Leg here will look at the foreground like behavior.
So if I run this now what do you expect to see what will the resulting matrix look like.
Let's talk about this for a second.
It's still going to be a 5 4 matrix so the main point here is that the matrix is specified by these
dimensions.
It's not going to change.
The data is still going to be the same inside the Matrix.
It's also not going to change the only thing I'll change is how the data is populated into the matrix
.
So instead of going 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 instead of being bent into the matrix like that is going to be bent
into the matrix like that vertically.
So even those are going to be the same matrix.
It's just going to have the same data populate in different way and it'll look quite different.
So let's have a look now.
When I run that you'll see that here we've got 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 and so on.
In this case you can see that the elements are in different locations and so even now if you want to
access the number 10 let's do that again.
There's another exercise if you want access number 10.
You would do it differently right.
So how would we get to number 10 would say it's in row 0 and it's in column 0 1 2.
So remember that numeration of course starts from zero.
So let's look at that matrix two rows.
To go for and not get the number 10 beautiful.
There we go that's how we use the reshape function.
And one more thing I wanted to show you here is the object oriented programming concept.
So we've discussed this a little bit.
So if we look at O.P. we can see that these objects actually are conveying with this object oriented
programming concept so let me explain what I mean.
Let's say if I take empy reshape my daughter.
So if I or let's just take the basic one to simplify things.
This one this is what we looked at at the start.
It's how we use the reshape function.
But what we can actually do is instead of doing this because my daughter how did we get my daughter
in the first place.
My daughter use the NUMP PI arr. function right.
So my daughter is actually it's an array.
Right.
So what are we going to do with.
So if we could look at my daughter here we look at Type of my daughter.
You'll see that it's an array What can we do with an array.
Well my daughter is actually an object and therefore instead of saying and P-Dog reshape we can say
my daughter Daughtry's shape right.
If we just press tab you'll see that the hint gives us a few functions that exist there so I can even
say dot and then press tab and you'll see all these functions that exist inside my daughter.
Right.
And one of them is reshape because it is an object.
And this is an object oriented programming language.
So I can call reshape from within my data so I don't have to go to the package and find the function
in the package what I can do is I can go to the object that already have and call the function from
within the object.
And what that will change is that now I won't have to specify to what Dot I need to apply I don't have
to say my daughter again here.
Right.
And then 5 4 because it would make no sense right.
We were already calling this function from within that object.
So there's no need to specify that we're applying the function to the same object.
All we need to say is what dimensions we want so far on this.
Now you'll see that I get the same result.
So I know this can be a bit tough to get your head around at the start but let's just quickly recap
so what happened here is that one way of finding this function reshape is to go to the package where
it's definitely store because that's where it came from and then apply that function to the object or
the data that we work in with the list and then say how many dimensions are the other ways to say actually
this is not just a list.
It's an area because we created with a function with the range function.
So this is an object that already contains this function.
So and you can check that by pressing a dot and pressing tab.
It already contains this function so we can actually just apply that function from within the object
and that is the beauty of object oriented programming so these objects actually carry around not only
Dadda but also the functions within themselves.
OK.
That is reshape.
And now we're going to look at the one that we're actually more interested in.
We're going to look at the NPR-A function.
So let's create a few lists will say I am happy.
And then I'll say are two what what a day.
And then three is three is going to be just a few numbers so one to three.
All right so let's run that now let's create just look at these lists inside of lists right.
So let's put these lists inside a list enduringly can tell when preparing this.
So here we've got a list of three lists so the first one has words.
I am happy second one has words what a day.
And the third one has numbers you can see that they actually numbers 1 two 3.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to apply the NPR-A function the one we talked about in our presentation
and I'm just going to apply it to this exact list of lists and what I will do is it will combine these
lists into a matrix row by row.
So let's have a look.
So there we go that's the output.
You can see here that it's got an extra bit of extra information that's just telling you what type this
array has.
And it's saying that it's use stands for Unicode five stands for five characters and less than sign
just means less than five Unicode characters in the strings.
So if you don't want to see that just take this and say print and the same thing and there we go.
So that's our matrix.
So it's got three by three right.
And because each element has three or each list had three elements.
And so we and we put them row by row.
So that's the first list that's the second list and that's a third list.
When you put them Roberto together we to a matrix of three by three but what you'll notice here is that
each one of these elements has been changed into a string.
So these are no longer just numbers these are strings.
Well that's because in arrays unlike lists you can only have one type of element and this is very similar
to our that in matrices and are just like vectors and there can only have one type of data in them so
therefore you can convert a word like Watt into a number but it's much easier to convert a number into
a string you just put quotation marks around it.
So that's what happened here.
That's why this matrix is a matrix of strings.
So there we go that's how the NPR-A function works.
And now if we quickly revert back to what we saw here.
Exactly that.
So we've got lists right.
So all of these lists have numbers.
And what is being done is then each of these lists is or these lists are added into a list of lists
.
Here you can see it starts here and God first list second this third list and so on.
And then the NPR-A function is applied and as a result what we get is matrices like that so we get arrays
which are actually matrices because they're two dimensional and all of that is done through the NPR-A
function.
And now we know how it works.
All right so what we learned today was we learned how to reshape data using the reshape function using
C like behavior and Fortran like behavior.
So two different types of ways that matrices populate populated.
Then we also learned about the object oriented programming concept that is contained within the objects
array objects that we can call functions from within them not just go to the package every time.
And also we learned that we can use the NPR-A function and we show how it works.
And finally now we can proceed to the next Tauriel and start working with our data.
And I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy coding