Hello and welcome back to the course and Python programming.
In today's tutorial we're talking about dictionaries and Python quite excited about this tutorial so
let's dive straight into it.
So dictionaries What are they.
I've already said the title over here and what I'm going to do is I'm going to remove the header and
the toolbar so I have some more space.
And before we jump into talking about dictionaries what I want to do is practice a bit of indexation
and that will kind of gradually lead us into that topic.
If you go to the top here we've got some matrices and let's say we to take Kobe Bryant's games for those
seasons so confront is the first is represented by the first row here so you can see Kobe Bryant and
that's how the matrix was created.
So he's at the top.
So we want to take his games or let's say we want to look at the brawne James we want to look at the
number of games for the past for the most recent season in this data set.
Right.
So how do we do.
Would we do that.
We would say games.
That's the whole matrix.
If you run that you'll see that the whole matrix.
And if I just want to access the first draw just say games and then say zero.
Because by an indexation starts from zero so that gives me that first stroke and if I want LeBron James
he's in the third row which beat games too.
And that's his whole row.
If I want just the past season I would look at the last row in this case.
It would be number nine.
So that gives me a 69.
Or another way we could do it is we could access it by a minus sign or you could say minus one.
Right.
It would be 69.
Also just means go from the other side go the right.
What else can we do we could say games to minus one like that.
So that's the same thing that that doesn't really matter which way it's eight games to nine.
We can do many different ways like that.
And what else could we we could for any player we could pick out their values or their rows.
However we want as long as we know kind of the position they are in the Matrix so whether they're numbers
0 1 2 3 for instance for let's say the points matrix would want say Chris Paul's points would have say
1 0 1 2 3 4 5 6.
So he's the 6 and we want the whole roll for example there are say games or points 6 and nothing.
So just like that.
And that is the role for Chris Paul and if we want to serve a year I would say foin So let's say we
want two thousand six for example so then would say this is a stellar 5 she's in the 2006 season so
say 0 1 so be 6 and then 1 then we'd be able to pick out this out.
But as you can see that's quite a tedious process so it is a good thing that we practice how to do the
indexation and I encourage you to practice a bit more and see what other numbers you can pull out of
here.
But at the same time it is a bit tedious to always remember or count the number at which each player
sitting.
And if you've studied Ari you'll remember that in our we have named matrices and named vectors and it's
much easier like that because the matrices actually have the rows and columns of the matrices actually
have names and you can sign those names to be like the player names or the years and therefore it'll
be very easy instead of specifying the number here and here you can specify the names of those dimensions
and it will be much easier.
But in Python it's not as simple as that.
So what I wanted to show you is a way that we can use dictionaries to help us with this a bit of a challenge
so therefore we need to learn a bit about dictionaries and then we'll come back to solving this problem
.
All right so let's have a look at dictionaries.
So what is a dictionary.
How does it work.
What is it used for.
I'll just type up an example and then we'll discuss it right away so we'll say dictionary one equals
and then in curly brackets you know how full lists we have square brackets for dictionaries.
Curly brackets and then also say key one poll on value or valid one and then same thing to pull on Valve
2.
And there's another one the D-3 call on all three.
All right.
So what we have here is three pairs right.
So cue one value one key to value two and three value three.
And what is happening here when I run this we've just created an object which is called a dictionary
and it's kind of like a list.
But the difference is that a list is an ordered set of elements whereas a dictionary is not ordered
.
It's got the key so therefore they are referenced by key.
For example if I have a list I would access elements by their number in a dictionary.
The way to access elements is using their key.
So basically the key is kind of like the label of each value.
Let's have a look an example I would say if I want to access this value so the values are what we are
after the values is the data that has been stored in the dictionary.
So let's say I want to access value to how to access that.
Well I would say dict one and then I would say inside square brackets instead of specifying numbers
.
If I just specify a I would assume if I if this is a list that would be 0 1 2 if I asked for one I'm
going to get an error.
Because you can't do that instead of that for a dictionary you need to specify the actual key of that
value.
So the key of value too is key too.
So let's specify too.
If I run that you will get value to the output right.
Let's look at a different one.
If I say dictionary 1 and then key one I will get value 1.
And if you look at actually dictionary 1 if you look at it you'll see that it's stored exactly like
that so it is always stored in pairs so you can always whenever you say key it will always know which
value you're referring to.
Will give you that value as an output.
All right so and to practice.
Let's do another dictionary here.
That's a dictionary too.
Let's just create a dictionary with countries where the countries are going to be Archy's.
Just to illustrate the point.
So let's say in Germany.
So the value here will be here.
I have been here let's say another one.
France and here.
Maybe instead of the actual just text.
That I've been here I can say two because I've been there two times or something like that.
And then for example let's say Spain I can say true.
So I can do a boolean value.
So if I run this.
This is just to illustrate that dictionaries can have different mixes of values or types just like lists
can in Python.
So if I run a dictionary too you'll see that it's been saved.
And another thing that you'll notice here is that here Germany is in the first place here.
Germany is on the second place.
How come is that right.
So why did France move to the first place all of a sudden.
Well that's because in dictionaries order doesn't matter at all.
There's no no point in order because we can't even access a dictionary based on sequential positioning
of each element.
We can only access elements of a dictionary through their keys anyway so that's why it just stores them
however it's most efficient for Python it doesn't maintain the order in which you specified them.
So that's another thing to remember.
Accessing the elements of this dictionary is still very simple.
So dictionary two square brackets and then let's say I want to get the value for France.
There you go.
I've got the value.
So it's very very simple and that's pretty much all there is to do is of course is a bit more.
But we won't go into too much depth into all of the intricate intricacies of dictionaries and things
that you can do more decrees if we need that.
We'll explore that further down the course or you'll be able to pick that up very quickly because this
is the fundamentals of dictionaries.
What we will do is we will look at how dictionaries are applied in our challenge.
All right so let's go up and here you'll notice that we actually have two dictionaries in our daughters
that we have as stickit.
So the season's dictionary and the player's dictionary predict.
So let's go ahead and explore how they're organized here.
So what you'll see is that the keys here are actually the names of the players.
So Kobe Bryant and the value is zero.
Joe Johnson and the values want LeBron James lvalues to Carmelo Anthony Dahlia's three.
So why would somebody meaning Kyrle create a dictionary which contains values 0 2 9.
What does that give us and the keys or the player names.
So how would that be helpful.
Well if you look at the matrices always Kobe Bryant is on the Zura on the road number zero and always
in every matrix he is on row number zero.
Basically what that is saying and all the other players are also in the same positions in their first
so Joe Johnson's always in the first row.
LeBron James on the second row and so on.
So what that is saying is that this dictionary can help guide us to which role the player is sitting
at.
So as long as we know the name.
So we were looking for information on Carmelo Anthony.
We can use this dictionary to remember that he's on the third row and then use that value to pass it
into the matrix into this matrix or whatever other matrix you want.
And that way we won't have to do that exercise of counting on which row the player is actually sitting
.
So that's the whole point of this victory.
And this one the season's very simple thing.
So 2005 we know that that is the first column.
2006 is column number one 2007s colon number two in every single matrix.
So again we can use this dictionary to access the number of the column based on the key which will be
the year.
So let's have a look at that in action.
It's a very interesting set up so here you kind of like you'd usually expect that this like 0 would
be the key or something like that to get to the Kobe Bryant in the list.
It is you get two words based on numbers here's opposites I know it can be confusing but let's see it
in practice and that will explain how it works.
So let's started with this one and we'll go to the bottom.
We're going back to our challenge so let's add a limiter.
And what are we going to do is we're going to look at Princeton's games right.
Let's look at the game's matrix.
So there's a whole matrix.
So what if I want to access how do I know where Kobe Bryant is sitting.
So I know by default that he's on a roll and miserable Let's say I didn't know that so how would I get
to him.
I would say predict.
So the players dictionary.
And here I would say Kobe Bryant because I remember his name so far on that.
You'll see that I get a value of zero.
So now then and this is my actual index so this is the name of the player.
But then he returns the index of where he's in this just to point this out the dictionary and the matrix
are not interrelated.
They have no connection whatsoever.
It's just a convenient way of structuring this approach that if you remember the name you can look at
the dictionary and find out his position in the matrix though we know he's always in that position in
the Matrix.
And then we can take this value and actually apply it there so then we can say games 0 and run that
.
So that will give us that value.
So if we say we want Derrick Rose right there across there we go.
So he's number eight.
So I want his daughter there it is.
And we can confirm that is true because in this season.
So that's 20 14 13 2012.
He was injured he didn't play any games at all.
So that is definitely Derrick Rose.
So we got his value here and a handy way of doing all of this instead of like looking it up separately
.
How do we do it programatic.
I would take this and place it instead of games instead of the eight they're so from that we are right
.
Do it right away.
So that's the value.
And that's the game so we can look up their dirty clothes and we can do the same thing.
Let's say for the Crows four.
So this was 2014 13 12.
So let's say we want to season 2012.
So again this is our games matrix right.
21 2012 we want to add once again.
This is the row number.
Now we want to add the row numbers in these brackets.
Now we want to add a column number column number so that would be 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 right.
The seventh value in here so far on this I'll get zero right because he didn't play any games.
Instead of saying 7 what I could say similar in a similar fashion I could use the dictionary.
And here I could just say 2012 or and that I get zero right.
Beautiful.
Let's try this for a different metric for same points and same thing.
as Derrick Rose 2012 should be there as well because he didn't play.
Let's look at a different player.
Let's look at Joe Johnson thousand 12 that's how many points he made in that year.
Right.
So if I take that and I remove this bit right this whole bit that's a whole row for Joe Johnson in terms
of points and we can go in and confirm that.
So 1 6 5 3 1 4 to 6.
If We'll look at the points metrics and we look at Joe Johnson 1 6 5 3 1 4 to 6 so that it is indeed
him.
And so that's how we can use dictionaries.
So just to recap these matrices that we creating and they don't have named Rose and named columns.
So in order to find the players we need to count at which row they're sitting and at which column they're
sitting.
And best way for us right now is to go through dictionaries because we also get to practice dictionaries
at the same time.
So what we did is we used the dictionaries that were supplied to us which tell us in which row each
player is sitting and in which column each year is sitting.
And based on those dictionaries we were able to create this kind of approach where we use the name of
the matrix and we're looking at and then we use the first dictionary to look up the player's row and
we use the second dictionary to look up the year the column of the year or the years column that we're
interested in.
All right so that is a very kind of tricky approach I know but the same time it allowed us to practice
with dictionaries and hopefully that shows the dishes aren't that complicated they're pretty straightforward
and can be useful at times.
And as you'll see throughout the section we'll be using them quite a lot.
And that's sort of a series of Tauriel.
I highly encourage you to play around with that and try to perhaps look up other players or maybe combinations
of players in years and in different matrices just to get a grip on dictionaries and practice them because
we will be using them in for the historians and that's for today.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then happy coning