Hello to welcome back to the course in Python programming.
In today's Tauriel we're talking about slicing in Python very juicy word and specific to pie.
Then let's learn what it's all about.
All right.
So here I've got a list.
It's got 10 elements starting from zero all the way 2:09 just got letters A B C D E F G H H H H I J
up to 10 letters.
All right.
So what is slicing.
Well the concept of slicing starts with this operator.
The colon.
What is the colon all about.
Well the colon has two parts to it actually three parts to call and solve and then two parts on either
side on the left and on the right.
So basically you can put something on the left and you can put a value on the right.
Now if you don't put anything by default and by the way the concept what we are talking about in this
whole presentation is what we're putting inside the square brackets so we practice the square brackets
previously a bit and we were just putting numbers and maybe negative numbers.
So you can actually put a colon and two numbers on either side into the square brackets.
Now I'm not specifying the square brackets here just for simplicity sake but we're going to assume that
everything we're doing is going on inside the square brackets and that is yielding results and we'll
see that when we move onto the practical part.
All right.
So the colon if you don't put anything on either side of the call and so you just use the cold by itself
it assumes by default everything.
So it will assume that you want to slice this list from the start to the finish.
And slicing basically means taking a subset out of a list so what we used to call in our subsetting
in Python is called slicing.
Now if I specify something on the left to for example.
Right.
What does that mean.
That means where I want to end my extraction as always in Python.
That actually means not the actual 7 but the number before it's not including that 7.
Similar to what we saw with the range function that we want to go up to 7 but not including 7.
And that means we want to extract these five elements one to check C D E F G and to call on 7 means
extract elements 2 3 4 5 6.
So important to remember that 7 is not inclusive.
Now let's move on.
What else can we learn about slicing.
Well we've already learned about negative indexation right.
So let's introduce our negative indexation here.
There it is.
Minus One two three four five six seven eight nine 10.
Now we can use negative indexation in slicing as well.
It's quite an intuitive thing.
All right.
So if you can use positive indexation why countries negative indexation if they have the same rights
.
Well let's have a look at how it happens.
Let's say I want to replace that too with a minus 8.
I can do that this notation minus eight call and seven is exactly the same as the one I had before to
call on seven.
You just have to look at the positive indexation of negative indexation and you can easily just replace
any positive index with its associated net negative index.
Very simple concept.
There's nothing hidden to it.
No complexities.
You just take the positive index you look at the same negative and have the same elements has and you
can replace it.
So now case we can also replace the 7 with minus 3.
Same thing we will get exactly the same result C D E F G.
All right.
So that's slicing with negative indices.
And now let's move on to some advance slicing.
So what's Ivonne slicing all about Carol.
Sounds pretty serious.
Well there's not much seriousness to it.
There's just a secret part to the colon and that is its twin brother the second colon.
Yes he can actually specify two colons in a row and that means you will have three spots now.
No the first two spots work exactly the same way.
That's where you want to start the second spot is where you want to end so let's go all the way up to
Element 9 and not inclusive.
And so what does a third colon do then.
Well the third colon specifies the step.
You can probably already tell the similarity to the range of function that we used before we also had
start finish and step.
So same thing here so start to finish.
And what step do you want to specify by default.
It's the step of one and that's how you get all elements if we specify something like 2.
That means we only want every second element and that will give us all of the even elements because
we're starting at an even number and well it'll give us all of the even elements except for the very
starting element of a sell us all that even elements between 2 and 8 including 8.
In this case because we went all the way up tonight.
So this notation to Colon nine colon too will return elements to 4 6 8.
And that means the letters C E G and I will be extracted from a list.
Now as you can see it's very very straightforward very simple things and it's just a matter of practicing
to get very comfortable with them and get them to an intuitive level so let's go ahead and do some practice
.
All right there we go.
So there's our code.
Let's start by creating our list.
We'll call it letters and we'll call it would create exactly that list that we spoke about just now
.
All right.
So there is a list.
Let's run it.
Now if I look at letters there it is.
Now as discussed if I say letters then square brackets and then I just say the colon.
So with nothing on either side that means start at the beginning.
So basically this means start at the beginning and at the end of your list.
Run that.
And once again of course the spaces are not necessary you can just say call on or for the spaces you
get the full list.
OK so that's a full very very big slice.
All right so now if I say something else let's say letters and I want to start at two and go to the
very end.
I can do that so I start at sets.
ERO that's the one that's two and go to the very end.
So as you can see that's exactly what I expect.
Same thing I can go letters and start at the beginning but only up till I'm in number seven.
So that is 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 so not including 7 so move back a bit and take those elements and that's
exactly what I got.
AB CD g.
Ok so now let's look at another example that same letters 2 2 7.
That's the example that we had.
Again there's all letters.
So that's 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 Remember 7 is all inclusive so we get C D E F G just as we said in the presentation
.
Beautiful and now this practice said negative indexation let's say letters and we'll start with what
was it.
So two we can replace with what can replace two of minus one minus two three four five six seven eight
.
We can replace with minus eight and go up to seven so we should get exactly the same result.
Let's have a look.
Actually let's zoom in a bit.
There you go letters minus eight seven.
So there we go that's exactly that same result.
Now we can look at replacing seven as well.
So we can say minus 8 to minus 3.
So there we go c d e f g.
Beautiful same result again.
All right.
And what else did we want to look at.
And now we wanted to look at some advanced advanced slicing.
All right.
What did we want to have a look at.
Let's say letters and we'll look at exactly that example that we spoke about so to call on 9 that gives
us a CD G H I.
But this time we want same thing letters to call them a 9 and we want a step up two.
So C E G I.
Let's look at letters again and see what we got we got we started this as 0 1 2.
We started here see and we got C E N G and then we got I.
Because this is element number nine.
Go back to 8.
And that was our step of to beautiful.
So that is how we work with the advanced colon as well.
And what else we can do is we can specify for instance a step or three if we wanted to we could say
letters brackets and then just say three.
So we want to start at a step of three.
So 1 2 3 1 2 3 1 2 3.
So as you can see we've got four elements are there are four step three so you can do all sorts of different
combinations like that and allows you to slice your list very very quickly and efficiently like that
.
So have a play around with that.
That is what slicing is all about.
And I've got a little challenge for you try specifying following up on what we talked about last about
exploring and asking questions.
Try specifying a negative step for your Slice see what happens there.
So what would a negative step do so if you for example just leave it like that exactly like that and
specify here minus one.
What will happen.
And based on that try to experiment and put in some values at where you want to start where you want
to finish and a negative step.
It'll be quite interesting very similar to what we just discussed is just going to be a bit backwards
.
That's the hint I'm sure you'll be able to figure it out and I'll leave you on that note until next
time happy coding
.