Hello and welcome back to A Course in Python programming.
In today's tutorial we're going to talk about creating a stacked distribution chart.
If we're not going to just talk about it we're going to learn how to create that type of chart.
And I wanted to warn you right away that this tutorial is going to be harder and more complex than usual
but I'm sure we'll manage it just fine.
We've learned quite a lot about Python and it'll be an interesting challenge for us.
And why will it be a bit harder.
Well because we're going to need to switch on some of our creativity and come up with a coding solution
techniques that we've talked about before.
So let's dive straight into it.
We're going to create a new Actually a few new cells here and what we want to plot.
Well what do we want.
But let's start with Peel T Dot HST so histogram and as we discussed before we already plotted for example
audience rating and critique creating.
How about this time we plot a budget in millions.
Let's have a look at that.
So here we've got we need to specify an object right so we can say each one equals BLT just budget in
millions right.
Or instead of that we can say all t dots show so we don't see that additional information.
So there is a budget of millions.
But what if we want to see that budget in millions for a certain genre.
So if we want to say a certain genre Well we already know how to do that we first need to filter our
data set right so this is one of the first technique that we're going to introduce here that we've learned
before but that we're going to introduce into this challenge.
So how do we filter daughter said hey simple.
We create a filter we say movie genre equals for instance drama.
And then this filter.
So if I just run this line now I'll just get this false structure to a false filter.
And how do I apply it to actually filter my door frame.
Also movies.
And then I put this in the square brackets like that.
So there we go.
And now I've got to just movies that are from the drama genre.
And then what I want to do is I want to say Dot budget millions.
So because this is a new doorframe now I can apply the same rules as previously so I can look up this
budget billions call.
If I run that there's my budget millions column and now I can take this cut it and put it into here
instead of this budget millions column from the whole doorframe.
I can apply or get the budget million Skolem from the subset a data frame.
So if I run this this is a budget millions for a drama I can change this for two action for example
so far on this now I'll get a different chart.
That is the chart for action.
So let's copy that.
That's done on the say thriller.
You can see that now they're kind of like adding up on to one shot.
So that's what happens in Python you creating a plot and then you want to show it that's when you show
everything and you're just adding things on top of each other.
So if I say drama you'll see that drama is hidden behind there.
Then you've got action which usually have higher budgets so maybe just change them around.
So they got the action.
That's drama.
That's a thriller and you can see they all have different beans so I can say bin's equals 15 to make
them look better.
Fifteen ands actually.
You never know if you look better at this stage.
OK so it does look a bit better.
So there you go that's how we can create these histograms.
But at the same time this is not exactly what we're after.
As you can see the histograms are overlaid one after another they're behind each other.
What we want is we want them to be stacked.
We want these bars to be on top of each other and to add up rather than hiding each other and that's
a very different type of chart that we're going to create.
So how do we go about creating this chart.
Well in order to create the chart what we can do is we can use the list function but instead of passing
it just one column or one list of data what we can do is we can pause it a list of columns so we can
say Budget millions for Thriller than budget millions for drama.
So I'll give you an example to make this a bit more evident what we're going to do is we're going to
take this these two.
So there's drama budget million for drama and the take action to stick it out.
So there's a budget million for action.
So I'm going to put these two in a list.
There's there's my first square bracket.
Then there's my coma.
Then let's put this here and there's my second square record right.
So this is now a list inside this list we've got element number one.
So it's a list as well.
It's got or it's it's a series of data and then we've got another series of data here.
So now if I take this list of two elements and I put it in here and I run this well and then I do feel
t dot show you'll see that we've got the bars but they're not stacked.
That's not a problem we'll just impurity here.
As an other parameter I will just say stacked he calls true so as you can see now they're stacked.
So that's what we are aiming for.
But the thing is that we've got way more genres as you remember we have seven genres and if I continue
typing up the score.
So for instance I could put the backslash here move this to a new line put a backslash there move this
new line.
Yes I can manually do it I can add a few more into this list right.
So that's my list over there that's where it ends that's where it starts.
That's the start of the list as the end of the list I could add a few more I could add the the whole
seven.
But what if we had 100 What if we had a lot.
So in this particular instance what I would like to do is I would like to use this opportunity to practice
on how to solve challenges like this.
This is a coding challenge.
It's not really a dot a science related challenge.
It's actually a coding related challenge and it will be interesting to see how we can solve what we
can come up with to solve this challenge.
Well what would we do if we wanted to do this manually.
The way to the way I think about these things what I would do if I wanted to do this manually.
Well I would take this and out another call my Here put a backslash and then output enter another one
right side and another one here and I'll change drama to Thriller for instance and then I'll keep doing
that so I would repetitively copy paste.
And that feels a lot like a monkey's task.
Had a monkey's job when your copy pasting and just changing one little thing.
So this could be comedy.
What do we say about monkey tasks or repetitive tasks like that.
We said that you can automate these things that you can use cycles or loops in the programming language
that you're in.
In this case in Python you can use loops to automate that.
For that to happen for you instead of doing it manually.
So let's see how we can do it in this particular case.
All right.
So first thing we need going to need to do is we're going to need to understand what do we need to iterate
and what we need to iterate is the genre.
So we need to go through the genre we need a variable that is going to change with the genre.
Right.
So let's go ahead and start trying to figure out how we can iterate that variable.
So we'll create a loophole say for g n so there's going to be a variable for the genre in and then we
need to iterate that variable over the different genres.
We don't unfortunately we don't have a list of these genres.
So how can we get a list of these genres.
Well we really have the answer if we scroll up to the top you'll see that using this approach we can
get all of the unique categories in a certain column and in certain categorical variable that's why
it's it's valuable thing that we have genre as a category because we can then call this construct and
that will give us a list of all of the genres in our data set action adventure comedy drama horror romance
and Thriller.
So if I go ahead and copy this and now place it here don't forget to call on after that.
Then would just create a loop for variable Shawn which is going to Orji and which is going to iterate
over the different values or categories of genre that we have and to check it we can just print it out
.
We can say print G and so was going to happen is the end is going to take the value of action it's going
to get printed then it's going to move on to the next value whether comedy and there's going to get
print that there's going to move onto the next one thriller and there's going to get printed silver
on this.
You'll see ogen action adventure comedy drama horror romance and Thriller.
So we've successfully created a loop that iterates over the different categories.
So that's a great start.
We already have this value so you kind of can see the logic behind this.
And again this is not really a data science challenge or programming challenge so it's not absolutely
necessary to be able to create this you can always create this manually but at the same time it's very
convenient to be able to automate a lot of your work while you're doing a science task and that's what
is so exciting as well because you get to combine the two fields.
You're doing some analytics so you doing data signs and symptoms you're leveraging the power of programming
to help automate your tasks and make your analysis more efficient.
So we've already got a variable that iterates over the different genres.
How can we now create this whole construct that will create a stacked bar chart for us using that variable
.
Right so what's the next step.
We're breaking this problem down into steps.
We're doing it step by step.
All right.
So what do we need ultimately is we need this list right.
So we need people to just requires this list that we were about to create manually so that list over
there has got one series to series three series four series of data is actually going to have seven
.
So what we want from a loop is to create this list for us.
And that's exactly what we do.
It's very simple.
We're going to take this line will actually work we introduce.
First we're going to copy this loop before this loop we're going to create an empty list and say list
one equals list so you can either create the empty list like that or you can just put the square brackets
just simply like that.
Meaning that's it.
It's a list which is empty.
For this method actually you can use any or any one of them.
So create an empty list before.
And then inside your loop where are we going to do is we're going to add onto this list so we're going
to say list one would append.
And then here in the brackets are you going to need to specify what you want to append.
And let's go ahead and copy this what we want to append.
Is this right.
So we're going to append it there so we're appending this series we're adding something onto the right
side of the list we're at every time this loop fires off.
Going to add a new element to the list and the element is going to contain.
In this case a series from our movies data frame where genre equals action.
But the trick is that we don't want to just action.
We want all the genres we're in take genre and we're going to change it here so every time a genre changes
this condition changes and we're going to pand and you series so first I'm going to append all of the
budgets for action movies and for adventure movies and comedy movies drama movies and so on.
So hope you're following along.
It is quite complex what we are building but nevertheless it does combine all of the knowledge we've
already acquired in this course of all all everything that it requires.
We've already discussed in this course.
It's a good practice exercise for us.
All right so there we go that's how we're adding a new series onto list.
Every single time.
And now so if I just run this line and then at the end I'm going to print print least one.
I'm just going to expand this and you'll see that list 1.
What does it have.
So that's the square bracket.
That's the start of the list.
This.
That's just the index that's the main Raley's of 20 million two hundred million thirty five million
.
That's the action movies budgets.
And you can see that dot dot dot.
And then it goes.
And then voila.
And so that was the first Parsa had 105.
No actually that's that's it.
That's where it ends.
That's the next one.
This is where the next list or the next series starts and the list goes and goes up to there.
Then the next series and all this starts.
Then you've got the dot dot dot.
Then the next series and all this.
So you can see that this is indeed a list of multiple series of different budget and there that's the
end of the list that square brackets over there.
So looks like we've built what we wanted.
And how did that happen.
Well the reason here is that a pen is one of those functions that does indeed change the underlying
objects so we're not just create adding something to the list and returning that value we're actually
modifying the underlying objects a list one does get and new series added to it every time.
So so basically what I'm saying is that there's no need to say list one cause list one pen.
So there's no need in saying that because this function doesn't change the underlying object so we don't
need to print a list once for on the line.
And now all we have to do is we just simply say we can say that in the same cell we can say age equals
Piazzi dog hist list 1 so far on that you'll see that we've got those bars together.
They're not stacked but that's very easy to correct.
We just say that Sabin's equals 30 and say stacked goes true.
So if you're on that you'll see now they're stacks.
Which is exactly what we're after.
Else we can do is we can see the gaps between the bars.
If you don't want to see the ball gaps between the bars per shift tab you'll see that there's a parameter
here are with so are with the calls 1 run that you'll see another close together so our with is what's
the ratio of the designated space the bar should take so if it's one and it takes up 100 percent of
the space and means that there'll be no gap between them.
All right.
So that's a great start.
So it's just a start.
We're nearly done.
So that's that's a great progress.
And then of course the main part here is is this line which helps us get rid of this task where we have
to manually rewrite multiple times of the same code.
It basically puts it into a loop for us that's the heart of this code that we've created.
And one more thing that's missing is the labels or the legend as you can see we've got different colors
here we don't understand what color represents what.
So how do we add legend here.
Well belted out ha Estes.
The histogram function has a legend function label parameter here.
If you scroll down you'll be able to read about it.
Let's find it here somewhere.
There it is.
So label string or non optional string or sequence of strings to match multiple datasets.
Bar charts yield multiple and so on.
So basically you need to pass sequence of strings into here.
How do we do that.
Well we need to create it first so we integrate a list and say my labels equals a list.
Again empty.
And then here in our loop what are we going to do is we're going to say my labels got panned and we
just want to pen the genre.
So this is a bit easier.
We just want to pen the actual genre into a list and here we go and say label.
He calls my labels.
If I run that that's ads the labels to the chart.
What we need to do is we need to show the legend.
So you need to say appeal to you.
Just to add legend and now we'll see the legend and to get rid of this what we need to do is of course
say guilty or not show.
There we go.
So that's our action movies over there.
That's our adventure movies.
Then you've got the comedy movies then you've got the drama and you could tell that that's how the order
they built they're stacked on top of each other in that in reverse order to what's here.
So the top one is at the bottom.
Second one is second from bottom cut comedy drama horror romance and Thriller.
So again the charts are much more crisp if you zoom out so you can see here that it's as crisp.
Probably that's what it's like on your machine.
I just it is I mean it's how we can see the code better but that's a lovely charge.
And as you can tell it's not that complex of a or something like that.
It would be very quick to create an Tablo or it would be not as difficult to create in our IT WOULD
BE quite fast in Python unfortunately have to unless you use some sort of pre coded solution you need
to go through some hoops to jump through some hoops to create something that and it's just a matter
of using the right tool for the right job.
In this case maybe it was worthwhile to create the same chart in another tool but nevertheless we powered
through it and we did get some really good hands on practice with loops and other concepts in overcoming
this challenge.
So hopefully you're able to follow along and create this wonderful beautiful chart as well.
So this is going to be our chart number four.
We're going to include in the report.
There we go that's one of the methods of creating stacked histograms in Python and only pausing on the
next tutorial Until then hepi coding.