Hello and welcome back to the course on Python programming.
Previously we spoke about functions in Python and today we're going to even further expand that topic
and we're going to talk about packages in Python.
All right let's get started.
So what is in these packages these so-called packages.
There is a package there's a package there's another package what's inside them while what's inside
is Blender's.
And you're right you guessed that we when we say Blender's we actually mean functions and sometimes
there's other things like maybe Klaas's or dadda and maybe some other things as well but mostly what's
in these packages is different functions which we want to import.
We want to add onto our program onto our code that we're creating.
So we can use them because as we discussed the core of Python comes with a very limited set of functions
so you have the minimum the maximum or you have some other functions but you don't even have things
like that you can to take a square root out of a number without including a package first and that is
how Python was designed.
And it's just something that you kind of get used to have time.
So whenever you need a certain functionality you just include that package and package will implement
certain things that you might in your code for instance package on the left might be for working with
big data sets a package in the middle might be or processing.
Twitter data the package on the right might be for creating bezels nations packages of in their purpose
and therefore it's actually quite good because you don't have the packages and the functions that you
don't need in your code you only include the ones that you actually need and makes your coding a very
lean process.
All right.
So solidify this let's look at the official definitions because we actually have two things that we're
going to be talking about.
We have modules and package are the words that are going to be hearing.
So you know how I don't like text on my slides but this is the one time when it's definitions it's a
good idea to look through it.
So a module is simply a file containing Python definitions functions and statements putting code into
modules is useful because of the ability to import the module functionality into your script a Python
session.
And here I Python's I see Jupiter notebooks now a package is just a way of collecting related modules
together within a single tree like hierarchy very complex package like an umpire scrapie have hundreds
of individual modules so putting them into a directory like structure keeps things organized and avoids
name collisions.
So there we go.
It's just a difference between modules or packages which is going to stick with the term package just
to make things simple.
All right so what are the steps of putting a package into your code including that functionality that
you're after.
Well the steps are actually very very trivial very simple and Erina want us to get this down pat so
that going forward we're very confident with what we're doing.
And we understand it very well because there's nothing complicated about it at all.
So step one find the package and it's an optional step because if you already know what package you
need like if you're just after cell functionality then you'll need to find what package your office
or what package implements that functionality.
If you already know what package you're after for instance it's numb pie or Pandurs or some other package
then you don't need to perform their superior know what package you need then you need to install the
package onto a machine.
That's step two and step three is you either import the package or you just import a certain function
from that package that your office or if you don't need the whole package.
As simple as that.
Now let's go through the steps one by one.
All right so step one find the package where would you find a package let's say you know that you need
a package for processing videos or for a package for analyzing handwritten text or something like that
where would you go looking for it.
Well the best place to start looking for a package is good hub.
Good how is a repository of code where people in simple terms they just code together and they develop
projects and work on different programming languages and packages for those programming languages and
so on.
So you can go to get help and look for a package there and we'll see how to do it.
I know it might sound a bit scary at the start and you might have heard about her before but don't worry
I'll show you around just now I'll show you in practice how to perform a search there and then step
two is install the package.
And there's two different approaches one for Windows one for Mac.
They're actually the same approach but just because of the different operating systems it looks a bit
different so for on windows you need to go to your start menu and in the search start typing in Anaconda
and this is if you installed Python through the method that we discussed at the start of the course
through the Anaconda installation.
If you didn't then you would need to in sort of an icon to look for your command line.
So just type in a command instead of an icon.
But if you installed how we installed the distribution of and at the start of a course and then just
follow along here.
Type in Anaconda into your search and what you will see is a Anaconda command prompt.
So I'm just going to zoom in here so you can see better there is Anaconda.
That sort of started typing and then that's what we got that it called the command prompt.
So if you select that then you'll get a black screen like this.
So don't worry about typing in kind of that Conder don't worry about that which you will need to type
in is either Khanda install package name and package name should be replaced with the package teacher
.
After that you won't install or if that doesn't work.
So if you can install it through Quander that's your first resort if that doesn't work then your second
resort.
You should try pip install package name and that should work.
Most of the time.
OK so that's how it's use or package on Windows and that's installing it onto your machine so you have
to have it on your computer in your python distribution on your computer or for you to actually be able
to then imported into your code.
So this is still step two and step two on a Mac you look for in sort of the Konda command prompt which
you look for is the terminal so just press comment space on your Mac and start typing in terminal.
This should come up once again.
Click that screen and section or black it's white on a Mac and there you go in that command prompt.
You need to type in again once again Conda install package name or you should type in people install
package name so try the first one and then if that doesn't work try the second one.
A quick note on the terminal in Mac.
If you are running Jabra or notebooks and so if you want cheaper notebooks using the terminal then you'll
find that it's actually occupying the terminal and you can't type in more stuff into the terminal in
order to create a second window for your terminal.
When you are in the terminal press command t on your MacBook and I'll create a second window and there
you will be able to type in these instructions.
All right so that's step two and step three import.
So as we discussed you cannot import the package or import it just a certain function and to do that
you either type in the code import scrape the for instance scrape is the name of the package so import
and the name of the package that you're after or as an example you type in from that package or package
dot something in the package important the function that your after says a bit more advanced but that
helps you avoid importing the whole package just imports.
The one specific thing that you need from the package.
All right so hopefully that all makes sense as you can it's a pretty straightforward process.
So let's go ahead and try it out in practice now.
All right.
First things first.
So here's good hub and let's say I want to look for something that is a package to do a web scraping
so hero type in web scraping and then I'll just click enter to search and as you can see here now I've
got all these different packages now.
So like Python at the top or just find Python here to make sure you're looking for Python packages and
then just select something from here so I'm going to scrape quite a popular Web scraping package here
it's got some information I know it can be quite a bit overwhelming all the things you see on good hub
whoops.
I clicked there by accident.
So all the things that can get good help can be quite overwhelming.
But nevertheless if you scroll down.
Usually they have quite a good description on how to install the package and things like that.
So here you got the quick way pip install Scrappy so when.
We talked about.
Also you can go to the Web site just check out scray p here they've got a whole Web site here and you
can see them.
They're using imported scrape.
What we talked about and here they've got to install scrape is instructions are all over the place.
OK.
So that's a good start.
We found the package that we want.
Now let's go and install it on a machine.
Remember Windows and Mac is different.
I'm going to be doing this on a Mac so I'm going to go to the terminal Here's the terminal window as
you can see it's currently used to around my Jupiter notebook so let's zoom in here a little bit so
we can see better here it's running Megilp in a notebook cycle really type in anything more so I'm just
going to click inside and press commentary and that creates a second window and I can use this.
So first thing I'm going to try is I'm going to say Khanda install scrapin just to see if that runs
.
Let's have a look.
So you can see now we're just going to click yes here because it's just asking for an update.
And as you can see it's actually installing this package through Conda is give it some time.
There we go.
So now if I tried doing the same thing Khanda install Scray be as good a second you can see that the
second time it didn't go.
It didn't run because all rechristen packages already installed so that's a good way to check if the
package is installed.
And so basically what happened is we installed that package through the Konda distribution.
Sometimes that works and that's great.
If it doesn't work then you resort research the second method which is just pip install scrapin.
And so if I run that again you can see that all of this code is just here but it says requirements are
already satisfied.
Meaning that all of these elements have been installed already.
OK.
So that's how you install the machine.
Hopefully you are able to follow along even if you're using Windows.
It's very similar you just use the Konda command line.
All right so that is installing onto the machine.
Now let's go to Jupiter.
And here we going to see how we can import it.
So let's say this is a program which we are creating some script that we're writing.
How do we import the package that we just install what we need to do is we need to type in import scraping
.
And if you're on shift enter just give to a second.
You see that that ran successfully.
So if I didn't have the names or if I had if I typed in scrape the test one two three if I run a try
around that you'll see I'll get an error because that package does not exist or that module does not
exist but because it ran well that means scrape it was imported successfully or the other way that we
talked about we can say import scrape the crawler from EMP scrape pleuro cruller or import Karole or
process.
So inside scray P There is a module or a called crawler and inside that module there is a function in
this case that are actually a functions a class that we're importing but that doesn't really matter
.
The same process as you can see that got imported as well.
Now what we Al-Samoud do we can just to check that everything is done.
Well we can say scray P for example Daut and then press tab and as he can see he'll come up with all
of these different suggestions.
So Spider field form request core Krol are and so so you can see cruller is that same Krol that we have
there.
So as you can see the suggestions are coming up so that means that your kernel that is running now can
actually see that module and it's working and you can work with it or you can try cruller process and
you press dot and you'll see all these methods inside that Clauss spiders crawl crawlers and so on.
Start stop.
So it's actually seeing what's going on.
And so you can start working with that in your code.
There we go that's how we import packages into our code.
And another thing I want to mention is that first of all if you are using an I.D. The good news is so
in an integrated development environment for like for example pi charme or Eclipse or some other environment
where you're actually coding so if you're not coding in Jupiter notebooks but in ID the good news is
that the steps are exactly the same.
So in order to find install and import the package you just perform exactly the same steps and also
a lot of the time these packages are already included in the content distribution.
So I can easily just go and say imports and umpire right now I don't need to install it because it is
included in the Anaconda distribution.
That's beauty of Anaconda because it already aggregates those most popular packages so you don't have
to go around looking for them installing them and only then importing them.
But now that you know this whole process the three steps it's not a big problem anymore it's comparable
at all even if it's not included in Anaconda.
You can just go and install the package onto your machine just like we did now and then import it.
Hopefully you found this tutorial useful.
And my goal for this tutorial was to make sure that going forward you're 100 percent comfortable with
packages in Python you completely know the ins and outs and what's going on when you install when you
port and things like that.
Hopefully we achieved that goal and going forward you will be 100 percent confident dealing of packages
and look forward to seeing next turtle.
Until then heavy coding