So what do the demand types, operations,
projects, and initiatives, all have in common?
Well, you need to collect your demand items,
they must be organized with value and benefits,
they are tracked and made available for everyone to see and understand,
and lastly, and maybe even most importantly,
you must prioritize them.
The outcome of these simple steps is a collection of well
organized and tracked demand items in priority order.
So at a macro level, demand for operations,
projects, and initiatives all need to follow this general process.
Now let's go to more detail for all three demand types.
Operations Demand Management.
This section contains my recommendations of the basics you need
for setting up your operations demand process.
Think of this as a starter kit or approach for you and your team,
and modify it as you see fit.
Okay, let's get started.
Let's define, in general, what ticket means.
For this course,
a ticket is a representation of an instance of potential work to perform,
that is a demand request.
For each ticket,
you must capture key attributes that'll help you make good
decisions about what to do with this ticket.
Sometimes the term ticket is also called an issue,
requirement, feature, or other term.
Call it anything you want,
as long as you understand it is a unit of potential work in your demand queue.
Okay, let's talk about where do these tickets come from.
If you give users or customers access to an issue or ticketing system,
well, that's great.
They can start the process there by entering their own tickets,
and if not,
all these are sources of tickets and they must map or
be transposed into a real ticket, a potential unit of work.
So tickets could come initially from: verbal discussions,
phone calls, emails, form-based systems or applications,
and of course, tickets themselves, and everything becomes a ticket,
period.
Everything should drive and become a ticket and that way you can
collect them and track them and manage them.
So now that we have a bunch of tickets flowing in, what is the next step?
Let's find out.
Operations for New Tickets.
Here's the process.
This slide represents a new ticket.
They have come in from the potential demand sources on the previous slide.
The new ticket queue or backlog must be monitored by someone
or a team or maybe alerts are sent to someone so they know
something requires assessing.
We sometimes call this assessment triage,
and you may have heard of that term in those medical or hospital shows
on TV when the patient comes into the emergency room.
You want to perform this triage, if possible as a team,
but maybe based on resources, a single person may do this.
With some of the new tools today, you could use Jira,
for example,
and then use Slack to have a quick call or video or shared
screen to quickly assess with others.
Certainly there are many tools to do this.
Now the ticket can be triaged into one of three cases.
Case number one, the one ticket belongs to another group or team.
In other words, it doesn't really belong to you.
It's not part of your responsibility.
So you want to reassign it to another queue or another backlog
since it does not apply to you and your team at all or maybe the
ticket is just not applicable or bogus or it is returned to the
ticket creator with a reason.
Now case two, the ticket does belong to your team,
and then it is super-hot production issue.
So you want to assign it immediately to a person
responsible to get this ticket done.
This means you have to have some documentation and
process for triage to handle this.
Case three, the ticket belongs to your team as well,
but it's not critical like in case number two.
You want to place it in the backlog queue,
and if possible, add a few attributes like a rough estimate,
maybe it's small, medium, large or jumbo.
I like to call this case the normal case since most
tickets will likely drop here.
So we have three cases: doesn't belong to you at all in case one,
not applicable, case two, it's a production issue,
you have to assign this ASAP, as soon as possible,
and begin working, in other words, it's approved and in work,
it never had a moment to be in your backlog,
and then the normal case, case three, is what I call your normal ticket.
It goes into the backlog for later grooming.
Now this is just a simple high-level process to give you
the general essence of the workflow.
Certainly yours may be more elaborate. Now let's move on to operations backlog and tickets in the next section.