Metrics are critical to collect in order to make solid and
informed decisions about your potential demand.
Let's look at a few examples.
Here's an example of operational tickets by category.
So if you are using a quality ticket tracking system, there are many benefits.
Here is a pie chart looking at where the operational tickets are coming from.
We can see that 40% are tied to the category of Ecommerce.
You may want to talk to the business managers in those areas,
find out what's happening.
Maybe there was a new system lag,
or maybe there are several new hires brought on board
and they have lots of questions.
And then try and put together a CAP,
a Correction Action Plan to address and then track against.
Secondly, you could also talk to the lead players for the other large categories,
Security, Engineering, and the Sales App,
to show them how much of your resources are consumed,
and to find out more about their business and what they may need in the future.
Based on this number and conversations with your key business customers,
you may want to move resources around and/or possibly hire
more in order to provide better service.
And again, if you don't track your work, you cannot do this.
Here's a thought: how about prevent tickets from coming
into the queue in the first place?
It is great that you can handle more tickets,
maybe helps more people and provide better service,
but don't forget about looking at the root cause of why the
ticket was issued in the first place.
Now, this spot does not apply to initiatives or projects.
My belief is that the backlog grooming will handle this,
and unworthy projects will not be approved.
But operations is different, and let's look at some ideas.
Forecasting Operations Demand Maybe you can do some things to
better forecast upstream operations demand.
Is there new business or significant changes to the business,
even mergers and acquisitions?
If so,
then you want to get ahead of that and figure out how those
business drivers will affect your ability to handle the
additional operational work load.
Do not wait for the wave to hit you.
Also, education and training can help mitigate and reduce support.
New hires can have lots of issues and questions.
New system roll outs can be very disruptive or large system
upgrades can drive more operational support.
Maybe provide online and self serve support as well
with online user documentation, and even Wikis are great sources of information.
Self provisioning.
For example, many obstacles, could be things like, "I need an I.
D.
", "I need roles or permissions,
" "Set this up so I can access this system or that system,
" let's see if any of those things can have self serve provisioning.
And this will mitigate the need for a call in the first place. Let us look at a few more examples.