Grooming for Operations.
This section contains the definition and process of grooming,
which is a great tool to help you manage the demand processes,
but first let's define in general what grooming
means so we're all on the same page.
Grooming is the process of reviewing items in the backlog to ensure the backlog
contains the appropriate items and that information or attributes are all
filled in and that the items at the top of the backlog are the ones of the
highest priority and are ready to be worked.
Now let's take a deeper look at the grooming process.
So we have our backlog ticket queue.
These are our normal tickets as I call them,
and as I noted in the previous section,
tickets that really were not part of our responsibility were already routed
to other queues and any hot production issues that were immediately
approved to be worked are not in this list as well.
So now we will perform our grooming that we defined in the previous slide.
And if you can perform as a team, since no one person knows everything,
that would be the best,
but sometimes teams cost a lot of money and it may just be one key individual.
That's your call.
Now some tickets might be set with a status of hold.
This means you don't have enough information to determine its
priority or what exactly needs to be done,
so the triage or grooming team may take the next step to perform further
analysis and or discussions with the ticket creator.
Again,
you're trying to fill out those attribute items to make sure you have enough
information to make this determination of this backlog item.
Next, reprioritize.
So you want to adjust priority order of the ticket in the backlog,
and in this case, if it is not approved,
maybe the priority is not high enough or you do not
have enough resources quite yet.
Next, reprioritize and approve to be worked,
that is the resources are assigned and a status is set to work in progress,
or W-I-P, WIP.
Lastly,
this branch is where the ticket is determined based on the attributes
you have collected and your team's operations versus project's threshold
to move the ticket to the project backlog.
Stay tuned.
I will discuss this move in the next section.
Okay, now let's summarize this process on the next slide.
Here's a summary of the grooming process.
Assemble the daily grooming team, keep at the right size,
just the key people, so other people are still working on the tickets.
Review production-issue tickets first.
These are the tickets that came in, and based on the criticality of the tickets,
were immediately approved and worked, like a system outage,
for example.
So take a look at any of those that are in work at this time to ensure
adequate resources are assigned and attention is focused.
Next, review new tickets, complete,
filling out all the attributes so you can assess the ticket or issue better,
then assign its priority.
Now review the top n-tickets.
Maybe that is the top three or five, or whatever works for you.
Approve tickets from the backlog, if appropriate.
That means they're ready to work.
Review tickets in work.
Discuss their status.
Maybe modify resources,
and even stop working on tickets if you need to reallocate
those resources to other more pressing tickets.
Don't be shy.
Don't be afraid.
If other priorities come up,
stop working on certain tickets and reallocate those resources to the priority.
All right. Now let's move on to project demand management in the next section.