Initiative Demand Management.
This section contains my recommendations of the basics you need
for setting up your initiative demand process.
Think of this as a starter kit or approach for you and
your team and modify it as you see fit.
Remember, no one process can be applied to every situation.
Now we are on the other side of the spectrum.
This is the big, chunky, and quite frankly,
the area where you can make and save the most money for your company or
organization and have by far the greatest impact to the business,
the employees and the customers.
What do you think is the current perception of IT by the business?
Well, let's see.
13% of business executives view IT as a business leader.
Wow, only 13%.
87% of (chuckles) business executives do not view IT as business leaders.
I think that is appalling.
Why do you think that is?
How can you be a strategic IT business leader yourself
and create and drive initiatives?
This module will help you get there.
Now let's see how you can overcome and change that perception.
How to overcome the perception that only 13% of business
executives view IT as a business leader.
So here are a few things you need to do.
Align your demand with business initiatives.
Make sure your demand is always in alignment with the
business strategies of the company.
Next, you want to add value to the business.
Don't just do cool, techie stuff.
Be sure it helps the business.
Next, increase revenue, avoid costs, improve service.
This trilogy should be memorized and used to help you prioritize your demand,
not just in initiatives, but actually in operations and projects as well.
Become a business leader and not just a technology leader.
Do both.
This can be tough.
Some people need to improve their leadership and communication skills first,
and there'll be more on that later.
And now you can start by understanding,
embracing and implementing what I'm about to say in this module.
Okay, let's first recap the definition of an initiative.
Let's define business initiative.
Initiatives are the means through which a strategic
vision is translated into practice.
A vision is a realistic and credible future state for an organization.
Initiatives drive activities you're going to do in order to
achieve the organization's strategic vision.
A business initiative is an organization's way of setting a priority.
It is usually a description of the direction the organization wants to
take and how that will improve the organization.
The initiative is usually a component of the
organization's vision for the future.
Now let's dig a little deeper in the next slide.
Initiatives are a means through which a strategic
vision is translated into practice.
Strategic initiatives are collections of finite duration discretionary
projects and programs outside of the organization's day-to-day
operational activities and these are designed to help the organization
achieve its targeted business goal or goals.
Now let's look at some examples.
Here are some examples of strategic initiatives: Increase revenue by 15%.
Build a new, cost-efficient aircraft.
Implement a new CAD, computer-aided design, engineering system.
Now increasing revenue by 15% may have been driven by the sales organization,
building a new cost-efficient aircraft may have been driven by
the engineering or manufacturing organization,
and lastly, implement a new CAD, computer-aided design,
system may have been driven by the IT organization.
Now all of these initiatives are likely to drive a lot
of demand and a lot of work into IT.
So be ready.
Now in the next section, we will look at demand sources and the portfolio management organization.