Demand Sources and the PMO.
In this section,
we will first refresh ourselves with the demand sources for initiatives,
that is where do initiatives come from,
and let's start laying out our need for the Portfolio Management Office,
the PMO.
Now let's look at the sources of demand for the demand type initiatives.
So where is all this work or demand coming from?
Board of Directors.
You don't get much more senior than the Board of Directors of a corporation,
large or small for that matter.
Typically, a Board is looking at very high-level and broad strategies.
Steering groups.
Many times these are comprised of senior company
individuals across multiple business domains,
such as manufacturing and engineering within the company.
Senior Executives.
They may band together to tackle problems and
comprise their own list of initiatives.
Business Leaders.
In this group, it's not only leaders in a company,
but may also comprise of business leaders in a community or their supply chain,
as two examples.
All of these make up your work intake, your demand,
that is your initiative, demand of things people are asking,
or maybe even telling you to do so.
So this is the point at which the initiative demand
management process begins and it begins by being managed
by the Portfolio Management Office, the PMO.
so the creation, privatization,
and execution of the initiatives is managed by the PMO.
Let's explore further.
Here are the key characteristics of a backlog of initiatives.
The first, they are very large-scale, second,
very senior executive focus, and as I mentioned before,
like the Board of Directors and senior steering groups,
the next,
long-term outcomes which will have a significant
strategic impact on the corporation.
These are reviewed quarterly or semiannually.
Please recall in operations backlog, we review them daily,
with the project backlog, possibly weekly and monthly,
and with the initiative backlog, they are reviewed quarterly or semiannually.
Lastly, they're a bit hard to measure.
Since these activities are so impactful and large,
they tend to be harder to measure and to see whether
they're having the intended outcome.
Okay, we need a PMO, a Portfolio Management Office, to manage all this.
Let's see an example.
Here is an example using the list of initiatives from a couple of slides ago.
We're going to have our container or portfolio of initiatives,
one of which is increase revenue by 15%.
All initiatives will be managed by the PMO, the Portfolio Management Office.
Now in order to achieve the goal of increasing revenue by 15%,
let's clock up other key initiatives that instead of being sibling initiatives,
they are subordinate.
So building a new aircraft will be a program.
We have multiple programs all supporting the higher-level initiative,
to increase revenue by 15%.
Now since programs can be a very significant amount of
work and use a lot of resources, we will create a PMO,
a Program Management Office.
We typically have one program as an office per program.
Now we have the program that is responsible to deliver the new CAD,
computer-aided design system.
It is made up, in our case here,
in this example of two projects and an existing operations group.
It is also managed by its own PMO, Program Management Office.
Yes, we have PMO which is Portfolio Management,
Program Management and Project Management.
Yes, it is confusing, so just saying the word PMO sometimes isn't enough.
Now, initiatives, programs,
and projects are management constructs that you can use as tools or
building blocks to best set up your organization to be the most efficient
at managing your limited and precious resources.
Here are the common goals for PMO, that is for any PMO,
portfolio, program or project management offices.
They all in general do the same things at a different level.
So first, define and maintain standards, metrics and process for what they do.
They all do that.
Execute on time and on budget.
That's very important as well for what they're responsible for.
They manage.
They plan.
They prioritize.
Lastly,
they perform cross-functional reporting and communication because
portfolio certainly slice across an entire company,
programs, maybe most of the company, projects,
a good chunk of key areas of the company as well.
So there's a lot of reporting and communication going on.
So basically, they will all function in a similar way,
but at different levels of granularity where a portfolio is very strategic,
long-term, big picture, program's a little more focused,
but always tied to an initiative, like many initiatives,
if you will, and finally projects,
which are very discreet and are either linked to an
initiative or under a program.
All right. In the next section, we're going to cover initiative governance and grooming.