Hello I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting the module, Building Your Initiative Management Process.
In the course, Demand and Work Management; a Practical Guide.
Okay, let's get started.
Let's recap demand versus work.
Demand, that's the stuff you have yet to do.
Also known as the backlog, and then there's work, the stuff you are doing.
Also known as work in progress or W-I-P, WIP.
Now earlier modules we talked about the work processes is for operations
and projects and now we're going to focus on the work processes for the
work type of initiatives in this module.
Remember in the demand module, we talked about doing the right work.
Selecting and choosing the things we think are the right things to do,
and here we're talking about doing the work right.
Hence we have already decided that what we are doing has been vetted in the
demand management process and we have just to get the job done.
So how are you going to get the job done?
That is what we'll be covering in this module,
Building Your Initiative Management Process.
Let's also recap the three work management types,
and these are a mirror image of the demand management types.
Operations, again ongoing, short bursts of activity may drive projects.
Any technical and domain knowledge certainly and that's
what we covered a couple modules ago.
Next was projects, they have a beginning and an end.
They're medium to long term.
They are focused activities and that's what we covered in the
previous module and now we're onto initiatives.
Longer-term strategies, they drive large projects.
Consume large resource commitments.
This module is all about the work management for initiatives.
Here are the key topics we'll be covering in this module.
Initiative work management, why?
A portfolio management office.
Portfolio management office processes.
Portfolio management office workflow, governance, designing portfolios.
Help programs support initiative work management
and an organizational viewpoint.
Now let's dive into the Initiative Work Management process and the Portfolio Management Office.