Just like for operations and projects, there's grooming for initiatives.
Let's explore.
How do you select the right initiatives to be in
your backlog in the first place?
Well, that is the million-dollar question for sure.
This is the hard part, even before the real grooming even begins.
At the operations or basic project level,
those are pretty basic things to do and people are typically
coming to you with the projects they would like.
At this level,
the business is presenting high-level initiatives and
strategies and maybe leaving the rest up to you.
This is a big challenge and selecting the right team members is the first step.
Building Your Team.
You cannot do this alone.
You need a team to help you determine your initial projects,
and as I keep mentioning,
how better to ensure the initiatives and projects are aligned to the business,
thereby including business leaders and Subject-Matter Experts into your process.
So with the Board of Directors,
I would suggest limited interviews to get their vision and recommendations.
They're probably really busy, hard to reach,
and you got to be careful with their time.
Next, with senior executives,
I would have regular interviews to get their vision and recommendations,
and maybe one or two from this group could actually be on your team.
Next, line of business or LOB leaders.
I really have regular and consistent interviews with them and I would
suggest that many of this group actually be on your team.
Lastly, well, this is your team,
a collection of line-of-business leaders and other Subject-Matter Experts
or SMEs helping to identify and collect the initiatives.
This then can constitute your team to first distill and
determine the initial list of initiatives.
All right.
Now let's look at developing project candidates.
Here is how you might get things kicked off with your team.
Select, invite, and assemble your team.
Have them bring their tactical plans, initiative ideas and project ideas.
Clearly describe purpose and outcome of your process.
Walk them through your candidate initiatives document that you presently have.
Next, it's the outcome.
Make sure they understand the outcome,
which is a list of prioritized candidate projects that drive business
value and directly tie back to the initiatives.
Now let's see how we can groom these initiative-driven projects.
Here's a way to do some grooming for your project candidates with your team.
Rank of value and benefits for each proposed project,
such as increasing revenue, reducing cost,
improving customer service and things like that.
Come up with your own criteria and use those to help
rank each one of value and benefit.
Appraisal of risk to achieve the benefits.
You want to probably have low risk, high benefits.
Next, the assessment of resources, people,
money, et cetera, that's available or not available to try to get the job done.
The alignment of the initiatives,
making sure that each project is truly aligned to the initiative,
again, that's the whole point of this section,
lastly, there could be some intangible benefits.
This just means these are things that are much more difficult to measure.
Sometimes market share or brand image is much tougher to measure,
but yet we do believe this initiative would help
with brand image or market share, and lastly,
is there going to be an effect on operations or other projects
in doing these initiative-driven projects?
That's important as well.
Of course,
this is just a starter list of attributes about each
initiative-based project that you need to collect and analyze.
Feel free to add more of these attributes yourself.
Now in the next section,
we will explore a technique to determine high-value and low-risk projects. These will be the best ones to go work on.