Here are a few of my other Pluralsight courses that are a great
agent to the topic of demand and work management.
Leadership and Communication Skills Everything we talked about in this
entire course has an underpinning and requirement for strong and
dynamic leadership and communication skills,
especially in the work types of projects and initiatives.
So check out this course if you have a chance.
Project Management for Software Engineers.
Since all three of the work types drive project,
then this course is a great agent to your learning experience.
To successfully implement demand and work management,
you need solid project managers and project management processes.
So check out this course as well.
Practical Team Management for Software Engineers.
Nothing gets done today and done well without great teams of people.
If you have any leadership role at all within the demand and work management
framework or any other leadership for management role, this course is for you.