Project work management and PMO.
This section will define what activities make up
project work management and the PMO, the Project Management Office.
Are your projects successful?
62% is the industry-wide success rate of projects.
That is barely two-thirds of all projects.
That's not very good when you think about it.
There are lots of reasons why projects may fail.
Fuzzy goals, poor requirements, inaccurate estimates,
weak ownership or sponsorship, lack of governance,
ineffective project managers, to name a few.
What are my thoughts?
If you don't have a process, an approach,
governance, and some structure,
your projects will either fail or be only partially
successful and you won't get your money's worth.
This module will help you improve your success rate.
Now let's look at some key requirements of a solid
project work management environment.
Here are the minimal requirements you need for good project work management.
You need an organizational structure for projects.
We call that the Project Management Office or PMO,
and we'll have more on that on the next slide.
You need project management process.
That is the work management processes for projects and it's
the discipline known as project management.
And we will be covering the processes of project
management in this module as well.
The project management process must support the demand
for large tickets from Operations,
where we determine that from the demand process side that
work that meets a certain threshold would be deemed a
project and not handled by Operations.
We do this to ensure that the best practices of work management are
applied to ensure the proper uses of company resources.
It must also support initiatives which drives strategic projects as
well as projects that are directed by management.
These are the projects that aren't from Ops and aren't from initiatives and
basically just show up based on a management directive.
You need experienced project managers especially for
resource intensive and critical projects.
You may also need dedicated project managers that are
available to work only on one project and not be diluted
by working on multiple projects.
And also you need a pool of project managers to handle
several projects concurrently within reason,
of course.
Next, execute and deliver to actually get things done.
If people are assigned to be a project manager and also
have a full time job making widgets,
then it is unlikely that they'll get everything done.
Now,
let's dig deeper as to the responsibilities of the Project Management
Office and how we might structure the organization.
Here are the key responsibilities of the Project Management Office.
Project demand management so they need to manage project demand,
planning and prioritization so the PMO performs the demand management side as
well as the other key project implementation responsibilities.
Execute the project on time and on budget but this also means
assigning the project manager and resources and a variety of
other supporting activities.
Define and maintain standards metrics and process
for the running of the projects.
That is,
what is the status of each project as well as what is the
aggregate status of all the projects within this PMO.
Perform cross-functional reporting and communication.
Now communication is so important.
The PMO must report out to senior management about the backlog,
the projects and work,
the issues with the project's schedules and budgets and so much more.
So you can see,
a PMO is typically structured to handle both the
demand and work management activities.
Now let's see how we might organize a PMO office within an organization.
Here is an example of an organizational structure with a PMO in it.
First we have a business domain.
I'm going to call that Ad Sales System and it's run by a vice president.
He has multiple Operations and this is just an example of one with a
manager and a team but also he has the PMO office.
This PMO office has the responsibility for all the projects
within this business domain of Ad Sales System.
And under this PMO are three projects that are
running right now all led by a PM, all having their project teams.
But also there's a small staff within the PMO,
remember, doing the demand management, deciding which projects to select,
coming up with the metrics and how to measure the success of the projects,
documentation and how to pick the good PMs,
how to hire all those things around running of the projects.
Now,
let's make sure we're on the same page with regards to
defining what a project is and the role of a project manager in the next couple sections.