In this section, we'll define what activities make up operations.
Your goal or mission in operations is the following.
Make it as easy as possible for your users and customers to maximize
their productivity in doing their daily activities.
You exist to service your customers.
You want a frictionless interface with your customers.
You want it easy for them to access you and your team,
to help them get things done.
Here's the takeaway.
Your customers are using your applications and systems every
minute of every day to get their job done.
You exist to service your customers.
Do not forget that.
Now let's look at the general scope of activities within operation.
Here are some examples of application operational activities.
All of these application items that I'm about to share with you could,
in fact, be managed and run by the application teams,
especially in smaller companies.
That is totally fine.
The important thing is that you understand as a manager and leader that
there are operational responsibilities that either you,
your team, or a dedicated ops team must manage and address.
These examples here are generally customer-facing.
Help desk or call center duties are sometimes split between an IT
applications help desk and an IT operations help desk.
Usually, the operations help desk is what they call level one,
and the application or system help desk sometimes is called level two.
ID or access management.
People need access to their applications or specific roles and permissions.
So they need IDs for this, and permission settings.
Sometimes this is managed centrally by operations.
Production or hot fixes.
Something is broke and it must be fixed ASAP,
and sometimes the operation group gets right on it.
Escalation.
You need a clear escalation path from when an issue is determined,
who is informed, and move quickly up your chart as needed.
You may need approvals for more resources or access to subject
matter experts that are beyond your pay grade.
So you would need to escalate the issue to get the necessary approvals.
The ops role is always looking to find, fix, and inform.
Small updates and features.
These are code changes that are small and are handled directly by the ops team.
Now you need to decide what small means, of course, that is level of effort.
For example, anything less than 16 hours may be considered small in your group.
Application subject matter experts, also known as SMEs.
Many times your issues may be simply handled by an SME or
a domain expert by talking or walking the customer
through the issue to resolution.
Off-the-shelf software installation and configuration
for business application support.
Many times off-the-shelf software or cloud-based software needs to be
configured and set up to support the customers.
And many times the operation group will perform this function.
Now let's look at a few more examples in the next slide.
These examples are generally internal-facing,
still things you are doing for the customer,
but indirectly.
Integration with business partners, customers, and other entities.
For example, FTP, EDI, eCommerce connections for ordering,
copying data between servers, setting up API endpoints,
et cetera.
Every company has business partners either on the supply chain side
or the customer side to work with electronically.
Job scheduling and management.
To ensure that all required jobs run according to schedule
on all platforms for all applications.
Remember, not everything runs through a user interface.
Actively monitoring applications, triggering alerts,
and generating automated tickets,
and then informing key operations people of an issue.
The last thing you want is the CEO calling you at
home because the system is down.
You want to know first, not last.
System logging and tracking.
Apps needs to constantly log and track their activity at all times.
So in the event an issue happens,
it is easy to review the log and help pinpoint an issue.
It's like leaving bread crumbs.
Database maintenance.
Applications and users maintain the database from a
database integrity viewpoint.
In other words, they know their data and its business meaning,
whereas operations maintains it from an efficiency and processing viewpoint,
cleaning up deleted records, re-indexing,
creating new indexes and views, backing up data,
things like that.
Data movement,
like file transfers and moving transactional data to a data warehouse,
for example.
So we have covered a plethora of operational topics related to applications.
Again, these should all be part of your business,
whether partially staffed by your development team or a separate ops team,
or some other combination of both.
And this list is not comprehensive.
You need to come up with the list that best suits
the needs of your organization.
Now, let's talk about a great technique to use to support operational tasks, tickets, in the next section.