As you can see from the graphic, things are stacking up.
So, what type of demand is it in those piles?
Where does it come from?
And, what do I do with it?
Let's find out.
Demand management is the planning methodology,
or an approach, or a technique, used to forecast,
plan for, and manage the demand for products and services.
In this course, I will be providing you with an approach to managing demand.
Now, let's deconstruct this definition.
Manage, that is to plan and operate.
Demand, the stuff that comes in, the things you need to do.
Products and services, someone is coming to you,
or your team, or organization,
because they want more of the things you do for a living: more software,
better software, new features, et cetera.
Now, let's look at the process flow for demand.
Here is a simple process flow to manage demand, also known as work intake.
Collect your demand.
That may be tickets, tasks, projects, or some other entity.
And, we will talk more about that in this course as well.
Organize your demand.
Email doesn't cut it.
Post-it notes don't work either.
Use the right tool, and, again,
we will talk more about tools later in this course.
Track your demand.
Know its relative value to other tasks.
Know its business value relative to other items in your demand list.
And, lastly, prioritize.
No matter how much senior management will tell you
everything is number one in priority, we all know that this is a fallacy,
and, in my opinion, an abdication of responsibility by management.
More on this topic of priorities later, as well.
The outcome of these simple steps is a collection of
well-organized and tracked demand items in priority order.
That's a nutshell of demand and demand management.
This is the process-side of demand,
and we will go further into detail in the next module,
but I wanted to give you a quick bird's-eye view right now so you have a
general overview of the process of managing demand.
Let's define, in general, what backlog means.
And, I will use the words backlog and demand interchangeably in this course.
Demand is a prioritized list of items such as features,
bugs, et cetera, containing information,
critical information, about the item or requirements desired in a product,
service, or system.
So, it is the list of things you, your team,
your organization, or even your whole company,
needs to get done. Now, let's look at the different demand types on the next slide.