Because there's no widely agreed on skill set for management practices in IT,
good managers come in all shapes and sizes.
There's an assumption everyone knows just how to do it.
This is like giving my daughter, who's never driven before,
keys to a car and told, "Well, drive.
" So,
to help mitigate the challenges you may have and to
save you time from trial and error, this course may be for you.
So here are the objectives for this course.
To understand and appreciate the difference between demand and
work management processes and their benefits.
To learn or improve your planning skills.
To learn and improve approaches and tools for demand
and work management processes.
To learn and improve your management practices and skills.
To help you use resources more effectively.
Your managers will love this about you.
And to enhance your career potential.
There is a strong demand for IT managers with the skills in this course.
Here are a few more course objectives.
To more easily prioritize your work.
If you can't do this well, you will struggle.
You will likely get work from all over the map and be told
they are all number one in priority.
This course will help you get a handle on this and enable you to
present options to your management in a constructive way.
Align your work to the business.
I have seen so many times that people are working on things and they
haven't a clue how it pertains or helps the business.
All work, all work that you do should map up to the company's business goals.
Be more effective.
We all want to be effective, be contributors,
and just plain do good productive work.
I will help you do that.
Lastly, to reduce your stress and anxiety.
This course will provide a necessary demand and work management skills,
approaches, tools, and techniques, to enable you to transition from a chaotic,
unstructured environment to a well-managed,
organized, and less stressful environment.
Okay, now let's see why businesses need people like you.
Businesses and companies everywhere need people with the skills
and knowledge you will learn in this course.
They need those who understand demand management.
They need those who understand work management.
They need those who can use your company's resources in the most effective way.
To do this well, you need keen insights into your company,
its business and strategy, the team, the talent,
and what they can and can't do.
They need those who can provide real leadership and insight.
I believe these talents can tie directly to salary growth.
People in the role of demand and work management can
command very high salaries indeed. Now let me give you a quick overview of the difference between demand and work.