Understanding demand types.
So, no matter what your demand type is you will always need to collect,
organize, track, and prioritize your demand prior to doing any work.
Now, let's see what they are.
For this course, I'm going to simplify and categorize all demand,
that is work you're asked to do, into three categories: operations,
projects, and initiatives.
So, what I am saying, in my opinion,
is that 99% of all demand and work will fall into one of these broad categories.
Now,
each category will be handled and managed at a macro level pretty much the same,
but, at a detailed level, somewhat differently.
Therefore, I have modeled this entire course around these three demand types,
and later, correspondingly, the same for work types as well.
Now, let's compare each one to better understand the differences.
For this course,
I'm going to simplify and categorize all demand and work
into three general categories: operations,
projects, and initiatives.
To better understand just what I mean by the term,
operations, here are a few characteristics: day-to-day functions of the business,
keeps the lights on, like a utility company,
you just expect it to work, issues are formally tracked in a tracking system,
such as Jira, or others, typically smaller units of work,
always running, sometimes even seven by 24.
To better understand just what I mean by the term,
projects, here are a few characteristics: projects drive new revenues,
supports existing products or services, drives cost containment,
has a maybe higher level management focus,
it's typically more of a medium level of effort,
and has a distinct beginning and end.
It's not ongoing like operations.
To better understand just what I mean by the term,
initiatives,
here are a few characteristics: initiatives propel a
company forward strategically, they are large-scale activities,
major new products or services,
and an executive focus rather than a mid-management focus,
and also typically very large activities in terms of resources,
people, and money required.
Also, long term outcomes, maybe even a year to three years.
Now you may have a better sense of my three major demand and work types.
It is important to understand these types since how you handle
the demand for your products or services,
and how you will ultimately handle the work-side are different.
Let's see some examples.
Here are a few demand type examples.
For operations,
a simple example may be add an additional drop down
values for healthcare application types.
For projects,
a simple example may be add a new module to enable users to
fill out healthcare applications online.
For initiatives,
a simple example may be develop a new healthcare paperless application system.
Yes, these are simple examples, but hopefully they convey a relative size,
complexity, and level of effort.
Speaking of level of effort,
let's be sure we are on the same page on that term's definition on the next slide.