Kanban: Easy Technique, Great Results.
Kanban is a great tool or approach to handling
operational-type work tasks such as bugs,
maintenance, smallish requirements, and things like that.
Let's check it out.
Here is a quick and simple technique known as kanban.
Originally from Japan.
Kanban is Japanese for visual signal or card.
Toyota line workers used a kanban,
an actual physical card to show steps in their manufacturing process.
The system's visual nature allows teams to communicate more
easily on what work needed to be done and when.
It also standardized its queues, things you put on the cards,
such as numbers, colors, icons, and things like that,
which help refine the processes which help to reduce waste and maximize value.
Kanban has a simple board layout.
Think of it as a big whiteboard, if you will,
that has sections or columns such as a to do column,
a doing column, or a done column.
Basically, your backlog, your in work, and complete.
Be creative and add additional columns or sections if you like, such as re-do.
Maybe this is the defect column from work in progress,
maybe user acceptance testing column, and lastly,
a production column.
In other words, you're finally done with the ticket.
Now, before I show you an example,
let's check out some of the benefits of using kanban.
Let's review the key benefits of kanban.
It enhances a team's ability to focus.
I think we all focus better when you have a visual dimension
with only the critical data on the board.
Offers flexibility and ease of use.
There is no one perfect way to do kanban.
Shape it for your team's effectiveness.
Sounds like agile to me.
Provides easy-to-comprehend visuals.
Visuals are simple and clear, therefore easy to understand.
I'm a very visual person, so I love it.
Focuses on continuous delivery.
With kanban, you see the flow of work from backlog to delivery or completion.
You see each step of your delivery process very easily.
Reduces wasted work and time.
If you use kanban, I truly believe you'll save time and money,
people work and collaborate better, and it promotes teamwork.
Lastly, it increase productivity and efficiency.
Because of the items I've mentioned above,
you will see an increase in productivity.
Also, what people don't always realize,
doing the wrong work at the wrong time isn't work at all,
it's just waste.
Kanban helps doing the work right.
Alright, now let's see an example.
For our example, every ticket is represented by a kanban card.
It is a unit of work.
Kanban's board has a grid.
This one is simple with three columns, but you can get creative.
Here is our to do list on the left, or our backlog.
The next column are all the things we are doing, work in progress.
And next are the things that have been recently completed.
I'd like to see the done column.
Since I can't remember everything we've finished and
it reinforces our accomplishments, that is a feel-good thing for me and the team.
And maybe they fall off the board after two weeks or some
other timeframe that works for you.
Now,
underlying all of this should be your automated ticketing and workflow system.
It could be that when tickets first come in,
they are in a pending column, then they move to a triage,
and then they move to the to do column, or backlog column.
Design it as you see fit with your team.
Now let's look at grooming the kanban board.
Now let's go through a kanban example.
And what I like about kanban is that it is simple,
visual, easy to understand, and very flexible.
Alright, here's our grid with three columns.
Our to do column on the left or our demand column,
our doing or work in progress column, and our done or completed item column.
And here are all our to do or demand items as tickets on the left.
And the center column will have our work in progress cards.
And lastly, of course, our done cards.
Now, if we have identified the purple ticket as approved and resourced,
then we are ready to move that ticket to the doing column.
So let's move it.
It is that easy.
Drag and drop the tickets as you need to.
And if you are in a conference room using a
widescreen monitor or over the internet,
it is very easy for people to understand.
Now, let's look at a sample screen from an automated tool.
I thought it would be a good idea to see a sample board from a real tool.
They really can look almost like my PowerPoint examples.
As you can see, here is the to do column,
then the doing column, and lastly, the done column.
But also, you can see the collapsed column on the left called backlog.
And my guess is that the designer of this board called the backlog,
as those items still needing some amount of triage,
and after the triage they are promoted to the to do column,
that is, it is ready to be resourced.
That is what's so nice and simple about the kanban.
Set it up any way you want to meet your requirements.
And notice on the right that they've added an archive column.
Perfect!
So after, say, two weeks the ticket or card will flow into the archive.
Now let's talk about the kanban card itself.
Designing kanban cards.
You can annotate your kanban cards to contain a brief
but rich amount of information.
Choose annotations that make sense to you and your team to
help you make timely and quality decisions.
Maybe green means a particular system, like a sales management system,
so they are very easy to see and identify.
Now let's say I want to drill into one of the green tickets.
Here is a ticket with reference number 12345 and a
brief description of the requirement, 12 month scheduling feature.
Next we are showing who worked the ticket, that's Joe and Mary.
And the estimate of 32 hours.
Maybe it'd be great if we included the actual hours used as well.
You can usually pick the type of information you need
that is relevant for you and your team.
Now, let's see an example of inserting additional columns in our board.
Here is a variation that I like to call the re-do or defect option.
Here's our grid, here is the to dos, here are the doing or work in progress,
and here is the done column.
And here we add the re-do column.
It means it was once in the done column, but a defect was found.
You could certainly just put it in the to do column,
that is fine, but I like the re-do column since it is of a higher priority.
The customer may be a bit upset and it provides focus to the team.
Plus if something comes back into the re-do column,
then I think it deserves a higher priority and hence more focus and attention.
Remember,
anything in the doing or in work column can always go
back to being in the to do list, that is back in the demand state at any time.
And don't be afraid to stop work on anything in order to free
resources to another more important task.
Now, you could add even more columns that represent UAT,
or user acceptance testing, and promote to production,
for example.
Be creative not only with columns but the information on the card as well.
Just be sure it is very simple, easy to read and understand,
even by your management or a customer, for that matter.
Now let's see how to run a kanban discussion.
It is one thing to say use kanban as a technique,
but it is another to use it effectively.
Communication is critical.
Here is an approach,
and please feel free to modify it as you see fit to make
better use of it in your organization.
Now, you may have heard of stand-ups with scrum, of course.
This is very similar.
Assemble your team.
If you are doing this face to face,
find a comfortable spot so you don't disturb others
and you can all see the board.
If you are doing it via the internet, such as using Slack,
then that works too, of course.
Begin with a lead-off statement, set the tone.
If any issues are critical, talk about those.
Maybe there is a change in management direction,
maybe someone is out sick or on vacation,
or maybe today is just a normal day.
Any changes to priorities?
Maybe you learn that manufacturing is behind schedule and as of 6
AM today the top priority in the company that everything
manufacturing must get moved through quickly.
Well, that would change your criteria for prioritizing your tickets,
wouldn't it?
Stop any items?
Well, based on the last statement regarding manufacturing,
we may want to stop one or more items so that we have the
resources to allocate to manufacturing tickets.
And as we discussed using colored cards,
it would be easy to quickly identify those on the board
or filter them to make your decisions.
Now, randomly go around the team and solicit inputs,
asking each person, what did they do yesterday,
what do they plan to do today, and if there are any issues or blockers.
Those issues, if any, will play into the next few steps,
plus you now have a good feel of the team's health and how
they are feeling about what they're doing.
That's important.
Now, look at the board and start with work in progress.
And if you have a re-do or defect column, consider that as well.
Any blockers?
That is any impediments to continuing with those tickets?
To make the best decisions, we'll use any top-down information from management,
you will use the feedback from getting inputs from the team,
and you will review the board to make any adjustments you might have to make.
Adjust resources and move tickets.
You may need to change resources, for example.
You might have moved a ticket to backlog and took that
resource to help on another ticket.
Do it every morning no matter who is missing.
In real critical times, you may consider a second one around 1 or 2 PM,
or pick a tempo that works for you.
Now let's contrast sprints with kanban and when you might want to use one over the other in the next section.