Designing Portfolios.
Now how you may go about designing your portfolios,
I believe is critical to the success of the underlying work,
and let's take a look.
I look at portfolios as collections or containers of work activities.
Here are some examples on how you might design portfolios,
projects and programs.
A collection of initiatives with the governance or oversight
being the Portfolio Management Office.
A collection of projects with the governance or oversight
being the project management office.
A collection of projects and operations and we call these programs with the
governance or oversight being the program management office and I'll have
more on this a little bit later in this module.
Lastly just custom collections, put whatever you want in the collection.
Here the oversight is any of the PMOs,
where PMA stand for project portfolio or program,
and do what make sense to your organization and your available skills.
In this course I have talked about portfolios as my collection of initiatives.
There may be one or more projects and operations
supporting one or more initiatives,
but out in the world organizations slice and dice these in a multitude of ways.
There is no one right perfect way.
Be creative, be focused.
Use a PMO, set up your policy and procedures,
set up your governance and keep it light and lean and you will
make a difference to your company's bottom line.
Now let's see who's in charge of these organizational constructs.
Given the previous slides orientation,
let's see who may be the best to manage each of those constructs.
Initiatives probably CEO, CxO or other very senior management.
Projects, business unit management.
Programs?
Probably cross-functional senior management,
and of course the famous mix, basically roll your own.
I have found that talent can lie all over an organization and they certainly do
not need to be a manager to have talent for jobs like these.
This slide was to give you context between each kind of initiative activity.
Now what level or type of management should likely be involved.
Okay now, who's going to do all this work?
Let's find out.
Here are the key portfolio management roles.
Executives who are driving the initiatives.
The executive governance body developing the policies,
procedures, processes et cetera, and how you will run the PMO.
Portfolio Managers.
They will be responsible for one or more portfolios and their success.
Program managers.
They will be responsible for one or more programs and their success.
Project managers.
They too will be responsible for one or more projects and their success.
Portfolio, Program and Project Management Office managers.
They will be responsible for their respective management office.
Remember there should only be one Portfolio Management Office,
but could be several Program and Project Management Offices,
and lastly a variety of other skills such as administrators,
finance analysts, business analysts and project and program coordinators.
Remember project managers are not normally part of the initiative or
portfolio management office from a reporting perspective and program
managers as well but as I've discussed, if it makes sense do it.
Also as project and program managers become more
experienced and mature as leaders they may be more suited
for a program management position,
for a project manager or a portfolio management position that once was
a program manager or a role within the PMO itself.
Now let's go into programs a little deeper.
The construct of a program is important since it marries projects and operations and the pairing is usually overlooked in organizations.