Forecasting,
that's the activity of predicting or estimating a future event or trend.
Typically, the demand for work comes to you,
and we will talk about those sources of demand in the next section.
Forecasting is the activity or process by which you get up
and try and figure out what the demand might be in the future
for your products and services.
So, you want to predict or estimate that future workload, that future demand.
This information is very important to help you prepare for your staffing,
budgeting, tools, methods, outsourcing, systems,
et cetera, as early as possible to meet the demand.
Let's see examples of forecasting for each demand type.
First, though,
remember we are doing forecasting to enhance your ability to forecast,
predict, and estimate as early as possible to meet the demand that's coming.
Okay, in the area of operations, how about 20% increase in help center calls?
That would help you decide maybe you need to staff up more in the help center.
In the area of projects,
you've learned that there's eight new projects coming your way.
Do you have enough project managers?
Do you have enough subject matter experts to get the job done?
That'll help you staff up and get ready.
For initiatives, there are three new initiatives coming.
What does that mean?
What are the resources required for that?
So,
it is very important to reach out to your customer
base in the area of initiatives, projects,
and operations to predict and determine what is coming.
Now, let's look at the sources of demand. In other words, where does all this work come from?