Now let's look at the construct of a program.
Again it is just another organizational container, but has several advantages.
Why are programs important?
Programs exist in order to focus resources that will enable
broader business benefits and objectives.
Programs have a broader reach,
therefore a much broader impact than a project on the business,
and therefore that is why I am emphasizing that more high-level business
benefits can be realized by employing the notion of a program.
Now here is a more formal definition of programs.
Programs,
a program is a group of related projects and operations
managed in a coordinated manner to obtain benefits not
available for managing them individually.
Program management is the application of knowledge,
skills tools and techniques to meet program requirements.
Organizations with mature program management,
I believe are more successful than those without it.
Now let's revisit some key points.
A program is a collection of projects and operations.
Typically the collection contains those projects or operations of a
similar type or kind or possibly having the same business objective and
goal and there also to enable synergistic benefits.
Such as increase in revenue or avoid costs,
things like that and lastly more benefits can be
derived from managing them collectively.
That is the projects and operations, rather than managing them individually.
Now where possible there are significant advantages to
defining a program in support of an objective and then
subdividing into component projects.
Instead of embarking on individual projects on their own.
This strengthens the alignment to the organizational
strategy and ensures better control and focus in realizing
those intended and expected benefits.
Because projects can have a significant impact,
positive or negative, on other projects and operations,
the construct of a program as a container to better manage
those interrelationships was created.
It is a simple and great idea.
Now let's look at the attributes of a program.
Here are the characteristics or attributes of a program which
by the way are similar to an initiative.
Which makes sense since we have learned that programs can be
employed to drive and execute initiatives quite well.
Unlike projects programs may never end or may end only when the
businesses requirements or strategy changes.
Programs have a higher level of complexity than projects.
Obviously since they will involve many projects and
operational elements and their dependencies.
Programs involve a broader range of senior management or stakeholders.
If you're going to have many projects and operations,
you will quite likely have more management and stakeholders involved.
Programs use more resources than any project might.
Well sure multiple projects and operations will certainly add
up to more resources in people and money.
Programs have more potential conflict and serious broad range business issues.
Well, yes certainly.
You have higher level management and much more resources to compete with,
which may result in more potential conflict.
Programs require much more coordination.
To say the least, it takes an immense amount of coordination management,
acumen, communication skills and experience to work on or run a program.
Now a couple of those might sound a little more risky or tough,
but the point is is you're going to get the benefits from
focusing all those resources on the big initiatives in your
company and you'll get more bang for the buck.
Okay now let's look at an example in the next slide.
In this example we have an aerospace company where one of the
initiatives is to sell better fuel saving jets and we may have
several programs and projects for this initiative,
but the main program is the new wing design.
This program is strategic to the business and we want
to manage to control all activities, sub programs,
operations and projects,
under one umbrella to ensure resources are used effectively.
So a portion of this program contains, engineering operations.
Obviously we'll be using engineering to design a new wing
and we want to be sure that current engineering operations
are included in this program.
A project to upgrade the CAD, Computer Aided Design software and equipment,
we need this highly unique and specialized platform to design our new wing.
Therefore we have a project for that.
Another project is to streamline the supply chain
with more supplier integration,
since a new wing will have new high-tech materials from new
suppliers and I want to be sure they are integrated into our
supply chain in the most efficient fashion,
and really this is just a partial list.
More components could be placed here.
Now on the right I have highlighted the upgrade CAD project.
It has a defined scope.
It has a begin date of August first.
It has an end date of October 14th, and we have a budget of two million dollars,
and as you can see the program includes this project under its control.
So in this example you can see the vast differences
between a program and a project.
So the construct of a program is a container of sorts that we
will use to group activities that are related.
So that to keep them coordinated,
working towards a strategic outcome and in this
case a successful new wing design.
Now let's see how this might look organizationally.
Now let's explore a simple example of a program structure organizationally.
So we have our initiative, sell fuel saving jets.
So we can make a lot more money,
and we're going to have a program to redesign the wing because we
know that's very important to help sell more jets.
Under that program we're going to have a program management office,
and that's where all the action is going to happen.
Then to the right we've included our engineering but it's the
operational area of engineering and we may have some other
operations that we want to put under here as well and on the
left we're going to upgrade CAD.
To the upgrade CAD project will be also into the program and also the
supplier integration project will also be under the program.
So you can see we have all these elements,
programs and operations, all under a program management office for wing design.
All of which are integrated and you're looking at sharing resources,
maximizing resources and coordinating the efforts towards the
initiative of selling more fuel saving jets. Okay, now let's summarize this module.