The first step of beginning his method is the cross.
And this is unchanged and advanced methods of solving the cube across will be exactly the same.
I'll teach you how to improve your cross and form it faster.
This is what the cross looks like.
We have four edges on a white center and the white side is a cross.
And notice how each of these edges matches up with this corresponding center.
Let me show you a really easy way that this can be done or how most people do it, which is the flower
method will get like a white edge right here.
Move that up to the top and then do that for everybody.
So this green one, I move that up to the top with the yellow center.
I see this white one right here, right orange.
I move that down.
And then finally, this white, red one.
So now I have this little flower pattern right here.
All the white edges on the yellow center.
We take one edge, like I say, this white, red one.
We twist the top so that now it's right next to its center and then we flip it down.
That solves this one.
And we can do that for every edge.
And looks like they're all solved somehow.
So I just moved every single side down.
And that's all across.