Let's start with the event, STRUS.
So the event for is very similar to the normal course.
The end result is the same, but there are more methods to solve the crisis that are more efficient
and faster.
So, again, our goal is for the cross to look like this with preferably white or yellow edges matching
the center to keep it simple and these edges matched in their adjacent colors.
I'll go over color neutrality or using any colored cross like Blue Cross instead in the next section.
But first, do you see what I'm going to use?
White grass to keep it simple.
There aren't really any algorithms in the up because it's all intuitive.
Let's start with the inspection.
Typically, you'll be given 15 seconds to inspect the queue before solving and competitions.
This is the standard for basically every soul there is.
So always inspect the cube while inspecting the main thing you should be looking for is where the white
edges are.
So we hold the cube with the white center down.
Let me scramble it.
We'll keep this site on the bottom.
And while inspecting, we want to look for where the white edges are.
So we ignore everything else is look, I see a white edge here.
This is white, blue.
I see one here.
This is white.
Orange.
This is white, green.
And it's already solved.
So I don't have to do anything with that.
And then here's white.
Red.
So during inspection, our goal is to find these edges and develop a way that we can try to solve them
so we don't use the flower method anymore.
This is very inefficient.
Instead, we want to look for an algorithm that will solve all of our edges.
So with this bluez, I can immediately see that doing a Yuto and an R2 will solve it.
And then I can look at all the others and I can see that instead of doing an R2, this edge will match
up with its center in between.
So I can just do an hour prime and then orient this red edge back here and then move the blue one down.
So we solve the red one by doing the blue one.
And then this orange one is tricky.
So I'm just going to move that to the top layer first and then now I can move this out of the way.
And I can take this orange side and match it up to a center like this that I can move this down and
fix the blue side with one move.
And that solves the cross and all of those moves.
I should have done in my head during inspection.
So that stuff seems really hard, but it'll get easier if you.
Well, once you tried it and if you use less moves because less moves are easier to memorize.
OK, so again, there is no more flowers up.
We just want to get a sense of insertion, insertion and try and move these ideas down to the white
side as efficiently as we can while being aware of the other edges.
So let's see.
With this one, I see green and orange right here.
These two can be sold relative to each other.
If I move this side up and move this over and move this down, then that solves both of these edges
not to do the red and blue ones.
So I know this one can easily be paired up with a center like this.
And then instead of just moving this down to solve it, I can see that while I'm doing that, this blue
one comes to a state where I can just push it over and match it up with its center in between and then
move this down.
So I just did an intermediate step to help solve this blue side.
So I move this one down first and then I move this over and then do an hour prime.
And now I can simply move this blue wedge down.
But a simple are two.
And I saw the cross again.
So I was much less moved than the flower method.
And it will be much easier to memorize an inspection because it should be less than 10 moves.
Ideally, if you're doing more than that, that you probably want to improve your dress.
So let's let's do another example of salt.
OK, so here we have another scramble cube.
I see this orange side has already solved.
And here are my three edges.
So let's see, this blue edge can easily be solved just by moving this to the side and flipping the
stone.
So there's two solved and then.
This is GreenEDGE.
I can move it down and paired up with a center like this that displaces this orange one.
But I can just fix that after flipping this frontside, solving this one and move this back up to fix
that.
Now we have three solved.
And then finally, this red one is really easy.
I didn't move it and match it with the center.
And I flip it down and those are across again.
So let's try something harder now.
Let's try and match the edges relative to each other instead of dissenters.
So by now, it should be clear that none of these centres move on the tube no matter what you what move
you do.
These centers will always be in the same place relative to each other.
So green is always going to be opposite blue.
Red will the opposite orange and yellow will always be opposite white.
So let's take this solved cross and work backwards.
Let's see what happens if I move the white side twice or do a PhD to move.
So nothing happened to the cross, but notice how the edges Mosler opposite centers.
So blue with green, orange is with red and vice versa over here.
So it's simple that we just did a D2 move and that solved the cross.
So working backwards, if we try and get this position earlier before we solve the cross, then we could
easily just do a PhD to move to solve the cross.
So let's say I have a case like this where I have the blue matching the green and the red matching the
orange, since I know that the orange and red and green and blue are already matching.
Then I can solve these relative to each other by simply moving the side down.
So with opposites right here, they're moving this side down.
And obviously, we get to do a PhD to to solve the cross again.
Similarly from across state, we can do a PhD or a deep rimu, and they'll also be one moved from solving
to grass.
So over here, we can see that red is with green greens, with orange, and all of this can easily solve
the cross in one move.
So let's work backwards again.
OK, so this is a pretty easy case.
We can see already that blues over here, orange is over here.
And you can you can both be moved down with an hour and a half, Primus.
So you can see that these are relative to each other.
So blue is to the right of orange.
And same with the.
Blue is to the right of orange.
So these two edges can easily be solved with a simple move.
One of the dollface.
We can just do that for every single sign.
I see that this green age is really convenient.
It's directly opposite the blue side.
So don't worry about the center.
It's not up to you.
Just know that if we solve these two edges again, then if I move this greenside down now, this green
is opposite blue, which means it's solved relative to each other.
And then now I can also see that this red side can easily be moved down right here, making it opposite
the orange.
And now I know that since all the opposites are in their correct positions to each other, that I can
just move the bottom of this to solve the dross.
So let's do another opposite of here we have red and orange mashed with green and blue.
So these two can be moved on to the white side.
We can see that the edges are matching their opposite centers.
So these two ideas will be solved with simple D to move.
But before we do that, we can easily just insert the other the other edges into these slots so that
we solve them with the D to move.
So let's see this orange as it can easily be moved down opposite run.
So that will be solved with D2.
But like I showed earlier, this blue edge is also attached to it.
So instead, what I'll do is while moving this orange edge down, I do an intermediate move and move
this edge out of the way and then solve this one again.
And now you can see that this blue and green edges are matched up.
I can move this down to the bottom.
And now all the edges are opposite again.
I can simply 32.
And that's all it.
OK, so let's go through some special cross cases in case there's edges stuck in certain places that
we don't want them to be.
So here we see we have a case where we have our green and red.
I just solved our orange edges over here, but our blue edge is in a wrong spot.
So you can see that the blue is not opposite green, which means it is not solved relative to each other.
So this is in the wrong place.
We want it to be here.
However, to do that, it would take a lot of moves and it would be really inefficient because we would
have to completely move this side up and then move it over and then move it down.
And then on top of that, we would have to solve the orange as well.
So instead, what we can do is just ignore this edge and replace it with the edge that's supposed to
go there.
So we know that orange is supposed to go here to match up with its center and to be opposite red.
So here's my orange as I just moved it to a stop and solve it up with its center and move it down.
That solves our orange side.
Now, by doing that, we've also displaced this blue center right here or this blue edge.
So now I can easily just move this to the side and solve it.
And we did that in much less move than solving the blue one first, because we solved the blue one by
solving the orange one.
So this was way more efficient.
OK, let's say we have a case like this.
We have three of our edges solved and our last as is in this position right here, it's in the right
spot.
It's with white and blue, but it's flip the wrong way.
So all we have to do is flip this over.
And the best way of doing that is moving this to the side to match up with a different center first.
So now we have blue and red.
And if we get this adjacent to all the other edges, then we could just insert this into this light.
So what I'll do is I'll get this slot over here.
And now we can see that if I move this down, the blue side will be opposite the green side.
So I can just do that.
And that gives us another adjacent solved edge case.
And I can simply easily be solved with a move, the dollface.
And as a solid cross, that's basically all I have to teach you for the cross right now.
I know this is pretty hard to grasp, but if you just practice trying to get all the edges and the rights
lights and all the special cases and how you can do it with adjacent faces instead of with their centers,
then you'll be able to do it with less than 10 moves.
Just keep practicing and asked me questions if you need some clarification.
And yeah, next step is actual, which is really, really hard.
So make sure you have this stuff down and then we'll try and move on to afterworld.