The next stop in Victoria's method is the first layer, this layer involves solving the wet side by
putting the corners in the grass.
And notice how this layer has a perfect color scheme and the corners and their correct salt positions.
So you can see here the orange makes a little tea like this.
So does every single other side.
So we still have our cross intact.
Let's do an example of salt.
OK, so here we have a solid cross state.
This is what it typically looks like.
This is what we had in the first up.
So I'm going to use the most simple method first.
This is what most beginners do will take an edge.
This one's already on top, preferably one in the bottom layer.
So like this one, we have white, green and red or in the bottom layer across it right here on top.
So we're going to move the bottom face until this is right below the spot.
We want it to go in.
So between the green and red centers and the algorithm that people do is our prime de prime, our D.
And that's all for this corner.
Next corner I see on the bottom is white, green, orange.
Put that in between the orange and green senators right below this light.
And I will do the same algorithm our prime de prime are.
And keep going until it's solved.
There we go.
This one still stuck in this light.
So let's find this one.
Blue, red.
Put that in between.
Do the same thing.
And now this one is in the bottom.
Sort of move it here and solve the layer just like that.
And that's the fourth.
First place on.
OK, so we're back with another solid cross.
And I said, I'm going to use the more advanced method.
So instead of doing that algorithm, we will keep the cross on the bottom and we'll use an intuitive
sense of insertion insertion.
So this is still above the corresponding corresponding centers.
And I'll just insert it using Renu moves and I'll do that for every edge.
So we have the blue and red one here.
This one is facing me, so I'll just do it on the left side.
So using our new moves and then this one one's down here.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to insert a random corner first like this one.
So I'll insert this just down here.
And what would I would do is displace this green and orange corner.
And then we can move that back to the top above where I need to go and simply insert it.
And that also shows the first layer.
But it's there's no algorithms to it.
It's intuitive.
So you need to just get in a sense of insertion.
And that's basically what we do in F 12.
But with edges.
So that's about it for the first layer.