The next tip I have is look ahead.
So parties are a massive time waster during a solve and they're frequent after algorithms are completing
different stages, like after well, this is because your attention shifts from one step to another.
I need a look at the cube and figure out which LPL pll are, after all, case you have.
Looking ahead is the ability to see what case of the next step you have before you even finish up your
arm.
So, for example, here I'm doing well.
And I see I have this pair here and I want to say here, and since I've got it of to and I know the
exact moves that I can, I can do this with, which is, are you prime our prime?
So this is just a finger finger exercise and my brain isn't working while I'm doing those moves.
So instead, if I do if I want my muscles to do something different from my brain, then I'll be able
to do one step ahead and immediately solve the next pair.
So while I'm solving this, I know that these two pieces are back here, which is my next pair.
So my brain, my my muscles will be doing these moves, but my brain will be tracking these.
So I'll just watch what happens.
I know this corner will come back here and now I know this edge is over here.
So from here, I knew exactly which, after all case I have, which means I can immediately solve this
and I go straight into solving the next one.
It's the exact same for oLow and Pilo.
So here I have another afterworld case, but my next step is ololo.
So I'm going to wash the top yellow pieces and see what happens.
I'll move this edge up, replace this, and then move another one here.
So I know love across case.
And then all I have to do is identify the corners while they're moving.
So I just watch the corners.
This one going back here.
This one will come down here and this won't be facing outwards like this.
So we have a suitcase.
So instead of just simply inserting this pair, now that I know that I'll have a suitcase, I can jump
straight into the algorithm.
And this is a really special case, because the insertion for this pair involves the OLALLA algorithm.
So I've already done this.
Are you are prime movers of the Zoon algorithm.
So I can just continue with a U.
Are you to our prime?
And I could see while I was insisting that pair, I instantly solved all all which saved a lot of time.