The next tip I have is to slow down because finger speed isn't everything.
Using look ahead, it's possible that your fingers will be working too fast for your brain.
If I can't see how other pieces are moving while doing an algorithm, there's no way to look ahead.
So the solution is to slow down finger wise.
Don't do your moves too fast.
Most times you're solving algorithm really quickly.
But then you'll have a long pause trying to figure out what the next step is.
And then you have solved that next up quickly, et cetera.
And your pauses will add up and you have a really long, solid time.
So a better strategy is to be very fluid.
If I know how have to insert this pair.
But I want to do this slowly so that I can look around for other pieces.
So let's just do a sample solve.
So while I'm solving this, I'm going to do it slowly so I can watch these pieces.
And now I know of this case.
So I'll do this slowly while watching, for example, this orange screen.
I know the orange green edges back here.
So I just solve this case.
And then I watch the red green and I know instantly what to do because I was watching.
And look at how fast we solved after.
Well, when you don't want to do is just do everything really fast.
So I'm going to do another solve.
But this time I'm going to do everything as fast as I can and not be able to look ahead.
So here's my first case.
I was trying to do it really fast.
And now I have to look around instantly because I don't know what my next cases are, because I did
that way too fast.
So after a long pause, I see this case.
So I just saw this as fast as I can.
Now I have to look around again.
I'm not really looking around.
I can't even do it that well.
I look around again.
I have to keep rotating and I solve it.
And now I still don't even know in my old cases.
So that's why it's really inefficient.
This is extremely common advice and competitions with high stress levels and lots of pressure.
People commonly make finger slips and mess up algorithms when trying to work too fast.
So, for example, I'm on the last up.
I'm on PLL, and I know exactly what the case is.
So I'm going to try and do this as fast as possible.
But keep in mind, I'm very stressed.
So you could see how inefficient that that algorithm was, my turns were awful, and I had to readjust
many times because I kept moving the layers that I didn't want to move.
That algorithm took a really long time, and it would have been better if I had just slowed down and
done and done everything very fluidly.