So first, let's cover ways of putting a pair and without breaking it.
So here we can see we have a white, green red pair.
It's already matched up with ads and needs to go into this slot right here.
So there's many ways of doing this.
But the most common ones and the reason why I just taught you those last algorithms is because they
can be used here.
So the first wave in this is just doing a reverse sexy move, which is you are you prime our prime.
And that inserts that really easily.
But we can also, instead of doing a reverse sexy, we can also just do the sledgehammer.
So from right here, our prime as our prime.
And that also solve it.
So when when you want to decide which one to use, I think it mainly relies on where your hands or you
are.
So it's just about which one can be performed more easily without moving your fingers too much to save
as much time as possible.
OK, this is another really easy case.
I know it looks like we don't have a pair because there's nothing trailing this edge right here, but
it's really easy to solve because we can see that the edges back here and these two colors are not matching.
So the white sides would be facing out this way.
And I Slott is right here.
So since these two colors are not matching, if I move this right side up, then they'll solve the pair
really easily.
And then once I move this right side up, I also open a slot to move this side into.
So I just move that in and put it back down.
And that's all of it.
And you'll also notice that was that that was exactly a sexy move.
So that was the sequence.
Are you our prime you prime the you prime at the end?
Is it necessary?
But if it helps you to remember it, then just know that in this case, you get to do a sexy move to
solve the hair.
And I'm going to cover two cases that you should already know.
Of course, it's obviously possible that after solving the cross, there's a corner that's already solved
and there's an edge that's on the top layer.
So let's say I got this case randomly.
I didn't insert this corner.
It's already canceled like this.
And that means we can just do the same algorithm we had earlier.
So this needs to go to the left.
We put the bar facing us and do the same algorithm.
And then that also solves the terror.
And that's why those second layer methods were really important and useful for Abdul, because those
two cases are actually two cases of the Attwell algorithms.
So let's try practicing making pairs now.
So here's a coin.
We have white, green, red again and you to go here and I would find the edge.
It's right here, red and green.
However, this corner is not facing this way.
And these two edges are the same color, which means we cannot do a sexy move to insert it.
As you can see, I didn't do anything.
So instead, what we can do is what if we try and get this edge into this light right here before inserting
it?
So you might think that we just have to do this, but that obviously displaces this.
We have to move this or this corner.
We have to move this corner out of the way somehow.
So if we do this, that messes up the back.
So we can't do it on this side.
Same with over here.
This gives us no way to insert it because we move it over here.
Then these two colors do not match.
We can't do it over here, which matches up this pair and we can't do it over here either.
So from this position, we want to put the corner in the top right where the slot is facing us.
And now here, you're the best position to not to, because now I can move this corner out of the way
without breaking anything.
And then I can move this edge and then bring this back up.
And you can see that we formed a pair.
And then I can just go and go to the side and incident.
So it's the exact same thing when we have a case like this.
We still have our corner over here.
Here's our edge.
And these two are still matching.
But instead of being over here, this piece is over here now.
So this is really easy.
This is exactly the same as the last case.
If we just move the corner out of the way instead of doing a U.
We can do in two to move this in the correct spot and then bring this corner back, and then we could
just easily insert it.
OK, let's say we have a case like this one.
So our white is over here facing that way, which means it's ready for insertion.
But this edge is over here.
So these two colors are not matching.
And this edges over here, which means that we cannot simply move this out of the way and put the edge
next to it, because that means the colors would mismatch.
And that's not what we want.
So we can't do a sexy move here either, because that wouldn't put the edge in, since it's not in the
right slight to be paired with this corner.
So instead, what we can do is use that last technique from the last pair to move this edge into a place
we want it to be and then insert it.
So right here, this is our open slot that we can work with.
So I'm going to move this corner to the back of this open slot so that when I move this side down,
then nothing gets interfered with over here.
So once I move the side down, obviously, I don't want to go here, because that means that this matches
the colors.
So instead, I want to move this over here, because when I move this side up, ill form up here, so
I'll go down here, move this over to this light, and then move the corner back up.
Now, you can see that when I move this side up, it solves the path.
So we go back to our open slot right here and get ready to insert it.
And we just do a sexy move.
And there we go.
A case like this is very similar.
It's basically the last step, but this edge has been already prepared up with this side and has already
been moved to this light.
So all week, all we have to do is really move this out to where we want it to go and then insert it
just like in the last step.
So here's our open slot.
If we just move this down, we can see that these since these two are mismatching, then we want this
edge to go here so we can match it up with this pair like this.
So I'll move this down, move the edge over here, and then move this back up.
So now these two are ready to get inserted.
If I move it over to the slot, I want it to go in and then insert it.
So this is exactly the same as the last step, if we have a case like this.
We have our corner already solved and our edge is already solved, but not oriented correctly.
So this is this would be fine.
This needs to be flipped over.
And this is actually one of the longest cases.
But it's really easy after we learn the lesson.
So all we have to do is take this out, which is like reverse inserting it.
So if we do the reverse of the insert, then now we've taken this out and then we just have the last
step again so we can move this out of the way.
And here's our open slot.
This is the mirrored version.
We just move the corner out.
We want the ads to go here so we can insert it.
So we do want you to move this quarter back.
And now we have a left side insertion.
So this will pair up with the edge over here.
And then we can insert the pair onto this bar and move it down.
And that solves it.
So a case like this is actually one of my favorites because it's really easy to do and really smooth.
So as you can see here, this slight we have orange, blue this time, all these others are solved.
So our blue edge is already solved.
It's in the correct spot and it's oriented correctly.
But this corner just needs to jump down here and flip itself over.
So.
All we have to do in this is it's really easy to put this on the right facing you and do three sexy
moves, that's it.
So are you are prime, you prime.
Are you are you prime?
And since sexy moves are really fast and really easy to do, then those moves are done really smoothly
and it's it's really nice to perform.
So let's say we have a case like this.
Here's our Orange Blue and here's our Orange Bowl ads.
And I'm going to ignore the green orange first, because let's say that the green orange is harder to
solve.
So are our corner need to go here and our age needs to go here.
So I originally I would do the green orange just to displace this one.
However, let's say that this one is harder to solve than this case.
So I want to show you how to solve this case.
If it was if it was the easiest one to do from here, we want to put this on the left side so that our
corners over here and our edges over here.
All I'm going to do is keeping this edge here.
I'm going to move this corner up into the top this, and then I'm going to move this corner into this
slot to make it ready for insertion.
So I'll do a YouTube.
And then once I bring the edge down, you can see that now I have a perfect insertion case.
This corner is facing this way.
And our edge is back here with opposite colors.
So I can just insert it.
And that's always the case.
And then over here, just for fun, we see we have this one against we do three sexy moves and it's
really fun to do.
Let's say we have a case like this one, it's similar to the other case where both are already solved,
but one is oriented incorrectly.
So here are edges in the solid state.
But this court needs to be flipped down this way.
So we have to take this pear out again and then reorient it and then put it back in.
And the best way to do that is simply take the pear out by reverse inserting it.
And now we have a case like this.
So remember, we just move the corner to the back of the open slot.
And we want to put this ad here since these colors are matching.
And there we have our pair, and then we just moved here and we can do reverse sexy move, which led
to an incident.
I'm going to do a sledge hammer this time.
And there's our pair.
So it's the same thing for the murder case here, we just have the last one, except instead of the
corner being flipped this way, it's flipped this way.
So it's facing to the right.
So what I'm going to do in this position is I'm going to put this side on the left.
I'm going to do a mirror case to it.
So I'm going to move the left side up and orient this corner into this light.
So it's facing in the correct position.
And now we have a repeat of this case.
So with the same hands, I don't have to do any rotations.
I just move this corner to the back of the open slot.
And I want to move this edge here since these these colors are matching.
So I move this portrait out of the way, move the edge into this light and put it back.
And there's a pair.
And then we can do a left hand sledgehammer to insert it.
And there we go, it's solved.
Let's see what happens if we have a case like this.
So we have our pairs right here.
They're connected, but this corner is flipped the wrong way.
And if we flipped over here.
So what we'll do, we already see that these colors are not matching.
So this edge needs to go over here.
So all I can do is move the corner to the back of the open slot again and then move the edge out of
the way to make this correct insertion form.
So now I just moved this back to the open slot.
And we have this case again, which is really easy.
We just do a sexy move.
And there we go.
It's all.
OK, so again, it's the exact same for the mered case.
Here we have our pair again.
So this needs to go flip the other way.
So here's our slight.
All I'll do is I'll move the corner to the open slot.
These two colors are not matching.
So this I need to go here.
So I'll move the corner down.
Move the edge into the slot.
Move this back up.
And then put this back and you can see that this is ready for insertion now and I'll just do a back
insertion.
So this is exactly the same, but I'm just doing it on the other side.
So match these up.
And here's our Baabda inserted into.
We have moved it in here.
And then move this down.
And there's our selfcare.
So I'm going to pause this section here or this lecture, because it's getting kind of long and I've
already went through a lot of afterworld cases to practice what I've shown you already get those all
down.
And then in the next lecture, we'll go over more afterworld cases and we'll do a bunch of examples.
So I should be covering pretty much every afterworld case there is.
And you should be able to get those all down once you learn in session and all that.
You should be able to do it intuitively.
You'll get a sense for it.
It's it's pretty nice to have.
But yeah, just keep practicing these and then we'll move on to the next lecture.
We will learn more at 12.