So the final tip is color neutrality.
But in my opinion, color neutrality is the least necessary step to improve your time.
So all it is, is the ability to do the cross on any color side instead of white or yellow.
So here you can see we have a green cross.
Everything's paired up with its corresponding centers.
And I still have another F to L case.
But we have to make really weird of two L pairs like this one.
So I have green, orange, red and sort of white matching up with light.
I do weird things like green matching up here.
I have to make pairs like this.
They look really weird with white on it.
Then I have to insert it into the correct slot.
And now this side looks really weird.
It's white.
The white is partially solved, which is not something I'm used to.
And everything can just be hard to comprehend.
So color neutrality is solely faster because of the existence of luck.
So in any given scramble like this one, the chance that the White Cross or Yellow Cross will be the
easiest to solve.
Out of all six colors is two out of six.
So over here, it just so happens that the Orange Cross.
Can simply be solved with an hour to move.
But since I'm not color neutral, then I would rather do the White Cross and just do something comfortable
to me.
So in a scramble like this, or whose color neutral would be able to solve a few seconds because they're
dressed up, would be really easily done.
But now they'd have to do to L and do it with weird pairs again, which can cost extra time.
So for me, all steps of the queue were basically ruined because I'm not used to doing Orange Cross
or any weird colored cross, so I'm barely color neutral.
And what I end up doing is wasting time on F to L trying to figure out how to make pairs, because I'm
just not used to making weird pairs with white in them.
So I'd rather spend my time improving on other stuff rather than learning color neutrality.
Because if I spend my time learning, for example, better F two L or how to be more efficient, I feel
like that would save more time rather than spending a lot of time learning how to solve the cross on
any colored center.
So if you do learn color neutrality, it'll save you a few extra moves, one to four at the start of
solving a cube and we'll save you like one second.
So basically, this is only necessary once you pass the ten second solved time barrier.
And I'm not even there yet, so I haven't even learned it.
But it's just not very it's not a very good use of your time.
You could spend your time learning other things and save way more seconds.
If you want to learn color neutrality, you can.
But I don't recommend it as it's not very necessary and hard to land.