So let's go through some more actual cases.
This one, it might look like we have to separate the edge and bring it over here.
But there's actually a better way of solving this one.
So instead of just disconnecting the edge with the corner in front, the slide in the back, instead
of doing this and then matching them up.
Another way we can do it is to put this whole thing in the back.
And then we move this side down.
Take this corner out this way and push this side up.
So now we've completely oriented this corner, and you can see that we have opposite colors on top.
So instead of having matching colors, we put this quarter down over here and this blue side came up.
And then also we kept this as in its place.
So we just set it up for insertion.
So once we do our prime, you are, then we can just do a YOUTU above the sizes to go in and insert
the piece.
Same thing here.
This is the Myrie case.
We have matching colors here and two pieces over here and they're not matched up.
So instead of doing this, an easier way to do it is to just put this above this light right here,
and then we're just going to do it the same thing as last time, but backwards.
So we're just going to take this corner over here, keeping the edge here.
Move it into this light and then bring it back.
So all we did was we flipped this corner over here and you could see that this is ready for insertion.
So you just inserted with the slide on the back a backwards insertion.
And there we go, that was much easier.
Let's say we have something like this.
We have our air here, but it cannot be answered because it's already taking up this lot.
So we'll take this pear out without breaking it and then we'll reinsert it to solve it.
So to take it out, I'm going to move it to this box.
Lots that can be easily inserted without breaking anything.
I'm going to first take this out and then use one move to put it back here and move this back down.
Now, we have a very easy insertion case.
I just go to this side, put the slide in the back.
I'll move the side up, do a YouTube move to match it, and then put this back down.
Here's another case.
We can see here we have our corner, it's solved, but it's oriented wrong and we have our edge over
here and it's making a bar.
So these two colors are not matching.
And we can see that if I move this side up, then we'll form a pair.
So that's exactly what I'm going to do.
But I'm going to do it in the back just so that it's easier to perform.
So I'll put this in the back.
I'll move this side up and match up there.
Move it out of the way and fix this side, and then I'll just do a Yuto to put it ready for insertion.
I'll go back to this side, move the side up, insert the pair, go back down and sobbed.
If we have something like this, these two are just completely it's a complete mess.
This is not oriented correctly.
This is not Marting, this one, and they're both like taking up slots.
What I'm going to do first is move this corner out of the way and I'm going to bring this up in a way
that these two will be ready for insertion.
So I'm going to do.
And are you our prime to bring this into here?
And now we have opposite colors over here.
White facing this way.
So I'll just put this above the slots.
And the seize up for him appear and insert it.
If we have a really another really messy case like this one, they're both in the right place, but
they're completely oriented on them.
Another way we can do this with is to take this one out and then we have a case like this.
But this would be a little bit too many moves.
So I'm going to show you a way that's a little bit faster by breaking these in the process of taking
them out.
So first, I'm going to do an F prime.
You F.
And now we could see that this judge is facing upwards and this edge is has been taken out over here.
So now we have a case from earlier.
I'm just going to match these up right here.
So I'll move this as back.
And then now if I move this quarter over for form up here and then move this over here.
So basically all I did was an hour our new are prime, then Bastos up and then I just insert it with
a sledgehammer.
And the reason I did a sledge hammer is because since I already have to move this side, I can just
do an hour, two instead of an hour prime.
So wall and mashing these up right here, I can do artu and instantly insert it without any breaks.
So here's another one.
We have our edge on this side, and it's up with green he to go to the left.
We have our corner here.
It's facing out this way and it's oriented wrong.
So first thing I'm going to do is take this quarter out and then match it up with this.
So I just take this out in the way that these colors are opposite.
And now we have a simple insertion.
Are you are prime, you prime?
And that solves it.
OK, so let's all the F to all cases I'm going to show you, I left out some of the married cases as
a challenge for you to figure out.
So once I showed you a case, if I didn't show you the mirror version of it, try and figure it out
yourself.
It's pretty simple.
Either just do it on the left side or do it from behind and you'll be able to get it as long as you
understand everything else.
And you'll easily be able to figure out the mirrors and you'll probably be able to intuitively figure
out how to solve it.
F2 Alpen without having to refer to this course or find an algorithm.
So crisis after.
Well, do do a bunch of examples of these with AV and just try to insert, try to match up.
Just keep practicing and you'll be able to do it very intuitively.
You'll be able to solve any pair in your mind without having to look it up or get help.
So eventually you'll be able to do it and it will become muscle memory.
And now I'm going to move on to some examples of just so that you can see some special cases or in case
you're confused on something or what you should start with.
So let's move on to those.
OK, so here's our first scramble.
We have resolved cross.
And let's look around for a first apair that might be easy to solve.
This is really obvious.
We have a mash up here right here, which is lucky.
So if it needs to go into is here, I'm going to insert it simply with a very sexy move.
And that solves it.
So now let's just look around for another pair.
These two might work.
Let's see these two maybe.
Oh, here we go.
We have our orange GreenEDGE solved and we have our orange edge over here.
So we need to go to the left.
So we'll do the same algorithm through insert it.
That's too soft to look around for more.
Here's another pair we have this case, the colors are matching and the corners facing this way.
So this edge needs to go here to make a pair.
So I see that this line is open, so I'll just use this light to match them up.
And that broke nothing, and now we have our pair, since this is in the back, I'm going to do a YouTube
and insert it through the back.
So I just moved this side down, bring this up, puts it in and fix it, and that solves it.
And then here's our last pair.
We have one of these cases.
So I'm going to keep it over here.
And we can see that this slot is open in the back.
So all I'm going to do is use this to break over these edges.
So I'm going to move this down.
I want to move this edge here since these colors are not matching.
I want you to put this back up.
Now, we have a simple insertion case where it's easily paired up, easily like this.
So I just move over to this side.
I'll put this above the slot and I'll do a left handed version.
And there you go, it's solved, and that's our first at Rodon.
All right, here's our next case, we have a sore cross again.
And first, let's look around for a pair that might be easy to solve.
So I see green and orange.
Are the red stuck down here?
Probably don't want to do that.
These two might be easy, but the slots in the back and then are blue.
Red.
This this is stuck down here.
So it seems like we're just stuck between orange, blue and green.
Orange.
I think I'm going to sort of blue orange first.
So again, using the open light, since all slots are open, it doesn't really matter anyway, which
is facing me.
This one needs to go here.
I'll move the corner out, move the edge and pull it back.
And there's are as a pair, I can just move this over, go to this side and insert it.
And then immediately I see this pair here.
I think I'm going to solve that one first because it's right next to me.
So do you two.
Now we have this case.
So again.
Because these are not noshing, we want to move this over here so we can form a pair like this.
And then the slot is back here.
So let's do a YOUTU and then this forms our pair and brings up the side to insert into.
So I just one the pair move this in and then put it back.
That solves it.
What else do we see?
OK, it seems like this is the easiest because these two are completely messed up, so we have blue,
red and blue red here.
So I'm going to have to move this side down so that I can form a pair like this.
But this side gets messed up.
So I have to do it on a different side so I can do it on this side.
If I just rotate to the blue side, then now there's an open slot in the back so I can move this side
down, pair the two up with a youtoo and move it back up.
And there it is.
And we'll move it here to a simple insertion.
And that solves it.
And then I see our lost her over here.
This is actually set up really nicely for our other algorithm.
So we see we have this case again.
The two are not matching, but the two on the top are matching.
So instead of just separating them, an easier way again is to move the core out and completely flip
it.
So with an ellu, Prime Alperin moves.
And now we can see we have this case.
These two are not nothing.
So just move this above the slot, rotate to this side, and then insert the left hand insertion.
And that's another Attwell.
Here's the next one.
South Cross, look around for a pair.
Look around for a corner and edge.
There might be easy to solve.
So here's my orange green.
Here's my red green.
Here's my red, blue and.
I'm not even going to bother looking for the other one, but there it is.
It's just not going to be easy to solve if I can't find it anywhere.
So I'm going to solve this one since they're already kind of paired up and right in front of me.
So these two are not matching.
So I want to move this edge here.
So I'll move the corner out.
Push the edge over.
Put it back.
Now, these two are ready to be inserted, needs to go here.
So our prime is already l u l crime.
Here's our next.
We have blue and red and you see, oh, here we have another easy case.
We just move this corner down.
Paramount needs to go right here, so this insertive.
What's next?
I'm going to do these two next, so.
They need to go back here, and this is in the wrong light.
So when I rotate this side down, I'll bring this corner over here while moving the edge over here,
which makes it ready to pair up.
So this edge will get moved here or this corner will be flipped over here and we'll have an opposite
color case again.
So then I just do it back in person again.
Put that in and there's a lost one.
So here's our open slot.
We can't do it here that breaks thread, so I'll go over to this side.
Break them up.
Push it in the back and then just do a simple insertion and that Sulligent.
If I do, one more example of and then we'll move on to oil.
OK, here we are.
Here's our cross look around for pairs.
We have another lucky pair already made over here.
So this is obviously going to be what I saw first.
I'm just going to do that right now before I look for anything else.
It's still here.
So I just do our prime you to l solves it.
Now let's find a pair.
We have red green and these two corners are stuck in the bottom.
So I'm going to solve my red green first.
But I take this out.
Move it to the back.
Separate them.
And then now another ready.
So light in the dark.
We have this over.
Pair them up.
Moving in the back.
Here's my next pair, Atheel, here.
This is another nice case.
This move this to the back of the open slot.
Break them.
And then insert them.
And then here's our last one has already solved this irds needs to go left.
So the same algorithm for earlier.
And there we go.
So if you were confused on any of those, just ask me a question.
I can clarify something if you need to.
But yeah, that should be all in all there is to after.
Well, I'll just keep practicing and you'll see what's there to do.
And if you just look at the use of the cross, look for a pair notwist pair you want to do first.
And just keep looking around for other pairs that you want to solve.
Then you'll be able to intuitively do it.
And every muscle memory for you.
So, yeah.
Let's go on to L.