So the first method after the Yellow Cross is the easier one.
But it's really useless.
And you don't use a you barely use any of the algorithms from it.
So I'm going to show you what it is, but I'm not going to teach you the algorithms because they are
not necessary.
So at this step, we take our Yellow Cross and we want to get these edges matching their centers, just
like how we did for the White Cross.
So we solve them.
Now, all of them are lined up and all these ideas are now solved.
And then what we do is we look for a corner that's in its right spot, but not oriented correctly.
So red, green and yellow, you can see that's between yellow, red and green.
So this is in the right spot.
All we have to do is flip it this way and it'll be solved.
So if we can do that for every corner, then we'll be able to orient all the corners at the same time.
So we just use an algorithm to position all the corners in the right place.
The orange blue is not solved yet because it's between blue and red.
Now it is so easy, red, blue with red, blue, red, green, green, orange and blue, orange.
So these all can just be flipped upwards and they'll sell the cube.
That's exactly what we're going to do.
Using the same algorithm from earlier.
Our prime de prime already sold this one and then move another quarter into the slot.
And then once we move that back, I saw the cue.