So the other way from here is to solve the yellow top and then solve the last layer.
And this is identical to old on pilo.
So if you know how to do this method, then it will be really easy to learn the other two.
So we start after solving the Yellow Cross by looking for a case like this known as the case or the
fish case.
We have one corner oriented in the bottom left and no other corners oriented.
We have one yellow facing us.
So towards us and not this way.
So if we do an algorithm from here, we'll instantly solve the yellow talk.
That algorithm is our you, our prime.
You are you to our prime.
You see the other side is solved.
But let me show you what to do if you don't get a scene.
So in a case like this one, we have no corners oriented, so we don't have a fish case.
What we're going to do is we're going to put this in any direction and do the same algorithm until we
get assoon.
So from here.
Are you are prime you are you to our prime.
Oh, there's a scene first try.
So put this in the bottom left corner facing us.
Are you our prime?
You are.
You two are prime one the top.
OK, so after solving the yellow side, we want to solve this corner first and then put the edges in
the right spots.
So we look for a pair of headlights like this one, which is just two corners that have the same color.
They're facing you.
So you can see we don't have headlights here.
These are not the same color.
These are not headlights, but these are headlights.
So if we get headlights like this one, we want to put it in the back and do the algorithm.
Our climb up our prime to r f prime, our prime to our two.
And you can see that now we've solved all of the headlights.
So all of these corners are solved, including one edge back here.
But let me show you what to do if you don't get headlights.
OK, so here we are back with the Salvio side, and you can see here that we don't have any headlights.
All these all these corners are not matching.
So.
We're going to do similar to before the same algorithm, but from any side until we get headlights.
So I'll just do it from here.
Our prime F, our prime E to our F prime, our prime Dinka are two.
And let's look around.
There's our headlights so we can put this in the back now and do the do it again.
Our prime as our prime into our prime, our prime e to our two.
And that's all the corners.
And I got lucky.
And it's all the edges, too, but mainly to solve these corners.
OK, so after that last stop, this is what the most common case looks like.
We have one small side just like this.
So this edge is solved and then we have three edges that are not solved.
So we still have headlights on every side.
But this as needs to go here, this will need to go here and this one needs to go here.
So what is use one algorithm to do that?
So put this bar in the back.
Put the subsite in the back.
And our new algorithm is, are you prime?
Are you are you are you prime our prime new prime artu?
Looks like it didn't do it this time.
So what keep this in the back, do that algorithm again.
Are you prime?
Are you are you are you prime?
Our prime, you prime are two.
And that's all Oliver edges and subtractive.
So that's about it for beginners method.
Make sure you know, all the algorithms I went through, because those are the important ones and not
the ones I didn't go through.
So all the algorithms that I taught you in this beginners method review will be used later on.
Make sure you know those.
Memorize those.
Write them down on paper.
Practice them.
So, yeah, let's let's move on to Cifas.