Hello everyone and welcome to this course in the previous section.
We learned how to define basic variables how to perform some mathematical operations how to do some
presidents which is you know kind of very important foundation if you're going to start learning programming.
And this section we're going to dig a little bit deeper into more a kind of intermediate concepts per
say.
So we're going to cover what we call it the comparison operations.
So we're gonna cover the comparison operators.
We're going to cover what we call it logical operators and we're going to cover condition statements
which is what we call it if else statements.
All right.
OK.
I'm super excited because this section will going to be kind of the first step to actually start building
kind of professional read world codes in Python.
So let's go ahead and define the.
What do you mean by comparison operators.
OK.
So when we perform any programming in general what we need to do that we wanted to compare two values
with each other.
OK.
So in order to compare two values.
All right let's say I have two values for example of two two parameters.
Let's say A and B for instance and I wanted to compare these two parameters together.
How can I do that comparison.
Let's see.
So let's assume that I wanted for example to compare number 15 compared to let's say Number 8.
So he would have number 15.
And I wanted to compare to number eight.
And I wanted to say for example if 15 is greater than eight.
So in order to write greater or less than we use basically these kind of operators to do this.
So let's go ahead and run this cell and let's see what's going to happen.
So if we're on the cell you're going to get a feedback or you know pay something to the playback telling
you actually that was true.
Yes.
Why.
Because you are asking kind of you know Python OK is 15 greater than eight.
OK.
So the answer is true.
That's right.
That means you actually have done comparison between the value 15 and between the number eight.
All right.
OK let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to compare for example five equals greater than for example or equals to
five.
Just very simple again example if we're done that that would tell me yes that's actually true.
Why.
Because I said I asked Python again is five greater than or equal five.
Yes actually five was equals to five.
So again Python replied back and tell you Well that was true.
OK.
And you can actually check pretty much all the operations in here.
So the first operation that's kind of the most important one we're going to be using extensively in
the practical part of the Course is we'll call it equal equal.
OK.
So simply you're comparing two values.
And you are saying if a equals equals B or if a equals b.
All right.
If it's true if that's true then post I'm going to apply back to you tell us.
That was true.
If not it will apply back tell you it was false.
Let's take a look.
So let's say I'm asking is five equals equals to five.
Let's run it shift enter.
That would tell me what.
Well that was true.
Right.
So I'm asking is five equals equals let's say six.
If I run it they'll tell me no.
That was false.
That wasn't right.
OK.
So they think the key important element here is why we don't just he was one equals.
Why did it and say for example five equals two six.
If I do this.
Tell me know that well that's not right because one equals sign is what we call it assignment.
That means you are assigning value.
You are copying value from the right hand side into the left hand side.
So if I say let's say x equals to six.
Yes that would work.
That means I'm putting six into the parameter x.
If I take a look at X you'll find it X contains six.
Which makes sense right.
All right.
OK.
So in order to perform conditional kind of perform a conditional comparison we use equal equal.
If you wanted to do an assignment which is you know putting value in a specific variable we use just
one single equal.
All right.
So what we could do as well is that we can actually perform comparisons on strings as well.
So let's take a look.
Let's assume that I wanted for example to compare.
Hello.
OK is hello.
Equals equals two.
Hello.
All right let's run that.
Now tell me whether that was true.
OK let's do it again.
Let's say it is Hello equals equals to Hello.
OK.
So please notice the difference here.
So the difference here was one of them was total.
All of them were uppercase.
And here the first letter only was uppercase and all of them were lowercase.
If we're wrong that you will find that the answer is false.
Which means when we tried to perform any comparisons on strings we have to make sure that all the letters
are actually the same.
Of all of them are uppercase then all of them here has to uppercase in order to get a true answer.
OK.
All right.
One more operator.
Which is what we call it not equal.
OK.
So for example if you're competing let's say the value of six and your value of five and you wanted
to compare five and six.
What we do is that we use the simply the exclamation mark equal the exclamation mark equals means not
equal.
So here if I'm saying for example is six not equal five.
Well that was true.
That's right.
Why.
Because six was actually not equal five.
So again if we press shift enter that will return back true.
If I say let's say it's five let's say not equal five.
And if I done that they'll tell me Well that was false.
Why.
Because five is actually equal to five.
It's you know when I ask if it's five.
Not equal five.
What.
Actually the statement was false.
All right.
OK.
Sounds great.
So let's go back a bit here to the table.
So again the equal equal that means if you're comparing two values you know like equal to the equal
to each other or not.
Exclamation mark equals.
That means they are not equal.
OK.
Here if you wanted to do greater than or less than he had you wanted to do if we are greater than all
right that's less then that's greater than or equal.
And that's less than or equal.
And that's very important comparison operators.
We're going to use them extensively throughout the course and they actually really really interesting
really powerful too.
All right.
Let's take a look at you know kind of a mini challenge.
I'm going to give you two examples.
And I'm going to ask you to pause the video and please go ahead and try to do that challenge yourself
without running the code please.
Because if you're on the code you know it doesn't make sense.
I wanted to kind of practice and tell me if you if you get the idea or not hear them saying OK is 15
greater than let's say six and is 15 not equals to six and a 15 is equals equals six.
And if 15 is less than or equal to six.
All right.
Please go ahead and pause a video and just you know guess what the answer should be on all of these
four conditions.
All right.
We're going to see you after the challenge.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge again without running the code.
So here 15 is 15 greater than six.
Well that was true.
So the answer I'm expecting was actually two is 15 not equals to six.
Well that was actually true as well.
Right.
So here 15 was not equal to six.
That was true is 15 equals to six.
Well that was false.
That doesn't make sense.
It's 15 less than or equal six.
That was false as well.
All right.
Let's make sure that our answers are true.
So can I go here to the cell.
Please shift enter shift enter shift enter shift enter.
And that's what we're getting we're getting true true false false.
All right looks great.
OK.
And that's pretty much all what I have for the for the first section.
Let's go ahead and recap what we have done so far.
So here we have just quickly covered what we called the comparison operators which is can be used to
compare two variables together.
If you're comparing you know that values wanted to compare if they are equal.
And please remember they are equal equal not equal greater than or less than greater than less than
greater than or equal or less than or equal.
And again the answer might be true or false depending on the condition.
And one important thing as well regarding the strings you need to make sure when you're comparing two
strings together is that all the letters have to match so that all of them are lowercase here.
All of them have to be lowercase.
If he had all of them are lower case here one of them for example is just upper case then the answer
is going to be false right away.
All right.
I hope you guys enjoyed that lecture and see you in the next lecture.