Hello everyone and welcome to this new project.
I am super excited because this project is actually one of my favorites because it deals directly with
real data and real views and what we gonna be doing here is we're going to do Amazon Alexa review rating
analysis.
All right.
So basically you guys are not familiar whether there is Amazon had a device called mini Amazon Echo
or Amazon where it runs Amazon Alexa.
So think of it as kind of an assistant you can ask Alexa to do whatever Alexa.
You know like for example play some music.
Alexa what's the weather today and so on so forth and what we are trying to do here is that we are trying
to kind of do some analysis to the customer reviews.
Actually three thousand Amazon customer reviews and star ratings and it just the overall idea here in
this project is to show you what we could do when we tried to do some analysis on like you know like
large amount of data like this especially if it includes you know kind of what we call it sentiment
analysis how can we do kind of some analysis to like if people love for example a product or not you
know if let's say people hate it or not if let's say there are some good reviews bad reviews and so
on to try to understand just get a feeling of what these customers are wanted to to do what to say.
So in this lecture I actually this project I'm going to dig into it like how to perform like the machine
learning out of it how can we let's say training classifier for example to let's say predict our star
rating when I'm going to be doing this.
What we gonna be doing here is just some data visualization some data manipulation I'm going to show
you how can we do that some data plotting to how can we actually like take data like this and visualize
it in an an amazing way.
And that's pretty much what they'll be doing and the projects Project's actually pretty pretty interesting.
I hope you guys were going to be able to enjoy it.
So let's take a look at kind of a project overview and I'll walk you through the key steps we're going
to be doing in this project and we're going to start again with a blank Jupiter notebook and then I
build up the project from scratch step by step.
All right so let's take a look at the data.
So data set consists of three thousand Amazon customer reviews star ratings.
There is a data review that is a variant which is you know if you if you check out the Amazon's Web
site you would find that there are so many variance there is maybe like you know like White for example
color there may be like charcoal color there maybe like in a walnut color and so on.
So maybe this information or that variance or call it variation might have an impact for example on
the customer reviews.
Who knows we'll going to try to find that information together and then the feedback of various Amazon
Alexa products which is the feedback column will merely include kind of you know the feedback was positive
or negative.
We're just going to have maybe like number one that indicates it's positive zero indicates it's negative
and so on.
So the objective the objective is to discover insights into customer reviews and put forward maybe some
sentiment analysis on the data because when want to take a look at the data the source of the data obviously
the data is readily available online.
You can go to Kaggle through this link you'll find that information and please what we're gonna be doing
here in this project we're going to use a package or a library called the word cloud.
Please go ahead and do your command window and do pip in this tall word cloud.
Okay.
You should find you know like like you know the if my take on it in my case it took like five seconds
or 10 seconds or so and it just went and downloaded.
So when we go here and we do import for example word clouds actually coming up down here when we import
when we say
from word cloud import word cloud when we do this we'll be able to actually we're not going to get an
error right.
But if you actually run the exact same notebook but without downloading workload or installing work
cloud then you know if we will come up with an error which is I don't want to do when it goes you guys
to to have any errors in here.
All right.
OK.
So let's take a look at what going to be doing here.
First we're gonna pull the data and this is a data gonna be checking out.
So it looks like we have you know multiple reviews in all of my echo.
Loved it and so on and then we're gonna do some analysis.
You know there's some reviews that we're having here.
We're gonna check out some you know the list of did some perform some data visualization.
We're going to check in all at positive reviews negative reviews.
We're going to see the count how many positive how many were negative.
We're going to see here the count plot the rating.
How many was five star rating.
How many was nothing.
How many.
We're gonna take a look at the different variations too.
So these are the different variations of the products.
Again I'm just walking really quick because in the next lecture we're gonna start again from the blank
page you're going to do all these steps.
I'm just when I walk you through what we're gonna be doing here in this project and then here we're
gonna take a look at our reviews and we're gonna do like really interesting kind of visualizations we'll
call it a word cloud.
It just you know like a plot that shows you like what are the common words that has been you know like
mentioned in the review it's really amazing like I really love this.
This very visual to tell you you know like these are the Commonwealth is Alexa there is love in here
that means you know a lot of people actually love the product that is you know like there's music there
is like great you know which is amazing there is like no everything you know can do everything for you
or something maybe bedroom.
A lot of people using it in the bedroom for instance there is like better product really and so on it's
it's really powerful where you're actually visualizing the data but I'm actually visualizing all the
data because it opened to visualize whatever data you want maybe bad reviews only good reviews only
and so on.
And then what we gonna be doing afterwards we to do some what we call a data cleaning or feature engineering
which is really amazing to what we're gonna do here.
We're going to look at every single word every single word in there and try to create kind of account
called account vector risers just try to count how many words for example of let's say Love has been
contained within review for example this is a review called Love Love Love for instance we'll going
to try to translate this into a number into a code and that code will indicate you know like an information
so we can why are we doing this we're doing this so we can know for example how many people for instance
let's say said the word love for example their comments how many people said the word let's say hate
may be like quality maybe stuff like that we can get a feel of what people are talking about and it's
really powerful.
All right.
And what we could do here afterwards we could
hear plot the histogram so I can show you how can we plot histogram of all the data here and then we're
going to take a look at maybe some of the reviews some of the shortest review some of the longest reviews
and that's pretty much it that we're going to conclude our project it's really interesting project C
stay tuned and I'll see you guys in the next lecture we're going to start with a blank Jupiter notebook
and build all this from scratch.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.