Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
This lectures we're going to keep going and know continue the solutions of the exercise meaningful for
available assignments presidents and mathematical operations.
So let's take a look.
So here I am asking you to write a code that takes the dimensions of a cube.
OK.
Which is let's say a.
And then paint its area and its volume right.
Because we're able to figure that out.
So we're going to find a value called a.
And I put let's say 20 into it and around it that will generate a nothing happened.
But I can check and go here and can view aids were there a quiz 20.
Right.
And what I could do I get any took a couple of cells press a couple of cells.
And what I could do here is going to say okay area equals two it's six multiplied by a multiplied by
eight.
Right.
So let's do it in a more simple basic way six multiplied by a multiply by a.
All right.
Looks great.
And I could think the area again and I can actually view it here to run it that will generate twenty
four hundred.
Alright that's okay.
Looks good for the volume okay.
What it could do then into volume is actually a CUPE or eight.
Well I could do amnestic volume.
OK.
Equal to a very simple four times a again.
Times a.
In a very very simple form.
If I did that and if I wanted to view the volume around it that would generate a thousand which is basically
the volume of my cube.
If the side is 20.
If I want to change the side and make it let's say here it's a whatever you know it's a two for example.
I don't have to go and do over all over again and just go and you know I run it and that will kind of
be in the update for me.
Give me the idea and then give me the volume afterwards.
All right sounds great.
The next question that we have is I want you to protocol that takes a number and incremented three times.
Again you are free to choose whatever number you want.
OK.
But let's take a look.
So you're going to say okay X equals two let's say 40 k..
What do they they're to incrementally three times.
If you're going to get a call you can do it in two other two ways.
You can do it first.
You say okay X plus equals two three.
Right.
Which means dig the old X and see to it.
And the results we're going to be the new X which is 43.
If I do that and if I wanted to view X if I run it then I come up with 43 great extent I can actually
do with the other way around and say say X equals 240 right.
And I can say okay X or equals to X new plus 3 or 8 and then I can view X and that there will need 43
46.
Exact same answer.
That's one way of doing it.
The other way of doing it which is you know pretty very very simple.
You can actually go heat as well.
So okay I'm not going to the.
And then at plus one or I and they're going to come here at plus equals plus equals to 1 and then x
plus equals to 1 which is obviously we're not going to go there and I'm going to do this anymore.
He did just again because it's kind of you know the Absolute.
After the beginners bet they'll get 240.
Add one add one and one to it.
And if I run it again the exact same answer.
Which means it took the first X you know a day to become 41 to 41.
They did become 42 41 42 of they did become fully 3.
That's what we're going to do here.
All right why am i explaining it this way.
I mean spinning it this way.
Because in the future we're going to learn how to do for the loops and why loops which is you know where
you take that comment and sort of writing it three times.
I can just condense it in one comment that does it repeats whatever operation for us several times which
is going to come really handy really powerful in the future.
Right.
OK.
Let's take a look at the next example.
So the next example that we have here is I'm asking you what went wrong.
Headlines the code so that Z becomes equal to 50.
Actually let's zoom in a little bit on it.
So I'm asking yoki think the value of x equals 20 y equals 230.
And I'm asking you to tell me what went wrong.
Okay so let's say let's assume I don't know what happened here and Arun it would Daimyo case something
went wrong.
Name is not defined which means I didn't define what is a then an operation.
I say define X yes I define Y.
But then in the final key What's s and then find that.
OK so what I'm asking you to do is to simply go here and line.
Okay so simply define S.
OK so again and find S here.
Okay so the answer is going to become equal to 55.
So I know that if I add explicit Y that would need 50 right so let's define S and put 5 into it.
OK which means 20 plus 30 plus 5 which in the 55 if one and that then.
Nothing will happen because it plods Z.
But if I create a cell here and it Z I around it then become a come up with the answer 55 which is basically
what I was asking you to do.
K I.
OK the next question that we have here is I'm asking you to write code that performed the following
mathematical operation.
I want you to simply deny the value of z and simply give the absolute of x minus y multiplied by x plus
why.
Okay.
All right.
How can we do that.
So if you get a call we have done let's say they find any valid values for x and y can say X equals
to four.
Okay.
They're going to say y equals two let's say two for example and they're going to say Z equals stew.
And what it could do to do absolute is if you call it was a B s just to do the absolute open brackets.
I'm going to say X minus Y.
OK.
That would be the first part.
And then do multiplication.
Can open the brackets.
I'm going to say X plus Y.
That's basically writing the exact same equation as a guest can see it.
And then here we're going to plot Z to view what's inside there.
Let's try let's let's run it.
And that was a 12 gauge.
Which simply put Peter got forward minus two which becomes two and then multiply by six which is four
plus two.
And that will generate 12 for us which makes complete sense.
Right.
Great.
The next question that we have here I am asking you to basically go through these kind of you know lines
of code.
Again there's tons of information in here again and you wouldn't find this kind of common that in the
concept lectures I'm not going to cover all concepts here.
I'm just going to introduce for example in the exercise some new concepts where you guys can you know
do for example extend the research.
Okay.
So here kind of you know introducing a new concept for you guys in the exercise event are kind of some
restrictions in a very big naming.
You can just go in name very and whatever you want.
These are kind of the allowable names you can for example do underscore salary that works.
Yes that's not a problem.
Salary under score.
OK.
That's not a bad salary one salary 2018 salary under the squawky.
You can do all these variables are you know valid.
They are look great.
If you do all of them you know kind of upper case that's fine.
But bear in mind that salary lower case is completely different variable compared to salary uppercase.
These are kind of represent totally different variables which means that you can go ahead and refer
to them again.
Okay.
We need to make sure that all the letters match.
Okay so will then that means you only fit into the exact same value.
Okay.
What about the Big Nose Knows what you know what you should do what you should and do it should start
available with a number you can go and say okay let's see two salary that doesn't work or if you use
any of the reserved words in here.
So here we have kind of a list of reserved words which is simply put a couple of words that we are not
allowed to use like for example for from Twitter try while true.
Just don't use them.
Why.
Because they mean something else for Python Python just to use them.
You know the kind of differently.
Okay.
So I'm asking you to do here is to simply go through that code okay and try to see which one is allowed.
Which one is not.
And make sure the record run OK.
All right so all if we've done it you'd come up with your invalid syntax comes off.
Ed we're going to show up.
Okay so first of all salary equals 20.
That looks great for me.
You know my problem is upper case salary equals 25.
Not a problem too.
But bear in mind this salary is completely different than this.
There's just totally two different variables.
I dare say for equal stenn.
Okay first four it's actually one of them is old words here.
So if you go up here you would see that Ford is here which is one of the reserve words which is kind
of you know not allowed to use and actually peiser on its own or an old book on its own which will highlight
it as green which means do use or right which means to do that you have two options either to deleted
or to do what with quality comment or commenting.
What in my comments so actually if you go ahead and do hashtag here.
And if you do space you'll see that the column has changed which means that basically this line becomes
a comment becomes kind of words that posted.
We're not going to be executing.
It's doesn't become a command anymore which means that the code we're going to go on to execute this
execute this come here.
Doesn't doesn't do anything just keep Do this do this looks good.
All right do it do this as well.
Looks good to me here.
Something is wrong.
What was it basically that we started that variable with number two which is again not allowed.
That's one of the stuff that we have not allowed to do is that we started a variable name with a number
we're not allowed to do this or you could do here can go and comment this gay or I underscore sandri
that works true equal 20.
Okay.
If you actually go up here you would see two as one of the reserved words you you're allowed to use
it.
So what it could do you're going to come here comment that out.
And Salad it underscored looks good underscored that it looks good to me.
Actually I do run it.
You will see again something is wrong but you would see that the wrong here has nothing to do with any
of that.
It's in the print comment which makes sense because here I am asking you to basically print something
that's not allowed anymore.
So I could and I copy this beast in here.
I'm going to go here.
Comment one of them which is kind of the given.
And I'm going to go here to remove the words that I had that I don't need to care for because they move
from here go here to move this one.
I don't need it.
We're go here move through.
I don't need it and all that looks great.
So if I were on this then you would come up with perfectly with the values 20 25 12 13 15 30 again here
we just cover print are going to show print simply now printed or stopped on the screen.
We can have lectured on print moving forward.
This just got kind of a quick exercise refresher for you guys to exercise their valuable naming and
which ones are allowed and which ones are not allowed.
All right.
OK.
Let's keep going.
So the question number 11 is I'm asking you to simply write a code that takes celsis temperature and
convert converted to fair and right.
So what I'm asking you to take celsis value multiplied by nine over five plus thirty two and that give
us an and hide value.
Okay.
So it could do here and say okay see for example the value of C which sense for Celsius let's call it
whatever let's assume it's 23 for example or let's say it's 20 or eight which is basically this value.
So simply when you run the code you should see that the result of the fair higher value is actually
68 which is the conversion that we're looking for.
So what it could do here basically is is going to add the exact same equation and say okay F which set
foot forward and height equates to nine divided by 5.
Multiply the answer by C right.
And then what it could do to add plus 32.
Let's make sure he took multiply this first which makes sense.
The answer again added to 32 looks fine.
And he knows it's going to show F which is what's and right and that right and that if Right and that
that would show me 68 which is exactly the same as we have here.
Looks great.
All right let's take another point.
Let's stay.
Let's say I think 40 degrees C in a go here.
Change it.
Make it 40 degrees C run it run it run it will generate 104 which is if you go up you'll see it's 144.
Basically this equation stands for the linear linear line equation simply OK.
So again the one to go into the mathematics of it but just you know here that's the intercept which
is you know like the intercept of the y intercept which is 3 two and that's kind of the slope of the
line which is you know the delta.
Why don't do X which is nine divided by five here.
And that's kind of the or the second conversion from Celsius temperatures to four in high temperature.
Again these codes are very useful.
Yes it looks simple but you can actually do it.
And you know like executed in reality like actually deploy it and use it for whatever application you
want.
Moving forward what I'm going to show you and show you how can we actually think that value is sort
of inserting the code.
I'm going to ask you moving followers to actually ask the users to improve that value so good as the
users to input.
What's the what's the temperature of today and the use it for this I think in a print the and hide value
for it more than for the last example that we have is asking you to write a code that converts from
kilometres per hour into miles.
But.
And I'm asking you to refer to this equation below again this is even simpler.
So you say okay kilometre per hour you can call it whatever you want.
And when I say let's say 90 which is you know like the value he they actually can see here let's say
it's 90 kilometres Brown.
What I could do.
Netsuke mph which sent from miles an hour per hour equates to exact same number point six to one 4.
Multiply this by kilometre per hour.
And then I'm going to show mph or a mile wide.
But if I am that one that done that that would generate fifty five point ninety to actually it looks
pretty.
This actual real This is actual like an old you value or even of you know image.
So here it is set our 90 kilometres per hour which stands for around 50.
This is 50.
Island 55 miles an hour which makes complete sense.
Let's take another example.
Let's go in and assume I'm going to do let's say pick for example want 80 kilometres for example I'm
going to say okay when 80 kilometres but our ground that saloum that on that that would generate around
111 miles per hour which makes complete sense.
Right.
Okay.
So again now we should be familiar with variables variables Simon's presidents and basic mathematical
operations.
Great job.
You guys should be proud.
I hope you guys enjoyed that section and see you in the next section.