Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the previous lecture.
We're able to cover the basics of how to create for loops and in this lectures we're going to learn
kind of a very easy way of creating a full loop using a keyword we'll call it range.
Okay.
All right.
So let's get a look first at what they mean by rains.
So rain generates a list of numbers which is used to iterate over with for loops.
So let's assume that I want to for example say to print numbers from 0 till 5.
All right.
So what I could do I'm going to say OK for i in range and here I can simply illustrate or iterate OK.
How many numbers I'm looking for.
So if I wanted let's say two print numbers from 0 to 5 I'm going to put here Number Six OK and bear
with me I know it might be a little bit confusing but this is just you know the way the way goes.
OK.
That is actually two confusing points.
All right.
So first I want to take it for i in range 6 and put column going to say Okay print.
Go ahead and print I should enter.
And here we go.
So we're able to print simply numbers from 0 up till 5.
So the first actually there's two points.
The first point is for loops when we do four loops using the range actually we start with an index of
zero.
OK.
So the index here starts with 0.
That's the first confusion.
All right.
Obviously in our world you know like as humans say no starts with one.
Right.
We don't.
We don't start with zero in general but that's what we.
That's how we know the index he works.
So going to take it for i in range six then first of all we're going to start with zero index based
meaning the list index of indices starts with zero not one that's four step the next step is we go here
if we list six we're not going to actually print the value of six we're going to print up two and excluding
the value of six which means I'm going to print number 0 1 2 3 4 and 5 and not 6.
All right.
Again let's take a look another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to let's say print range 0 and 10 that will generate numbers again integers
from 0 1 2 3 4 up until 9 and not including the value of 10.
All right.
I know it's strange.
That's fine but that's the way it works.
All right.
So I'm going to ask you guys to please go ahead and maybe posit video and print numbers.
OK.
From I want to print numbers from zero to 14.
All right.
That's what I wanted to do.
I wanted to print numbers from 0 to 14 using again obviously arranged.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
You guys were able to figure out the challenge.
What I ask you has to do is to print numbers from 0 to 14.
So simply you're going to take it for i in range.
And here are going to pass along and instead of because I want to 14.
Then he put 15 hit instead.
All right.
And afterwards I'm going to take a print and print I shift enter.
Here we go.
See you print the number 0 1 2 3 up until 14 we didn't include the value of 15.
All right.
Sounds great.
OK.
So let's go ahead and maybe print numbers from 49 49.
So going to say OK print.
All right.
And I wanted to print I obviously.
OK.
And before doing that that will be the body of the four.
So going to say OK tab I won't say four.
OK.
Say i in range and I wanted to print numbers from four till nine.
So I guess a fourth till 10.
All right.
And put my column here.
Enter.
Here we go.
So now we'll be able to if we put for example range here with only single value that means I'm going
to start from the number zero.
All right.
And I will keep going up to and excluding the value.
However if I wanted to let's say put range and I put two values four to 15 that means I'll be printing
numbers starting from four going up to and excluding the value of 10 second printing four five six seven
AB until nine.
All right sounds great.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted to print.
For instance let's say numbers.
OK that goes 1 3 5 9 and so on.
All right.
Let's see how can we do that.
First of all I take it for i in range.
And here I can pass along what I wanted to do.
They wanted to print numbers from 1 to 20 with a step of two.
All right.
OK that's kind of an even advanced form.
So again with using the word range you can use to kind of three ways of doing it.
First you can specify only one number and that should go from 0 up to and excluding that number.
Here you can specify range.
You can take it for till 10.
That means are going to be printing four to nine.
Another way of doing it you can see it for i in range want to 20 with step 2.
What you could do let's go ahead and actually print I and see what's going to happen and as we're going
to get.
We're gonna get one and then because we were mentioning step two.
So each two numbers we can do a step.
So that's what we did.
We skipped number two so.
Okay one and then three and then five and seven and so on.
Up until nineteen.
All right.
Okay sounds great.
Let's go ahead and maybe take a look at one another examples.
All right.
And actually before doing that example let's go ahead and actually go do a little bit of challenge.
What I want you guys to do is to print numbers.
All right.
With a step from one to 30.
All right with the step of three instead.
All right.
So again I wanted to print numbers from one to 30.
With the step three.
All right.
Let's do this.
Go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
We're asking us to do is to simply go ahead here and do pretty much the same that we have done in the
past when and take it for I in range and I'm going to pass along numbers from one till say 30 or 31.
And with the step of three.
All right.
So instead of Step Two before we're going to do step three.
And again come here and take a print.
I just enter.
Here we go.
So now I print one and then step it skip three then representing for 7 10 and so on up until 28.
OK.
If you wanted to maybe make it let's say print 31.
All right.
Maybe make it to 32.
And here we go.
OK.
So if you wanted to include maybe the note number thirty one for instance.
But obviously he'd want to print numbers from one to thirty two just going to stick to 30 here.
All right.
All right sounds great.
Let's take a look at one example.
For example let's assume that I wanted for example to let's say print numbers in a descending order.
So I wanted to print let's say numbers 10 8 6 4 and so on.
How can we do that.
Let's.
OK.
What we could do in a sec for i in range can pass along before here we started from a smaller number
going up to a bigger number right.
Well we could do here can do the opposite.
We're going to start from 10.
And I'm going to stop let's say at for example zero and I'm going to do a step of minus two.
All right.
OK.
When I say print print my value I should enter.
Here we go.
All right.
So what we could what we did here is that we went in in descending order.
We started from a large number 10.
And every time I'm going to go subtract values of two from each index I mean I say 10 and then eight
and then 6 4 and 2 and so on.
All right.
OK.
Sounds great.
Another way of actually doing it.
You can say OK for i n it's actually worth we'll call it reverse.
We're going to say reversed.
All right.
And you can pass along key range let's say number five for example.
And I'm going to go ahead and say print I shift enter.
And that's kind of a way of reversing kind of rates if I leave this range on its own it will go from
zero up to four.
But what I've done here with it reversed.
So they're kind of you know flip kind of the the the printing operation in a way it's going to say for
three two one zero and so on.
All right.
OK.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And this lecture we're able to kind of practice a little bit more on the reading the range keyword.
It's very powerful.
And if we saw if we can actually print the seeds of numbers starting from 0 up to and excluding that
value we're able to do that.
We had the mini challenge and we're able as well to go ahead and print instead of starting with index
0.
We can start let's say indexed for for example and this here and we're able to even step kind of you
know skip certain numbers by doing the step here.
All right.
And we have done kind of a mini challenge too and we're able as well to go in in a descending order
instead of ascending order by going from a large number and going down instead using the mining index
and or be able as well to use the keyword as well reversed.
If you wanted to print in a reverse hash in here as we have shown in this example.
All right.
Okay sounds great.
Keep it up.
You're getting better at it every day.
And next lecture we're going to discuss kind of an advanced form of looping is what we call it nested
loops.
All right.
And we're going to see as well kind of a little bit more advanced topics for the gods too for loops.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.