Hello everyone and welcome to the model training section.
All right so just let me recap real quick.
So first of all we know that the data the cancer data and we loaded it the we didn't have to clean the
data or anything.
Everything was pretty much ready for us.
We knew the head and tail all the data and then we verify the data afterwards using keyboard.
And then what we're going to do right now is that we wanted to simply set up the taining data set the
testing data set and actually run or turn our model.
Okay so let's get started.
First step is we wanted to define what are our x values or what's our inputs.
And I want our y events which is our outputs.
Okay.
So first step is to define our inputs X simply.
So what we're going to do.
They're going to let X equals to simply other data is contained within our data frame which is d.f.
underscored kenson if you go as they call that was simply our data free.
So we're going to do here is that we can do d.f. underscored cancer.
That's our data frame.
And what we need to do with that we need to include Yes it's the Empire values we want.
And fortunately we have the target in there.
We have the output included.
And what we need that we not only include the input and the X..
So we're going to do we're going to call that data free but instead we're actually going to drop the
last sample we'll drop the target column.
How can we do this we can actually use the method drop to actually drop our
column in order to do this.
We're going to define This is basically our target that we want it to drop.
Okay.
Any to define at what access we're going to be dropping from the dropping the in column that we're going
to find the access one is specifying the column.
Well again let's recap so I'm going to do that we called the Data frame need in time data for him except
the target event.
That will be our x value.
Okay.
You want to view it as a site X and let's run the cells.
That we tell us okay that's been much all very values.
And if we scroll down here.
Let's see if we have the target or not actually we don't have the target which is perfect.
That's what we expect.
The next step is that we wanted to define the output or why we're just simply our target column.
So we'll get to the final y equals to d.f. underscored cancer.
All right.
And we're going to do is we are going to simply the target column.
Simply that we're in the final weeks right.
So let's run let's fund the cell and then let's you why.
So simply you can see here this is simply our target values again.
So the users are ones.
If it's so if it's malignant or benign and we have the next 500 system on it the next step is we want
to let's insert a couple of cells and I'm going to need to do that we wanted to split our data into
training data and testing it.
If you get a call that we have to take in our model we're were going to do that we use a subset of our
data for training and then after them on the list trained what we're going to do in order to test the
model we're going to use the testing dataset which is data said that the modern has seen ever before.
OK.
So what we're going to do we're going to use the killer learn to actually does that for us.
So were going to do is going to load from Escuela and we're going to try to model selection underscored
selection.
And again we're going to specifically imports.
Okay gene tests split actually full a tab that will actually do like an auto complete for you so that
what you're going to your team to split which is simply the method going to be using to split the split
data into testing entity.
Let's run this gets done successfully.
The next step we're going to do it that we are going to use to split screen test if we're going to have
a complete and if we click shift tab that will tell us OK how can we actually view the data.
How can we how can we call the team split.
If you scroll down you would find that there's an example so you can actually simply just copy and paste
this example.
So this girl is sort of more of this let's copy and paste.
So we have extreme excessed Whiting weightiest team splits and he just specifying the values of x and
y.
Okay.
So and that's pretty much all one means to have to split.
We have X we have y here we have a size.
So what percentage do we need to be included in testing.
So here we generally specify let's say point three values.
Okay or maybe point two.
And he didn't specify them in them state.
Those One answer is to be to match specifically.
And so you have to select kind of a random state that matches mine.
So let's say I'm going to select five for example v. the Basically the method I'm going to work and
get into usually turnback extreme X test y teen and white test.
Okay.
All right.
Let's run it let's see what's going to happen so successfully.
And what are going to do with it.
Actually when have you what's extraneous so extreme actually going to show you this next scene looks
fine.
And how do you see that this 450 overall.
So we actually divided the Empire State cancer dataset into proportion a subsequent of it which is only
80 percent which is 155 Rose.
All right.
What if I wanted to view let's say Why.
Why teen for example.
So were going to do let's say Why there's good team there.
Tell us okay this is why our team and the values is that's our basically our target.
Okay.
And the less 455 I ought to do is let's say if one of you let's say X tests ok if you want to view the
actual testing data you will see that we have hundred and forty laws which make sense.
Now we actually divided the data set into training and testing on it.
Okay.
I think right now we are ready to change our model.
This simple it's really simple.
The first step we're going to use Escuela and we're going to use support of the machines simply to do
the classification right.
So we're going to do we're going about from Escuela.
Right.
And going to dog as VM was said for support of a machine.
We're going to import s.
Okay.
And what we're going to do let's run this and the next step is that we're going to simply use as well
the metrics inside which is kind of classification report and confusion Matrix because we use it as
well as moving forward.
OK so I'm going to do was going to write from scaler and dot matrix.
I'm going right in Port and we're going to import classification to port justification underscored reports
and we're going to import confusion underscored metrics.
Okay.
Let's run it through successfully.
What we're going to do is 10 shift simply an object out of the B C.
Okay.
So going to do is going to right let's say you can limit whatever you want.
You know I'm just name is vishy underscored model that's pretty much what object is going to be using.
I'm going to write as see.
OK.
That's basic Is she an object is a b c model.
So we're going to do in order to do the perform the training.
We're going to use the fit method on in on the object that we just created to actually train our model.
So are you going to use a key as we see underscore model which is basically an object that we had here.
And they're going to use a fit method and we need to pass simply our input and output which is simply
our tuning.
So gettings underscore team I'm going to use y underscoring to simplicio the date if we don't get that
done that means the model has been trained and we are good to go.
Obviously here within if event with the model yet.
And that's all going to be doing in the next section.
I hope you enjoy that section and see you in the next section.