Hello everyone and welcome to this new lecture.
The biggest lecture we're able to cover the basics of for loops and we cover a couple of kind of special
keywords such as how to do break how to break a loop how to continue within loop and we've covered as
well a couple of the advanced topics within loops which is how to perform nested loops which is kind
of a loop inside the loop.
All right.
And this section for going to learn kind of an advanced liberal advanced topic or so-called list comprehension.
OK.
All right let's take a look at the description first and then I'm going to take a look at an example.
All right so let's comprehension.
Kind of as an elegant tool is used to transform one list into another.
OK so let's assume that I have for instance a list and I want to take that list and let's say square
each element within that list.
Right.
I have two options to do it or have two ways of doing it.
First one is to simply create another list and go ahead and do a loop within each specific element within
the first list.
Take it square it and append it and put it in a different list.
All right.
This is kind of a very basic way of doing it and actually going to start by doing that basic way.
And I will show you how can we use list comprehension to make it way way 10 times even easier.
All right.
Let's take a look at an example let's assume I am going to use the exact same example that I listed
so going to take a minute my list equals two let's say one two one two three and four.
And when I wanted to do was to simply square each element in here.
So simple ways say OK this is my input list I'm going to create an out list right.
And I'm going to create it as an empty first.
I'm gonna go ahead create a loop for element in my list.
So every time I will go in my list and here grab an element which is gonna be element here maybe one
and then two and then three and then four every time I'll take it.
Right.
I'm going to dig that element.
All right.
I'm going to square it.
That's how to square it.
Right.
And when I need to do is to take the square of the element and append it it's kind of you know think
of it this concatenation just taking the element and append it to my list the element the next element
and append it to the list and so on.
So to do that I'm going to say okay.
Output on the score list dot append and even append that new element to my list in here.
Okay.
All right.
And afterwards after I'm done the loop I'm just gonna go here and print my new output the score list.
Again let's let's actually it and see what's happened shift enter.
Okay.
So now do we have a problem because Out list actually called output list.
My apologies.
And here actually it's call it output lists shift enter.
Here we go.
So as you can see here this is the original list was given this was one two three four.
And this is my output list was 1 4 9 sixteen.
All right.
So what do you mean by what happened.
So what are we have done here is that we create an output list and we initialize it as empty just no
blank empty list.
And what we have done we've created a loop that takes each element within my list.
Take the element squared it and append it to my output list and keep repeating repeating repeating.
So we keep doing this so we end up with basically and elements that are kind of a square of the original
element.
All right.
This is kind of you know that the easy old way of doing it.
Now we're going to become experts when it comes to list comprehension.
All right.
Let's see how can we do all these.
Just you know in one line of code basically.
All right.
That's our code to do that.
What we could do we could say OK.
And it might sound a little bit confusing but please bear in mind we're going to create kind of you
know lack of lists like this.
And what I would do I'm gonna say for element in my list.
All right.
So this is exactly pretty much the same at this command.
Right.
So going to say go into my list loop or each of the specific these elements.
All right.
And what happened is when you take that element right instead of creating an actual for loop and putting
the columns and having the body then creating a new list and all this stuff we don't need to do any
of that.
All that all what I'm going to do in a circle for element in my list.
OK.
What should I do.
Take each element within my list and simply square it.
Okay element.
Square.
That's it.
Done.
Here is my list comprehension.
This is just like in you kind of elegant way of creating the for loops and simply just you know like
iterating on a specific list.
Doing something with it square it multiply it whatever shift enter here we go and we're able to create
kind of you know like can you lists you can call it whatever that has these kind of new element.
And that's what we call it new list comprehension.
Again very elegant very powerful way of doing you know a lot of command summarize a lot of commands
for loops and stuff just in a very small one line of code.
All right.
OK.
So I'm gonna ask you guys to do it.
Please go ahead pause a video.
Well I wanted to us to do is to simply take all these elements and instead of squaring it when I want
you guys to do is to take each of these elements and multiply it by 10.
So I want to see the results is basically 10 20 30 and 40.
Please go ahead pause the video and please use list comprehension.
Obviously so again I to as to kind of use this.
Very similar to this command to simply multiply all the elements by 10.
Please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
Well I guess we have to do is to simply take again.
Think of it this way element in my list every time I take that element.
All right so four elements in my list every time I think the element I will take it the element and
simply multiply by 10 that's it.
Okay.
Shift enter.
Here we go.
So we ended up by 10 20 30 and 40.
Okay.
Awesome.
All right.
Let's take a look at another example.
Let's assume that I wanted for instance to
start with a specific again empty list.
So I'm going to start with a new list called minus equals to bunch of numbers.
One two three four five six seven eight nine and ten.
And when I wanted to do is to simply create again using the conventional way using the basic all the
way create a for loop that simply goes in there and only extract only extract the even numbers and out
of these even numbers.
I just wanted to square only even numbers.
So simply put I wanted the output to be two squared which is four four squared which is 16 six square
which is 64 four and then eight square and then afterwards we're going to be.
I'm sorry six squared which is three six eight squared with sixty four and then ten squared which is
one hundred.
So let's how can we do that with the conventional way.
OK.
I'm going to try to get my list or we'll call it that's a new list.
This is the output list.
It's got to find it's an empty first.
And what I would do then is take a four I in my list every time I go in my list.
Let's first check if that number is even or odd.
Okay.
If I divided by two equals two zero.
Right.
So if it's an even number OK take that number and simply take the new list dot append.
So again append to it that number whatever the number square.
So if the number is even if you find the ever even number go he'd go here take that new list and take
that number squared and append it to my new list.
And then after when you're done you just go ahead and print your new list.
All right shift enter.
Here we go.
Now we're able to print 416 36 64 and 100.
Let's see how can we do that using list comprehension.
Again one command one line will and we'll call it today.
OK.
So what we could do again second new on the score list equals two.
All right.
And open basically to kind of the list like this.
I'm going to say OK for I in my list it's exactly the same as we have done here for I in my list.
I'm going to do this right.
OK.
All right.
What what I need to do is I need to add a condition here OK.
And then the return we're going to be here which is you know what I need to do after the element satisfy
that condition I need to put it here before the for loop which may be confusing if you think about it
again.
So what we're going to do is take it for I in my list if you find the I index divided by two ways equals
to zero which means if you find that number is even number.
OK.
What should I do.
What should I do is not written here.
OK.
It's written before the four.
It's confusing as hell but that's fine.
So that's for I in my list.
If you read it like that if I was divided by two equals equals to zero if my number is even what I should
do I'll take that number and squared it.
That said OK.
List comprehension.
It's amazing.
You simply just summarize or you know like kind of knock down all these lines into just one single line.
Run it again.
Let's take a look at new list.
Here we go 416 thirty six four and one hundred.
OK.
Perfect.
All right.
So let's take a look at a quick challenge OK.
It's mini challenge.
What s quest to do is they're going to provide you with a temperature on the score C OK and which is
simply just a list of temperatures and degrees of degrees Celsius 25 30 40 and 50.
All right.
And when I get asked what I ask you guys to do is to use list comprehension to simply convert temperature
celsius to temperatures Fahrenheit.
Right so please right.
You know kind of a list comprehension here to simply going to create a for loop that goes in here.
Take the elements in here and simply do the conversion from Celsius to Fahrenheit.
Do you guys remember from 4 Celsius to Fahrenheit the equation was nine divided by five times the Celsius
plus three divided by two.
Right.
My apologies plus my procedure.
So this is the equation the equation was nine divided by five times temperature in Celsius plus 32.
That will give us the temperature in Fahrenheit.
All right this is the equation.
Please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge will ask us to do to simply use this comprehension
to kind of transform that list which is temperature in Celsius to temperatures in Fahrenheit.
Let's see how can you do that.
Going to take it for I in temperature C so every time I go into that temperature see grab an element.
OK.
What should I do with it.
There is no condition right.
I don't need to add if condition in here.
I'm going to do that on all elements.
So I'm gonna say OK what I'm gonna do I'm going to say nine divided by five right times.
I plus 32
plus 32.
My apologies.
Here we go.
So every time I'm going to take the temperature which is gonna be element within the temperature C which
is 25 first and 30 and then four and so on take that number multiply by nine divided by five plus 32.
And that should be temperature and finite shift enter.
Let's take a look at temperature Fahrenheit V.
Here we go.
And that's the translation simply of all the entire list here into a new list that has temperatures
in Fahrenheit.
All right.
Perfect.
Let's take a look at one last example and that should conclude the list comprehension.
Let's assume that I wanted for example to the finest drinks or the finest thing call my string equals
two.
And they're going to say I am I am becoming a master Python master.
I just just a string.
Okay.
And maybe it's defined in 30 days and becoming the python master in 30 days.
And what I wanted to do is to simply return back only the numbers I just wanted to return only these
3 0 here.
How can I do that using list comprehension.
So I'm gonna say OK I'm going to create another list and that list is going to call it numbers equals
two.
And what I wanted to do is to simply loop here when each element each character.
So going to take a four I in my string so that will go ahead and look at each element and he had character
every time I have to check.
So going to take it if you find my character I dot is digits again that's pretty new.
We haven't that we haven't discussed that before.
But the overall idea is OK.
Check that number if the number is digits was digit.
OK.
So was like like a number like 3 and 0.
Right.
So this is kind of you know where to turn true if the number is digit return False if not what we need
to do.
Just return i.
That's it.
So please go ahead.
Check each of the characters in there in my string.
Grab any of that.
Make that check if that character was is digital or not if it is they should just return it and that's
it.
Shift enter.
OK.
Let's take a look at numbers or print.
We'll get.
The numbers enter.
Here we go.
So we'll be able to return back to 3 and 0 which is only two elements in here within my string.
All right.
OK.
And that's pretty much what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Let's recap all we have done so far in this lecture we have been able to learn about list comprehension
which is a very elegant new way of just you know writing a lot of lines of code into a very simple line
of code an elegant way just simply converting a list into another list in one line of code.
We have a list and we wanted to convert it for example Melissa squared or multiplied by 10 or do whatever
we can do that using these commands and what we could do as well that we can add an additional condition
as well.
OK.
If you want to kind of you know add a little bit smartness in there and we're able as well to maybe
use here kind of you know special like functions look like that is digit for instance to check if that
digit or not and then using less compression as well we're able to extract the numbers 3 and 0 out of
my string.
All right.
That's pretty much all for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Next lecture I'm going to walk you through the while loops which is really interesting as well just
a different kind of taste.
You know like to perform a loop similar to for loops and that should conclude that section.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.