Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
I'm going to walk you through the exercise.
Question for the print end user input.
Right.
So the first question that we have here is I'm asking you to write a code that takes the speed input
from a user in kilometres per hour and converts it into miles per hour and print both speeds to this
claim.
Basically here is what I'm showing you is kind of the example we're expecting it to see.
We're expecting to see into speeding Columbus but our let's say the user input 30 for example the program
that we're going to print speed in Colombia put out equals to 30 kilometres an hour and then speed and
miles per hour equates to 80 miles per hour.
OK.
Again this should be pretty much kind of an extension of the exercise that we have done before but now
because we know how to get data from the user how to print data to this creed we should be experts in
actually doing this and using the print for print as well along with a format method as well.
OK if you guys will be able to figure that out easily.
The next question asked me to do is to ask you to print the calendar for the month basically and whatever
months you have.
OK.
So again this is kind of you know extended release which I generally like you know encourage students
not to just stick to the course because there are tons of like Python commands and a guy can be covering
this because you're like yo I need 500 hours to cover all the Python commands for example.
So here I'm asking you to go ahead and research for example import kelan there.
OK.
And I tried to include kind of you know like a like a like a hint here that if you use calendar this
month and you pass along the year end the month then you'll be able to clean something like this again.
You guys do your research.
And I want you to come here and just print whatever month whatever you're you you specify OK exemplars
three.
I'm asking you to expand the code above actually ask the users to enter them in three years or enter
a year.
For example let's say 2019 and then entered a month let's say March for example and then here the.
This would be going to be printed on the screen which is simply the calendar for that specific month.
All right.
Again you be able to use this month to print whatever you want on the screen.
It's very simple just one single comment.
But I want you guys to go and do some research as well to see how you can use the print command and
on with it get it.
The next example that we want you to do is I wanted to write a code that takes two integer two integers
values from the user and printout the summation along with a multiplication something like this into
any integer number.
Let's say the user input for another number.
Letting the user enter it let's say 5 and then the multiplication equals to 20 addition equals to tonight.
That's what I wanted to do.
Again please leverage the format method that we used before to basically print out the summation and
with the addition multiplication sorry along with the addition.
OK.
Right.
Question number five I'm asking the user to write a code I you to write a call that takes a value from
the user and print out the number the number of square and the number.
Q Something like that.
Enter any integer.
Number two things are in the four and then they going to print the code in their print for 16 and 64.
That's it get.
All right question number 6 I'm asking the user to ask Are you sorry to write a code that takes a temperature
input from the user in Celsius and converted to at night.
Again the scandium an extension taum I've done before but here this is kind of you know like something
and actions with a user.
So I'm asking the user to enter temperatures in degrees Celsius lipsey 30 degrees C and then get a pre
printing out both entries and temperature in Celsius.
Were going to be something and then you have to add the grisi afterwards and then temperature in Fahrenheit
is 86 F and then you can actually compared it as well.
Let's say by performing a simple Google for example search just to make sure the conversion is pre is
right.
Again you can leverage what we have done before using the equation that we discussed in previous previous
sections or in Question 7.
I'm asking to asking you to write a code that takes the length and width of kangol from the user and
prints the area and the premiums.
Again we have done that before but he did just kind of you know a little bit of that action.
I'm asking you know the user to enter the wits with you as before and to leontes 5 and then a print
area a quick 20 and deliver it equally.
One last example.
I'm asking you to write a code that takes the radius of a circle from a user and print the area they
ammeter and circumference to again try to encode kind of a summary of what we need to do instead of
actually going there and doing your research.
So the idea would get to be PI Our Square they emdur is two times R and the circumference is two.
Ah OK.
Again the radius of a circle should be used should put three and then you're going to be printing out
Circle diameter to six Circle area.
Is this and then circle the conference.
This.
That's all what I wanted to do.
Okay and that's pretty much all of what I have for this section.
Best of luck and hope.
I hope you know you will be able to figure these questions out.
If not if you get stuck Don't worry again.
You know we are still you know giving up all your knowledge.
Please check out the solutions video.
And by that you should be familiar with print and how to get data from the user.
Great job I hope you guys enjoyed it and CEO in the next election.