Hello everyone and welcome to this project and this project we're going to try to kind of practice about
how to use files how to get the input data from the user how to perform or use dictionaries how to do
for loops how to do if conditions and how to treat files as well.
Maybe access files or print data from the files so there's like tons of learnings in this particular
project.
However this project is actually pretty easy.
It's pretty straightforward and simple and it's really useful too.
So what what I want us to do is we want it to assume that for example your university student and you
would like to develop a day planner.
OK.
So I want you guys to write for example a code that takes a user name and password from user and grant
or deny access.
All right.
And if the if the password and the user name matches what we saw which is you know what we could still
going to be doing here storing that data here.
Once the access granted the system we're going to request to get the time of the day from the user.
So from the users to enter the time of the day afterwards we are going to store within our program a
certain specific timeframes going to say let's say at 10:00 we have let's say programming lecture in
room 8 at 12:00 we have let's say computer vision lecture in Room C at let's say one o'clock we have
our lunch at the cafeteria.
It's kind of a day planner you are guiding yourself you know kind of you know like to attend for example
specific lectures.
It's kind of a reminder for you.
And what what we're going to do afterwards as well if the system were going to provide the user with
details on the lecture title and location which is you know what we've just discussed and as well we
are the software as well once we once the software decides which lecture is going to be going to be
selected by the attending they will as well retrieve lecture notes that we already stored before in
a text format scholar lecture notes not text.
You guys will find that lecture note the text in here.
All right.
And the course package if you guys go here you will find that there is a file called lecture on this
called notes.
Right.
And here you will find that you know there is like lecture notes date 2016 Professor let's say Mitch
you know election one and it's kind of a coding exercise.
All right.
And basically you just wanted to retrieve that information so you can access it you know for the user.
All right let's get started and let's build some codes here.
Let's read some quotes before we read the code.
Let's take a look maybe at some of the code in action.
So here I am asking to enter user name so the user can enter Ryan and then password we're going to select
whatever Password please bear in mind that here the password in this case was actually didn't show up
for the user.
Right.
That's very important point.
OK for the user name actually showed right for the password which I will try not to use kind of you
know like a very important and easy way to actually enter the password.
And it sure will show stars.
So nobody would actually look at your password and know it.
And if the user name and password matches the user name and password that we have in our database they
don't get a say Okay access granted.
Welcome to the system.
And we're going to ask as well.
What's the time right now.
So the user are going to insert the time between 8:00 a.m. and 3:00 p.m. So let's say they use it until
it's a nine then the program again direct him to you should attend programming lecture room A.
And here you go.
This election notes.
All right.
Let's take a look at how can we build this.
First of all let's go ahead and
let's define our user name and password.
First we're going to say user name equals two.
You guys can call it whatever he'd say let's say user name is Ryan for example.
I'm going to set passwords and then say password equals to you guys can name it whatever you want here.
I'm going to call it let's say why S.K. percentage 1 2 3.
So this is the password and username that they use it has to enter in order to keep going in order to
actually grant the user access to the system.
All right.
So we're going to do here.
We're going to get the user name and password from the user.
So going to say OK let's input and we're going to ask the users to enter your username All right.
And we're going to take that and put it in input underscore username.
All right.
OK.
Looks good.
Let's as well get the password.
We're going to say input.
OK.
Underscore password equals two.
We're going to say OK.
Input and here we're going to ask him okay.
Enter your password.
All right.
OK.
Looks good.
Let's keep going.
And let's make a check here.
So he'd have just tried to fill out the easy part right.
Some say OK if you found a user name that the users had that saved in the system.
These are the seven system was equal to our input on the score.
Username.
Right.
Which is basically what the user have entered.
And so obviously the username and the past would have to match.
I was going to say input underscore password equals to the password right.
If these conditions happen I'm going to say Okay if that's successful I'm going to say Okay print
okay.
Access has been granted.
Welcome to the system.
All right.
Looks good.
Okay.
All right.
And then we'll go do something here.
Okay.
What if it doesn't happen.
Can take it.
Else if that doesn't happen it's printout.
I'm going to say well username for password is not correct
access denied okay all right.
Looks good.
Okay.
Let's actually give it a shot.
Let's see what's going to happen.
Let's run.
That's when we run it.
Introduce me to say Ryan for example.
Enter password.
Let's say I'm going to insert like random password 1 5 7 8 whatever.
Enter obviously the username and password did not match what we have here.
So we got user name or password is not correct.
Access denied.
Which is simply we didn't execute the body of the if we only executed the LS portion of the if.
Right.
Okay let's run it again.
Let's enter for example Ryan like this and let's match the password let's say why SDK percentage 1 2
3 run it well again it didn't graphing it didn't get me access it says username and password as well
is not correct.
Access denied to even though they use a name as it should be the same right but please bear in mind
that this is case sensitive right.
So we need to make sure that the key is that the first letter only is uppercase right.
So let's run that let's let's match it this time let's enter why is K percentage 1 2 3 run it's access
granted.
Welcome to the system.
Perfect.
OK now this is just the basic just the beginning.
All right OK.
What I want you guys to do here which is you know like we had we have an issue here with this code.
We haven't done anything yet but you we have an issue here and want to fix it.
So the issue here is that the password.
OK everyone can read it right.
So you can actually can read that the password why escape percentage 1 2 3.
What we want to do here is that we wanted to kind of you know do kind of a little bit of a check to
actually hide that password.
So what we could do we're going to say OK import get pass and get past we'll actually get to help us
tremendously actually showing the password getting the password without actually showing it on the screen.
So let's go ahead here and let's comment that out because we don't need it anymore.
Let's copy it.
It's basic here.
Take it input password equal and sort of input what we're going to do.
We're going to take a get pass DOT get pass.
That's it.
Once we do this let's try it.
So this enter user name.
He writes Ryan enter your password.
Is exactly what we have here.
And if we entered y SDK and that's the beauty of it if you just take a look here you will find that
there is no I can't read anything right which is pretty much what will happen in real world.
Right.
So let's read it again.
So we have Y this key percentage 1 2 3 strong it's access granted welcome the system and the password
does not show.
Which is amazing.
That's exactly what we're looking for.
All right.
Okay.
And that's pretty much the first step in building our code.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And the next lecture I'm going to keep going.
We're going to define our function.
We'll get to for loops if conditions.
Dictionaries we're going to do tons of stuff in the next lecture.
Please stay tuned and see you guys in the next lecture.