Hello everyone and welcome to this new lecture in the previous lecture.
We're able to learn a lot of information about for loops and we've covered a kind of wide range of of
options within for loops like you know like how to perform range how to do nested loops how to do list
comprehension.
Now to the fun part let's take a you know kind of a little bit of shift and and see and call a different
type of loops which are all called Y loops.
So while loops can be used to execute a set of statements as long as a certain condition holds true.
All right.
What do you mean by this.
Let's assume that I wanted to print numbers let's say from 0 till 10.
What I could do.
Say OK let's define an index when defined it is set at a 0.
And what I could say would say OK while i is less than four equals to 10 and then add the column press
Enter print I and every time I'm going to say I equals two I plus 1 enter.
Here we go so I'll be able to print one to ten.
Let's see what happened here.
So what happened here is I defined a variable.
I set it to zero and I defined Heatwole called a while loop.
Ok.
Think of all a loop as kind of you know like.
That's kind of you know it's it's a loop with an if condition in it at the same time.
So think of it here I'm saying OK while OK as long as for a while if you find that condition is true
please go ahead and execute this.
Keep repeating repeating repeating as long as that condition is true.
Think of it again as kind of you know doing a loop with an if condition associated with it as long as
i is less than or equal to 10 print I an increment i with one go up again and do it again.
Let's take a look at you know look at this loop from scratch.
First one first run we're going here and saying OK I equals to zero.
That was my initialization.
I'm going to go here and say OK is zero less than or equal 10.
Yes.
That means that condition is true.
So while true Some think that condition was true.
Right.
That's good.
That means I'm going to go here and print i.
And that's why I was able to print zero and then come here to zero add one to it becomes one and put
it here becomes one.
So I'll go up here again.
I'm not going to go here.
This is initialization.
This is just something in the past.
I go here in a while and check again is one less than 10.
Yes.
So go here print one and then go here increment one comes to go up here again is two less than or equal
10.
Yes.
So print two and to go here it become three go up again and do do repeat repeat until you actually print
Number 10 which is here you print it out and then you come here to say OK 10 plus one is 11.
You go you go up here.
Here is 11 less than or equal 10.
No.
Right.
This is this.
This is the element that's where the loop will going to be broken so that what's happened is again is
just going to skip this you're not going to execute the body of the wild anymore.
You go here and there is more lines.
Well we get executed if not exit.
And that's why we're able to print numbers from zero till 10:00.
And that's pretty much how I loop works in a nutshell.
OK.
All right.
Let's take a look at another example.
Well I've got to ask you guys to do kind of as a quick challenge I want you guys to print numbers from
three till 20.
OK I wanted to print numbers from three to 20 using while loops OK.
All right.
So that's kind of a mini challenge.
Please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge will ask us to do is to simply pretty much go
out here.
Copy that code.
Put it here and I want it to print numbers from city 20.
So here are a set of initializing to the zero initial initialized to three and here instead of stopping
at ten I'm just gonna stop at 20 enter.
Here we go.
So now I'll be able to print three four five and so on.
Up until reached number 20.
OK.
That's pretty straightforward.
All right.
Let's take a look at another kind of example if we do Y in true.
So if I say let's say Y equals two let's say zero.
Okay.
And if I say while true Okay print let's say I.
If I do this.
All right.
This is a disaster.
OK.
That means it's we'll call it an infinite loop.
When I say while true that means I'm asking all the time just to repeat this and do it all the time
forever.
OK.
Let's actually give it a shot.
Let's see what's going to happen.
OK.
Obviously with the corner we'll get a break.
So please if you're going to run it expect that you need to go and actually stop the colonel or interrupt
somehow shift enter.
Here we go.
So I'm printing 0 0 0 0 to just keep going and I will do Colonel interrupt.
OK.
Just stop the colonel and maybe restart the colonel restart.
OK
so all right.
Still
case interrupted.
That's good.
Let's go ahead and actually do Colonel maybe restart and clear output.
All right here we go.
So what happened here is I said OK let's go ahead and while to to all the time just print i print zero
all the time forever which is crazy obviously when I don't want to do this.
What I want to do.
Maybe add a little of smartness.
I'm going to say OK every time I think I and maybe I increment i plus 1 and maybe make a condition if
you find if I was greater than or equal let's say 10 were going to break enter.
It we go.
Now we're able to print numbers from 1 to 9.
OK.
OK let's take it.
Let's read it one more time.
So I got the idea here.
I want to just to illustrate for two guys wedding by While to the idea of went through simply just go
ahead execute the commands forever basically which is something that we wouldn't want to do.
So when I say while true print I every time I go here is increment i so I becomes here at 1 and then
2 and then CNN 4 and so on.
And here we can add simply what we have done here.
We can say okay go ahead repeat the entire loop unless a certain condition is satisfied.
And when it says the condition is satisfied you just gonna break.
All right.
So I say if you find I greater than or equal to 10 you're just gonna break.
And that's why we're able to print simply numbers from 1 0 to 9.
If you wanted to make it let's say eleven enter.
That basically would be equivalent exactly to this code because the outcome is exactly the same.
Zero to ten.
Here the number is zero to 10.
All right.
The only difference is when when we do while and then we add the condition after it it's kind of think
of it again.
We added a while loop with an if condition just both of them intact in one spot.
OK.
What we have done here is we separated the while.
So we set it to the loops.
We make it way to just repeat forever and we separated we load the if condition manually separately
here and this it's pretty much the same printing.
Pretty much the same content as the previous time.
All right.
OK.
Let's go ahead for a quick challenge.
I wanted to print numbers from three to 20.
Using that format exactly the same format.
I just wanted to print numbers from three to 20.
Please go ahead pause the video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge.
We're just going to copy that paste it here and simply I wanted to print numbers from three up until
20.
So just gonna stop it to 21.
Enter.
Here we go.
We're able to print numbers from 3 4 5 and so on.
Up until 20.
And that's pretty much equivalent to what we have done here in this section.
All right.
OK.
And that concludes the four and why loop section.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
In the next lecture we're just gonna get started and actually start doing a lot of exercises because
we can have hopefully have fun when we can have.
I think we have like almost 10 plus exercises with tons of videos and tons of explanations.
Best of luck and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.