Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture in the PBS lecture.
We learned how can we do if conditions in Python and in this lectures.
We're going to walk walk you through the questions related to the exercises for four and while loops.
OK so in this lecture I'm just gonna walk you through the questions and in the next video I'm going
to walk you through that through the detailed solutions.
So please make make an attempt to actually solve these questions if you can't or if you don't get stuck
that's fine don't worry about it.
Again these levels please bear in mind that these levels are intermediate levels.
They are not beginners anymore.
OK.
All right.
So let's get started.
So here I'm asking you to tell me what will this code generate.
OK so here we have it lists my phone iPhone BlackBerry Samsung and Google.
And here there is simply a why loop.
OK.
And it seems like you know what kind of printing for example that list and that is kind of a condition
here that you know like might stop it at some point or something.
So that's I'm asking you without running the code please tell me what do you expect to see when we when
we run the code.
OK.
The next question is I'm asking you to write a code that display all numbers from 1 to 20 using while
loops and for loops.
So that would be a great kind of exercise for you guys to practice why loop and for loops and that would
be kind of the expected results.
So here we're expecting let's say 1 to 19 and you're expecting 1 to 19 as well.
Obviously you can adjust it and make it want to exact 20 hit.
I mean just excluding 20 years or so from 1 to 19.
All right.
The third question is I'm asking you to write a code that generate the following table.
I want to try to code that generate basically number 1 1 1 for instance and if it's two it seems like
you know the second number is kind of you don't like like the first number square and then here this
number is kind of you know looks like the first number cube.
That's the overall idea.
I want you guys to do it and kind of to print that table for us.
Question for I'm asking you to create it rolling dice game.
The game should assume two dice either number one and two are being thrown and the random number is
generated every time the game should prompt the user to ask if he or she would like to keep playing
or not.
So this is basically what we're expecting to see.
So I'm expecting to see OK rolling the dice.
Please wait and hear rolling result for Dice one should be whatever random number.
So obviously we're going to use a random kind of library or package to generate random integers from
1 to 6 for Dice 1 and for those 2 and then it seems like you know we're going to be stuck in a loop
somehow because I'm going to be asking the user all the time to do you want to roll again or do you
want to play again or not.
And then you have to enter yes or no.
2 Just keep going.
Or two exits.
All right.
Question five I'm asking you to develop a code that printout the multiplication table the quote you
from the user to enter the maximum number to be printed which is no going to be from 1 till 9.
So basically when I ask the user to enter number ok whatever number so he'll enter number between 1
and 9.
So the user let's say enter eight and then this is basically the table that I'm looking for my apologies.
This is a table I'm looking for eight times one eight eight times two 16 and so on.
So basically you take whatever number they use you will enter and multiply it by series of numbers from
one to 10.
All right.
Question 6 I'm asking to write a code that takes the maximum and minimum limits from a user and printout
of the even numbers only between the provided range.
So I'm asking you to enter a number lower bound let's say 20 upper bound let's say one hundred and then
here I'm just printing the even numbers only 20 22 24 26 and so on so forth.
Question 7 What does this code generate.
So it seems like there is a for loop and there is you know kind of an if condition in here that kind
of breaks the loop or continue the loop at some point and I'm asking you to without running the code
to please tell me what do you expect this code to begin to generate.
All right.
Question 8 actually have tons of exercises and and this I believe we have we have actually sixteen sixteen
exercises so that's a lot.
So let's go back again to a question 8 I'm asking to write a code that takes a list of temperatures
from a user and convert them from Celsius to Fahrenheit for example the user will enter a list of temperatures
in the greasy they'll be separated by space.
So let's say 30 40 50 and 60.
And basically what the code we're going to generate will generate something like this temperature.
Are temperatures in degrees and Fahrenheit we're going to be like.
These are all the temperature in degrees C and these are all the temperatures in Fahrenheit.
Obviously you can google the equation but we have done that before in the past.
How can we convert from Celsius to Fahrenheit.
Question number nine we're asking you to create a password generator that takes the required password
length from the user and generate a password.
The password should should have the password should be a make the mix of characters numbers and special
characters.
For example I'm asking to enter the lengths of the passwords to say it's 20 and then this basically
going to be generated.
Again it's this is a little bit tricky.
You need to do kind of an extend research on how can you actually generate these like random random
numbers.
All right.
Question number 10 I'm asking theoretical takes a string from user and sought the words and print all
words afterwards so simply using an answer for example like you know like like a sentence so I answered
that let's say I'm so happy learning Python today.
And then he would sort it like this.
This is uppercase right.
So that's why it has been sorted separately.
And then a H L P S and T.
So basically are or ordering them in an alphabetical order basically.
Okay.
All the words that they used were going to enter Question Number Eleven print the corresponding elements
in both lists between using below.
Sorry using two different methods.
So I wanted to print black iPhone black Samsung that black BlackBerry white iPhone white Samsung white
BlackBerry gold iPhone gold Samsung and gold BlackBerry actually here in this case let me let me show
you the list.
Actually this has should be here.
So that's actually the list.
OK.
So that will be provided within the question.
And I'm asking you to basically print the combination of all of them together using two different methods.
OK.
Think of it as kind of you know doing nested loops OK and using as well.
List comprehension as well.
OK.
All right.
The next question.
Question 12 I'm asking to write a code that takes a string and calculate the number of upper and lower
cases characters in whatever word you enter or sentence so he for example ask the user to enter a value
he entered hello world and here he basically the program counts.
Oh there are two upper cases and the rest of lowercase.
Right.
So here there's two upper cases and eight lower cases.
Question 13 I'm asking to write a code that takes the range number of number let's say for any number
from one hundred to 900.
So the user will insert the upper lower bound and I'm asking to print numbers would all digits are even
so basic.
You're getting all these two numbers and he were printing when all the additions digits are even so
let's say two hundred two or two two or four to a six all digits not just the numbers and just the numbers
would be pretty easy.
Here we have to kind of you know create a loop that basically goes along for each of these like you
know like digits and check of the R even or odd question number 14 we're asking to write a code that
prints I love you for example followed by your significant other name every three seconds.
Again you need to do kind of accident research and I give you kind of a hint to use time dot sleep.
OK.
That will you know kind of you know you answer the name of significant other it's a mom for example.
I guess if I love your mom and then after three seconds you print I love you mom and then you keep doing
this and you need to make sure that basically this loop will keep going forever.
So you have to go here to colonel and do interrupt so to interrupt the Colonel so question 15.
I'm asking theoretical that asking users to enter a password and ensure that the password satisfy the
following conditions has to have at least 10 characters has to contain at least one uppercase and at
least one number.
OK.
For example if the user enter let's say hello world you're going to say OK.
Password does not satisfy the requirements because there's no number in it overheated when the user
tried to enter.
Hello.
One world.
I say OK you password save successfully.
All right.
Why.
Because that's five all the three requirements and the last question I'm asking you try to code that
continuously gets data from the user and calculate the average and print it out on the screen.
So simply you're going to have a while loop or for loop.
Right.
And every time the user can insert a number let's say 10 then the average will be 10 and then let's
say they use an and 20.
So the average going to be 20 plus 10 divided by two which are going to be 15 and then using instead
a new number and they're going to divide again.
I'm going to click the continuous average as the user feeds in the data.
All right.
So best of luck.
And again if you guys get stuck there are tons of challenging questions here.
The objective obviously is not to challenge you at all.
The objective is for us to practice just stretch your limits as much as you can.
And then in the next lecture we're going to walk you through all the examples in great details.
Best of luck and see you guys in the next lecture.