Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and the previous lectures.
We learned how we first import all our libraries that we would need you know like panda's name pi profit
and so on.
And we know right now how can we load the data which is often crowded out CSB into a data frame.
I forgot to underscore what we need to do right now that we need to visualize the data.
Okay and explore the dataset let's see what's going on here.
So what we could do.
We're going to say OK let's go ahead and get the data frame which I've got underscored data frame dot
head right.
And let's run that and we run the head here basically it's gonna give us you know a couple the first
couple of lines in here which is you know like the lines that we're getting here.
All right.
So basically again total volume.
Here we have the average price per unit.
We have the date here we have the total number of bags.
Here we have the type either conventional or organic.
Here we have the year.
And here we have the region.
Is it like in the United States.
Is it like you know like in east west and so on.
OK.
All right.
What I want you guys to do is to pause the video and please try to remember how can you obtain the tail
of the data frame if you guys remember we can plot the beginning or the initial section of the data
frame and we can all we can also as well visualize the ending or the tail of the data frame.
OK.
Please pause video and try to go through that challenge and then we're going to go back right after
the challenge.
All right.
You guys were able to figure out the challenge.
So if you guys remember from previous section within the course what we could do if you wanted to view
the last elements within the data frame you're going to say OK forgot avocado underscore the data frame
dot tail.
Right.
And that will basically bring us the tail of the data frame the last elements you can see here the index
here from 0 to 4 right here the indices are eighteen thousand going down to let's say eighteen eighteen
thousand two for eight.
All right.
OK.
What we could do as well if you as a member let's practice a little bit on CNN on data frame we can
say OK avocado on the score data frame dot head and instead of just if you leave it blank here you know
that the default maybe it going select the first couple of lines.
What if I wanted to view let's say the first 20 items are going to say OK forget the head and just put
20 here and let's run it.
And if you see here we actually have been able to plot 20 line items in here which the first pretty
much line items.
What we have here.
OK.
All right.
Again let's it's time for a quick challenge.
I want you guys to plot the last or to plot here on the screen or to view the last 20 elements within
the data frame.
OK.
Please go ahead.
Puzzle video are going to be back after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge yourself.
I'm asking you to plot the last 20 items within the data frame.
Right.
So we could do it in a C Okay.
I forgot to underscore the data frame the tail and I'm going to pass along here 20.
Right.
So if you leave it blank again here when we left the blank we were able to obtain the last five rows.
What we could do here if I want to view the last 20.
You can just run around like that and that will view the overall number of items the 20 items.
All right.
OK let's go ahead and do some manipulations to the data.
OK.
So what we could do is that we wanted to view the date OK versus the avocado price.
All right.
So what we could do here first is that we can go ahead and sort the values of the date.
OK.
So the values here based on the data we can have kind of a chronological order you know going for let's
say from 2015 to let's say 2016 17 and 18 and so on to do that.
What we could do we're going to say OK avocado underscore data frame equals to take the data frame again
I'm going to say dot sort on underscore values and we're going to sort through date.
All right.
So getting used that date column here which is the date here to sort our our data.
Right.
That's actually one that looks good.
Let's run it again let's view it and that's how the value there is sort.
Please bear in mind that.
OK.
This is the earliest date.
So the earliest date was actually in back in January of 2015.
And you guys can see here the index has been shifted right.
So when we do the sorting by date we actually sorted the entire entire row right who selected the entire
row.
So yes we use the data to sort but we we got the entire row as we move forward.
Right.
That's why here's the index didn't start at 1 2 3 and so on.
You will see that the different numbers here you know are kind of mixed based on the data.
All right let's go ahead and let's visualize for example the date versus the average price.
Let's take a look you know with the price going up with the price going down.
Let's take a look.
So what we could do here we could say OK I'm going to DPL T dot plot and in order to print the plot
the date versus the average price what we could do can silky Africa avocado underscore the data frame
and we can say OK I need the dates and I need again avocado on the score data frame and here I need
my average price.
You guys remember average price in the name has to match right.
So here I'm trying to plot.
That's right.
So the average price.
Exactly have to match.
Please note that the A's uppercase and PS uppercase and here the date D uppercase right.
All right let's go down.
Okay.
Looks good.
Let's run its stake in limit of time.
I have tons of data in here and here we go.
So here you will see that we plotted the date here.
Obviously it's very hard to read and hear the prices you know like it's just it's going crazy all over
the place.
Going from one point five dollars maybe sometimes it's like three dollars you know it's again it's very
expensive sometimes goes down 2.5 and so on.
That's pretty much the price as we as we see it now.
All right.
OK.
What we could do as well in order to make that graph a little bit better what we could do that we could
come here and we could say OK P L T that figures just change the figure size and we can say okay think
size equals two and we can make it let's say 10 and 10.
For example let's run it.
It should be better to be more.
You know we can view it a little bit more all right.
Looks much better now.
So now I can read it they can look at the variations in the price.
That looks great.
All right.
Let's go ahead and actually we're not going to be using the region that much if you go up here you find
that there is a column here called region let's go here from the region called like West e and so on.
Let's go ahead and maybe visualize the regions.
Again the objective here is for us to practice as much as you can using seaboard.
OK so we could do that to say OK I wanted to use as an S dot count plot so I wanted to count basically
the the elements.
Right.
And what I could do the data they're going to be using the data is simply our avocado on the score data
frame which is our data frame basically data.
And what I wanted to do.
Going to say OK I wanted to count elements based on the region right.
So again my apologies are going to say region.
All right.
So that will simply end and go ahead and plot for us our count plot within a plot the number of regions
here it's really hard to read as well.
So going to make a little bit bigger and let's see how the count how many they come.
The number of elements here as you guys can see here the count how many elements is the data kind of
like
it.
The question here is the data balanced or not.
And that's the objective what we have done here.
So the data is pretty much balanced right.
So the count the number of items number of elements are down three.
It's actually pretty much extremely balanced right based in the region.
Let's actually make a little bit bigger to actually view as well the regions if we could we could say
it could say OK BLT dot figure and I'm going to use fig size equals two and I'm going to say twenty
five and let's say twelve.
All right.
And let's run that's all right.
Looks much better now.
And again it's really tough as well to read here it looks like they are overlapping right.
OK.
What we could do as well here.
Maybe we can try something else.
What we could do is that we can use what we call it the rotation key.
We haven't done that before but maybe let's let's you know learn something new today escapee empty dot
and say X ticks.
So simply I'm just going here to the X sticks here the x axis what we have here and I wanted to rotate
it by 45 degrees so when I say rotation equals to forty five.
So that will simply going to go ahead here and rotate it.
If you guys look take a look here it actually looks much better now.
Now it's actually a bit more readable which is great.
Let's zoom in more and you guys can see here there is like south east.
That is Chicago.
There is like you know made mid south the rich Charlot Houston that is South Carolina.
You know Seattle so it's you know like the region San Diego.
The region is pretty much you know obviously us a base that is Detroit Philadelphia.
And one element here one important element here is that there is one region that will call it total
US.
I'm not sure if it's actually shown in here or not.
OK so but in general there is a reason to call a total U.S. I believe it might be like overlapping here
and actually gonna be using total U.S. mainly in the nexus in this and the second part of the of this
exercise to actually visualize the data is specifically for the total U.S. we're comparing just the
overall market kind of thing.
OK.
All right.
Let's take a look at another graph.
Let's maybe review the the year.
Let's compare for example the sales compare for the year.
OK.
What we could do is say OK let's do a census that count plot and what we could do we can pass along
X as the year and we can use the data which is simply our data frame rate we're going to say avocado
underscored data frame.
All right.
And let's run that.
And that's what we're getting here getting the year is 2015 16 17 18 and that's the counts the number
of samples that we have here the count is around you know 50 500 pretty much stable and 2018 because
the year wasn't you know kind of complete the data wasn't complete in this case.
So it has been you know chop kind of hit a little bit.
All right.
OK sounds good.
What we could do again right now is that let's go ahead and review the data.
OK.
So if you guys remember we have been able to go ahead and get a full gateau underscored data frame.
Right.
And if you take a look at the data frame and that's all that's the overall data right.
Let me zoom out a little bit.
That's the overall data we've got we got here.
So we have got data average price total volume and so on so forth.
Honestly speaking I'm not interested in any of this.
OK all what I need I need my date and I need my average price.
That's all what I need specifically for the profit
media operation that's for predicting the time series.
So what we could do.
Going to say OK I forgot to underscore profits.
I'm going to define a new data frame.
All right.
Def and that data frame specifically dedicated for the profit operation only.
OK.
When I say I forgot avocado here.
I'm going to go ahead into the data frame and then not I'm not going to take the entire thing.
I'm just gonna extract mainly the column that I'm interested in I'm interested in date.
Right.
And I'm interested as well in the average price all right.
Okay.
Looks good.
Let's run it and let's take a look at the profit section.
If you run that that's all we're getting we're getting the date and we're getting the average price
looks perfect looks great.
And it's actually has been you know looks good has been sorted.
If you guys take a look here you'll find the last decade was March of 2013 and that's why when we actually
plotted the count here you'll find that count is not that much as we started 2018 right.
Okay.
All right.
That's great.
The next step is I wanted to do here is let's go ahead and actually train or you know like prepare the
data to actually apply the profit.
All right.
So that we're going to actually going to be doing in the next lectures and that's pretty much all what
we have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoy it.
And please stay tuned in the next lecture going to start training our actual you know kind of model
per say and try to predict the price in the future using the profit package.
All right see you guys in the next lecture.