Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to dig a little bit deeper in to our confusion the network that we discussed in the past.
I'm going to kind of get more details about each individual later.
OK.
So the first layer if you a call that we had the feature detector or kernel layers.
What do you mean by this.
So simply put we take our image and we feed that image to certain filters or call kernels or feature
detectors.
OK.
So when we say when we see kernels or feet say feature detectors what happens.
Think of it as kind of a filter.
Okay.
And that filter goes it here and scan the entire image and apply specific kind of a feature detect detection
algorithm to extract information out of this image.
OK.
And what happens is once we apply these feature detectors we appeal one quality feature the maps think
of feature maps as kind of you know different variations of this image so this image is kind of divided
into certain you know like series of images we'll call it feature maps.
Let's take a look at the feature detector in action.
Let's assume that here we have our image OK.
Which again if you have it a member any image is just a bunch of numbers that change from zero to two
hundred and fifty five.
And let's assume that in this case our image contains a bunch of zeros and ones.
What we do here is that we're going to we're going to assume that this is our input image.
And here we have our feature detectors.
OK.
Which is simply you back.
That's our feature detector in our kernel.
Our kernel is again in Matrix 3 by C Matrix has a bunch of zeros and ones.
And what we could do would what happen when the convolution on networks is that we apply this feature
detector on our image.
OK.
Let's see how can we apply it.
So first we place our feature detector here on this image here.
And then what we do with that we multiply each of the pixels.
This is simply see by the pixels.
Here we have to see Basically as well and multiply We simply like apply the convolution.
What do you mean we multiply one basia that will generate 0 0 by one woman and it is 0 0 by one widget
in zero and so on and then we sum up all the results of all of this.
Okay.
Let's see how can we do this.
So simply if we multiply all these pixels by all these values in here and some the opposite that would
generate a value of 1 or a.
Why.
Because simply put all these values originated as zero here zero times 1g is 0 1 0 0 0 times literally
Lokey zero times 1 0 and then Hume 1 times 1.
That's the only value that's used to this once we miss some of the values here which is all of them
are zeros and one.
Some of them are these.
The outcome will going to be one or a gate.
And what we do afterwards is that we move out of feature detector to the right a little bit OK and then
we apply the exact same method again so we multiply all this by this.
Some of them up in the value of one.
OK.
Let's shift it again once we shift it again we multiply again all this by why all this will gaoth the
value of one and then we move down to here.
And then we multiply.
Let's do this actually.
So here we have 1 claims 1 8 1 0 times 0 0 0 times it.
Okay.
Here we have zero times zero is zero one.
Times are one.
That's my second one right there.
All we have to now zero times you know as you know.
And then we have zero time zero zero one thomes one is one.
That's my third one and then zero times one is zero.
That's why when we apply the feature detector on our image we actually need the value of three.
Let's keep going.
And once we do that once we move the colonel wants to move the feature detector over the entire image
we come up with this feature map which is simply put this feature map.
It's kind of really kind of a reduced form Okay kind of a condensed.
Think of it as kind of the zip file kind of a condensed information out of our image.
So this image will apply to our future detective here has been condensed to become this feature map.
All right.
Okay.
And what we do is that we don't only do this once we actually go back if we go back here you find that
we have this seat as a feature detectors.
So that's one feature detector.
We have another feature detector so the second feature detectors will generate another feature map another
feature detector was it that featured a map and then we come up with all these future maps and then
we're going to be ready to use them moving forward to the next layer.
OK so let's let's go ahead and read all the slides we have convolution is use a kernel Matrix dust can
give an image or an image.
This econometrics feature detectors and apply filters to a set in effect an image kernel is a matrix.
You stop light effects such as blurring control trial sharpening.
So simply put.
Here we can use that kernel's to prit let's say perform for example blurring.
Or for example.
Sharpening of the image kurnos are using machine learning for feature extraction to select the most
important pixels of the image.
So simply put once a year when we apply our our site our colonel or our feature detector to our image
he will paint kind of you know the most important features out of our out of our image.
And that's one feature map.
It's kind of again a condensed form that contains all the information that we need out of our image.
Let's go back.
So convolutions preserve or spatial relationship between pixels and that's actually very important very
very important.
Okay.
And that's why we actually we don't feed that image directly into our traditional network in a flat
and format.
We have to pass it through it couldn't for luciane and layers which is our contribution you know feature
effectively.
Why.
Because now simply this value for example 3 does not capture only specific pixel actually captures what's
happening over and over all in this entire region.
So that's why it covers all of this spatial kind of dependency between this specific pixel for instance
and all our neighbouring pixels.
OK.
That's very important because you know if you want to look at the eyes for example the way I look at
the eyes and let's say the eyebrows for example if want to look at the teeth for instance you can look
at the neighbouring pixels too.
And so on.
And that's why you know we have to apply the convolution and layered first before we put the data into
our convolution of neurone work.
Alright.
Let's go ahead and take a look at kind of what look like involution which is really interesting really
powerful in that link.
Let's go.
All right.
So let's take a look at convolution in action.
OK.
So this is pretty cool website.
It's called a tool set of aisles less easy it's less image Col's and you can find the link in the actual
slides and it's actually pretty really interesting.
It shows shows you here is your image so that's pretty much an image of a like you know like a person.
And here it would show you all the pixels in here.
So these are the actual values of the pixels.
So if you take a look here for example this pixel is really white.
That's why it's umbilically about 255 of value.
Right.
And if we go back to this pixel for instance these are kind of very dark or very black.
It shows let's say 29 venue which makes sense because we know that you know like if we have a certain
image zero indicates black collar 255 indicates Wyke white collar and in between these are just different
shades of grey.
So if you go here for example there's kind of a little bit of grey shows like hundreds in 10 if you
go here's hundred fifty five 255 because they're white and that's pretty much how can we interpret images
within in a digital format within our within the computer.
Okay.
So now to the fun part of this actually implement kernels in and see how can we implement criminals
in action.
So let's assume that we for example select this specific kernel.
Again if we when we say current or feature detector it's simply a matrix okay of let's say here had
three by three for example we have different options for kernels we have let's say sharpening the blurring
we have different options.
Let's pick one.
So let's let's say sharpening.
Okay.
So zero minus one zero minus one five minus one zero minus one and zero.
And actually what we could do here is we can actually implement convolution in action.
It's really really amazing.
So here that read a three by three That's our kernel or our featured text with place of feature detectors
here in the corner.
OK.
We can then apply the convolutions.
So if you can see here it's more of the mouse so you guys can you know kind of you know try to interpret
what I'm seeing.
I'm talking about this base of these values in here.
OK.
So if I put my kernel here in my in the corner you would find that there is 206.
These are the value of the pixels the actual pixels to a 6 to 5 to 4 7 to the first row.
And then 2 4 2 4 4 1 6 1 1 3 7 there's a second the actual value of the pixels and the multiplication.
Here are the actual values of the kernel of our feature detectors which is what sharpening feature detector
zeo Minus 1 0 minus 1 5 minus 1 0 minus 1 0.
And what happened is he and we just multiply basically the two.
And some of them up so we come up with this value which is you know in this case was let's say 65 for
example and then value will get to be translated in here to the right hand side.
In that basically opaque image.
So here on the left hand side that's the input image he was using our colonel.
This is our mathematical operations and here's the output.
So if we put the kernel here on the left hand side if we do the maths multiply them together some of
them up become 65 that will be translated to the output and then we shift the chrono to the right a
little bit do the exact same maths we'll come up with minus 42 and then go be transitively upward.
We keep shifting shifting shifting to the right as we move forward.
And then we go down here.
We keep shifting to the right to forward and we basically scan the entire image and that's the power
of convolutions or it's what's that what happened.
You know it's amazing because now we actually use the input image.
You applied your feature detector and you come up with the output image.
If you take a look at the output image you would find that the output image is kind of feel a little
bit sharpened compared to the input image which is really powerful.
Okay let's take a look at for example another feature detector.
Let's assume it's blurring for example.
OK.
If we do the maths again we're going to scan again our colonel you'll find that the images have been
blurred which is really interesting or exciting too as well.
OK.
It's kind of like if you take a look at the on the actual blurting it looks like you're not in the average
for all the value of the pixels.
And that's why you're kind of you know blurring the image in here.
Obviously there are hundreds you know there are tons of kernels in here and that's pretty much how can
you apply for example filters Instagram filters or you know like Snapchat filters or whatever.
It's pretty much the same idea.
Have you input image.
You are place specific kernel to it or you know a feature detector and you come up with the output image.
But in our exercise in our example we're going to use that output image which is our kind of feature
maps to actually feeded within our network.
The beauty or the power of convolution and neuro network.
We do the convolution layer first and then we take that output we feed it afterwards to our next pulling
layers on.
Afterwards we had some of that northern sections but that's pretty much of the overall overall idea.
How can we all paint or perform convolutions before we actually run our fission unit.
All right.
And there's been much with this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next lecture.