Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because we are getting a little bit closer to our goal.
We're our target of actually building our convolutions your network together.
This understanding is from a theoretical perspective and then we're going to be ready to go ahead and
start recording the entire network and detect you know happy or smiley faces.
Right.
So the next layer.
Okay.
In our our journey is what we call of the max appallingly.
OK.
Again let's let's take a look.
Let's go back.
Let's take a look at one.
So if you give us a call that's our convolution network.
OK.
That's the overall network.
Again here we have our fully connected artificial network which consists of a bunch of neurones which
as we discussed how can we do that.
Here we have our Simply our target class we have either zero or one zero indicates not smiling.
One indicates mining.
And here we have the different layers.
OK.
So we have our image here we have our first convolution layers which generates our feature maps.
He we know how can we do the beta Lou which is you know again used for non-linear and non-linearity
within our network.
And now to the fun part.
Now we need to discuss how can we do the pooling or Max pooling which is this layer cake.
So pulling simply takes the feature detectors.
So these are the feature maps and simply put reduces the dimensionality of these feature maps into kind
of you know welchol Appalling filters or smaller versions of them just to make a bit more efficient
to be ready to train our network or defeated or fully connected network.
How can you do that.
That's our topic for this lecture.
All right.
So in order to do mext pooling or I we simply let's take a look at a quick example.
Literally that's our image.
Okay let's assume that we're going to use a max pooling layer of all college to buy 10.
So simply put the mext pooling is again another filter.
Hume and assume it's two by two.
Okay.
And well Greek Greek use a specific type of pooling we'll call the max pooling.
OK.
What do you mean.
So simply put we're going to go through this simple assume that we have two by two matrix.
So we're going to put the two point two Matrix here on our image.
We're going to select the maximum pixel value.
So he what's the maximum out of these voter values.
Simply put it's a six.
And that's why here.
This pixel going to be six.
And then we're going to move simply our filters to the right and then are going to select the maximum
value so the maximum value out of all of their wins out of all of these out is 8.
So that's why we selected eight.
They all come here.
We select the maximum value which has lines will select nine.
We've come here to select the maximum value which is four and that will become four.
And that's pretty much how can we do with the max pooling.
All right so what's your what's the essence like what happened.
What happened is actually very important.
Here we had a an image or a feature map of four by four pixels.
Right.
This has been kind of reduced it to becoming two by two which is very powerful.
Now we actually use them in shanidar pretty much in two like you know like half or even maybe like kind
a quarter of it.
So pulling down sampling layers are placed AFTER called volution leaders to deduce feature map they
mention allotey this improve the computational efficiency.
So now the network doesn't need to go ahead and train all these players.
Actually teams are kind of this smaller values.
One key element one key important aspect is that pooling helps the model to generalise by avoiding overfilling.
And there's actually a very important aspect.
So let's assume that for example the value of six was in here let's say the value of six for example
it was here okay.
What's going to happen actually this this matrix will going to be exactly the same which means that
even if the pixels are shifted a little bit.
So let's say this 6 was contained in here.
Even if they apply the exact same spooling the value of this you know would become six as well.
Why.
Because again we just we are putting the maximum of kind of renauld Reason of pixels and that's very
powerful.
So the network would be able to generalize so even for example if let's see the smiling face shifted
a little bit to the right we've shifted a little bit to the left.
We'll do an old shift that somehow like let's say the faces looking down or up or whatever we the network
would be able to generalize.
Why.
Because we are NARP pick some dependent we are paying the maximum values here.
Out of all of them and we come up with certain value for specific hinode kind of you know kind of zipping
format you are condensing all these pixels into one value of pixels quality 6.
So Max Pauling works by detailing the maximum feature response within a given sample size and if each
map.
So we simply select only the pixels that have the highest impact.
So out of let's say these pixels the highest impact is this which is that's why we selected it out of
these pixels the highest one of the best one is actually the value of nine and so on.
Great.
All right.
OK.
Let's take a look at a life illustration of the of the Empire layers that we discussed so far.
So now we know how can we perform Peacher detection.
How can we do our play there Lou.
Activation function.
And then how can we obtain our our next pooling actually before going ahead to the life illustration.
What I wanted to show you is one last layer is what we call the flattening layer.
And after that then we're going to be ready to the life lustration.
What happened after mewl pain this matrix.
Okay.
With this kind of you know the max spalling layer we or we perform a code flattening we simply take
this and flatten it up.
We make it in a one column six eight nine and four and that's it.
Then you are pretty much ready to take veres the flattened layer and feed it to the network and that's
pretty much how can you run or how can you build your volution urine.
Before we start coding Let's go ahead and go into a light illustration to understand what you mean here
to that link.
I understand what you mean by this.
You know could have been convolution in that network in action.
All right.
So let's take a look at the convolution here our network in action.
So please go ahead to the s c s.
Right.
And let's see a backslash.
And there is a Harley spects ledge vis Leisure's com flat HCM.
And you can find the link as well in the lecture slides and that's pretty really interesting website
because it shows you the in Piku convolutions in action.
So simply here.
In our example we wanted to kind of perform a very simple exercise to detect happy faces are these smiling
or not.
Either one or zero.
However he we wanted to detect numbers so this kind of in all this dataset that Selena famously set
just you know like you can draw whatever value you want here and it would tell you what where did you
draw he was at 0 1 2 3 4 or up to nine.
So let's give it a shot.
Let's assume I'm going to just going to write five here you can simply computer write five.
Okay.
You can write whatever five you want.
All right.
And basically that's the that's all the different layers in action.
It's brilliant to have really amazing.
So I guess I can see here if you find that these are kind of the first layer to the convolution layer.
These are the different feature maps that you're pinned.
And that's kind of you know like the first empirically you can show or disable an image.
So if you can do show if you can remove it that we're on move this.
That's our input.
So that's our employer.
This is the convolution lady can show it and you can enable it.
So that's our feature maps.
You guys remember we apply the convolutions which is you know different filters to come up with these
feature feature maps again all the featured maps the different you find you know here a little bit darker
here a little bit like or brighter here and so on.
And that's our feature maps firstly and then afterwards from the feature maps we do with the max pwning
layer which is simply what we call it here down sampling.
So down sampling this is pretty much a scene for mext pooling.
You can actually show it you should hide it.
It's really interesting too.
If you guys can see that simply the image here was let's say the dimensions was let's say 64 64 here
it has been down sampled.
OK.
Which is the advantages of the wiener Amex pulling in.
Bear in mind that the image just pretty up to see if you take a look at here between these two.
Okay.
The actual features are still intact even though a lot of information has been you know kind of downsized
have been down sample have been kind of zipped.
Think of it as kind of doing zipping to the fire.
The information is in the sea.
However the size is much less.
And then afterwards we have another convolution layer which is convincingly as to you can show it and
you can hide it which is this confusion low.
OK.
And then we have another down sample English which is simply this lake which is taking again these features
there and selling them again one more time and then down now to the fun part.
Basically what we have here is our fully connected fishing network.
We do the fully connected which is this layer.
But my this has been flattened.
Right.
And then we have another fully connected layer which is this layer and then the output will be out quickly.
If you get bitten.
This is very important to make sure that here we have 10 samples of 10 neurones in the output showing
simply our values from zini from zero to nine.
Okay which is which is exactly what we're looking for.
To classify whatever value we're going to be putting here into one of these categories from one to nine.
All right that looks great.
So that's pretty much how can we implement convolutions or evolution you know what in action if you
can see here you would find that the guest the first guess was actually right we had 0 5 in here and
we put your pain down.
The actual value added to the first guess was actually five which is perfect.
And what it's telling you here the second guess which is you know kind of the next best one is milk
is eight case with saying you the best one was five and then the next one it might be eight but because
the first guess was highest has higher probability.
So that's what has been classified as five which is a two stroke class or eight.
Let's actually give that and let's maybe try another value.
Let's try for example zero as we do here.
And that's telling you okay that's out there on cemp and growing that's our 0.
Our first guest was actually 02 which is you know these again our all the future maps all I want Max
pooling layers.
Again another feature convolution lay of two.
And then another down sampling layer and then again another two layers here showing the fully connected
network which is a maze again a classes you two.
And then I guess a six.
Let's give that let's may be right for example eight.
Let's make it.
Looks a little bit like this.
Aniston and you again the first guess eight second guess is six.
Let's maybe try zero.
But maybe let's not con this non stop like here.
It's actually even you know it was able to even deal with even though we're didn't close heat here.
The first guess what's the insula which you'll scream.
Let's maybe try another parameter.
Let's say try for example seven.
So let's make it like you know like this for example shows yorki.
Yes was seven.
And the second guess was one one.
Why.
Because one is actually speeding pretty close to the seven.
Right.
Let's try one.
And it tells you actually that was first class was first guess was one.
Looks good.
Let's try for example make a little bit later all seven or a one day.
Again the first guest was one and the second guess was seven mixteca Looks good.
Again you guys can you know spend the entire day playing here with you know with this.
It's really interesting because now I actually see kind of you know like like an immense brain which
is amazing.
Now you've built kind of the mini brain.
You're right you can train that brain to do whatever you want.
Classifying numbers classify images translate data you know like to interpret for example voice the
natural language processing.
It's just fascinating.
All right looking let's enjoy that section and see you in the next section.