Hello everyone and welcome this lecture.
I'm super excited because we're going to start building our conclusionary network and this lecture.
So let's get started.
Please go ahead to the smiling face faces the doctors using CNN ads.
OK.
In the course package.
And let's get started then build our network from scratch.
So here as you can see here we have a series of steps.
First we're going to introduce the problem statement and then step two.
We're going to see can we improve the data visual either data train our model and then evaluate our
model.
Ah right okay.
It's the problem statement.
Again as we've discussed before in the series lectures that the dealer set contains a series of images
that can be used to solve what called the happy house problem.
Okay.
We can use it to build an artificially network to detect happy or smiling faces only smiling faces will
be allowed to enter the house and the data set consists of seven hundred and fifty images.
Six hundred examples are for training and one fifth the hour for testing and the data source.
All right.
Let's go ahead and import our packages and our data as well.
So what we're going to do here as we have done before.
We're going to import pandas as PD.
We're going to import num pie as n.p. and we're going to import maths plus clear thought.
PI plot as.
NY going to import as well import seaboard.
Seaboard's as s.a. and as well.
We're going to import two important packages too which is going to use them later to call it import
each 5 p y which going to be used mainly to read our specific images which is you know kind of stored
in a and reformat I'm going to show you right now.
And then we're going to import it as well.
Our Random form of random number generation.
That's from these gay ran good or good.
Now let's go ahead and let's import our data set.
So if you guys go to you the Course package you would find that here there are two datasets we'll call
it test underscored happy dot H H5.
And this train underscored happy.
H five.
All right.
So let's go ahead and read the lead these fights.
First let's see how can we read the keys out of this file.
This is kind of this very special file.
Show how can we need it.
It's very simple.
But before we did it let's see how the data within that file is actually classified.
So let's assume they're going to say okay fine I mean equal to.
We're going to say train underscore happy and let's see Dot H five.
Okay.
And let's say okay f equals two he were just reading a file that say okay where do you use H 5 p y dot
file and please make sure that the f is uppercase.
And we're going to pass along the finally an OR get a pass along and open that file for reading purposes.
Okay.
Let's run.
That's Gail looks good.
And I would add the file and the file hugest thing with an F..
Let's go ahead and indeed the keys within that files or win a sale key for key in F dot keys.
And what are going to say okay let's print out the keys.
So that's one that I'm sure to spend the key because we're just getting key on that.
And that's what we give here.
We have got the list classes and he we have team set x and we have train set.
Why.
So simply put our team and the squad happy look each 5 which is a training data campaign simply these
you know three we're not interested in just in this one really interesting the input upbeat.
I just wanted to do that mean so we can call them accordingly.
Okay.
All right.
Let's see how can we read them.
Miss Let's read again let's open our file.
So going to say okay I'm going to call happy underscored training equal to h 5 p y dot file.
And what are going to open our chain underscored.
Happy H fi quality underscore happy thought.
H5 and we are going to open this as well for reading purposes right.
And then we're going to do the exact same thing.
Then a copy paste.
I'm going to read that instead of happy training.
You're going to read happy but we're going to keep happy.
Testing and instead of teen.
I'm just happy with is going to be test of discord.
Happy that age 5 again for reading purposes.
Let's run that.
OK you know what.
Good right.
So now we have simco HAPPY training and help testing and what we need to do with it.
We need to go ahead within these two.
Okay and that's why we actually performed this step.
We wanted to go ahead and capture or fetch our train and just set X entertain underscore set Y and that's
what we're looking for.
Once we have that then we're good to go.
Then we can simply prepare the data as extreme.
Why train ecstasy and why tests are it.
Let's start with exchange we're going to get say OK extreme sequence to what we wanted to do that we
wanted to get.
Extreme whiteread excess weight in an umpire array so we can say okay n p doc array or agreed to call
our happy underscore training which is what we are paying here.
Okay but we want it to simply go ahead within this and actually capture team underscore sets and discotheques.
So let's take that.
Let's copy it here and let's do this.
And wanted to get all the data so you can say okay let's go ahead.
Colin indicates we're gonna need all the data within treen said X. Let's do the same thing here.
But we wanted to mr. that extreme.
I'm going to call it ytn.
And again I'm going to go in with an happy training.
Which is here which is our fire that you're in here.
But when old painting set in the X women equality and said why are we going to do the exact same thing
but not for training.
We're going to do it for testing.
So we're going to go here with happy.
Vesting.
And happy.
Best thing.
I'm going to have extreme tests.
Why tests are right.
Looks good.
Let's sit on it.
Let's stay on it.
Let's try it.
Okay that is an error here.
So my apologies.
These are called test set X or these so-called tests and these are called testers were strong.
It looks good.
Now we're good now are good to go.
Now we have extreme ytn X test what they're stylistic.
Look and view some of the data so extreme.
Take a look at extreme.
And that's all we've got here.
What do you mean by this.
These are basically a bunch of images that our image if you just remember it when we represent any image
it's simply a bunch of pixels and these pixels has values fridges from 0 to 255.
We're zero indicates total black 255 indicates total white.
And these are the values of the pixels.
That's our all our images here.
So basically this is a kind of a little bit dark or black pixel.
This is like kind of a grey pixel.
If you go down here that's you know like let's say that's two hundred and four.
That's all kind of very white pixel 255 that's pure white pixel and so on so forth.
OK.
Let's take a look at let's see how many images do we have.
Let's confirm if we actually have 600 knots let's say.
Extreme shape.
Let's run that.
And that's the format.
So now we have 64 by 64 which has dimensions of the pixels.
And because it's a coloured image and it's not a greyscale image.
So you would find the column image actually consists of three layers.
And that's why we have 64 by 64 by three and we actually have 600.
It's kind of you know 14 dimensional array in a way where 600 in the kids the number of images we have.
Yes that's right.
We have 600 images and there's the format of each specific image.
Let's take a look at why train for the train.
You will come up with this which is basically a bunch of Zoos and once we're zino indicates no smiling
one indicates smiling.
That's it.
Let's confirm the whiteread shape so you can see why train dogs shape they can look at it.
Again it's 600 values which makes sense because that's the opaquely.
Right.
It has only 600 values of from a training perspective.
And we have a bunch of zeros and ones corresponding to each of the images that we have in our training
did.
All right.
Let's recap what we have done so far.
Well done so far that we went through the problem statement.
We imported all our libraries here and then here we imported all our data into extreme Why treat ecstasy.
Why test.
We took a look at the images right and we took a look at the shape as well so now we have 600 images.
When it comes to training and we have 150 actual testing and that's pretty much all we have for this
lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next lecture.