Hello everyone and welcome to this election.
Let's get started.
Let's try to solve a couple of the questions that we have here.
OK.
So first I ask you to create a dictionary we see of your favourite friends and their respective age
and print the age of the second meme you choose.
All right.
Let's get it straight talk talking a created dictionary.
Call it let's say my friends.
My friends.
And here I'm going to did declare or define a dictionary can you scrawly brackets.
And let's assume let's create a couple of new cells here just to make a little bit readable.
And what it could do here.
I'm going to say okay then my first friend let's call a Killick column for example lylah for instance.
And the age let's say is 25 I bracket comment.
Okay.
Let's find the second name.
Let's call it Sally for instance.
And we're going to call it 22 years old comma and let's say again a third name with good solid quality.
Rob for instance and their age is let's say 31.
All right let's make a little bit clear here.
So here they have my beautiful dictionary okay for it it's right.
And it actually come here.
And guess it it prints.
And I can pass along my friends and you'll come up with the beautiful dictionary.
Right.
And I'm asking you to print simply this second the age simply of the second name you choose which is
whatever name you choose you get.
So what we do here.
Say it prints little X's second element and say okay go to my underscore friends pocket dictionary and
again to access that specific value for you as a member.
I can access the values within the dictionary using its key which is Sally here they open square brackets.
And here I can specify case Sally and that's it.
So if you access it at 22 that's exactly what I was looking for.
All right.
Perfect.
I hope you guys were able to figure that out.
That was pretty straightforward.
Let's delay couple of cells here and let's enso Couple of nuisance here.
Second question is I wanted to create a dictionary with some of your favourite friends and their respective
hourly wage.
End up Kane the average of all the standards.
OK that's pretty interesting.
So let's get started.
And I say Okay my underscore for example friends.
All right.
And I'm going to say okay equals two brackets.
I'm going to say Okay.
First name is let's say again I'm going to stick with the C names lylah and let's say I was making 25
dollars an hour.
Second one we're going to be let's say Sally and Sally is making for instance twenty two dollars an
hour.
And then the last name let's see equality Rob and Rob is let's see making for example thirty one dollars
an hour.
Whatever you guys can call it whatever.
Or I could do here.
And then I say okay that's good.
And I can come here let's say to Prince for example my underscore friends I'm going to print my dictionary.
Looks great.
And he don't want to talk cane.
For example the average little kid the average I need to go into my dictionary.
Access these numbers add them up and divided by three.
That's pretty much it.
Let's get let's see.
Can we do that and say OK I wanted to first access my first element which is my friends.
Right.
And I wanted to access the first one I can access again using the name lylah that will return the first
value which is 25 right.
I can.
Let's say.
Copy and paste.
And instead of lay low it is going to say OK I need Sally right for a minute.
They'll give me twenty two a second venue.
Great.
I can copy it again and I can put raabe and you for it and that's that should return me back so want
which is so so then perfect.
Now I need to simply I can put that just copy this and put it here.
Plus and copy it.
Copy.
This one and plus and copy it's perfect.
Now I have to master the summation of all of them.
I don't mean the summation of the average.
So to some of them up we're going to users are going to add parentheses here.
For example right here know some of them up and now I can simply buy them divided by three.
Sorry just to give the average right.
And I can put that lets say into a variable called Average for example.
And if I run it and I can go here and print for example my average and if I had done it you would come
up with a value of 26 which is basically the average of all these numbers.
All right.
That's pretty much how can you update the axis elements within dictionary and an opt in their average
beauty.
Perfect.
The next question that we have here is let's create new cells.
And I'm asking you to update the previous dictionary we still have your next favourite fans and the
respective salaries too.
And then the average of all the salaries.
Let's this again copy our Again the exact same one here.
I mean I'm trying to test you and or your abilities on how to add additional elements to your dictionary.
It's OK to do that and say okay my underscore friends and I will love to add in your line I am going
to say okay.
Square brackets.
I have to specify the key for us.
See.
For example Mary and I'm going to associate the value of 22 for example as her salary.
Again add another line my friends or the new key value pair and I'm going to call her for example or
call him exemplar Peter.
An ominous sign.
An hourly wage of 25 for example.
And that's fine and that looks good.
Nor etta's if I wanted to print for example my apologies print my underscore friends all around it.
You'll come up with lylah salyer ROBB Mary and Peter which means that you have successfully added these
two new elements.
Right.
What if I want to talk in the average or right or pin average as we done before.
We can go here and do this exact same stuff you get but I need to add.
First and it did this make it 5 because now I've done the average of five elements but I need to add
two more elements to do that.
Then I say okay I'm going to copy this right.
In a sea of kit plus pastes plus and paste but only to update it.
Obviously here is a good garbage in this market.
Mary Ann come here to update this and make it okay.
And let's make a little bit better.
Let's run it.
So we're on.
That's And I can come here and print the value of the average and that then you would come up with a
value of 25 or OK.
OK.
Perfect.
Again this is kind of you know a very basic way of actually paying all the elements with addiction.
I'm going to show you one forward that there's a better way of actually doing this just all in all elements.
Now in the summation of okay how can we do that.
Let's actually cover it right now right away.
In order to do that.
Another way of doing it.
I'm going to say Okay want it all.
All the elements within like I want to say 25 22 31 22 and so on.
Well let's do that.
I'm going to say OK.
Go to my friends.
OK.
And apply a method that we call it values and open basically prentice's that we're just going to go
there and open in all the values right away.
You don't need to go and Axxess each element separately which is the beauty of Python that's actually
very powerful.
But just using this simple method you can opt in all the values right away and then you can upload you
can do wonders with them.
I think what I could do here I say okay I need to some play function.
It's called Some nation.
Right.
That's some of the values and after you do this just multiply whatever you're going to get here by five.
All right.
And let's print that and let's print that.
So if I wanted to print it it is going to go here and print their value for it.
You'll come up with the exact same answer which is great again.
Just to clarify it I'm printing.
With the print right.
I'm told to print again.
It is a summation.
It is a summation function of trying to some right some summing up elements.
Right.
And.
The summation simply dividing by five walked in the average.
And this returns all the elements.
This simply returns all the values and getting hit 25 22 31 22 and 25 which is in a just one shot of
writing all these lines.
I can just do it here in one simple show.
All right.
Let's take one more example.
Okay so here I'm asking you to write a code that multiplies all elements in the following dictionary.
Okay.
So in order to do that what I would do here.
You're going to say okay I need to for example to multiply all elements are going to find kind of an
accumulator or a variable that is going to be be using to just pick an element and multiply it so it's
okay.
I'm going to set it to one gay and every time I'm going to say okay my total value equals to my total
or are old and will get to multiply by go please to my dictionary which I have here and please is the
first element so I can access the element data one.
All right.
So that we're thinking in a go here or in the first element.
Right.
And multiplied by 1 and then we're going to be the total here.
Okay.
I want to do it again in a very simple form I'm going to do it you know and kind of on separate lines.
OK.
So going to copy this and I'm going to go here in a paste and paste.
Every time I'm going to go get data to an income give it a three.
And my total value and then here is going to go and print my total.
Right.
So on this.
Let's run through on this first.
This and this any would come up with the total which is simply the multiplication of all this.
Again I'm going to leave it for you guys.
You can again do it again in one line obviously but I'm just showing that to you because moving forward
I'm going to show you how can we use 40 loops to actually do all this operation.
Just in a very simple just one single line.
And it's not like of course which is the simple truth.
All right.
Okay.
And that's pretty much what I have for this election.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and let's continue with the next exercises in the next election.