Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
And the biggest lecture I want to see how can we extract more than one page from a PDA.
And we simply just obtained or created our 3D PBF object and we simply looped across every single page
within our our PDA.
And we're able to obtain the entire text simply here.
What we're going to do here in this kind of you know mini project per say that we wanted to add a watermark
or PDA.
OK.
Which is a little bit different.
So the first step is in order to add the watermark to a PDA if you think about it that we have we need
to have two sources.
Right.
We need to have two PDA FS Our original PDA if that we wanted to simply add a watermark to it.
And the second one is the actual watermark which is going to be a PDA.
Right.
And then what we need to do that we need to simply merge these two Fs together once we merge them.
That's it.
That means you added a watermark already.
So let's go up here and see OK.
What is the watermark.
So while you guys can see here you'll find that there is a watermark kind of confidential you know like
PBF I created here.
I'm going to provide you guys with it too.
This is can you get can I please go ahead and tell you whatever you know like PBF.
The idea here is to show you how can we merge two PDX together which is kind of addition.
The idea of adding a watermark so simply and you just needed to add confidential here to whatever PDA
or whatever sample you have they're going to be working with says go ahead and see how can we do that.
All right.
So the first step I need to simply open two files for reading purposes and open one file for writing
purposes.
Right.
OK let's go ahead and read the first one.
So first I need to open my watermark
so you find that there is watermark underscore confidential on the score to PD F and we can open this
for reading purposes.
OK.
And what we could do after is we're gonna say okay let's create an object and let's let's actually name
it.
So we won't be like you know like confused afterwards I'm gonna call a 3D but this is read mainly read
for the watermark right.
So this an actual watermark I'm going to say PBF file reader because I can open it and can open that
file F and let's go ahead what I need I just need to get page but I need to get the four page number
to zero only because it simply contains just one single page going to say OK watermark
on the score page equals two.
Again read watermark which is our simply object that refers to the PD f that had the watermark and one
of that saying I need to get page and I need to get page number zero.
So that means we just obtained in here just one single page which has the confidential kind of you know
like sign in there here.
Okay.
All right that's good.
Shift enter looks great.
Next step is we wanted to create our file to be watermark right.
It's going to take a F equals two open and I'm going to say here I'm going to open let's say you know
the exact same simple file and I'm going to open it again for reading purposes
it's actually do this shift enter looks good and afterwards I'm going to say okay let's go ahead and
create three PD F equals to PD f reader again because I'm gonna be reading right and I want to read
that file again.
It's exactly the same as these two lines exactly the same because I'm reading APD f it's exactly the
same idea but this one will just read it because this is a watermark file.
This one is simply our file to be watermarked which is you know our let's say the exact same text that
we had that shift enter shift entered Osgood.
So simply now I have to read re PD Fs.
Okay.
Now I'm pretty much ready to actually create my right to object and do the actual writing.
So let's create our writer objects are going to say okay right underscored PD F equals two.
We're going to create PD f writer so PDL file writers.
Okay.
And that'll be my first object here.
Here we go.
Shift enter.
Good.
And let's go ahead and actually loop across every single page out of our PD F and do that kind of merging
in there.
That's the overall idea.
So what we can do is say Okay nine pages let's go and obtain how many pages we have because I'm gonna
do that every single page in there myself KP The F dots get num pages
get numb pages.
And here actually that will be our because we're reading our read PDA.
So let's go ahead and actually Captain our EPD F to obtain get nine pages.
Let's run that.
Let's take a look at it.
Let's take a look at number pages.
Here we go.
Now we have eight eight pages which is good.
All right all right.
Now we're pretty much ready to go ahead and do our full loop so going to take a forward page in range.
We're going to pass along here our nine pages.
Right.
OK.
So we're going to loop on every single page every time I'm going to go there obtain a page out of our
read PBF object which is our original PDA of the PDA that wanted to watermark and merge that page with
our work watermark page watermark page which is what we obtain here.
OK.
This is simply our watermark right.
So every time I was just gonna grab a page and merge it with this.
Grab another page merged with this and so on so forth.
Let's do it.
So I'm gonna say okay our single and the score page equals to re PD free to underscore PBF dot get page
of page.
So every time I'm just gonna go ahead go ahead in here and obtain a single page.
All right.
Let's so every time I'm going to go here over this Loop go to my red PBF which is my you know sample
the that I wanted to have more watermarked obtain a certain page with specific index.
And we're going to call it single page and take that single page object or that single actual actual
single page.
And what we're going to do going to see emerge page along with our water mark the underscore page which
is simply what we have here.
Watermark on this page.
Okay.
Looks good afterwards.
Let's go ahead and this is simply right now single page contains the actual just sample page that has
been watermark.
Let's go ahead and do it or write it into our right PBF object which is simply going to be our out output
file.
Right.
So going to take a right underscore PD f I'm going to say dot ed page and we're going to pass along
here our single underscore page again.
So here we merged our watermark page to our sample page that we obtained.
Take that simple single page and added to our right PBF object.
So by the end of the loop and we keep going our right PD field will contain eight pages and all of them
are watermarked right shift enter the caliber of time looks good.
Let's go ahead and simply take our IP F and just put it into like whatever document you call it whatever
it's going to take APD f underscore outputs equals to open.
And here we can pass along our let's call it sample PD f watermarked.
This is gonna be our new newly created PD F and we can open this video for writing purposes when I say
right binary.
And then afterwards we're gonna say Okay let's take our object which is IPD F right underscore PD F
and dot right our information again.
Right.
Object write it to our PD f output right.
Our file K looks good.
Let's go ahead and close both of them.
So PD f underscore.
Output dot close.
And let's go ahead and actually close f close as well which is our file in there.
Shift enters.
Looks good.
My apologies actually we forgot to do this.
Shift entry looks good.
Let's go ahead and check said check out sample the F watermark PD F so let's go here.
Samples.
I call that sample PD f watermarked.
Let's open it.
And here we go.
This is our beautiful file obviously because this speedy video is kind of you know like it.
This is not transparent.
So yes we actually merge it.
OK.
But we were unable to actually obtain here to make it transparent.
Right.
No please go ahead guys and try to maybe like you know change that confidential thing and added he'll
make it transparent somehow and merge it.
But as the overall idea of how can we actually add the watermark to our PDA.
Okay.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed the entire lecture and the entire project as well.
All right.
That's all what I have for this project.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Let's recap what we have done so far so far.
So in this project we were able to master kind of our PBF manipulations.
We're able to add our first part of the project to extract information from a PDA file so we're able
to actually you know learn how can we get document information or even extract text out of a PDA.
And in the next learning outcome we're able to copy a single page and paste it in a newly created PDA.
Again the overall idea is to create a reader object create a writer object and simply just write your
PDA f object into whatever name you want it to specify in the learning outcome three were able to rotate
PDA PDA files and right into them.
So able to actually extract pages rotated clock clockwise and then write it in whatever PDA you have
here and then in learning outcome for we're able to read multiple pages overall idea is exactly the
same.
You can open our our PDA.
And then here instead of just writing or extracting a single page we're just gonna create the for loop
to go ahead and pass over every single page and extract it.
All right.
And we're able to actually set every single text within our PDA.
And then learning outcome 5 which is kind of know the most fun part of out of all is to simply merge
two PDX together.
So we're able to kind of you know get a simple PBF and then merge into it a watermark.
All right.
And we did that every single page.
That's why we had to do again on other for loop in here.
And then we closed all files and that should conclude our project.
All right I hope you guys enjoy this project and see you in future projects.