Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm so excited because now we're actually going to start evaluate our model or test our model and see
if it makes sense or not.
OK.
And the P.S. We show how can we actually build our model.
So we built our model here in a sequential fashion using all the convolutions mext pooling drop out
flattening and then we actually use the EDM optimizers to optimize our models so we optimize it and
we as well went through a little bit of challenge mini challenge and we plotted using 25 epics to actually
change here and teach our model.
Let's go ahead and please evaluate our model.
Okay.
So how can we do this.
So simply on our model or were network Wheat's everything is simply contained here within our object.
You see in an undiscovered model that has everything all the information we want.
So you say okay eveil equals two CNN underscored model dot evaluate.
Then we can pass along our testing data and then say okay X underscored test and let's see why underskirt
tests work.
All right.
And that should simply kind of you know look evaluate our our performance using the testing datasets
Let's try and that's to get an matterless Okay.
That's the valuation again you know we have 150 semples.
All right let's go ahead and actually print our evaluation.
So let's go ahead and say okay print.
We're going to specify here our test accuracy what we do use the format method.
We're going to say that there was less accuracy and we're going to use Quilly bracket huge figures in
a membership to see Dot format.
And basically the eveil here what we are pains in here when we then evaluate method simply give to our
accuracy in the location number one.
So we we have simply event contains two value zero on one and he would in number one.
OK.
And the umpire Ray simply we're going to update our accuracy in here.
So that's on that.
And here we are actual page 93 percent accuracy which is really good.
All right let's.
Over the pure testing dataset.
OK so what we need to do here is that we wanted to actually visualize the results and that's pretty
interesting.
So what we do here we wanted to plot render images.
OK.
And we're going to simply plot our intended index okay which is the right index or like a label persay
which is for example if we have a smiling face that will have output one anyone going to clock as well.
The predicted opiate kind of out of our model.
So simply put we're trying to get to basically print both at the same time when to print the right or
target label.
And we're going to print as well.
The predictions coming out from model.
So let's take a look and actually view the predictor class when they say okay predicted.
Predicted underscored class.
Are going to say it equals to CNN underscored model which is our twin one.
Anyone going to say okay CNN that underscored model dot predict underscored classes or can pass along
our testing datasets were simply here.
We can say okay we use our.
This is again our teen model.
We're going to use the product classes method.
We're going to pass along our testing dataset and here that will give us a little section on there.
Let's see what's going to happen.
Okay let's go ahead and actually view with a pretty big classes.
Let's run it.
And that's very interesting.
So I guess I can see here this basically a bunch of zeros and ones.
And there are one hundred and fifty values.
OK.
So we have one hundred and fifty of predictive classes or a that's kind of you know the the the guests
coming out of our trained network.
Right.
OK.
So let's go ahead and add a couple of the lines he had because you have tons of information coming.
Let's go ahead and actually view our predictive classes dimensions.
So this book it predicted underscored classes dot shape.
Let's take a look.
So predicted underscored classes.
They're cheap.
So predictive clatters is not defined.
So it's actually called predictive class.
My apologies.
Let's run it's a classic.
That's 150 by one.
OK.
That's looks looks good.
Well one to compare is simply wouldn't it wouldn't in our predictions going to compared it to why underscored
tests.
If you remember to test our right labels straight this is our predicted labels coming from our far from
our model.
So let's compare the dimensions of both actually 150 and 150 that looks good.
Now one actually pretty much ready to go ahead and plot our data or visualize our out of date.
So to the final key I would agree that again we're going to say eliquis 5 equal to 5 and I'm going to
say a figure as a member figure and axes.
Axes equals two BLT darts sub plots figure as a member of the logo at l o w n our fig size.
Equals to Ghana.
Let's say they find us 12 and 12 and we're going to use axes equals two axes dot travel.
Right.
To flatten it up against exactly the same as we've done before.
And I say okay for are in N P dot arrange in a pass along from zero up till L multiplied by W..
N or against the Iraqi axes of index II which is or any number that is generated image show an on going
to say okay I need to go ahead and view our next guests of index II.
So when to show the retesting the actual imaged excess of index either the actual image and reaction
want a plot as well.
Two things.
On top of it we wanted to plot our predictive class and our true class as well.
Okay axes of index I got Seth underscored tidal.
We're going to say okay let's sure litzman Shami predictions.
This is my apologies this is my predictions.
Or a prediction class let's call it so it makes sense to us and brings a friend met method trick in
this book that's really bracket's you.
And what really do we do in and use becs flesh.
And if you remember it that we're going to print the next whatever going to write it afterwards to be
printed in a new line.
What I wanted to do with I wanted to show prediction class equals let's say one or zero and then in
the new line we're going to print our our tooleybuc afterwards as well.
So it's okay.
Our true class equates to going to have brackets as well.
And good to see Dot formats anyone get a pass along our predictive class classes predicted underscored
class of index.
And we wanted to show us why underscored tests of two rates.
That looks pretty good to me.
Okay let's actually run there.
Let's see if we if that makes sense.
Ah right.
Looks pretty great.
So now we have all our images five by five.
And if you take a look here he did sure this our prediction class of 1.
So that's kind of our comfort of the upper coming from our network.
Okay during testing fees and there were two classes what that means.
This is correct.
This is good one on one.
This is a good one and one great that's a bad one.
OK is this prediction class was actually zero.
While the tool class was actually showing one.
OK.
Which is simply put that's that's that's kind of you know one of the one of the sources of the area
that's why we didn't achieve for example 100 percent accuracy on the testing data.
We actually had showed 93 percent accuracy on the testing dataset.
Right.
And here we can view that much.
So what we could do here.
I'm going to say okay let's go ahead and do the space.
If you as a member of the there before BLT dot sub plots on discord adjusts as a member and were going
to say Okay deblieux space or H space would be let's say point five that will shift us.
Let's let's find each piece first equates to let's say point four.
And let's try on that.
All right.
Looks a little bit better.
Let's actually make it even point six.
And it looks way better now.
So we actually now have our image.
We have our producer class and I was to class as well.
OK.
Looks pretty good.
Well we could do as well that we can disable our Sukie axes of index.
I would say Dot axis.
Then we can send that to off.
Let's say from that that we're just going to disable simply all our you know 64 64 pixels because we
know that the are 6 4 6 4 pixels anyways.
All right let's go ahead and parse the video.
Please go ahead and try the challenge.
Well I wanted to do here.
I wanted to again instead of printing 5 way.
I want to print 10 by 10 matrix.
Please go ahead and tested yourself and piece let me know how many semples have been corrected been
classified and how many samples have been misclassified.
Go ahead a positive you and see you after the challenge.
All right.
You guys were able to figure out the challenge yourself.
So what you were asked to do is simply to go ahead and change.
Here's this from five let's say to 10.
Right and two please go ahead and run this so let's try it.
And that's what we've got here.
It looks pretty cramped.
You know like you actually can't read it much because of ask I've asked you to count how many semples
have been correctly classified and how many Semper that have been misclassified.
So we could do it that we could say okay maybe we can adjust the width here between the semples.
OK we're going to keep realty sub plots against say pythian Suppose underscored just N we're going to
see a key deblieux space equals to let's say point five.
Let's run that.
And that's what we've got here.
Again it didn't help much.
So maybe we can adjust the H space so we can dual kill it's go ahead and just the H space.
Make it for example a little bit more.
Let's say one point five for example just to make it you know look as much as as big as we can.
And again it's really tough to see your heart actually read it.
OK.
So let's go back and exchanged point five an organ to do here.
Again do a little bit of kind of a trick ok.
I'm going to see okay let's copy this.
Let's keep it as is going to.
Copy.
I'm going to go here and paste it.
Let's have a basically comment this out and here it seems the prediction class in auxilary new long
word the word I'm doing and I say okay that's our prediction right.
So were going to say okay that's our let's see.
Quick guess and let's make it as efficient as possible.
And were going to make the true class let's call it true.
And that's it that's run that.
And that's what we've got here.
Actually maybe you can increase the each space make it let's say point nine let's run notes.
And it's much better now.
That's actually way more readable.
Okay so while yes cats do hear construction accounting.
So here we have one misclassify.
He we have all that are good.
We have two.
Three okay.
And then keep going.
You basically count all the number of samples that have been critical as a fibre misclassified.
All right.
And that's pretty much all of what I what I would ask you to do for the challenge in the next election.
I'm going to show you in much better way.
Actually the present of the data okay in a very beautiful kind of format.
Right.
More confusion matrix.
Please stay tuned.
I hope it doesn't do with their letter.
And see you in the next lecture.