All right.
Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's get going.
So the question for I'm asking you to develop a script.
OK apology.
This should be a script whose items are squares of the original list.
All right.
So let's go ahead and maybe define any lists of necessary.
My list equals two.
Let's call it range.
And for example the final 121.
OK.
And what we could do here.
I'm going to say OK.
The let's go ahead and print the new list right.
And that list will simply be what we could do.
We're going to take it for x in my underscore lists.
So every time I'm going to go.
Go ahead in this list which is usually defined before.
Take a number.
And every time you take that number and simply square it we're going to say okay x square.
That's it.
So that's simply a script whose items are squares of the original lists.
Pretty simple really simple it's run it.
And that's what we're getting.
Let's maybe define for example 10 and let's say 20 for example let's run it.
And that's what we're getting so 10 100.
And then number eleven you know squared and so on so forth.
And that's what we're getting here.
All right sounds great.
Question number five and ask you to write a function that squares a variable and then apply the function
write a function that Square is a variable then test the function using the list of integer numbers
ranging from minus 20 to 20.
So basically that's my testing.
OK let's write the function first.
So you don't want the function that simply squares.
No that's really simple I've done that before actually my safe gave.
Define squared.
And I'm going to pass along the variable x and we're going to return to the main our x times x.
That's easy.
Let's call it.
It's going to say okay numbers equals to a defined range.
Right again here from minus let's say 20 to 20.
Okay.
All right.
And what we could do here.
What I wanted to do with I wanted you to add to apply or to run if you guys remember the map.
OK.
The map keywords are really powerful.
We're going to say OK let's let's go ahead and do it.
Going to see a map right.
You guys remember.
Right.
We're going to use a lambda expression right lambda especially take X correct.
And it's going to return these squared of X right and what we could do here when we do the map when
I say okay lambda x we're going to turn the squared of X. You can do it obviously here x squared or
you know X times X and that's it.
You know and with the map you actually pass along the entire list.
Right.
So that's simply our entire list.
You can pass it along here.
Right.
So what you do here is all that you have to cast it again in the form of list right.
I know it's too much.
But again doing one step at a time.
Again think of it this way.
We're going to mapping we're doing a map right.
We're mapping an entire list.
Getting an entire list which is numbers and applying something on all the all the parameters all the
numbers you need to do for loops you don't need to do any of that.
It's going to say okay my numbers here.
I'm going to do a K lambda.
If you pass X I can do X squared or I can just you know call my function squares a square of x.
And afterwards what you're getting here is you cast it in a list format and that simply will going to
be my number.
My numbers or numbers call it numbers squared.
All right.
And let's print that out.
Let's copy it and let's go ahead and print and give you my number squared.
All right.
Obviously that's my kid I'm saying no squared and let's run that and actually you know what.
Let's make it better so I can say okay the square of the lists and it's defined as list is like this
is this for example if you guys remember we can do that list close to the brackets and let's pass along
our numbers right.
Which is simply our input and he ain't gonna pass along our numbers squared.
All right.
Please don't forget to do the format.
So you have a format and we can dig that.
Copy it here.
And that's it.
OK.
All right let's run it.
All right.
So let's take a look here.
Here it looks a little bit weird so it seems OK.
Range minus 20 to 20 right.
So in order to convert that order to make it like you know maybe a little bit like like like readable
what we could do here.
We can go here to the numbers.
OK.
Because the numbers here's data type is actually range.
Let's take a look at it.
So we say okay let's say type of numbers.
Let's run it.
And it's actually range.
Right.
So what we could do is that we can take that numbers right.
And if we cast it here like that.
Convert it into a list and then call it let's say num if we run it.
And if we take a look at num run it you can actually kind of come up with a list here and you can actually
take a look at the type of this you will find that the type is lists.
So now you actually convert that kind of from range you know into a list.
What we could do here you know we don't need to repeat it again.
We're just gonna go in and say OK.
Lists of numbers.
Let's run it.
And that's what we're getting here.
All right.
Looks great.
Actually we could do as well is maybe like add backslash n for instance.
So that's what we're getting.
You know obviously it's not very readable.
We can do as well or we could do with a square of lists and maybe add backslash and here's two.
OK.
Let's run it.
That's what we're getting to the square of the list.
This list is this.
All right.
It looks perfect.
Last question five.
Question number six.
I'm asking you to write a function that takes a radius of a circle and it's in the diameter actually
ask you to see functions to the diameter area circumference and just the function using an input from
a user.
Let's see how can we do that.
All right.
So let's define our first function it's actually very easy question so we ask you to define.
So I'm going to say Circle K OK call.
I call it his diameter.
And some of them are going to take the radius.
Ah OK.
All right.
Looks good.
And simply the radius is our radius of a circle.
If you guys remember it two times whatever input I'm getting right.
OK.
So that's the diameter is simply two times the radius.
All right.
That's good.
Let's define that next function's trying to define again.
Circle area obviously can drive that in one function but here the objective is for you guys to practice
as much as you can writing the function doing all the column doing all the returns and so on.
So we can hit again return and what we could do to turn math dot Pi of this end into defined math and
defined right now we're going to take a radius and that would be radius squared.
Right.
Okay.
And before that let's go here and define import math right.
Looks good.
And the third want to go define circle.
Let's call it that conference.
All right.
And I'm going to take the radius as well.
And the function should return my 2 pi r if you guys remember it was two times math.
The PI and times the radius again.
All right.
Let's go ahead.
Let's run.
That looks good.
And let's test it.
So let's take an input from the user.
OK.
And let's bring them out.
So I'm going to say OK R equals to say and then ask leaves of input and we're going to say OK enter
a radius
OK the user will enter the 80s and then here will get a call basically the functions are going to say
print.
Right.
I'm going to say a circle diameter equals two.
All right.
We could do here is a format method or we can just use this.
We can call the function circle right on the score diameter.
Please make sure it's the same exact same words to circle diameter looks good.
And I'm going to pass along the variable R.
All right.
Let's do that copy and actually going to do that three times.
Second one will get a copy the area.
So that will be the area and here are going to copy these at conference.
Copy this at conference and I'm going to call the area and we're going to call that said a conference.
All right.
Perfect.
Let's test that and radius let's say.
Let's start with this is number two.
So simply radius two becomes four.
Okay.
Good.
Circle area 2.5.
All right.
And then the set conference here is two math Pi which is twelve point five.
OK.
It looks like we are OK.
Two math pi.
OK.
Looks good.
That's pi are squared.
OK let's run it again.
Obviously here it's really simple because here we just the radius here was too right.
So it was it had the exact same answer.
Right.
Because here you you're multiplying two times two as one times math Pi which is exactly the same at
the area.
This little little bit confused I thought that might be we made a mistake or something.
Let's maybe try three.
That's what we're getting.
Actually yes they are pretty different.
So the diameter is six and the area is 28 and the circumference is eighteen point eight seven.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and we'll see you guys in the next lecture.