Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because in this lecture we're going to discuss the conditional statements which is
why we call it if any statements they are really really powerful and they are kind of the foundation
or the kind of the basic building block of any programming language.
All right so let's recap what we have done before in the previous section we covered the logical operators
and we cover it as well what we call it the comparison operators.
And in this section we're going to cover the conditional statements which were called if statements.
Let's assume that we wanted to divide our code.
Okay.
Kind of into two sections.
Would you call it two different path lines.
All right.
Let's assume that I wanted to for example compare the value of let's say five number five.
And number two.
So I'm gonna do that comparison like this I'm going to say Okay if that's how we write the if condition
I'm asking if five is greater than two.
Okay.
And then in order to write the if condition we put Colin in here and then press enter and you would
see that simply here that has been indented.
That means you know like there is kind of a space in here and here we actually write the body of the
if condition.
Okay.
And that's the beauty of Python.
You don't need to put like you know like brackets or curly brackets or you know like C or any other
programming language which is really tough to like I don't say tough but it's it's way more complex
than Python python is very intuitive very easy.
So let's assume that I wanted to compare a five is greater than two.
I want to go ahead and do something and then I say okay.
Else if that condition is not true let's do something different.
Okay.
So I mean I'm asking if five is greater than two.
I'm going to say Okay print and I'm going to say print true.
All right.
Okay.
So I wanted to print on the screen too if this condition is true.
All right.
Okay.
Looks great.
And what I'm gonna do here I have to go back.
Please make sure that when you write the F if statement that the F and the else have to be aligned here
and the body of the F has to be shifted a little bit.
So here I'm gonna write.
Okay.
Else and please don't forget the column press enter and you'll find that simply the body of the F and
the body of the LS we going to be aligned we're going to say Okay print and I'm gonna print false.
All right that's it.
So simply put what we have done here is really powerful.
Okay.
It looks pretty easy but it's actually very very powerful why it's powerful it's really powerful because
now I actually created kind of you know like to pass within my code I'm going to say Okay I'm gonna
split my code into two sections this section which is the body of the F and this section which is body
of the LS which means that if for example here if I compare five compared to two and then say Okay it's
five greater than two.
Well that condition gonna turn true.
Right.
So if the if condition is true then we are going to execute this command and that's it.
And that's the beauty of it.
We're not going to execute this one I'm gonna go to the else ever.
We're just gonna execute the body of the if condition if the if condition is true.
All right.
What if this condition is false.
If this condition is false.
We're actually going to skip this and only perform the body of the ls but execute the body of the else
which is the beauty of you know F if it's condition.
All right let's run that annual find that you know simply here it has we print true on the screen.
OK so why is that.
You know like what happens.
So simply put because five is greater than two which is this condition was true we actually implemented
this and that's it.
We didn't basically implement the LS portion of it.
All right.
Let's take a look at again pretty much the exact same examples it's going to copy it here and let's
print for example something different let's say OK if condition is true I'm going to say here for example
if condition is false.
All right.
OK let's run that and that makes sense.
So basically here we said OK if Group Five is greater than two let's go ahead and basically execute
the body of the if and that's what we have got here.
If not let's go and execute the else condition.
All right.
So OK sounds great.
So what I'm going to do here I'm going to leave you guys for a quick challenge here are going to compare
actually let's going to compare this and I'm asking you guys without running the code please let me
know which one will going to be executed if this one is gonna be executed.
Or this one will gonna be executed.
Please go ahead and pause the video and see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge yourself here simply am asking is five equals
to ten or not.
OK well five is actually not equal to ten which means that I cannot or I will not going to execute the
body of the if I'm going to go back to the L's here I'm going to execute the LS part which is well if
condition is actually false.
All right let's run that and that's all I've got here.
Which makes sense.
Why.
Because the if condition or this condition actually failed or we know was wasn't true.
So we went there and we executed the L's body only.
And that's why we executed if condition is false.
All right let's take a look at kind of a little bit more advanced concept when it comes to if conditions
which is what we call it.
Else if.
OK let's assume that I wanted for example to compare let's say or have three different parts within
my code.
So instead of having two different paths I wanted to have three different path.
Let's do this.
Let's take it if five is equal to seven.
OK Colin I wanted to go ahead and print.
Let's say first statement is true.
OK and here and that's the beauty of it since I wanted to create kind of three different path.
I cannot just go and write else I actually wanted to import or insert another ill else if conditions
are going to say OK try this I'm gonna call it.
Else if and we actually combine it in just l. l if you guys can see that he it's turned to green OK
which is kind of reserved keyword for python I say OK Elif two equals equals to four for instance just
any numbers in the first enter and here are gonna say Okay print second
statement is true
and the else which is if none of these conditions were true let's go ahead and do this.
Let's go ahead and print let's say the last statement statement is true all right.
OK so what do you guys expect.
Let's OK without running the code here I'm asking is 5 equals 2 7.
Well that was false.
So I'm going to skip this right when I come here I'm going to have to have another if condition I'm
asking is two equals to four.
Well that wasn't true.
So I'm going to go ahead here and execute this which is the last statement is true.
Let's on that.
And that's actually what we have got here.
Last statement is true.
OK.
All right let's go ahead and leave you guys as well for a quick challenge.
OK I'm going to say OK.
Copy that.
Let's paste it and here we're going to compare is less than here.
Going to say greater than.
And that's it.
OK.
Please go ahead guys and pause a video and please do not run the cell just tell me what which one do
you expect we're going to be executed.
Please go ahead and see you guys after the challenge.
All right.
Hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge yourself.
So you know I'm asking if five less than seven.
Well that condition was actually true.
Right.
So here I'll simply going to execute the first one.
So let's run it.
And the first one we're going to be executed.
So first statement is actually true.
All right.
Makes complete sense.
Let's take a look at one last example before we jump into the exercise section.
So here I'm saying OK let's for example insert let's define let's assume that wanted to build kind of
our password
password system.
So we're going to grant access to the user if the enter the password successfully.
All right.
So let's say can we do that.
I'm going to say OK when I say OK name equals two which is our variable input in order to feed data
from the user.
I'm gonna print to the screen enter your username.
Sorry user name.
All right.
So he is simply I'm asking the users to enter their user name.
And if the user name was right which was correct without giving without at will pass without anything
just if the user name was right.
Oh just gonna give them access if it's wrong then I'm not going to give him access.
That's pretty much it.
And the user name they're going to use here is let's say what you can pick whatever name you have just
selected for example like my name for instance I'm going to say okay if he and I'm comparing simply
and that's why we use the if condition because we wanted to have to have two options within our code
we have either to grant the user access or to deny him access.
So I'm going to say okay if name equals equals to Ryan.
Okay and please don't forget the column I'm going to say Okay print I'm going to say access granted.
All right I'm gonna say here.
Else which is if not I'm going to print access denied all right and that's it.
That's pretty much it.
Let's run that code.
Let's run it.
So here.
When I press shift enter you'll find that he was asking you enter you enter your username so you have
to enter username.
So I gonna say Okay I will enter Ryan and if I run it you'll find well x is granted Y because this condition
has been satisfied I inserted value here okay and name has my name right now has Ryan in there and he'd
have competing as Ryan equals equals to Ryan.
It would me.
Yes.
Then we're gonna get access granted.
If not then X is gonna be denied.
All right let's run it one more time.
Next say enter your username.
So I'm gonna say are y n.
And please note that here I inserted all the values here were uppercase right.
If I run that you'll find X access denied.
It will tell me no access denied Y because when you compare uppercase all uppercase with the the only
letter only first letter uppercase actually the access will not gonna be Grant.
These two strings are not the same.
And that's why you get access denied in this case.
All right.
So I can leave you guys for a quick challenge.
Slip it might be a little bit tough here.
I wanted to basically make the system a little bit more robust.
Okay.
I wanted to grant the user access if the enter their name like this or if the inserted their name like
this which is r y n all uppercase or if they inserted the name all lowercase like r y n all lowercase.
Right.
So I leave you guys for that quick challenge.
Please go ahead pause a video and I'll see you guys after the challenge.
All right I hope you guys were able to figure out the challenge yourself.
So what I ask us to do here.
Let's copy this space of here and ask you guys to make the code kind of a little bit more robust in
a way.
And in order to add here instead of having just are as uppercase and Ryan afterwards I wanted you guys
to add more conditions so I'm gonna say okay if name equals equals to Ryan or write name was.
Equals equals to all uppercase right.
Or name was equals equals to all lowercase.
So I'm saying if all of them are uppercase or all of them are lowercase or the first letter only with
uppercase and that the system will kind of be being a little bit more robust.
So you know that you can insert user name whatever you feel like.
Let's run that and let's make sure it actually works.
So let's enter our user name let's try our first one which I've tried before with any well access granted.
Let's run it one more time.
Okay are y n all uppercase.
Let's run it then we will access granted to if you guys remember we if we did that before it was access
denied.
Okay so one more time I'm saying he are y in all of them are lowercase.
Let's run it then.
Well X is granted to.
Okay.
All right let's run it.
And for example insert let's say Ryan one for instance let's run it then well access denied which makes
complete sense.
All right I hope you guys enjoy this lecture.
Let's recap what we have done so far in this section we discussed how can we do conditional statements.
So now we know how can we write if else condition and kind of create you know kind of to pass within
our code here we learned how can we do multiple if else conditions like this one which is having three
for example case cases in this case and we learn as well how to kind of develop more kind of advanced
form into doing or creating a password or username access system if the user insert the access or user
name correct we can give them access if not we can deny them access and we learned here how can we produce
the or logical condition to actually apply more than one condition that might be true we're gonna give
the user access.
All right I hope you guys enjoyed that lecture in the next lecture we're going to start go ahead and
start you know like we have tons of exercises for you please stay tuned and see you guys in the next
lecture.