Hello everyone and welcome back.
So in a section we're going to cover one called Two polls and sets.
So again a slurring.
What do you mean by you both in my set and we'll see how can we define tuples and define sets.
And what's the difference mainly between duple handsets and all other you know data pipes that we cover
previously in the past.
So let's get started with tuples for us stupple is a sequence of water column immutable Python objects.
Okay it looks intimidating but you know it's very very simple.
Simply put.
Once you find a tuple you simply can change it again moving forward.
It's kind of you know like a like you know like using you're sort of variable and that variable doesn't
change.
You're not allowed to even write it again.
OK.
It's like it's like you're password you know you just said it once and you're not allowed to change
it.
For example you know like ever again.
OK.
Let's assume that you can change it.
Moving forward.
Right.
That's pretty much what tuples is.
You know the definition of tuples you know is pretty much very similar to the definition of lists a
way of accessing or indexing elements in tuples is very similar to a list as well.
And you're going to see that there's tons of similarities between the two.
The only difference is tuples.
Simply you can just go and override it all.
That's it.
That's all what I wanted to know.
All right let's get started.
So can we find a tuple.
Let's get an idea for a slogan to say okay I'm going to find tuple underscored one is whatever you can
qualify tuple or whatever.
When we define a list we use square brackets like this right.
When we define a tuple we actually use parentheses like this.
Then you can list whatever you want and say okay mench for example the first element Sandy for example
a second element 10 15 whatever in 1992 whatever you want.
And that we're going to be my tuple.
That's it.
That's how you quality.
Let's make sure that's actually we are on the right page in this case to type my tuple and the score
one for that that then you'll find that the type is duple which is a new data type that we will just
introducing know how to access elements within the tuple.
Actually it's even even easier.
So I say okay I want to go into cuple of duple underscored one it's my tuple and I want it to access.
For example let's say the first element here Mitch.
It's exactly the same as we have done before when it comes to a list open square bracket and let's say
0 that would return Mitch and make it one that would return Sandy.
Make it two.
And that should determine number 10.
Right again 0 1 2 3 and four exactly the same as last weekend.
All right.
That's how we do indexing.
How can we do slicing to capture for example specific elements again even easier to pull on the score
one open square brackets and then you would say one is for example 1 to 3.
If you're on it again that's in the zero that's index one you get x.
This is number two right.
So again take 10 and 15 because when it's mentioned three take up two but excluding number three exactly
the same as we've done before in the past.
Now to the fun part all that looks very similar.
Okay.
The only difference basically as we have done before now is this.
So it's the square bracket.
We just make it you know entity that's it.
That's all what it is.
Okay.
So what's the difference.
Let's see what's the difference so if we say for example tuple underscore one and I want to go let's
see it.
Element number one.
And then one at assigned It's number thirty two it's all right.
OK if I do this.
No that's the problem here.
I say OK.
No no you're not allowed to do that tuple object does not support them.
SIMON OK.
Which makes sense because that contradicts with the definition of the tuple which is a sequence of immutable
Python objects which as you know stuff that you can't change.
He is asking to change this element and put 30 in it.
Which is you are not allowed.
Alright OK.
This is basically the main difference.
Okay the last one is if you wanted to create a new tuple from an existing tuple.
You can actually do that too.
So let's assume that I wanted for example to create.
Tuple and other tuple for example.
So I'm going to say okay I need to let say the same group that we have before you pull one.
I'm going to copy here again and I want to create let's say tuple underscores to and let's say going
to define it.
As for let's say 5 9 and let's say two.
OK that's another tuple.
And when I wanted to do here if they wanted to let's say create a new tuple I can actually do this from
the pre to these two tuples.
I can create the tuple count call to put three.
That's equal to tuple and the squad one class.
Tuple underscored two.
Well that's allowed.
If I had done that.
We see there's no error here which is good.
And if I wanted to say prints my tuple underscored 3 I can do that.
Then you could find Mitch send the 10 15 1992 for 5 9 2 which is simply you concatenate the tuple 1
and 2 you have to get our.
Perfect.
The next topic that we wanted to discuss here is what it sets eset is an un ordered collection of items.
Simply put there are no no duplicates and we have no order.
OK.
What do they mean.
Let's take a look.
So a little soon ago find my set.
How can we define a set with a finite set.
Using crilley brackets masik is one two and three.
Then you have defined the set.
And if I wanted to let's say print for example might set they're going to print my set for it.
You'll find that this is my set looks great.
And if I wanted for example to let's say get the data type and say OK I need my datatype of mice of
my set for that.
Then if I did up I actually said OK that's great.
Ah.
So what do you mean by having no duplicates.
Okay which is basically each element has to be unique.
Let's take a look.
Let's assume going to define again my underscore two sets.
And I'm going to create let's say couple of elements one two three four and this city and get it on
that.
And if I let's say I'm going to print my on the record set on it you'll come up with one two three four
which is we are you know if you take a look you find these two elements have been ignored which makes
sense because now because these elements are duplicated because we have two and three here we have two
and three again.
Basically what we have done here is set which doesn't allow duplicates that are no duplicates.
Each element has to be unique.
Right.
And the order doesn't really matter.
All right.
That's pretty much how can you not define a set.
And if you're if if you define a set and if you have different elements that are duplicated you know
if you print a few grammar again and print your set you'll find that the element that duplicated the
Odyssey basically eliminate it.
Make any duplicate element is eliminated only just wondered if the sample is kept right.
So how can we convert for example from a list to a set.
So let's the finalist my list and why else with using square brackets the fine 1 two three and 2.
K this is my list so if I actually run this you will find that if I wanted to print for example my underscored
list.
If I run it you'll find that my list has one two three and two.
OK if I wanted to convert from a list to eset I can do this and say okay my set would be equal.
Do I need to create the set out of my list.
So again go to my list.
I create a set out of it and put it in my set.
All right so let's see that.
An if I won it too little say print my set for it.
You'll find that basically the element has been due any duplicate element has eliminated it so this
too has been eliminated.
We only kept one two or three which is simply how can we convert from a list to a set and that's it.
That's all what I want you guys to know when it comes to tuples and sets and that's pretty much what
I have with this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you guys in the next lecture.