Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
Let's get started and let's try to solve the sets and tuples exercises so the first one is where have
I defined my tuple here that has Chanel and 26 and I am asking you to print Hello followed by the name
and the age and its people.
All right so this should be easy.
So we're going to do print right.
I'm going to say OK I need to print.
Hello.
And I want to pin the name.
So if you as a member is using the fournette method I can say Okay clearly brackets here.
Right.
And then you're going to see okay you are for example here again another one causing and a person on
the age 18 years old and let's put exclamation mark for instance what it could do basically dot format.
Right.
And then I'll pass along basically my tuple elements zero and one of indexing it's this heat I'm just
trying to kind of experiment with you guys to make sure they understand how to access elements within
the tuple which is kind of an indexing that we have them for my sake.
I need to go into my duple square brackets and is the element zero.
OK.
That's the first element within the format.
Right.
And then the second element is going to be my tuple.
Square bracket of 1.
Ah right.
That's pretty much it.
That's it.
Say hello Chanel.
You are 26 years old.
Looks great.
That's exactly what we're expecting.
All right.
This question here is that I want you to define a tuple.
Six of your favourite friends.
Print all the tuple list elements.
And first last element sorry first Ellen.
OK.
So.
Here I just have you know a couple of names that I selected so in order to define that message came
my and this tuple equals two and you get say a scale you can call whatever names you want.
OK.
So if that's okay and let's cut it a couple of couple of lines here and say okay let's let's say for
example of print on a picture that might you please define properly my tuple and that you'll find that
these are the names.
Looks great.
I wanted to print all the names.
Actually we have just done that or what you could do going to say Okay.
So now we are parted.
This looks good.
Second point is I wanted to print the last element.
So what are you going to do here.
Going to see.
I need to print.
And they want to access my tuple but I wanted to print the last element to do that.
I mean say again negative indexing if you as a member of minus 1 and that should return me my last element
here.
Steve Right.
And if I wanted to print or should you know to show the first two elements which are Chanel here Mitch.
What I could do let's delete this.
Harder to do that are going to stick it print and want again go into my duple and I'm going to use slicing.
I need to get zero and then column and then to four and that they'll give mission elements.
Because remember this in the 0 1 2 3 and 4 and now again 2 which means that were going to go from zero
till 1 would simply exclude the number two which of the hundreds of times before.
Right.
OK.
So question number three is that we wanted to define a tuple with your first name last name and age
and find the length and the type as well.
That's easy.
So we're going to say OK in my example tuple Okay equals to call it whatever I'm going to say okay let's
say mittened for example which are going to be my name here.
OK.
And I wanted to let's say for example of the find your last name let's call it Steve for example.
And I need to define the age that say 25.
And that's okay and if I want to let's say prints take a look at it prints my tuple from the middle
Steve Steven 25 it looks great.
I wanted to give the sense of the tuple.
You can just use length function length and pass along my tuple.
And then to come up with a value of three.
And if I give the type you can just use tape.
And then use my parcel of my tuple again.
Perfect.
And you come up with a value of duple which makes complete sense.
Are ready.
Question number four wanted to print the number 40 print the word in the word world in the number 25
print the entire list and tuple Listed below are eight.
So let's see how can we do this.
First I wanted to print the number 40.
Okay.
So underpin this how can we access this.
I mean think a print.
I want to go into my underscored tuple and I want to access specific elements.
So first element is I want Okay this is indexed zero all that is Index one right which means that when
I go here into one and inside it because I want to print 40 This is index zero this index ones which
means I want to go and get inside the nested these sickly lists and that should generate some apology
that actually in a word tea.
Right.
Why.
Because because he wrote in and run my duple my detachable just went up here and just captured the element
here.
OK.
Please don't be confused which is going to run that first and then run this and then you're cockup come
up with number 40.
Okay.
Because that's the latest value that we have.
All right let's copy that.
And they want it to print the word world.
So world here has the index this is zero.
All that is one.
And all that is true.
Right.
So I need to just I need this and I need to go ahead and select two that would print were perfect.
One copy that again and put it here.
And I wanted to print the number 25 which is here.
All right so basically this is 0 1 2 and 3 that means I want to go HUGE into three.
And this is zero.
This is one.
So I want to do this actually looks good.
And that they will come up with the number 25 perfect setting ourselves using a copy again.
And I want it to print the entire list.
I wanted to print that to print the entire list which is basically this is the only list that we have.
So I don't need to do this and that's it.
What a good to go.
If you're on it you've come up with because this is in the zero.
All that is in one that will return my list.
Perfect copy that's they say again.
And I wanted to print the entire tuple.
I wanted to pin the entire message to people.
That's what I meant.
So here this is 0 1 2 and 3.
So if I go here just change it to three four I run it over them up with the tuples which it looks great.
I hope that's pretty easy appreciate for well what's a five.
I wanted to execute the following commands and explain what went wrong and what went right.
So if I assume that you're fine you know it's OK tuple does not support item assignment which basically
kind of you know contradicts a definition of a tuple you want to write something in a tuple which doesn't
make sense.
You can you're not allowed to do this tuples are immutable objects.
Right.
OK.
So what about here.
If I basically run this OK you you'll find that you know it's when just find it when just.
Okay.
So what happened here is that you basically went in here.
You were able to overwrite values within the list.
OK.
So simply put you when they're into the items is 0 1 2 and 3.
So this is not the number three.
When they're through the first element 10 and you overlay va'ad value and you put 9 into it.
You are actually allowed to do this.
You are allowed because this is kind of a list within the tuple to allow to actually override the value
of the list which is pretty interesting.
You can't override the entire value of a table however you're allowed to write in values within the
list defined inside its ubel.
It's kind of a nested tuple in a way.
Okay.
Question 6 is executed the following commands.
And explain what went wrong and what went right.
We found that you'll find that tuple does not support item deletion because I wanted to go ahead and
delete specific elements within the tuple.
Okay so it doesn't allow that.
Why.
Because again tuples are immutable.
However if I wanted to get rid of the entire.
Cuple can actually let's assuming just create this year copy in the next one.
From on this you'll find this has been executed correctly.
No problem.
So if I do print my tuple in 10 well my tuple does not need.
That is not defined does not exist because you just believe the entire thing.
So you are actually allowed to delete the entire tuple.
However you are not allowed to go ahead and deliver just one element within it you just get read if
you want to get registered.
You're allowed to get rid of of of of the Empire tuple of the entire thing completely.
You're not allowed to just delete one single element within the you are right.
Perfect.
Question number seven.
Check of the name python.
Exists in a tuple.
OK.
Again we haven't done that so far.
But you know I'm assuming you guys are experts now so you can just go and research for example.
So in order to check for a specific name what you could do is say okay I wanted to print for example.
Well I think you use the in kind of keyword.
How can we do that and say okay in.
And I'm looking for the word piceance going to see a python.
Right.
If Python is in my tuple.
It's a very easy way to say Okay.
Could you please check if Python the word Python is contained within my cuple.
And this basically sentence should be return true or false.
That's it.
Or if I had that you'd find the actually that it and the value is true because why.
Because Python was actually one of them.
All right.
If I let's say make this an upper case for example and I'm asking you then you can know well false.
Why.
Because this is upper case and this is lowercase.
So this one python will upper case P is not included here.
What about let's say physics for example.
I'm looking for physics.
There's physics.
I'm sorry if there's word physics is contained in my tuple for it with only no false.
However maths is maths contained within my tuple.
Well that's true because maths is contained in maths.
All right.
Perfect.
The next question that we have here a question 8 they're asking you to remove the duplicates from the
fundamentalist.
So if you as a member if we wanted to create eset out of mind of the list this should declare of all
these duplicates.
Right so we're in due here agonistic is set to a creative set out of my list.
Right.
OK.
And this is basically you can create a set.
Right.
But I wanted to do the duplicates and create and put them in a different list to do that.
I'm going to cast it again into a list.
All right.
And there will be let's say let's call it mind you will list my new lists.
Four and that's.
And if I were for example it's a prince and I wanted to print my new lists here.
If I had met you would find that basically here you remove all the duplicates.
Number two has been deleted because it has been duplicated 50 has been just one to one sample has been
duplicated.
And mine as well has been included only one value because has been duplicated as well.
Great.
The next question that we have is I want you to add your name to the following set and convert it into
a list.
OK.
Let's be interesting.
So in order to add a specific element again here we need some research centre research to do that.
Let's actually run this and let's run this just cleaned up.
That's all I need to do to add a specific element to a list.
You're going to say came my underscored set.
OK.
Don't add.
Which is a method that you can use to add specific elements to a set and then you can add for example
the name right here.
And if I want let's say two four of them.
You might set the four on it you would find that there is name for example.
Actually John because John is repeated only one John has been used which makes sense.
Mike Ryan which is is the name has been added.
And Sarah again here has been included as well.
Right.
For one it for example to convert it into a list you can again.
I've done that before several times can say okay lists.
And I wanted to use my set.
So I get a good verse from my set into a list and a call.
There's output lists.
And here I can just go ahead and print basically my out on the scores list.
So you find that basically you have a list with all the names after removing any repetition.
Right.
The last example that we have is that wanted to run the code and explain what it does.
And again I'm asking you to on the code to write the code because we're going to have that in a lot
more details in the future.
He'd just ask you to define for example here set which is my gaucherie and Cherry And I'm asking you
can you please check if orange is in my grocery.
Okay which is again if condition.
It's kind of you know like a like a teaser you know like to the next lectures we're going to be discussing
what they mean by if conditions then what do we need it.
But the overall idea is you see that the checking is or is contained in my grocery list.
Yes please print.
Yes I have got older and in my gaucher List don't worry about the syntax.
And what about the Collen here and all that we're going to cover it in more and lot more detail than
whatever the indent here which is you know kind of a standard I'm going to use if if conditions if I
am that you would find that nothing has been done.
We didn't print anything.
Why.
Because orange is action not contained within mangosteens.
However if I did that you would find that it has been printed.
Why.
Because in this case orange is actually contained within my list.
So when I checked it actually I was able to hear implement the body of the if.
Why.
Because this has been satisfied.
This was the return of this was actually true.
Yes was was contained in my gauci list.
Then I'm going to do this here.
I didn't do it.
Why.
Because audience was in the micro list and that's pretty much what I want you to know.
Up to this moment.
All right.
I hope you guys enjoy that lecture.
I hope you enjoy it all the.
You know seeders exercises again.
That was a lot of exercises.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
You can kind of you know familiar with the sets and tuples and see you guys in future lectures.