Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
All right and this lecture we're going to continue through the files questions.
Okay so question number seven I'm asking you to write a code that takes several inputs from the user
as long as the user does not enter stop the data then saved on output file.
OK so it seems like we need a while loop.
Right.
So what we could do.
I'm going to say OK we are going to save the file of the data into a file open and let's call it for
example output underscore user underscored data the text.
Right.
And we're going to open that.
As for appending purposes is going gonna append file elements to it when I say a while true.
OK.
So every time I'm going to take an input from the user right.
So I need simply to take a sentence from the user sentence equals to input and I'm going to say okay
enter something right.
I'm going to ask you is it please enter something I'm going to say okay if you found this sentence
equals to stop uppercase because he indicated all of them on uppercase right.
If you find that the sentence was what's top well close the file file the close and let's get out of
here.
Let's break.
So a pretty good loop.
OK.
Else other than that.
Just write it to the file right.
That means doesn't it not stop them.
There's something in their file.
Right.
And we're going to pass along our sentence and we're going to add a backslash end for a new line all
right.
Let's go ahead and maybe change the name.
Call it let's say trial for example.
You can easily track a trial to for instance because I have the same pretty much the same name in my
folder on the circuit it's run that and let's again run the simulation again again.
Okay.
Happy happy learning python.
Python is amazing okay.
And let's press top and looks good.
Let's take a look at it.
Let's see what we have here.
So we have child to right.
So we have out names.
I'm sorry output user data.
CHILD 2 let's open that one and if we take a look at it you will find that that's exactly what we've
got.
Right.
Happy learning python and python is amazing.
Looks great already.
Question number eight I'm asking you to write a code that basically search for all the text files on
your computer and print print all the files and their path.
You guys we're gonna find that there is very like you know like famous kind of you know
function that we could use which is we'll call it os walk or dot walk.
It simply can be used to look up you know search for whatever you want.
It's really powerful because you know you can use it to look for files look for images look for whatever.
OK.
And it's really powerful.
Let's see how can we do that.
Well we could do here.
We're gonna say OK we're going to import what we call it F and match.
OK we're gonna see how we're gonna be using it.
I'm going to say OK.
Import os angle first we're going to get the pass rates are say OK path equals to OS dot get current
working directory.
You're just getting my pass right.
And afterwards I'm going to say okay let's search let's for let's look for within the root.
Let's look for directories and let's get the files in OS Dot.
Walk and we're gonna walk the path basically here.
I'm just gonna get in my path and.
Apply OS walk for the path get all the routes directories and files.
Right.
And here are going to see a four fine name in F and match f n match K Dot filter.
All right.
What we could do is say a Please compare the files that I'm getting okay and compare it to.
I'm looking for text files right.
I'm comparing this to start the text or text.
Okay.
And I'm going to do here to see if you find it.
If you find a text file this please give me the parts.
That's of.
Okay Os dot path the join I'm going to join again.
Our route.
I'm going to act basically attach the route along with the fine name I wanted to print on the screen.
Basically the route of the file along with the finding so something with this going to show up.
Let's run that.
And that's what we're getting.
So simply here you find there is tons of text files right.
So simply these are all the text files we've been generating right.
So we generated you know output files and to amplify data use the data.
These are all the data we have been getting.
All right.
Perfect.
One last example.
Let's do the exact same thing but we're going to do here.
I wanted to you guys to search for
images instead of text files.
So I wanted to do the exact same thing but I wanted to search for p g j peg and G.
Let's do it.
Let's take a look.
Okay.
Import F and match.
Just for comparison.
Right.
We're going to import os and I'm going to say okay let's return all the found images.
I'm going to put it for example an empty here string and T list sorry.
Okay let's define the path.
All right.
You can get in defining a path you can say OK for example here we can do the same thing.
Path equals to get current working directory.
What we could do here are going to say OK I need I need to look for specific extensions lights I'm going
to define image underscore extensions
extensions.
Looks good.
Equals too.
And I'm looking for specific extensions.
That's looking for its asterisk dot JP.
Gee I'm looking for
asterisk dot JP e.g..
Right.
I'm looking for Estrich that P N G right.
Okay.
Looks good and let's go ahead do the exact same for loop that we have done before.
So it's okay for roots.
I need directories I need files in OS walk.
Of path.
Right.
And I wanted to for I in image underscore extensions because I'm gonna simply loop on the extensions
right.
So gonna say okay extensions right because I'll have to check for all extensions right.
So I'm gonna say okay.
It's okay for if you find fine name in F and match f n match dot filter on going to compare our files
with ie.
So basically to compare the files with the extension.
Right.
We're going to say Okay print to us O S dot walk dot join we're going to join simply our route along
with our file name.
All right let's run that's something is not right.
So he does a function object has no object join.
So here's we did filter we did.
Or s I'm sorry not.
I walk it with DOT pass join that's on that and that's what we're getting we actually got image 1 image
2 and all of them are JP jira.
These are all the image within our folder here.
If you guys obviously change here the path to whatever for example your you know your your drive for
example or D Drive or C drive you can get literally all the images within your computer which is amazing
really powerful you can do that here and then what you could what you could get you know here you can
simply export it for example to like an Excel file or something like that to have it really handy for
you.
All right that's it.
And that's pretty much all what I have for this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
Now you became experts were comes to file operations and see you guys in the next lecture.