Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited because here we can actually apply what we have learned in the concept lecture and
see how can we implement comparison logical operators.
And if else statements as well.
Let's go ahead and walk you through the exercises.
OK.
I'm gonna walk you through what we need to do here.
Here we actually have 10 questions.
So in this lecture I'm just gonna show you.
I'm gonna walk you through the questions please make an attempt to actually solve the questions on your
own.
All right.
And in the next lecture we can have detailed video explanations for all these questions.
If you guys get stuck in any of them.
Okay.
So I'm asking you what will this code generate again please do not run the code here we have a couple
of you know like comparisons and I'm asking you which one you know is should that generate false or
true.
Okay.
All right.
The question too.
I'm asking you what would this code generate as well.
So here we have a couple of questions.
Okay.
We have some and some and here and we have all conditions well.
And we're asking you what will this code generate.
All right.
OK.
In the third question I'm asking you again what will this code generate.
So I defined a variable X equals 20 and define other variable Y equals 30.
And here I am comparing using pretty much all you know like the easy comparison operators that we have
done before.
I'm asking you to tell me okay.
You know like how can we what do we expect to come out of this code.
All right.
QUESTION FOR I'M ASKING YOU GIVEN THE DICTIONARY below.
So here I am giving you a dictionary which is a little bit kind of an intermediate level.
Please bear in mind that these questions are intermediate level.
Okay.
So we pretty much passed the beginners level which is we have discussed before in the previous section
here we learned what they mean by dictionary if you guys remember we can have key value pairs which
is let's say key one that associate the value of 20 key to us here 20 30.
And Casey had the value of 50 and I'm asking you given the dictionary below please write to code write
a code.
My apologies here.
This should be a write a code.
Write a code to select dictionary elements that are greater than or equal to 30.
And place the values in a list.
So I'm asking you guys to go here and simply try to obtain the values of the dictionary all the various
within the dictionary and compare them to the value of 30.
If they are equal to or greater than 30 then place them put them in a separate list.
OK.
Again that might be a little bit challenging please if you feel a bit of a challenge you don't want
about it.
We're going to have again detailed video explanation to illustrate how can we do this.
All right.
Question 5 I wanted you guys to write a code that takes a number from a user and compare it to a randomly
generated number and states.
Which one is larger or smaller.
So simply put here I'm going to ask the user to insert a number and I'm going to generate a random number.
OK.
And we're going to simply compare the two together and print to the user.
If that number is greater than or equal to the randomly generated number.
OK.
Again this is kind of little bit advanced intermediate advanced.
Again the objective here is not to challenge you guys.
The objective is to give you as ton of exercise as possible.
So pretty much in the first like let's say three examples were pretty straightforward.
You guys we covered that before.
Here a little bit more intermediate a little bit more advanced.
Don't worry about it.
We're going to solve all of them in Question 6.
I'm asking you to write a code that takes a number and indicate if it's positive negative or zero.
So I'm going to ask the user to insert the number and they're going to compare that number to zero to
see if is greater than zero.
If it's less than zero and if it's equals to zero.
All right.
In the next question I'm asking you to write a script that will prompt a user for an input and checks
if the number is divisible by five.
But not a multiple of 7.
So I'm asking the user to insert the number and simply we're going to compare.
We're going to see if that number is divisible by five.
And it has to be not a multiple of seven.
Okay.
All right.
In Question 8 I'm asking to write a code that takes an input from the user and indicates it's number
of digits.
So I wanted to see OK how many digits are in there.
Again that's a little bit advanced.
Don't worry about it here.
I just wanted to introduce you to the questions.
And the next lecture we're going to go ahead and answer all our all these questions together in Question
9 I'm asking you to write a code that takes input from the user and indicates if it is even or odd.
So if you guys remember to check if the number is even at all we can take the number divided by two
and if we don't have any remainder then the output is even or the number is even if it has the remainder
then the outcome is odd or the number is odd.
Right.
And the last question here I ask you to write a code that takes the value of the dictionary below.
So you have a dictionary Sally with each twenty three Dina of age 30 and holy of each 50.
And I'm asking you to take these values the dictionary below and output values more than 25 in an output
list.
So basically I going to compare all these values if they are greater than or less than basically sorry
if they're greater than twenty five.
We're just gonna use them we're going to basically kind of export them in a separate list.
Okay.
You can call that list out took a call list whatever afterwards.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have for these questions lecture please make an attempt to solve at
least let's say the first three questions.
Okay.
And afterwards we'll get to in the next lecture we're gonna go ahead and have a detailed explanation
to all these questions.
I hope you guys enjoy the lecture and happy learning.