Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to talk about simple linear regression.
All right.
And we're going to learn how can we use simple linear regression to predict revenue based on specific
parameters.
Right.
So let's get started.
First in simple linear aggression the objective is that we wanted to predict the value of one variable
y based on another variable X..
All right what do I mean by that.
Let's take a look at a quick example so we can understand what you mean by this.
Let's assume that we have for example that can very simple ice cream cart for example business.
And let's assume that here we collect the temperature measurements of the outside temperature and and
we have an avenue that we can collect the total daily revenue with that we get out of this basically
ice cream cart.
Again this is a very simple example.
The objective is is to first start with a simple example then go in and move more on to more complex
scenarios moving forward.
So basically we collect data.
So let's say at temperatures twenty four point five.
The revenue was 400 and 500 and thirty four dollars per day at 26 degrees Celsius.
The vineyard was six hundred and twenty five dollars.
Twenty seven six hundred and sixty.
And it's assumed that you know as a business you as a business owner you wanted to get the relationship
you wanted to develop kind of a model.
Okay a very simple model.
Between the temperature and our revenue.
Okay.
All right.
So the question is here which one of these is the independent variable and which one is the dependent
variable.
Right.
OK.
It's pretty pretty obvious so the independent variable is basically our temperature.
So here this is the this is the the value or the premier that if we change it then the revenue will
be impacted by it.
Okay so that's a long story.
Is very simple for the temperature let's say is very cold let's say zero degrees C Well expecting that
everything to be very small.
However once the temperature rises then we are expecting the revenue to be much higher.
Okay that's pretty much in an in a nutshell.
So the relationship between the temperatures and the revenue is a linear relationship.
Okay.
And that's why in this case we're going to use the simple linear regression.
Right.
OK so again insipidly year regression would predict the value of one of these are the x x is called
the independent variable.
Right.
And why it's called dependent variable.
So the two important questions here are why it's called Simple and why it's called linear so linear
it's pretty obvious because the relationship between them changes in a linear fashion.
Simply put if for example let's say the independent variable increase or decrease the dependent variable
will increase and decrease as well in a linear fashion.
The next question is why it's called simple.
It's called Simple because we only have kind of two variables.
We have a relationship between two variables only that are temperatures and revenue moving forward and
then we can have more of the input that can predict for example that everything.
So for example if we add another column here that says for example let's say the location so we have
the location of the car of the ice cream for example car and we have temperature then we can predict
the future based on it then that would be kind of more of a multiple of linear regression.
Not a simple linear regression.
Okay let's take a look at the exact same example in graphical format right.
Let's assume that we wanted to plot here these points where one of the plot the temperatures in degrees
Celsius and wanted to applaud the revenue.
Here in the US which is a daily revenue.
All right.
So going to do here is a plot of these points so these are the points that basically indicates temperature.
An indicator of revenue and what we do here is that we wanted to simply connect here straightline that
pretty much passes through all of these points.
All right.
And that's Peter one of the objectives of simple linear aggression that we wanted to put in a model
relationship is straightline for example that governed the relationship between those temperatures and
our revenue.
OK.
That's pretty much the impression for simply an introduction.
So let's take a look at the exact same example.
But let's dig a little bit deeper into the mathematics of it.
So here again we have our temperatures here we have our revenue.
He reported the points.
It seems like temperature increases the revenue increase which makes sense as the weather gets hotter
What expecting you know more money to get out of that business if we draw that straight line.
And if you guys remember from previous basic mathematics class that any straight line can be presented
by this relationship.
Why.
Which is the opposite.
Equal is to be no less be one times x y equals to explore see if you as a member are right.
So what do you mean by this.
Simply put.
X again is our independent variable which is our temperature.
In degrees C and why is our independent variable which is our revenue in dollars.
And when we say that we wanted to develop kind of a kind of a machine learning model that means we are
looking for values of b.a. and be one that's it.
Once you obtain the values for the Beano then be one that is.
Congratulations That means you're able to obtain your model.
And that's our goal here in this exercise.
OK.
So let's take a look again at the mathematics behind it or what do you mean by it in a very simple form
and once we'll pin that model here that means every 10 degrees for example increase in temperature that
corresponds to 20 dollars increasing your denia everything for it for example.
This is just again are like some random numbers.
But moving forward once we go to this you know book and implemented this simple it aggression we can
actually open these values and then be able to predict okay what's the equivalent value.
But here just for sake of illustration once we open that model then we can know how much for example
can increase let's say the temperature.
All right.
They can reflect fatigues for instance 20 dollar increase in revenue for example.
So 10 degrees C is equivalent to 20 dollars increase in revenue.
All right.
Let's take a look at Piedmont executive example.
But you know like a kind of different parameters for naming conventions if you're getting a number if
we if we have these points here we are going to have our temperature here we have our dollar value our
revenue.
Here we have our independent variable x here we have our dependent very good why we can actually mother
the exact same equation exact same you know a relationship of that line using Y equals to explicit be
right where m indicates the slope of the line which is simply how basically that line is kind of you
know like sloping which indicates Delta y divided by daltex.
Right.
Which is simply.
Let's actually go here.
So when you say M that means Delta change and why then to y divided by the index.
That would give me the slope of the line.
And B parameters which has B value here that indicates the y intercept which is how did we how that
straight line simply intercept the y axis here.
If it passes through the origin then B will be 0 simply and then the equation becomes y equals to M
x or y.
OK so again just to to give again an overview of what we have done so far.
We wanted to predict or game the relationship between two variables.
That's why it's called Simple and we assume that relationship between the two variables is linear and
that's why it's called Simple limit regression.
And the objective is to obtain simply these two parameters.
We own it or play in the value of M which is the slope of the line and I wanted to talk in the value
of b which is the intercept of the line.
Once we do that then we can talk a how like that line you know tilted that way tilted that way.
Going for example you know like that with a negative slope for instance and so on.
Once we have that model then we have a very powerful thing.
Why.
Because now once we have them order then we can predict for example Okay what's the expected revenue
at certain temperature.
Even if that value was in pain before in the training dataset for example let's say viz. let's say 60
degrees C what's going to happen then we can predict.
Maybe when the temperature is six degrees C that evidence might be let's say eleven hundred dollars
and so on.
All right.
And that's pretty much all what I have with this lecture.
I hope you guys enjoyed it.
And in the next lecture we're going to dig a little bit deeper into how can we actually or pain that
straightline using really important fame famous method called Lee Square.
I hope to get into their lecture and see you in the next lecture.