Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture and this lecture.
We're going to cover three important topics mainly call variable assignment.
And then we're going to cover what college presidents of the order of operations.
And then we're going to cover how to perform basic mathematical operations such as addition subtraction
multiplication and so on.
Right.
Just a quick overview before starting you know with the first Jupiter notebook here.
When you guys go and open the course package you will mainly see kind of like a standard folder where
you going to see that we can introduce any concept like for example here we're introducing these tings
concept.
So you will find that it's a lecture three a concept that has ching's followed by the exercise right
away.
See you guys again in this quarter you would find tons of exercises.
Right.
So you can make an attempt to actually solve the exercise on your own.
And that's where you would find it has it be index here and then afterwards you guys are going to find
the solutions right away.
All right.
So again in general for each topic we're going to be introducing you will find that there is a concept
lecture just in deducing what it is.
First all right and we have some examples as well followed by the exercises questions and then are going
to find the exercise solutions afterwards.
Right.
Okay.
So let's get started.
Let's first cover the first topic that we have here which is very Simon's presidents and basic mathematical
operations.
And then afterwards are going to cover the topic too which is how we do print operation and how to get
user input and then we're going to cover topics three strings.
Followed by topic four which is lists followed by Topic 5 which is dictionaries and booleans.
And they call it going to cover top execs which is polls and says Alright guys enjoy this.
There's like you know there's tons of information here and this is kind of the you know the basic foundations
to do any programming and mainly for Python programming language.
All right.
So let's get started.
So first OK we're going to cover is how can we do basic mathematical operations.
Alright Alright so here's what you guys can see here.
Is that in the dupatta notebook.
What I try to do with it is try to include text along with the codes.
So here in these cells we'll be able to go ahead and actually write lines of code so any lines of keuning
here could be actually executed at OK.
However here these are not actual cults.
These are the we'll call it mark-ups down right down cells so if you actually click here on any of these
cells you would find that they are listed as marked down right.
Another option is the filter you listed as code.
Well I'm going to be using you know heading means you're going to be focussing on code and mark down.
So mainly here are the all these are nouns which means a few For example I came and said look.
Hello for example.
Hello world.
All right.
Well I guess I can see here this is LIST right now as code.
All right so if I try to run it you know we find that there's an error.
There are new invalid syntax because it doesn't mean anything to python.
However if I go here and a chain that says to mark down or right and you run it then you will see that
actually becomes kind of you know like a like a heading or a tidal.
Okay so you can hit.
That means that Python were not going to be executing any of the lines in here.
Right.
Okay.
So what we could do is that we wanted to delete this cells to delete any cells dupes.
You come here you press here and then you press double deep OK.
You press deep deep so deep deep okay that will remove the entire cell.
If you want to add the new cell you can press a.
That will create new cells in here.
Delete them.
I'm going to go Press deedy to delete different cells.
Let's get started.
So first let's assume that we want to perform kind of you know basic addition.
Actually Python is very intuitive it's actually very easy and simple to use.
So what we could do if you wanted to add any two numbers you can simply go and just straight into a
numbers and add them.
Let's give it a shot.
So it's a tumour.
And I wanted to add let's say five plus 10 stores in say five plus 10.
All right.
It's like you know writing in a calculator.
And if I wanted to run that self way you could do they can press shift and enter shift and enter mainly
goes here and run this cell.
That means it actually execute the cell and generates an opiate for you.
So if you press shift to enter you will see that the python is at a play.
Back to you kind of telling you okay so five plus 10 that's actually is it means 50.
All right.
OK.
It's pretty pretty simple.
If you wanted to subtract to number of say again you can perform subtraction.
So let's say if it's four text five minus 10 or right and you'll run a shift and try again that would
give me minus minus five.
When I perform multiplication.
Then you can say five times 10 again I'm going to stick with these two numbers per say and shift and
turn and they'll give me 50.
I said again would apply back with the answer right away.
Again it's like a calculator in a very simple form.
If I wanted to do division again you can divide 5 and then back like kind of a slash and then you press
10 you're on it.
That would give me point five which is you know kind of the end of it if I want to greater a new sensitive
and I press a.
That would create new sense for us.
If I wanted to heal I'm just trying you know these different kind of operations.
Okay I'll try to summarize all the operations here for you.
So here again if you want to do addition in oil cover addition subtraction multiplication division.
What do you think one is for example to cover let's say like floor division.
All right.
So let's give it a shot.
Of division.
Case and divide.
For example let's say 10 divided by five.
Okay.
That would give me two.
But if I do float a division which is divide the kind of two backslashes and around it that would give
me two as well.
All right.
So here you don't see the difference.
However if a change in the market it 11.
All right.
And if I just make it one division only if I had on it that would give me two point two.
Right.
Which means you know like a give me the actual selection and he inflection fetch in value.
However if I do the double division here or double double.
However if I wanted to do the 11 kind of you know like floor division as you can see here if you do
double double the max Max less five and around it that will give me two which means it's just giving
me the cushion value it's not giving me the actual remainder as well.
All.
This is just newbert all idea of using it when I'm going to be using it much.
But what we're going to be using extensively is what we call it mod or module or here which is a mod
be alright which is a percentage.
This is very important.
Right.
So let's assume that in one or two let's say divide again 11 divided by 5 or around that would give
me two point two.
However if I do 11 module Loaches percentage sign 5 if I run it that will give me the actual remainder
value which is simply if you divide 11 by 5 that will give me two right.
And there is a remainder of 1.
That's kind of the demesne out of it or out of the actual division operation.
Okay so the remainder here is important because that will help me in the future to identify if that
number is even or if that number is odd.
So for example so number 11 we know that the number is odd right.
So if I divide number 11 okay by let's say two for example and ranit.
All right that would give me five.
As the caution however it will give me one as it may mean that.
All right so if you want to do any test tips to see if that number is even or odd I can simply divide
by two and get the remainder.
If there is a remainder in this case that means that number is over.
If there is no remainder of the remainder is zero that mean that that number is even.
Which is pretty critical.
So let's give it a shot.
Let's assume that we have for example Number 10.
If I divide and divided by two getting that to mean that if I run it I know that 10 is divisible by
2 which means 10 divided by 2.
That would give me five with zero remainder.
Then I can tell this number is actually even right.
Let's give another example.
Divide 15 by 2 and take the remainder if I run it you merely mean that one which means that that number
is odd.
Then by doing that operation I can tell if that number is even or odd.
Which is pretty cool.
Or the next operation I want to do I need to take let's say any variable and we can actually add like
a minus sign to it.
You know kind of negation or don't want to do negative for Lent so I can do negative let's say 10 and
run it to those in the UK that there is no negative then OK it's pretty pretty simple.
What if I wanted to get the absolute value.
Actually that's again pretty straightforward.
I can do absolute All right.
Okay so if I take for example any number absolute and if I open brackets and I'm right here for example
and minus let's say 50 and you focus on it.
Oh OK.
The VA actually absolute of a minus the value is actually 50 as well.
OK.
As you can see here the absolute of minus 5 minus 50 is just returning the positive value out of it.
What if I wanted to do the exponent.
What if I wanted to take let's say a and give the exponent of it so I can do this.
Let's say I wanted to perform for example five or eight and a do I want to give the exponents do multiply
multiply again two.
If I run it that would tell me it's mean kind of 5 square and that will return 25 right.
OK what if I wanted to attain.
Let's say the square root.
Right so if I have an n like number and I want to talk in the Squidward of that number right.
In order to do that you have to import what you call it amodio.
OK I will get a copy of the modules in the future.
But in order to import that kind of you know in Python in general we have different modules.
If we wanted to let's say import for example.
Like trying to print some for example graphs.
There is no specific modules are meant only for printing.
If I wanted to do maths operations there are some modules mainly used for importing operations so here
because we're going to do mass operations we're going to we're going to do going to say okay import
right and list maths and that we're going to import kind of the you know the module form to perform
any mathematical operation.
And what we're going to do here.
I'm going to say okay I need maths.
All right.
Dot.
Square root.
All right.
And then open bracket and then going to say let's say the number that they wanted to get the square
root for it.
So square root of 25 if and that educate.
Well that ends this fight.
Which makes sense.
I know that.
So I wanted let's say to get square root of 16 for go here make it 16.
Run it they'll give me four or eight.
That means they got the square root of that number which is again to do that.
You can go and just do maths.
That's square throw it away.
You have to actually import again the the maths and then I'm going to be covering tons of modules again
in the future.
That's pretty much all what I wanted to cover in this lecture.
So in this lecture kind of an introduction lecture.
Now we know how to perform addition will perform subtraction multiplication division to the floor and
get the module module or when we know how can we how can we use mode to get you know to indicate that
number is even or odd.
We know as well how to do negation was just to get negative value of any number.
How to get an absolute value as well of any number.
So if you have a negative number if you do absolute of that negative number that will generate no return
back a positive number.
Now we know how to get now to the power of which is five for example to the power of two.
That would give me the square value of five which is 25.
If I wanted to attain the square root I can as well do it.
But I have to import the maths module and then perform maths.
That's where we do it and then pass along the number that will generate back our square to value.
Right.
And that's pretty much what we have for this lectures.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in the next election.