Hello everyone and welcome to this lecture.
I'm super excited to talk about these simple linear regression and to actually program and write our
code initial in book right now.
All right.
So please go ahead to the hour course package.
You'll find the jupe the lawbook and nick name predicting Lavigne using simple linear regression which
is kind of our extreme example Morgan to do here is going to walk you through step by step into a how
can we actually develop our model.
OK.
All right.
So just a quick overview of our steps.
So first we're going to import libraries.
We're going to import our data set and then I'm going to visualize our data set and we're going to create
testing and training data.
We're going to train the model that's the model and evaluate our model which is pretty much kind of
tied to our testing the model.
But we're just going to do it in a kind of a more visual form and that's pretty much it.
That's pretty much to conclude our section here.
Alright.
So first step is the problem statement.
Again we cover that problem statement before when we walk through the intuition of simple regression
look let's walk you again through it again let's assume you own an ice cream business and you would
like to create a model that could predict the daily revenue in dollars based on the outside temperature
which is in degrees C.
You decide that a linear regression model should be a good candidate to solve the problem.
Our dataset contains our independent variable x which is our outside temperature and our independent
variable is why you choose our over all day revenue generated in dollars.
OK so again we only have to call.
That's why we're going to call it simple.
And the next question is or the second point is why it's called linear because we can assume a bit as
a linear relationship between the two.
OK all right let's get started.
So first insert new cells.
We press a few There's a number from before.
Once you press a that will in new cells the first step is we're going to import our library we're going
to import pandas spdr we're going to import.
No pie is n.p. because as a member of getting pandas for data freeing for many predation.
Again what it's like excel in a way you can import.
No.
None.
Pies.
M S N P.
I'm going to use some pie mainly for for detre many pollution going to show you show you what we're
going to do with pie and penders right now and then we're going to do some plotting as well.
So in a poor maths plot libya's Well map plot lib dot PI plot as realty.
Anyone going to import seaborne as well import seaborne seaborne as s.a. again Seaborne is very powerful
when we wanted to do some of it.
Again it's kind of an advanced form of metal gotlib for plotting but we use it mainly for for.
Very pretty.
Kind of images or diagrams meaningful statistical analysis.
I'm going to show you as one how can we do that.
Well that's pretty much a first step.
Let's sit on the cells let's sit on it.
So here it is loading and now we're good.
And that's the first step.
That was pretty easy it's actually delete so to delete cells we just come here and press d d.
D this is so deep the Delete delete delete.
We wanted to insert new cells or just going to press sequence press a again.
So the new cells first step is we wanted to obtain our data set.
So if you go back here you would find our way to a basically machine learning in the machine learning
section or machine learning and by section.
And what you could see here is that here we have our ice cream.
It's actually opened that fire.
So once we opened the file if you guys can see here simply in this data we have two columns.
We have temperature n head we have revenue.
OK.
And let's scroll down and you'll see that we have around 500 than 1 or 5 on the semples.
Pretty much.
Okay.
All right.
So go back and let's get started.
Let's see how can we load the data.
So the import of the dataset was going to use pandas to say okay I'm going to call the data or my data
from I'm going to call it let's say ice cream.
They're not going to do here.
It's going to use a PDA.
Dot read underscore.
C is V.
And then we're going to pass along the name of our fire which is ice cream data dotsie is V.
All right.
And that's pretty much again wagonload the data using read discourse is the that we're going to put
it in our data free ice cream free.
All right now what.
Good.
Let's take a look at our ice cream.
We're on it.
That's pretty much our dealer here.
It's again.
PANDAS is very powerful.
Only the like it because it's kind of again it's like you know again using excel within a python development
environment.
So you have a temperature here we have our everything.
All right.
Again we have our 500 rose by two columns.
Looks exactly right.
What if what if for example.
I don't want to plop fully in a sense of that difference.
I wanted to play cricket see the first five samples ONDI.
What it could do is say okay ice cream and then a person let's see the first song let's say first story.
Ice cream let's say dot head.
And then add a person on five.
That means a one of the head.
I went the beginning of it and I want it only the five samples.
What if I wanted to get the last elements of nhp ICE CREAM messy dot tail and then let's say let's say
five or six or nine or instance or 10 for example.
And that will give me simply because I mentioned 10 here that will give me the 10 last samples within
our debate offering our own perfect.
OK.
The next step is we wanted to use or called the described method.
So were going to say okay ice cream that's again our data from.
They don't describe any food on it that will give me kind of a quick run over on the statistical data.
Then you'll see the account number of samples.
500 samples.
I mean the average kind of value is 22.
The temperature.
Our revenue was around 500 dollars a day.
We have our standard deviation which is our dispersion from them is around 8.
And our revenue is one hundred seventy five level of minimum value.
The minimum temperature actually is zero of our maximum value was 45 temperature.
So the temperature ranges from zero to Greasy to 45 degrees C the revenue ranges from ten dollars to
up to 1000 dollars.
And he would give you kind of you know the 25 percent down to 50 percent percentile and 75 percentile
I don't worry about it at the moment.
Again we're going to discuss that when we actually seen the model moving forward.
OK.
All right.
Just to clarify I wanted to make sure that this is actually a beta free.
If you remember from before we can say okay type and then you kind of pass along our name now then Milkie.
That's actually a pen.
There's a called Dr. fremont's the frame which is simply that the three or eight.
Okay.
Before we conclude that section let's go ahead and do a little bit of just a mini challenge.
Let's assume that only one in two of pain.
The first let's say 15 semples of the heads and the last 15 samples within the data.
Okay.
Please go ahead and parse the video and I'll going to give that that challenge a try.
Let's try to again we wanted to applaud the last the first 15 semples of the data and the 15 last semples
of the data.
Again you guys can perform that he only can insert new lines and do that he does well.
Again please go ahead pause the video.
And we're going to solve the challenge after the pots.
All right I hope you were able to figure it out the challenge.
So in order to pain or get our first 15 samples and last 15 semples I say okay ice cream which is our
data from the head and then we're going to say OK only 15.
That's all we need.
And that again will get open for us.
Our 15 first few samples and in all the talk in the last last 15 semples I'm going to say again our
ice cream.
Dot tail.
And again we're going to pass along the last 15 semples.
If we're on that that will open in our last 15 sackfuls within our data.
Again that was pretty much a very easy challenge.
I hope you were able to figure that out.
All right let's recap what we have done so far.
We have done so far that we were able to in step one important all our libraries which is simply panned
there's no pie metalocalypse and keyboard.
And in step 2 we're able to obtain or load our dataset from our sleazy file and Walgreen were able to
as well obtain or review the data.
The first couple of samples using the data frame had is the head method on the our data free and he
pass along our number of samples that we wanted to view and he were able to as well obtain the last
samples as well.
They could look at the data and were able to use the described method as well to show us kind of a quick
statistical overview of our data showing them to count the mean standard deviation of the men and Max
venues.
All right.
And that's pretty much all ahead for this lecture in the next election.
We're going to see how can we actually go ahead and create our testing and teaching dataset and we're
going to visualize our dealers as well and you'll see more in the plot.
A lot of our beautiful choice.
I hope you guys enjoy their lecture and see you in the next lecture.