Hello everyone and welcome to this project and this project we're going to ask the user to input their
date of birth.
Okay.
And then we're going to predict or you know provide the H along with a zodiac sign.
So here I tried to kind of include the table that includes all the zodiac signs along the date of birth
range.
So we have you know alias for example between March 21st and April 19th.
We have let's say cancer between June 21st and July 22nd.
So the whole idea is once the user input the date of the date of birth then you can simply apply and
if condition they can select key between these do two dates.
OK.
Then there will be cancer between these two days going to be Leo and so on and so forth.
Again it's pretty simple kind of game for say or a project that it's you.
How can we deal.
How can how can we open information from the computer leg to date.
For example today's date because you won't get the expect the Predict the age along with some you know
like if condition which is again pretty pretty simple.
So let's get started.
First we're going to ask the user to improve the date of birth including the year the month and the
day.
OK.
So that would be the first step.
Let's ignore this for now.
First up I'm going to put it as Cookie input.
We have done that before several times.
What's your year of birth and then going to give them examples.
Well so with the format we're going to be matching our example and they give input our what's your month
of birth as well as specified let's say October here.
And then what's your day going to be the day of your day of birth.
Going to be let's say 25 gay and they'll be out a year 1992 month end.
OK.
All right.
Once you do that then we can actually print to the use it okay that's your date of birth is and then
we can specify Okay that's our first variable day and they're going to add plus they're going to add
here our backslash.
OK.
Just to specify the date as it can kind of you know like a date for a match going to be kind of good.
Visually I think it adds plus months I think an hour plus as well as the year here too.
And are going to be our.
You're going to say okay that's going to be your date of birth.
Is that is something.
Let's run it unless it's okay.
What's your birth excepts going to say 1990 for instance.
And then what's your month or birth at say.
Or five.
And then they let's say 25 and they're going to New York.
Good.
They can actually plot it they're going to be plotted to the user your date of birth is let's say 25.
File 5 1990 which makes sense.
And the next step is in order to know the age we need to know what's today's date.
Okay.
I wanted to do that you can actually use an important important date OK to use from Date Time important
date and then it can actually go there from the computer can exchange information about the date of
the time.
It's very useful to actually get critical information about what's happening right now.
So I'm going to do here in the UK today are I going now for use a method today.
What date.
They'll give us our today's date.
Get.
Actually before doing any any activity.
It's actually it's a little copy here and let's sign it.
So when you run it or it can actually you these dates they will tell us.
That's what today's data let's say 2013 10 21 for example.
Right.
OK.
The next step is we wanted to simply put the Year because when I think the age we cannot predict the
age in a very simple form just from a use perspective.
So when I say okay we're going to take today's date.
Today's date.
Sorry dot year which is going to be our first argument coming back coming back.
If we take that if we subtracted minus the input of the user input here which is already year that would
tell us what in each case.
So you don't get a print of the user.
Your age is something you know age years old no.
Let's run it.
You are twenty eight years old.
Right.
And that will be the kind of you know the first section or the first requirement out of your project.
The next step is that we want it to specify what zodiac sign.
There's the use of have.
So simply put we're going to create you know if conditions if for example the date was between March
21st and April 19th.
Then you were going to print areas and so on.
If it's between June 21st and June July 22nd they get cancer and so on and so forth.
So if we're going to go here we're going to say okay if and then specify if the month for instance equals
to 12 that means well in December end the day is greater than 22.
Okay.
Or.
Right.
And then he would have specified many take.
Capricorn If you have a Capricorn here you will see that it's between December 22nd and January 19th
which means it's between two month month month of December.
Okay.
There's the you know let's say it last in December and the first nine these in janeway.
So to do that we're going to focus if we are in December end our day was greater then 22nd.
Eight.
That means you're 22nd on December or you are between Or if you are in janeway sorry you are in Jena
with the month equals to one.
That means you're jeanne-marie END IF THE days is the 19 then we're just going to print then our side
going to be capricornia.
And then at the end obviously going to the site.
And then you get to do all the conditions for the rest of them.
Again if the save areas there between you then you're And one month of the third or games is a mean
March and the days grow then 21 or in April.
And it is less than 19 and so on so forth there's be much how can you create a condition to go ahead
and scan through the entire zodiac signs.
Right.
Let's action on that part.
They'll tell you okay that's your Gemini and that's pretty much how can you.
You run it again.
Colonel let's start and clear output and let's turn it again.
So you run it that you're okay what's the year it's 1992.
Let's say you're in one of the bullies to say 10 to 25 and they'll tell you okay that's your data which
is you know 25 10 1990 to get to today's date plotted these days.
Again we'll get the difference of here.
You're 26 years old and if there's nothing you're okay then you're a scorpio and me which makes sense.
Right.
And that's pretty much all I want to have with this project.
I hope you guys enjoyed it and see you in my next project.