Everyone welcome to this course overview lecture before we get started.
I have one quick favorite to ask of you and that is to please do not skip this lecture even if you've
already taken other you to me courses in the past.
Or if you've even taken some of my own courses in the past we've packed in a lot of useful information
in this one lecture so don't be tempted to jump straight ahead to the technical material.
In fact we are even going to go over the course curriculum in this lecture.
So a lot of useful information here.
Go ahead and just watch the whole thing.
And I thank you very much for that favor.
So what do we actually talk about in this course.
Overview lecture.
We're going to discuss how to get help during the course some useful course taking tips so you can get
the best course experience how to get the notes for this course how this course curriculum is structured
and also please check your automated welcome message for some nice useful information and useful links
there including information about how to access our chat channels.
So let's get started with how to get help.
During the course the very first thing you should do is if you're on an air.
That's just a simple typo.
Or are you getting an error that says maybe something like Module not found.
Please double check that you're running are provided notes directly for every single lecture.
There's a set of files or notes that correspond to that lecture.
They should be able to run and get the exact same result we do.
Also keep in mind that we're going to discuss this in more detail later that we actually have an environment
file for you to use.
That way you can make sure your run of the same code in the same environment that we developed it in.
Because plotline dash they're really new libraries.
So I'm certain they'll change in the future and in order to avoid any simple typos mistakes or errors
go ahead and run our provided notes in our provided environment.
If that still doesn't work for you then you have a more general question that is not related to something
that simply running the nose will fix.
I would actually suggest that you do a quick search in plotless in-dash documentation.
There's a lot of useful links and information there that may quickly get you an answer.
Or we can also try using Google or Stack Overflow search those Eliab to get a really fast response because
it's simply just searching in your browser for useful information.
Now let's say that still doesn't work for you.
You can go ahead and search the previous question answer forum posts and see if a student had a similar
question to you in the past.
That's most likely already been answered in the question answer posts.
If none of those solutions work for you feel free to post a new question to the question answer forums
and either I or one of the teaching assistants will be happy to get back to you and help you out.
One quick note on getting help in general.
If you're having trouble with the TO ME platform are you having issues such as video player issues or
you have questions about your certification or things like payment issues or enrollment issues where
the Course is missing.
I can't actually help you if that your best way to get help with that is to either open a support ticket
on the support page for you to me or to email them directly support you to meet DOT com.
Again those are things like platform issues issues it's a video players or certification etc..
Some quick useful tips for getting the best course experience you can use the gear settings on the video
player to adjust the playback speed.
So for a lot of people including myself they like to kind of zip through the videos especially if they
already have the corresponding notes so personally I tend to watch lectures at 2 x speed or maybe English
isn't your first language.
You want to slow it down a bit.
You can do things like captions or slower playback speeds on the gear settings on the video player.
You can also feel free to jump around sections if you already feel familiar of some material.
And we're going to go over the curriculum in just a little bit to give you a better idea of what sections
you can skip if you're already an experienced Python developer.
OK so this is the overall course curriculum.
Now these are the main topics.
These are exactly lined up with the sections but you can think of these as the overall theme so we're
going to cover throughout this course.
We first start off with the introduction section and that's basically the section you're in right now.
It consists of the Course overview lectures such as the curriculum overview that we're going through
right now.
A frequently asked questions lecture that you can quickly check and also a general overview of the data
visualization ecosystem for Python and what plotline.
Use Cases are.
So the data visualization ecosystem for Python is very new and it updates very frequently.
So what we're going to have here as the last lecture for this kind of introduction section is the broad
overview explanation of what poly is what that is what different types of problems they solve for you
and just more general information.
So you can be informed of what you're going to learn throughout the course.
So that's going to be the end of that introduction section that we're in right now.
Then after that we're going to have a pint pand this crash course section.
So in order to actually create dashboards and plots we need data and we're going to be using some PI
to generate random data sometimes or we'll be using pandas to read in existing data sets.
And if it never actually worked with them pi or panderers we need to teach those just a little bit first
in order to move on to learning about plot Lee and dash.
So in that crash course we teach you just a very very basics of Pi and the very basis of the Panthers.
You're not going to be an expert in either of those.
You're going to know just enough in order to continue off the course with pottery and dash.
If you've already taken one of my previous courses in data science or machine learning or Python and
you're already familiar with those libraries you can probably go ahead and skip that crash course section.
We do have a quick exercise overview so you can check out what skill level you need to be to continue
on the course.
After that we start off with plotless basic charts and plots.
So plot Lee has a python visualization library already and it's called plot Lee and it can produce interactive
plots on its own in Python.
So in this section we're going explain how to reproduce the main types of plots with just Python and
plot.
So it's not dashboards yet.
It's just interactive individual plots.
Once we understand that then we move on to actually learning about Dasch basics for dashboards.
So here we begin working with the actual Dasch library from plot to begin serving components and several
plots as a web app in our browser.
So that's going to be a little different than just a singular plot plot.
Instead we're going to be able to combine multiple things and have a full service dashboard that's actually
basically a web service or web app in your browser.
So once we learn about the dash basics we'll move on to discussing summative asked dashed topics.
So that has several more advanced and complex features are definitely worth exploring and I think that
this is really where the awesome part of the course comes into play.
We'll deal with things like multiple inputs and outputs interactive components control and callbacks
with state and linking together group plot plots.
So a lot of really cool things that advanced topics then because we've learned so much by this point
in the course we go ahead and try to wrap everything together with a code along milestone project.
So we'll bring in together everything we've learned so far at this point in the course of a larger code
along milestone project and we're going to be doing.
And you may have seen a little glimpse of it in some of the preview videos is that we create a basic
web app that will automatically look up and serve stock ticker data for you in two sets of time stamps
that you get to choose and it's all done through a dash dashboard in pure Python.
It's a really cool project and I'm super excited for you guys to work through it.
Then once you've done that milestone project we just need to finish up with some more advanced topics
on basically having your dashboards interact with other people.
So one of those things is will he live real time updating.
So we're going to see how we can let dashboards update themselves in real time with a continuous stream
of data and we'll have a really cool project there where we read in live flight radar data and serve
dashboard that's constantly updating information about that.
And then finally we'll talk about deployment authorization.
So throughout the course we're really just going to be serving dashboards locally on a single computer.
But eventually most likely you're not going to be the only person using your dashboard.
Other people at your company or maybe other people around the world are going to want to see it dashboard
you create.
So we're going to walk you through how to host dashboards on a server such as Heroku.
And then we'll also talk about securing dashboards to only be seen by authorized viewers.
So maybe you want to host something online but only let certain people see it.
We'll show you how to do that with Dash and dashboards as well.
OK.
So last but not least a huge thank you for enrolling in this course.
I'm always so humbled that students decide to choose my courses as resources for them to learn and continue
to build an understanding of Python programming in a variety of topics.
So thank you so much for enrolling in this course and I'm really excited to start teaching you politely
and dash for dashboards if at this point you have some sort of question of something you've already
discussed.
Go ahead and send me a message on to me I'll be happy to get back to you.
All right let's get started.