Welcome back.
It's finally time to combine everything you learned in the course so far to a larger milestone project.
In this lecture we're going to do an overview of that project basically we're going to be building as
a stock price dashboard project where you will be able to pick a different stock ticker from a dropdown
menu and then once you hit submit and choose your dates you'll be able to see the actual historical
prices of that stock.
Now there's two main approaches you can do.
The first approach is for the more independent and ambitious student where you like to tackle projects
on your own so you can do is at the end of this lecture once you seen what the dashboard looks like
try to recreate that yourself without actually looking at the scripts to start out with.
So you get an idea of what a dashboard looks like either by seeing it online such as in this video or
by thinking about it in your head and then you try to use what you already know about plotless and dash
to recreate that actual dashboard.
Keep in mind there's going to be a few new elements that we haven't discussed yet for this dashboard
but it's always nice to tackle on that challenge just like you would in a real world situation.
And if you ever need a hint you can use the various scripts we have for you in the hub repo.
The second approach you can take is just follow along with the lectures for this larger code along project.
We've broken down this project into more manageable benchmarks so you can go along and test everything
you've gone so far that way you can make sure that you're building a true understanding of plotless
and dash.
It's really up to you what approach you prefer.
Different students are going to like different approaches.
Now keep in mind there is a separate guidebook for this project as a resource.
Definitely check out the resource link for this lecture on the overview and you'll be links to a separate
google doc for the stock ticker project.
The other thing I want to mention is that this project is dependent on the internet especially in the
later phases of the project and the Panas data reader library.
If you're not familiar with the pandas data reader library basically it's an additional library for
Pancho's that allows you to grab stock price information and historical information online.
However the panda data reader library is updated really often because a lot of times the API calls for
stock information change.
For example it used to be really popular to use the Google API or the Yahoo API for the pandas data
reader library but now those API has change enough so that it's broken.
So now we're using API such as eye X for the investors exchange or Morningstar.
However in the future maybe you're watching this six months from now or one week from now you never
know.
It may change or update.
So we're going to want to do is be highly aware of the later half of this project.
We're using Panas data reader you may need to look up the latest documentation of Hannas data reader
as far as what stream codes provide to actually read API stock data.
The other question I'm often asked is how you can use Panas data reader to grab international stock
information.
That also changes quite often.
So the best reply I can give you at this time is to check out the panda's data reader documentation
to see what availability there is for international stock markets.
As of right now I'll just officially say that only supports U.S. stock.
But I really encourage you to check the documentation.
It is a project that changes very quickly.
So I'm sure there's updates to help people looking at international stock markets.
Now with all that being said let's check out the dashboard that we're going to be building in this milestone
project.
OK.
Here we are what the final dashboard is going to look like.
Keep in mind we're really focusing on functionality here not styling.
So it's not the prettiest looking dashboard in the world but it definitely gets the job done.
The main ideas behind what this dashboard can do is you can select stock symbols from either a dropdown
menu.
So here all the essentially all the stocks listed on the Nasdaq as of this recording.
And you can actually search this dropdown menu.
For example if I'm isted and Apple stock begin begin to search the Apple stock ticker AAPL and then
select from the dropdown and add that on.
Then there's also a date picker core component here from dash reken choose the dates that are relevant
to me.
So maybe I want information from November 2017 to January 2018.
A third.
Then I hit submit it will reload grab that information from the Internet and then I get to see the historical
prices and compare them in this graph here.
And that's really all this dashboard does.
But hopefully I can see here that it's already a lot of really cool ideas and a lot of things that we've
already implemented in the past.
We've already implemented things like dropdown menus but we haven't actually implemented a date picker
but you should know now how to look in the documentation for those core components that we mentioned
earlier.
Pick out the date picker and then just plug it into its own div and we've definitely seen how we can
use callbacks and how we can use callback state to have things execute once you hit submit.
OK.
That's really all this dashboard is going to be doing and we're going to break it down in the next series
of lectures step by step.
All right let's get started.
I'll see you at the next lecture.