Welcome everyone to the dash basics section of the course now that we understand the basics of creating
visualizations with politely it's time to finally begin creating dashboards with cash.
Remember to use the provided requirements textfile shown in the installation lecture video to install
the required libraries for cash.
If you already set up your environment like we showed in the installation video then you're good to
go.
So the section goals for this portion of the Course are to again understand what is used for.
Understand the very basics of dash and create our first dashboard web application with platies dash
library sulcus started remembering what that was for.
Recall that dashes for creating dashboards purely in Python typically for things in the past you would
have had to have known all the front end technologies to create a dashboard web applications such as
T.M. C Ss and Javascript.
But dash allows you to do this all purely in Python and then these dashboards are served as web applications
so you'll actually be visiting what is essentially a web server hosted locally on your machine that
later on will show you how did the Poitou a Web site.
They're not just static HTL files like we previously saw with the regular plotless library.
We can then connect and interact with those dashboards that apps are mainly composed of two parts.
The first part is the layer of the app and it describes what the application actually looks like.
Basically where your visualizations are going to go inside your dashboard.
The second part of that describes the interactivity of the application.
For example if you move a slider in your dashboard How does that affect the visualization.
Now the good news is you don't actually need to know any T.M. or CSSA to use that.
As we've mentioned many times before we get to do all of this purely in Python.
Most HTL tags are provided as Python classes within that.
So for example in-dash you would type something like HTL dot H-1 and then children equals haloed dash
and that would actually then from your script result in H.T. elements in the web browser.
It would end up automatically creating a header for you.
So we had to H-1 Hello dash H-1 and that's an H table element so you don't actually need to be able
to write.
H t m l.
You're going to do that all within Python now bash offers two distinct component libraries that previous
code we just showed that comes from the dash underscore aist underscore component's library which essentially
has a python component for every single possible aist him LTI such as that first level heading H-1 the
other library that contains is the dash core components.
And this was really nice to work with because it offers a higher level interactive component system
where it's going to generate things like javascript HTML and see us through the re-act thought JS library.
All in Python.
So we're going to be using and leveraging the power of Dash core components a lot throughout this course.
That way we can even abstract further from HTL and really focus on creating dashboards quickly and easily
with pure python so dash components whether H T M L base or core base is describe entirely through keyword
attributes.
That means that is declarative.
All you need to primarily do is just describe your application through these attributes just like you
would with normal Python.
OK so that's the very basics of what bash conceptually is going to do.
But let's really understand that by building our first dashboard We'll see you in the next lecture where
we actually start coding this out.