Welcome back.
Now that you know how to create bubble bursts of partly let's test for new skills with an exercise we'll
go over the exercise of this lecture and the next lecture will go over the solutions.
Let's jump to that PI script.
All right.
So for your bubble Churr exercise your main objective is to simply create a bubble chart that compares
a couple of other features from the mpg that C S V data set.
So that can do things like compare mpg versus cylinders and then use displacement as the actual bubble
size or maybe horsepower versus weight.
Then use acceleration as ball size et cetera.
So it's really up to you which fields to choose.
But remember basically we're trying to show three features three to them and plot.
So you're going to do your imports create the data frame create your data choose fields for X Y and
then the market size attributes.
You may want to play around that mark size attribute may need to make it smaller or larger and then
create a layout for title and axis labels and then create a figure.
So for example you can have a plot that looks something like this.
Here we have vehicle acceleration versus displacement.
So acceleration equals seconds to reach 60 mph then displacement on the X-axis.
And if you hover over you'll end up seeing some information about the actual model car there.
OK.
So that's it for this Boulter exercise.
Best of luck.