Welcome back everyone.
And this lecture we're going to be talking about histograms a histogram displays an accurate representation
of the overall distribution of a continuous feature in order to create a histogram what we end up doing
is we divide that entire range of values of the continuous feature into a series of intervals and these
series of intervals are known as Binz.
We then count the number of occurrences per been basically per interval range and then we can change
the bin size.
Either get more or less detail.
So let's actually give you some examples of what this looks like visually.
So here we're looking at the same data as before the mpg that see every file.
And what we're doing is we're just plotting out the distribution of a single continuous variable.
So in this case we're just planning out mpg of vehicles histogram.
So this is taking a single column of data in on the x axis.
We see the miles per gallon range and on the y axis that's the actual count of vehicles that fall in
between that range.
For example if you look all the way to that bottom left here we can see that Ben whose interval range
goes between 0 and 10 and it looks like our count on the y axis is just one.
And what that means is there is only one car that had an MPG between 0 and 10.
And as you go further into the right of the histogram along the x axis we can see that we have higher
council vehicles during the 1970s that had a mpg of 15 or 20 or 25 somewhere in those ranges.
And then as we get higher and higher in the value of miles per gallon we get lower and lower counts
on our y axis until we only really have one vehicle that has a miles per gallon of greater than 45 miles
per gallon.
Now something we can do here depending if we want finer detail or more broad analysis is to actually
change the interval range so we can make those bends wider or narrower.
For example if we increase the size that is to say if we make that interval range wider than we're actually
decreasing the total number of bends.
So increasing the size means make the bends wider.
So now that very first been on the left instead of just going from zero to 10 it now goes from zero
to 15 miles per gallon.
So they're going to be a lot more vehicles that fall inside that bin.
But in doing so increasing in that bin size range we've decreased the total number of bins on the histogram.
And in fact you can see quite clearly here that it looks there's only one two three four five six seven
bins total.
Now if you want more detail you could do is decrease the interval range.
So if you decrease the bin size then in total there's going to be a lot more bins in your data set.
So you get a little bit more detail here.
Now there is a problem with just decrease in the bin size smaller and smaller because sometimes you're
going to want to see a lot of detail.
But if you go too far in this direction what happens is if you look all the way to the right you're
going to have gaps where there are no counts which is sometimes not super useful.
So you'll notice kind of in between 40 mpg and 45 mpg.
There's essentially just a blank bin and that means there were zero counts for that particular interval
range.
OK.
So you're going to want to be careful when choosing a correct bin size.
A lot of times these defaults are going to work fine.
So just keep that in mind.
All right.
Here we are.
Our text editor I've gone ahead an important plot line off line.
Polygraph objects and pandas PD for a little warm up.
We're just going to plot a histogram of that MPG data set.
So do this.
We're going to read in our dataset we have read CSP because it's a CSP file and then we'll say data
slash mpg.
And then here will create our data list and we'll say go histogram and for histogram we just need one
continuous feature.
So in this case we'll say x is equal to mpg.
Remember that if you're trying to do the similar thing for a categorical feature you want a bar chart
not a histogram histograms or for a continuous feature analysis then what we are going to do here is
say Puno plot and let's plot out our data.
So in case you want a Leo let's go ahead to do that as well so we can give this a title will say go
lay out I'll say title is equal to histogram and then let's say fig is to go that figure El Paso.
That is all data and layout equals wups way out.
And now I'm just going to plot out that figure.
OK.
Save that and let's say Python and in my case I'm calling it basic about pi.
And then we'll get a little HTL file here that we can play around with.
So we have this nice plot file and what's nice is you can actually see the counts.
So you don't need to line up your eyes carefully which is really hard to do especially over here on
the right hand side.
It's hard to tell what actual value is based off the y axis all the way on the left hand side but with
partly as you hover over it gives you that nice little count of the actual size of that been.
Oh it's nice.
Also reports back the range of the men on the x axis.
So you can see here as they hover over along the bottom of the x axis.
It's telling you that actual interval range that this bin is representing.
OK.
So we have this very basic histogram.
Let's go ahead and expand on this idea now.
All right.
So usually where are you going to be editing with a histogram is the actual size of those bins.
And there's several options here.
But first what you're going to do is inside this go the histogram call you will say X Beenz is equal
to the ICC.
So we'll call that dictionary and there's a couple of arguments we can provide here.
We can actually provide a start and an end range for a histogram.
So let's imagine that we had millions of cars in this dataset for whatever reason and we had some experimental
cars that had like 200 miles per gallon.
And for whatever reason that wasn't actually useful to us what we could do is say or only show me cars
from 0 miles per gallon to 25 miles per gallon and that we are not displaying the histogram for your
entire dataset.
If that's not useful to you or you could say Give me from zero to 50 mpg.
So sometimes that's what you're going to want to be able to do.
So you have to start an end in order to do that.
If you just want to do the entire dataset you could just say start is equal to the minimum value and
end physical to the max value or zero to the max value whatever you feel most comfortable doing here.
Remember each situation is going to be slightly different.
Now the most important one here is the actual size parameter.
So what you're going to do here is you will say the size of the actual bin you want.
For example if I say size is equal to 10 than each bin is going to represent a range of 10 mpg.
So we'll have the number of cars MPG from 0 to 10 10 to 20 20 30 and so on.
Let's go ahead and run this so we can see what it looks like price on base up high.
And now when I bring this over I can see here the actual bins represent the range of 0 to 10 mpg 10
to 20 20 30 30 40 40 50.
So right off the bat I can see that the majority of cars are between 20 and 40 miles per gallon.
So that's what's nice about having these really wide been values what's not so nice here is I don't
have a lot of detail for more refined characteristics in the MPG.
If I wanted that detail all I would need to do is change the size to a smaller bin size for example
give me range interval ranges of two miles per gallon.
So now when I run this you see an increased number of bends and the size is going to be smaller.
So it's going to be a little finer here and we can see we get something that's actually pretty close
to the default.
All right.
So that's how you can edit the bin size for your data sets.
And that's really the very basics of histograms since it's quite a pretty straightforward plot.
We're going to do next is discuss the distribution plot which is a very similar plot except that adds
in another layer of information on top of a histogram.
We'll talk about it in the next lecture.