Welcome to this lecture on dashboard deployment let's deploy our applications to the web so other people
can use it.
So far all of our applications have just been locally hosted on our computer.
But we want other people to be able to visit our dashboards from other computers what we need to do
is take our application dashboard service to the Web through some sort of hosting service and then people
can visit that your L and play around for dashboard.
We already have a full step by step guide for this deployment in the guidebook.
This video is just going to follow along those steps in the guidebook.
Please keep in mind that you have lots of hosting options besides Heroku which is what we use in this
video.
There's options like AWOS Digital Ocean Google Cloud Platform Azure et cetera.
There's dozens and dozens of options.
Keep in mind that the process for the playing a dashboard with Dasch is essentially the same as a flask
application since what dash is creating is a flask application.
So if you want guides for it deploying a flask application similar to our dashboard the various other
platforms we can do is just view this link right here.
It has full step by step guides for the deploying flask app to over a dozen other hosting services.
Since there's so many hosting services it doesn't really make sense to do a single video for all of
them especially since they all seem to follow the same basic process.
What we're going to do is use Heroku since it's one of the easiest to deploy to and it has a free tier
option.
Are we going to do now is continue by deploying the app we just created in the authorization lecture
to the Web.
Let's get started.
The first thing you need to do is go to Heroku dot com and then figure out on the page where you can
sign up.
There's always a free tier.
And keep in mind this page does change from time to time but you can either click sign up over here
but there's usually a sign up for free button somewhere on the page.
Click on sign up for free and then you're going to enter your information.
First Name Last Name email address and then roll and country.
Let me go ahead and fill this out and then create my free account.
All right.
Once you've created your account on Heroku you should receive an e-mail so you just confirmer e-mail
set your password and then it will take you to your dashboard which is that dashboard the Heroku dot
com slash apps and then we want to get started.
So when were you to Heroku its going to ask us what language we're using.
So we're going to be using Python.
So click on python there and then it will take us to a setup page.
And basically this is the entire guide we're going to be following.
So once you click on Python the next step is to click here where it says setup going to zoom in a little
bit here.
And I'm going to click over here which is set up and then you'll see a command here that says download
the Heroku command line interface.
So this will apply to deploy your application directly from your command line and the pending operating
system you are using you'll download for Mac OS Ubuntu or Windows.
Since I'm on a Windows computer at the time that I'm filming this I'm going to download for Windows
64 bit and then click the download button and then down here on the bottom you should see it being downloaded.
I'm going to fast forward in time and install the Heroku command line interface.
Once you've downloaded the Heroku command line interface and you begin to set it up you should see the
options for installing three main components.
One is the Hiroko CLID.
The other one is setting the path to Heroku Seelye and the other one is get.
So go ahead and install all of these.
So click next and it's going to install Heroku click install and let it set up.
It's fast forward in time till this is finished.
All right.
Part of the installation process for the Heroku command line interface is get go ahead and just click
next through these and choose the default options.
So a lot of this is just what get or recognize and what it won't.
So go ahead and just choose all the options that are default and then install that will install it for
us along the Heroku command line interface.
We're going to forward in time until it's finished installing.
All right.
I finished installing the Heroku command line interface and at the next step is to create and activate
and populate a virtual environment using the virtual in vi library which will work very well.
Heroku as a quick note these instructions are going to be slightly different for Windows and Mac OS
Linux users.
That's why I would recommend going to our Python dashboards guidebook and then going down to where it
says deployment.
Scrolling down a little bit and eventually you'll see deploying apps Heroku that step one step two that
we've already gone through.
And then here we're going to start with installing virtual environment.
And if you follow along eventually there's going to be a step five for Windows and a step five for Mac
OS and Linux users.
Since I don't own Windows computers I'm filming this.
I'll be following along with the Windows version.
But keep in mind if you're a Mac OS or Linux user you're going to want to follow with these commands.
They're very similar but they're a little slightly different for things like source activate instead
of just saying activate.
Keep that in mind.
So Mac OS the Linux users you have a separate set of instructions to follow.
When we start talking about creating and activating our populating a virtual A.V. right now we're on
step install virtual NVI what we're going to do now is install it by going to a command line and installing
install virtual EMV at my terminal.
Let's do that right now or I've brought up my command line.
I'm going to type Pipp install virtual envy and this commands the same for Mac OS Linux users or Windows
users.
It's just a simple Pipp install.
Same way we Pittman's called Dash and all the other libraries so just continue on and this will take
just a few seconds to install virtual ENTP once it's finished installing the next step is to actually
create our virtual development folder.
We're going to do is wherever you want on your computer you're going to make a directory and then CD
into it.
Right now ometer users and then my user name.
I'm going to CD to my desktop and now I'm located on my desktop and then I will type M K D R that stands
for make directory and then I will type out my dash app and what this is saying is go to your desktop
and making new directory or a new folder called my underscore dash app.
We want to make sure that we have no spaces in the file path.
OK.
Once I created that directory I can see the into that directory.
So say my cache and you should be able to tab autocomplete this and now I'm located at my dash app folder
underneath my desktop.
And if you type CD and hit enter it should report back that same directory.
Now we want to initialize an empty get repository to say get in it for initialize enter and it's going
to initialize an empty get repository.
And now we're at the step 5 where it's a little different for when the users are Mac OS so reference
the guidebook Mac OS and Linux users.
If you're going along this video we're going to do now is create a virtual environment.
We can do that by typing up Python that M. virtual NVI and then all savey and the enter.
And this is going to create a virtual environment and recall that a virtual environment basically is
a way to make sure you have the same versions of packages inside of your virtual environment so that
you don't have to worry about updates to packages.
I want to fast forward in time until this virtual environment has been finished creating.
All right.
Looks like it's already done.
Now what I'm going to do is activate the virtual environment.
Again keep in mind it's slightly different for Windows users for Mac OS users going to Windows.
So what I do is the following.
I say Period backslash V E and V backslash scripts backslash activate.
Now what this is saying is just go to the scripts folder inside that virtual environment folder and
then activate.
So I run that and notice now in parentheses I see the end of each.
And that means I'm running the virtual environment called v v v v.
That's the actual name of the environment.
So technically you could have called this line of V.
Ian V whatever you wanted was calling it virtual environment.
Now we need to do is install dash at any desired dependencies into our virtual environment.
This is essentially just the list of Pipp install instructions so we can Pippin's all dash Pitman's
thought dash authorization.
So I'll do that as well.
And I'm going to forward it serious and time until I'm done with installing all requirements for a list
of all those requirements just check out the guidebook they're listed right there.
I'll see you in a little bit when I'm finished installing all these libraries.
Right.
I just finished installing all those requirements.
Keep in mind if your dashboard has other requirements like it's using Pandurs or an umpire pantless
data reader you will need to install those in your virtual environment as well.
Since we're doing a relatively simple dashboard that just depends on dash and dash authorization.
We don't need to install those further libraries.
OK so we're going to do now is installing new dependency called Piep install and then unicorn.
So the unicorn enter.
And that's going to allow us to directly connect and push this to our Hiroko application.
So we don't step five again step five is going to be a little different for a users of Mac or Linux
or Windows users.
But now that we have a directory called my flash application and we have a virtual environment for the
libraries we need where we want to do is add a new file to this development folder for my app which
means I'm going to go to the Adam text editor grab the application file add one more line to it and
then save it to my dash app.
And again this is step 6 inside the guidebook.
Let's go ahead and copy the basic authorization section file and add a new line to it so we can successfully
play it to Heroku or here I am at the Adam text editor here I have the previous file it's also in the
guidebook of our authorization section code or we just added some username password pairs and then added
those to the authorization of the actual file.
We need to do now is add one more line here and the line we need to add is server is equal to app server
and that allows dashboards to understand that you're actually deploying this to a server.
So I'm going to save this and then I'm going to save this file to the folder we created earlier on my
desktop.
So I will say file say this.
So underneath this top under my dash app remember'd that's the actual directory recreated at the command
line.
I will save this as app one dot PI and then hit save.
OK so this is app one that pie.
Again it's underneath the folder I created at my desktop what I'm going to do now is add a few more
files.
One of them is a ignore file which is used by get and that identifies files that won't be pushed into
production.
The other one is a deployment file that we're going to need to add a little information about what server
and the file name of our application.
And then another one is a requirements that text file which describes her Python dependencies and that
can actually be created automatically.
Let's start by creating the ignore file rule say file new file and inside of this I'm going to type
in the following.
Let me zoom in here.
We'll say the envy Asterix dot PI see dot D s underscore store and then dot envy.
And again you can always copy and paste this from the actual guidebook.
I'm going to say file save as then.
Back in my desktop under my dash app what I'm going to do is save this as get ignore and just have the
save as all files so here's ignore.
I'm going to save this.
So there's my ignoring you can notice.
Adam should probably change at styling for it that I'm going to create a new file.
This one's going to be our prok file.
It's going to say web Colin G.
Unicorn space app one colon server.
So app one here that refers to that file name the apple in the pie of our application and server that
refers to the variable server inside that file.
So that connects to that server is equal to app that server that we have inside the Apple Pie file.
So right now this is entitled I'm going to save file save as and again under this my dash underscore
app but I'm going to do it just save as all files proc file save that and then that's ready to go.
And then we need a requirements that text file and that can actually be created automatically.
Let me show you how you can do that from your command line going to open up a command line here.
And then I need to CD into the file I created earlier.
Right now I'm partly examples which is not what I want I'll say see the dot dot.
Now I'm at my desktop that is going to change directory into my dash underscore app or whatever you
happen to call your directory file.
And here is where I'm going to run the line.
And let me make sure that my virtual environment is activated will say the backslash the NV backslash
scripts backslash activate.
All right.
Looks like my virtual varments activated.
That's good.
Now I just to say Pip freeze greater than requirements.
XTi.
So going to zoom out a bit so you can see it all in one line there.
All right.
So what's the saying is once you have activated your virtual environment again that's just the line
right here.
It's a little different depending if you're on Mac OS or Linux.
Check the guidebook though we just say that freeze and then grab all the actual libraries installed
in this virtual environment and set it to the requirements file then enter and you should now notice
when you go to your desktop under the my app if you do ls or Diyar and we expand this we now have a
requirements text file which is just a list of all the libraries so we need to run our dashboard.
OK so we're ready to go.
Let's now actually logon to our Heroku account and we can do this at the command line as well.
So we will say Heroku log in and then you're going to need to add to your Heroku credentials.
So we'll do that now.
They the type Heroku create.
And this is where you need to choose a unique name for your actual Dasch application.
The name must start a full letter.
It can only contain lower case letters numbers and dashes.
So I'm going to try to think of something unique here by just saying M 1 1 1 1 1 1.
I don't think anyone's ever chosen that application name since we're on the free tier.
That's where we need to do so again you can't use this actual name because I'm creating it right now.
Choose your own unique name here.
So Heroku create and then your unique application name will say M whatever here and then enter and it's
going to update and I'm going to fast forward in time until that's finished updating and setting that
up.
All right.
Once it's done you should see a URL here.
That's the or that or you're going to be able to visit in just a little bit.
Once you've actually pushed your application dashboard to this your L if you get some sort of error
like Access is the night that means you didn't actually choose a unique name and you need to choose
another name.
Basically just repeat the Heroku create with some other more unique name.
OK.
So we have my dash app.
What needs to do now is say get at.
So that adds all the files then we're going to get commit dash em and then say initial launch use double
quotes here and then that's committed everything and then we're just going to say get push Heroku M..
That's going to push all our files to Heroku.
We don't have that many.
So it shouldn't take too long and it's going to essentially deploy your current code to Heroku.
Keep in mind the first time you push it's actually going take a little while longer because it's setting
up Python and or dependencies on that remote server.
I'm going to fast forward in time until it's finished installing and setting everything up for us.
All right so that's finished what we want to do now is actually run our application by saying Heroku
P.S. colon scale Web equals one.
And that's essentially the frontier they enter and it's going to scale.
I know diagnos notice it's running free.
So if you scroll back up you're now ready to visit.
At that your URL that was shown earlier which in this case is right here.
This is B.S. and the whatever your Dasch name I'm going to copy this and visit this in my browser and
I should see my dash put up location live and running.
All right here I am at the browser.
It needs me to sign in.
Which makes sense because we set it up with authentication which you should probably do if you're running
your stuff online.
So user name password I'm going to sign in now.
And here we get to see our dashboard.
So notice now I can play around and scale it and the dashboard is live and operating.
And you can also make changes any time to application.
You can check out the guidebook on how to actually update your application if you update your files.
It's essentially just adding committee and then pushing it again to Heroku master and then Pip freezing
and installing the new requirement files as necessary.
There's also a troubleshooting guide in the guidebook as well in case you get anything like the app
server not found there.
Those sort of mistakes.
Usually they're just typos if you followed everything we just did.
And if the guide book you should now have an application live at this.
Whatever you are all was chosen.
All right I hope that was helpful to you and I hope now you have all the skills necessary to deploy
your own dashboard to the web and share your new creations with the world.
Thank you so much for taking the course.
I hope you learned a lot.
Feel free to look at the next lecture where we have various coupons and offers for other courses.
We'll see you at the next lecture.