Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to walk you through some basic dash layout components.
So we're going to do this lecture is create our first dash application object and then we're going to
edit that app's layout and we're going to show you how to do things like add.
Elements through that dash core component capabilities and it will also show you how to add a graphs
and figures to the actual dashboard application.
One quick note here is we're going to start off with a very manual way of creating our data and layout
for the figures we'll be using some dictionaries and nested lists.
But I want you to keep in mind that later on in just a few more lectures we're going to be showing you
how to easily insert partly figures into an existing dash dashboard layout.
That way you can use all the knowledge you just learned about partly charts and easily insert them into
your dashboards.
The reason we're going to show you a more manual dictionary method right now is because that can better
reflect the actual official dasht documentation.
So we're going to lineup in the beginning with the dash documentation and then later on show you how
you can easily use plotless figures and insert those.
And at the end of all this we'll show you how to run the app server and check it out in your browser.
So let's get started by hopping over to our text editor.
All right.
Here I am in my pie file.
I went ahead and called this basic thought pie and we need to do a couple of imports here.
We're going to say import dash.
That's the main one.
And then we're going to be exploring Dasch core components and dash HTL components through this lecture
and the next one.
So let's import them both right now.
We're going to say import Dasch core components as DCC.
And then we will also import Dasch HTL components as h T.M..
Notice here those underscores there.
Then the next thing to do is actually create our application which is essentially the dashboard itself.
So we'll see.
App is equal to dash dot dash.
And if you're familiar a flask at all this is essentially creating that flask application that dashes
doing for you.
So it may feel a little familiar if you've gone through a flask course before.
If not don't worry.
You don't need to know flask to know dash.
OK.
Now let's go ahead and continue by grabbing our apps.
Lay out and then we're going to set that equal to a few things.
We're going to call HVM.
Remember that's the dash HTL components dot and then call Divx office.
So this is going to create what is essentially a division in our dashboard to insert things.
So inside of this Div. I'm going to create a variable called children and I'm going to set that equal
to a list and there's going to be three main things in this list.
One we're going to show you how to add in more HTML components.
So if I wanted a better component I could say a simple H-1 and then inside of this I could just pasand
something like Hello dash.
So we'll just keep that one item in this list and we'll add on items as we go along.
But there's my app layout.
Now what I'm going to do is at the very bottom of my script I'm going to do a simple if name is equal
to Main and then inside of this Ossi app run underscore server.
And essentially what this does is it just checks if you're running when you call Python basic but pie
if you're actually running the script.
So that's if name is equal to Maine meaning you're calling the script directly it's going to grab the
application object and then run the server.
So right now when we run this application for our dashboard we should just see.
Hello ash.
Let's save that and run it Python basic about pi and what's going to happen is it will spit back out
the address to visit.
So it's typically one to seven point zero point zero point one eighty fifty.
Make sure to copy it with a Right-Click.
Don't use Control-C Otherwise you will actually quit the dashboard.
So just a quick hit there and then I'm going to paste that into my browser and bring it to my browser
overseas and see what it looks like.
And there it is simply Hello dash as a header one element with the mail.
And that's our first dashboard.
And we did this all with Python.
So typically you would have to no front end stuff like HTL directly to actually do this and create a
file that would serve it.
But we did this all just a few lines of Python code.
Granted it really does help if you already are familiar with things like HTL to understand what each
element is referring to.
But it's not 100 percent necessary when to close this now and let's kill our server by then Control-C
at our command line.
So he created that simple H-1 hetter one.
Let's go ahead and add something else to it.
We're going to now add a division inside of this we'll say T.M. and we can say something like this to
create another div and here I can say dash web dashboards with Python so I'll say that as well.
Let's make sure we have commas here.
And if we run this again and go back and bring in our browser again.
So 1 2 7 8 50 then you should see.
Hello dash dash web web dashboards with Python from there.
So that's adding simple HTML components with dash into our actual dashboard.
So now that we understand that flexibility Let's go ahead and add in a graph.
So the way we're going to do this is we're now going to use that higher level more abstract service
which is Dasch core components.
So the Estela components that allows you to essentially do HVM all calls like H-1 or divs.
Can check that documentation for the variety of HDMI components that are available to you.
But really what you want to be working with later on are the core components.
Those are the things that are really going to look a lot more so to speak python instead of h e OK so
we have reached him all components there.
Now let's play around with our Dasch core component and we will call DCC dot and we're going to call
graph here and inside of this graph we're going to give it an ID so we can reference it.
Let's just call this example.
And then also inside this graph object what I'm going to do is add in a figure parameter say a figure
is equal to.
And this figure is going to take in a dictionary and this dictionary is going to have two familiar components
or two familiar keys.
I should say it's going to have a key for data which is later on going to have some stuff and it's going
to have a key for layout.
So as you know we've already worked with plot Platini for graphs and we've definitely already created
our data list and our layout calls.
And later on in a feature lecture we're going to show you how to answer exactly what we already know
into this dasht component graph call.
But right now we're going to create these manually which means recall that data is a list inside of
this data.
What I'm going to do is this data list I'll say X is one to three y what's the string Why is the list.
Let's say for one to
and then I need to specify that type Let's make this a bar chart.
So it takes in the string bar and then we can give this a name.
Let's give this the city name S.F..
So it's going to be a bar chart of certain values for San Francisco and we're going to create one more
dictionary inside the state.
And we're going to just copy and paste this dictionary because it's going to be almost the same thing.
And let's give it some different values for why that way the bars are different heights.
So I'll say two four and five and let's give it a different name such as NYC.
And for the LEO we can go ahead and just pasan a dictionary here.
So inside this dictionary for lay out let's just say title
and give this thing a title the sexual Grath can say bar plots.
All right.
Now something to be really careful of is you'll notice we're using a ton of braces and brackets.
It's really easy to XLE unbalance them.
So if you ever have any syntax error such as end of line errors or unbalanced parentheses errors.
But I would highly suggest for now is copying and pasting from the notes we provide later on when we
actually insert plot lead figures like we already know how to create.
It's going to be a lot easier to keep those balanced but we're going to follow the documentation quite
closely in the beginning that we have as a reference and then later on we're going to show you how to
simplify things with plotless itself.
But for now let's go ahead and quickly review what we just created.
We already know that we created our app here so that's our dash app then we grab the layer attribute
of our application and inside of all this we have T.M. div.
So this prince who's right here is actually the last print sees down here on line 18.
So everything inside this div It's a children's list for here.
So this is everything by children means everything is going inside this div and we have an H-1 in other
div inside of that.
And then this graph object and this graph object is coming from Dasch core components and inside of
this graph we went ahead gave it an ID and then we have this figure dictionary which has a data list
inside that list.
We have two dictionaries are going to represent bar plots where we have 1 to 3 on the x axis and then
these Y's are going to represent the height of the bars.
It knows it's a bar because we're set type bar.
And then it's going to be able to name them on the cover with this name key value pair.
And then after that we have this layout dictionary which is just title bar plots.
OK.
And it's a little difficult to read because there's a lot going on here that as I keep mentioning don't
worry in the future.
And just a few lectures it's going to be really simple but let's go ahead and run this into Control-C
run Python basic pie and see what this looks like in our update.
And we should be able to now see our nice dashboard with the figure.
So I'm going to bring it in over here.
And he comes here we can see bar plots we see Hello dash dash web dashboards of Python bar plots and
I can hover over these.
I see one two three and I can see my bar plots.
All right.
So we just created this awesome dashboard.
Let's do a very quick overview of the main ideas you should be getting out of this lecture.
Don't worry about memorizing everything you just saw here.
All I want to do is point out some key characteristics of dashboards.
The very first thing I want to point out is you'll notice appeared in the Yoro were actually visiting
a Web application so you'll have to keep running this.
This is not just a static H-2 him l file.
You can save here to your desktop.
You'll need to actually run the server for the web application to work.
So it's very much like any web application for other tools like flask or Django.
I'm going to control C here only minimize this terminal and quickly just go over the main ideas.
So again the main ideas we have these special imports for dash dash ct s h t m l.
We create our Dasch application we call lay out offer a dash application and then all we can end up
doing is call each T.M. div which is basically going to be a container for either HTL components which
you can use if you're very comfortable if h Timah already or which we're going to really focus on in
the course that core components and its core components their higher level more abstract objects that
were going to be able to quickly use to actually insert plot lead figures.
So inside our typical call will be something like DCC.
That graph usually won't be calling things like h tim l H1 or H to melt.
Instead will focus on the core components here.
Notice how this graph component is going to be a really common one that we're going to be using.
It takes in an ID and a figure and inside that figure we can see that it has data and layout.
So later on we're going to be able to actually answer our previous lists for data like the traces we
made with go that scatter calls or go histograms that sort of thing as well as the layout parameters
we previously described.
Once you've set everything up in your layout down at the bottom you're going to say if name is equal
to Main which basically says OK if I'm running this stop PI script what should I do.
You take that application and you run the server in the very next lecture.
We're going to take this exact code that we have here and expand a little bit on it just to show the
level of customization that is available to you.
Again I don't need you to memorize any of this stuff.
I just want you to understand the general structure.
Do your imports set up your dash dashboard get grabbed a lay out set div and then inside.
This will have Estela components or dash core components.
If you understand those basic concepts then you're good to continue on.
We'll see you at the next lecture.