Welcome to our first part for the Milestone project here we're just going to build a skeleton of what
the dashboard is going to look like.
By setting up our basic imports and then setting up our layout Let's get started.
Let's begin by importing dash.
And we'll also import Dasch core components as DCC and we'll import h T.M. components as h tim L. Then
we'll create our application by saying app is equal to dash dash.
And then we will say app layout is equal to h team l div and let's add some components here will str.
have an HDMI component.
This will just be an H T.M. head or one such as the title we see at the top and we'll call this our
stock ticker dashboard
then we'll say HTL H-3 and this will be the text right above that dropdown.
So it will say enter a stock symbol and because we want it to be right above that drop down the very
next component should be that drop down and that is going to be a core component called input.
We'll get an idea so we can later link it to a callback we'll call it my stock picker for its ID and
let's give it a default value just for the sake of seeing something when we run this will give a default
value of the Tesla stock.
Then after this we'll put in a graph later on we'll expand this graph to be something a little more
complex.
But right now I should say the idea is my graph and I'm going to create a few more lines here so I can
scroll down.
So the idea is my graph and then we added the figure parameter which remembers just a dictionary.
And right now let's make it a very simple and key value pair of data member data as a list.
And in this case we'll give it just a simple dictionary value.
Recall that if you just pass in a dictionary instead of passing and something like go that scatter probably
will automatically create a line chart for you given x and y points you provide inside this dictionary.
So I'll say are x coronets are 1 and 2 in our White coordinates are three in one.
So what we see here is going to be a line chart from points 1 and Weikel 3.
So 1 3 2 point 2 1.
So just be kind of a very simple downward slope line.
Once we've done that let's make sure everything worked out by running our server.
Say app run server.
OK.
And this code correlates to what the stock ticker one pie.
Remember you have a separate guidebook for this project.
I'm going to run Python basic Bajpai make sure that I'm missing anything up.
And we are running.
So let's head over to the dashboard.
Okay looks like our basic layout matches up what we wanted.
We have our dashboard header Interesse stock symbol this input box which later we're going to expand
to be an actual drop down option where we have a list of Nasdaq stocks and then we have our graph here
which again we're going to update later on.
OK.
Now it's time to go to the next step where we can edit this further by adding in some more features.
So in part two we're going to end up doing is adding in things like an input box that can have a basic
callback to display the input value that is the ticker on this graph.
We'll see you at the next lecture.