Welcome back.
Now that we understand the basics of using that interval core component and setting our interval times
in this next example we're going to scrape a Web site that updates every eight seconds.
That site is Flight Radar 24 dot com and basically it receives flight data from around the world and
continually updates its page plotting real time flight data.
On top of Google Maps for this particular project we're really only going to care about one number on
that screen which is the total number of active flights worldwide.
We're going do is every eight seconds we're going to grab that number and then use it to update our
dashboard.
We'll have a little continuous plot that updates in real time.
OK.
So as a quick note this does depend a little bit on web scraping.
So if your workplace network or your network at home blocks that sort of activity make sure you either
ask your administrator or you wait till you can use this on another computer because your Python will
be accessing the internet for this particular example.
Let's get started.
All right before we actually head over to the text editor I just want to quickly give you a tour of
the actual Web site we're going to be scraping for information.
This is Flight Radar 24 dot com essentially shows you every major airline flight that's happening around
the world all at once.
You can see it has everything overlaid on Google Maps.
What we're going to do is we're going to grab this total flight number appear in the left hand corner
and we're going to use that for dashboard and do a line plot every eight seconds.
Updates for the total number of flights still be cool to see that updating in real time.
Let's go to our text editor and actually type this out.
OK let's begin by doing our imports we import dash.
We're also going to import H2 and all components as HMO as well as core components import dash core
components as DCC.
And then from dasht dependencies.
Make sure you spell that right from dependencies.
We will import input and output and actually grab data from the Web site.
We're going to send the requests.
So new import requests.
If you don't have this library simply do Pitman's thought request although it should be in that requirements
that textfile that we have at the beginning of the Course will create our application and we're going
to do here is just set up our layout and then we'll set up our function which actually inserts things
into the layout for every Interpol that's called so our app layout is going to be T.M. dif.
And one of the things we can actually display with HCM L is the source itself of the Web site.
So to show you how to do that you will probably not do this that often in a real dashboard as far as
just grabbing data from a web site and displaying it.
But this is just to show you that it's possible inside of the Stiv we're going to say T.M. dot I-frame
and then say that the source is equal to HGT P.S. colon for Slash for Slash the libido w dots flight
radar 24 dot com.
OK so we're going to pass that in and then we can also set it to a certain height so it doesn't take
up the whole screen and say height is five hundred and the width is twelve hundred.
Try to keep the same aspect ratio as a normal screen so it doesn't look too weird.
Once you've done that so that's an it's own div right here.
We're going to create another div and this is going to have a pre-formed mounting block.
HVM apre we're going to set this idea to be called counter text essentially counting how many times
we've updated our dashboard and then the children parameter is just going to say active flights.
World wide so that's our formatting.
Also inside this div 1 I'm going to do is so notice we have the Stiv list.
So right after prae put a comma.
This is where interval components are going to go.
We'll give an idea of interval Dasch component
the interval we're going to update every six seconds.
Keep in mind that may or may not be too fast because if the Web site itself only updates every eight
seconds maybe on a certain update you don't see anything change.
So just keep that in mind and we'll set our initial number of intervals as zero so we have our interval
core component.
We have this pre-formatted.
And we have an I-frame which is actually going to display part of the Web site itself all of this is
in our layout.
Now it's time to set up our function here we will call up Leo takes on an and we're going to pass in
a u r l.
This is actually a specific Yoro that you can find by kind of messing around on the site and looking
at the source code of the data.
Again this has more to do with web scraping which is a little bit outside the scope of this course.
So because that has to do with what script am is going to copy and paste this you are l this sort of
you are all going to be different every time.
So keep that in mind for your own web sites that you want to scrape.
It's not going to be a one size fits all solution.
So keep that in mind.
After that we're going to say Ari S is equal to requests dot gets and when a pass that your L and the
fake headers actually necessary to access this site you should be careful not to overdo it with scraping
the site where we're going to do it for a few seconds so it shouldn't be any problem but when you say
user agents and will pass in Mozilla forward slash 5.0
and then we'll set data equal to reds that join.
Excuse me ROSAT Jason.
And then we'll our counter equal to zero and then we're going to do here is say four elements in data.
Here we're just parsing in the data that was sent back save for data that's total.
So that's the total number of flights will say that the counter plus equals data stats total and then
grab the element there.
Then after all of this we're going to return active flights worldwide and we're going to format that
value.
So just to counter OK save that let's do a quick rundown explanation of earth that is going on.
But before we do our if Maine is equal to name as it will to main app run the server.
Ok so we're going to zoom out a little bit here so we can get an idea of everything that we just did.
So what we did is we created the ash application importer requests.
We've set up an I-frame and that's actually going to grab that Web site directly and show it in our
dashboard.
Then we set this pre-formatted.
With an idea context it's just going to show the string acts of flights worldwide and then every six
seconds we're going to update this upon every time we update this.
We have this your will then we're going to grab a request from that.
That's going to return back some data.
And from that data we're essentially grabbing the total number of flights.
Now all that's left to do is connect these components to our function with an app callback.
Back here we're going to say app call back and we'll say output counter text.
Well let's make sure we match that correctly.
Counter underscore text and we're just going to grab the children so we're sending our output there.
And for the input she's going to be illest and put here is interval components and then we're going
to grab the number of intervals.
All right.
So on every up there we're running this let's make sure that all works by running our dashboard Python
basic the pie looks like or dashboards up and running.
Let's check it out in the browser.
OK.
This is what your dashboard should look like right now.
Essentially that I-frame is showing that entire web site within the height and width of that frame.
And if you look down here you should see active flights worldwide.
And that's going to update pretty much every six seconds depending on what the update is actually showing
up here in the plot.
OK.
So what I want to do now is add a little bit of a tracker.
It'd be nice to have a graph here that tracks the changes over time instead of just displaying this
number changing.
Let's go back to our text editor put in a core component graph and update the figure based off what
information is being passed back in.
OK.
Back at the text editor we're going to do here is right above this interval components still inside
the Stiv.
Well I'm going to do is put on a graph object this graph core component.
We're going to give an idea of live updates Grath and we'll give a style dictionary of
tall hundred say that and then we're going to create another function.
This one is just updating for information.
Let's have one that updates that graph.
We'll create an up graph function and it's going to take an end and the callback is going to be quite
similar to what we have up here so it's just copy and paste as callback.
So copy and paste is callback put it in here.
And instead of the output being countered text with children we're still going to take the same input.
However now we're going to send this information to that graph.
So it's going to go to a live update graph and it's sort of children.
We're going to update the figure in that graph.
Figure.
There we go.
And now let's update that figure.
So we do hear sort of the figure that's going to that graph go figure we're going to have this be a
scatterplot with lines and markers.
So the data parameter lips actually the yes the data parameter that's going to be a list with a go scatterplot
And it go that scatter in or to use go that scurrilous sure with imported graph objects.
So I'll come back up top here and we will say import plots the dots graph objects as go save that come
back down.
Here we have our go scatterplot ready to go and we'll do the following.
We will say x is equal to a List Range length of counter list.
So the X is just going to be from zero all the way to the length of how many points we've counted so
far.
Essentially how many times have we refreshed this page.
So be careful of the number of Franciso there's lots of them.
Then why is going to be equal to the counter list.
That's the actual count for the flights and then the mode is going to be equal to lines and markers.
And after all this is done we're just going to return that fig to the figure.
OK so let's zoom out here and do a quick overview of everything we've done.
We did our imports I-frame that's showing the Web site directly.
This pre-formatted that's showing text depending on how many active flights worldwide there are.
Then we have this graph that's going to be updating constantly or every six seconds and then we have
this interval component which technically is hidden you don't actually see it in your dashboard.
It's just keeping track of how many times they want you to refresh this dashboard than our first one
is just going to update itself by returning back something to that children.
So it's going to return back how many active flights worldwide there are pretty much all of this is
just web scraping information.
So it's grabbing that Jaison data from that web site and then grabbing the total number of flights and
a lot of this is parsing Jaison and web scraping.
And this is going to be unfortunately pretty much different for every single Web site you scrape.
So there's no general approach here we can really say as far as which you are Elle's or what you're
going to need to parse that Jaison.
That's one of the unfortunate parts of scraping.
It's pretty much a custom job every time.
So keep that in mind for your own use cases down here.
We're taking that same information and then we're going to update the figure with it.
We're going to return that figure.
And the last thing I want to do here is something I forgot to do is actually set our counter list.
It's actually not the find anywhere.
We want to set our counter lists to be defined just somewhere globally we'll say counter list is equal
to an empty list.
And that way we can keep appending to our counter list over in the update layout.
So we have counters to zero counter and right after that for loops done we're going to grab counter
list.
Whoops.
Let's make sure we type that right.
And we're going to append the current count to it.
OK let's say that now we should be able to use counter list inside of this update graph we'll be able
to grab it globally.
So let's try this again by some basic but pi.
Enter And it looks like it's running.
So let's check out the Web site.
Make sure it's working.
All right here's our dashboard.
We can already see that first number of flights has been recorded and every six seconds.
You should see things updated.
You should see this Web site be updated.
You can see this number be updated and you should see this plot be updated if you're to do any faster
intervals than six seconds.
You would probably see the same number over and over again because this Web site itself I believe only
updates about every eight seconds or so.
So keep that in mind if you're re updating this graph is faster than the rate.
The web site itself updates you're going to see repeated points.
You can see the flight seemed to be increasing.
And we just created our first live update.
Again something I really need to stress here is every web scraping job is going to be different.
Keep that in mind as you're trying to implement your own ideas for how to connect your dashboards to
the live web.
I hope those useful to the main ideas here for live updating is really all has to do with that interval
core component.
You set the number of intervals as well as your interval time.
And then you use that within your callbacks.
Thanks everyone and we'll see you at the next lecture.