Welcome back everyone.
Now that we understand how to create distribution plots with politely Let's quickly test your skills
with an exercise in this lecture or go over the exercise file and show you what the end result should
look like.
OK here we have the exercise for the distribution plot and the objective here is using the famous Iris
dataset which is a data set containing some information about flowers.
We want to develop a distribution plot that compares the pedal lengths of each class so the file itself
is underneath the data folder it's Iris CXVII.
It has several fields or columns which are basically simple length simple with pedal length and pedal
with and then a class call them and the classes that are available in that column are Irus Tosa Iris.
First color and Iris virginica.
And in case you're not familiar with this iris dataset basically what it is is every row contains measurements
of the length and width and pedal length and pedal width of a particular instance of flour.
And that instance of flour can be three different species of Iris.
Iris Tosa Iris first color and Iris virginica.
So what we want you to do is create a distribution plot for the pedal lengths feature so that pedal
underscore length for each of these separate classes.
So you're going to perform your imports create a data frame to find the traces.
Now we've left you a little hints here as far as how to actually grab the pedal length column for a
particular flower.
Probably the easiest way to do it if I uncomment this is to say grab the data frame were they to frame
class happens to be equal to Irus and then whatever particular species or flower class you want and
then off of that in the same line you can then grab the pedal length column.
So this could be the pedal length information for this particular class.
All right so that's a little hint for you.
Again it's mostly deals of pandas.
Once you've done that you should end up with three traces set up at a variable and then you'll have
three traces one for each ires species.
So let me show you quickly what that should look like at the end.
OK so this is what the finished distribution plot should look like.
So we see here the distribution for Iris the Tosa and Iris virginica and Iris versicolor as well as
the rug plot and basically the main idea behind this is we can see the iris at Tosa as far as its length
is concerned.
This blue one is quite different than Iris virginica and Iris versicolor so we can clearly see the iris
Tosa has quite a different pedal length than these two other species of irises.
All right.
Do you have any questions feel free to post to any forums in the next lecture.
We'll go over an example solution.