Welcome back.
Let's not go over the solution for the distribution plot exercise.
OK here we are at the exercise file.
Let's go ahead and start off with our imports will import plot lead off line lips not config.
Off line.
As p y o.
And then since we're using distribution plots we're going to import plots.
And here we import your factory as F F and then import Pandurs as PD.
OK so those are imports then we want to read in the data frame from the iris data set that's equal to
PD.
I read C S V and in my case I'll say data Irus thought V.
Then when need to find the traces we gave you this hint which basically tells you how you can do this
or one method of doing this so will say Trace's 0 is equal to and that will be where the class is equal
to Irus and we're going to do this for each one of these so Irus a Tosa is one of the flowers so will
copy and paste that.
And this grabs that pedal length column values where only the classes Irus at Tosa.
So let me copy and paste this two more times because we have two other classes of flowers So this sets
up for traces and then we need to replace.
I was at Tosa with the other species so that would be Irus versicolor and then ires virginica.
So again all these lines are doing.
Is it saying grab me the data frame with the data frame class is equal to.
This particular species and then off with this data frame only grab the pedaling for a column.
Technically this can be done in two steps but it's really common with Pancho's to see it all done in
one line like this.
Then you will need to find that data variable all say this data is equal to trace 0 trace 1 and trace
to and then we can create our group labels so the group labels essentially is going to be the list of
species names.
So let's just grab that from here.
Since you've already provided that for the classes just got to make sure that it's in the same order
as your traces such should be Seto's the first color virginica.
And if a piece is here it looks like the same order.
Then we just need a creator figure.
So I'll say fig is equal to f f create underscore this plot and we're going to pass in that data as
well as the group labels.
Let me make sure that I have this as an L there.
There we go group labels.
Save that and then we say P wheel and we'll plot that figure save this and let's run it.
Let me pull up my terminal and I will say Python basic but PI enter and we should see it as an output.
So going to bring that over and there we see the distributions.
And again this basically confirms that Seto says pedal lengths are quite different than virginica and
versicolor so Stoessel flowers are quite separable from virginica inverse colorize.
OK if you have any questions on that feel free to post any forms and make sure check out our solution
up-I script.
We'll see you at the next lecture.