Welcome back and this lecture we're going to have a brief overview of the notes and explain how they're
structured as well as the guidebook that you get along this course.
As far as where to find these resources you can check the resource links in this lecture for the link
to the get up for the notes a zip file of the notes as well as a link for the google doc for the guidebook.
And a lot of this was also linked in your automated welcome message.
Let's get started by explaining the note structure on the page and then we'll also explain how the guidebook
works.
All right.
Here we are at the hub page if you want to download this as a zip file what you can do is click on the
screen button where it says clone or download and then just say download it and then it will download
a zip version of all of this to your computer where you can then unzip it.
Or if you're familiar of a hub you can fork or clone this yourself.
The way this is organized it's just in chronological order as it's presented during the lectures.
So we can start off a like Crash Course upon this crash course and so on partly basics.
And this is basically lining up exactly how it's presented during the course lectures.
As far as the numbering scheme it's basically the first number is the order of a overall topic.
And the second number is going to be kind of a subtopic of that larger topic.
So zero here represents crash courses and then 0 1 is not pi 0 2 is painless and so on.
These actual numbers they don't relate to any numbers in the lectures or the sections on the videos
and that's really because you to me automatically read numbers everything.
If we add in a new lecture or section.
So that would mean we would have to come back and manually be constantly renumbering all these if we
ever added in more content.
So it's that you can just imagine all of this being chronological order.
Overall it's actually pretty self-explanatory.
If you go along for the course you'll just be going from the top and down.
If there's exercise folders such as exercises here usually what you'll end up seeing is an exercise
and then a solution file.
So X stands for exercise.
S L stands for solution.
And then there's an e-mail file which as you learn about poly you'll understand just what the actual
output is.
The last thing I wanted to know is for some of the more advanced topics we usually end up creating a
very large script during the video.
So for example if we take a look at one of the more complex topics such as control and callbacks which
state you'll notice here that I have three files callback six six eight and six B during the video.
We actually show all of this and essentially the final result is callback 6 B.
So that would look something like this right here callback 6.
But to not overwhelm you by providing you the final entire script a thirty four lines what we liked
to do is break it up into chunks.
So if you look at callbacks 6 It starts off with what we show in the video at first.
So we basically break it down for you step by step.
So we'll start off with this kind of very basic structure and then we'll keep adding on to it.
We have callbacks 6 A and then keep adding on to that with callback 6B with more and more stuff.
So if you ever see that in the folders where you have like an A or B or Version 1 version 2 it's most
likely that we're just adding onto it.
So you can see the various steps taken during the videos.
Now this is further explained in the guidebook.
So have a python dashboard guidebook for you.
And this basically is an entire book that goes along with all the videos and all the lectures in the
course.
So not only do you get all the videos you also get this entire guidebook and there's a content's table
here that you can click on any of these topics such as line charts and then click on the link and it
will automatically take you to the link for line charts where we have a little bit of an explanation.
We actually tell you what the that PI script matches up with the video lecture and then some sort of
image for explanation.
We also for the more complex topics if we start scrolling down here we'll break down all these complex
topics step by step along with the videos.
So you have an entire book for reference here and we do special highlighting to show you what's being
added throughout the video so you can see an explanation for callback one PI OK.
So you'll definitely want to make use of this guidebook as a resource especially when we start getting
into more complicated topics.
Again you basically just got an entire book here along with the video course.
So we really hope that you enjoy this guidebook as you go along through the course.
That's really all there is as far as the notes and the guidebook.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums but I really hope that you find these resources
helpful during your studies.
We'll see you at the next lecture.