Welcome back and this lecture going to give you a quick crash course on pandas now that we know about
non-pilot we can learn about pandas which is a library built on top of Pi which allows Python to read
and datasets from various formats such as CSC files in this course we're mainly using pandas to read
and datasets and select or columns of data in order to plot them out.
We can also use panels to quickly graph statistics such as the mean value of a particular column in
a dataset in case you don't have panels yet.
Go ahead and install it at your command line fighter pipin style Pancho's or Konda install Pandurs for
this lecture.
We'll go ahead and create a simple script and run that script at the command line.
So let's Chambord to her editor and get started.
OK here am Adam.
I'm going to do is create a new file under my example folder will say new file.
And we're going to just say my example dot pi.
Make sure you don't call this file Pandurs that PI Otherwise your Python is going to be confused when
you import pantless.
It's going to think you're referring to the file itself.
So it makes you don't call any files Pancho's that pi.
Instead call it something unique like my example.
PI.
OK so we have my example of Pi and I'm also going to open up a new instance of my terminal at the same
location or my file is.
So I have it saved right now under an example folder.
The last thing we're going to need is from your zip file notes.
There's a CXXVI file that we're going to be working with.
You can either run the script at the same location of the notes or you can make sure to know where that
salary's not CSB file is what I'm going to do is I'm going to move that salary's thought CACP file from
the zip download of notes into my example folder.
That way I can easily call it from my script.
So let's do that now.
So here I can see under plotless dashboards of Dasch under panderers crash course there's a CSP file
salary's thought CXXVI I'm going to copy this and then I'm going to go to my example folder where my
example that postscript right now is.
And paste it in.
The other alternative is to just pass in the entire file path to the CSP file.
When we're working with it with Panas and I'll make a note of that as we actually perform that command.
So let me close this now and if I expand my example folder I now see my example that pi and salary's
thought CXXVIII.
So we're going to do first is we will say import Pandurs as PD and then you can read in a C as file
into what's known as a data frame by saying PD read underscore CXVII.
And then here you can pasand the entire file path or because my dot PI script is in the same location
as my is that C is free file.
All I need to do is say salary's thought V So let's save this as a variable called DMF and then we're
going to do is we're going to print out that D F and F stands for data frame and data frame is the main
way that Panas works with tabular data files.
So I'm going to make sure to save this otherwise we won't see anything.
And let's call our actual script.
I'll say Python and then say my example is should be able to tab autocomplete that.
And if you run this you now see our data frame in our data frame has automated index numbering so 0
1 2.
We have a name column John Salley and Elyssa we have their salary.
So just some made up salary numbers as well as her age.
So here I can say I have columns and rows very similar to a Num. pie array or Num. PI Matrix except
now I have a numbered index in named columns so you can actually select columns with a bracket call.
So if I wanted to select only the salary column What are do is appear It might if I would have square
brackets and then passen the name of the column.
In this case the name of the column is salary.
Again make sure to save that and let's run our script again to see that change.
And now it only reports back the values of the salary column.
So it reports back here the name at the bottom that you're dealing with salary the index positions are
still numbered for you.
And now we see the actual salary values.
So we're going to be using this a lot this sort of reading in a as file and then grabbing a particular
column of data points in order to actually plot them.
If you remember anything for this lecture it's essentially is these two simple commands reading in a
data file and then grabbing a column of data if you want to grab multiple columns of data.
What you need to do isn't just pasan a list of columns so will pass and a list of columns I'm going
to grab salary again pasted in here.
And let's also grab the name column so we'll say name comma than salary.
So a lot of times I get questions from students.
Why again do I have these two sets of brackets.
Well that's because this on the inside that's just a list of column names that you're passing into the
data frame.
So save that let's run this again.
And now I will see my name column in my salary column but I won't see the age column because it wasn't
selected here on this line.
Now similar to them PI you can actually create calls of min max mean on the Panas data frame for a single
column.
So let's go back to our salary.
So just single brackets needed.
So if I say DFI salary that's kind of print out the salary column off of this just like a kid with some
pie I can call men save that.
And then it's going to return back.
The minimum salary value in this case it was John's 50000 and I can also do things like Rabbe they mean
so ill return back the mean salary value and if I run that I get back the actual mean value here.
So these are very similar commands that we performed back when we were working if not pi.
Again just like non-pilot we can use conditional filtering to select rows that meet certain criteria.
So for example let's check out our entire data frame again.
So just print out RDF and we see our entire data frame the names the salaries and the ages.
Let's imagine that I wanted to sub select rows from the state of frame based on a certain condition.
For example I only wanted to select the rows where the person's age was more than 30 years old.
What it could do is manually start checking all these but instead of going to do it with conditional
filtering.
So what I end up doing here is the following.
I say DMF of the column I'm interested in.
H.
And then I have some sort of comparison operator such as greater than 30.
So here this is going to return what's known as a series of boolean values.
Floats go ahead and check that out.
We're going to say our of Boole.
It's a long variable name but it's just so we remember what it's referring to.
And then let's print out that variable.
So when I run this notice here I get back.
True true and false.
And that refers to the actual original rows.
Let's expand this a little more so we can get the full picture here what it's doing is on that command
on line 5.
I was asking hey where is the data from.
Age column greater than 30.
And that returns back this series of boolean values.
And here it's essentially the age except the type is now boolean where the first one is true.
It's greater than 30.
Second one is true.
It's greater than 30 and the last one says is 27.
It's false.
It's not greater than 30.
What I can then do is pass in that series of boolean values into my data frame so notice here how I'm
using the square brackets save that.
And if I run this again what I get back is the entire data frame only for that particular value happened
to be true.
So you don't typically actually see this done in two steps.
Instead it's done and once that you'll see in just a second.
But hopefully this logic makes sense to you.
All we're doing is we're saying is H column greater than 30 that retrieves back a series of boolean
values we can use that series of boolean values to then filter the entire data frame by and we get back
all the columns in the data frame and all the rows where this condition happened to be true.
And as I just mentioned typically you don't see this done in two steps.
Instead people don't bother with that variable assignment of series of boolean and they just cut this
and paste it in here.
The reason I like to show it done in two steps first is because this sort of double D F can be a little
confusing for beginners.
But again we're doing the exact same thing here inside of our data frame we're just asking where is
that age column greater than 30.
And we're printing out those results.
So if I were to save this and run it again I get back name salary and age just like we did before.
OK.
There's a lot more other commands you can do with pantless.
Again just like Nam.
It's a huge library.
In fact it actually has some visualization properties already built into it.
I'm going to show you just a few things you can do with panderers that you may see in the course later
on.
And if anything else comes up with pandas in the course we'll go ahead and introduce at that time.
But some useful methods they can call off a call.
Are things like grabbing unique values.
So if I were to say age I can say datt unique.
Make sure I spell that right.
Open close parentheses.
And what that does is it's going to print out all the unique values for that particular column.
So let's comment that out.
And then if I run this notice now I get back this array of values so I see 34 45 27.
Those were my unique ages.
I can say and unique if I just want to get the length of that list.
So that just says hey there are three unique values for age just as we saw a.
Here is essentially calling the length of unique.
There's other things we can do such as grab all the column names off a data frame.
So right off of DMF directly you can say that columns notice here for this particular attribute.
I'm not calling open close Princie because it's an attribute of the data frame.
And if you run that it just returns back this index object that is essentially a list of the column
names.
And now let's go over it just a few other useful methods that you may find using pantless.
One is info.
So info what it's going to do is report back information about your data frame.
So if we run this again what it does it's just reports back how many entries you have the data columns
and then how many objects and the type of object.
So you can see here that salary and age those were integer type objects and for strings we'll just report
back objects.
We can see how much memory it's using up inside our computer.
There's also the scribe which is a kind of similar thing except the report's back a statistical summary
of your data frame.
So for the actual columns that are numerical what it ends up doing it reports back things like the counts
the mean the standard deviation the core tiles and then the min and max values we don't use this too
often but is a very useful statistical summary of your data frame.
And just like we did of columns you can also call index.
In our case it won't be very interesting because memory index is just 0 1 2 3.
So it created an automatic range index for us where it starts at 0 stops at 3 and the step is one which
kind of nice that we print out all the numbers for really large data from okay to finish up this lecture
what I'm going to do is combine the ideas of Pi and pand those to kind of quickly generate a data frame
a panther's data frame that is data using some up-I generated numbers.
So typically the way we do this is we're also going to import some PI and P and I'm no longer going
to read a CSP file here.
Instead what I'm going to do is I will say and arrange and I will say from 0 to 50 and then I'm going
to reshape this to be five rows by 10 columns and you can do this all in one line or you can do it in
two separate steps.
And we're going to call this Matt.
So there's my kind of matrix of numbers here.
And then finally we're going to do is we're going to turn that PI matrix.
So if I were to print this map right now and run this I would just get back a non-pay matrix.
I can actually convert this into a pand this data frame using PD dot data frame.
Notice here how the f is capitalized and then it takes in various parameters such as data index and
columns.
So let's start off just by providing the data will say data Matt and instead of printing up Matt.
What I'm going to do now is say DMF is equal to PD data frame and I'm going to print out that DSF save
this.
And now when we run this python my example of Pi.
Notice what happens here.
It may not be clear at first.
But secondly now a data frame where this rate.
Here are the column names and pan this is automatically labeled a column just numerically for us.
And this first thing right here is are 1 2 3 4.
That's the automated index for the data frame.
And you can tell it's the index and the column names because there's a little gap here and everything
inside in the middle here.
That's the actual non-pilot data.
So that's what happens when the only passen data.
But we can also do is passen an index and columns.
So to actually show this I'm going to reduce the size of our data frame just a little bit.
Let's go ahead and just say 11 here.
So actually zero through 10.
So we'll arrange from 0 to 10 that should be 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9.
Remember it's up to nine including 10 and then I'm going to reshape this to be five rows by two columns.
So when I run this I get back a similar thing except now it's five rows by two columns and I'm going
to add an eight columns argument here.
And you can just pass and a list of columns so will say column A and B all my columns.
So then when I run this instead of automatically labeling it 0 and 1 it chooses the column names that
I provided as a parameter.
So now I have a and b.
So this is a Panas data frame.
Again 0 1 2 3 4.
That's the index that has been automatically generated if you wanted to provide your own index.
You could just provide an index argument and again pass on a list of the actual index names you wanted.
In general we won't really need to do that so much really.
As I mentioned the very beginning if you just get out that you can read CXXVI files and grab columns
or multiple columns off of them.
That's all you need to know about pandas for this visualization course.
OK.
I hope those useful to you.
Coming up next we're going to do a really quick exercise review of non-pilot Pancho's.
Make sure that you've retained everything we just talked about and then we'll move on to actually learning
about plumply.
Thanks and I'll see you at the next lecture.