Welcome back.
We just saw how to use hover data and click data.
Now it's time to switch up the code for select the data we're going to quickly show an example of how
selected data can work on that bicycle dashboard that we've been working with.
But then we're going to expand that to create a new dashboard where we can actually detect the density
inside of a box on our scatterplot.
But let's first show you the very basics of select the data by working with that original dashboard
where we only showed the information that Jason file instead of actually showing an image.
All right.
I've gone ahead and copied from the notes the select one PI file.
Essentially this is the exact same thing we were working with we were first starting to learn about
hover data except one of the changes we did is instead of displaying the image right now we're just
showing that pre-formatted block.
So recall when we were first working with Hover data we just uses preform in order to show that just
on file that rectally.
So that's what we're using right now.
And then what we changed here is instead of saving saying hover data or click data we're now saying
selected data and I have gone ahead and changed some of the strings and ID's to better reflect that.
But again the IDs these can be called whatever you want as well as these variable names.
So select the data and select the data here inside of the callback image function.
You can technically call that variable whatever you want.
Same with these IDs.
The selection ID and the selection of ID and the output that could technically be whatever string you
want as long as they match up.
Same here for this variable as long as they match up.
You can call it whatever you want what you can't change is this ID for the input you would need say
selected data.
And this particular format the D capitalized that would allow you to actually connect with that property
ID.
So I'm going to save this and run it and we can check out what it looks like here.
So again here's our scatterplot right now.
And notice here even if I click on something or if I hover over it I don't get to see anything it just
C.M. what I need to do is either use box select or lasso select for use box select once I select one
of these points then I get to see the actual results of my selection.
So here I can see information about the points themselves and I get to see information about my box
itself.
So we're going to be using both information about the points that are within the box and information
about the box itself.
So you'll notice if I receive something like 4 points now I get to see information about points here
and all of that list and then I get to see information about the range they cover so I can see I'm covering
an x range from red and yellow and then my y range that's an actual number of my box.
So we're going to be using that information to basically create a scatterplot or we can write a box
and then measure that density of points in that box.
And just to show you can also use Lassus select for this sort of stuff.
If you want so you can use a little lasso get the information points and then since our points are categorical
these last appointed a whole lot of sense but it's basically telling you the layout of all these dashes
right here on the x and y axis.
OK.
So let's close this and then actually begin working on that density example.
And let me show you what the examples point to look like.
Once we finished up that we get an idea of what we're building here.
So here is the random scatterplot we're going to be doing for our new dashboard.
And then when you click box select you're going to be able to make your own box and will report back
the points and range of that box.
And then later on we're going to take information like this and convert it to a dashboard that looks
something like this.
So again same plot except now when I do box select and I select something I'll report back some density.
So the density of points here is 0.2 four and now it goes up depending on your box selection.
So if you try to select a small box of a lot of points you get a much higher density.
If you select that box with maybe just one point over a large area you get a very low density.
OK so let's go ahead and create this plot.
Let's go back to our text editor.
All right back with the text editor.
I've gone ahead and done the dash import as well as my corn HTL components input and output from dependencies.
Go for graph objects and num Piet's create some data and panderers to format it into a data frame for
later on.
First let's create our application by S..
Opposite CO-2 dash dash.
And then we're going to create some data so we'll create some data from pi and the random seed will
set the turn and that's just for repeatability so we can get reproducible results and your results will
be the same as mine.
I'm going to separate X into a left half and right half so say x 1 is equal to and b all in space.
So that's linearly spaced points will go from 0.1 to 5 and we'll ask for 50 linearly spaced points between
0.1 and 5 and for X to we'll say and P in space from 5.1 to 10 and we'll grab another 50 points there
and for y we're going to just grab 50 random points we'll say why is it to be random rant random integer.
So get me 50 random integers anywhere between 0 and 50.
So we have our left half right half and then 50 random points.
Then we're going to create three frames for this.
So have our data frames the one that's going to be equal to PD data frame and you can actually pass
in a dictionary with the column name as the key and then the array has the value so x 1 and we'll say
the same for y and then I'm going to copy and paste this two more times.
And we'll sign this DFI two and three we're actually going to have DFI to be essentially a duplicate
of d'Urfe 1 and then DFA three.
Or don't say is X 2 matched up with Y.
So later on you'll see why we actually needed the f one and the two separately.
But what we're do for now is combine this all into one large data frame by saying.
PD thought concat So that sense for concatenate Wrekin basically glued together a list of data frames.
So we will concatenate the one DFI 2 and 3 right now that if one A.F. to those points are going to overlap
because they're both situated on X1 want to done that it's time to actually affect our play out.
We'll create our division list and then I'm going to grab some new lines here just just get enough space
to work with.
Well we're going to do now is insert a core component graph DCC dot graph and inside this graph will
give it an ID we'll just call it plot as its ID and then we need to provide it a figure parameter.
Remember this figure parameter it's just a dictionary with data list and then your layout value so it's
Stortford data.
We're going to have just a simple scatterplot here we'll call it a go getter and then put this new line
here.
We can work this out.
Go scatter.
This is going to need x x equal to f of x and we'll set y equal to the if y.
And we'll set the mode equal to the string markers.
So we have our scatterplot there and then Furley out we'll sign scientists go that way.
And here we can give it a title scatterplot and then we'll say hover mode is equal to closest.
Let me save this right there.
And in order to actually add some styling to this graph.
Let's provide its own div.
So inside of this div I'm going to say H team l div I'm going to put a list here.
Let's actually grab everything from this graph that we just created and we'll stick it inside this div
list and now that we've done that notice how I have my list here what I can do is outside of this add
a style dictionary and the style dictionary is going to allow me to edit the width of the sexual graph.
And I just wanted to take up 30 percent of my dashboard and then I can also add in a bunch of other
properties for SEE assess the next one's going to be display.
And we're going to set that to inline block and that's just another formatting style choice just to
make our dashboard look a little nicer.
All right so we have that div with the graph inside of it.
I'm going to create one more thing here.
And this div is just going to be a head or one object that has an idea of density.
And that's going to be the actual string that reports back that density.
So we have equal density and then we can get this a style as well.
Let's add a little bit of padding on the top so we don't get any issues of fit being cut off.
We'll say this is a value of 25.
And for this overall div we can also add more styling.
So let's give it a style dictionary.
Very similar to our graph.
We'll give it with a 30 percent and we'll say display block
excuse me display is equal to inline block as well.
And also for formatting we can give it a vertical alignments will say vertical line and we'll align
it to the top OK.
Most of this just for formatting it.
So it looks nice and you kind of see the graph right next to the display of density.
So we've set up our layout.
We set up our data frames as well as our data that construct these data frames.
Now it's time to just create the callbacks and we're going to do here is going to copy and paste a lot
of this from the notes because it's essentially just repeated calculations sort of first going to create
or function and this function is lowercase that we'll call it find density.
And in this case we just need to find that density given the selected data so the selected data that's
going to be information that we saw previously displayed as text we're going to be able to parse through
that information to grab the x and y points to calculate the square and then calculate how many points
are in that square.
So because of this it's actually quite complicated.
So essentially it is calculates the density.
So we're going to be copying and pasting from the notes to make sure we don't mess that up.
And then we'll walk through what each line does.
But before we do that let's add in our app callback manually app that callback we set the output we're
going to be outputting the information to this H-1 to the ideas density.
And since we over it we just want to overwrite its text.
We will say children and then a member input goes in a list.
In this case we just have one that's going to grab it from the idea we created up above.
So ideas plot and lots are input and we're going to grab the selected data.
Remember you have to use this story string just like we had to do for click data and hover data.
So what's this find density.
I'm going to copy and paste the actual formatting here because it's quite a few lines of code and then
we can just walk through it together.
So how does find density function.
Well we're going to do is we're going to say how many points are there and that's going to be the length
of the selected data with the key points to remember select the data.
Is that dictionary in one of the values or one of the key value pairs.
It's going to be points to that first half describe all the points and we just want the length of this
to give us back will how many points are within the selected area.
Then what we can do is we can make a list from the selected data keys and then we're going to call this
either a range or essentially lasso points because select the data returns either a range key or a last
appoints key depending on whether we use that box tool for that range or the last appoints.
So in this case we had to get a little creative with how we're actually going to mind the size of the
selection.
You should note that lassoes in general they're always going to have overstated areas since essentially
what we're doing here in our example is we're building a box around the minimum and maximum x and y
values of whatever that blob happens to be.
So we're kind of estimating based on the last points.
All right.
So essentially all we're doing here is if you recall coming back up here we overlapped the 1 and DFI
to when we concatenated it.
So that means there's two points on the left hand side and there's going to be one point on the right
hand side.
So we're going to be able to see that effect Well we're actually running this plot on the dashboard.
The densities on the left hand side of the plot they're going to be double the density of things on
the right hand side because those points are stacked on top for each other which is why we're kind of
doubling that up here to see that effect.
So as I just mentioned the examples don't have points on the left hand side.
The plot doubled up.
So wherever we actually see a point there's two overlapping points and the right half of the plot is
occupied by single points.
So the cockily density is going to be twice as high on the left as on the right for similar selection
of points.
Once we've created this list with that either range or less appoints key We're going to remove all the
points here we already have the number of points.
Now we just want to build that box for a density calculation.
And essentially what we're doing here is driving the max value for the X the minivan new for the X..
And then the x y and mindwipe.
Then with those values we can just calculate a simple area by saying Max x minus min x is the length
of X times max y minus.
Why that's looking for y so X times Y gives you the area that square.
So the density is a number of points divided by that area.
Often your dashboards won't be this complex hopefully but this is kind of just to show you what's possible.
And then we're just going to return that density formatted let's say this and you can always reference
our guidebook where we explain this in more detail but you can think of this more as kind of an example
of what's possible really if you're just interested select the data all you really need to know is the
selected data string key.
And then you can play around with our select to a PI file to see the actual Jaison output that's returned.
So I'm going to run Python basic but PI
and I actually forgot to run our application so let's add that and we'll say if name is equal to mean
take her app and run our server.
Let's save that again.
Run this.
OK it looks like it's running our dashboard.
Let's bring that up OK.
Here we are at our scatterplot.
Keep in mind we actually need to use the box and last select.
If you're just to select like that that's actually zoomin by default.
So let's use box select and then we'll select these three points on the right hand side and it reports
back then that is 0.24.
But remember we double stack the points on the left hand.
So if I were to grab these three points we essentially almost double 0.4 6.
Now my box sizes aren't going to be exactly the same each time but hopefully you get the idea that it's
more or less about double the density on the left hand side.
So you can play around as example.
More to see the effects.
But essentially this is how you can interact with select the data.
Often you probably won't be reporting density like this.
Instead you may be displaying more information about another plot or another graph and we'll be showing
you examples like that later on in the course.
OK.
I hope that was helpful to you.
Just keep in mind that whenever you're working to select that data click data recovered data.
It's essentially just a string code from your graph object.
And then that's returning back something that looks like Jaison which you can later manipulate to grab
either data from another folder like the image files or just return the Jason information yourself to
either use internally or to show the user.
Hope that was helpful.
We'll see you in the next lecture.