Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to go over the exercises for the crash course.
This is just going to be a trip for a few simple tasks for you to fill out.
Just to test your knowledge of non-time pandas recall that we don't need to know in-depth pandas and
and.
Instead we just need to know enough to continue on to learn about partly and partly.
Let's get started by opening up the PI script.
So if you go to crash course exercises folder you'll see that there's two pi scripts one is Crash Course
review exercises that pi and the other is Crash Course review exercises solutions that pi which contains
the solutions which are going to go over in the very next lecture.
Let's start by opening up the exercises up by file.
Ok so when you open up the exercises that py file it's going to look like this.
You'll notice it's essentially just a bunch of comments with descriptions of the tasks you need to complete.
So task number one is to import pandas and some pie.
Task Number two is the setting umpiring the number generator to be at the seat of 101.
Like we showed on the lecture then we want you to create a name PI matrix of 100 rows by five columns
consisting of random integers from 1 to 100 then task number four is to use P-T that data frame to read
in that non-pilot data frame from task number 3 as a Panas data frame.
So all you need to do is simply pass in that Ampyra into that particular function.
PD that data frame to get back to data frame remember.
Just like we shouldn't lecture.
The columns are going to be auto labeled Zureda for then test number five is to use your previously
created data frame and rename the columns.
And there's a hint here in case you can't figure out on your own how to actually rename columns and
pandas you should be able to do this all in one line by using the dot columns as equal to some sort
of list.
So we want you to rename the columns to this list of names so you can go ahead and check out that link
in case you need another hint.
But it should be pretty straightforward.
And then finally your last task number six is to basically combine all the other tasks.
So the final task is going to lie to quickly check to see if you're at the right level.
We want you to create a data frame with the columns A B C and D where each column has 50 rows of random
numbers for data in the random numbers should be between 0 and 100.
So just a hint as far as what steps to take here for that last task.
Use them pieds create the numbers Pasadena's PD that data frame and then remember you can use data equals
an index equal parameters in that PD that data and call.
OK.
That's really all there is to it.
Remember this should be pretty straightforward tasks.
So if you're able to zip right through them that's a good sign.
If you're struggling a little bit make sure you check out the next lecture where we go over the solutions.
Thanks and we'll see you there.