Welcome to this lecture on updating graphs on interactions now that we know about hover data click data
and selected data component properties.
We understand that we can actually grab information directly related to user interaction such as them
hovering over a specific data point or selecting a group of data points.
Now so far we've only display that information back to the user either through Jaison or an image like
we saw with the wheels and colour's example we're going to expand on this idea by now actually using
that interaction information from either hover data click data or select the data from that user and
then adjust it to another plot on your dashboard.
And this is where you really get to leverage the power of dash and plotted together because you're going
to be able to have a user directly interact with one graph in order to up another graph on the same
dashboard.
We're going to be using the MPG data set to display a scatterplot adjacent to an acceleration plot.
The updates upon user interaction.
Let's go ahead and see what the final dashboard product looks like and then we'll create it ourselves.
All right so this is what our completed dashboard is going to look like on the left hand side.
We have model year of the car and how many miles per gallon that car got.
And then as you hover over these cars you get to see a representation of the acceleration and how many
cylinders are have.
So if you look at this plot on the right hand side it will display the model of the car and the thickness
of that line corresponds to how many cylinders that particular model of car has.
And then we can also see a calculation for its acceleration.
So the slope of that line is visually representing how fast this particular model car can accelerate.
And you can also see that below that graph we display the actual values of displacement as well as how
fast it can go from zero to 60 mph.
OK.
So let's go ahead and get started on creating this dashboard.
Here am I text editor.
We've already done the regular imports dash Gorne HTL components graph objects panels PD and from by
pi we're going to import random in just a little bit you'll see why it's really to add a little bit
of jitter or kind of randomness to the year values.
So first off let's critter application by saying app is equal to dash dash.
And then we're going to read in the data frame for the MPG data set will say PD that read underscore
CXXVI and in my case I'm in the same directory as my data folder.
So all I need to do is say to MPG that see V your file path may differ depending on where your files
actually located on your computer.
Once you read in the data set list start off by just creating a quick scatterplot and seeing what that
looks like.
Oh say app out is equal to and here's where we're going to say H.T. maladaptive as we've done in the
past.
And let's start off by just inserting that graph for the scatterplot.
That's a core component graph and here it needs an ID.
So let's reference this as mpg that scatter and now it's time to edit the figure.
So let's get a couple more lines here.
Just so we can get some more space.
So inside of this we have our ID and we have our figure parameter and this figure parameter as always
takes in a data value as a list and a layout value which is just going to be that go that way outcall.
So let's start off with what goes inside the list.
Here we're going to call our scatterplot and are scatterplot is going to need an x and y value will
say the x value is the model year so that's the model year of the car.
And if you look back at that data set the model years actually does represent it with two digits such
as 87 or 77 or 68.
So we're going to go ahead and add 9500 to all those values so that displayed as 1960 instead of just
68 Why that's going to be the mpg on the y axis.
So replumbing 1968 per mpg for that particular car.
Then the next parameter we're going to define is text and also equal to the name of the car.
And there's actually no another parameter that allows you to specify more specifically what information
should be displayed.
And that's the hover info parameter.
So if the hover input parameter it does is it allows you to combine things like the X column or Y column
or text column to display that information.
And it should actually be a lower case i.
So hover info equals and then you just passen a string such as text and it's going to grab whatever
is in this text parameter and display that as the information hover.
But it also allows you to do things like add y and then it will display not just the name of the car
model but also then the model year or excuse me in this case the mpg if you wanted to display all three.
You could then add in the string and then that would correlate to the model year itself.
If you're interested more in information about hover info.
You can check out the portly docks here.
This is the full reference I have.
And if you go down to hover info gives you more information about essentially what you doing just any
combination of x y z text or name and you can join them in a matter of with plus.
OK so coming back here we've developed our hover information the text as well.
And now it's time to move on to the last parameter which is mode and we'll set that equal to marker's.
Then finally let's have our lay out.
We'll say go dots lay out and let's give this a title title we'll just be mpg data and let's give the
x axis and y axis some titles as well to do this is say X X primed or equal to and then you have a dictionary
title and we'll say this is the model year we'll set the Y-axis title be equal to let's say mpg or mpg.
And we will also say hover mode on this layout equal to the string closest though we close the string
to the cursor is the information that's displayed.
OK so that should be it for our basic scatterplot.
Let's come down here and run our server and you're going to see a little bit of an issue that will then
later be fixed by using this random data.
Or I should say a random library.
Let me zoom out so you can see the full picture.
All we've done here is basically essentially created a scatter graph that many times before using the
model year and mpg data.
Save this.
And let's check it out.
Well run Python basic thought PI and let me jump over to my dashboard.
OK.
Here's our dashboard right now we're just showing an entire scatterplot.
We haven't edited the width of this so it's taking up the entire screen but something you should also
check here is that every car is basically released on a single year which is integer.
Right.
So it's either going to be released 1970 or 1971 the way our data is set up.
Realistically if we wanted to get finer detail it would be per this particular month of a year.
Right now what we can do in order to not have this look so spaced with these lines is we can actually
add what's called jitter to this model and it essentially adds a little bit of random data to these
points.
That way they surround the year they released but not all stacked on top of each other.
Let me show you how to do that.
And then you can really decide if it's up to you whether you want to add that jitter or not.
The jitter makes it look a little nicer but then it's technically not the real data you are adding a
little bit of noise to it.
So keep that in mind.
But let's show you how you can add jitter to this and then you can decide whether you want to keep it
or not.
So to add jitter to this come back here to your text file and with this random library we're going to
do is after we read in the data frame going to zoom in here I will say DMF and I'm going to create a
new column called year remember or default column for the years called Model underscore year and also
year equal to random dot Rand I enty remember that's grabbing a random integer and I'm going to grab
a random integer let's say from negative 4 to 5 and I need the length of that data frame number of random
integers because I'm essentially going to add a random integer to each of these years.
So I'll say negative for it's negative five random integer value there.
Then multiply it by point 1 or 0.1.
That way it's a small value being added onto that year.
So it's essentially going to be something like 1978.
And then we're going to either do plus or minus from negative for some value.
For example positive 3.
Multiply that by 0.1 So that would be point 3.
And then you add that to the year which already exists.
So then we'll say model year.
So essentially all this line is doing is adding noise.
And this is also called adding jitter.
So what happens is right now our years are all stacked on top of each other.
For example two cars will have 1978.
Instead all we can do is we can take that 1978 pick a random number between negative four and five such
as let's say negative three.
Then we multiply it by 0.1.
So now that's negative 0.3 and then we're actually going to add that.
So in this case you could subtract that because it's a negative.
So you get something like 1977 point seven.
And so we would do the same thing for 1978.
And because this is random again maybe you end up something like seventy eight point two.
So now they're not stacked on top of each other.
When you actually plot them out.
So that's all we're doing with this in order to make sure that actually effects come down here it's
a model year and just set it as year.
We're still going to add 19:00 to it because technically it just is 78 and 77 not 1978.
Not 1977 by the time we're actually working with here I'm going to save this.
Let's rerun our Python basic about pi file and let's visit that dashboard again.
All right checking out that dashboard now you can see the effect that the noise is having.
It's basically taking everything on that year and then giving a little bit of noise.
You'll notice that some of them end up actually on the year.
That's because that random number happened to have been zero.
And because I didn't succeed.
Your results may look different than mine but overall you should see this general trend that MPG tends
to go up slightly as the years go along.
And as you hover over this you get to see the information.
OK.
So that's our basic scatterplot we just showed you how to create a scatterplot between model year and
mpg and add a little bit of noise to it.
We're going to stop this electric here.
And then the next lecture will actually show you how to update another graph interactively.
But hopefully this is more review for you right now in the next lecture that's we're actually going
to connect in other plot that will display the acceleration which means we'll also edit the style of
this particular scatterplot.
So it has less of a with we'll see you at the next lecture.