Welcome back to part four.
We're going to go right where we left off last time and now add in our actual date picker as a core
component and then linked that to our callback.
And there's a couple of things we're going to change when we link it to the callback such as formatting
back from a string to a Date Time object.
Let's get started.
OK here we are back at the text editor.
We've done our imports created dash and then what we're going to do before we get started is refactor
our layout just a little bit.
The fact that we're going to do is we're going to put H-3 an input into its own div and that way we
can line it up with a div for the date picker.
So right after H-1 we're going to do here is say T.M. div and then number pass and a list there comma
and we're going to grab everything from H-3 and input.
And in fact we're going to delete that comma.
Grab this cut and paste it into that list.
So essentially we just took H-3 input and put it into a list inside of this new division.
And here is where we can edit a little bit of styling for the H-3 where we're going to do here is inside
of the H-3 call.
I'm going to add in the style dictionary and say padding right.
And set that equal to 30 pixels.
Essentially we're going to be doing here is giving a little more room.
So it lines up for next year that we're going to create this input it's going to stay the same.
My ticker symbol Tesla and we're going to add in one more parameter here.
We'll say style.
And let's get rid of this comment.
Style is equal to.
We're going to edit the font size a little bit so it looks a little nicer.
So 24 font size.
And let's give it a width of 75 to notice that's not a percentage is just a number there.
And then we're going to pastille for this entire div.
So here's the list of the div let's say comma after that list and pass in its own style dictionary.
Say display inline block.
It lines up with the div we're about to create.
Then we're also going to say vertical align is top.
OK so that's this div right here.
We're going to put in one more T.M. div comma after that and here's where it ends at in another Hetter
or H-3 and the date picker.
So inside that list will say each div T.M. H.
And this is going to say select a start and end dates and then right below that.
Still inside this list for this div we're going to put a core component date picker range.
And of course if check of the documentation this is essentially the component that brings up a little
calendar free to pick data from.
So we'll give it the ID of my date picker and we're going to add in a couple of parameters here.
Essentially the parameters you add in are the minimum and maximum dates allowed and then the default
Vartan and dates so many dates allowed.
Well is it that this is really just an arbitrary choice here.
But let's have it only go back to January 1st of 2015 and let's have the maximum date be today.
So the way to do that is just say Max they allowed is equal to and then calling date time you can say
today.
So those here now are still important date time in order to do these calls.
Time today.
And then we can set a default start date.
So start is equal to date time the default start date just be the first of 2018 and we'll have the default
end date be.
Let's just have that also be today date time
OK so we have those parameters the minimum maximum dates allowed as well as default started and dates.
We're also going to do is for this div including H-3 and it pick range inside this list.
I'm going to do is read after that list add in a style dictionary.
And we'll just set the display to be inline block
OK perfect save that we'll still keep the same graph and we'll be updating that figure.
So remember that we can take in multiple inputs in sawder callback.
So the inputs we're most interested in is this start and end date.
So it's come back down here.
Here's our input and we're going to do here is in this input from my date picker I'm going to grab that
start date parameter and then I'm also going to grab again from my date picker the end date parameter.
There we go.
So this list of inputs is passed in the same order to update graph.
So that stock ticker parameter is going to be the value.
And then you want start date and end date.
So it's past those in as well.
Make sure these are in the same order start date and date.
Now unfortunately it would be really nice if I could then just say start here is equal to start date
but it's not going to work that way because what happens is and this is kind of an annoying feature
but it's just the way it's going to have to work is date picker range internally.
It's dealing with date time objects.
So that's no problem.
However once you actually grab it and then pass it into this input it's going to grab its string representation
which is fine except that string representation isn't going to work with this web data reader call.
So we actually need to then reformat this string again to be a Date Time object.
So the way we do that is using Date Time strip time.
So I'll show you how to do that will say date time Dot strict time and then we're going to grab that
start date string we grab from the beginning all the way to index 10 of that string and then we pass
and the formatting we want and the way this works to say percent sign the Y stands for a year.
Percent sign and stands for a month and then percent science.
That's an effort to date.
So what this is doing is basically saying hey the strings come in this format go ahead and then convert
that string into a date time object called start so we can then pass in here into our data reader.
And that's again because even those start date inside a date picker is the date time object.
By the time it gets passed into the input what Dash's doing ascribing the string representation of it.
So inside of this because we want to add a date time we need to reformat it again.
I'm going to copy this paste here and then for the end and sort of start date it's going to be.
And the all right save that then.
Now we have a data frame where the index is going to represent the actual time stamp and then the closing
column is going to represent the close price.
And we can do this.
You can either say that close but it's usually recommended that you do a more classic Pancho's column
call by passing a string in braces so we can say DFI close in this manner as well.
Let's save this and let's make sure we have no errors here.
It's really easy especially when you're adding in new divs up here to get typos of commas.
Let's make sure we haven't done that ourselves.
Let's say I'm basically a pie.
And like is mentioned really easy.
Looks like a start date date time isn't working here so let's make sure we did that correctly actually
put an 0 there that should just be the number one.
Let's save that and let's run this again.
Python basically pie and it looks like we have one more issue here.
The argument might the picker start is not a type dash.
Put so we'll come back down here and it looks like I forgot to actually put these into an input function.
So it's copy and paste that down here.
There we go.
So that's what I'm trying to tell you it says hey you're not doing a dash input which makes sense because
I was just passing in a tuple.
I should have in passing in a list of input functions.
So hopefully this helps you debug your own code or just get practice really in reading these errors
understanding how that reflects your code.
So it's a more realistic experience you're not going to be perfect on your first try.
My thumb based up-I we run this again.
Good.
Now we're ready to go.
So let's go back toward dashboard OK here's my dashboard you can see right now it looks like it's falling
along the default January 1st and then all the way to today's date.
I'm going to edit our dates.
So let's go back much further in time.
Maybe something like May 2017 and it's actually grab a month of data may 2017 the whole month and then
boom we have updated and let's choose another stock.
Make sure that still works we'll choose Apple and updated for Apple stock.
OK.
Awesome.
Now what would be nice if we can later add in something like state to actually then just have a submit
button.
So once we're ready for actual start and end dates and our stock symbol then we can tell the plot to
adjust and graph.
So we're going to do that and some of the next steps and we'll see at the next lecture.