Welcome back in this lecture we're going to quickly go over the solutions for the crash course exercise
questions.
Let's get started.
OK.
So for the first task it was to import pandas and pie so that should have been pretty straightforward.
Just import them pies and P and import pandas as PD and test number two is to set some pies random number
generator to seed 1 0 1 so to do that we call N.P. And then after this we call the random library and
that offer that we call the seat function and then passen 101.
So that's all you need to do.
You actually don't need to assign this to anything you just call that random seed.
And then that allows you to create our random matrix so we can say Matt is equal to the random and then
we'll call rand I.A. for random integer will give it the limits so we can go from 1 to 1 0 1 because
that upper limit is Xclusive.
So it goes up to 1 including 1 to 1 and then as a third argument we can't pass in a tuple of dimensions.
So 100 rows by five columns.
So if you messed up and put in 100 here not a huge deal.
Just keep in mind that the limit may be exclusive.
And then we're going to print out that matrix so we can see it at the end when we run our script then
task number four is just basically passing that matrix to PD data for him.
So we can actually copy and paste that in here will say F is equal to Panas data frame Pasdar matrix
and then we will print out Matt then up next task's number five.
That was to reassign these columns to be this list of names.
So the way to do that is simply one line just say D-Nev. columns is equal to.
And then you can just pass and the list.
So we call that the list is going to need to match up as far as dimensions.
So if I try to pass in a list of two values when I have five columns Pandurs is going to give you an
error.
The Here we have essentially five values in this list.
So is going to rename the columns 0 3 4 to these five names right here and then we can print our data
frame again to check that that worked then task 6.
So let's go through this.
First we need to actually create the random numbers.
So we'll say random numbers variable is equal to the random the rand I.A. and it's going to go we can
say 0 to 100 We'll grab 200 values there and then we're going to reshape that to be 50 by four.
So that's one option.
The other option instead of doing this reshape is to just grab this and then stick it in here.
As the actual dimensions.
So it's kind of up to you how you want to do this.
Then we're going to grab column names and we're going to have this just be a b c the actual going is
copy and paste here ABC the other quick trick for this is if you just say A B C D as a string and then
call that split on it.
This command right here will return back this list.
So on the solutions you'll see us use that split command.
But for now we'll pass that list itself and then using that we can create a frame we'll say the physical
to PD data frame where the data is equal to our Random data that we created before.
So those are going to be those random numbers and then our columns argument is just equal to call names
parameter we just made an endless print out that to frame to make sure that all worked we will save
that.
Now let's open up a terminal and run the script.
So say Python and I just call that my example.
You'll call it probably of course crash review exercise or whatever happens to be called we'll run this
and let's make sure everything worked.
So it looks like we have our data here.
We scroll all the way up.
We have a b c d.
So that's looking good.
We scroll up here looks like we have some real numbers and we have EF 1 EF 2 or 3 of 4 label that worked
out.
Looks like we have a matrix of random numbers so that'll work out as well.
Probably should have chosen some smaller numbers but hope we can see that everything turned out as expected.
OK.
If you have any questions who are free to post the Q&amp;A forums.
But really that's all you need to know for the rest of this course is to just be able to read any data
using pandas and then be able to manipulate it slightly.
Such as grabbing columns or grabbing rows.
Thanks everyone and we'll see you at the next lecture where we finally begin to discuss plumply.
We'll see you there.