Welcome back in this lecture we're going to briefly discuss how to get help for it.
Ash Now usually the best way and most useful way to get help with cash is to reference the documentation
online directly where you can do is also quickly generate help with two separate methods.
One is the help function call inside of Python and the other is a pie doc call at your terminal.
Let's discuss how these both work by jumping over to our editor.
OK here we are at our editor what I want to now point out is let's imagine you were going to import
Dasch each team as components as each team.
And you had a question on each team L that.
You just weren't sure and you want more information about it something you can always do and you can
do this for any component object as you can print out the results of the help function call on this
particular object.
And each of these components is well documented.
That way you can actually see the entire documentation for whatever Dasch component you're interested
in.
So I'm going to run this but I'm going to zoom out a little bit in our call here so I can see the entire
result.
So down at the bottom I'm running just a file here Python base that pi or whatever you happen to call
this.
And as a result you should be able to see help on class div in module built ins and I'll say more.
So what you do is here it's terminal.
You keep hitting enter and eventually it will if I expand this show you the entire documentation for
this particular component.
So essentially all the keyword arguments that this class can take things like style and also show you
different links that are useful to you.
Available events and a lot more information.
So this sort of kind of an API information that you can get off any component in Dasch keep any answer
you'll get all this information here.
OK.
So that's one way to do it.
Again it's just simply calling the help function and then printing out the results of that and when
type CLX to clear this.
Or if you're on Mac or Linux you can type clear.
Let's zoom back in the other way you can quickly generate help for any component is by doing the following.
Let's imagine again you wanted help with the divx component that's inside.
Each time components at your command line where you can do is say P-doc dasht W for right and then type
in the actual library that you're importing from.
HTL components and then dot and then whatever object you're interested in.
For example the div..
So let's make sure we spell this right components.
So here I'm saying PI dock space dash w space Dash 8 to components that.
And when you run this what's going to happen is this will automatically generate an H team L5 for you.
So let's go to our file browser and open up a steam file.
When you click on it it should automatically open in your browser.
OK so here I am and examples.
And now I see this dash HTL components that that HCM l file and if I double click on this you should
then see something that ends up looking like this.
Essentially all the information that was in the help call except now it's nicely formatted as HVM.
So that's another option that you can have in case you want to quickly generate documentation based
off what's available to you in your downloaded version of HTL components or really any Dasch components.
As always I would recommend you check online first but maybe you're on a train or something or just
a quick help and you don't have access to the Internet at that point.
You can always run these commands that we just showed you here.
All right thanks very much and we'll see you at the next lecture.