Welcome back.
Let's go ahead and work out an example solution for the interactive components exercise.
We'll head over toward text editor.
Now let's get started.
By performing the imports we know we're going to need cash to create or dash replication and we're going
to have core components as well as h team components.
So we'll import dash core components as DCC loops as the CC.
And then we will also import dash HVM components as each team will then from dash dot dependencies we
will import input and output.
OK so then we'll create our application.
So that's launching the application app equal to dash dash.
And then we need to set up the layout so we will call app lay out and let's create a couple lines here
and then zoom in a little bit so we can get a clearer idea.
So we have our aptly our first things first.
We create that outermost Div. and we're going to create two objects and here will create a range slider
as well as another div or an H1 so say DCC let's put this on a new line.
So the first component is DCC dashboard component and we're going to use a range slider and hopefully
you're able to get this from documentation.
And the second component is really up to you.
It's going to be the output component.
So it can be another div or it can be another something more specific like H-1.
We're going to use HTL dot H-1 to make a header.
It could have also been div..
Either one is totally fine.
Again you have a lot of flexibility here.
So we're going to say H-1 there as our output let's get these IDs.
So we don't get confused.
So the range slider will get this idea of just range slider and will say this has an ID of the product
because remember we're going to be multiplying the two numbers together.
Otherwise known as the product of two numbers.
So that's all we need to do for that matter.
So basically you're going to report back whatever that output is for the range Schlyter.
We're going to give it a couple more options.
You have a lot of leeway here as far as what minimum values to choose.
Let's say it will go from minimum to negative 10 and we'll say Max we'll have it go to 10 which means
because indexing starts at zero we have to actually say Max is 11 so that when you see the actual range
Schlyter it will go from negative 10 to positive 10.
So keep that in mind when you're working out of range Schlyter and probably one of the hardest parts
of setting this up is the mark's parameter.
So this marks parameter.
If you check it out in the documentation you need to create a dictionary so you could then if a for
loop or with a dictionary comprehension.
So we'll show you how to do if a dictionary comprehension.
We're going to say I colon string I for I in range.
And we're going to go from negative 10 to 11 here.
OK so that's how we can create the marks.
Again you could have done this for a for loop.
Lots of different ways to create this.
And finally let's go ahead and give it some values to start off with.
We'll say that the marks start.
Excuse me the initial values.
It takes it in as a list.
We need one for the men and one for the max.
Essentially one on the left side one on the right hand side will go from negative one to one as our
starting values.
All right.
So this one this one part of the marks is probably the trickiest part.
You could miss a variety of ways.
Maybe a for loop so you could say for I in range from negative 10 to 11 and then you would have constructed
this dictionary by adding more keys and values to it.
So we have our general lay out.
Let's create our value function.
Our value function.
It's going to take in a list of values.
Again the range Schlyter returns a list of values.
The one on the left hand side and the one on the right hand side.
So that's our value list.
We're going to want to return the first value of the list so we can index that 0 and we're going to
multiply it by the second value in that list will say a value list index 1.
Again one of the trickier parts because you had a look at the documentation realize that the range player
returns back this list.
So you grab the first item in that list.
The second item multiply it and there is a product.
Now all that's left is to connect this to the IDs in order to successfully grab these with the callback.
So the app called back will start with the output.
The output should be the product in the H1 and then it's going to be children just like it was for Divx.
So that's just the normal text that goes into each time component and then the input remember it goes
inside of a list.
Here we just have a single input.
The idea for this one we decided it would be a range slider and then we want to insert or basically
grab the value so that list and that's all we had to do.
And then finally we finish it off with if name is equal to mean.
So the app runs server will save this.
And let's take a quick look at what we just did.
We did all our imports we create her application then we set up our application lay out application
layer has two main components a core component with this range slider and then some time component to
show the output.
You had a lot of flexibility here could have been H-1 Divx slug's give it an ID and then remember that
children is the actual property you want to edit here for the range slider.
You can set up any M.R. any Max you want.
Mark's this is actually even optional.
You could technically not have any marks there and just see an empty slider with no marks but it would
still work.
And then you have a value.
This is a default value one for the left hand side and one for the right hand side on that range slider.
OK so let's save this.
Run it and make sure it all worked out well say Python basic but apply enter let expand this to make
sure it's running.
OK I'm going to go to my online dashboard and see if it all worked out.
OK here I am at my dashboard so let's say negative six times four.
So that equals negative 24.
It looks like it's working.
So I'll say that 10 times negative five.
That's 50.
Perfect.
So it looks like a range slider is working just fine.
And looking back at this I think something I just realized that we may have done incorrectly.
Is this can actually go up to 11 because I set the max at 11 but I didn't take that into account when
creating the marks so I can either adjust the max or the markings.
Let's go ahead and just the max value so I'll set the max value to 10.
That was my mistake let's go ahead and go back and fix that.
So back here on points set the max as 10.
And the reason it's 11 here is because range goes up to but not including this last number.
So that was a mistake on my part.
Let's fix that.
Pythonesque that pi had back and there we go.
Now we see the market only go up to 10.
So my apologies for that kind of slight typo.
You can check out the documentation the guy had but for more details.
But again min and max that defines what the actual min and max for that range slider is for the marks
that defines the actual markings we see here those numbers that we see.
So if your marks are different than your min and max value you'll still see the range slider hit your
min and max values.
There just won't be markings there for them OK.
That's really all there was to this dashboard.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forms and make sure to check out the guidebook as
well as our provided solution code.
Again I just want to stress lots of different ways you could get done this.
So feel free to share your alternatives in the CUNY forums.
We'll see you at the next lecture.