Welcome back everyone in this lecture.
We're going to go over the solution for the line chart exercise.
Let's open up the file and get started.
OK so here we are at the exercise file.
The first thing I want to do is start off with our imports.
So for this we're going to need to import plotline the off line as I go.
We're also going to need to import plot the graph objects not grid objects craft objects as go and since
we're going to be using pandas we'll import pandas as PD then.
Coming up next what we need to do is create that pandas data frame which has actually already been done
for us as well as that list of days now that we have that we're going to create this for a loop.
So here we're going to do is for every day in this day's list we wanted to create a scatterplot set
that has a trace and then append that to our data.
So this is one way we can do it.
You can also do this through a list comprehension.
But let's start off with a simpler for loop since there is no real advantage for list comprehensions.
Besides making your code a little shorter so it's always a tradeoff between readability and how long
your code is as far as performance that's going to be the exact same.
So let's start off with a for loop with scatter.
First we know we're going to the X-axis as well as a Y axis and then we can right off the bat set mode
equal to lines.
And then what I'm also going to do is set name equal today.
So what that does is when I actually create this scatter which is essentially going to be a line chart
then I will set the name of that particular trace equal to the day in that list so start off with Tuesday
that will go on Wednesday and Thursday.
So that's how we can easily set up our legend there.
So we have mode and we have a name now which is the tricky part figuring out what goes x and figuring
out what goes y and if you take a look at the data frame file you can remember that in the X-axis what
we want is the actual time.
So that means if you take a look at the data frame that's going to be Eliz t underscore time.
So that's our x axis and then now we just need to figure out what the y axis is going to be.
And this one is a little trickier.
So the y axis I'm just putting this on a couple lines here.
That's going to be equal to the if we take a look at it C underscore our underscore Avijit from the
data frame.
Now the issue with just passing in the F temperature Our average is that we're not filtering based off
the day inside of this list.
So this is the tricky part.
We only wanted to grab this information for the particular day of Tuesday Wednesday Thursday or Friday
and so on throughout the loop which means we need to do the following.
We'll say Where the f of the Day column is equal to day and then off of that will grab that hourly temperature
average.
So let's break this down a little further.
Remember they're in this for loop we're saying four day in days and then all we're saying here is why
is going to be equal to the data frame for only that particular day.
So we're seeing where DFA happens to be that day.
So then we're only dealing with Monday only the end of Tuesday and so on.
And then with that data frame go ahead and grab that temperature average.
So this was probably the trickiest line out of everything.
And then once you created that scatterplot you can go ahead and append it to this trace or appended
to the data list.
Speaking of trace then we can set up our layout and here it's really up to you how far into detail you
want to go.
The can set up or lay out.
Say something like title is equal to daily temp averages and then we can also specify things like a
hover mode or x axis title and so on.
But let's keep it a title for now and then we create our figure from the data and Leo.
So again that one is pretty straightforward.
We'll say fig is equal to.
Go figure pasand data is equal to data and lay out Ezekial to lay out then I will say who I know and
we'll figure and you can always set a file name there as well.
So let's run this and make sure it worked well say Python based pi or whatever you happen to call your
PI file.
It looks like I have a quick point loops.
Let me fix that.
This should just be for me since I'm located at the same folder location should just be data.
So I'll run that again and then I got my answer.
So it looks like this for me.
And it should look something very similar to you.
So as you go along here you can see the various days.
All right.
So that's how you can do that with a for loop.
There's also an advanced solution basically solution B and that allows you to actually create this for
loop in a single list comprehension.
So I'm going to copy and paste that code here just so you can get a look at it.
It deals more pandas and with plotless which is why we're not really going to focus it too much but
let's go in and show you what that could look like and where to paste in here.
So this couple of lines of code is actually going to give you the exact same result that we just saw.
So recall walrus talking about partly basics.
You could just pass in a dictionary for light charts since it defaults to a line chart.
So we covered that in the partly basic lecture.
Alternatively you could just call go that scatter here but this is not even going to use this list and
said what it does is it sets X equal to that last time so it's y equal to the same filtering.
And then you'll notice here it says for day n and then it grabs the unique list.
So this day's right here this list of Tuesday Wednesday Thursday.
That's actually the exact same thing as saying DFI they give me back all the unique days in that particular
column.
So that's a way to do this essentially all in one line with a list comprehension.
Now whether or not this is more readable is really up to you personally if you're just starting off
a partly to recommend going the for loop route.
But later on it will start start to switch our convention to list comprehensions.
Since it's a little smoother than the four loops.
OK.
That's really all there was to this exercise.
If you have any questions feel free to post the Q&amp;A forums and I will see you at the next lecture.