Hello.
I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting module five, Project Execution,
in the course Project Management for Software Engineers.
Okay, let's get started.
On your mark, get set, go!
Well, not quite yet.
So just what is project execution?
Well, you're going to implement your plan as we designed in module three,
and you're going to measure and monitor its progress
as we talked about in module four, but before you get going,
there's a lot more to it than just that.
Let's first do a little quick recap.
So to recap, we built a project plan.
We first validated the PDD, the Project Definition Document,
we built our WBS, the work breakdown structure,
we wrote up our acceptance criteria, we applied resources to the WBS,
we developed estimates and schedule.
And it also includes all of the parts of the project control elements,
such as communications and change management,
risk and issue management, configuration and requirements management,
and procurement and quality management.
While the project is underway,
we are in the project execution phase and we are following the plan,
which includes updating the plan and managing the project
through our project control activities.
So now we are executing our project,
but exactly how are you going to do these activities,
and what I mean by how,
what behaviors and interpersonal relationships will you employ?
Now let's see what I mean.
The emphasis of project execution module is centered around
three very important and critical capabilities that every PM
should demonstrate on the job.
The first is leadership, the second is effective communication,
and the third is relationship management.
This project execution module is divided into these major sections.
Your success is tied to how well you execute your project
exemplifying these three elements of project execution. So let's get started with the first, leadership.