Leadership.
While your success as a project manager is certainly based on
the fundamentals of project management, your leadership capabilities may,
in fact, make or break your success.
Think for a moment.
Ask yourself this.
Why should anyone be led by you?
So you must find ways to engage people and stir their
commitment to the project's goals.
Okay, now let's see what I mean by leadership.
This class is titled Project Management for Software Engineers.
It does not say project leadership, but certainly could.
So here's a simple definition of leadership.
It's the action of leading a group of people or an
organization to a common set of goals.
Now a little deeper,
leadership is the ability to guide others into a direction or decision that
leaves them still feeling empowered and accomplished.
That is a very tall order and a very challenging task,
but very rewarding when you accomplish it.
Yes, you still need to be able to create plans and have good project control, but more essentially, you will also need great leadership.