Now I would like to discuss leadership qualities.
In other words, what are those qualities that make for a good leader?
The first, someone who can embrace and champion change.
Remember as a PM, you are in fact a change agent,
leading projects, completing your mission for the stakeholders,
that is the leaders of your company.
Next, earn credibility across the organization.
You may not have people that work directly for you,
but instead for other managers, and they are assigned to you for the project,
hence, giving you the ability to influence others towards a common goal.
This can be challenging.
A desire to lead projects and people.
Maybe PMs may be more comfortable running the project from a technical side,
making plans, writing status reports, etc,
but not that comfortable with the people side of things,
and that is the most important part of your leadership role as a PM.
Ability to build trust.
We focused on this in the last slide and how important trust is to your success.
Strong communication and marketing skills.
How are you going to lead if you can't communicate well?
The next section of this module will address improving
your communication effectiveness.
Strong negotiation skills.
How can you succeed as a project manager without negotiating
and balancing the needs of many interests?
Strategic planning skills.
As a leader, you are thinking strategically and not just tactically.
You understand the critical role of well-defined
processes and strongly support them.
Successful projects are not random happenings,
but typically follow defined processes.
Lastly, project and team management skills,
well certainly, you need these basic skills that we outlined in modules two,
three, and four.
Now we have come full circle.
What I asked at the beginning of the module, why should anyone be led by you?
Okay,
I'm going to talk about four different areas where people ranked very
high that if they had these types of attributes,
your team would follow.
First, by exposing some vulnerability,
you reveal your approachability and humanity.
So beyond creating trust and a collaborative atmosphere,
communicating a weakness also builds solidarity between followers and leaders.
Your ability to collect and interpret soft data helps
them know just when and how to act.
So as a leader,
if you can sniff out the signals in an environment and sense what's
going on without having anything spelled out for them,
that is good.
Indeed, great sensors can easily gauge unexpressed feelings.
They can very accurately judge whether relationships are working or not.
The process is complex, and as anyone who has ever encountered it knows,
the results are impressive.
So look into their eyes,
look at their body language to see those visual cues
about what may not be expressed verbally.
Real leaders emphasize fiercely with the people they lead.
They also care intensely about the work their employees do.
Another quality of good leaders is that they capitalize
on what's unique about themselves.
It may be your expertise, honesty, or integrity.
It even could be the way you dress, talk, or carry yourself when you walk.
It could be your smile or your eye contact.
It could be that you are incredibly smart,
work long hours, and always engage in small talk with team members to relax them.
These things may seem small or even silly, but they are very powerful indeed.
Lastly,
people do not commit to project managers who merely live
up to the obligations of their jobs.
They want more.
They want someone who cares passionately about the people and the work just as they do.