The next project control planning element is change management.
That's the reviewing, approving, prioritizing,
and implementing changes, also known as just plain ordinary change control.
This covers any changes whatsoever that might arise regarding the project,
such as requirements, scope, which is the most common,
budgets, schedule, resources, business changes,
etc, anything that wraps around those kinds of changes,
and so we need to then create our plan on how we
will implement and manage changes.
So why do we want to do change control or change management?
Well, project changes will occur no matter what,
and it's just part of project life,
and you'll want to be prepared on what to do and how to deal with them,
so you'll want to have a good process and plan in place.
Now one of your main challenges will be scope creep.
And again, scope is the features you're going to implement,
and creep means they just keep on growing.
Or it might even mean that you had a poor or inadequate scope to start with and,
therefore,
it didn't meet the requirements out the gate and you're
always playing catch up on the scope side.
So how will deal or manage with that?
And there may be other factors that drive scope creep or drive changes,
which would be milestone dates,
they may change or move; system performance issues,
maybe the hardware or software or the cloud services are insufficient to
meet the performance requirements; budget changes,
budgets don't always go up, they usually go down; acceptance criteria,
what does it mean to be done or acceptable by the user; roles and
responsibilities of different people or players or stakeholders; and
technology might be a moving target as well.
So because of all these, we want to get a good handle on change control.
In summary,
one of the most common reasons of failed projects is poor requirements or the
ability to gather those requirements in a methodical way,
so you might want to check out one of my companion courses,
Best Practices for Requirements Gathering,
here on Pluralsight.
Here's your change management or change control road map.
Plan for changes.
In other words, create a change control plan,
and add it to your overall project plan.
Institute a change control or change management process, have a process.
Educate and train everyone as needed,
especially the stakeholders on what the process is.
And, of course, follow your process.
Someone comes up with a change; don't just go implement it.
Follow the process of your change control.
And a little tip here is just minimize scope creep as much as
possible unless it meets your change control process.
For example, change control process may in fact be your best friend.
If you have a criteria,
say change is tied to the e-commerce module will be implemented in release one,
all other changes will not,
then that change simply goes into your back log to
be looked at or dealt with later.
This can be very helpful in educating your users on hey this
isn't quite as important based on our change control process
criteria; it moves to the backlog.
Before you is an example of a change management process.
First step is document.
We want to document a change,
so a change request form will be implemented with a change number,
a date, who, what, when, value, etc.
You can make the form as simple or as complex as you'd like.
Change comes in; you document the change.
Next step would be to evaluate the change.
We look at it with a certain criteria, maybe a benefit,
cost, impact to budget, schedule, customers,
stakeholders,
milestones like our previous example if it's tied to the e-commerce release one,
etc.
Now the evaluation criteria can change over time based on priorities.
You document, you evaluate the change,
and then you have a disposition of the change,
in other words what action are you going to take.
Stakeholders decide to agree or not agree to add to scope.
Okay, so document, evaluate, have a disposition,
and you put the stakeholders in control of the
process so they feel that ownership.
I recommend you use some sort of automated web-based or cloud based
change management system to track and log all the changes.
That way team members or stakeholders or users can easily fill out
the form and propose the form for evaluation.
Maybe your team meets daily or weekly or monthly to
look at different changes to evaluate.
And then give it a disposition, either it goes in the backlog,
or it will be implemented and planned accordingly.
And lastly, a report out.
That should be done regularly as part of your normal reporting activity.
For example,
maybe part of your status report will say that we have
received five new change requests, three are under evaluation,
and another two or three from a previous status cycle have
been approved and here's what they are,
so you're going to constantly report out as well on terms of what's coming in and out of your change control process.