So now that we have the project defined in the previous section,
this section is on project planning, so let's plan the project.
Here's a quote, "Plans are nothing, planning is everything.
" This is a great quote by Dwight Eisenhower, Mr.
D-Day.
What he is trying to say is that the process of creating plans is
actually more important than the plan itself.
You will find that you will learn and discover so much more about the
project than you imagine through the planning process.
The plan is mainly the outcome of the planning process.
By the way,
the plan is never static since the planning process is
continuous throughout the project lifecycle,
plans are constantly updated and improved.
So the project definition step provides the what,
that is what is the project going to do,
and in this section, we will discuss the how,
in other words, how the project will get accomplished.
The plan is merely the outcome of the planning process.
We are now transitioning from the what to the how.
Now the what, that's the project definition,
determines what the project will do,
and it documents what we want to accomplish in our project.
Now the how, which is coming in this section,
the project planning focuses on how the project will be accomplished,
how we're going to get those deliverables done and developed,
and also determine how the project will be managed along the way.
Okay, now let's segue into a few definitions first.
Definition of project planning,
project planning is defined as the process for determining all the work tasks,
the resources, schedule, and cost.
I mean,
this really is the essence of project planning and the main part of this module,
but also project planning addresses all sorts of other aspects
such as project control and project execution,
and we're going to address those in the following three modules a little later.
I'd also like to stress that project planning is a very disciplined process,
and it requires discipline for completing a project successfully.
You're going to need to be able to articulate objectives of the project,
what are going to be the deliverables of the project,
come up with reasonable estimates and schedule,
apply resources, and then go execute the project.
And again, I just want to stress that it's a disciplined process,
in other words, you have to know what you're doing,
you have to stay true to the cause, and focus at all times for success. Okay, let's move on.