Hello, I'm Michael Krasowski from Pluralsight.
I will be presenting module 1, Course Overview,
in the course Project Management for Software Engineers.
Now let's cover what I'll be presenting in this course.
Spoil alert!
Proceed at your own peril.
Project management is hard and very challenging work,
but can be very rewarding professionally and monetarily as well.
Are you up for the job?
Are you ready to embark on changing the way you think and
approach your career as you may consider evolving from a
software engineer to a project manager,
or even developing in to a leader of your organization or company?
Well if so,
then this course will help you quickly master the basic skills of project management for the software engineer.