Relationship management, or what I like to call customer service and then some.
This section of relationship management will cover customer service,
your customer's expectations, developing and building relationships,
and how you can manage and improve those very crucial
relationships as a project manager.
Okay, let's get started.
What is customer service?
Customer service is the act of taking care of the customer's needs.
It sounds very simple, but it actually is pretty challenging.
Now sometimes as PMs we get so focused on our many tasks,
we lose sight of the customer's needs.
It will happen, and it's happened to me certainly as well.
As PMs, we want to provide and deliver professional,
helpful, high-quality service and assistance before,
during, and after the customer's requirements are met.
Just like I had the five Cs for effective communication,
for customer service, I have my five Ps.
Here are some characteristics of really good customer service.
The first, you're a provider.
You will provide the needs and desires for your customer.
You are focused on their needs.
Promptness.
Promises for delivery of your services must be on time.
Delays and cancellations should be avoided at all costs,
and never be late for a meeting certainly.
Politeness.
Politeness is almost a lost art.
Saying hello, good afternoon, sir, mam,
thank you very much are a part of good customer service,
even in project management.
Don't forget, always use good manners not only for your customers,
but everyone you deal with.
This builds your quality and character, plus it's just the right thing to do.
Professionalism.
All customers should be treated professionally,
which means the use of competence or skill expected of the professional,
of you.
Professionalism shows the customer they're cared for and
this builds trust in you and your team.
Personalization.
Using the customer's name is very effective in
producing a connection with each other.
Customer's like the idea that whom they do business
with knows them on a personal level.
Quite frankly, I have a hard time remembering names,
so I spend extra time learning them and getting to know
my customers just a little better.
So think for a moment.
Use this list as a checklist.
Rate yourself on a scale of one to five.
How did you do? Think about what you could do differently and start doing it tomorrow.