Now we are at the second part of building your plan,
and this is the implementation element, but before we get started,
let's just put it back in context on the next slide.
Now we just covered the first part of building your plan, the core element.
We validated the PDD, we built the WBS, and we itemized the acceptance criteria.
Now the second part we're going to cover now is to apply resources to the WBS,
develop an estimate, and develop a schedule,
and these last three I call more of the implementation elements,
so let's get started on those.
In step four,
we're going to determine the resources that we need and apply them to the WBS.
Now resources are typically people and tools,
but could include other items,
mostly they're people who will be assigned the what task,
how many hours they'll be assigned, etc.
So what you'll want to do for each entry in the WBS,
you want to identify you will work that task,
Michael, Mary, Paul, and when they are needed,
maybe the date they're needed.
In addition, you may need some other resource details.
For example, the role they'll play like programmer,
developer, web designer, database modeler,
required skills, maybe C# or jQuery, maybe some training needs,
they may also need some training on AngularJS and things like that,
and they may also need a certain skill or experience level,
well we need to do some architecture work,
we may need a very experienced developer or software engineer,
and maybe other areas, a QA analyst,
maybe they need to understand the domain they'll be
testing in and things like that, so let's see some examples of this.
Here is our example from the previous section,
so this is our WBS that we built up.
I'd like to call your attention to the right,
we've added two additional columns, the who and the when,
and in this case for the who, I just used people's initials,
MK, PS, things like that.
And another little example here is JK/MK because they'll be two
people working this particular task together,
and if I don't know yet,
I'll just put TBD and I'll come back and fill that in later,
and over on the right, I put the dates when they'll be needed for the project.
Now on this example, I kept it simple, but you could add additional columns,
you could add the role they're going to play if you weren't sure,
you could add some required skills they need,
you could add another column for training needs,
even another column for skill and experience,
and maybe even another column as a little note field,
so you can add those different elements as you see fit to add more robustness
to your plan to help you get successful in your project.
So now that we have the resources assigned,
and when we would like them to start the task, let's move on and start making estimates for each of our tasks.