Now let's recap the key points of fundamentals.
Project management.
That's the planning and organization of a company's or
organization's resources in order to move a specific task,
event, service, or product toward completion.
The project.
It's a temporary group activity designed to produce a unique product,
service, or result, and group activity again means teams.
Next, you know what makes an activity a project.
Now each company or organization will have different thresholds or
definitions as to what is a project versus a simple activity,
and some threshold examples would be dollars or hours,
or simply if something is really critical to the business.
And usually there's a project review process that helps set those
thresholds and vets those projects for approval.
Next, hard and soft skills.
Remember hard skills are about a person's skillset and
ability to perform a certain task or activity,
such as knowing how to use PowerPoint, for example,
but you also need some soft skills,
which are personal attributes that enhance an individual's interactions,
job performance, and career prospects.
Next, we covered some key attributes of a PM,
and one of the main ones I'd like to stress here is ownership.
It's the attitude that this project is mine and I will do
the very best I can do in that project.
Also another key attribute is integrity.
That's the quality of being honest and having strong principles.
Also lastly, effective communicator,
and this facilitates information sharing between company employees,
team members, management, vendors, etc.
Next, project teams.
Remember it's all about teamwork and remember your team members may work
directly for you or they may work for another manager,
but are assigned to you.
This can and will challenge your leadership skills.
Desired outcome, a successful project,
and that's keeping your projects focused and in line
with the business goals and objectives.
Now let's review the next module.
Here's a recap of the planning module.
Remember beginning any project with a project definition document is critical.
We outlined an approach of creating a project
definition document with key elements.
Also a project definition provides clear and expected project characteristics,
and most importantly, project outcomes.
The WBS.
We discussed that project planning is the process for determining tasks,
resources, estimates, and schedules, and begins with creating the WBS,
the Work Breakdown Structure,
which is a hierarchical list of tasks decomposed into phases,
deliverables, or work packages.
Next, we itemized the acceptance criteria.
This portion of the plan is typically written in simple
business and user-oriented language,
such as the system's ecommerce module will be completed on
March 1st to support credit card processing,
for example.
Next, determine and assign resources, which are usually people,
to each task,
and also we identified for each resource any additional training or
skills that are needed to complete this task.
Then also for each task we estimated the hours that it
would take to perform that task.
Scheduling.
For schedule resource loading,
we take each task and we determine the start and end
dates and with the start date being on or after the date
that the resource is available.
We also looked at the resource load chart and how
important that was visually seen how they allocated hours
per resource will lay out over time.
And lastly, even though our plan is looking really good at this point,
its focus is the work itself.
There are other elements that must be included in the plan to support the
process of actually managing and controlling the project,
such as reporting and requirements management,
and as we talked recently,
it needs to also include the transition plan to be
implemented during project closure.
In project control,
you learn that you need to determine your approach and processes for the eight
project control activities prior to beginning your project,
and in fact are added to your project plan.
Then when your project begins,
you will then follow each of the processes you laid out.
Reporting management.
Sometimes we call it communication management.
We discussed what you will say, the content,
and to whom you will say it to, such as the stakeholders.
Effective communication is critical to your success, so get good at it.
Change control.
Change is a part of the business life,
so be flexible and agile and have a solid process for managing change.
Configuration management.
That is controlling the versions and content of the project deliverables.
Requirements management.
This is ensuring all requirements are identified, tracked, and managed.
These are tightly coupled since as you add requirements you need to plan what
version it will be part of and when they will be delivered.
Risk and issue management.
Remember risks are those things that might happen to the
project that you want to be aware of, keep an eye on,
and tag, and track.
Issues, on the other hand, are known items that are impacting your project,
such as software defects that you need to track and disposition.
Quality management.
I'd like to say, hey that's the easy one,
just plan and execute the project control activities,
and you will have great quality.
We also discussed some simple techniques that your team can use,
such as checklists and templates, which will allow you to implement consistently,
and therefore, with quality in common team activities.
Lastly, variance analysis.
This is an approach to help you determine if your project is on track or not.
Remember, you will constantly be asked if you are on track,
and if not, by how much and why,
and variance analysis will help you answer and address those questions,
as well as keep your project on track.
In the Execution module,
we stressed that you must find ways to engage people and stir
their commitment to the project's goals.
As a leader, a project's success will be all about growing others.
One of the key and most important attributes of the leader is trust.
If they trust you, they will follow you on all levels.
The next major emphasis in this module was effective communication.
Remember it's all about getting the right information to the
right people at the right time and using the right method to
communicate that information.
We talked about some other great communication tips that I call my five Cs.
In all your communications, you need to be clear,
concise, courteous, consistent, and compelling.
Before you send any note, email, document,
or presentation, please run it up against the five Cs.
Lastly was relationship management.
This includes delivering great customer service and our five Ps,
provider of great service, promptness, politeness,
professionalism, and personalization,
and that's using the customer's name in a very positive and effective
way and producing a good connection with each other.
Remember managing customer expectations is indeed challenging,
so do your best to get the win-win.
In other words, it's not your way or my way,
it's a better way, so work towards all parties feeling good about the decisions being made.