Hi and welcome back in this video we're looking at what is a database and I'm sure that you already
know what a database is you think that you know what a database is.
And chances are you probably do.
Databases have been around for a long time but nevertheless let's take a quick look at what our data
bases and also a couple more things about databases and about specifically the database system.
We're going to be using when we talk about databases we tend to think of these things.
This is a table and as you can see it has four columns.
The ones going from top to bottom ID which can be an identifier some sort of unique number.
The first name last name and an email address so here could be for different users of a product or of
a business and user with ID 1 2 3 and 4.
And you've got their names and their e-mail addresses.
This is a very normal table to have in a database system.
So we normally think of these things now in database systems nowadays they've evolved substantially
over the last few decades and now we are not limited to just storing data in a table and then retrieving
it.
There's a bunch more things we can do.
And one of those things is what I'm going to show you now.
So table should store data related to one thing only and that's the key premise.
So just for example customers or items or you know that sort of stuff if it belongs to a larger entity
such as a business or a web application then it may store related data in separate tables.
And what I mean with related data is customers items purchases stores they're all somehow related.
Customers can purchase items and items can be inside stores and so on.
So we have related dates and I'm going to show you three tables customers purchases and items.
Let's start with customers let's say we've got a customer table that has four columns like we saw before
with an identifier which is a unique number for each row.
And then if got a first name last name on an e-mail.
The first customer in your table could be ID number one with first name Jose last names and email there
and then you can have more customers as well.
So then you have for customers for example let's now move on to the items table an item could have for
example an I.D. a unique identifier.
Once again a name of the item and a price.
For example one of your items could be with identifying number one a check that cost a hundred or 55
units Maccabi dollars it could be pounds euros etc. and you could have more items as well naturally
.
Finally the more interesting column toy the more interesting table is not the customer or the items
table but rather the purchases table.
And to put it in the middle for a specific reason let's say that this purchase this table has once again
three columns but now there is no information related to the purchase itself.
For example say how much it was paid how much a customer paid in that purchase but rather only an identifier
for the purchase.
The customer I.D. the customer that made the purchase and the item I.D. which is the item that was bought
in that purchase.
This is assuming each customer can only buy one item per purchase.
For example in your first purchase customer number one bought item number one in your second purchase
.
Top try that.
This is a bit of animation there.
So this links up the first customer with the first item in the second purchase.
We had the first customer buying the third item.
Item number three in the third purchase we had Customer Number Two buying item number four.
And in your last purchase we had customer number for buying item number four.
So as you can see there are relations between the staples.
This data is related to one another and we call this relational data.
The purchase is stable performs the relationship between customers and items.
But in a more basic way the customer's table is related to the purchases table and the purchases table
is related to the items table.
So there is no relationship between customers and items.
There's only relationships between customers and purchases and between purchases and items.
And that's a key distinction related data is something that we can model these relationships with so
we can model relationships between tables and columns using data based systems designed for modeling
these relationships and there are some other data systems which do not allow for relational data.
And I may sound wild you may think well why would you not want to allow for data that is related to
one another.
And the reason is because not allowing for relational data and gives you other advantages such as increased
speed or simply scalability among others.
If your system doesn't have to cope with the ability to relate to data one to another then it can be
a simpler system and therefore it can be faster.
Now although we're talking about scalability Let's quickly mention a bit about scalability.
Don't worry about scalability as the first thing.
At least not until you are forced to.
Here's a few things to remember.
A database management system such as Pascola sequel which is the one we are going to be using is installed
and runs on a computer for example your own computer and applications such as your Python apps then
connect to that computer and ask it to retrieve data for them.
So the database by itself is not particularly useful unless you've got somebody directly communicating
with it.
Normally you're going to make an app and the app is going to communicate with a computer and that is
going to ask the database to retrieve data for it.
If there's too many requests for data for example too many applications then the computer can end up
unable to cope with a load and that is why we need scalability.
Scalability entails enabling the database to be spread across multiple computers and then our apps can
request in more places at once which reduces the load on each individual server for example or another
option.
Instead of splitting across multiple servers we can make it we can just make one of the servers a lot
bigger and not more powerful.
And then it can deal with more load due to the two ways that we can perform scalability.
But this is not a course about scalability relational database management systems which are the RDBMS
is which is Pasqua equal if one of them tend to not scale as well as non-relational database management
systems.
So what this means is that things like Pasqua sequel or my sequel we're going to be looking at that
tend to not scale as well which makes sense.
The non-relational systems are simpler and therefore it's easier to make them scale.
There's a few more reasons for it.
It's not just because they're simpler.
But we won't be getting into the reasons why because that would be more on a course about non-relational
database management systems.
So is gullability important.
Yes it is important because it enables the servers to serve more clients.
So either you have more servers or you have more powerful servers and that's what capability is about
and your clients are your applications.
So that's what scalability is important because if if your server or your database doesn't scale at
all you may end up not being able to cope with an increased load.
However RDBMS is allow you to interact and retrieve data easily a lot easier than it would be with a
non-relational system.
As an example and we're going to be looking at a lot of examples throughout the next couple of sections
as an example using the table shown earlier with your customers items and purchases.
It is a lot easier to get something like the revenue generated per customer in total using an RDBMS
rather than a non-relational system and with a lot easier I mean substantially easier.
You can get the revenue generated per customer just asking the database for it.
What is with a non-relational system.
You cannot with a non-relational system.
Your application would have to get multiple bits of data and then join them together in the app as opposed
to in the database.
So should you use a relational database.
If your data is simple and there are few to no relationships between them then don't use a relational
system.
Use something else.
I hope that's not the case because you're already here.
So that means you think you need a relational system.
If your data is related expect that as the applications grow and more data is collected you as a developer
will find more and more relationships and the relationships will grow and your data will be more interrelated
and there will be more and more need for a relational system.
If you have really good data use a relational system and a word of warning if you're not sure use a
relational system.
Just use an non-relational system if you're sure that your data is not related.
If you're not sure use a relational system at least to begin with.
So a couple of other elements of relational database management systems and we are going to be looking
at these throughout the course.
Are things like views which non-relational systems don't tend to have functions which are not original
systems sometimes do have to be give you a lot of power and specific Pasquier sequel has a lot of these
and that they're very useful aggregation which some non-relational systems have but a lot of others
don't.
Then there is things like adding data together in the database and we're going to be looking at how
to do that and Joines which allow you to link tables together and retrieve data from all of them simultaneously
.
And we're really going to be looking at that in the course and there's a lot more things.
Relational database management systems are a lot more a lot older than non-relational and they are a
lot more mature.
In general they are reasonably fast.
They give you a lot of ease of use in terms of retrieving and interacting with your data.
The really great systems and a lot of people nowadays think that relational systems are just outdated
but really they're not.
OK.
There are various relational database management systems.
There's my sequel which is arguably the most popular and that is because a few years back back when
my sequel was on version for plotting the sequel The main competitor which is the one we're looking
at wasn't version 7 and possibly sequel was not very good.
But nowadays Patras equals vision.
Nine point five has come a long way and possibly sequel I'd say is arguably the best.
So if you are just learning about relational data using porticos equal scores is perfect for you because
Patras equal is arguably the best system nowadays in terms of performance in terms of adherence to sequel
standards and a bunch more things.
You've also got Secret Service which is also very good but it's not free.
So if your company has a Microsoft subscription then you can maybe use sequel server instead.
But it is quite expensive and there's a few more such as made by Oracle but these three here are the
main ones.
Now that we're here we've quickly looked at a few things related to database management systems.
So just scalability how they're structured how you can link data together and a few of the relational
database management systems available.
And in this cause as I mentioned we're looking into possible yes and that is arguably the best system
there is right now and certainly the only one that is as good and free.
So without further ado.
Thanks for listening in.
And I see you in the next video