Hi, welcome back.
In this video, we're going to be installing psycopg2
on Windows.
Psycopg2 is a library for Python
that lets us talk to PostgreSQL databases
from within our code.
Now, first of all, let me say that the method
I'm going to show you in this video is a fairly new method,
so it's possible that it won't work for you
and if it doesn't, just move on to the next video
and try a more manual approach.
But first, try what's shown in this video
because it's much simpler.
The first thing you have to do
is go ahead and open your File Explorer
and you need to go to your Python installation folder.
In my case, the Python installation folder is this one here,
so that's C:\Users\Jose\AppData\
Local\Programs\Python\Python37\Scripts.
Make sure you use the Python folder
for the Python you've got installed and you want to use.
In my case, I've only got Python 3.7 installed.
But if you have multiple versions of Python installed,
just make sure you use the one that you want to use.
Once you've got this, put it aside,
and then open up your Settings.
In here, we're gonna find a setting
which is, just type PATH,
and it will tell you Edit environment variables
for your account or something similar.
So, you can click on that, come over here,
and just make it a little bit bigger
to see what's in your path.
And what you wanna make sure
is that either this Path under User variables
or this Path under System variables has your Python path.
If it doesn't, well, you can see it here by the way
in my User variables, if it doesn't contain that,
just double-click it and add a new field here
and put the path in it.
The path has to be the path to Python\Scripts,
so make sure you add the Scripts in there.
Okay.
We're gonna start with that.
Make sure it's there.
And once you've got it there,
don't close any of these just yet,
go ahead and open the Command Prompt.
The Command Prompt may look a bit scary
but it's just a text interface to your computer.
So basically, you can use it to run programmes
or do anything your computer can do
but with text instead of graphics.
Something we can do in the Command Prompt
is, for example, type pip.
Pip is the Python package installer
and we can use it to instal
any Python libraries that we want.
And in this case, we're gonna use it to instal psycopg2,
so all you have to do is type pip instal psycopg2.
Now, if this works,
you'll just see it instals without any issues.
And if that works, you can try to type Python
and see what happens.
If Python is not recognised
as an internal or external command,
that means that we need to add one more thing to our path.
So, go back to your environment variables,
double-click your path, click New,
and what we're gonna type in
is the same path as above but without Scripts.
Okay, it's just like that.
Then press OK.
And now, press OK here as well.
And we can go ahead and restart our Command Prompt.
So, what we've done there, by the way,
is we've told our computer
that whenever we run a programme using our Command Prompt,
it should look in the Scripts folder
and also in the Python37 folder.
So, we're gonna go ahead
and go into our Command Prompt again.
Now if you type python, Python runs.
That is running this Python programme
that you see here inside my folder.
Because as soon as we type python,
it goes and looks in the path
and tries to run any programme called exactly python.
And because it's found it, that's what we're running.
Now, we should be able to do import psycopg2
and we don't get an error, which means everything worked.
If you do get an error here or you got an error earlier
when installing with pip or something like that,
feel free to ask a question in the course Q&amp;A,
but you may be better off trying the method
that is outlined in the very next video.
It's a bit more manual.
It's gonna teach you a little bit longer
and you need a couple more tools
to be able to do it, but it should also work.
Of course, if this has worked, you don't have to watch
or do anything shown in the next video.
So, if you are able to import psycopg2,
that's it, you can skip the next video entirely
and you're ready to start with this section.
So, that's it for now.
Thanks for joining me and I'll see you in the next video.