Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to look at installing Python.
Up until now we've done our development using Ideally the python shell which is an interactive interpreter
which gives us instant feedback when we're typing.
However we've looked at creating files with it.
And really it's only simple enough when you've got one file when you've got one file on your program
only that file then it's quite easy to use.
Ideally to develop However when you want multiple files and when you want to create a larger project
ideally sonce lacking a bit on that aspect the tool I'd like to introduce to you is Pi charm which is
essentially the most used Python ID in the market if you don't want to use Python or you don't want
to use an ID.
You can also use just a normal text editor and create your files using different folders.
And that's also going to be better than using idealy text editors you might want to use in an atom text
Wrangler and there's a lot of others like sublime text.
However in this cause we're going to be using Python because as I said PI charm is the most used Python
ID in the market and by the way ID stands for Integrated Development Environment which means that Python
has everything you need to develop large and complex projects
in order to download Python.
Let's go into the IDs section and then click on Python
then go to download now.
And here you can either download the professional edition which comes with a 30 day trial or the community
edition which is free.
Remember you can pick your platform here and program on works with all common platforms if you use the
community edition.
You'll be able to follow along the course totally fine and there's really nothing different between
the community edition and the professional edition for what we are going to be doing in the professional
edition does have slightly better integration with data bases.
But we're going to be using something else for our database management so we don't really have to worry
about that.
Once you've picked your platform and which one you want to download go ahead and just downloaded and
installed it like any other normal program.
Once you've installed it.
Come back to the next video and we're going to be going over how to set it up so I'll see you there
.