Play and we'll come back and this video will look at lists in Python.
Up until now we've been looking at variables as a box that contain one thing.
So just one number on one string that is useful no doubt.
But sometimes we want to have a variable that contains many things.
For example if we had a web application we may have a variable that contains all of our users.
Or if we had a list of telephone numbers we want to call we may want to store them in one variable as
opposed to many variables.
So there's a lot of uses for variables with a list inside them.
So let's look at exactly how we can create a list in Python and it's actually really simple.
For example I'm going to create a list of numbers and the only thing you have to do is say numbers which
is your variable name equals and then open and close.
Square brackets in Python.
The square bracket is a list.
So right now this is an empty list.
It doesn't have anything inside it.
However we can put things inside the list.
For example I'm going to put the numbers from 0 to 9 so the first number is 0 and then a comma and then
one two three four five or so.
Now this list contains 10 elements.
The numbers from 0 to 9 and I'm going to press Enter at the end to see if this list.
And now if I type numbers then this is going to give me my list.
Notice that is a list.
It's not a string it's not a number.
It's a different type.
Notice how it's not a string because it doesn't have quotation marks around it.
It's not a number because numbers are only digits themselves and not the square brackets so this is
an entirely different type which is a list which contains many elements lists also have a length.
And we know the length of this list to be 10.
What is going to happen when I try to get the length of this list.
So if I say Len and the numbers what do you think is going to get printed out.
9 is the largest number in this list.
There are 10 elements however.
So I would expect the number 10 to be printed out and indeed that is what does get printed out.
The length of the list is not the largest number in it it's not any specific element but rather how
many elements are inside.
So how do we access the last element of the list the number 9.
Well we need to say numbers and then we need to give it the position of the number we want.
So for example if we give it position 1.
What do you think is going to get printed out.
There's only 10 numbers in this list.
So then position 1 is going to be the number one.
So in computing we always start counting from the number 0.
So if you guessed that the number that should be printed out is zero.
That's absolutely fine.
It's a very common thought in the beginning.
But in computing we start counting from zero.
So numbers zero is actually the number 0 which is the first element of this list.
So there are 10 elements but actually the number 9 is not in position 10 even though the length of the
list is 10.
The last number is always the length minus 1.
So in this case numbers 9 is the number 9.
So numbers LN numbers.
So if we try to access the position that is Lenn numbers aka 10 we will get an error list index out
of range.
So we're trying to access index number 10 and it's telling us that that does not exist.
It's outside of the range of this list.
This list ranges from 0 to 9 inclusive.
So if we wanted to access the last the number take a guess at how you would do it only with a length
.
So the solution to that is numbers and then Lenn numbers minus 1.
And that way you would get the 10 from here.
Take away 1 would give you one index before the length which is nine in this case and that would give
you the number 9.
So this is a very basic about lists how we can create them how we can access elements in it and how
we can get the length of the list and also accessing the last element is not the same as the length
of the list.
OK.
I'll be seeing you in the next video where we're going to look at how we can access each of the elements
in order.
And so you're