Hi and welcome back in this lecture we're going to be looking at the split method.
This method is going to be essential when we require users to give us various values at the same time
and also in a wide array of other instances as well.
But especially for this section we're going to need to use the Split method when we want our user to
give us multiple data points at the same time.
The data that the user is going to give us in this section lottery numbers that they want to play we're
going to ask them how many numbers you want to play or which numbers you want to play and then they're
going to tell us six numbers that they want to play.
As you may have guessed the applicant to be building in this section is a lottery app.
So the user is going to have to pick six numbers that they want to play and they have to give us all
the six numbers at the same time.
Now they could for example just type the numbers 1 2 3 4 5 6 and then give us these six numbers and
we could simply take one character and that would be each of the numbers that they want to play in this
lottery.
However if they wanted to give us a number that has two digits such as number 11 then we can't really
do that with that method.
So once the user is going to give us is a string in the format of five 16 twenty 3 four and one for
example.
And these are the six numbers that are usually one to play for example.
And what we have to do with that is extract each of the numbers.
Let's assign this to a variable.
When to Call numbers.
And now we've got our numbers string that contains these things here every string has a method called
split and the split method allows us to just do that generate a list from a string by splitting the
string at a specific character.
So what we want to do now is say numbers don't split and then the comma.
So take your guess as to what this is going to do.
It's going to generate a list but what is going to be each of the elements of that list.
Think about that just for a moment.
And now I'll press enter.
And as you may have guessed each of the elements is the number itself.
Five twenty five and so on but they are all strings.
This makes sense.
The parent is a string.
Each of the numbers is a string as well.
So this is how our user is going to give us the numbers.
It's going to be something along the lines of use on those phone numbers is going to be equal to input
into your numbers separated by comments and then they are going to enter the numbers 1 2 3 4 5 6 for
example.
And then we're going to split that string user underscore numbers split on the comma and that is going
to give us a list of numbers.
But do note is that each number is still a string.
So we may have to do some work with that.
We're going to have to convert each of these numbers to an actual number so that we can then do some
protesting with it calculate winnings and things like that.
So let's try to convert that into numbers in the very next video.
That's either