Hi will come back in this section we're going to be looking at API and Python web.
I'm really excited for this section.
In fact what I do in my day job is python web development and mainly So I'm really excited to introduce
you to this field.
Not only am I doing that because I do that in my job but also the Web nowadays is completely taken over
everything else.
When we previously wanted to make mobile apps now we're usually making mobile Web sites.
It's just faster it's easier it's a nice experience.
So it's.
And also we're requesting a lot of things via API.
Now if you don't know what an API is that probably sounds like Chinese to you but we're going to be
looking into that in this section.
And I'm really excited.
And you should be too.
It's a really interesting find really useful as well in this video we wanted to look at.
What is an API.
Just because if you don't know what an API is then it's really difficult to understand why it might
be useful or even if you're using one already and you don't realize it.
Let's look at the eye first.
The i in API it stands for interface.
Now a lot of people don't know what an interface is and that's totally fine because it's not a word
that you really encounter very often in the in your day to day.
In the case of the I in API it's an interface between two programs.
So let's look at what is an interface.
Think about when you go to a restaurant when you go to a restaurant you want food.
You don't want to talk with the server the waiter although you do.
You don't want to talk with a chef although you kind of do to some extent.
You ask the waiter or something and they then ask the chef something and they produce the food for example
.
So in the case of a restaurant the chef makes the food but you don't communicate with a chef.
So how does that happen.
How does the knowledge of your food get to the chef.
And the answer is via the server or the waiter.
So the server or the waiter is the interface between you and the chef.
It is the the thing or in this case a person that enables communication between two separate processes
two separate programs two separate applications.
In this case two separate people.
We could take that a step further and think the chef is an interface between the server and the food
.
And I put a question mark there at the end because I appreciate it may be a bit confusing but if the
server knows nothing about cooking and knows nothing about what the chef does the only thing the server
is doing is asking a person the chef something and then food magically appears.
If you were the server you would think the chef is an interface between you and some magical food producing
machine.
It could be.
So this is what I mean with interfaces.
Innovators are confusing because they are not things they are just kind of methods of enabling communication
between two things.
So the interface isn't an actual thing it is just a way of enabling communication a way of permitting
that flow between two separate things.
OK let's revisit that in a couple of moments.
And first let's look at the other two letters.
The A and the P in API.
It stands for application programming.
And that doesn't really mean anything to anybody but the interface the API is used for Application Programming
and now that gets a bit more meaning it's an interface which enables communication and you can use that
enablement you can use that new found communication to do programming of your applications.
So what does that mean.
Lets give you a few examples because all this theory is a bit confusing.
For example the methods in psycho-BS G2 which you've used to communicate with postscripts those methods
are an API to interact with lib P-Q.
And what is P-Q the methods in lippie Q Aren't API to interact with potsherd sequel.
So when we were using Cyclopedia to really we were using an API that allowed us to interact with another
API which allowed us to interact with Pascola sequel
so that's a bit of a contrived example but nevertheless that's something there.
Twitter for example exposes an API to allow your applications to interact with Twitter for example create
tweets search tweets.
And so what does this mean.
It means that although you cannot interact with Twitter itself directly with the code that makes Twitter
Twitter.
Twitter does give you a way to interact with it and create tweets and search tweet and do a number of
other things like see which subtribe you've got or which followers you've got so.
So the API is just an interface to enable communication.
But you are not interacting with Twitter directly.
So in the case of Twitter there is a web API.
It is an application programming interface that just happens to be the Web.
But we've also encountered API use for other things we've encountered API is to interact with other
API as such as with Pascola sequel that was not a web API.
It didn't happen on the Internet but they can also happen in the Internet like the Twitter one and the
sequel API encyclopedia 2 came in the form of some Python code that we could use directly inside our
code.
We could just import Sanko OPG too.
And then we could use psycho-BS G-2 as if it were our code only and it was an API that was already written
by somebody else.
And as I said there are also web API.
And these are not Python code psycho-BS youtoo was some Python code we could import and use web API
things are not Python code so that they work with any programming language.
Not only Python for example Twitter is not necessarily written in Python.
It may be written in a bunch of other languages like Ruby Java and so so we cannot import web API directly
into our program and use them because they are not Python code.
So how do you use web API.
Well there's two main types of whether it be eyes and they are called sope be in one of them and rest
being the other.
We're not going to be looking about sope because it is kind of fallen off the radar recently.
Rest is by far the most popular type of API.
And we're going to be looking at rest API.
So let's explain quickly what rest is because this is also something that is not very often understood
rest stands for representational state transfer.
And if you're just starting now with programming as I would expect you to.
You probably have no clue what that means and I don't judge you for that.
Rest is a way of organizing and exposing an API to the outside world.
For example Twitter gives us a way of interacting with Twitter and that is at rest.
API I'll give you a simplified version of what rest is because the original description occupies a chapter
of a Ph.D. dissertation and I'm not going to bore you with all the details.
OK.
So in the Internet we usually have servers and clients so we have a server.
So just Twitter pooter can be a server or it can be running on a server.
And we've got clients for example your computer and when you access Twitter you now can be saved.
You are a client of Twitter because you are accessing Twitter with your computer the server on which
Twitter is running is also a computer like your own only we call it a server because it is kind of serving
Twitter to multiple clients.
That's why we call it a sieve.
There is that line of communication there between your computer and the client and the server.
You can move that up.
So rest specifies that the communication between those two things is a client server interface.
So the rest interface the API is a client server interface which means the API runs on the server your
computer the client communicates with it and asks it for things.
We also see it's stateless.
And what does that mean.
Well it means that the server doesn't know who is who.
In terms of the clients if your computer asks the server something the server just thinks it's a completely
new entity that is accessing the server doesn't remember who you are.
Unlike in a restaurant where the waiter may remember who you are and what you've kind of ordered before
on things like that for example the waiter may make recommendations for food and things like that.
The server does not know who you are by default and what that means is that because the server doesn't
have to keep track of who is who.
A lot of people can make requests at the same time and the server doesn't have to be juggling information
.
It also means for example if you are logged into Twitter every time you ask Twitter for something.
Twitter doesn't know who you are.
So it doesn't know you are logged in unless you tell it that you're logged in.
We're going to look at that later on
it the next thing is that it is cashable.
And what that means is that essentially the server sends the client some information and if the client
requests the same information immediately the response will be the same.
What Let me give you an example.
Say you your client goes to Twitter to the dot com to Telecom then sends you the page to Telecom which
is you cannot log in register to Twitter and things like that.
And then if you refresh the page what the cashable means is that you would expect the page to be identical
.
And what that means is that your client can then cache the web page.
Why is that important.
If your client requests Twitter dot com you get a web page back you have to download the page you have
to download images that are on the page.
You have to download code that makes up the page.
So its slow because you have to download things.
If you refreshed the page and the contents should be exactly the same it means that your computer doesn't
have to download things.
You can just reuse them because it's got them in memory.
That's the cache.
Finally the rest API should be a uniform interface.
And what that means is that your client the computer doesn't have to always communicate with the same
server.
There can be many servers and it doesn't matter which when you communicate with because they are all
the same they are all uniform.
OK.
So that was a bit of theory as to what rest is.
And to remember it is just an interaction between client server is just an interface between a client
or a computer and a server.
And it does things like be stateless.
The server doesn't know who you are.
It is cashable meaning the response should be identical if done immediately again and it is a uniform
interface which means if the server is not just one server but many it doesn't matter which one you
are asking.
That goes well into play with a fire that is stateless.
And it doesn't know who you are because it is a uniform interface.
Your client can then ask any server none of them know who you are.
And that's fine.
OK so what do they look like.
Because all that theory doesn't really have any meaning until you see some examples before looking at
what rest really looks like.
Let me introduce you to hate TDP.
You may not know what hatred's to be is but it is a set of rules we use in our day to day to transfer
data over the internet.
Stands for hypertext transfer protocol and we use it all the time.
Whenever you go on google chrome and you go on our website you were doing a TDP request.
You are asking for a web page using HTP and it looks like that it looks like a verb the version and
then what you're requesting.
In this case the verb is get.
You're asking to retrieve something.
The version is AGP version 2 which is the most recent version.
And finally the Uniform Resource identifier the website you're requesting.
In this case if you use Google Chrome to go to w w w dot API dot example dot com.
Google Chrome is doing this.
Google Chrome is doing get hated to be slashed to w w w dot API or exampled dot com that gets sent to
the server which is hosting w w w dot API for example dot com so the server receives all of this stuff
and says OK this client wants this page here and they want it using get.
So then the server can do something with it.
We don't know what just yet but we're going to look into them.
So is that an API.
No that is what the browser does to as an API.
I rest where API has to be able to respond to that which is what I just mentioned.
So the rest may be and usually look like this.
Let's have a table with a few verbs.
So as we saw get just before.
There's also other verbs like put post and delete when you access a web page using Google Chrome for
example or Safari or Firefox.
What you are doing is at get request.
So say for example you want to access API for example dot com slash.
Use a rest API would interpret this request like so if you use a guest a guest.
Sorry that would tell the API that you most likely want to get a list of users because of the slash
users at the end
if you were to use that put verb it would tell the API to replace the entire collection of users which
is the Slahi users with another collection of users that you are sending as well.
If you use post it would expect you to be sending information to add a new user to the users list or
collection.
And if you send a verb with a delete it would delete the entire user's collection.
So what am I talking about here is the sort of web page that you are accessing.
And depending on the verb that you use the program that is giving you that web page can perform one
of various actions.
This thing here is the API.
It would allow you to interact with the users of API for example dot com but instead of using slashy
users we could do something else like Slash users slash one to three for example if we were accessing
user with identification number one to three and that would.
And if you use get retrieve the user with ID 1 2 3 if you use put replace the user with ID 1 to 3 with
another user or create one if it doesn't exist.
If you use post it's not usually done because you would expect the user to already exist.
If you use delete you would be deleting the user with ID 1 to 3.
Notice that I'm talking about this in a prescriptive manner but it doesn't have to be like that.
Instead of slashy users you could have for example Shlash customers or slash students or slash user
without the apps the API itself defines what these you are Rail's what your eyes look like.
So it doesn't have to be a piano sample or locums slash users.
It can be Twitter dot com slash friends for example of com slash followers.
It can be anything.
What matters here is that you're accessing a specific end point a specific you are ill with a specific
verb and this is what might happen when you do that whether the Twitter API and similarly other replies
will tell you exactly what will happen.
This is only what might happen.
Another example you might want to access some items on.
If the API has the endpoint slash items then here's what might happen.
You could get a list of items you could replace the entire collection of items with another collection
you could add a new item to the items collection.
If you use post or you could delete the entire collection if you use delete.
OK so these are all fairly normal examples of what address API might have.
It might have the user's collection it might have a specific user or that you can access in there.
It might have items similarly could have other things like stores that could have friends.
It could have tweets it could have status updates it could have anything and you could use these verbs
to interact with the API.
If the API allows you to use these verbs so the API has to give you the possibility to for example to
delete which they often don't because it is dangerous and you can delete data.
Let's look at a final example of an endpoint which would be in this case.
Slash auth slash logging what make this end point do.
And normally this endpoint in an API will be called slash or slash logon or maybe slash or maybe slash
off.
It can be called a number of things but it usually does the same thing which is allow you as a user
to log in to the system.
The guest is probably not used and the reason why is probably not used is because in order to log in
to a service you have to send some data to it such as your username and your password.
A get is used to retrieve data so it's probably not used.
In this case because in order to log in we need to send data get is used to retrieve data.
So we're not sending things.
Port is probably not used because it is used to replace things and in this case we don't want to replace
anything we just want to send somebody out and have it do something the normal thing to do when we're
sending Nitta is to use a post and in this case the poster will use it in the request to authenticate
a user.
But remember the server does not know who you are.
So you have to send the data that authenticates you have to send data related to you.
So this is what that data might be.
We can send it is as Jason for example and it could be something like email is email or example dot
com password is 1 2 3 4.
So we could send this data to the server.
And then if the server is programmed to accept data in this format it could verify that and a user with
this e-mail account exists and that the password is correct for it.
Finally delete is probably not used either.
I'm giving you a lot of information in this lecture.
But don't worry about retaining absolutely everything.
We're going to be looking at more examples and we're going to be using the Twitter API over the next
section so we're going to be looking at these a lot more in detail.
Here's some examples of what the Twitter API does give you the examples in the last slide were just
examples of what an API might look like.
In this case we're going to look at specific examples that do exist.
The first the first one is Gantt.
And what you can get is direct underscore messages slash sent dot Jason.
So if you request that Twitter API which is something like API dot dot com then you would expect to
receive back the direct messages that you have sent.
Another endpoint is the friends slash list not Jason.
And once again you would expect to receive back a list of your friends.
Another one is followers slash IDs that Jason.
And here you probably might expect to receive back the IDs the identifiers of your followers.
There's also another one which is search slash tweets dot Jason.
And then at the end you've also got a question mark and then a Q and then as a equals and then he says
computers and filter Colan images.
So what.
What is that.
Well search slash tweets don't Jason.
You probably expect them to be searching among tweets right at the end.
Well you've gone after the question mark.
That's called a query string parameter equidistant parameter can be passed in a get request and they
can give the server some information.
In this case the information we're giving the server is.
Q equals and then the contents of Q Are computers and filter Colan images.
So what that is doing is it's searching for tweets where the tweets contains the word computers and
it has an image.
So that's how we can search tweets using Twitter.
So the Twitter API has a lot of endpoints.
And in this section we're going to be looking at a couple of them just to learn how to interact with
web API.
And that's really important nowadays because we are constantly interacting with where API is whenever
you see a loggin with Twitter but in log in with Facebook logon Google Plus.
Those are all using web API.
Whenever you do things like a request or weather data in your phone that weather data is coming from
a web API whenever you get your e-mail that's coming in from a web API whenever you play a game on your
phone that's interacting with the game servers using web API is where we are everywhere.
It's important that you know how to interact with them and how they work to some extent.
So Twitter authentication that's kind of the focus of this section we're going to be authenticating
with Twitter and allowing users to log in.
Something very common is things like logging with Twitter button and you've got Twitter Facebook Google
and up a bunch of others as well.
And this model of authorization.
The fact that you can press a button and then a few steps that happen after you press the button.
All that is called all off and off is Kanneh a few steps that you have to follow in order to log in
with Twitter Facebook Google et cetera.
We're going to be looking at in this section how to log in with Twitter but you can apply that knowledge
for a number of other providers.
While we learn how to log in with Twitter we're going to be learning about web API how we can interact
with them and in the end we're going to be getting out of this section is a app that will allow us to
retrieve an image gallery from Twitter so we can browse Twitter images like that.
And the learning we're going to be doing is to do with web API use rest off and storing things in databases
once again.
So it's going to be quite jampacked with knowledge.
So I'm excited about it and I'll see you in the next video