Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to look at saving as Jason and to be honest.
Saving as Jason always just feels a lot cleaner to me.
Something I see as V feels a bit 2000s or 90s you know seeing as Jason is is cleaner and it's more structured
and it allows you some greater flexibility gives you more more power.
Let's look at how we could do that.
So first of all I'm going to delete because C as V is from the last century and we don't want that well
that we're probably all from the last century what's in this book you know and we're going to save us
.
Jason instead.
Jason is essentially a python dictionary.
It's a python dictionary that can have lists in it.
So if we were to export the user to Jason we would simply want a dictionary representation of the user
.
So it would be something like.
Name itself that name movies itself that movies.
And I'll tell me this is not cleaner than all the other hassle we had going about with this C S V saving
.
There was a small problem however when we save when we write this to a file itself don't movies is going
to be a list of this stuff when we convert it to a string.
And naturally we don't want that.
It doesn't tell us enough.
We need to be able to save the movie's name Yanar and whether we've watched it or not.
So what I'm going to do here is the movies that I'm going to be saving to a file are going to be movie
don't.
Jason for movie in south movies we've done this before this construct this list comprehension stuff
and we don't need the opening for some black audience right.
But that is what this is going to do is create a list of movie don't Jason for each of the movies in
movie.
So we have two movies.
This list will contain two movie don't Jasen one movie that Jason for the first movie and one movie
got Jason for the second movie.
Naturally movie Jason doesn't exist.
So we have to go and create that.
Let's go to movie and create a Jason method.
And once again this has to be a dictionary representation of the movie name of that name Jano self-taught
genre watched but watched.
And what this does once again just a me with the movie's name with a key name the key genre on the movie
genre the key watched and whether it's been watched on.
And now the user will save the user's name but also the movies.
Jason for each of the movies in self-taught movies.
Let's go back into apt on P Y and create me again and add a couple of movies which are in the Matrix
so I guess I probably get pretty bored of seeing me type this at movie and the end of you comedy and
finally print user Daut.
Jason let's see what comes out of it.
Let's roll it.
And this is what we get.
We get the name which is the user's name and then the movies which is a massive list of movies.
And for each movie we have the dictionary that his movie does Jason with the genre the name and whether
it's been watched on that key thing here that is quite nice the name and the genre are strings as demonstrated
by the quotation marks watched is not a string because Jason supports truthy values supports boolean
values so we can save things directly as true or false.
Which is Quincy's we don't have to worry about converting it later.
Now if wanted to save this to a file.
What we would have to do is open the file and save it or we could use a library which is adjacent library
.
So I'm going to import it.
Jason appear and what I want to do is see Jason dot load.
So I save dump top that's the word dump.
And what I want to dump into is the file pointer.
So with open my file that takes the right mood as if Jason dump and what I want to dump is in F at least
I think that's the way it goes.
I want to dump user Jason my band into APH and let's run that.
And now let's open my father 60 and we got Jason in there.
OK.
So to recap we previewed a user added a couple of movies and then we're going to dump with the adjacent
module the users Jasen into F which f is the file we've opened up here.
And as you guys know I'm going a bit faster now because you guys are getting more acquainted with Python
.
And you have no problem following what I'm doing.
I hope with that said let's move on to the next video where we're going to be looking at Jason daat
load which is going to allow us to read some Jason and then use it to reconstruct our youth.
I'll see you there.