Find Welcome Back in this video we'll look at the format method before we had to add strings together
.
And normally when we Abz things we would expect for example two plus two to give us four.
But when we add two strings together it's not that obvious that they're going to get concatenated and
because it's not that obvious.
I find this to be quite difficult to read.
You have lived for and then you're adding an SDR and then you're adding in some seconds at the end and
you have to really know that this is going to join the strings together.
You have to remember to put the spaces at the end of the first string and at the start of the second
string so that you have spaces between the string and the other strings it's a bit of a faff and somewhat
of a hassle.
So instead of doing this this is actually not what is recommended.
Instead of doing this what we're going to do is we're going to use the format method.
So the format method is great because it simplifies and it makes it just a bit easier to read.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to cut this.
So it's going to get deleted and then I'm going to close that here and then I'm going to do an opening
in closing curly brace opening and closing calibrates inside the string.
So now this is one long string.
You have lived for open and close Culebra use seconds and then what I'm going to do is not format and
I'm going to paste that in.
And this is it's important to count your brackets to make sure you're not missing any brackets this
bracket here is coach with that one.
This placket hagfish with that one.
This bracket here goes without one and therefore we're missing one from the print method.
So important to enter all your brackets and notice how the idealy does highlight what that bracket covers
.
So fantastic.
Not getting any brackets.
So what do you think is going to happen when we run this program.
And the answer would be that you're not going to notice any difference at all.
So let's see if that press function five key to run it.
And I'm going to enter my age 30 which I know my age by the way.
And then we get the you have lived 4 9 4 6 0 8 2000 seconds or so.
And that's pretty much 146 million.
OK.
I'm glad I'm not there yet but I will be.
So not a difference.
So why would you do that.
Well the first reason why we would want to do that is because now just from reading the string you have
lived for something seconds.
We know that this is going to print.
You have four something seconds and this can be replaced for something and that something is whatever
is inside the brackets of the format method.
So this stuff that is inside the brackets is going to then replace the opening and closing calibrates
.
Not only that but the format method can implicitly convert an integer to a string which means that if
you want to replace this by a number the format method will convert that to a string.
And what that means is that we don't need the SDR method anymore.
We can just print the number and then the format method.
We get that and replace it into there.
So I'm going to save that press run and I'll type in age again.
I noticed that that just works.
So that's fabulous.
OK.
So this is how we can use the format method and we can in fact do more with a format method for example
as we saw in a previous with you.
This corresponds to years.
We don't need this because the user has given us the years.
But nevertheless it's something we can do and we can print it out.
So take a wild guess as to how you would make sure that the format method knows to replace this by the
number of years
.
So I think what is reasonable is that we are going to have to give this format method not only the number
of seconds but also the number of years somehow.
So the way you do that is by using the comp.
So the coma and then age and now the format method knows that these two things are separate.
It will replace the first set of curly braces by the first sort of argument or parameter and the second
set of curly braces by the second argument and you can do that more and more times you can add more
curly braces and add more and numbers or strings here and it will just keep replacing them.
So let's say that unpressed EF 5 function 5 to run and then enter your age.
And now we get the usual error which stems from not counting your brackets properly.
Now you go.
We were closing the format method there.
We have a bracket here which closed the form method.
So then the age was not inside the format method.
It was inside the print method and the print method did not know what to do with that age.
So save that and run it again.
And now let's avoid the error and indeed we get.
You have lived for that number of seconds and this corresponds to that number of years.
OK.
So this is how you would use a format method.
And there's actually a lot more you can do with the format method but we're not going to get into it
just at this stage.
Now we're ready to move on into the next section now that we've completed our app.
We are ready to continue developing our python knowledge.
So congratulations we've made the app that converts the user's age into seconds and we've learned about
variables strings numbers printing getting user input and the format method along the way.
So that's fantastic.
And I see you in the very next video and the very next section with a lot more content.