Klein welcome come back in this video we're looking at a recap of classes and we're going to be creating
our User class and making sure that it works.
This is going to be a good video for you to remember what classes are on how to create them and also
have gone in and tried out the font size on the tablet and on my phone to verify that it is big enough
and it seems fine.
So let's go into our user Doppie Y and create our class.
Now I think you will remember how to create a class in Python.
But it was a few sections ago.
So you might have forgotten and that's totally fine.
The way to create a class is just to type class.
And then the class name.
So in my case it's going to be user.
And finally a colon.
If we don't want our class to do anything which in this case we do but if we didn't we can always write
pass in Python.
The past keyword just means do nothing.
For now we're going to be deleting that in a moment.
As you can tell I have made the font a wee That bigger.
Just a couple of points more.
OK the init method in the Klaas's allow us to define the properties that are stored in each object.
So let's define the init method first.
It's death to define a new method and then underscore underscore to seperate underscores remember in
it.
And then two more underscores there as you can see PI Genom also has a suggestion and the suggestion
in this case is correct.
So we're just going to press enter and then it fills the rest for me.
We've also got the keywords self which just means the currently bound object.
We can now look at exactly what that means again in just a couple of moments.
Now we have to decide the properties that a user might have.
So in my case I'm going to go for something simple and each user is going to have an email address a
first name a last name and also a unique identifier an ID and I'm putting it at the end for a specific
reason and I would see that maybe in a few videos time and then what we'll do is self dot email.
This defines the object's property is equal to email and this email is the parameter that the init method
received self first name is first name.
Self-taught last name is last name and after Id is ID.
So as we can see this may sound a bit confusing but what is happening is the parameter that we're passing
the in its method.
This email here is getting assigned to a property of the object called email.
They have the same name but this email is the parameter.
This email is the object property.
OK so this is the Nids method.
It allows us to define the properties of the object and give them some values.
Let's go into our app P Y and create a class of type user so we can remember what that is.
Do you guys remember how to create a class of type user what do we have to do before we can create the
class.
And the answer to that.
I'm sure you got it is to import the user class.
So let's do that from user which is the file user Doppie why import user with a capital U.
Which is the class that we've defined.
I'm going to going to user her so you can verify that user is with a capital U and that should always
be the case.
Classes should always use camel case like so.
At the Capitol the first letter of each word should be capital and then to create the object.
I'm sure you guys know how to do that as well.
We have to define a variable and then give that variable the value of the new object.
I'm sure you got that.
We can create a variable which I'm going to call my underscore user but you know this can be anything
and that is going to be equal to the new user object which we define like so.
What this does is it calls the method and allows you to define the properties.
So these two brackets here you can think of them as these brackets.
Here we have to pass it email first name last name on ID the self keyword is a special keyboard and
we don't need to do anything with it.
So inside these brackets we have to put in email first name last name and ID and as we can see my chum
tells us that we're missing some parameters so let's do that.
We can put in as an email.
My email as a first name my name as a last name my last name and then as an ID we can put one for now
and we're going to see how we should why we should and how we can make this auto incremental in using
sequel.
We've seen how to do that using sequel only now we have to do that with Python as well.
OK.
So this as we know is going to create an object and this string here this hosing at school of Gautami
is going to be passed this value into this e-mail property here and then that same email property the
value of it is going to be assigned to the object's email property.
So self not email that object my user that objects email property should be Jose and school of code
not me.
So let's verify that.
I'm going to print my user don't e-mail.
Notice how is quite nice with the autocomplete.
Now we want to run this and there's a few ways we can do that as we can see there's a place symbol up
there.
But it is grayed out and it doesn't work yet.
That is because pyjama doesn't know that this is a file that we may want to run.
So what to do is right click the file and press run.
Or we can just right click any way and press run and there we have it.
That's the e-mail that we've printed out.
OK.
So now we know that this string is getting passed to this e-mail parameter or argument same thing and
then that's getting assigned to the object's property which also happens to be called the e-mail but
it could be anything else.
OK then I'm going to create the wrapper method that we've seen before as well.
Do you guys remember what this method is for.
What does it do.
And if you don't remember that's fine.
It's a bit of an obscure method not used that often but I like implementing it because it can help you
out a wee bit.
And what this wrapper method does is it allows you to print the object.
So I'm going to do.
Return.
And then it has to return a string a string representation a literal representation of the object and
it can be anything you want but normally a Helps if it does represent the object.
So I'm going to type user so that when we print the object we know that it's a user object.
And then I'm going to use the format to type and open and close curly braces close the crocodile clip
and then dot format.
Self-taught email.
I tend to get this question that people ask in My students ask why do you put these crocodile clips
in there.
And the reason is because I like it they don't have to be there you can delete them if you want.
That's totally fine.
They are not required.
They are simply there as literal characters.
So they are not necessary unlike these opening and closing braces.
These two are necessary because the self the email the value is going to be replacing them.
So those two unnecessary The Caracal Eclipse are not they're just there for aesthetic purposes.
Basically I like seeing this because it tells me this is an object that I've printed out.
OK.
Now instead of print my use or email we can just print my user and let's run that.
And as you can see we get those clips printed out alongside the user and the email.
If we don't put the wrapper method and we run this what we get is something maybe not as interesting
.
We get that type of the thing with printed out user dot user object and we get the memory address at
which it is defined.
Not very useful.
So that's why I like this.
It gives me something at least that I can work with.
So this is a short recap on classes and what they are.
And at this point what we've seen is that they can be a store of data and we can name the properties
that are in the class whatever we want.
So it's useful to store data in this case related to our users.
We can create a variable called my user and it store some properties and the variable can have names
for those properties which in this case are email first name last name and ID.
So it's useful to store things.
And if we wanted to create another user with different details then we could do that too.
However it can also do more things.
And we're going to be looking at that in the next few videos.
And some of those things are methods that declasse the objects can have and can perform.
So let's look at that in the next few videos and see you in the next one.