Hi We'll come back in this video we're going to be looking at creating users in the last section.
We actually looked at the same thing.
We created users and we saved them to the database.
Now what we want to do is make sure that when the user authorizes us to use their Twitter account that
we save the access token that means both the auth token and the off token secret because we need them
both to create this token and we need that token to create the client and that client is the one that
can do the requests.
It's actually not that complicated.
We've got the code from the last section on creating user objects and saving them to database.
I don't know if you recall things like connection from database from pool Asare cursor from connection
from pool.
We also created things like database class which is the connection pool.
We created user object and we saved them to the database.
We did all those things but those users that we were saving to the database only had an email first
name and a last name.
Now we want to make sure that we're saving a password and auth token and then off tokens secret.
So really it's exactly the same code as we wrote in the last section only that we're going to be saving
a couple more things to the database instead.
So let's go back to the code that we wrote in the last section which I've got on my screen but I'm going
to be paste in here and going over it again just for your convenience.
So let's go over that to that code that we wrote in the last section and import it into this project
.
I'm imported meaning copy and paste.
And when I right click the project and go to a new python file and create a database copy why file.
And here I'm going to be pasting the code we wrote in the last section and quickly going over it again
.
So I don't know if you remember this stuff but we wrote a class database that have a connection pool
and then we could initialize that database in a class method and that created a simple connection pool
and then we could get connections from the pool and put them back in and we could also close all the
connections and we also have a cursor from collection from pool class that was essentially a cursor
which would allow us to retrieve or insert data into Pascua sequel and they would return the connection
back to the pool or get a connection from the pool.
When we use it naturally in order to be able to use this we need psych OPG too.
So let's go to our requirements not the XTi file and put in Psycho puji to remember if you are in Windows
you need to go and use the installer.
As we learned in the last section and put that installer on your virtual environment or you can just
use the same virtual environment for your last project as you do in for this one.
You can always change your virtual environment by going to patch on preferences and not there but when
the interpreter selects the virtual environments are you created in the last section so it would be
this one intro to databases you can select the same virtual environment and that won't affect your code
.
It will just affect the libraries installed in the virtual environment which means you'll be able to
use like OPG to if you installed it on that virtual environment and you do not want to go through the
pain again.
If you are on Mac or Linux however the only thing you have to do is write it in your requirements text
textfile and then install the requirement here.
Remember you can only do that on Mac or Linux not on Windows.
And naturally config executable not found.
So we are going to need to go to a terminal and as you remember from the last section there is a way
to do this which is export path equals Dola path then library and Pasko there sequel 9.5 bin.
And then we should be able to go into the virtual environment which is in documents personal courses
Python polocrosse with a log in virtual environment and do been Pipp install Cyclopedia too and that
should work.
So what I've done there is just gone over again.
What we did to install Cyclopedia 2 in the last section of this command here we went over in the last
section export path equals Dollar path and then told them to just go back to
you export paff equals dollar path colon and then the location of your Pasqua sequel bin folder which
should be if you use the default in slash library slash Potter sequel slash 9.5 slash bin and then you
can go into the do CD and then the folder in which your project is.
And then you can just do and been slash Pip installs like OPG too.
And that should do it.
But again if you do have any problems which refer back to the video in the last section where we installed
it on Mac that should solve all the problems.
OK now that we have an psychobilly to installed we are able to import it inside our database file and
that's the pool that we were creating there.
And now we can also right click the project and create a new Phyton file which we're going to call a
user and once again I'm going to go back and copy from the other project.
So let me do that
then we go.
If you remember this was about we know that this was what we had in the last project we had
import curso from collection from pool and then we created a class user in the unit method we specified
that email first name last name and the ID which would be none.
Initially we would be able to save the database and here we would insert into the users table email
first name and last name and then the dollar so the percent as would get replaced by the properties
in this table.
And the idea would be auto incremental because we defined it that way in Passaro sequel.
And similarly here in the load from D-B by email we would execute this select where we would retrieve
a user with an email who would fetch one and then we would create a user object with that.
OK so now we want to do a few more things instead of e-mail first name and last name and ID.
We also want to pass in an off token and an off token secret so auth token and auth token secret which
means we also have to initialize them here
like so we're just creating the properties or token and author can secret inside the user objects that
we are initializing in this method in the same to D-B We're also going to want to insert
these two values there inside the brackets that specifies the columns that were inserting values into
.
We're going to want to put 2 percent Essie's there at the end for those columns and also the parameters
should include as well as e-mail first name a last name.
Also the new properties self-taught auth token and self-taught or and secret.
So now what we've changed is simply added two more columns to more parameters and two more properties
there.
So we're going to insert those when we saved to D-B in the load from.
We're also going to want to get the ortho can an ortho can secret.
So here we are creating and an object of type user and we're passing in data from this row that we selected
here and the data we're passing in is the first column for e-mail.
Second column for first name third column for last name and the fourth column is going to be Ortho-K
.
And the fifth column is going to be Ortho-K and secret.
So we're going to do here is auth token equals user unschool data for.
And you can see I'm very well off token secret equals user underscore data 5.
And then remember that common as well you can always just type enter and that's totally fine in Python
.
And I'm just going to make it a bit nicer to read.
OK so now we have the ability to save the user including those new properties that we have requested
from Twitter.
What we don't have right now is a password but we want to worry about that just after we managed to
work with this.
So what we want to do now and what I would encourage you to try on your own is just as we did in the
last section where we created the user object and we saved it to the database go and delete your possible
sequel Users table recreate it with these columns.
Then make sure the make the ID column comes in first so Id email first name last name or token or token
secret should be in that order and then go and after the log in create a user object with an email you
can ask the user for an email using the input command and save that to the database.
It's a bit of a longer problem but I would encourage you really would to try that on your own and then
come back and continue with this.
Okay now that that's done we're ready to move onto the next video is really getting a bit long.
We're going to be solving that problem.
We're going to be creating the new the new table with the new columns and saving the users in there
and making sure that the user doesn't have to reauthorize every time they want to use an app I see in
the next video.