Hi will come back in this video we're going to be loading from an adjacent file.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to work the other way around.
I'm going to first define what my laptop is going to do and then I'm going to implement the methods
in user and movie to match that we've got my file that takes the.
Which has the Jesus that we want to load.
So I'm going to change this.
OPEN TO BE IN read mode which is going to then allow me to read the file.
Now if the file pointer to a file that can be read because we were using read more than me the Jason
rende the data that we're reading in which is now a dictionary when we load it is going to be Jasen
don't load F and Jason data is now a python dictionary.
I'm going to go into my follow to actually look at how we're watched in the movie is false.
With a lowercase f.
When we load it that's going to be Python false with the uppercase f it's going to be proper boolean
stuff.
So we're no longer dealing with big strings and CACs.
Now we've got a better data structure in the background dealing with this stuff.
So we've got a python dictionary there.
And now what I'm going to do is say user from Jason Jason Day and I'm going to see user is that
OK.
So let's create that method that's going to use up and create the from Jason method from GX.
Now I think you guys are able to actually complete this fully.
I don't think you need my help at all because what we have to do now is get the Jason data that is a
dictionary and we can access things like Jason data name because you know this is a dictionary.
This is how we access things in a dictionary.
If we go into my father 60 you know that name is somewhere in here there of the end also as an aside
remember Jason is not ordered.
So the name can be at the end or it can be at the beginning.
It doesn't matter because this is a set a set of key value pairs and remember sets are an ordered.
So we've got the name there and we've got Jose.
So if we go into our user Jason Deighton name we'll give you Jose.
So now you can make this a class method you can load up and create a new user give it to the username
from Jackson data and you can do the same with movies.
I would recommend giving yourself a few minutes and actually doing this.
Convert this to a class method.
Use decent data to create the user and the movies.
Put the movies in the User object and then return that to be honest I think you can do all that if you
give yourself some time pause a video and go for it because by doing will be the best way to learn.
Now hopefully you've attempted that and I'm sure you've succeeded.
I'm going to make this into a class method and I'm going to call this CLX because that's the standard
.
And what I'm going to do is say user is user Jason data name.
And then the movies are going to be an empty list for more for movie in self Tom not of the movies my
.
Jason Dade adult movies isn't the movies.
I'm going to say movies not Penn movie and the movie details are in this movie dictionary.
We are iterating over.
Jason Chordata movies which is here and it's a list.
So when we read off the list each of the elements in the list is a dictionary.
So are we going to get that dictionary and then we're going to get this dictionary which tells us that
movie's going to be a dictionary that has the details that we saved the genre watched.
I mean so this is going to be movie movie name movie Shannara movie watched.
And we don't have to do any Boullion conversion because that's already a.
Finally user Daut movie is movies return user
and I'm sure you got that as well.
Just read over the movies penned each movie.
Object to that list and then send that to me the use of movies and finally return user.
Let's go back into our app and print you said Jason because that's going to give us everything we need
to verify that it worked.
Let's press play and there we have it.
Movies.
And then the name of the end doesn't matter whether name is let's However improve this a wee bit something
I don't like is the fact that I have to instantiate the movie object inside of user inside user.
Instantiating a movie object and you won't feel this way yet because of lack of experience but to me
that just feels a bit like the bit wrong.
It feels like the users shouldn't really be creating movie objects that it's loaded from a file.
I think the movie should have a from Jason method as well and that should be used to load up the movie
from Hajis.
So I'm going to go into that.
I'm going to go into a movie.
My class movie and create a class method which is going to be from Jason that except some Jason data
and what it returns is a movie with Jason data name Jason data John-Roger and Giese and data watched
assuming that Jason data has the right keys.
Naturally then we go back to our user what we are pained to this movie's list is movie don't from Jason
movie and this movie remember is a dictionary.
I'm going to rename movie just so it's a bit clearer by pressing shift f six shift an F six Let's me
rename something.
Movie date.
And that gets renamed in both places.
So where we are spending now is movie from Jason which creates the movie object but we don't create
it here in the user which looks a bit ugly.
Instead we're telling the movie see how you can deal with it Jason yourself and the good thing about
that is if we do then and more properties of the movie and we change the Jason method we change the
from Jason method then this bit will work here.
The user is not concerned with what properties are in a movie it's just concerned with calling from
Jason if we want to make changes to the properties of a movie.
We have to make the changes in this file and not in the user file.
And that's always a good thing.
With that said I know that this was also a long way to you but it was essential to make sure that there
was an explanation of the complete flow of loading from a Jason File.
What we're going to be looking at in the next video is argument unpacking which is exciting and also
it's a bit confusing.
So I don't want to put it in this video which means I'll see you in the next one