Hi welcome back in this video we're looking at argument unpacking and that's the last thing we're going
to look at in the sort of Jason loading and saving series argument I'm backing is just going to make
your life slightly easier.
And that's really all it's going to do.
Let's talk about before argument on unpacking named parameters in Python.
This is the way we've been looking at passing parameters is we've got the movie object here with the
movie class where initialising and then the name genre and watched the first three parameters to the
init method.
And therefore Jason data name matches the name Jason did a genre it matches the genre.
They'd have watched matches that watched.
They are in order and that make sense.
They should be but they don't have to be.
They could be not in order.
And then you'll see what how he's going to know Python which is which.
And that's when named comes in we could say genre equals Jason data genre watched equals Giese and they
watched name equals cheese and data watched so name rather.
This is totally valid as well.
And that is interesting because it means that with the name Python doesn't need an order it means that
if we give names to everything they can be on order.
Similarly we can also not give names to some.
You can do this as well.
The first one is ordered is the name.
The second one has a name so it goes to that one.
And the third one has a name for that one.
So you cannot do is skip the name in a parameter after a name.
So if you have a named parameter you cannot have a non name parameter after we have a named parameter
.
All parameters after it have to be named as well.
So what I was getting at before is there is no longer a need for order.
If we give names and this is where argument unpacking comes into play we have a dictionary of data and
this data is isn't the format
name is some name genre is some Anjana watched is true for example.
And what I'm telling you is if we give these parameters their names in the method call we don't care
about the order and that's important because as you know dictionaries do not have to be ordered.
So potentially the genre could be first and then we could have the name.
And so so what I'm going to do is with the simple command which is called argument and unpacking is
unpack this dictionary into a set of named parameters.
So what I'm going to do is instead of name equals name watch the quolls watched John Rickles genre.
Sorry about that.
I'm going to say asterisk asterisk Jason data and what that does is it says OK you want me to pass this
dictionary as a set of named parameters.
So what I'm going to do is say the first parameter a genre equals the content.
Second parameter is name equals the Condon's.
The third parameter is watched equal to the contents and that is the same as before.
It works well that allows us to do is pass data that is a dictionary but allows us to pass it as a set
of named parameters which is you can see makes your life easier because this less to type and that is
good.
OK.
Thats everything for this video.
I'm sure you are extremely disappointed.
You probably felt this was going to be something really exciting but it is it is exciting because it
now means that if we make a change to the properties of movie we only have to make the change in here
and we no longer have to worry about this code down here which is great and it also means a few more
things that we will get into as the course progresses.
Which are all very exciting and it's really important this in python you will encounter these two asterisks
countless times when you look in the Python code.
So it's important that you know what it means because a lot of people don't.
So that's what it means.
It's a dictionary that you're passing as a set of named parameters.
Now with that said let's move on to the next video.
We're going to be creating the menu for our app.
So I'll see you there.