Hi and welcome back in this video we're looking at loading data from postscripts using psycho OPG to
we've looked at saving data.
And the way we did that was using with psychopathy to connect passing in the details of our connection
.
Amazing ass connection and what that did was initiate a new variable create a variable called Connection
give it to the content of psycho-BS you connect and then we use that to open a Carcer which would allow
us to then execute sequel and insert our data in.
We also looked at what the with statement does.
And in both of these cases where the with statement does is it closes and commits the appropriate things
to the database at the end of the with clause.
So the with clause for the cursor is this one.
And at the end of it that closes the cursor the with clause for the connection is all of this.
And at the end of it it commits to disk.
It saves the data to the disk that was interacted with in that connection and then inclosures that connection
too.
In this video as I said we're looking at loading from postscripts.
But before we can do that we need to look into a new type of method which is the class method.
These seem to be wrapper and init methods all share something in common.
As I'm sure you realize and that's the self self self self what is that.
We've kind of looked at self and I've explained what self is.
And I appreciate it will take a long time until it really clicks with you if you're only just starting
programming.
It certainly takes a long time when you're starting about the average I think it's between six to 10
months for it to really click in to what these things all are.
So if it doesn't get don't worry.
But what the self is and I'll just say it again is the currently bound object.
When you run a method so I'm going to go into my app and then I've created an object called my user
and that type is user.
And I've passed that in some variables when I run my user don't seem to be really what this is doing
is it's doing something like this user don't save to be my user.
So that was going on there.
My user is the self parameter.
So when we run the method using my user Daut safe to D-B this thing that is calling the method IIS passed
in as the first parameter.
Even though it's not inside the brackets.
So this is happening.
My user is self and then this is identical us doing my user Daut e-mail except my user is not defined
in this file so we don't have access to it.
Usually when I'm going my user is passed in as self.
So whenever we run a method that uses self it modifies my user.
So that's why if we say my user don't e-mail is something else then my user of see if the D-B has access
to that new e-mail.
We've changed the property of my user and that is what is passed to save to TB.
OK long winded way of saying it doesn't have to be like that.
What I'm going to do now is define a class method and a class method doesn't access the currently bound
object
.
So what I'm going to do now is create the method load from DBI by email.
And notice how pyjama smartly replaces self with CLX which is the standard name for class methods.
So take a wild guess wild guess.
I mean really wild if self normally is the currently bound object.
What do you think CLX is inside this method.
Take a moment to think about because it is a logical thing to be.
And the answer to that and I gave you a few moments to think about it.
CLX itself is normally the currently bound object CLX is the currently bound Plass a.k.a. a user.
OK.
We're going to use a CLX in this method and that is going to be if we do less.
And then for example
not it's Then remember this can be anything.
It doesn't have to be my name I'll just change it just for you sakes.
This line here is exactly the same as this one here except it naturally creates a different object with
different properties.
But we could still assign it to a variable.
CLX is the currently bound class which makes it user.
Those two things are the same.
Ok so now we know that CLSA is user.
So let's load from the database.
What do you think is the first step for me to load from the database.
Remember when we save we connected and then we open the cursor and then we Ransom's equal and then we
closed the cursor and then we close the connection.
That's what it with does.
So what do you think I should do to load from the database.
I'm sure you got it.
The first step is to open up the connection once again.
So I'm going to copy and as you may guess the next step is to create a cursor.
And as you may guess the next step is to execute some code.
And now what we want to execute is not an insert but rather he selects because we want to retrieve some
data.
Select start from users and I'm loading from D-B by email.
So I want to filter by the email.
Do you remember how to perform a filter using sequel.
I'm sure you do.
It is way e-mail.
Equal percent S and that percent as of now is going to get replaced by the parameters that we pass in
as the second argument to the execute method and the execute method.
These are the brackets for it.
The string here and the query is the first parameter and after we have to put in the second parameter
which is a set of arguments to pass to the query and the only thing we want to hear is that email
Bhagwat email.
Naturally in a class method we don't have self.
So unfortunately we can't do self-taught email and also by the time that we want to load from the database
we want to load.
So we can create an object which means we don't have self-dual email we don't know what that is.
So what to do is pass in the email as a parameter.
And we're going to look at how to do that in just a moment.
However that is a key thing here and that can be a huge headache if you don't realize it.
And if we hover over email in page it tells us remove redundant parentheses but they do have parentheses
up here.
So there's the set of parameters has parentheses around it and it doesn't say to remove them but it
tells us here and that is because Python thinks these parentheses are like the parentheses you would
use in a maths equation you know like if you do five plus five times two this would be ten plus five
right.
The multiplication runs first and Python by default things these parentheses are a rule like this you
know five plus five times two.
So these are like giving priority to the email and it tells you you know you don't have to give priority
to the email here because that doesn't make any sense and they're right it doesn't.
Well we want to do with these parentheses is defining topple and I'm not sure if we've looked at this
before.
But a couple something like
one two three four five six.
This is a table.
It is identical to a list essentially.
So the table uses normal brackets the least use a square brackets.
We've looked at lists before and we've not I don't know if we've looked at doubles but I'll just explain
it anyway.
The table is exactly like a list except you cannot change.
You cannot add new elements to it.
So it is essentially an immutable list.
So you think that these are four priority.
So we have to put a comma a b and to tell it that this is a table and that's it.
And if you didn't know that this would never work and you would never know why
so now we have to read this cursor to execute this statement.
And because it's a cursor what it does is it stores the result in the cursor.
Think of it as a table.
And I'm going to just go over to pgm and 3.
Think of it as it's retrieving this table here and the cursor is starting just above the first row.
And now we can ask it to give us the first row or potentially give us all the rows and then we can do
that with a method inside cursor.
So what we're going to do is say user data is cursor don't fetch one and that fetches the first row
.
We're assuming that email is going to be somewhat unique.
So fetch one should give us that the only user with that email because they should only be one.
And finally we can do return CLX And here's where we're going to be returning a new object of type user
which is currently bound CLOS using the data in the row as you know the email is not the first column
but the email is the second column the first name is the third column and the last name is the last
and fourth column.
So email equals use underscore data 1.
The second column where I'm going to starts at zero.
First name equals use an underscore data to last name equals use or underscore data 3 and the ID equals
use or underscore to zero the first column.
You may be asking why are you putting this stuff in there and I don't have to be you know we can delete
that if we want.
All that's doing is it's allowing me some more readability.
So this is simply going to say call the user class which is the current class for this method and past
user data one which is the the second column into email.
The third column in into first name the fourth column in the last name and the law the first column
into ID and then that's going to populate my object and it's going to return a new object with this
date.
And if I do this as I am again I'm not sure if we've looked at this but it does exactly the same thing
.
But now we can put it in the wrong order if we want.
Just to not confuse Python the default.
Put them in order.
But if we name them if we give them name and parameters then we can put it out of order.
It's not a very nice thing to do.
It doesn't make sense.
So don't do that.
And that's it.
Now we are able to load from the database.
After that the cursor gets closed and after that the connection gets closed so we can go into an app
and am going to first of all go into puji admin 3 and am going to open up and the sequel editor when
I select staff from users and I'm going to delete everything that's not with ID 1.
You don't have to do this but there are a lot of duplicate data here.
It makes sense to delete from users where Id is not one.
And that just deletes everything except the ID one.
Do notice the next user that gets entered is going to be id 6 because the sequence does not reset.
OK.
And then what we're going to do is instead of defining a variable like so we're going to do my usual
equals user don't load from DB by email and then we're going to give it the email that we want to load
and then we're going to print my user
and then we're going to run it and then we're going to get a user with that e-mail.
And now that is great because you are now able to understand how to connect to Pasqua sequel using psychopathy
to how to insert data and how to retrieve data and that's really the most important thing you could
do.
Essentially anything you want in now really you can create an application that allows your users to
enter data and then you can retrieve it to perform calculations with it such as calculating averages
doing something like our student system would be superbly easy and using sequel you could even use views
that you've programmed into your sequel as we've looked at before.
There are really countless things you could do and all that stems from this flexibility that sequel
gives you you don't have to know a lot of Python.
The only thing you need to know is how to connect how to open a cursor and how to execute some stuff
and the stuff that you're executing a sequel which gives you the freedom to run a lot of these things
.
In the sequel side of things as opposed to in your Python code and that really just relieves you from
a lot of the work.
So with that said you now have learned a lot of stuff about retrieving data using the cursors to fetch
one robot we're going to look at fetching more rows and we've reviewed the named parameters we've reviewed
.
We've looked at tuples we've looked at Cillessen class methods and really we are just learning loads
of Python right now and all of these things you can apply in other areas too.
Let's continue though.
There are a few problems with this app and we are going to be looking at those over the next few videos
.
I'll see you there.