Hi welcome back in this video we're looking just a bit more at lambdas and I've called it all Ramdas
in the wild and I'm not intending to be funny with that.
This is something that I have written for my work.
So this is something that you will potentially see in the wild when you're working in the industry.
It's not an example that is simplified for you.
This is something that is actually done.
So that's it.
Yeah I just wanted to for you to look at a real example.
So what I've done is I've got my class currency am that we created in an earlier video and I filled
in the built in methods for greater than less than less than or equal to greater than or equal to.
So hopefully you also were able to do this in the couple of years ago.
And what we're going to be doing now is stay away from essentially just looking at using the currency
class and we are going to be using lambda functions together with a currency class now
in order to look at some more advanced lambda functions we need to use a bit of imagination.
Let's imagine that the currency data such as the code and the exchange rates are we are retrieving them
via an API application programming interface that we've looked at previously such as a rest API for
example.
So the first thing I'm going to do here is I'm going to create a method called Get currency resource
and I'm going to it's going to have two parameters a resource on a transform the transform is going
to be lambda Lumba x x.
Please bear with me just for a moment.
Why do this.
Now imagine we are retrieving currency data from an API.
So imagine we're doing requests Gatz blah blah blah blah the dot.
Jason and we are retrieving currency data where it's moving things like currency codes and currency
exchange rates so much so that we're ending with something that looks like this.
Items like items is a list of items where we have a code which can be something like USV and an amount
to USD which can be something like 1.0 for us these
GBP EU our GP Y and GBP one point twenty one that is 0.07.
This is 0.14.
I don't really know the exchange rate so please bear with me.
OK this is the part where we need imagination.
Imagine we are retrieving this data.
This Jason data from an API somewhere on the Internet and we have to use imagination because I don't
want to confuse you further by actually going to an API and retrieving it and all that.
So just imagine we are getting this from an API somewhere on the Internet and what it returns is a dictionary
a Jason an object with the key items.
And each of the items is in a list where the item itself is another dictionary with a code and an amount
to USD.
The code is USD.
In this instance there's the value and the amount is at one point.
Oh because USD 2 USD is worth exactly 1.
Then we have another code which is TBP and the amount of us is one point twenty one and so on.
So we've got here four different currencies that we've retrieved from a web API somewhere on the Internet
but we are not concerned with how that happened.
OK.
And that's where we need imagination.
Now what I'm going to be doing is I'm going to say that my resource is data resource.
So I'm going to be accessing the data that we retrieved from the API.
I'm going to be accessing specifically one of the elements of that dictionary which is going to be the
resource parameter.
So that could be for example items.
And then what I'm going to do is I'm going to return another list x for x in my resource.
If we do x for x in my resource we are retrieving all of the elements inside my resource as we know
we're just creating a new list and putting those elements in there.
And presumably if we call something like
this with items there what this will do it'll say items so doesn't go into resource then down here my
research will be data items which will be this list and then we will return x for x in my resource.
So we will return each of these dictionaries do take a moment to pause now and make sure that your understanding
where this is coming from what is going on.
And if you don't please do pause the video ask a question in the course forums.
So what about this transform.
What does it do.
Well here's the more interesting bit.
Instead of doing if transform X what we're going to do is transform X..
In the beginning.
So we're not going to put each of the elements in my resource into my new list.
We're going to put a transformed version of the element into the new list.
So we're not necessarily going to put only the entire dictionary.
We can change it by using the transform function
.
However the transform function has a default value which is lambda x is x.
This lambda function essentially does nothing.
It's the sort of unit lambda function.
It doesn't change anything.
It just returns X and gets a parameter x and it returns that.
So transform X with this lambda function will leave it unchanged.
OK let's press play so you can see where we're going am now abound.
Am I run the wrong file.
So there we go.
Took me a while to figure that out.
What we've got here is a list of dictionaries where each of the dictionaries is what we see in here
.
As you can see the first one is us the and I'm onto you with each one.
This first dictionary here is also us the the amount to us to use one.
And so on.
So as you can see we've left the list of dictionaries unchanged because we're using this lambda function
there.
OK.
Whether we can pass in a different lambda function that does something else.
For example lambda x is x code dot Upper the dot upper method converts a string to uppercase.
So it just makes it all caps.
So now when we get the first X this thing here what we're going to return is not X which is the entire
thing we're going to return X code which is USD to uppercase.
Show us the in upper case then we're going to go on to the next X and we're going to get the code.
And then we're going to convert that we're Paki's.
And then you are to uppercase JPY 2.
That's Pressplay ones.
Now we see that instead of the data that we retrieve from the API we have a set of currency codes.
Why is that interesting.
Well because now we can do def get currency codes and this can be this thing.
So instead of being dependent on getting the data and then returning it we can change it and get what
we want from it's using lambda functions instead.
As you can see they get currency codes method doesn't need to retrieve things from an API doesn't need
to know about the data.
It just needs to know that data is coming from there's not currently a resource but we can transform
it using this lambda function.
And now the get currency code method just returns a list of the available currency code in this API
.
OK.
Something else that it can also be interesting.
Let's get instead of the currency codes Let's get currency objects back.
Remember the currency object is up here and it has a code and an amount to exchange the USD that amounts
to USD is the same as this one here.
So what we want with this get currencies method is to get a list of objects where each object uses the
code and the amount of USD to be initialized.
Remember a currency takes in something like USD and like 1.0.
This is how you create a currency object.
So what I want you to do is to return get currents.
I've been making this mistake for the entire video come believe it and let's rename this to make sure
it is not incorrect.
Get currency resource madman where items is there and the lambda function is going to return a currency
object as opposed to a specific element of that dictionary.
Pause the video and give that a go.
Create the currency object from that date.
I'm sure you got it.
The way to do that is to create the currency object with X code and X amount to USD.
Now the code becomes the first parameter to the init method and the amount of USD becomes the second
parameter to the init method which as you can see is up here and is what we need
.
So now get currencies returns a list of objects.
Let's run this file as you can see we get currency objects now as opposed to dictionaries.
And why is this useful.
Well now that we have the currencies we can do things with those currencies that we couldn't do just
with data.
For example convert money to different currencies.
Let's create yet another method this is going to be the final one.
By the way that we don't know that it's going to let us calculate dollar amount in all currencies available
to us
.
How do you think this should be done.
I want to iterate over each of the currencies converting this USD amount to dollars using these two
USD method.
Give that I go.
I recommend posting the video and giving it a go.
But make sure to try hard and engage with it as that's the best way to learn.
I keep saying that but it's just true.
Hopefully you got that what I'm going to do is print
no format.
Use the amount.
All that is going to do is just print a line saying for example $1000 dollars in all currencies and
then for currency in get currencies which is as we know a list of objects we're going to print in a
specific currency that amount format currency to code currency.
Don't to us the U.S. the amount.
So what this does is it prints out that in GBP It is eight 800 and something dollars pounds rather.
OK let's run that and see what happens here.
Well we have one thousand USD and all currencies is incorrect numbers by the way.
I made a small mistake in USD 1000 which seems correct in GBP 12 and 10.
This is not correct in euros ten thousand 1070 and Japanese yen one hundred forty.
So what we've done here is we've converted.
We've treated the USD amount as one thousand pounds 1000 euros 1000 yen.
But if you can realize that.
But 1000 pounds converted to dollars is twelve hundred and ten one thousand euros converted of dollars
is one thousand seventy.
So what we want to do is in the US the I suppose to share in USD in currency sorry as opposed to 2 USD
.
That wrong method used.
Let's run that again.
And now we get the correct numbers there.
So in pounds we get a hundred twenty six.
And so something to note is that there is a lot of numbers after the decimal place.
But we can change that.
This second set of curly braces is being replaced by the float the number of decimal places when that
is the case.
We can do this poll on dot to F and then when we print out it will always be to two decimal places that
were the two means we continue to five if we want for example just a bit of a hint there.
But the formats and method has a long list of the things you can do with it which has more information
.
OK and so this is everything for this video.
I wanted to show you a real example of something that I have done at work not with currency objects
but with something similar where you can use lambda functions and transforming values to simplify your
code and get things out more easily.
Here we have an API call with some imagination which returns some data but we can modify the data as
we go by using lambda functions.
Something to remember is that just as before we have the filter method which allowed us to filter out
of some values in Python We also have the map method.
So the map method does exactly the same thing as this does.
It essentially transforms each of the values in my resource and then returns a list with that.
So this thing here this list map transfer my resource is identical to this list comprehension once again
in Python you normally use a list comprehension but if you're working with people from different backgrounds
who prefer to use the more standard map and filter do use that as that is fine as well.
Well that's everything for this video or hopefully you want to board and hopefully you didn't have to
use too much imagination.
Remember this was meant to be an API call something you get from the Internet and we've looked at a
real example of using lambda functions and transforms to on the fly modify the data that we are retrieving
from a method.
So hopefully you learn something every enjoy that and obscene you in the very next video.