Hi welcome back in with you we are implementing the stack assignment.
I do hope that you've given it a go.
Downloaded the files and tried to implement it yourselves.
That is the best way to learn.
Watching the videos only is not going to make you the best programmer in the world but programming will
.
But now you're here.
Let's go ahead and implement the linked list section off the stack and then we're going to go over and
implement the stack as well.
The first thing to do is to make sure that we can add at the start of the list so we can reuse the method
we implemented previously.
So let's do that.
If the route is defined then the new nodes next node to be the route and finally set the root equal
to be the new node.
We know that this just puts the new node in the middle between the sort of linked list entity and the
root.
So it essentially creates a new route and puts it at the beginning.
Then let's go over to the find method that's implement the new node the new method.
At the end marker is the root and we know that.
And while the marker has a value if the markers text is equal to the text that we're looking for then
we're going to return it.
And if not we're going to say marker equals marker again next.
And finally at the end if we exit the while loop without returning anything means that we didn't find
what we're looking for and the node with text that was not found in the linked list and we can format
the text like that.
I'm going quite quickly because I'm sure that you already have seen this a few times.
So there's no need to go too slowly.
All we're doing there is iterating over trying to find the text in a specific node returning that node
if it is found or raising an error if it's not found the size method is just going to return a count
of notes actually.
So let's create the marker which is the initial root and the count which is zero.
And while the marker has a value increase the count and then also move over to the next node.
Finally return the count at the end which is the number of nodes in this list.
Remember this is only the list and not the stack.
For now the stack is going to be implemented going to be implementing a wrapper around this list.
Finally the removed start from list it has to if the route is none Rayson error.
Then if it is not in create a variable which stores the root sense self the root to be equal to self-taught
roots next node and return the variable created previously.
It's going to be a shorter method and hopefully you were able to implement this given it a bit of thought
about how to implement the removal from the start.
The first thing to do if the nude if the route is not set so if not self not route we're going to raise
a runtime error because it doesn't really fit in any of the other built in arrows trying to remove from
the list.
But it was already empty.
If we do not raise the error that means the root has a value because we've not gone into this if statement
.
And if that is the case what we want to do is remove the root so the removed note is going to be the
root that's going to be just a new variable created there.
To which we assign the root.
And then we say self don't root equals itself don't root.
Don't get next.
And that sense this variable up there to be the current routes next node.
Remember we've not deleted anything yet until we execute this line but we still have the old root stored
inside this variable.
Remove node so we can return that and that is going to be removing the note.
Another option instead of raising an arrow would be to return None of that could work just as well.
In Python it is quite common to raise errors when things don't quite go as expected.
And in a remove start from least we expect to remove a node.
That is why an error does make sense in this scenario.
The expected outcome which is to remove a..
Didn't happen because the list was empty.
So in that case I ever kind of did happen returning none would be an option.
Without dealing with errors but the error also makes sense.
Next let's go over to the links stack the All we have to do here is the wrapper around the linked list
.
As you know the push method just has to add at the start and we're going to add this node that we're
passing in as a parameter to the push method.
The pop method.
All they have to do is remove them from the start but remember to return the node.
And finally the.
All he has to do is return the size of the linked list and that's it really that's everything for the
stack is quite a short one.
And what to do once we have done all this is to run the tests and make sure that you get all nine tests
passed.
If you don't I recommend you go ahead and look at the tests.
Look at the code verify it think it through as if you were the computer and if you still can figure
it out do go ahead and ask the questions in the course Q and A.
And as always I'm there to help.
So please do ask questions.
Don't don't keep it to yourselves.
And be stuck because it just doesn't make sense really.
I'm here to help.
So might as well use that power that you've got to ask all the questions you need.
And I'm always there for your convenience but that's it for this video.
We've now implemented the stack and I went quite quickly through this one because there is not much
difference between this one and the queue.
I don't really want to waste much of your time and in the next set of videos we're going to be implementing
a binary tree.
We're going to be looking at what a binary tree is and that is the last data structure we're going to
be looking at.
And it's also the only non linear data structure we're going to be looking at in this course.
And there's also a bit more complicated so please go ahead into the next few videos.
We're going to be implementing that.
Hope you're not too bored of data structures yet.
But as you remember from the start of this section data structures are quite important especially when
looking for jobs.
So without further ado I'll be seeing you in the next few videos.
We're going to be looking at binary trees.
See you there.