Hi welcome back in this would we're going to be removing some duplicate code as you can see.
Our app has a bit of duplicate code that can sometimes be a problem and we're going to go into exactly
why it is a problem in this instance.
The main bit of duplicate code and the bit that worries me is the speed here and there is one particular
reason why it worries me and that is because it contains string literals it contains the user name that
we're using to connect to postscripts the password the database and the host.
I'm not concerned about security at this point although I would be if this was my real password what
I'm concerned about is what happens when we change the password in posh Grace.
What happens when we change the password is that this then fails and we have to come into the file and
change it.
Here and here that's fine because we've only got two instances where this is happening.
But potentially they could be 10 places where we're using this connection or 20 places or 50 plus users
depending on how large our application is.
So the best thing to do is to make sure that this is only written down in our code once and when we
have to change the password would just go into that one place and change it.
This is also duplicate code with connection dot cursor as cursor.
And we're going to get there later on we're going to get to this bit.
Then after the first thing to do is to remove these duplicate clothing for the reasons I said earlier
.
So I'm just going to cut these things and then I'm going to go into the database Doppie why file and
define a method which I'm going to call connect and that is going to return that.
So what that does is when we call the connect method that returns the connection to postscripts And
we also have to import psyco P.G. to show how we are able to do that.
Now in the User class instead of inport psycho puji to what we do is from database import connect database
is our database file connect.
Is the method that we've created and now we just do connect like so.
So with CONNECT as connection and what this is doing is getting the return value of the connect function
and calling it connection as a variable.
And then when you get to the end it's going to you know save it and all were OK.
So let's see vamp's.
And now let's run the app and we still see the user being printed out and going to verify that saving
to the database also works.
That is something you should get into the habit of doing.
Making sure the things that you've changed are work.
So I'm going to create a new user
and save it
and then press play.
Nothing will be printed out but I'm going to go over to Peachi admin run it and Rowlf is there.
Which means what we've done has not broken our program which is great.
So now what we've done is simplified our code but we've gone we've done more than that what I've managed
in this video is to communicate to you the importance of making sure that your code is maintainable
.
If you have the same string everywhere suddenly your code becomes unmaintainable unmanageable when you
have to make a change you lose yourself and you don't know where to make those changes.
So it's very important to remember to keep your code easily readable easily maintainable so that weeks
months years down the line when you come and make a change it's easy.
And if you have the same thing written all over the place that is not the case.
So make sure that your code is succinct readable easy to maintain and you'll have great fun programming
.
And that's what we've done is video.
So now let's move on to the next one.
I see you there.