Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to be retrieving users from the database and seeing if
they already have an email and if they do we're not going to ask them to authenticate and if they don't
we are going to ask them to re authenticate.
It's actually going to be fairly simple and I'm really hoping that you attempted this on your own because
trying this and trying to do it yourselves and then seeing a solution is going to be a lot better for
your learning than just reading the solution from here.
OK the first thing to do is create a user object from an e-mail.
So let's go into a user Doppie wine and notice that we are going to be retrieving data from the database
and we can load up the user object based on an e-mail.
OK.
So the first thing to do is to say user on the school e-mail is input What is it.
Or rather enter your email address and then we'll say user is user don't load from database by email
use or email.
Now something that you should be thinking about is what happens if the usual email doesn't exist in
a database.
What happens if they misspell their email address.
What happens if they use or does exist.
OK.
A few things could happen and we're going to be looking at exactly what does happen in a moment.
So let's try that.
Let's press play and it Alaskas Our e-mail address.
I'm going to put my own.
And that seems to not have failed so I'm going to refresh and I'm going to deliberately misspell and
forget it.
At the end there we have something.
We have none type object.
It's not scriptable.
Now some script is this square brackets one there were accessing a subscript of user data and the service
Rubert accessing is one and they were accessing two and so on.
Well it's telling us is that an object which is none.
So a noun cannot be subscripted.
So you cannot do square bracket one square back at two and so on on something that is none which tells
us that user underscore data must be non In order for this era to have arised arisen.
One of those two.
So we have selected from user where email is something and then we've said that user data is cursor
not fetch one.
We've selected the first row returned from this statement.
However there were no rows returned and so we get none.
So what to do is if user data is not none
do this.
So if the user data returned is not none it means that there was some user data returned which means
the select statement found an account because it found no account.
Sorry about that.
We can then use that data here and create our user object if user data is none then we do not want to
run this because we will get the error.
What we want to do if you Salita is none is written.
OK.
Now we're going to simplify this code a bit.
I'm gonna explain a couple more things about Python as we go return None is the default return for all
methods.
If your method does not return something then it is returning none.
That is always the case here we return a user object and therefore we don't return None.
But if we were not returning a user object.
So if we delete this we are not returning anything.
As you can see in this method but actually the method is returning none.
That is just the default behaviour in Python.
OK so I'm going to undo that which means that this return None is redundant.
It is not necessary.
It happens by default return None is a default behavior so we don't need that.
And because we don't want to do anything else other than return None.
We also don't need this else.
It's also an unnecessary permission to delete those two things.
A None object also is equivalent to false in a boolean comparison.
So what that means is if user data is none then that means user data is false in a boolean comparison
only.
What is in the if statement is a Boolean comparison.
So what we want from this if statement is a true or false value.
This thing here this thing that I've selected will evaluate to true or false if it evaluates to true
.
We will go into the if statement and execute this code.
We know this already and if it evaluates to false then we will not go into the if statement.
We know that.
So we know that user data may be none.
And where we're seeing is if user data is not known then returns the less useful data is not.
None evaluates to true if user data is not known.
However what I just said earlier it may have been a bit confusing is that none evaluates to false in
a boolean comparison.
So what I mean with that is we can just delete that if user data by default means if you tell the to
is not in on because user data because.
Because none evaluates to false.
So if user data is not in that is false and then it would not go in there if user data is not known
then it would go in make sure do rewash that if you need to clarify what I meant.
But what I meant is none is equivalent to false in Boolean comparisons.
So what we're doing here is checking that user data is not enough.
OK.
Now we have that which means me means something.
It means that user download from the B by email is going to return a user object if the user object
.
If the user data exists if it doesn't then it's going to return None.
OK.
So that means we can say if user is not nothing then we can do something.
But as we know none evaluates to false.
So we don't need that again.
So if user if the usually exists then we just want to use the user and we're going to do that in a moment
or else the user does not exist.
We want to ask them to do all this stuff.
OK.
So if the user exists we don't need them to re authenticate reauthorizes if the user does not exist
we want them to reauthorize our app or authorize them.
Orthorexia OK.
Now at the end of this authorization process we create a new user and we save it to the database.
This is fine because we know that user is not in a database already.
We've checked earlier.
We loaded it from the database.
It was nothing without e-mail.
So then we save it again.
Right.
Instead of e-mail now we can just use user e-mail that we got from above at the beginning.
OK.
So we no longer need to ask them for their e-mail twice now the rest of the stuff.
The stuff here we want to do even if I am the user because both of the user exists or if it doesn't
exist.
This is stuff that
this is the end stuff.
Once the user has registered or if the user already exists we want to get the author I stole can create
a client and make the request.
OK.
Now why are these things yellow.
It says Name access underscore token can be not defined here as consumer can be not defined.
The response one is is that there's a bit of a different era I'm not really sure why it's appearing
there.
But let's forget about the response yellowness for now and what is seen as access token may not be defined
and consumer may not be defined.
That's correct.
Consumer is our Twitter app using the consumer and the consumer secret.
It is not dependent on whether a user exists or not.
So we should just remove it from there
and move it to appear because it is not dependent on the user existing or not.
It doesn't make sense to have it inside the else right.
OK.
Instead of access token we should use the user's access to and the user is going to be either this user
that we've created here which is authorized has an access token or it is going to be this user up here
.
Now we've loaded from the database.
So what we should do here is say user don't auth token.
And here we should see user Daut or token secret.
Instead of using the access token that we retrieved from Twitter we can use the access to the retrieve
on Twitter but that we saved in the user and because we create a user here with that token and that
secret or we retrieve a user up here and they have a token and a secret we can just use that.
And that is independent of whether the user existed previously or not.
This line here is only going to happen once we have a user for certain.
We created one there or we loaded it from above.
OK.
So now let's press play again and I'm going to enter my correct email address
and now my Tweets come out because it's using the off token.
And the author can see secret from the database.
However
if I make a mistake then it asks me to authorize again and I can do that
and then it gives me back where they asked me to put my details in here.
Notice how it doesn't ask me for my e-mail.
And then it retrieves the tweets.
And now if I put that same e-mail again Ill just retrieve the tweets again because it's saved that to
the database.
So what we've achieved is actually quite a lot.
We have now got a registration system that is smarter a lot smarter than it was before.
And we are able to save the users of the TVs including the access token which is required to represent
the user in Twitter.
And we've also got a bit of an error handling there.
You may notice that we've got a bit of a redundant if statement that it doesn't do anything.
So we could just remove it and instead of just say if not use.
And that way if the user is not existing It could be the user is not.
Then we will run this.
OK.
I'm quite chuffed about all this stuff to be honest.
I know that when I started programming a while ago I'm doing this all off was was a bit of a pain actually
.
And the first few times that we tried to do this in some teams it wasn't very clear.
So hopefully I've managed to clear this off protests a bit for you and now you are able to log in your
users with Twitter.
Exactly the same Twitter is Facebook Google Plus.
And there's a bunch of other services that all use oils and they use it because it is kind of the standard
now.
So there should be no complication between using Twitter versus Facebook or others.
You will have to however find out the endpoints the API endpoints that you need to request.
Whereas for Twitter we were using API that would add a comb or else request token for Facebook it may
be applied on Facebook dot com slash mouth slash get request token it could be slightly different.
It could be wildly different.
But the core flow and the process is the same.
So with that said I hope you enjoy this video.
I'll see you on the next one.