Hi will come back in this video we're looking at the connection Puni class which is a step towards allowing
us to use the with statement here as we recall.
We created a connection pool and then we were able to successfully get a connection from the pool and
put it back which meant our pool was not getting depleted but the load from D-B we were getting a connection
because we were then returning something we were not able to put it back when we return we exit the
method so we can't execute anything after the return which meant we couldn't return the connection.
So what we want to do is make sure that we can use the with statement so that it is simpler to do that
.
There's other ways as well but and this is this is the way that is simplest I believe.
So what we want to be able to do is something like.
With connection pool as conn sorry assed connection we want to be able to do something along these lines
so that we can do something like this get a connection and then at the end it closes itself and it you
know it returns to the pool and all that.
And here the same with a connection pool thing that we haven't created yet.
We want to be able to do this and get a connection and then so that at the end it puts it back itself
.
So we want to be able to do this now the first step is to have this class this this thing this connection
pool thing.
So from the database I'm going to import connection pool and that also doesn't exist.
So we have to go into a database and create it.
So I'm going to create this class called Connection Pool and the objective of this class is just to
teach you how to use the with.
Statement this connection pool class should have a connection pool associated with it.
So I'm gonna have it in that method where self-dual connection pool is this thing.
I'm going to delete it from the app and then I'm going to just format the code and with old command
.
L I think that's some way here.
They're inside code reformat code and that just makes it a bit nicer.
And I'm going to delete that now.
So now we have a class that has a connection pool in it.
This is exactly the same as having our permission pool outside.
Except now if we want to access the connection pool we would do that with like so cp is Connection Pool
C.P. connection pool
.
It doesn't do anything that's right.
I was wondering why was the yellow.
But yeah it doesn't do anything naturally.
But nevertheless this is how we would access this connection pool here.
Right.
So how do we now make sure that this can be done.
Because I'm going to delete this thing from here.
If I if we run the app now we get an error saying attribute error underscores underscore exit underscore
underscore in this line here which tells us it doesn't know what to do with this connection pool class
surely.
And I told you before we have to specifically program the width construct to be able to be used.
That's right.
We have to.
So how do we.
Well fortunately for us it's quite simple.
The first thing we have to do is define an entire method and what I a pass because it doesn't do anything
for now and an exit method more of a pass because it doesn't do anything for now what happens if we
run the app now.
OK.
Now given a different era now it gives an error on the second line with connection not cursor as cursor
.
It says None.
Type object has no attribute cursor.
It's basically trying to access an attribute called Carcer But this thing here is none.
It is not something that has a cursor property which means that when we create this variable up here
this is not.
Which means that this thing here is returning none.
And the reason why is retaining none is because this is not calling the unit's method.
It is calling the enemy and the entire method doesn't do anything.
For example say we return 1 to 3 which has a number an integer and we press play.
Now it says impt object has no such a beaut cursor.
This number here that we have returned doesn't have a cursor.
So what we have to return here is a connection to the database.
The connection does have a cursor.
So let's wrap return self dot connection pool gets calm this gets a new connection and then returns
it right.
Let's press play.
And there we go.
We now have the program working.
This is a bit of a red herring.
Rummer our app is doing seems to be in its looing load from D-B by email and then it's doing seemed
to be against us doing three operations three connections
the connection pool that we create only has one connection available.
How is this happening.
This seems magical.
There's three connections available but we are only using one up here.
We've only created one and we've certainly not cold put corn anywhere.
So how are the connections going back into the pool and now is the time you wish that this was magical
and it just worked.
But unfortunately it is not the case.
It never is in programming.
Earlier I lied.
I said that when this gets called the init method does not get called and that's a lie.
The method gets called.
And then we enter method gets called.
So the thing that gets assigned to the connection is the result of the Enter method.
But before the end method we call the init method.
I think now you can guess why we have three connections available.
Can you give it a bit of thought.
Why do we have three connections available.
With what I've just told you that the init method does get called.
Well here's why we don't have the connections available.
What we have is three connection pools available.
We're creating one connection pool every time that we call this thing here.
So this is even worse than what we had before.
Now we no longer have the overhead of creating three connections.
Now we have the overhead of creating three connection pools and each one creates one connection.
So that's essentially double the overhead.
This is not a good solution.
So down here we really should be returning the connections but how how can we do that when we are creating
a new connection pool each time.
And the answer is this is not the answer.
So that's everything for this video.
I wanted to show you how simple it is to make something that works.
And do you think is correct.
That really isn't so sure to question everything.
This is not the answer.
But it was not a complete waste of time.
It is getting closer and closer to the answer.
And the reason why I'm beating this up is I don't want to throw you in the deep end too quickly but
I do want you to see the sort of thought process that goes into designing this sort of stuff.
So this is not the answer but it's getting there.
Now we're going to look at that in the very next few videos.
So it's either