Hi will come back.
This way you will going forwards and creating a database class through all this section.
We've learned loads about Python and I know it can get quite confusing quite quickly.
I am going to use this moment to just encourage you to ask questions in the course Q&A if you have any
.
I am truly honestly committed to helping you learn and I answer any questions as soon as I can.
Let's create a database class.
Now you may wonder why we're doing anymore.
You know we've got this cursor from connection pool that gets us the cursor really easily we've got
this connection pool that OK only has one connection available but they can have more.
And you know that is great.
This is very fast performing quickly because we've got the connection pool.
We don't need to create new connections.
And yeah you know that's correct.
It's good.
I'm telling you but we can do better and we should.
There is one problem though that it's something I don't really like about pythoness.
One of the few things I don't like about Python but it is unavoidable and it is I don't know if you
knew this but Python is a compiled language.
So before running files like database Doppie why before being able to gain this connection pool we have
to compile this file and converted into something the computer can understand.
I'm not going to go into what compiling is essentially converting this into something else.
Converting this text essentially all this text into something else than the computer or in this case
the Python interpreter which is another program can understand that can execute.
So we have to compile all this and that's OK.
But something else that also has to happen is that the imports have to get cleared.
And what that means is if we go into an app which is our starting point app Doppie why we execute apt
IPY when we run our app we right click app IPY Y and we run it at dopy y imports user the user class
.
So before going to app before running the first line what we do is we go into user and we run that we
run the user file first because that's the first thing here.
And we have to make sure that the import is available you know when it works ok that makes sense.
So we go into the user file and we run this file.
And what this file does is it imports something else.
It imports from the database file.
So before going in and running this we run the database file.
So here we go in the database and the first thing it does is it imports from cyclopedia.
So it goes and then runs that we're not going to get into that but that's what happens.
And eventually it finishes running psycho-BS you too and it gets back to the database and then it says
OK I'm going to run this now and then it runs this.
So the first thing in our application the first thing that happens is this variable gets created that
the pool gets created one connection gets created into our database and then the class gets analyzed
.
We kind of realizes that this is a class.
It does not execute the methods.
That doesn't happen.
It just knows that they are there essentially.
But this does get executed.
We created the connection.
That's the first thing that we do in our app.
Then it goes back to the user it goes back in time essentially and it runs these and then realizes this
is a class as well and it has some methods you know.
And then it goes back to the app and then realizes OK we can import the user that class that exists
.
Let's do that.
And then it runs the first line there then it creates the user object and then it runs this method.
It knows this method exists because it saw it when it was analyzing the other file.
But this is the first time this method runs.
OK.
So that's what happens.
The thing I don't like is that the connection pool gets executed before anything else.
We don't have the ability to say when we wanted to execute this connection pool.
So for example this application had a graphical interface and we wanted our users to be able to interact
with the interface potentially the first thing we'd want to do is show them the interface not initialize
a connection pool.
Now I appreciate this connection pool does not take a lot of time to be initialized but potentially
it could.
So this is why I'm telling you all this if we put these in a class and we initialize it inside a method
of the class it does not get executed immediately.
So that's what we're going to be doing so that we can control when it gets executed.
So I'm going to read a class database and this database is going to have the connection pool in it.
But if we do this then this is not the best way to do it.
So what are we going to do is we're going to initialize the collection pool property of the database
inside the method.
So the connection pool is going to be none.
Sorry about that up there we go.
And I'm going to cut all that stuff.
So now we've got a class database and the date the class itself has a property called Connection Pool
.
Notice this is not inside the init method.
This is inside the class.
So this property here belongs to the class itself and not one of the objects.
OK.
And then we're going to do def initialize and we're going to say
database dot connection pool equals the pool that we know and love.
OK.
So we're seeing the property connection pool of the data base class.
Note not an object.
The Database class if it was an object we would have to do something like database equals database.
Remember that and then database dot connection pool which is also valid by the way.
But the connection pool is not belonging to an object it is belonging to the database itself.
And so all objects that we create of type database would have the same connection pool available to
them.
We're going to get into this more later on.
But I just wanted to tell you about this a bit more.
So when we run this initial x method we initialize the connection pool we see data which is dot connection
pool equals pool or simple connection pool blah blah blah.
OK.
So I'm going to go back into my app I'm going to delete this stuff here and I'm going to show you what
the data is not Cornish and pool means.
So I want to objects.
Well first of all I want from database import database and then I want two objects the lobby one is
going to be a new database database two is going to be a new database too.
OK.
And then we are going into the following print database.
One dot connection pool print data is to dog connection pool.
What would you expect them to be printed out at this point.
We've created the database object with another object and we're printing out the connection pools that
are in them.
I'm going to go into the database now and see that there is no init method.
There is no init method.
There's only a initialize method that will tell you that does not get executed automatically and there
is a connection pool variable there inside the class that is none.
What do you think is going to get printed out.
Possibly your answer was none.
And you would be correct none gets printed out.
In both cases the connection pool for the top one is none.
The connection pool for the two is also none.
But here's here's what happens.
I'm going to do deliveries one not initialize.
What do you think is going to happen now.
What is going to get printed out.
Now this is weird and I appreciate it if this is the first time you're encountering this sort of stuff
.
You're thinking this is way over my head but it's really not.
Trust me we've got database one which is the database object and we know that these objects are separate
from one another completely separate from the properties of one object can have the same names as the
properties of another object but they have completely different values.
So we print the connection pool of database one and we get none.
Then we initialize database one then we print the connection pool of the database to and there is a
connection pool there.
What is going on here is what this connection pool belongs to the database and I've said this before
.
Not to a specific object so it is shared amongst all objects of type database.
When we set a value to it all of the objects of type database get to that new value and now you're thinking
is that useful for anything and yeah yeah I mean it's useful for some things.
I can't really think of any of the top of my head.
But the great thing about giving this connection pool to the Database class is that we can also just
skip objects completely just see databases dot connection pool because the connection pool belongs to
the Database class.
What do you think is going to happen when I run this.
Think carefully about it because it is a trick question.
OK let's run it.
Error message type error.
Initialize missing one required positional argument self.
We are not passing itself.
Remember when we have an object my object equals database and are misspelled.
And we do this just cannot spell it correctly.
I get OCD and we do this.
My object gets passed in ASP self right.
We've looked at this before briefly but now we want to run the method directly on the database because
the connection pool belongs to data because it does not belong to a specific object so it doesn't make
sense to create an object.
We just want to run it on database.
Can we do this.
Yes we can.
Just like at.
Class method.
Replace the self for CLX and pointed to the currently bound class static method.
Just remove it completely.
There is no reference to the current class.
There's no reference to anything else we could do.
Class method and then we would have to put CLX here.
CLX would be a reference to the currently bound class so we could do this.
That would be totally fine.
We can do that.
Well.
OK so a lot of stuff going on this video.
What else can we do.
I've just introduced static method to you and have introduced static properties such as Connection Pool
as a static or class property.
That's what they're called and we can do more things we can do.
Class method because we can access where we can access the connection pool directly.
So I'm down here instead of connection underskirt pool.
We could see the Tabby's dot connection pool and Dot get clean.
This is something that's valid and down here we could do database dot connection pool dot put on we
can return the connection to the pool.
But this is not very good style.
The table is dot connection.
Please don't get caught.
There's too many dots.
This is too confusing when I want to do is say database don't get connection and what I want to do is
a database don't return connection.
I think that reads better for me that's cleaner code.
So we're rolling with that.
We want to be able to do this.
That's actually quite simple.
Using another class method we can get connection and all this has to do is return C-Class dot connection
pool and don't get caught.
So this is doing what we were doing down here but now whenever we interact with a database class it's
a lot simpler.
We just call database dog connection.
We don't have to say database dot connection pool don't get connection.
It's a bit simpler.
This is only in one place in our code database dog connection could be in many places now.
We can also have a static method for a class method.
It doesn't matter which one to use.
Just remember CLSA is totally replaceable for database.
There's a few reasons why class method exists but we're not going to get into those just yet return
connection.
And here we want to say database dot connection pool.
Don't put on and we need the connection that we want to put back in.
So I'm gonna pass it in as a parameter as an argument.
Same thing.
And then that is going in event database don't return connection and I'm passing it in the connection
that is in this cursor from connection from pool.
OK and that's that.
There's also another thing that we could implement and which is just useful to do.
And it is part of the connection pool which is close all connections
.
There we go.
That just stops the commit from going through to any connection and closes them all.
It's not something we've used but it's something that can be done and just in case we need it for later
on I'm going to put that in.
OK so does this work.
Can we do what we were doing before and I'm just going to copy it so I don't bore you.
Can we create a new user and then save it and then load it and then print it out
and want to import user.
And then I'm going to create one user like so save it to the database.
Sorry I have to put none down there at the end of the ID field and then we're going to load it from
the database with that email and we're going to print it out.
So do you think it is going to work.
Do you see any reason why it shouldn't work.
Give it a think.
Remember I'm always trying to catch you out.
So think about it carefully.
Let's run this thing.
Oh no I caught you none type object has no attribute get conned.
You were thinking that was going to work didn't you.
It says get caught is not an attribute of none.
So let's dot connection pool is none.
Let's get to it.
It's basically saying you're trying to run this but this thing here this CLX not Connection Pool is
none and none doesn't have get to as part of it.
So you can't call get con on none.
It makes sense.
None is an anything so why should it have a get con method associated with it.
So how do we fix that.
That is nutten.
I smell a pattern here.
This is also known that is non knowledge.
How do we fix this being none.
Well I'm sure you got it from database import database.
And remember we have to initialize the database.
We now can choose when we want to initialize the database.
So now we can run this and that is fine because we can choose.
We could potentially initialize it after creating the user.
That would be OK.
We've not used that yet.
We can we can initialize it here instead.
That's fine but naturally if we put it down here then that is not fine because then that is none.
Let's put it at the top.
OK a long video.
I appreciate.
I do admire you for staying with me until here.
Hopefully you are learning some stuff.
And that's it for this video.
So in the next video we're going to be looking into more stuff and what we're going to be looking at
is into him making sure that we are not limited into what servers we connect to for our database.
So I see you.
Actually I'm excited about that.