Hi welcome back in this video we're going to look at flasks before request decorator.
Remember a decorator is just this at thing that appears before the method the flasks before request
decorator allows us to run something before each request remember a request is just when the user arrives
at any one of our pages.
That is a request the user made a request to our server and we are responding with some sort of template
or a redirection or some data or something else so we can execute some code before each request.
And now you're wondering well why would we ever want to do that execute the same code before each request
.
All of these methods are completely different and you are right now whether there is a use case for
one method to be around before each request.
Let's go down here to our profile.
And as you can see when we rendered the template which is the profile the hatred e-mail template we
are passing in the screen name and that is stored in the session.
Now what we wanted not the screen name but the entire user object so the user had other details that
we wanted to show in that profile.
For example their email address or their name or something like that an option would be to store all
of those things in the session.
That's something we could do.
But we are able of searching the database by screen name to retrieve a user object.
So why not pass in a user so passing user equals.
And here we would pass in a user
but we don't have a user to pass it.
The only thing we've got is the sessions screen name.
So easy fix user don't load from the screen name session screen name.
Perfect.
Easy enough right.
Well yes but what if then we needed to get the user somewhere else.
For example when we're searching for tweets we're going to need the user an object as well.
Wouldn't it be nice if we could have access to the user object in every method.
The answer is yes yes it would.
So let's do it.
I'm going to write a wee bit of code first and then show you exactly what I'm doing so that you can
understand where I'm going to create the top of the file it doesn't have to be at the top but I'm putting
out the tab anyway and not before request
and I'm calling the method load.
Underscore user you can call it whatever you want.
Any name is fine but make sure it kind of describes what it we're doing or what we're doing when it
load and use what we're going to say is if screen name in session and what that does is say is there
a key called screen name in the session variable.
And if there is what we're going to do is we're going to load up the user.
So we're going to say gee that user equals user data load the wrote on the screen name session screen
name and we have to import G.
So let's import G from flask.
Why is this interesting.
The only thing we're doing is we're creating some sort of jihad user variable and we are putting in
it the user object.
Yes but now the variable is special.
It does not die off when we exit this method.
It is globally available during the entire request.
So this thing here happens before the request we load up the user and we put it inside the variable
we call it user G dot.
And we load the user object.
And now this G variable is available throughout the entire request.
So if we go to the profile page.
So we go here to the profile page.
The first thing we do is we execute this before request and we create geed out user.
And now I said that this variable is available through the entire request which means it is available
in the profile page.
That's what we requested.
So the other method happens first and then we go to this one and we have g.
So instead of user equals all this we can just say usually equals geed or to user.
And this is especially interesting because as long as screen name does exist in the session we're always
going to have access to the user object and that is interesting because the user object not only has
properties although it does not only does it have a screen name on stuff it also has a method which
allows us to make Twitter requests and we're going to be using that shortly.
Let's go back into the app.
And now here we've got the profile which now has a variable user.
So let's go into the profile page and instead of screen name we can do user dot screen name so we can
access the screen name property of the human object just as if this were Python only it's Jinja too
.
So that's also quite interesting.
And now we are able to do that.
So in every method as long as screen name is sent we are going to be able to have the dot user property
.
This also does mean that now that we have a user object we can do Twitter requests but it also means
that whenever the browser with a cookie comes in then they are going to be logged in and we're going
to have access to the user property.
So it makes sense to also have a log out endpoint so that users can clear this action and make sure
that nobody else has access to their not only their screen name but also the ability to perform searches
on their behalf.
We're going to be doing that in the next video but now we're going to be implementing the logout button
.
So below the logon let's just create another route app route log out
and there's a logo building has to do is to section not clear.
And then it has to redirect the user to the home page for example return.
Redirect your L4 homepage.
And you know that that's redirects the user to a page Yura for calculates the Eurail that we're reacting
to by getting the associated endpoint to the method home page.
OK.
I'm also going to use this time to go into the home page home not HD M-L and below Hello world.
I'm going to put a link to the logon page.
I'm tired of them constantly going in and having to modify the the address bar so I'm going to put in
a link a link in a page DML is an A which stands for and Kuhr and it actually anchors a page to another
page it links it and hates ref.
Is that the address that we are linking to.
And in here you guess that we can once again do an open double and calibres plausible calibrates and
putting your l4.
And here we go.
Twitter logging Ramba that has to be the method name of this method.
Let's go back in here and close the anchor and you can here put in the text that is going to be linked
.
So log in with Twitter.
OK let's restart our app and go over to it.
I'm going to open it up.
And now we get this button here.
Log in to it.
Now we can go there and then that initialises the log in we no longer have to modify the address bar
.
So everything still works.
So let's keep going.
And I see you in the very next video