Will come back in this video we're going to look at cleaning up the database class.
I think it looks quite clean but we can still do more.
The first thing that we'd like to do is make sure that's the connection pool is not accessible from
outside the class which is making a variable private.
And we don't really have a keyword for that in Python.
If you know any other programming languages they sometimes do in python we don't have a keyboard to
make a variable private.
The first question to answer is Why do we want to make these variable private.
And what does that mean say in the cursor from connection from pool class which I know is a bad name
but let's leave it at that.
We have these self-conviction equals database.
Don't get connection.
And that is great.
It allows us to get a connection from that database say that this connection does get connection method
.
Not only did this say it did more stuff for example said that connection are poor.
You know something it doesn't.
But imagine it did.
Imagine it did things with the connection before giving it back.
Right now even though we have this method nothing is stopping other classes and other parts of the program
from doing what we did before.
Database Dogget connection database not connection pool.
Don't get caught.
Nothing is preventing my program from doing this or if somebody else was working with me their code
.
Promoting their code from doing that either.
And if this method was setting things up and doing more things then doing this could potentially be
dangerous.
It could have unexpected results.
Ideally we would want everyone to be forced to use get connection.
Because of that.
Not only is getting the connection but also setting things up and all that.
So I imagine it does do that.
Well fortunately we can kind of stop them from accessing this variable directly.
Let's select the variable and then press shift FCX or the refactor and then refactor this rename.
Now we go refactor and then rename and then in front of the connection pool.
Put two underscores So not just one underscore not one long underscore but two separate underscores
.
OK that does that.
It renames the variable to two underscores.
Connection Pool.
Now let's go back to our cursor from connection from pool and try to do that.
As you can see it can no longer be done.
That variable is no longer accessible and that is how you make variables private and make them hidden
from other programs or other parts of the program using Peifer.
You just put two underscores in front.
OK.
Something as I mentioned in the last video that I also wanted to be able to do was limit or rather decide
way I'm connecting to in the initialize method and what I mean with this is I'd like in my apt on P
Y to be able to say database equals learning host equals localhost him user equals postscripts
with T Room.
Yes it is.
And password Schrank password equals 1 2 3 4.
I'd like to be able to put it here in the initialize method so that I can change it more easily so that
I only have to change it in here if I do want to change it.
And there is a way to do that.
There is a way to do that.
As you can see these four parameters then are named parameters.
They have a name to them and then they have equals and then they have a value.
So these are named parameters and we can pass all of these parameters together.
What I mean with that is we can do as we discussed risk quorums and we've seen the aster discussed this
before and we can put apologies asterisk asterisk quorums here and now.
Notice how the yellowness disappears pyjamas says.
This is now OK and that is OK with the sonic asterisk asterisk.
Means is any named parameters so the apt IPY that is passing for named parameters.
That is fine because the initialize method is now accepting any number of named parameters and it knows
the name as well as the value.
So then we can posit those named parameters to the simple connection pool and then that if we go into
simple connection pool.
It also accepts keyword arguments there as well.
And I know this is a bit quick and I'm not giving you a chance to look at this code.
But we don't care about this code just know that this is something that you can do.
So what we're doing is we're accepting any number of named parameters named arguments and then we're
passing them on.
So now we can accept these things here.
And this was just a cleanup of the Database class to make sure that we can choose where we want to connect
to more easily and so that we can hide the property connection pool.
So it's not mis used by other areas of the program and that's it for this video.
So you the next one.