Hi, and welcome back to the course.
In this video, we're going to be setting up PyCharm
on our Mac.
It's going to be a really straightforward process.
Just open up PyCharm Community Edition,
and it'll look very similar to what I've got here,
but of course on the left I have a number of projects
that I've already started for other things.
And you don't have to worry about that.
If yours is empty, that's totally fine.
Nothing to worry about.
Go ahead and click on create new project,
and then make sure that in the location
you enter the folder that you want your code to be in.
And in my case, I'm just gonna go into documents,
programming, python-postgres/students,
because we're gonna be building a student project
in this section.
Then, open up this project interpreter drop down
if it's not open already,
and select existing interpreter.
We're going to look at this other stuff
later on in the course,
but for now, select existing interpreter
and then from the drop down,
find the version of Python that you've recently installed
whether that's 3.5, 3.6 or even 3.7.
If you see many options, like for example,
these that say Python 3.7 virtualenv at blah, blah, blah,
don't select any of those,
just go ahead and select the ones that are in your library.
See, here /library/frameworks, select that one,
and again it doesn't really matter
if you go 3.5, six or seven,
but just for keeping in with the latest standards,
I'm gonna go with 3.7.
And go ahead and click create, and that's you.
Then your project will appear,
and you'll have your students folder.
And in here we can create all our code files.
So that's it for this video.
In the next one we're going to look at
setting this up on Windows,
it's pretty much the same thing.
And so if you're using Mac,
you can totally skip the next video,
and just move on to the one after that.
So with that said, I'll see you in the next one.