Hi welcome back in this video we're going to be creating our new project and create our first class
.
The first thing to do is open up charm and create your new project and you'll be greeted with a screen
Remember if you are using the community edition instead of the professional edition you won't have all
these options on the left but that's fine.
The option we want is pure Python and then select where you want to save your project which is going
to select my options here and my thing moved to my other screen for some reason.
It is here and then a new phone number which you use when the system.
And then I don't know why this keeps moving that will be that and then selects the interpreter that
you want to use.
And in this instance it is just the ADD installed version of Python that you should have in your system
.
I am going to go with this one.
It doesn't really matter and it'll be version 3.5 or version three point four
and then you get this screen which we know already you'll have your empty project folder on the left
and then your external libraries which won't have much except the Python version you're using.
And for now it doesn't really matter.
And if you're using Python 2.7 than 3.4 3.5 they're all fine.
So the first thing to do is create our first class.
Let's go into new python file.
And because we're creating a movie rental system I'm going to call this movie and this movie dot P Why
file is going to hold my movie class.
Notice that they don't have to be called the same.
The file can be called whatever you want.
Class as we've seen in the last video is just a structure that lets us store properties stored data
but also has the ability to contain some actions that it can do.
And it can do those actions on itself.
So our class movie is going to contain data related to the movie and also is going to contain a few
actions that a movie might take on itself.
As you know the properties of a class of an object are defined in the signed underscore underscore unit
underscore underscore.
And remember these are two separate on the scores there and inside the init method we define the properties
that each object will have in the case of movies.
These are going to be a name and a genre for now.
And these are these properties are going to get passed in when we create a new movie object and therefore
self-taught name should be equal to name and self-taught genre should be equal to John.
And what it does is it sets the object's name to be the name that we passed in and the objects John-Roger
to be the genre that we passed in.
OK let's now go into our folder and create a new Python file which is going to be app Doppie y and in
here we're going to use very fine.
The movie is working well.
So let's first of all import the movie file which can be done by from movie import movie.
Remember the capital M because what we're importing here is the class and we are importing it from the
movie Doppie why file and then what we can do is say my underskirt movie is a movie with a capital M
.
And here we can put the name and the genre of the movie because that's the parameters that's the init
method.
Except
I'm going to put the Matrix and I'm not really sure what genre it is scifi I guess action sort of thing
.
And now we've created the movie and what this does is it says OK I'm going to see what a movie is and
then he goes here and he sees the closet.
OK this is this is a movie.
It has this init method.
And then he says OK because you're asking me to create a new movie which you know it is because it's
using the class name.
And then the opening and closing bracket it goes OK.
So the method I want to run is the in its method and Python just knows that.
And then it says OK let's run the method you're giving me two parameters.
The Matrix and cipher.
So I'm just going to put those in name and genre respectively and then it runs through this method and
it says OK now this movie has is going to have a name and a genre and the name is going to be the name
passed in the genre are going to be the genre passed in.
And then what we can do is say print my underscore movie Daut name.
So let's run this Right-Click the app Y and select Run and we get back the Matrix which is what we'd
expect.
So here's a question for you.
What happens if we print my movie don't direct
what we think about it.
Let's press play and see what happens.
But I would expect a bunch of red text to appear.
I am right and it's important in Python especially that you read the errors and you try to understand
them the property of an object is also known as an attribute and the arrow down here is saying on the
line.
Print my movie dot director.
There was an attribute error movie object a key my movie has no attribute director.
It doesn't have that property.
We haven't defined self don't direct or any way anywhere but if we do self-doubting director equals
I'm going to embarrass myself spelling that
if you do define that inside the init method then you can run this again and see the name coming out
.
So it's especially important to remember to define the properties that you want inside the in its method
Try to avoid defining properties inside a different method.
But we'll get to that later.
So that's everything for this video.
Just to get you once you get acquainted with creating a class which is done with a class keyword and
then the class name and the init method which is underscore underscore in it underscore underscore has
self as the first parameter and then other parameters that you want to pass it.
You define the classes properties in the in its method and you can pass values to populate them in here
when you create the object itself and also to realize that you can access properties using the dot operator
and if x is a property that doesn't exist you get an attribute error but that's everything for this
video.
Just a quick look at that.
And now let's move on into the next one.
That's you there