Hi and will come back in this video we're looking at creating a linked list and we're going to answer
the question what is a linked list a linked list is a base for many data structures.
So we're going to be constructing other data structures like the cue or the stack using linked lists
a linked list is actually fairly similar to a normal list except it may be a bit more optimal in some
cases.
Let's have a look.
The linked list is just a sequence of items just as your normal list would be.
However instead of all the items being kind of there in the list all accessible.
For example you could do my list and then inside the square brackets you could put a 5 and that would
get you the sixth element in the list in the linked list.
Each item knows where the next item is and hence the linked part.
So let's have a look at how that works.
And really what that means let's imagine we have a linked list of students.
Each element of the list which we're calling a node holds with the name matriculation number and year
of study for each student.
So just some data for each student.
And it also holds the next node.
Remember each of the items in the linked list knows where the next element is and we're going to look
at exactly what that means.
OK.
So that's our node class and it has the name Mattrick number and year of study as well as the next node
.
Now I've specified that the next is F-Type node the next variable has to be also a node object.
Now we don't have a way to enforce that in Python but it should be that way when we are interacting
with our link list.
So the first node we create could be for example this one.
And the name is George.
The magic number is 1 5 7 5 4 6 5 G.
And the years of these two and the next node is another node which is Anna 3 3 2 4 5 1 5 P and 3 for
your study.
And it also has a next node and the next note here is another node which in this case is Philipe and
eventually you're going to have infinite number of nodes and eventually the next node ends up being
none.
Which means there is no next node.
So here we've got a linked list of three nodes.
The first one which is called the head or the root is George and then George's next node is Anna and
Anna's next notice.
Phillip So George knows where Anna is.
George does not know anything about Phillip as far George knows Philip doesn't even exist.
However if we know George then we can get Anna because we can go to the next node if we know and then
we can get Phillip because we can get that next.
OK.
So that's how a linked list works.
So in your linked list you would not be able to get Philip directly you would have to start with George
then go to Amur then go to Philly.
Now you may think that is very bad and in some instances yes I would agree.
I mean it is not the most optimal thing to do but in other cases having this limitation actually might
improve performance and we're going to look at exactly how.
So to implement a linked list we need two classes the node which holds the data and the next node on
the linked list class which manages the nodes.
And most importantly hold the first node if we have just a node floating about as an object then that's
not very sort of easy to use if we have a list object that should hold the first note.
We're going to look at how to program this as well.
So the linked list class has methods to find a node in the linked list for which we need to supply the
student name for example and to add a new node at the beginning of the linked list.
OK.
So let's look at the interaction between the looks dominant we've called the linked list here and the
linked list has a variable called head.
But I have said there is a type node but again in python we don't have a way to enforce this because
we don't have pipes where we don't have static typing.
So the hand is initially none.
When you create your linked list object we don't have any nodes in the list and we have the node there
as we know which has the name the metric number and the year of study as well as the next node the linked
list also has the two other methods.
Add to list which takes in a node and we'll add it to the list and a Find method which sticks in a string
and we find a node inside the list.
So the add to list method is going to take a node as a parameter and then it's going to do something
with that node.
So the node is going to go into the list in one of two ways.
If the head is not in that means our linked list is empty.
Right.
If the head is on we don't have any node already there.
So the head is not our linked list is empty and we're going to make the head of the linked list equal
to the new node.
So what we're going to be doing is say our linked list has no elements.
Let's make the link let's hand equal to the new node that is going to put the new node essentially in
the hand of the list.
If the linked list is not empty then we will put this new node at the beginning by making the new nodes
in the head of the linked list and making it point to the next node in the linked list.
Now I know this is a mouthful and it's not really very easy to understand without going into the programming
.
So we are going to go into programming shortly.
So if the linked list is not empty it means that the hand has a node and what we're going to do is we're
going to say the new node is going to become the head and the new node which is not a hand is going
to point to what was previously a head.
OK let's have a look at an example we've got a linked list here.
When the head is initially none and then we're going to call this method add to the list we're going
to happen is that we're going to create a new node and put it in place of the head.
So the head is now going to be this node object here which is George.
And now we're going to call the Atlas method again and what's going to happen is that we're going to
get a new node and we're going to make that new node the hand and that new node is going to point to
what was previously the head.
So basically this is going to we've got a new node.
We've put it and made in the hand and that new node points to what was previously the head George was
previously the head of the new node now points to George and the new node is the head.
So what we've done is essentially added something at the beginning
to create a new node and it points to the previous head and the head is now the new note that we've
added.
Ok.
The find method is going to go over all of the items in a linked list.
When I iterate over our linked list and if any node has the same student name as the one we're looking
for we're going to tell a user some information about that.
So imagine we have this linked list here which has three elements.
The first one is George.
Second one is Annah.
The third one is Phillip and then Phillip points to none which means there is no more elements let's
call find Anna.
So what we're looking for really is the second node.
And what we're going to do is we're going to go to the head of the first node in the list and check
and we are going to be there.
And then we're going to compare the node name with the name we're looking for which is Anna.
Are we going to see that it's not there.
So then we're going to go over to the next node and then we're going to compare the nodes name to the
thing we're looking for and we'll show you that it is there.
So then what we do is just pulling things out and then stop iterating over.
We're going to look at how we can iterate over a linked list as well in the next video.
And that's really everything for this video.
So I hope you enjoyed that and learn something.
And this is how you create a linked list and how it works.
Each element knows what the next element is but not where any of the other elements are.
And you actually need a starting point.
So the node hand of the linked list can be your starting point.
Without further ado I know this is a bit confusing.
Let's go into the next video.
We're going to be programming this up to you there.