I will come back in this video we're going to be searching tweets.
Finally we are able now to log in the users using Twitter into our web application.
We're saving them to the database.
Now what's left is to actually do something with Twitter data really.
So in this video we're going to be searching for tweets and displaying them on a web page.
We've got a profile page.
We've got the off.
We've got the log in log out on the home page.
Let's create another route for the search.
So app don't root for search
and here where we want to do is to get the tweets the tweet texts.
We did that before in our loggin dopy y.
So ideally what I would like to do is to have a list of the text inside each tweet that we search for
.
You guys know how to do that already we've looked at that before.
I would once again encourage you to pause the video and try that.
It's the best way to learn it's by trying to make mistakes.
So go ahead and do that and then continue here.
OK.
Hopefully you managed.
And what we're going to do is say tweets equals and remember we have access to the currently logged
in user in jihadi user so we can't just say gee don't use or don't twitter request.
And here we can request the page that is going to allow us to search.
And if you remember the page of the P.S. call on slash slash API or to about com slash 1.1 slash search
last tweets Don.
Jason and then we can put in a query at the end which is what we are searching for and the query is
going to be in this case computers plus filter images.
It doesn't have to be that that we can be anything you want.
And rember that the request by default to use the get verb.
So this request is going to happen using get.
Which is what we want.
OK.
In order to get the tweet texts we're going to say use a list comprehension.
We're going to go into the log in the IPY file first.
And here's what we did is we iterated over the status is.
And then we printed the text for each tweet.
Now here's a wee bit of a challenge for you.
Instead of printing each tweet out put each text in a list inside tweet text tweet texts.
So ideally what I like in the end is something like blah blah blah.
To eat one tweet to tweet three
and so on.
So for each of the tweets in here put the text in a list like so I would recommend using a list comprehension
.
We looked at that before.
You can certainly do that.
Go ahead and try that.
OK.
Hopefully you managed.
And the way to do that is we're going to see a tweet for tweets in tweets and what this is doing is
it's iterating over the tweets in tweets and it's just putting the entire tweet in in that list.
Remember the tweets are not directly in here but they are inside.
The status is key.
So we have to see for tweets in tweets statuses and now that's iterating over each tweet but we don't
want the entire tweet to go in the list.
We only want the text.
So what to do is say text and now the way this reads is get the tweets text for each of the tweets in
tweets statuses and then just putting that in say the new list.
So that's what tweet texts will contain.
And finally what are we going to do is return a rendered template search dot HTML and the content is
going to be tweet text remember content can be anything you want.
This is just the variable name that we can then use in Jinja to such the DML doesn't exist.
So let's go and create that right reichlich template press new HDMI file call it search dot page DML
and then why does it seem to work search results.
You can put that in the title there.
You can put it search results you can put anything you want really.
And now we're going to be instead of printing things out to the console we're essentially going to be
printing them out here in the body of our HDMI file.
Remember the body is what users see.
So we're going to be putting things in the body and users are going to be able to see them.
OK so what to do is say
open a curly brace and then a percent sign and say four element in content and then close the percent
sign a curly brace and at the end two lines down.
Type in and forth.
I'm sure you recognize this from Python.
This is just a normal for loop that it's going to be iterating over content.
The list we passed in with our tweets and it's going to be calling each element Element.
OK.
So here we could put in a p tag a p tag is used for paragraphs and we can essentially just put anything
we want in it and we're going to put in is double and curly brace element and that is going to access
this element variable there and it's going to print it out.
So the element variable should be the text of the tweet and that is going to be each of the texts in
site content which as we know is the tweet texts which is the list of tweet texts.
My god that was a bit of a mouthful.
OK let's restart the app and now we can go over to the you are Rayle type log in with Twitter.
We get that and then we're going to type in search
and there we have some tweets.
OK it's not very pretty but we have tweets that have come out of Twitter and we're displaying them on
our Web page.
Now if you started only programming at the beginning of this course where you didn't have much experience
I'd say this is quite a lot of practice.
So I'd like to congratulate you on that.
We have come really far from the beginning of the course until now.
And that's really great.
Hopefully you are understanding what's going on here.
I always encourage you to ask questions in the course Q and A.
I really do take my time answering everything that I can.
OK.
Now we're presenting the results there and we know that each of the elements is the tweet text.
So now we can worry about presenting them better instead of just printed them one in each line.
We can maybe do a bit of styling and present them a bit nicer and then we can move on to do the sentiment
analysis on the tweets which we're going to be doing.
And I'm not going to go into what it is just yet but we will get there.
So now that we are able to display the tweets like so we're going to move on to the next videos we're
going to be styling them a bit better making them prettier and then doing the analysis.
I see you in the very next video.