Hi and welcome back in this video we're looking at drop table and this is going to be a lot shorter
than the previous video because the only thing we have to look at is how do you delete a table in sequel
and we're going to be deleting the two tables that we've created over the last few videos to delete
all the data and drop a table.
We can do drop table and then a table name to public DOT uses.
What do you think is going to happen when I do this.
Drop table public don't use
and it is a trick question because these public don't use or stable is being referenced from movies
.
There's a falling key relationship from movies pointing to the user id column.
So when I run this it tells me that you can't do that essentially cannot drop table users because other
objects depend on it the constrained videos use Radie foreign key on table videos.
The Pens on people users is quite a nice area.
And then it gives you a hint you may want to use drop cascade to drop the dependent objects too.
So by default what's happening here is we're doing drop table public dock users restrict and if we run
that we give you the same area naturally because that's what what's the default.
So if we don't type restrict then that's what's happening.
And what restricts does is it analyzes other tables incoming relationships.
And if any depend on this table then it tells you.
Wait a minute.
If you delete this table you're relationships in other tables are going to get screwed up.
So the only option that you've got is to use cascade.
And if you use cascade this is going to delete the rows in the I'm sorry my bad it's not gonna delete
any rows but this is going to do is going to delete the foreign key relationship between and the videos
table and they state.
So forget about the rows.
Nothing is going to get deleted in videos.
But what's going to happen is that the foreign key relationship that constraint is going to get deleted
.
So what does that mean.
Well it means that because we're deleting this table we're dropping it.
The videos table no longer can have a foreign key relationship a reference to this table.
So with Cascade we delete that reference we don't delete any data we just delete the reference.
So let's do that.
We've deleted the constraint.
But when we select staff from public videos the data is still there.
OK.
I'm going to now go into the other window and refresh the tables and you can see we've got videos here
.
And notice how the constraint am for foreign keys is not there and that constraint is there for example
in purchases.
And the constraint foreign key.
Blah blah blah that is a foreign key constraint that is no longer there in videos because we've deleted
the constraint by cascading and the deletion from dropping the user stable so that cascade does but
optionally The other solution is to delete the video Stabil first and then they use a stable.
That's also another option.
Drop table public videos that athletes not tape.
Notice is that if we try and do this again it gives us an era of say stable video that does not exist
.
You're trying to drop something that doesn't exist.
So there is a way to fix that which is drop table if exists.
Public videos.
And then it doesn't give you an error it just gives you a notice.
It is as video videos does not exist skipping.
And that's fine.
That's just so that if you want to create a table videos you naturally want to delete table video so
you don't create something that is already there.
So instead of drop table videos you may want to do drop table if it exists videos because if you don't
you'll get an error if it doesn't exist and then your program will crash.
So this is just useful in case you want to do drop table exists and then create table videos.
So that's why that's useful.
OK.
And that's how you drop tables.
And similarly you can drop data as well and you can drop sequence.
You can drop view when we're going to look at views very soon.
There's a there's a bunch of things you can drop.
And that's how you delete them and that's it.
So thanks for watching and I'll be seeing you in the next few videos.
We're going to be going into some more advanced Posterous sequel stuff such as views and dates and other
data types.
So I'll see you there.