I will come back in this video we're going to talk about raising our own CSX.
Now remember this cause is not about learning CSSA learning it's the metal etc..
So all I want to teach you in this video is how you can use these things from Python how you can embed
jiujitsu in them teach you a bit about essentially using this stuff with Python because that's where
the future is going.
But if you want to learn about history Eliseus has in more depth you're going to need to go online and
learn about that somewhere else because this court is not about HD and SS and Javascript.
OK.
Now writing a Rosia says and importing it from here it's actually fairly simple and it has a nice way
of flask has a nice way to do it.
So let's close up our templates tab and open up a new directory inside our project.
And I'm going to call that static now inside the static I'm going to get a new directory called CSX
.
And in s.c.s as I'm going to create a new file called style Dotsie SS You can call it whatever you want
as long as it ends with Dot.
Yes.
Now let's go back to our search down the mail page and presenter before the title.
And we're going to import another style sheet.
Make sure that your style sheet is after bootstraps style sheet because it says works by reading the
first file first and then the second file and so on.
So if bootstrap were to overwrite anything we write in our CSSA file then that won't happen if our test
file comes after.
I will type your link rail style sheet and hates ref which is the hypertext reference is going to be
you guessed it you are on the go for inside these curly braces.
And what we're going to put in there is going to be static and then filename equals CSSA slash style
those yesus.
So what we're doing now is we're accessing a special flask endpoint called static and this endpoint
allows us to define the file name we want to retrieve from the static folder.
So we're accessing the CSSA folder and in the CSSA folder there's a lot CSSA file.
So this is some special flask and Ginger code used to access static files.
OK.
So this is how we do that.
And that's it.
Now we can go into our style that CSSA and write our own the essays.
This is not again a complete introduction to see.
But I wanted to show you nevertheless how it works.
So let's go over to our search and we can see we've got this list here.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to push it down because it is too close to the top so I'm going to
push the list down.
And the way to do that we see a sense is to add a margin a margin just as some space between two elements
.
And in this case the speed is going to be between this an ordered list element.
Let's go into our.
Hey Jim if the space is going to be between the top of this an ordered list and the container.
So the bottom the container the top of the container is right now aligned with the top of the list.
That's why they're both up there.
And now we're going to push the list down by adding a margin to this an ordered list element.
OK.
The way we do that is there's a few ways we can either type UL and then open a close bracket.
And now any styling we write in say these curly braces are going to be applied for all unordered lists
in this page.
There are only one.
But if there were many it would apply to all.
Another option would be to type Daut list dash group and then the styling we write here would be applied
to all elements in the file that have this class list group which right now there's only one ul.
OK.
Another option would be to give the UL an ID to just tweets and finally go into a style Alosi essays
and type in the hash symbol tweets.
Now IDs in Haiti should be unique so this should only be one element with the ID tweets in your entire
page.
It's not a requirement.
You can have many if you want but it is recommended there's only one.
So you know when you write some CSSA if you're only affecting the element with the tweets that you're
only affecting one element.
And in this case this is what we want to do.
And then what we're going to be doing is adding margined at the top of the element.
So we will push it down some margin dash top.
We're going to say one RAM and a ram is a type of unit that change in size depending on the device.
So if you're using a phone the RAM will be quite small if you're using a desktop like I am right now
.
The ram will be quite big and that's good because it means that on smaller devices the spacing is still
reasonably consistent.
OK let's now refresh and as you can see there is a bit of space now looks a bit but ok.
Not everything I wanted to show you in this video.
I'm not going to go into massive styling because that's not the aim of this but I wanted to show you
how you can import your own stylesheet from within your pages using Jinja too.
And just a couple of knowledge bombs about CSI how you can access different things in CSX and how you
can apply your styles Naturally if you want to learn more about CSL which I would encourage you to do
which is a useful thing.
Then please do that and you will be able to style your pages a lot more nicely.
That's it for this video.
Thanks for watching and I'll see you in the very next one.