High will come back in this video we're going to allow users to search and I realized the title is maybe
not very clear.
We've already got the search endpoint and that has a query string parameter that the user can type directly
into the you or else to perform a search.
But really what I meant is we're going to be creating a form that the users can fill in so that they
can then perform the search more easily.
Let's open up our template file and go into the profile page when the user arrives at the profile page
.
They are already going to be logged in.
Which means the user can go from the profile page to the search page and that's fine.
And it wouldn't be fine if they are not logged in because the search page requires a user to be locked
in in order to perform the Twitter search using the API.
So we can allow the user to perform a search on Twitter from their profile if we put the form in the
home page.
The user may not be logged in at that point and then they will try to search and then it will fail because
they're not locked in.
So that's why I like to put it in the profile page instead.
At this point.
OK.
Well we're going to be doing is we're going to be writing some hated e-mail code which is going to display
a form.
The first thing to do is to type in form and include a tag and pyjamas should it may or may not close
it for you.
So the opening tag is just form and the closing tag is form but with the forward slash and then we're
going to do is put in an input and the input tag just creates a field and it creates a text field.
If the type is set to be text.
So that's just a text field where the users can type something and then we're going to set up two more
properties.
The name which is going to be q and the ID which is going to be q and clip and then we're also going
to set a button of pipe submit.
And here we're going to type in search.
So what this is doing is we're creating a field a text field which we're calling.
Q And has the idea you were going to go into what the queue is a moment and then we're also going to
create a button of type submit the buttons of type submit when they get pressed they send the form some
way.
And when we send the form the content of the text field we get sent where we specify.
OK let's go into our log in which would this is what we've got right now in the profile page we've got
a text field and we've got a search button.
OK.
Now we can also add a placeholder
and we can either placeholder make it equal to your Twitter search or anything else.
And we will refresh.
Now that's kind of they are grayed out and we can start typing on top.
OK.
So that just gives the user a bit of a bit more information regarding what they might be expected to
type.
However it is best to also put a label label that describes what the input field this fall.
So let's do that.
We're going to put in a label and four is going to be q and that Q is the ID.
Q And the label is going to say something like Twitter search and when we refresh we now get that with
a search there.
OK.
Now when we press search.
Nothing really seems to happen let's type something in here.
Hello.
The press search and as you can see they there's a queue Hello up there.
So when we press search we generated a query string parameter called Q and MIGA equal to Haloo.
Now if we can instead of worrying when we do that like high for example what happened is that we stay
on this page but it refreshes and with the pretty strong parameter if we can instead of staying on this
page send the user over to the search page with the query string parameter that is going to perform
the search essentially.
Because with that query string parameter we're going to be able to read it and then pass it in to that
with a request like so.
So go to our profile page and here make sure that it says action equals you are on the SQL for search
and sorry this should be called I think Twitter search.
Now just search OK that's fine.
So what that's going to do is it's going to instead of send the data to the same page that the form
is in it's going to send the data to a different page and the page is going to send it to is that you
are out of there.
OK let's refresh.
And now perform the search like cars
and there we go.
We're searching now for cars only as you can see the query string is only cars and we could limit that
further by going here and see a plus filter images for example.
And now we get that there.
And these are just encoded but they still mean and plus and color.
So that's how we could create a simple form to send the user to the search page after they've typed
something in an input field which we call queue this queue.
There is the name of the query string parameter.
So that's the question mark.
Q That's happening.
OK.
So that's how you create a simple form.
And again I reiterate this is not a similar course.
So please if you want to learn more about this go ahead and do that now you're learning about serving
these contents with Python.
Learning more about the mail and see essays and Javascript is always a good thing as well.
OK.
That's it for this video.
And thanks for that.
And in the next video we're going to be doing sentiment analysis which is going to be very interesting
.
We're going to be able to color our tweets differently depending on whether the people writing the tweet
were angry or happy things like that.
So let's do that in our next video.
And I'll see you there