are a lot of ways that you could make this better such as adding a menu bars and improper logging and
registration areas not only using Twitter but also maybe Facebook integration.
There's a lot more things that we could do.
But nevertheless I think it has achieved its purpose which was to teach about auth about API about Twitter
logging and also about creating an interface with flask.
Now if you'd know which TMLC a sense that is endless amount you can do with this sort of knowledge in
terms of interacting with your program through the web but that said for this section.
So I hope you enjoyed that.
And we're going to leave it here for now in terms of flask and we're going to be moving on to more advanced
life and stuff over the next couple of sections and I'm excited about that because it's going to take
you from sort of someone who can write a bit of Python code to do some things to someone who really
understands the algorithms data structures behind the different areas of computing.
So without further ado let's go there.
I'm excited to get you introduced to algorithms and data structures and I'll see you in the very next
video.0:01:35.930
And that comes out with a label negative and then they have the text.
Hi friend.
And that ends up being more or less neutral.
OK.
So this is quite interesting and we're going to we're going to be doing is calling this API on our tweets
and then coloring the field differently.
The list field lists index items like this item different depending on the label.
So if it's positive we're going to collect green if it's negative we're going to color it red and if
it's neutral already blue.
Let's go over to pite charm and have a look at how we might go about doing that.
We've got a list of tweet text and this is the tweet content essentially.
So we want to pass that through their API.
OK.
To analyze the sentiment of some text the documentation says do an hasty T.P. post to this address here
with form encoded data containing the text you want to analyze.
And we're going to get back just an object responds with two attributes.
The label on the probability like we see here.
OK.
So let's do that.
Let's perform a hasty post on some of that text in order to perform HAGE-ALI post.
We are going to be using this time because this is not using auth.
We're going to be using the requests library as we learned previously.
Now notice this is requests with an S at the end and I say it's not request without this.
This variable here is part of flask requests.
It's a different library entirely.
We're going to be for me before we're able to import that library.
We're going to have to put it in our requirements.
So let's go there and put requests here then go back to app and I just should tell you that you should
install requests if you don't have it already installed.
But it's possible though you already do.
And I do.
So if you do have it installed then you won't be prompted to install it.
But if you don't have install that you will let's import that import this name and you want to import
requests like so and we're going to do a post.
And then what are we going to do.
Is the Eurail that we want to send data to and retrieve data from which is this API you are ill as the
documentation tells us and then the data that we want to send a Says form encoded data containing the
text you want to our allies.
So it has to be a text equal the text that we want to analyze.
So this is a dictionary of data that we want to send.
And in this case the text that we want to send is that the tweet itself.
OK.
So here will be the tweet itself.
When we do this we're going to be assigning that to a variable
and then what we're going to get back is a Jason response which is going to be equal to our Don.
Jason this is going to retrieve the Jason contents of the request.
I'm going to assign those two Jewson response variable and the label is going to be Jason responds label
.
So the label field that is in here is inside the Jason and we wanna put that in the label there and
then we want to associate that label with a specific tweet.
So the way we're going to do that in this instance is we're going to put these tweets in a dictionary
where it's going to be tweet and label
like so.
So we've modified the list comprehension.
So instead of only the tweet text now we are appending a dictionary for each tweet and the dictionary
contains the tweet content under the key tweet and the label under the key label.
In this case the key the label is always neutral but we're going to be changing that down here.
OK.
So how would we iterate over the tweets in here in this list as I'm sure you know we've done plenty
of times for tweet in tweet texts.
We're going to be doing all of this only instead of the text being the tweet itself.
It's going to be tweet tweet so we're accessing the key tweet inside each of the tweets in the list
that we are creating
and the label is then going to go into tweet label equals label.
OK.
So to recap what we've changed this instead of getting only the text and putting those in a list.
We are now creating a list of dictionaries where each dictionary has the tweet content and also a label
which is neutral by default then we're iterating over the tweets and for each tweet we are performing
that request to the text processing API with data equal to a text key that has the tweet contents and
that has to be a dictionary there.
Then we're getting the Jason in that response.
We're getting the label that is in that Jason and we are assigning that to a variable label.
And finally we're putting that label inside the tweet label.
Then we're going to return the tweets.
OK.
Take your time to read through that and understand it or make sure to know what's going on there.
But that's everything we need them and then what we're going to do is go over to the search file here
and we're going to color things in differently depending on the label.
But first of all let's just run the app.
Go in there.
Log with Twitter.
And notice how I'm there and perform a search.
So this takes a bit longer because now we're not only getting the tweets back.
We're also getting a label which has positive label positive or label neutral or sometimes label negative
.
So now we have a label as well as a Tweet what we want to print out here is just the tweet.
So in our For loop where we're printing up the list items we're going to say element tweet like so.
And now all that's going to get printed out is the tweet content itself.
But we want to make sure that we can change the color of the background depending on the label.
So we're going to change the color of the background by doing something like this instead of Plast equal
list group item.
We're going to give this list element to see SS classes.
So we're going to say list group item and then space and then we're going to put a different class in
CSSA you can add multiple classes by just separating them with a space.
So here we're going to say list group item danger.
OK.
And when we do that all of these list items are going to be read.
So let's save that on refresh.
So now we should see all of them been red
keep Now we are only seeing the text content and we've only got read labels or read Field List items
.
So we don't want them to be read.
We want them to be read.
If the label is negative or green if it is positive I'm blue if it is neutral.
So I'm going to do a bit of Jinja sort of magic here where I'm going to inside these percent calibrates
percent thing sort of tokens.
I'm going to put in set see I set on the school class equal list group item default instead of default
let's use info default I think has been discontinued now and then this class is going to be equal to
list group item info.
So what we're doing here is we're just creating a new variable.
And in ginger too we need to use the word set.
So basically what this is doing is setting a new variable called CSX class to be equal to list group
item in instead of down here having that class.
We can just have CSL on the school class and that is going to be replacing the value of that variable
in there.
So if we were to refresh now everything would be blue but let's not do that because you should believe
me when I when I say that is what's going to.
Then we want to do if because in ginger too we can also do if statements if element label is negative
and naturally we're going to want to put this inside the for loop if the element label is negative.
We want to set CSSA class to be equal to list group item danger.
So that's going to make it red.
And then if just like in Python element label is positive we want to set the class to be the list group
item and then bootstrap.
This is called success.
And finally and if so let's go over this again just to make sure that everything is clear.
What we're doing now is we first of all create a CSX class variable a variable just called CSX class
and we give it a value list item.
In fact this is a bootstrap class that colours in the list Gloup item blue plothole it does essentially
.
And then we're going to iterate over each of the tweets and if the tweets label is Knigge which is for
negative then we're going to set the CSSA class to be list group item danger which once again is a bootstrap
class that colors it red.
Elif if this is not true but the element label is positive then we're going to set the squares as class
to B list group items success.
And finally we're ending the if so by default the CSSA class is going to be listening to and and info
.
But if the label is negative we're going to change it to danger.
And if it's positive we're going to change it to success.
And finally we're going to just as before and create that list item with the class list group item and
the class defined above.
OK let's refresh
and it turns out that most of these were positive except for the last one.
And these are actually these aren't live from Twitter so they're coming through really quickly.
So we can try and refresh and see if we can add a different set of orders or it is quite slow.
We're not getting a difference at this time.
We're too quick.
This is quite slow because it is not only retrieving the tweets from Twitter but also it is performing
that API call of the sentiment analysis for each of these tweets.
So it does take a while.
OK.
But that is how we could introduce a bit of sentiment analysis on this code and that is also how we
can show all the tweets different colors for them and start making a bit of a nicer interface.