Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to look at boolean expressions Boullion.
The word comes from a guy called George Boole who is a mathematician from the UK and he was the pioneer
of this boolean logic and essentially boolean logic.
All it is is a set of operators that allow us to decide whether something is true or false.
Some of these we already know for example 5 is greater than 3.
That is a boolean expression and evaluates to true.
So how could you in Python represent that.
Let's create a variable called greater than 3 and then make it equal to something.
And this is going to be five is greater than 3.
Take a guess as to how you could represent this five greater than three.
In Python
The answer is using the mathematical operator for greater than.
Which is the crocodile clip looking to the right.
So five greater than three returns a boolean value.
So let's say greater than 3 and that will give us the value of a variable which we know contains the
result of this expression which is true not is true comes with a capital T.
And that's important in Python.
So now we've got the ability to evaluate whether something is greater than or less than or equal to
.
How would you evaluate whether something is equal to 5.
So let's create a variable equal to 5.
And now remember one equals sign is used to assign a value.
So for example equal to 5.
In this case 5 would be coming in and be assigned to a variable.
So how would you compare five with five to verify that it is equal to 5.
So what we want here is say equal to 5 it's true if this number is equal to 5.
So the answer to that if we use another equal sign then this is also assignment.
So here what we're doing is we're assigning 5 to 5 and they are assigning 5 to equal to 5 and we don't
really want to do that.
What we want to do is say equal to 5 is true because 5 and 5 are the same.
So what we do is we use two equal signs instead of one.
So now we've got equal to 5 is the result of five equal equal five.
So equal equal means we're comparing their values.
So we're saying five is five.
Five is equal to five.
Yes that's true.
So this evaluates to true and that goes into equal to 5 that are now equal to 5 contains the value truth
.
Notice that we don't have to assign this to a variable we can just say five equal equals five.
And that gives us truth as well.
Similarly five less than three give us false because five is greater than three.
And also we can do things like five greater than or equal to six.
But if is false five greater than or equal to 5 gives us true and five greater than 5 gives us false
because five and five are equal one is not greater on the other.
So that's why it gives us false.
So knowing all of this create a for loop that will print whether each of the numbers in our numbers
list is greater than 5.
So it is a bit more challenging than before.
But the only thing we have to print is true.
If the number is greater than 5 or false if it's less than 5.
So let's create the for loop for number in numbers.
Now we are iterating over the numbers list.
So number is going to be first 0 then 1 then 2 and so on.
And what we want to do here is print number is greater than 5.
And what this will do is if number is zero then zero greater than 5 is not true.
It will print false then it's 1 and 5 Element falls and so on until it gets to 6 6 and 5 that's true
.
So what we're going to be seeing is six forces and then four troops which is exactly what we would expect
This is for the value 0 1 2 3 4 and 5.
They are all less than or equal to 5.
And finally six is the first number that is greater than 5 6 7 8 and 9 are all true.
OK.
So this is not too useful.
Ideally what we would want to do is print this number is greater and 5 as opposed to printing.
True.
So we're going to look at exactly how we can do that in the next video by looking at if statements.
So I see you there