Find Welcome Back in this video we're looking at moving around and using the terminal.
The terminal is just an interface to your operating system.
What I've got here is the finder which in Mac is just like the Windows Explorer.
It shows me the files that are available in one of my folders and we all know how this kind of works
.
And as you can see here I've got two files which start with a full stop.
And for those that were full stop or period they are hidden files and they are created by the operating
system so don't worry about these two files.
I know that they are there but they don't really mean anything.
Well we're going to do in this video I'm going to show you why and how the terminal behaves when compared
to the sort of normal way of interacting with the system.
The first command that I want to show you in the terminal is going to be the command clear and the clear
command just clears the terminal and if you have a lot of stuff written down then it just kind of goes
up and at it puts a bunch of whitespace above the after the command.
So let's you clear your workspace a bit of that sort on ice because the terminal can get a bit messy
.
If you write a lot of stuff OK but command doesn't really do anything except modify the terminal and
it may not work in some systems.
So that's just something if you're using a Mac or a terminal that supports it that's something you can
then ask them on that I wanted to show you is a command called PWT the P.W. the command stands for present
working directory and basically that tells you which folder you're currently in.
So if I type enter it shows as being slash uses slash JSL VTR slash desktop and I'm going to go over
to my desktop folder which is here when I move it down a wee bit so you can see.
And as you can see the path that is shown here by right clicking on the finer.
I'm going to show you the path is in Macintosh HD which is my hard drive and I know that is in my laptop
but this is not showing the path to a Macintosh.
HD is the hard drive them in and it you save the users JSL with the desktop fold and package the is
the hard drive and that is represented by the initial forward slash the initial four was like is the
current hard drive.
And if you're in Windows and you type this using the Get shell then you may see something like this
.
See slash and blah blah blah blah blah blah blah.
Which is essentially the same thing.
So C is the hard drive or the partition that you're in.
And then each of the sub folders is the subfolder that you're in.
So in this case I mean desktop which is McIndoe HD they the user's folder that JSL Salvati folder and
inside that there's a desktop for it.
And indeed if I go to jail cell of Batya you can see somewhere in here there's a best of four.
And if I go in it then I'm going to Best up which is where the terminal is currently at.
You can find out where you're at by typing PWT the folder I'm currently in is here shown as desktop
and if I go to a different folder then this thing here will change to show the folders name that I'm
currently in but to get the full path you need to type PWT.
So how do we go to a different folder.
Well that's done with the cd command.
It stands for change directory.
We can for example go to the JSL VTR folder which is the parent folder the parent folder just means
that it contains the Desktop folder.
So the Desktop folder is inside the JSL VITTIA folder.
And if I want to go up a level if I want to go to the parent folder the only thing I have to do is type
CD.
And then two periods and then as you can see I'm in now in the U.S. slash JSL VTR folder.
This is a special folder because the JSL VTR user which is the user which I use to log in to this computer
is the user that I'm currently logged in as.
So the current user is JSL Batya that's me and the users slash JSL which folder is this user's home
folder.
Essentially the folder that belongs to this user.
And that's also a special folder and it's as shown as this small Tildy.
So that really just means and slash user slash genocide.
Or if you're using your own user then it could be slash users slash your user name.
Let's go once again into the Desktop folder by typing CD desktop.
And now let's go onto the next command which is to create a directory in these terminals that's known
as make a directory and the command is M-K there for make directory and then here after we can a space
and then type in the directory name that we want the terminal does not allow us.
Not easily to type spaces in directory names because this base is used to tell the terminal that this
is a different command or something like that.
So if you want to use spaces you need to use quotation marks to type your directory name.
And if not you can just type it without quotation marks.
So I'm going to create a directory cast and that's what they do that.
You'll see it appear here on the Desktop folder.
There you go.
So that is the folder and I'm going to go into the folder by doing CD test.
So now this terminal is inside the test folder.
So let's create another directory and then go in and see if that has worked.
I'm going to create a directory once again with empty dirt and it's going to be work and always and
it doesn't appear because we are not inside that folder.
But if I go in it the work directory is there.
Now let's delete that directory because it is a test directory to delete something just to r m for remove
.
And if it is a directory if it is a folder we need to also type Dasch are.
And then we can type in the directory or we want to remove.
And that is now disappeared.
Notice that this dot D.S. store file has appeared and Mac puts that in there automatically whenever
we access a folder using the Finder which I am doing.
So we are in the Test folder.
Now let's go back up to the Desktop folder.
And surely you remember how to do that.
And it is CD.
And then the parent folder is always two periods.
So now I am once again in a desktop folder.
OK.
That's everything for this video.
We've learned how to get the current directory how to change directory and how to make Burek trees.
And we've also looked at what the Tildy is which is the user's home directory.
The purpose of this video was just to show you a bit about how the terminal works because we're going
to be needing just a tiny bit of knowledge so we can interact with Gates a bit more easily.
So without further ado I'll see you in the next video.