Hi and welcome back in this video we're looking at the interactive python shell the python shell is
a program that is fantastic for rapid development.
This is because every command that you type in the python shell if it is valid Python the python shell
will run it evaluate evaluated instantly and give you instant feedback.
It's great when you're developing large applications to have a python shell beside you so that you can
quickly test what you are doing and you don't make any silly mistakes.
So what does a python shell do.
Well as you said it's an interactive python environment Python interpreter.
So it runs.
Any Python code that you put in it.
So let's type some Python statements in here and see how the python shell copes with that.
Python is a language that is more so than others geared towards some mathematical uses.
That doesn't mean that Python is a scientific language by any means but it does have some mathematical
operators.
And it can be used for some mathematical purposes.
So something that we can do in Python and in most of the languages is type some basic math.
For example two plus two we evaluate Python will see this as something that is valid Python because
Python can add two numbers and then it will tell us okay that's fine and we'll evaluate this statement
when we press enter.
I'm going to do that now and then we get out the value for which is where we would expect.
OK.
So similarly we can do the same thing with multiplication.
Notice that in programming and indeed mostly in computers the multiplication sign is the asterisk.
And if we do this we will also get the number four.
And just so you can check that I'm not lying if we do two times three.
We get the number six which is completely OK.
So here's a small question for you.
See if you can guess the answer to this one.
What happens in Python if we do two times times three.
So we have two times signed in there what do you think is going to happen.
Is he going to give his backing number or is he going to give us an error.
Well in most programming languages this would give you an error.
It would say What are you doing two times times is is nonsense.
However as I said Python does have some mathematical uses.
So when we do this it gives his back to evaluate which is 2 to the power of three.
So two times two times two gives us eight and that's what the double time signs means.
OK.
So this is the plate and shell we haven't looked at much Python code yet but we know that the python
shell can run Python statements and it evaluates them instantly and gives us instant feedback which
is fantastic when we want to test things or verify that things are valid.
So for this section we're going to be developing in the pipe and show and in the coming section we're
going to be moving on to something more suited for larger application development.
But for this section we're going to get just acquainted with Python just going to start with Python
and we're going to stick to ywis which is a fantastic tool.
OK.
So and so you in the next video