Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to continue with our app and we're going to enable it
to create some random numbers so that we can then compare those with the play numbers and then calculate
the winnings after that what we did in the last video was this first part.
So what we wanted to do in this video.
It's the second part here to calculate the six random numbers between 1 and 20.
So the way we're going to do this is once again in a method and I'm going to create this method create
lottery numbers and this method is going to initialize an empty set and then it's going to populate
that sent with empty numbers and make sure that the set has six numbers at the end.
So the first part you can do initialize an empty set.
So go ahead and try that.
And I'm sure you can do it.
So as we've seen before the way we initialize an empty set is we see the set name the variable equals
set room of that a set is always represented as being inside the curly braces.
But in python we initialize an empty set.
Using this we cannot initialize like so.
So don't initialize an empty set like that because in Python that means something different.
OK so now that we've got the empty set we want to add numbers to the set.
So let's do that.
We want to add six numbers.
So therefore we can do a for loop.
Right.
We know how to do a for loop between that iterates over six numbers and then we can add six random numbers
into our set.
You guys know how to do a for loop that runs six times.
So go ahead and try it out.
You can use the range method for that.
OK.
So the way I would do it is see for index in range 6 and this will run six times Ramba range is 0 1
2 3 4 and 5.
So index it will start at 0 and then it will be 1 and 2 then 3 and 4 and 5.
So in total it'll run six times.
We're not going to use the index variable in the for loop because we're going to be creating random
numbers but nevertheless the index variable goes from zero to 5 in order to generate random numbers
.
We're going to have to import the random modules.
Let's put that to the top and then we can say values Daut and random dot Rand in between 1 and 20.
And this is going to add to the values array which show the values set.
Right I'm at the end with return values.
OK.
So in theory this should work right.
We are initializing an empty set.
Then we are going over six times this fall loop and then we're adding a random number between 1 and
20 to the values sent six times and then we're returning the values set.
So let's run that
and see what happens.
What do you think is going to happen when we run this.
Well what I expect to happen is that everything will work more or less OK but with a minor caveat.
See we've only got five numbers in here.
We want to run that again.
And there we go.
Here we go six numbers.
The first two times we ran the SAT the generation we only got 5 numbers and now we've got six numbers
here.
So why could this be why.
What is wrong with our create lottery numbers method that it is allowing the set to have either five
or six numbers.
And what is wrong is that the random number generator can generate the same number twice.
It doesn't.
It doesn't generate.
Always a different number because there's only 20 to choose from.
So in this case in two of those cases actually the number generated was already in the set and that
meant that we couldn't put it in the set.
Again because the Sanch don't have duplicates.
So what we wanted to do is not this for a loop because this fordable always want to run six times.
And really what we wanted to do is run it until the values set has six numbers in it which is not to
say the same thing that Foley was going to run six times.
So with the number generator generates the same number twice.
That means our set is going to end up with five numbers.
What we want to do is run the loop until our set has six values.
So the way we can do that is with a WHILE loop in a while we get a new contract that we've not seen
yet but it is similar to the for loop.
The way it works is that we say a while and then we give a condition.
And as long as that condition is true then the loop will continue running.
So how do you think we should put this into Python code.
We want to run this loop while the set does not have six elements.
So I hope you gave that ago.
And the way I do it is I would say a while the length of the values sent is less than six.
I'm going to keep adding When the length is 6 or more which it shouldn't be then I'm going to stop the
while loop and I'm going to return values.
So this loop this code here is going to run as many times as it needs.
While the length of the center the number of elements in the set is less than six.
OK.
So let's save that and run that again and that how now we've gone there six numbers.
I'm going to run it again.
Now right now we've got six numbers and so.
So trust me we'll always get six numbers from now on Woods and this is how you use a while loop and
how you would create these random lottery numbers.
It is a bit more work because you need to make sure that you've got six numbers all the time and that
you have to use sets which is something that's under used in Python.
But now that you've got the two cents it's really easy to check how many the user got right just by
doing an intersection.
So we're going to be doing that in the very next video and see you there.