Hi will come back in this video we're going to be preparing to log in with Twitter and what I've done
here is created a new project created a virtual environment for it.
And now we're just going to be setting this thing up so we can log in with Twitter.
The first thing to do is right click your project go to new file and type in requirements tot he XTi
.
And that's going to be the file that as you know is going to hold in that dependencies.
So the Python libraries that our project depends on in order for other people to be able to just install
what we write in here.
So the library is going here should be cheap installable libraries.
This is we should be able to install them with Pipp.
What I'm going to write is off too as that is a library that we're going to be using in this sort of
logging with Twitter flow and it's used to just simplify the off process which Twitter Facebook Google
Plus and others use them.
I'm going to go and Right-Click the project and create a new python file which I'm going to call constant
.
Now I've already got off to install them in a virtual environment.
But if you don't you'll get a nice window up here saying that you don't have it installed just install
or two.
If you don't have it installed already and you'll be fine.
Now we need a few constants here and I'm going to create a file with constants in them just so it's
a bit easier to access those constants the constants we need or the consumer consumer consumer key.
The consumer secret.
And these two are part of our couter application.
And then we need a request token you RL which is going to be part of the Twitter API and it's going
to it's going to be the you are the we request or other we ask a request token of then when the access
token you are able and we need the authorization.
You are right.
So these are the concerns we need and we're going to have to go and find them on our application.
So let's go there.
The first thing to do is go to your application and copy the consumer and the consumer secret and paste
them in here consumer key consumer secret and then these other three requests can you read access to
can you tell us an authorization yourself.
Those are part of the Twitter API.
So let's go to the API documentation.
Def dot dot com slash overview slash documentation and you'll get a Web site like this and we can go
to auth there because this is not a web application.
What we are creating it is a console application at least for now.
We're going to need to use that PIN code that I talked about in an earlier video so that where we want
to go is to pin based off.
And here you have an overview where pin based off is and essentially is the same thing as implementing
something with Twitter and the three legged authorization.
Well the only difference being that the value for all the Colback must be said to be.
And also here at some point the user sees a pin code that they have to give you back.
So this is the pin code.
They have to copy and give back to your application.
OK.
So we're going to need a few things.
We're going to need the request token you.
So that we can get a new request token.
We're going to need the access token you or else so we can get a new access token once we've gotten
that authorization code and we're going to need the authorize you RL which is used to request a user
authorization that is to get the authorization pin code.
OK.
So let's just copy those.
This is the request token you know we're going to need the access token you which is used to get an
access token.
Once we have the PIN code we need the authorization you RL which you use to get a new pin code.
This is what users are gonna go to in order to say yes I agree to sign in with Twitter for this.
Now that we have these Constans here we are ready to move to the next video and we're going to be starting
the log in process.
Another option was to just do everything in one video but it will be quite long and I don't really want
to bore you too much.
So let's split it up and I'll see you in the very next video we're going to get started with this.
So I'll see you there.