Hi will come back.
And really we're looking at creating a queue.
Now we've looked at it.
Q EAS which is just like a real life.
Q Where people go in at the end and leave from the front.
Let's look at how we might program a Q Using the linked list that we've already created.
Let's remind ourselves what can you do it can add a new element which is just a note at the end.
Or you can remove an element from the beginning.
You can also find its size or tell us its size and print itself out.
So just sort of normal housekeeping things so that would be a push method.
I'm going to call the method push but as it is the normal sort of name for it.
But you can call it whatever you want to add a new element at the end.
It's pushing an element Pop is going to remove an element from the beginning.
Size is going to get its size and print it's going to print the queue.
So in the next video we're going to be creating a waiting list queue for a phone house so it will hold
the name and telephone number of each person in the waiting list and we can add or remove people from
it.
If so that AM For example the people that are waiting for the calls can then received the calls in order
and the order they were made.
So we're going to go with A.
The holes nodes.
Each node has a name and a telephone number.
Excuse me.
How to implement it.
You then what we're going to use the linked list that we created previously where each node is going
to hold the data relevant which is the name and telephone number instead of generator.
And this means we have to modify the Node class to include these two variables instead of the name matriculation
number and year of study that we used last time.
But that's not a big deal.
I'm sure you can do that change a couple of variables around and the that would be fine.
So how do we add an element to the end instead of adding at the end and removing at the beginning.
We can just reverse them and add at the beginning and remove at the end.
That's doing the same thing but in reverse order.
So both of these things work fine.
The end result is that the things are going in first and coming out first.
You can pause the video here and have a think about it if that's not clear.
So instead of adding at the end removing at the beginning we're just going to add at the beginning and
remove at the end so that the same thing is going to happen.
So the push method because we're adding now at the beginning we can just use the linked lists add to
list method and realize in the last presentation this was using camel case as opposed to pants on case
.
But that's fine.
I mean the method name the pop method is going to remove an element from the end and then the side is
going to get the size and print in the print itself so the push is just going to be our add to list
method.
We're not really going to cover that.
It's just going to be the same thing as before but now we're going to have a pop method which is going
to remove an element from the end of the list.
So what if you make this pop method to remove an element from the last element in the queue.
And how do we do this.
Well let's have a look.
We're going to get this second to last node and then we're going to make the node to which this note
is pointing to equal to none.
And then is going to do the work to actually delete the last note from memory.
So let's take a look at a more visual explanation.
I know that this text is a bit confusing.
We're going to make the node to which the second to last note is pointing to equal to them.
So we've got our node which has a name or telephone variable.
It also has the next node as before and the first node might be George with that telephone number and
the next node might be Anna with that telephone number and the next node might be Philipe with that
telephone number and finally the next node is none.
So this is once again our usual 3 node queue.
In this case that's the first node that is the second to last node.
It's not the last one is the one before.
And as a last note scenario we're counting from the end here Philip is the last node and is the second
to last node and Georgia is the third to last node release the first note.
If this was a 2 node linked list then George would be the second to last node and I would be the last
note.
OK so what we want to do is we want to iterate over our queue and find the second to last node.
We're going to look at how we can do that in code later on.
And then instead of pointing to Philipe we just make it point to none.
And although we're not explicitly destroying this node we're not just telling Python to delete it from
memory.
Python will realize that nothing is pointing to this node and it will be removed from memory for us
and then we'll end up with a 2 node queue
so the next method would be the size and only to find the size would just iterate over and go through
all of the nodes in our linked list queue.
We create a variable that would store the number of nodes we've gone through each time we visit the
new node.
We increase the variable by 1 and eventually when we get to a next to no there is none we stop increasing
and we return that value.
So we're just going to count each of the nodes in our queue.
The print method is just like the size but instead of increasing a variable we're just going to print
the node's details out and to implement this.
Let's take a look in the next video on how we might go about programming a few.
But before we do that I would encourage you to try to program it yourself with a knowledge that you've
got now.
Knowing what the methods are meant to do and with a linked list that we've already got I would encourage
you to try to program this yourself before we continue.
But if not I'll be seeing you in the very next few shorts either.