Hard work a Mac in this world you we're going to be creating our own exceptions.
Now in the last video I mentioned that sometimes it's better to not catch everything or rather not deal
with everything because then if you just get a lot of things printed out you may skip some errors.
In many instances it is better for the error to appear for the error to crash an application so that
you can realize that the error is there.
When that happens maybe a Jason de-code error or a key error is not the best error to receive.
Maybe you don't really know what that is or am I don't know.
Maybe you think a key error just means that's the Jason wasn't ready or the response was incorrect but
rather what you would have is a missing label error.
For example instead of adjacent decode error maybe you would rather have a incorrect Jason response
error or something along those lines.
So what we can do in some of these instances is create our own exception so I'm going to create a new
play in file and call it create exceptions to create your own exception.
It's really simple.
All you have to do is say class then your exception name.
For example missing label error.
We should be a subclass of key area and I should be a subclass of Kibera.
If that is appropriate.
So if the missing label error is a key error is missing from a dictionary.
In this case if it's missing from a class for example or missing from a web site you may have to supply
a different era.
Which ever you subclass isn't the most important thing.
But it just gives you a bit more information.
Similarly you could have a class page not found error that could be a subclass of lookup error.
You could have incorrect password error that could be a subclass of value error.
You can have a class API throttle limit error which could be a subclass of runtime error.
So why am I.
Why am I telling you all these things.
Well in some cases you can receive a value error and that's fine.
In other cases you may want a bit more granularity in what your exceptions mean and in those cases creating
your own.
Even if they are just value errors with a different name because that's what this is.
It gives you just a bit more information.
You can have for example class incorrect user name error
and these two classes really are the same thing.
They're both value errors.
They don't add anything to value error but they have different names.
When you see that in your code you're going to know.
OK I know what happened and also you can catch them and do things differently with both.
What I mean with that is say you have a user trying to log in to your application and they give you
their username and password and you know that the username doesn't exist in the database.
You could raise an incorrect username error and then the user would see that this is an incorrect username
error.
For example this is how you raise exceptions by the way raise incorrect username error.
That if we run this you can see there that we get the traceback and we get incorrect user name error
so something happen.
See we have our program program user enters wrong username and your program raises an incorrect username
.
OK so you have this method that is logging in and the user enters the wrong details and we raise an
incorrect username error.
What you would do is you would say try and log in and you would catch incorrect username error or not
catch sorry except I keep thinking Java terms and you would print here.
Your username was incorrect.
Have you forgotten it and you would also accept an incorrect password error and here you would say print
your password was wrong.
Have you forgotten it.
So when we run this we get you using was incorrect.
Have you forgotten it because the logon method raised an incorrect username.
If this raised an incorrect password error we would get your Paschall was wrong.
Have you forgotten it now.
This is not very useful like this but when we ask a user to log in say in a web site a logging method
that takes in a username and password may raise an incorrect password error and if that is the case
maybe you'd want your web application to redirect the user to a.
Have you forgotten your password page.
For example if they forgot the username.
Maybe you want to refresh the page and show them an error message.
What you want to do doesn't matter.
But now you can reuse different errors when different things happen and then deal with them in different
ways.
And that's always nice and also it's a very Pythonic way of doing things.
So definitely recommended that when you encounter a situation that you cannot fix raise an error for
it and you can deal with it in a different level of your application.
OK that's everything for this video I just wanted to show you that you can create your own exceptions
and we could even use them here instead of Jewson the code error we could create our own and use it
there and maybe with a better name as I was mentioning at the beginning but that's it you can create
your own exceptions.
Give them good names subclass of valuable built in error classes and that will give you a lot of info
and in the very next video we're actually going to be looking into some of the built in classes so that
you are not completely in the blank with this.
I'll see you in the very next video