Hi welcome back another we have these constants.
It means that we don't have to go back to the Web sites and get them when we are ready to proceed and
start creating our Twitter log in.
Let's go into the project right click that and create a new Peyton and file which I'm going to call
logon dot p y.
And this is going to be essentially what's going to allow us to log in with Twitter.
There's a couple of things we need.
One of them is the Constance files or import Constans.
The other one is the off to library import auth to.
OK.
We're going to need a third library but we're going to do that a bit later on.
We don't need it immediately.
OK.
So there's a few steps that we have to follow in order to log in with Twitter.
The first thing is to create a consumer.
The consumer is an object which represents our application.
And this is part of the oath to liberty.
So the consumer equals off to dot consumer.
So this consumer is a class inside the auth to library and we're putting this consumer inside a variable
called consumer or lowercase.
This can be anything you want.
Remember in order to be able to identify our app we need to use the app constants.
Essentially these secrets here these consumer key and consumer seek.
So let's pass those in to the consumer.
So we're Pozen and Constans the consumer key which is the consumer key we've read from our constants
and after the comma Constans not consume a secret which is the secret key that we've passed in from
our constant together those to allow Twitter to identify this app.
So this tweet analyzer app that we've just created.
However the consumer is just used to identify the app.
It can be used to make requests so it can be used to request things from an API.
Instead we have to create a client.
So let's create a client.
So I not see small c.
So the client is going to be a client object which lives inside the author to library and it needs the
parameter which is the consumer.
The application that this client is going to be making requests for.
Then we can do client request.
Now this is different from the way we were requesting things before.
Before we were doing requests dog get for example by using the requests library.
Now we are using this client that we've created to do the request instead.
This is because Twitter goes very well with this.
Off to library it makes sense to use this library instead of request.
But normally when you want to retrieve pages from the internet or interact with other API as you would
be using the requests library which is why I showed you it inside these request method when you to put
in the you or I that we wouldn't request.
So do you remember the first you were Elda we need to request in this off process.
The answer is until you get it is the request token you are able.
And this is going to make Twitter create a request token going back to safari.
We can see that at the request token your role is a post you were real.
So at the end of this bracket after the coma we're going to put in post.
So the first parameter the first argument that we're passing the request method claimed the request
is that you are l.
The second parameter is what type of verb we want to use for that request and this case it's a post
that's what Twitter expects.
However in this case the Twitter and saltless going to request during the week even though it's a post
the Twitter API does not expect anything in the post body.
So the post-party has come up empty and we don't have to send anything back.
Sorry we don't have to send anything to the API there.
OK.
So what is this going to do.
Well we would expect it to return something and indeed it does.
It returns a response and also returns some content.
So we're going to see a response my content equals that.
And then these two variables here are going to get populated with the thing that gets returned by this
request method.
We're assuming that the content is going to be some sort of identification some sort of request token
and the response is going to give us some details as to what happened during this exchange.
So basically did the exchange succeed or not.
OK and then we're going to see if response and Dot status is not two hundred.
If you remember the two hundred code means that everything went well.
So if this Summer school is not 200 it means something didn't go well.
We can say print an error occurred requesting gaining the request tokens from Twitter.
And finally let us sign the request token to a variable.
I'm going to create a variable called request token and I'm going to give it to be equal to dict.
And here is where we are going to be needing our second library and there's going to be you Arel parse
.
There's a library we need.
So let's import your parse import your ad lib dot parse as you autoparts.
Now if you're using Python 2.7 you will just have to import your old parts because we're using them
3.5.
We have to import.
You are a lib dot parse and we as just renames it so that we can call it your Parsky.
So we're accessing the you are a lib dot parser library but we're calling it your parsed in this file
so we can access it like that and then we're doing a parser not parsing QSL.
And then we're going to put in the content there.
OK so what is this.
Well the content is in the format of a query string parameter.
So this is used to parse the query string.
OK.
And then we're going to convert that query string into a dictionary.
So let's look at this in a bit more detail.
Right now it's not really clear what content is.
And I and I appreciate that.
We don't know what content is unless we've used this before.
I've used it before and I know what it is but you don't.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to click here on this gray area and that's going to create a breakpoint
and add up that red circle there and then instead of pressing play we're going to press the we bug icon
that starts the debugger.
So let's press it and notice how we get down to this line here and we've got a blue line around it.
There's some gray text about it everywhere.
And then we sort of get this thing here.
So what is happening.
Well we've stopped the program at this point.
So now we can go and see what variables we've got available for us.
For example this consumer variable that we created is available here.
And we can open it up and look at the properties.
It's got a key and a secret which we passed in.
Similarly for that client.
It also exists down here and it has a few a bunch of variables and so on.
But what's more important for us is what is content the content.
As you can see is just a string of bytes.
Let's have a look at it.
This is what it looks like.
It is auth token equals a bunch of text and or token secrets equals another bunch of text and or Colback
confirmed it's true.
So it's this thing here.
And notice how it is in the format of something equals something else and something equals something
else and something equals something else that's in the form of a query string.
So this parse QSL is going to convert it to something else.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to select you parse dot parse on the school QSL uncondemned and
then I'm going to press the calculator icon there and press evaluate.
And here is what we get when we run that.
So when we run this come on here we can use this calculator evaluate expression window to see what we
would get if our program runs this and this is the result of that.
The result is a list and each element of the list is a couple.
And with that we know what a table is.
It's just an immutable list.
The first element of the table is the name auth token and the second element is the contents.
So the second item in here is that long a number and then the second element of the list is at the auth
token secret.
In the first part and this other thing in the second part.
And finally the last one is or callback confirmed and true.
So when we run the parse dot parse underscore QSL and we pass it in the content we get back this list
of tuples where each of the tables has the name and then a value.
Now the DEQ method can be used to do that.
So I'm gonna once again run the calculator and type in dict and then I'm going to put in a list of tuples
OK.
And in the first couple I'm going to put high and then one two three.
So I'm running the dict method on a list where the list contains a tuple and the first element of the
top all is high.
And the second element is 1 2 3.
So what do you think is going to come out when we run this.
Take a wild guess and the answer is we get a dictionary with the key high and the value 1 to 3.
If we add another one
then we get another key.
We get the key hand and the key high.
And they have their values there.
So the Dichter method can be ran on a list of couples to convert tables in this format.
Key value into a dictionary and that's quite handy because a lot of things can be expressed in this
sort of format.
Key value key value and the fact that we can convert those to a dictionary easily is nice because dictionaries
are just a bit nicer to interact with in Python.
OK so if we run all this then what we get is a dictionary of oarth callback confirmed as true or tokens
that ortho can see couldn't miss that.
Notice how they are all bytes and they have that B in front.
That tells us they are bite's if we wanted to convert them to strings in Python 3.5 then we have to
do another step.
If you using by them to win 7 I don't think you have this problem but if you are using Python 3.5 we
can stop the debug on and hear the content we can do dot decode UTF Dash 8.
And that is going to convert those two strings as opposed to bytes.
So is a debugger again
and now we stopped here we're going to select all that plus the calculator I can evaluate.
And now we have strings.
Notice the SDR there as opposed to bytes as it was before.
Now this process of running the debugger often is really fantastic and you should do it using the debugger
is one of the key skills for programming if you can use a debugger that means you can essentially find
out what the problem is that any point you can always pause the program at some point run things with
your calculator figure things out and then continue programming and you don't have to ever wonder what
it is.
For example content.
What does it contain.
What is respons.
We can just press the calculator I can type in response here and then we get the result of the response
variable which is we can see has a status property in there which is what we're accessing and we know
it's 200.
So you can always create a breakpoint by just clicking on the gray area and then pressing the bug icon
and start looking at what things are using to calculate it.
I'm going to pause a debugger at this point and we're going to stop here for this video because we've
made it a bit long now and we've looked at put a lot of stuff.
So that's it for now.
We've looked at making this logon file creating our consumer client which is used to make requests.
Then we've got the request token you Arel which has to be a post as per the API documentation.
And finally we've also managed to get a dictionary of the request token which has in there a request
token and the request token secret which are going to be used later on for authorization.
So and so you the next video we're going to be looking at more things and we're going to be sending
the user over to Twitter to press the signing button there.
So what's the next video.