Hi will come back in this video we're going to look at methods that return dictionaries returning a
dictionary is exactly the same as returning an integer or a list or as we look at later on a table to
return the dictionary.
The only thing we have to do is say return and then the dictionary that we want return on a method can
do that.
In this section the app we're creating is one that will allow us to create new students and give them
a set of marks and then will let us calculate the average mark of one of the students reasonably simple
program but it is to introduce a number of things that are going to be essential for later on such as
dictionaries being one of them.
What I'm going to start with in this video is with a method that will allow us to create a new student
dictionary.
This means that it's going to ask the user for the student's name and it's going to create this dictionary
that contains a list of marks which will initially be empty.
And then it's going to return that.
Let's let's walk through that
as we know we can create a method with the death keyword and then we give it that name and then we give
it the opening and closing brackets.
And that tells them that this is a method and inside the method we can put some code.
And as we know when we execute or call the method the code inside will run from top to bottom.
And this method is going to ask the user for the student's name and then it's going to create the dictionary
and the format name is going to be the student name and Marks is going to be a list and then it's going
to return that dictionary
also whenever you have a method that doesn't do anything or doesn't do anything yet you can just use
pass as a placeholder and Python accepts that if you don't type anything then Python tells you hey this
method has no body even though it's got a few comments comments don't count as we know and then it says
that it expects there to be something there.
So you can you just use pass and that's fine.
Or we can indeed implement it.
Now you can already ask the user for a name you know how to do that and you can certainly create a dictionary
.
I mean we've done it appear is going to be name and then the student's name which the user is going
to give you and then it's going to be marks.
Remember the comma and an empty list and then it's going to return that dictionary.
I think you can do all of those things.
So go ahead and post the video and then come back once you've attempted that.
OK now that you've tried that let's go ahead and do it here.
The first thing we want to do is to say name is going to be input please enter the new students name
and we've used this plenty of times before.
Input takes in a string and the string is what gets printed out and the user can then start typing at
the end of the string.
And here we would expect the name of the new student and then we're going to use that name in sign our
dictionary and would to create student data and data other funding and where you're from.
And this is going to be name is name and remember name inside quotation marks is the string the literal
representation of these symbols and a m n e and name a without the quotation marks is a variable which
we have defined up here.
Remember if we do not define a variable called name.
For example I call it names.
Then Python gives them an error because it cannot find names so I has to match exactly but it can be
anything you want.
And finally Marx was just going to be an empty list.
We know that this is how we can create an empty list and there is a list with zero elements.
But definitely could have elements here if we wanted but it doesn't make sense when we are creating
a student for the student already having a set of marks.
So we just put an empty list in there.
And finally we can return the student date and now I'm going to delete the comments and the reason why
I'm deleting the comments is because it's really easy.
Just from the code to understand what this method is doing is asking for a name that is creating a dictionary
that contains that name and a set of marks and then returning that it doesn't really need any extra
explanation.
And if we leave the extra explanation here and then next week we come back and change something because
it is a comment and it doesn't run and it doesn't cause errors.
We may forget to update the comment with the new info the new things that we've written in the method
and if we do that then it would suddenly lose a lot of value and it would indeed become confusing because
the the comment would be saying one thing and the code will be saying something different.
So if not necessary let's remove the comment and I don't think it is necessary.
The method it creates.
And as for a name put in a dictionary and then returns that.
I think it's fairly obvious what is going on in this method.
None that we've got the method to create A-student we can run the thing and see what happens.
Remember because the method is defined above we need to put the print statement below it and I'm going
to just call print or create student create student call is going to happen.
First we're going to jump from here up here and we're going to get asked to enter the name then we're
going to create a dictionary and return that.
So what we're going to be printing is the student data that we've created.
OK let's press play up here.
Now notice how we get asked to enter the student's name so I'm going to put my name and then what we
get out where we get printed.
Is this dictionary that we have created.
I would always recommend you do this.
This process of creating a small method that does something and then printing it out to make sure that
it works the way you expect it is something you should get accustomed to doing and testing things out
as you go.
Now that we've got that ready however we are ready to move on to the next set of functionality which
is going to allow us to add more marks in and because naturally an empty list isn't very useful in the
next video we're going to be appending things to at least not to.