Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to look at using posh grass on Mac Miller we've installed
the graphical interface all we have to do is go to your Applications folder find Postrel in here and
then run the puji admin 3 program.
You've also got access to the sequel shell which lets you interact with Pasko sequel through the console
but because we're only learning sequel in this course and not really the intricacies of Postrel sequel
then we're going to be looking at using PGE outman 3 which lets you run the query like that the same
if you are going to be learning in the course.
You can also do through the sequels shell.
It's just a bit nicer to run them through.
So let's open that up and then we will look at what we can do with it.
So what we've got here as soon as we open the PGE have 3 interface is a fairly nice bit 90s looking
interface and that nevertheless works quite well.
The first thing we've got here is our server that we've just installed and noticed it's got a cross
because we're not connected to it.
What to do is right click on that server and press connect and then you'll be asked for the password
that you used when you installed the server.
In my case I'm going to put mine in and then just press OK.
And then we've got here the contents of the server we've got databases table spaces group roles and
logging roles and these calls we're going to be focusing on data bases and logging roles.
We're not going to worry about people's spaces.
And I'll briefly go into what a group rule is but we're not going to be creating any just yet a log
in role as simply a user and users sometimes can log in to their server and they can do things like
retrieve data from databases or tables and create more databases or tables and do other things.
We've got one user called postscripts by default and I've created one called admin for this cause we're
also going to create another user.
So let's go reichlich logging roads and press new logging road.
I'm going to call this user.
My name's I'm going to put my name in the role name there and you don't have to worry about any of these
other things.
The definition you may prompt you might put in a password for the user and normally you would use a
password if the user was available for others to potentially try to log in with.
And what I mean with that is if you have a server for example online and people can potentially hack
into it or connect to it and then you may want to use a password to secure your database a bit more
.
Certainly not the same password as you would for the server.
In this case you can also put a connection limit if you leave it blank.
There is no limit where you can put in a limit here.
And what that would do is for example.
So you've got a web application that has a lot of users using it simultaneously but your server cannot
cope with more than 500 connections at once.
Then you may want to put in a connection limit so that when more users try to use your app they'll just
it'll just grab it slower essentially.
So your server doesn't go down.
So if your server is limited by Ihram you don't have a lot of RAM then maybe you want to put this in
here.
But for now we're not worried about that.
And this is more advanced stuff.
The road privileges is what is more interesting.
The first one is checked inherits rights from palindromes and this one doesn't have any parent roles
but we might as well just get that checked super user ability means that it can delete all the databases
and normally you do not want to give this property to anybody except your post user.
That's just because the fewer users that have the ability to delete databases the better.
It means there's fewer chances of potentially other people using the account to delete your data.
I'm going to check.
They can create databases check box here because I'm going to be creating a learning database for this
user that we're going to be using across there throughout the course to learn about how the sequel commands
Kevin rerolls allows this user to create other users.
And in this case I'm not really interested in that.
And the other two were not really going to bother with roll membership allows to give this user a group
role and that means that it can inherit from the group roles and potentially have extra privileges.
But we're not going to worry about that here.
Variables and security labels it's not something we should be concerned with.
And finally the sequel command is just what is going to execute on the server when you press OK.
So this is interesting because it tells you if you didn't have access to this visual terminal what you
would have to do in the console to execute the same command and as you can see it's quite simple.
Create role and the role name has the ability to log in and create databases and it's valid until infinity
means it does not expire.
Fairly simple command.
So let's press OK and then we can go ahead and that will run and we will get on you user so that we
have a log in roll and now we can go into a data bases and create our database.
Notice that you will only have a postscripts data base and of course sample database there as well.
The some sample data and I'll be sharing that database with you so you can download the sample data
for this course.
First thing to do is right click databases and create press new database and then we can give this a
name as well.
I'm going to give this the name learning and the owner is going to be the user.
We just created.
You've got other things like definition and we don't really have to worry about this because Pasqua
will populate these automatically with your system values and things like that.
So don't worry about this in coding is the character sense that we're using and there's load in here
UTF 8 is a very extensive cactus and that allows you to use other languages like Chinese and things
like that.
If you want to store the actual debate if you want and add more space saving in your disk and fewer
character sets used.
You could choose to call ASCII.
And I would only let you use the ASCII codes which include just essentially American characters American
English characters and symbols.
But we're going to use UTF 8 just because it gives us a bit more flexibility.
Once again the connection limit.
But we're not going to use that in this database.
You've got some variables that we're not going to be using privileges that we're not going to be using
security labels that we're not going to be using.
And finally the sequel code is going to be running when we create this database.
We're not going to be using privileges in this database because we've got the owner which is the person
that's going to be accessing the database and the owner has the ability to enter data and retrieve data
.
So we don't need any extra privileges in there.
Once again to create a database used to create database and then the database name and you can provide
the encoding so that it does not use ASCII by default.
So within coding UTF 8 that just gives it the encoding and then owner is the log in roles name connection
Limited's minors one to not have a connection limit do notice the new sequel the new lines and spaces
and things like that don't matter.
So we could technically just have this like that if we wanted and they would do the same thing.
But to not delete any characters the spaces are important just new lines are not.
And finally the semicolon at the end just as it tells the sequel that this is the end of the statement
so you can run that and so OK.
And then that creates our learning database.
Why pressing on it and then it gets a wee arrow there and we can see what's inside and there's quite
a of things inside it.
There's catalogs event triggers extensions schemas and slowly replication.
The only thing we're going to be looking at in this cause which is basic sequel stuff schemas and we've
got the public schema which is the default schema.
And this allows us to define tables inside the scheme.
You can have multiple schemas if you want multiple groups of tables.
Living in the same server and if you use the public schema which is the default then that just makes
it a bit easier when you're running sequel queries and I'll explain why later on.
If we wanted to create a table we would just reichlich table unpressed new table and we're going to
go into that in a couple of videos.
But as I said I'm going to be sharing with you the code that you just have to run and then you'll get
tables in your server with some sample data as well.
So what about that and we've seen just quickly how to interact with the pgm in 3 program and create
our own log and roll and database now that it is empty.
But we're going to populate it very soon.
With that said I'll see you in the next few