I will come back in with you.
Let's look at running a file from idea.
Naturally we have to write our programs line by line where each line gets executed instantly.
It means we can't really write programs that are much longer than one line.
This is why in python like in all the programming languages we can create the program in a file and
then we can run it.
Ideally the python shell is not a requirement for running Python programs.
However it does have the functionality to run a file.
So the way we would create a new file from Ideally the Python show will be to go to the File menu and
then press new file or just press command.
And if you're on a Mac what I would assume control and if you're on Windows.
Well as pre-stamped and then it creates this here and I'm just going to resize it.
So it appears on the screen there we go.
And now notice how the crocodile clips have disappeared because we can now write whatever we want in
this file as long as it's Python code and then we can run the file all in one go.
Python programs like most other programming languages run from top to bottom so whatever we write to
the top will get executed first and then the next line and then the next line and so.
So let's try to write a very simple program that will declare a variable and then display the variable
value.
So let's create a variable.
We know how to do that.
Age equals five for example.
And then as we've learned previously the only thing we have to do in order to display the age value
is to type it in and then Python would evaluate that and this play is the value.
So let's press run.
I'm going to run menu and then run module and then it will go over to the python shell and execute that
.
And we must see it first.
So I'm just going to save it as a him print and notice how nothing gets printed out which is kind of
ironic.
It did run the file and then just did nothing.
So let's go back into our file and figured out why this is.
And the reason why is because the IDL e is programmed to evaluate each line sequentially.
So whenever we execute a line it will evaluate and then when we execute another line and we'll evaluate
that too.
And in this case when it evaluates age it just returns the value of it and which is what we would expect
.
However when we run the file it doesn't quite run the same way when we run this fine.
It runs in the normal sort of Python runtime.
And what that means is that it does not evaluate each line and return the value of it to the user.
What it does is it just evaluates them and keeps them in memory and then we have to tell it give us
the value please.
In order for it to actually come out and be printed.
So instead of simply typing age we're going to need to do print.
And then in here age and now when we run the model which you can do by pressing the function 5 key you
must save it.
And then the value 5 does come out which is fantastic.
OK we are approaching very quickly the ability to create the sections program.
So I'll leave that up to you.
How would you instead of printing just the age.
Print out the number of seconds that the user has left for for simple challenge.
However it still requires some thought.
OK.
So in order to just print the number of seconds without giving the user much information we would have
to multiply this by 365 than 24 for the number of hours 60 for the number of minutes and 60 for the
number of seconds.
So if we save that and run it again we now get the number of seconds printed out.
Second challenge give the user a bit more information for example something that I would like to be
printed out is the string.
You have lived for the number of seconds and then seconds.
So let's print out.
You have lift for seconds and then seconds where this is the number of seconds that we've calculated
here.
So that's the second challenge for you to try and create a program that will print that out
slightly more challenging than the last one.
What we have to do is write the string you have left for and then added to the string representation
of our number and then add seconds at the end.
What this does is it says you have lived for.
Remember the space there and then it appends to it the string representation of our multiplication.
Remember it does the multiplication first and then passes so that to this command and then it depends
.
Seconds at the end remember the space there as well.
So let's say that and run it.
And now we get a slightly better message you have lived for that number of seconds.
However the user hasn't told us their age which means they do not know how many years this corresponds
to.
So you can optionally tell them this corresponds to five years.
Or we can continue moving on and actually ask the user for their age before giving them the age in seconds
.
OK so trying to tell them this corresponds to five years as a string.
And you know how to do that.
You just have to add a few more things at the end.
And then we move on and try to get the user input.
So after your next video