Find Welcome Back in this video we're going to be looking at saving our user to a file in order to save
our use it to a file.
We need to know what we want to save.
Naturally we can't just save something that we don't know what it is.
For example we can just tell this class save yourself.
We need to specify what we want to put in the file because only that we will be able to then load it
up into our system again in case of the user.
The only data that the user has the only things that we could put in a database of a name and the movies
if we put the name and the movies into a file that will then allow us to load a user from a file by
reading the name of the movies and putting it back into the user.
That's the only point of saving to then load if we save to then not use it for loading.
There's not much point in saving anything
then let's save this user into a file.
There are two ways really that we could save this user to a file we could use a CXXVI format saving
the user with a comma separated value format.
Or we could use a Jason format javascript object notation for.
Let's go over both.
In this video we're going to explain how to use a CXXVI format.
And then the next we'll go over Jason.
The first thing to do is to remember that the user can save itself to a file potentially.
Or rather it can tell you what it wants to write on the file.
So
let's create a method save file.
And what this method might do is create a new file with the user's name and some of the user's movies
.
Let's open up a file with open and then we might call the file the same as the user's name self not
name in writing mode as F and in this file we might write.
All right then here we'd say self dot name and then we would write the movies.
How could you write the movies in a file.
Each movie has a name a genre and whether it's been watched or not
well in the next line we could save each of the movies or we could put them potentially in a different
file if we wanted.
In my case I'm going to put them in the same file.
So I'm going to write the user's name first and then I'm going to add the backslash NC-Janitor which
breaks into the next line.
And here in the next line I'm going to add the first of the user's movies
as not right.
And what we want to do is separate each of the movie properties with a comma because that's what comma
separated values are.
So what we do here is say self-taught movies zero dot name plus comma plus self don't movies zero dot
Londra plus comma plus self self-taught movie Zero dot watched.
And as you know this axis is the first element in south that movies.
And then we print out the name
and then we are adding a comma to the string and then we're adding stuff that moves zero or Jorah.
And the wording a comma and then when I think of the movies or watched remember watched is a boolean
.
And so we should use the str method here to ensure that it is converted to a string.
By now you may have seen a couple of things wrong with this statement here.
Stop the video and see if you can see two things that are not really right with this tape.
OK the first thing that you might have noticed is that I'm accessing self-taught movies zero the first
element in movies.
But what if the user doesn't have any movies.
Well then you can expect to see quite a lot of red text underneath where you should do is see for movie
in self-taught movies and then invent that put it inside the for loop and a hearsay movie not name movie
Dongarra and movie don't watch.
What is the second thing that isn't wrong but could be made better in this statement in this line 26
.
Improvement that we could put in here that would make things more readable is to use the format method
We could simply say open it was blackcap coma.
It rocket coma open close bracket dot format and then genre and movie watched.
And that's just it.
I think it's a bit easier to read to know about you but I think that now I know that his name Leandra
and movie watched and I can immediately see that what I'm writing to this file is a CXXVI formatted
string a comma separated values string because the values are separated by commas.
There is more problem with this C S V file isn't really a problem but it's something that we have to
keep in to into account and that's the first line contains self-taught name and the other lines contain
other data that is not related to the user but rather to the movies themselves.
So these two differing types of data in here may cause a problem if we don't know if we don't remember
about this.
Something that I forgot but you must remember to add a new line there at the end newline character so
that the next time that we write something it goes over into the new line.
So now what we have is the user's name in the first line and the user's movies in the second line something
that you may find interesting is we are writing the user's name in the first line and the file is called
the user's name.
To open this file we would need to know the user's name.
So there's not much point in saving the name to the file as well.
There's a couple of ways that we could go around this.
We could call the file users and then right multiple users of the same file.
We could just not write the user name there.
Let's leave it like this for now because we're not really concerned about it.
Next up let's go into our app and create a user at a couple of movies.
Save it to the file and see what happens.
So uder is going to be a user with a name I would say.
And remember we have to import that.
And then user dot add movie.
Remember we no longer need to import a movie in our app because we can add the movie directly from the
user.
The Matrix safelight and user apps movie.
What I'm going to put here is the interview comedy.
And in a way you're from that is OK.
And finally user don't save to file and that's going to hopefully create a new file called Jose and
save the user and the movies into that.
Let's press play and see what happens.
OK.
There's a fire called Jose there.
And if we open that up Fair enough it does contain the matrix the interview and falls and falls and
my name in the first line.
A couple of improvements you may want to do use and call the file the user name Dottie XTi.
You may want to do that so that when you run the app again which I'm going to do just now you get Jose
up to 60.
That maybe looks a bit better.
And you may want to think about whether you want to save the user's name or not or save the file with
a different name.
But what we've looked at in this video is that the user can save itself to a cxxviii file and can write
itself to see as we file what we're going to look at in the next video is loading the user from the
C S V file and then we look at Jason that.
So with that said I'll see you in the next video.