One will come back in this video.
We're going to look at how we can add or append a mark in that student data dictionary.
However remember that when we create a student that is going to give us a new of these dictionaries
and we want to be able to add a mark to one of those specific dictionaries and not to all of them simultaneously
For example I'm going to give you a small bit of structure and then I'm going to ask you to complete
the challenge in order to add a mark.
We know that we have to call the aband method.
So what we're going to do is we're going to create a method called add Mark and this method is going
to take in a student.
And this is going to be a dictionary.
And then what this method is going to do is it's going to append a mark to the student dictionary and
that's it.
That's really the mark that is going to append is going to have to be another parameter student is going
to be a dictionary.
Mark is going to be a number an integer.
And I think you can you can do that pretty easily.
Remember that student is going to be dictionary in this format so I suggest pause the video remove the
pass and try to do that and then come back and we'll continue through and we'll do that here.
OK.
Let's first remove the past because we're going to be changing this here.
And the only thing we have to do is student and Ramba marks because we want to access the key marks
in the student dictionary.
And I want to say append mark and that's it.
And now you're thinking do we not have to return things we have written things before.
Why are we not returning things.
Now remember that default in Python is return None.
OK so I'm going to make it explicit just for a moment but this is not necessary if you remove it.
Remember it's still there.
This is the default in Python return None is what happens if you don't have a return statement.
So let's let's begin with treating each student with a call it s.
Not a very good name.
But I'm going to call it s for now.
Create student.
And remember this is going to ask me to enter the student name and then it's going to create a dictionary
and then won't return that dictionary.
So June and it's essentially going to be a dictionary.
So as it's going to be a dictionary and then what I'm going to do here is print s and that's going to
be the dictionary you remember that we've created here.
There is a method definition in the middle but that doesn't matter.
Remember that defining a method doesn't mean work cannot execute the method.
We have to call the method first.
So let's let's run this first and I'm going to type in my name and notice how what gets printed out
is empty as well.
Market is empty.
The name is Jose.
So that's the dictionary that we created before and comes back to us defining the method doesn't mean
that a method gets executed.
It just say that the method exists.
I don't know what happened there but there we go.
The method exists after line 16 so now we can call Adam Mark after line 16 not before line 12.
So what happens if I do demarc and then I pass in S and then they say 5.
For example remember X would be the student 5 would be the mark.
So I would append the five onto Marks what do you think is going to happen.
Do you think that X is going to be like here.
It's going to have an empty marks list because I should return a student here.
Do you think X is going to have a 5 in the marks.
Do you think it's going to give me an error.
What do you think.
Now let's run it and see what happens and I'll explain why it happens.
I'll put the name in and there's the five.
So there was no need to return anything.
The tone is redundant as you know.
Under-five nevertheless is still there.
So what has happened is Python has got the ace.
And we've defined a method which takes in a student and a mark and then it says student marks append
that Mark.
And then when we call out Mark that S doesn't get copied the value of x does not go into the student
variable but rather they are the same thing.
So then when we modify a student we are really modifying as and this is very common is passing by reference
.
And this is a common term in computer science for development something you should know passing by reference
as is what we're passing here is not the value of this it's not the dictionary but rather the location
of where that dictionary is stored.
If you want to show where passing a reference to the dictionary and student is a reference to the same
dictionary so s and student have both the reference to the same thing.
So when we modify student we're modifying s because they are both referencing the same dictionary behind
the scenes.
It's something quite deep and quite theoretical but that is what's happening behind the scenes.
OK.
This is unlike for example and I'm going to just scroll down and make it clearer for you.
Add number x and y.
This is unlike me doing X equals x plus why.
And then I can define X up here.
Actually it was five when I got the and number number X and 10 and that is exactly what we've done above
.
But I'm sure I'm going to call this this and in fact just pilot that a complaint
is exactly what we've done above essentially.
But if we print that out you'll see that it is still 5.
So you can see there five is zed.
And the reason why that is is because Zayde the number five is a primitive value.
And that means that it gets passed via value passing by value and that's another important thing.
These are the only two ways that you can pass an argument by the way.
I'm sorry about that keeps popping up.
And what's happening is that the zid then the value 10 and it's the only five that is inside Zayde gets
assigned to x and now x and z are completely different things.
So when we change X up here then and nothing nothing happens essentially with Zayd because they are
getting passed by value.
OK.
So that was a small aside and I'm sorry about going on a tangent there but nevertheless an important
tangent and important thing for you to understand this student here is the same as X.
So when we change that student we don't have to then return it because it changes the thing that's coming
out as well.
So that's everything for this video.
We've learned how we can add a mark to each student and now we are ready to proceed and to the next
video.
We're going to be looking at how we can calculate the average mark for a given student.
So I'll see you there.