Hi and welcome back in this video we're going to be defining our own methods.
The first thing to know is what is a method.
A method is nothing other than a name for a block of code so you can get a few lines of code give them
a name and then run them whenever you execute that name.
Right now our program runs from top to bottom.
We execute the first line and then the next line and then the next one and so on.
However it doesn't have to be this way.
We can create a method and then execute that method multiple times for example without having to duplicate
the lines many times.
So what we're going to do is we're going to get these few lines the lines that ask the user for a number
and then verify whether the number is right or not.
We are going to select them and cut them and then we're going to come up here and say def ask user and
check number and then we're going to write open and close bracket and the colon.
And now we've defined a method def is a keyword to define a method.
Then we type in the new name for a method we can type whatever we want.
It follows the same conventions as variables.
You can't stop them with a number that's all or with an underscore.
Actually you can start with an underscore just not with a number.
So the not the name.
And then open and close brackets.
Then a colon and then press enter and type in our code then are pasted.
And now we've got ourselves a brand new method.
This method is called Ask user and check number and what it does is it does exactly that.
It asks the user.
And then checks the number in order to run that code.
The only thing we have to do now is call our method the action of calling our method is the same as
executing the method.
Just type in here ask user and check number.
OK so now we can save this and run it and actually you can see we get the chance to type in our three
numbers and then it tells us whether we got it right or not.
So we know that this code is running which is exactly what we wanted.
Something that we can do is we can also create a method for this code down here the code that runs our
program three times.
So let's create a method def run program X times and I'm calling it run program X times for a reason
.
And we're going to get to that reason in just a moment.
OK so now I'm going to save this program and run it.
And what do you think is going to happen when I run this program.
Well let's find out.
That's what happens when I run this program.
Absolutely nothing.
And the reason is because even though we've defined the method that actually does stuff we've not executed
we've not called that method so we have to call our method down here.
If not if we don't call the method all the program does is import random define a method that bosal
something but doesn't run the method.
Define a variable define another variable and find another method.
It never actually does things.
It never runs the for loop if we don't execute the method.
So that's why we need this line down there.
So now let's save it and run it again as we can see and we get the output as expected.
OK so now let's go back and actually fulfill the name of this method.
This method says Run Program X times but really change is equal to 3.
So it's running at three times.
It's not running that X times right now.
This method should be called non-program three times.
But we're going to change that.
We're going to pass in a parameter or an argument.
So for example I'm going to pass in the argument to and what I want what I want this method to do is
to get this to and run the program two times.
And if I put 5 in here I want this method to get this 5 and run the program 5 times.
But right now change is equal to 3.
So that's never going to happen.
Even if I put the 5 in there right now and I run the program then what comes out is just an error.
So let's let's do that just for convenience and then that's what happens is as run program X times takes
0 arguments but one was given it doesn't have any arguments but we gave it one.
So we're going to find out exactly how we can make it accept an argument we've given as an argument
the method is not accepting any and the way we make the method except argument is we put the argument
name inside these brackets.
So for example I'm going to cheat coalmines chances so not what's going to happen is this five is going
to be placed inside a variable called chances.
And then that variable chancet is going to be used up below.
That means I no longer need this chances up there.
OK.
So instead of 5 Let's do it once and let's run that and run.
And now we only get one attempt.
So here's the challenge for you.
Make it so the user can be assigned How many times they want to run the program.
You've got the skills for those already.
You just have to ask the user using the input method.
Convert that to an integer and then pass it in as the parameter.
So pause the video if you need to and try an attempt to that.
Now
none of that's attempted.
Let's do it here together.
The way I would do it is user attempts equals input and then input and then enter the number of attempts
and then close the brackets and finally put it down.
Here is how simple it is now that this method has the parameter and we can pass it the number of chances
.
The only change we have to make is in there create a variable that will hold the number of attempts
we want and then pass it in as a parameter and that's it.
So let's save that and run it.
And now we can type in two and that's it.
It says there's Adam 0 on this attempt.
So that's it.
That's how you can create your own methods and how you can pass parameters to them.
And in the next video we're going to look at how we can not only pass things to the method but also
get things back from a method.
So let's look at that in the very next video.
I'll see you there.