Hyde will come back and there's really we're going to be dealing with user authorization in some cases
here we're talking about our Earth for example in oh Ives or when we go to Twitter and we talk about
authorization another word though you'll often see is authentication and now they are completely different
.
They are often confused for one another but authentication means verifying that a username and password
combination is valid.
Authorization means to give permission.
What we're doing with logging in with Twitter is allowing the user to authorize our Twitter application
to use their account.
The user himself has to authenticate with Twitter by logging in but we are not concerned with them being
logged in.
We're only concerned with them giving us authorization to use their account.
So that's just a bit of a knowledge bomb there for you to remember.
And now in this video let's get the authorization talking the pin or the redirection.
If we were a web application we would have the logic somewhere in our code to allow the user to visit
our Web site.
We're going to be looking exactly how to do that later on.
But just imagine we allow the user to visit our Web page like so w w w dot our Web site don't come when
the user log goes to our website.
They may see a log in with Twitter button
and when they press that they will go to Twitter dot com when they press that
they go to Twitter or com.
And then we generate this request token as well.
So what you do first is generate the request token that we have already.
Then they get to Twitter and they have to authorize our application remedies.
I'm just reiterating over what we know they press sign an OR or authorize in Twitter dot com and then
Twitter sends them back to e.g. the bedo literally dot our Web site dot com mouth.
And when they send them back to our website they also send back an authorization code and then we get
that code plus the request you can send it to Twitter and we get a access token.
OK.
Just going over what we know or rather what we've already covered.
But I do appreciate this is a confusing topic and I'm going over it a bunch of times.
We don't have a web application right now.
We don't have w w w dot.
Our Web site dot com although we will so Twitter cannot redirect the user back to our Web site because
we don't have one.
So what we did is going to do instead is generate a pin code and we are going to need to get that pin
code from the user which is that code and use that with request token to send it to Twitter and get
an access token back.
OK.
So the next thing to do is get into that authorization token.
So let's tell the user that they need to go and get that pin code the way we do that is very simple
.
We're going to tell them go to the following web site site too in your browser your browser.
And then what we're going to do is print the user rail where they address that they have to go to with
their browser and the address they have to go to is this wealth on this go to can use that format.
And what has to go in there is something there and something there.
Remember this is a query string.
So it has to be in the format of name equals some value.
And we can send that to Twitter.
Twitter can then retrieve that.
So we're going to be doing is accessing the you URL for authorization and pass that you are I'll give
that you were ill.
This query string.
So right this query string there and the query string parameter we're giving is the wealth underscore
token sure we're accessing the authorization you RL And we're giving it as a query string the old token
.
So in this format What do you think I should put in.
Remember we need the authorization you know and the oath token.
Now we haven't really covered how together you outspoken even though we have a request to can but we
know that the first thing is going to be Constans don't authorization you RL I think we could get that
far because here what we need is to allow the user to authorize our application.
Now this our token is the request talken that we've generated that with our consumer.
So Twitter knows it is our application.
And for this specific user.
So Twitter knows that we are linking up the request token that we're passing in with the user that is
currently logged into Twitter.
So the talk and there is going on the Web we're going to find out by once again doing a de-bug.
So I'm going to press the bug icon after setting a break point and we'll find that request token which
is the variable we created up here has an oath token value there.
And that's what we want to send to Twitter.
So after the coma I'm going to stop the debugger after the coma.
The second parameter to replace this.
There were going to put request open and then it's a dictionary.
So we have to access it with the square brackets while talking.
OK.
So what we're telling the user now is go to the following site in your browser and the site is going
to be the authorization you're able with the query string which use the old token equals the requests
request tokens while token and that old token put a nose comes from our app because we generated it
with this consumer and then it will allow Twitter to link up our app to the user currently logged into
Twitter.
And we'll see exactly how that happens.
I'm just going to press play now and then I get to the following site.
You're proud browser so I would just click that
and now notice we've not told Twitter which user which Twitter user we are wanting to log in as we've
not told Twitter that because I'm already logged into Twitter.
So once I get to this page I am no longer in my application.
Now this is Twitter and Twitter can see that I'm logged in.
So naturally the user that we are logging in as is currently logged in user.
And if I was not logged in then Twitter would ask me to log in here and then it asked me to authorize
tweet analyzer and I can say authorize yes or no if I press authorize then what I get is a pin code
.
So now we're going to be using this pin code to generate the request talk through the access token.
My bad.
OK.
So I'm going to close that window because now our program has finished it's not doing anything else
apart from printing that it doesn't have much use for this pin code.
The next thing to do would be to store the pin code so all of the verifier.
You can call it whatever you want.
I'm just calling it off verify it's going to be input.
What is the pin.
And we've seen the input function before and we're using it now to ask the user for the pin code that
Twitter gave them when they visited that page.
And once we have the PIN code then we can use it to generate another token which is going to be sending
to the access token you RL And we're going to be generating the access token.
Let's do that in the next video though.
So to review we have asked the user to go to specific you are l which gets the currently logged in user
input and generates a pin code for that user.
So the next step is to use that PIN code and the request token to generate an access token.
So you can actually