Will come back in this is we're looking at some advanced Python and we're going to be doing that as
well over the next few videos.
So what I've done is here in Python I've created the new project I've called it advanced python.
And once again it's using a virtual environment using Python 3.5.
We're not going to be using any external libraries in this project.
So instead of a virtual environment you can just use the system interpreter if you want.
In this first video I wanted to talk to you about builtin methods in Python.
Now we've already looked at some builtin methods such as the in its method or the wrapper method which
is useful representation but we're going to be looking at a couple others that's although use less often
is still good to know about them and they can still be very useful in some scenarios.
Instead of giving you examples using the usual animals and numbers we're going to go a step further
and give you a slightly more useful example maybe not the most useful example in the world but nevertheless
a slightly more useful example.
Let's create a new file and you put it in file.
And I'm going to call it built in methods not p why you can call it whatever you want.
The name is not important.
And what we're going to do in this video is create a class that we are going to be using across the
next few videos as well.
The class is going to be a class currency and currency is something that poses a few problems in computing
them not too many but a few problems such as exchanging between currencies and things like that.
The objective of this class is going to be to store a currency code such as GBP for great British pounds
or USD for U.S. dollars and also the exchange rate between that currency and U.S. dollars.
So U.S. dollars is going to be the base currency.
And we're going to create other currencies that are going to convert to US dollars.
We're going to create a constructor that is going to take in a code the currency code and the exchange
rate to U.S. dollars.
So let's start with that crater in its method to the constructor that digs in a code and an exchange
to U.S. dollars and sets them to as properties of the object.
Hopefully you achieve that.
And I always recommend even if I don't say pause the video try it yourselves and go ahead of me if you
can.
As that's the best way to learn the init method is going to take in a code and an exchange to us the
as we agreed and then we're going to set them to as properties of the objects of the code equals code
.
So that exchange to us the equals exchange to USD.
So what we're setting here is just two properties that all objects of type currency are going to have
a code and exchange to us.
And we are going to pass those in when we create the object.
So let's create an object down here just to keep track of overdoing and we look at an object called
pounds that is going to be a currency object and the code is going to be GBP.
The exchange the USD is going to be one point twenty one.
So the GBP as you you know just to review is the code 1.20 one then goes to exchange the USD that's
separated by commas.
The code then goes into self-dual code the exchange to us the then goes into Server Exchange to us the
.
Now the pound object has these two properties a code and exchange the USD.
OK.
Now this doesn't do much.
So what we are going to do is be able to also store a quantity of pounds in the object as opposed to
just the pounds on the exchange rate.
We're also going to allow the users or allow the programmers to store an amount of pounds Saulteaux
amount equals zero point zero zero.
We're going to initialize that to zero for reasons I'm going to explain soon.
Now the next thing to do is to allow the programmers using this class to modify the amount in python
we can just do something like Pound's not amount equals something else and that's totally fine.
We can do that or we could also create a method called set amount and that takes in an amount and sets
south'ard amount to be that does the same thing.
Essentially it just gives us a bit of a proxy a bit of a name for what we're doing here is not necessary
but in some scenarios then it might be interesting to limit how we can interact with a property.
In this case it and we're going to see more examples of when it is important to limit that later by
just creating this to show you how you would create a method to change that which I'm sure you know
already.
But nevertheless it's important to not assume too many things.
And the next two methods we're going to create are the methods to convert this amount to US dollars
or to convert an amount of US dollars back to this currency.
So what I'm going to do is create a method to allow to convert pounds to USD or USD to pounds.
So the methods are going to be in currency and they're going to take in an amount and 2 USD which is
going to take in an amount but it's going to be none by default and I'm going to go into why in just
a moment the incumbency method should convert the amount which should be in USD to the currency stored
in the object and the to us the method should do the opposite.
Convert the amount or this parameter to USD using the exchange rate.
So go ahead and try that on your own.
I really recommend you go ahead and play around with it make mistakes and that's fine.
And then we'll come back and do it here.
OK.
Hopefully you managed the currency method and take an amount of USD converting it to the currency that
we have created.
So this is going to be return amount which is the parameter divided by the exchange rate.
So for example if we wanted to convert a thousand dollars to pounds we should get fewer pounds because
the pound is more expensive.
Each pound is one point twenty one dollars.
So when we convert dollars to pounds we lose some amount we essentially end up with fewer pounds than
we had dollars.
Let's let's try that.
We're going to print pounds to USD 1000.
We're going to print one thousand dollars converting it to pounds.
We're going to print all that.
So now we drive click and run as you can see we get none.
And why is that.
Because I used the wrong method.
Great.
And I know this is a bit smaller now.
Zooming in to it and it's for your.
I'll change that in a moment.
As you can see the number we get is eight hundred twenty six which is fewer pounds than we had dollars
.
So something to remember.
Remember to use the right methods as opposed to the wrong ones.
And so now we've got that method created.
We ended up with 800 or something pounds which seems about correct given this exchange rate which by
the way I do not know if it's exchange rate is correct or not.
The next thing to do is to create the 2 USD method.
This method is going to do the opposite.
It's going to convert an amount that we pass in or self-taught amount and is going to convert that to
US dollars and it's going return that I would recommend you try that try give this a go once again if
you haven't already.
And we'll continue now.
We're going to do a return amount but in this case because we want to calculate the amount of dollars
we multiply instead of divide.
So if we multiplied 1000 pounds by the exchange rate we should end up with more dollars than pounds
because the pound is missing just more expensive.
Similarly if this exchange rate was less than one we would end up when multiplying with fewer pounds
than dollars.
How about if we do this all we're doing is multiplying the amount parameter by the exchange rate.
So this gives us an amount of dollars but we are completely ignoring self-doubt amount and self-taught
amount may in some instances have a value and in some cases amount maybe none because that's the default
value for the parameter.
So what we want to do is to make sure that we are using amount if it is not known if this is a number
then we will use the parameter.
But if the parameter is none then we're going to use self dollar amount.
Okay.
So what we do is create a variable called to convert and that's going to be amount if the amount is
not None.
Else self-betterment.
So what this is doing is it's saying to convert be assigned the value of amount if amount is not None
.
And if it isn't then use self-harmer.
So to convert variable is going to have either amount in it or self-taught amount in it because this
is so common to use a parameter if it is sent and to use a property if it is not sent there is actually
a shorthand in Python that is also part of the advanced Python section which is or so we are going to
do amount or sell that amount.
So we're going to be using the parameter or softer amount if the parameter is none.
And that's what that means.
And down here instead of using a mount Naturally we have to use our variable and so that we're using
that.
OK now let's print the opposite pounds to USD 1000.
So now what we're doing here is converting one thousand pounds to us dollars so we should see twelve
hundred and ten one thousand two hundred and ten printed out and indeed we do.
So that's fantastic.
And I apologize for the tax being a bit smaller.
I've changed a couple of things and it has become small but I would fix that for the next video.
And now what we have is the ability essentially to compare whether currencies are more expensive than
others or whether on a mound in a currency is more expensive than another currency.
For example let's create another currency which I'm going to call euros for example and the exchange
rate for euro is going to be one point seven.
Let's.
I'm not.
I'm not sure if this is correct or not but that's fine.
Now I want to see whether one thousand pounds is more expensive than 1000 euros.
The conversion is always going to go through U.S. dollars.
How would we do this.
How would I check whether £1000 gives me more dollars than 1000 euros would go ahead and try that program
that printed out and try that on your own.
Hopefully you got something and that gives you the right answer.
Something like potentially and print and pounds to us the 1000 and greater than euros to USD 1000.
They should print true.
If this value is greater than this one unfolds if this value is not greater than baseball I'm going
to press play.
And we see the value true come out which is what we would expect because the exchange rate of one point
twenty one will give us twelve hundred and ten.
The exchange rate of one point 0 7.
Will you give us one thousand twenty one thousand US and 1070.
So the pound is going to be more expensive.
That makes sense.
And that's great.
However when we're comparing this we have to do Pound's not to USD one thousand euros up to USD 1000
and so we could simplify this slightly by instead of passing the parameter in say in pounds Dotts set
amount one thousand euros don't set amount one.
And now we can just do that leaving the parameter as non then to convert is going to use self-dual amount
which is one thousand and we are going to be getting that.
So once again if we print this we should also SOTY true which we do.
However we still have to convert to USD.
This is not ideal because what's happening now is that the pounds we are no longer comparing pounds
and euros.
Now we are comparing the amount converted to USD and the amount converted to USD so it's not as obvious
what is happening here maybe more I guess it is reasonably obvious but it's not as if we are comparing
pounds in euros directly.
We know it's not possible to compare pounds and euros directly we have to convert them to USD.
But someone that only wants to compare pounds and euros might not realize that converting to USD is
necessary.
So what I want to be able to do is this pounds are greater than euros.
Now that we've sent the amount I want to see if the pounds are greater if they're if they are worth
more.
And here is finally where are going into the big 10 methods.
So up to now this has just been a bit of a build up.
Now we go into the built in methods and which is actually fairly simple but nevertheless we're wanted
to give you a bit of background.
Well in order to be able to do this well first of all what happens if we do it.
If we if we just run this file what happens we get a type error on orderable types currency graded on
currency.
We've seen that type error occurs when we give something the wrong type but we're not really calling
anything.
We're not calling a method here.
We're calling the print method.
But even if we remove the print method we still get the type error.
So it's not the print method that's the problem.
It's saying that these types are an orderable it cannot realigns with the pounds rather than Euros or
Guruji rather than pounds because they cannot order them.
It's in the currency Goodland currency doesn't make sense because I don't know what the greater than
sign means for this object that we've created.
So we have to tell it how to calculate greater of them.
So let's once again put the print back in and we're going to tell it how to calculate greater than and
the way we do that in Python is defining another built in method which is G.T. the GTY method is greater
then and it takes in itself.
And another thing that we're comparing with.
OK.
So what we're going to do is return self to us the greater than other to USD.
So what's happening now is that the greater than method the greater than symbol really is calling Pound's
dot G.T. euros.
This is what is being called when we execute pounds greater than euros.
It's getting the pounds object and it's calling the underscore underscored G.T. underscore underscore
method with the opposite side as a parameter.
You wrote as a parameter.
So the GC is not some sort of magical builtin thing in Python it's just another method that gets called
and we can tell it how to compare things.
And when we call the G.T. method we're assuming that other is also a currency object because recalling
that to us the method on it.
So what we're seeing is self is naturally a currency object as it always is.
And other also is a currency object.
And what we're going to do is convert self to USD and the other two USD and compare Now those which
is essentially exactly what we were doing before.
But at the point of use it becomes easier.
So that's why it's useful.
So now we can run this file again and we see the word true come out which is great.
OK.
This is everything for this video but as well as G.T. is also worth looking at.
L t l e.
Which means less than or equal to and naturally G E which is greater than or equal to greater than or
equal to
the elhi is less than or equal to
LTE is less than G.T. is greater than naturally we need to also be able to say whether they are equal
equal equal and if we run this we get false.
What we want to do is eat you and say self-doubting USA equal equal other got to USD and now instead
of comparing the objects themselves is going to compare the contents of that to us to them.
So what it does when we don't have the equal method is it campaigns to see whether the objects aren't
exactly equivalent.
And when we have the EU method then it compares whether the result of this is correct and we have to
return as well.
OK.
And there we go.
So I'll leave it to you to implement these other methods as I'm sure you are able to.
Knowing how these two are going and that is it really for these if you built in methods these are not
all the built in methods that are available in Python but these do make your life a bit simpler when
dealing with mathematical things especially but also with things that can be compared.
It doesn't have to be numbers.
It can be for example to two student objects and you can potentially implement these methods to see
whether their grades are greater than or less than and etc..
So this has a range of uses.
But always remember to make sure it makes sense to be able to do this.
Make sure it makes sense to be able to do lbs greater than Euros.
Does it make sense to do student 1 greater than student 2.
Maybe maybe not.
So keep that in mind when you are implementing these methods.
Do they make sense to use these mathematical operators on them.
But always remember that you can do is not limited to numbers only you can compare anything you want
.
You can compare any property of self to any property of other and that's totally fine.
So that's everything for this video.
Just wanted to teach you about these mathematical symbols and how they are just methods in Python and
also introduce you to this currency class which you're going to be using over the next few videos as
well.
So thanks for tuning in and I'll see you in the very next video