Come back in this video we're looking at how to use the provided data files when you're in PGE admin
3.
Select your database and press the sequel query builder.
And then you'll be greeted with this window that we've seen before that allows you to construct your
sequel queries for the purposes of this course and to get you up to speed and get some data in your
database.
We've also provided you with three sequel files that you can download from the download section in this
lecture.
If you download those and open the folder up then you'll have the three files that you can execute and
those files all they do is create three tables and put some data in them just so you can get started
a bit quicker.
However we will cover everything that those files do here as well as you can learn what they are doing
and how.
But that's just to get you up to speed a bit faster.
That's all for your convenience.
So once you've opened this query builder presses this icon for open file or you can go to File Open
and then you can find the appropriate files which are these three and run the first one first seven
underscore one and then seven on the go to then seven on the three to open seven on the school one underscore
customers.
Open that up and that populates this year.
And what that does is it creates a table and then insert some data into it and then add a primary key
and we're going to be looking into what all those things are and how they work.
And but for now all we have to do is press play which we have to up here and that just creates the table
for you so you don't have to do anything.
Then select all of the contents in here and just delete them.
And we're going to open up the second file and ask you if you want to save your changes and you just
can say no.
Finally open up the second file and do the same thing.
Just run it and finally delete everything there and open up the third file like that and run that again
.
And now what we've got is some data in them we can just close this what we've got now is
three tables there and took a while to appear.
But nevertheless we got three tables that have customers items and purchases.
And they have a very little amount of data but we're going to be putting more in the next few videos
.
And this is just as we can in a small data set.
Explain the different sequel commands and how they work and how you can use them.
And so it's going to be a quick overview of all the sequel commands that are going to be doing over
the next few videos so that you guys can start using sequel in your applications quickly and then after
we look at sequel we're going to be looking at how you can use sequel from within your pipe and application
which is going to be really interesting as well.
So without further ado let's move on to the next video Well we're going to be looking at how the sequel
commands work which commands we can use and how you can really interact and get your data out in a format
that you want.
So what's next with you.