And custom thumbnails for YouTube videos is one of the most effective ways to get more views on your
video and have a consistent brand.
However if you just created your youtube can't and uploaded your first video you may be seeing this
message that you're not eligible for custom thumbnails.
And at the moment you only have the option to select a thumbnail which is an image from the video that
you've uploaded now to enable custom thumbnails.
What you wanna do is go ahead and click on your icon in the top right hand corner.
Then you want to come down into Creator studio and then you want to come down here to the left side
bar and click on channel then you want to move down here and really click on verify.
Now at the moment this is this YouTube channel is not verified and you can see that I am eligible for
some stuff because some thumbnails external annotations and other important features of YouTube are
not enabled.
So what you want to do is go ahead and click verify.
And here you will have a couple of options to verify your YouTube channel.
You just firstly select your country and then you can call it with an automated voice message or text
with a verification code.
Now I think putting in your phone number is probably the easiest thing to do.
So I'm just going to type this in.
Once you put in your phone number just hit submit
a not in the verification code once you get it by text message on your phone.
And now this account has been verified.
If we go back to check our status now and scroll down we can see that the custom thumbnails has been
enabled and those other features as well.
And returning to our video is reload the page and I can see now that I am able to upload a customized
thumbnail.
Now it's your turn.
Click on your channel icon.
Go to the creators studio and verifier can turn my channel so that you can add custom thumbnails to
your videos and get a whole lot more views.