In this video you're going to learn how to use real time reports to monitor activity as it happens on
your Web site or up to access your real time reports.
Just log into your Google Analytics account and open up the sidebar so that you can click through to
the real time reports.
Then there are six reports here.
Overview locations traffic sources content events and conversions.
And if we start by looking at the overview realtime report we can really get a summary of most of these
reports.
So let's have a look at some of this data and then we can discuss some of the use cases of it.
So this is pretty cool.
We can see right now how many people are active on the site and you can see those numbers go up and
down on even the devices that they're logging onto the site from we can see where they're spending their
time.
The top active pages we can see the breakdown of active users.
This is really interesting to see in real time where people are on our site.
We can also see some of the top web sites that they've come from on any social traffic if they've come
from those traffic sources like Facebook or LinkedIn or Twitter Instagram etc. Some kinds can see the
top keywords that they've accessed our site on.
So they may have typed in something to the Google search engine and come through that way.
Often there isn't a lot of information coming through here but it can be useful if it is provided.
Perhaps one of the most interesting real time reports to look at is the locations where people are coming
from and it's just really interesting to see where people are logging in from.
And it can really bring the whole experience of Google Analytics to life and make it real and see all
the changes and people moving around on the site.
Up here we can see the page views per minute and this is really just showing us the number of page views
per minute.
Over the last 30 minutes you can see that's 30 minutes and really up to now.
So what are some of the use cases of this data.
Well first of all if you're seeing data here you know that you're tracking code is working on your Web
site or up because information is coming through onto your Google Analytics.
It's also useful use these real time reports to monitor whether newer change content on your site is
being viewed.
So it can just be good if you've sent out a blog post to see how many people are actually coming through
to have a look at that could be an e-mail or blog post that you promoted by e-mail or maybe on social
media and you can really check if people are coming through from those social channels.
It can also be pretty cool if you've got a one day promotion or a sale on and really see our people
coming through from that.
When are they on the active pages that you want them to be on.
Now another thing that you can use these real time reports for is if you've made any changes to the
conversion process or the check out process to really just make sure that people are actively going
through those pages and there's not something broken off teeth made any changes there.
So these real time reports are pretty cool.
They're even just interesting to come in and have a look at especially see where people are logging
in from and they can be very helpful just to check that everything is working and to keep your finger
on the poles of any campaigns that are active right now.
And for the most part we will be analyzing historical data to guide our long term Web site strategy.
But there are some clear use cases for these real time reports coming into your demo accounts or your
own Google Analytics account and check out these real time reports for yourself.