In this video you're going to learn how to add a Twitter button to your website.
And to do that the first thing you want to do is go to publish dot Twitter dot com on here you will
see all the options for what you can embed from Twitter onto your Web site.
You can click to drop down here to see everything that you can embed or Personally I find it's sometimes
easier just to Braz these options and get a visual of what I can embed for this video we will be adding
a Twitter button so select on this option and you can see that there are different types of buttons
that you can share.
Been to share an article or a link follow button mentioned button hashtag button or message button.
For this example I'll just take the Follow button and then you really want to add your username in here.
Now as you can see the advantage of outing this follow button is that it can help you grow your audience
on Twitter and it makes it easy for your website visitors to really find your profile on follow your
account without even needing to leave to leave the blog post.
So I'm going to hit preview here and then I get this code and what you need to do is really embed this
code onto your Web site so we can copy the code and then as it says here paste this code directly into
the to him a portion of your site and you'll be good to go if you need more instructions.
There are complete instructions here.
So the process is going to be slightly different for each type of web site that you have.
But coming into a WordPress site I'll show you how it's done.
I'm going to click say a post new post as if I was writing maybe a new blog post.
And then what I can do is I can come across to text.
This is where I paste in the DML control V and then if I come across to the visual just need to do it
again so that's in the visual Plaisted and in the text and then I'm going to see it in the visual and
once I hit publish then it's going to show up exactly like that.
So now that you know how to add a Twitter button to your Web site.
Come over to publish dot Twitter dot com and add any button that you want to your Web site so you can
really grow your Twitter got Twitter audience from your Web site.