In this video you're going to learn how to art a YouTube card to video and having a car just like this
that links back to your Web site is a great way to convert leads and generate sales from your youtube
videos and you can also use these cards to add links to Youtube playlists or other videos or even prompt
viewers to make a donation.
So they are a fantastic way for you to really get your viewer to take action and engage with your videos.
No to add cards to your youtube videos you first most need to upload the videos so we add these cards
afterwards.
So in order to access videos that you've uploaded you want to come into each channel click on the icon
in the top right hand corner then come down into the Creator's studio and click then into your video
manager here in the video manager you're going to see even videos that you may have shed Ewold so it
can be a good idea to shed all your videos until you've added the card.
If that is something that you've mentioned in the video like check out the video linked above etc. so
to the Cards find the video first and then click on edit then you can see that there are a number of
tabs across the top here.
We want to come across to the card section and then we really want to start by deciding where we're
going on this card.
Now if you were linking off to another video you may have mentioned that in your video and said If you
want to learn more about that check out this video and it'll be linked above or you may just at the
start of the video encourage people to check at your Web site so we can move this bar to really set
the time that we want the card to appear and you can add multiple cards if you want.
But in this example I'm just going to add a card that pops up after four seconds.
And the card here is a link to my website now to enable a link to your Web site.
You do need to have associated your Web site to your YouTube channel.
And if you don't then it's going to appear appear if you haven't done that you can just click through
and you're going to see the option in settings here to that associate a Web site and it'll walk you
through all the steps to really do that and have that success and green lines show up.
So if you do want to link back to the Web site you can go ahead and do that.
If not you can use one of the options here to link to channel.
If you just want to practice this song and link to web site insert the Web site and click next.
Now we have to put in the card title the call to action and the teaser text.
So if we go back to this example it's already done.
We can see that this is the title.
This is the call to action.
And in fact the teaser text to show you what that looks like.
This should pop by after a couple of seconds up here like that.
So this is something you want to get somebody who's attention so it's fun and some that want to learn
more.
And the call to action we can just put in like something like that
to create the card then just go ahead and click create this image will be pulled from the Web site.
But you can change the image if you want to use a specific one for the card.
So I'm going to go ahead and click and create the card.
Now if we play the video we can see it right here in the video manager.
It appears maybe move it back to the start
and there we go and says want to learn more.
Now if we click this open it is a link back to my Web site and that will help generate leads and sales
from my YouTube videos.
So now it's your turn to come into your video manager and across to the tab for cards.
An ATM card to your Web site or a channel or to promote a video or play list that you have created.