In this video you're going to learn about the most exciting new feature on instagram it's called shopping
on Instagram.
And this is incredibly exciting because it really changes Instagram from a platform where you can inspire
customers and potential customers to a platform where you can sell directly to them.
So let me give you an example of this.
I'm on the Instagram account of this company 10 syle and you can see that they have pictures of their
products here.
It's kind of a tent that you tie up off the ground.
Pretty cool.
But you can see as I scroll them through their Instagram account you can see in some pictures that there
is a little shopping bag in the top right corner.
So let's go click this open now it can see it says top here to view products.
And if I tap that open up combs the product name and the actual price of it.
If I click through I need to be bought to this intermediary page where I can click through again.
And now I'm being brought to the company's Web site where I can go ahead and buy the product directly.
So this is extremely exciting for business owners because you can use Instagram as a way to directly
sell to your customers now and that's a big change from it just being a place to kind of inspire and
show how the product is used in its environments et cetera.
So then to come back here and just explain a little bit about how this works or what's actually happening
here is once you upload a photo you just want tags and then you can put the link to send off two so
people can purchase the product.
Now Instagram isn't taking a cut of these transactions.
That's the other exciting thing.
If you wanted to advertise this post then they would be making money on the advertisement.
But they're not taking a commission on the sale which is even better news for business owners now have
to say that this feature here and shopping on Instagram right now at the time of recording this video
is restricted to certain verticals in for U.S. businesses only.
But I would have done the research and the early trials have been extremely successful.
So there's no doubt in my mind that this feature will be Rhoda rolled out globally across every single
vertical.
So what does that mean for you.
It means this is the number one reason why you should be taking Instagram seriously and building up
your audience right now because this ability to sell directly to your customers for free is just around
the corner.
So hopefully that has got you excited by this new feature on Instagram in general and if you want to
learn how to enable this feature I will link the instructions in the resources of this video and you
can share.
Then if its available free to do right now or if not just look forward to this and coming to your market
or vertical soon.