One of the best things that you can do to grow your Twitter account is to come in and review your Twitter
analytics on a regular basis and to access your Twitter analytics.
Just click on your profile image and then ENM then and click on analytics.
Now in here there are a couple of different screens across the top and then on this home screen especially
this is a great place to find out what kinds of content are getting the most engagement.
Who are the most influential people in your audience and then especially in the audiences time here.
You can really start to understand the age gender and location of your audience.
The demographics very valuable to know.
So let's get started by looking at the top tweets here on the home screen and this is really the top
tweet for the month so far.
That's got the most amount of impressions.
Now this is fantastic to know because you can look at the topic of this tweet.
You know what we're we really talking about here.
You mentioned somebody maybe that resonated with the audience that got likes you could continue to create
more content around that topic going forward because you know that's popular with your audience.
You could also essentially share this tweet throughout the month or next month with slightly different
wording so that you're continuing to maybe share popular content as what you can do in terms of looking
back at your other top tweets as well as look at the format as well.
Did you include an image to include a video.
Are you seeing a lot of differences in terms of impressions when you change up the format.
And that's something that you can test out and then come into your own lines to really see them make
a difference or not coming on then to the top followers.
Another very interesting part of the analytics because in here you can really have a look and even click
through to their profile.
You can thank them for following you can start a conversation with them.
Maybe if they have a similar audience they might have a blog or a pug those podcast.
Then you could say hey you know maybe we could do a guest post.
I go in your site you get on my site etc. if they have a similar audience now you will need to go in
and really click through see if that is you know legitimate cant and maybe they just bought the followers
so you might want to check that out.
But going through even the previous months you can see who their types of followers water content they
put out.
Is there a good match there.
Maybe you could do something like guest post or pour gas or maybe just even connect with an influential
person on line.
Now over here we also have the top mentions So this is a tweet in which someone mentioned you that got
a lot of engagements so you can look at these top mentions maybe thank them again retweet them and in
future try to encourage your audience to mention you or engage with you on Twitter because you will
be shared not only the bills the person who mentions you.
Youll be seen not only by all of their audience but your audience as well.
If you retweet it so it's a great way to kind of if you can get more mentions.
It's just a great way to create content for Twitter that you can retrieve and also then you can really
get in front of other people's audiences as well as encouraging people to connect with you.
I mentioned you on Twitter.
It's just a great way to get more impressions coming across away from the home screen.
We do have a tweet Stabb here which can be interesting to look out to get a look at your total number
of impressions over the last say 28 days you can change the period here you can export the data here
as well if you want.
So again not only looking at your top tweets but also looking at some of your other tweets to see how
they've performed against each other.
And I'll just give you a more in-depth look and metrics for your tweets.
Now in here in the audiences tab This is pretty interesting as well.
You can see a lot of their interests here which can be interesting.
I think Twitter gets a lot of this information from partner sites including like the average income
of your audience et cetera.
What they're interested in so it's pretty high level stuff to be honest take it with a pinch of salt.
But it can just be interesting come in and look and see there's that kind of match up with the audience
that you're trying to attract and probably the most valuable topic is the demographics.
You can see it male female split in your audience 60:40 there and you can see the age range as well.
So you just want to come in and say you know is the audience that I'm trying to attract is the audience
for my blog or my product or my service really matching up with my Twitter audience.
And if not maybe I should make it clear in the content that I'm putting out that it really appeals to
these type of people of this sex but the type of problems that they have that I'm speaking directly
to those type people and even those types of jobs may be and these particular countries as well.
So this is a fantastic page just to get a really clear picture of who may be your best follower is on
Twitter in terms of their persona and you can use the information in here to build that persona up so
extremely valuable.
So Twitter analytics are one of the best ways that you can use or one of the best tools you can use
to grow your Twitter account.
So I'd really encourage you to come in and check it out and once again you can come in and click on
your profile when you're on Twitter.
And then just click on analytics to access it and to analyze it and to get all those insights for yourself.