In this video you're going to learn how to use video IQ to grow your channel.
So firstly what is video IQ.
Well it is a browser extension for Chrome and it shows you a ton of extra stats about your own videos
right on the watch page and also gives you an incredible insight into competitor YouTube channels and
videos and there's a huge amount of information here.
I'm going to walk you through some of the pieces of information that I find most helpful.
But firstly how do you get it.
Well as I said it's a free Chrome browser extension.
I'm going to put the link to this in the description of this video.
And essentially you can just go ahead and take that put to add it to your chrome browser.
And once you do that and reload the page on YouTube you're going to see all of this additional information
next to any video that you open up.
And there is a ton of cool information here.
I just want to dig into some of the ones that I find most helpful when creating videos in order to grow
the channel and really get more views.
One of the best pieces of information here is video tags so I can see for this for this video which
I'm thinking to make a similar video on.
I can see the tags or keywords that this video is ranking in the search engine for it.
So if I type in how to use YouTube analytics
I have to use YouTube analytics I can see that this video is coming up.
Number one as it says here if I just go ahead and type in youtube analytics I can see that the video
is number one.
So this shows me really the ranking of this video for these particular keywords.
Now how is this useful.
Well if you were to create a video you want to make sure that your ranking for these tags is well and
include these tags as part of your video when you're optimizing and uploading your video.
Also you can use this information to put together a title that's really going to match up exactly with
those terms.
So you could make a video like here like how to use YouTube analytics to grow your channel.
That ties in exactly what people are searching for and it is a compelling title and it's different to
the competitors title as well so these tags are incredible just for getting an insight into what search
terms a competitors ranking for.
You can use that information to help optimize your own videos and you can also see what your ranking
for this information will come up for your own videos.
And you can maybe adjust your title slightly to make it fit better with the tags that it's already ranking
for.
And that'll help you get more click through is now as well as the video tags.
Another thing that I really like about video IQ and how it helps me to grow my channel is by looking
at the referrers here.
So getting social shares is a key part of getting those initial views on your videos especially if you've
very low audience.
You do want to get that promotion out there and things that you can do for example by looking at these
referrers is come up and open these up and maybe you could tweeze add this particular U2 profile or
Twitter profile here and say you know hey I've noticed you shared out a similar YouTube video in the
past.
I've made a version of myself.
Maybe you want to share it with your followers.
You can also do that with other people who shared it on their Web site.
So if we look at this referrers again we can look at the Web sites where it's been shared.
We could maybe email them and say hey you know I've created a similar video to what you've shared in
the past.
Maybe you want to share it as well.
So that's another cool thing that you can do as well as looking at this information on the watch page
of videos.
There's a lot of information about you know the channel here as well and which monthly revenue it earns
or type of stuff.
And but another interesting thing is if you come in and search for something you can give you an indication
of how competitive this keyword is and the relative search volume.
So you really want to be creating videos around search terms that have a high search volume but low
competition and you can see it gives you an overall score here 71 out of 100.
So that is a pretty good keyword to make a video about because there's high search volume and low competition.
So that is how you can use video IQ to grow your channel by spying on the competitors and seeing what
their ranking for using that information to run your home videos and also help pick the topics for the
videos that you're going to go and make.
So now it's your turn.
Go ahead and click the link in the description so you can add that IQ and use it to help grow your YouTube
channel.