The first step to getting your business in front of 200 million people on Pinterest is to set up a Pinterest
business account so to do that you want to go to Bisan stop Pinterest dotcom and go ahead and join as
a business.
Now in here you can put in your business name or set up a Pinterest profile for your personal brand.
Now I do want to say that if you do already have a personal Pinterest account and you want to use Pinterest
as a personal brand all you need to do instead of setting up a new profile is to go into your Pinterest
profile and then in settings you can convert it to a business profile.
And the reason that you want to set up a business profile either for a company or for a personal brand
is because the business isn't Pinterest profile will give you Pinterest analytics and it also enable
you to advertise directly on Pinterest if you want.
So you need to do is go ahead and fill out the details.
And I'm just going to fill this as my own name and then I'm going to go ahead and create create and
it can't so just select whatever language and country that's suitable for you.
And then we want to pick three things your audience cares about.
So I can say for me education
technology and I can also say maybe 10 here means OK or inspirational quotes maybe better.
And now we've created our Pinterest business that can't.
If we come into our profile here we can see it is pretty bare at the moment.
But that's really the first step to getting set up on Pinterest to go ahead.
Pinterest of business dotcom and create your Pinterest can for your business.