In this video you're going to learn how you can perform in-depth analysis in Google Analytics by using
custom dashboards and custom dashboards appear here inside the customization section of your Google
Analytics account.
So really what this is enabling you to do is go beyond the standardized reports that you find in Google
Analytics and create custom dashboards or reports for yourself by creating the CS customized dashboards.
You can really do that in-depth analysis and see correlations that you might see inside the standardized
reports.
So if we come in to the dashboards here we can see that there's already a number of ad dashboards set
up in this Google Analytics account.
For example if we click into these side performance dashboard what we can see here are many metrics
related to site performance in one place.
So why would you want to set up a dashboard about site performance.
Well many of these metrics you wouldn't find them normally in one report.
So what you can do is really gather the information and put them into one dashboard like this so you
can monitor this particular aspect of your Web site in a very focused way.
Now you also might want to create a dashboard say if there's somebody on your team who's responsible
for more technical stuff about your Web site and in particular site performance well then you can create
this dashboard for them so they can really focus on improving these particular metrics.
They might not have anything related to do to marketing or advertising so they don't really need to
see all of this other stuff down here.
So the way that these dashboards work is that these are actually widgets and these are summaries of
different reports or metrics taken from different reports.
And that's the advantage of these dashboards that you can see a lot of different metrics and reports
or a summary of them in one place and that allows you to see different correlations be tween metrics
and really spot trends and opportunities to grow so as well as creating dashboards for things like site
performance you could create it for say somebody who's responsible for the PPC advertising or responsible
for SEO.
You can create those dashboards for those different roles or for those different aspects of the business.
Now there are two ways to add dashboards to your Google Analytics account.
The first way is to create them from scratch yourself and you can pick a blank canvas like this click
Create dashboard and then you can go ahead and build up an ad in these widgets.
Taking those metrics or reports or summaries for them and putting them in one place.
Now there is a little bit more advanced and can be quite quite time consuming.
So the easier way to add dashboards to your Google Analytics accounts is really to get them from other
Google Analytics users who's who've already built them.
And the easy way to do this is to come into the Google analytics solutions gallery.
This is where different Google Analytics users share the templates for their custom dashboards and reports
and you can really import these into your Google Analytics accounts in one click.
So there are a list of the most popular custom dashboards and reports here or you can also say search
for one specifically if you want to find that.
And you can see here SVOD dashboard there is top content in keywords you can look at something like
this a starter bundle which if you click to import you can see this not only contains some custom dashboards
here but also some custom reports.
That's really a big starter bundle and you just have to click Create there.
And that is going to be imported into your Google Analytics accounts and then you'll find all of those
once you import them underneath your custom dashboards and custom reports.
So the cool thing about the dashboards is there's those two ways to add them and it's great that you
can just go to the solutions gallery and import a load of them check them out.
Now one thing that you can do also is if you've imported some dashboards and you find well that's way
too technical or it's not what I'm really looking for.
What you can do is come in and collectively dashboard and you can just get rid of them and focused in
on what you need.
So if you do create dashboards and you want to share them with team members what you can do is come
in here you can export these dashboards so if you wanted to give a specific report to say a boss on
site performance you can export the dashboard as a PDA.
And that really gives them like a printout that you could present in a meeting or in a presentation
really showing the key metrics related to say your specific role.
You could give this to clients for example to really give them some metrics to see how it's performing.
Now there are a couple of limitations with custom dashboards.
You can have up to 20 dashboards per account and also within each dashboard you can only have 12 widgets
or 12 kind of snapshots of different metrics or reports so choose those wisely.
So in summary custom dashboards allow you to go be on the standardized reports and get a dashboards
full of metrics and reports that are specific to your business or roll.