In this video you're going to learn how to create a customer file custom audience.
It's an extremely valuable audience that you can use to target your Facebook ads to keep this whole
off what you want to do is once again come into your odds manager.
Click on the dropdown in the top left hand corner.
We're in audiences again.
Just click on that and you'll be brought to these audiences page once again up here.
You want to click once again on create audience and click on a custom audience.
And this time you're making it from a customer file.
So what we're doing is actually uploading our e-mail list into Facebook and then Facebook is going to
match our customers with the people on Facebook.
So they'll be able to match them by an e-mail address or a phone number or even sometimes a name or
a combination of those.
No it doesn't have to just be an e-mail list.
It could be for example if you have an e-commerce store and you have those details from people when
they've bought a product.
So as you can imagine this is an extremely valuable audience to create because it's not just people
who visited your web site.
It's actually that people have taken the next step demo to PD.
You sign up to your main mailing list who bought a product so very valuable audience to use to get started
then just click on customer file on here in order to create this audience and upload your list of two
options.
You just copy and paste the data and they do have an integration with MailChimp so I'm going to go ahead
and use this option.
Otherwise you're just really uploading a CXVII file and importing it into Facebook.
So they're going to click on import from MailChimp if you select this option.
You don't just need to go in and log in then and start to create a custom audience from any of the email
lists that you have.
Now at this point it's important to say that I'm going to be importing my full e-mail list for my web
sites.
About 9000 people on that.
If you do want to import just a segment of that e-mail list maybe people who have signed or opted into
a particular e-mail list or people who bought a particular product then you would have to segmented
before you really imported in some way to create an audience of this here.
Now I can name this customer audience if I want and I'm just going to put in an email list.
Custom audience and click Next on their And go ahead and click done now what you can see is that it's
showing up as not ready yet and it will take up to half an hour for the total e-mail list to be imported
and matched up to Facebook's users.
Now one important point of note here is that Facebook custom audiences do not automatically update subscribers
are added to your email list so you will need to rebuild your audience each time you want to create
a targeted OD for them and not that caveat is not just for MailChimp But as you can see if you're just
uploading a CSP file of your e-mail list then you will need to update that or create a new audience.
In order for those additional people to be added one of the thing that you need to be aware of as well
is that not everybody on your list is going to be matched up with profiles on Facebook.
For example I bet 9000 people on my email list I expect to maybe get about 4000 5000 by 50 percent.
Much of that is a good guideline for you as well.
Once youve created your customer file custom audience you want to start taking advantage of it straight
away.
So I wanted to give you four cool ideas or use cases for how you could put it into action.
The first thing that you could do is to create a campaign to increase your page likes and to use this
new audience to really make that happen.
So you probably have people on your email list or on your customer file who have not liked your Facebook
page.
You can use this new audience to run a campaign with that objective and you can really exclude people
on that same campaign.
You have already liked your Facebook page you are on the list Syrie to getting targeted.
Just people who haven't like the Facebook page and that's going to give you a huge boost in page lots.
Another cool use case of this custom audience is to extend the reach of your posts.
So you probably have people on your email list who maybe aren't opening your emails or who aren't engaging
with you at all on Facebook and by using this custom audience you can really reach them there and extend
the reach of your posts.
The turn way that you can use this custom audience is to sell or sell a product.
These people have already joined your email list or they've already bought a product in the past through
an e-commerce store they are going to be a very warm audience.
They're even warmer than people who just visited your website and so the probability that they are going
to biproduct for you or buy a product similar to the product that they bought is very very high.
So being able to target those people is very valuable and is a great way that you can put this custom
audience to work in the final way that you can use this code to monetise is to create a look alike audience
and really target people in your Facebook ads who are similar to your subscribers.
Now I'll show you how to set up a look alike audience later on.
But it is an advantage of even a small email is using it as a source for a much bigger look alike audience.
So then you know how to make a customer file custom audience.
Go ahead and set one up for yourself.
Following the steps that youve learned in this video.