In this video you're going to learn how to add a profile image to your Instagram account.
That's going to attract your audience.
So what I'd recommend you do is you click in and open up the top influencers that you have already added
to your accounts and it's in here that you can see the profile images that you or that they are using
now for this example the kinds I'm just creating an account where I'm the face of my business and I
may be a personal finance planner.
So what I can see here is that because it's more of a can't where on the face my business and I've followed
these top influencers.
They're all using personal profile images.
And if I scanned and through these five scans personally the one that grabs my attention the most is
this one at the bottom.
Dave Ramsey here and I think he's done a couple of things particularly well in this photo which I wanted
to point out because these are best practices that you should use for yourself.
So the first thing is that here he has got a very clear background it's a bright color.
So it really does.
His face really pops off the page.
Also the picture is very close in terms of it's cropped quite close.
So we really get a good picture of his face.
He's also I think dressed in an inappropriate way that's going to appeal to his audience.
So if we read his bio here it says America's trusted voice on money solvency trust is a very important
being an authority.
And you can see he's wearing a suit and a shirt and he's got passes on.
So he looks smart.
He's kind of an older guy and so this is kind of a perfect profile image which I think would really
attract his audience because they would see him as an authority.
And it's obviously a professional photo.
It's easy to recognize him and it kind of suits the type.
He's wearing the type of thing that his audience would expect if he was in his gym clothes.
Well it wouldn't be obvious that we're talking about business and money.
So that is a great example of someone doing it really well let's have a look at some of these other
guys we can look at Tim Ferriss here.
Now I think personally for me you can see that he's quite a bit of a distance back from the camera he's
pointing to his T-shirt which I don't understand what that's about.
And it's also just hard to recognize in the background of that image is obviously him standing in maybe
a house or something like that.
I don't really know what's going on there.
So you can see it doesn't pop off the page as much now in his profile page here.
It's probably still recognizable as him.
But if we go to a kind of a an individual post you can see he appears much smaller at the top of the
page.
So it's much harder to recognize that as him.
And so that's really the difference between the two that we've seen there.
Maybe he could improve that a lot by just following more similar to what Dave Ramsey is here doing here
a much closer shot of the face and maybe a clear background that really pops off.
He doesn't have to be in his seat.
If that's not what is really going to attract his audience and what his audience expects to see.
Now there's some other ones here.
You can see that Gary Vaynerchuk he is is a picture of him in the front of a magazine which is quite
a clever use of it gives him some social proof.
But again I can't really read any of that.
And maybe just a closer picture of the face would be better.
So in terms of your personal profile picture again to recap some of the best practices keep that shot
of the face pretty close.
I wouldn't bother putting any text in there trying to have a clear background if you can and dress appropriately
to watch your audience for expects that doesn't have to be business.
If you're into fitness you could be in your fitness clothes or whatever.
So that is a personal profile picture and always have a look at top influencers in YOUR needs to really
understand what they're doing.
And let's have a look at some actual business accounts.
So I want to show you a company here called HubSpot.
And I think they've done it quite well.
You can see actually they've got a number of accounts on Instagram here and what they've done is they
just have one background color and then a color for their logo only two colors.
And I'd recommend you follow that as well.
And then also you can see there's no text in there.
It's very simple.
Even if we click into in to look at one of their posts in the top left corner here it's still instantly
recognizable as them.
And it really pops off the page.
Now I want to show you another account that maybe isn't on as well just so you have that comparison
again.
So this company tends tile actually pretty interesting company.
They kind of have these tents that you tie up.
So pretty cool e-commerce company.
But you can see their logo here.
It is two colors but it's black and white.
And they have text on it also and it looks OK on their profile page.
But then when we come into one of their posts you can see it's it's black on white so it doesn't really
pop off the page in the top left hand corner.
And also that text becomes unreadable.
Then there's no real need to include any text because the name of the account is right there.
So my opinion would be for them to change that logo maybe have an orange on wice and just keep that
kind of image removed that text and I think that would pop off a lot more on the page be more recognizable.
When people see these type of posts in their news feed.
So for a business it can't as well.
There are those best practices and if you want to come back and have a look at a good example HubSpot
you can see that they've done it well.
It's no tax just one color.
Navy's bright colors to make sure it really pops off the white background that goes on in school.
So once you have decided what profile picture you want to use to actually add the profile picture you
want to come in and click on settings.
Top right hand corner and it profile and then you can change your profile image.
Now the option here to import it from Facebook Twitter etc. or choose from your library.
I'm going to do now I've got a picture that I've uploaded to my phone before and this is as I've as
I've kind of recommended just two simple colors and just using this for a set up demo Cance.
And I think that looks pretty good.
I can click done and I just need to confirm my email which I'll do now.
And then I can just click on.
So if you come back to my profile you can see the profile image is loaded up.
I think it really does pop off the page.
Got a bright color backgrounds and that is how you really add a profile image to your Instagram accounts.
So now it's your turn.
Go ahead and add their personal profile picture or business logo to your Instagram account following
the steps and best practices that you've learned in this video.