The number one thing that you can do to have success on Pinterest is to follow five top influencers
in your niche now by doing this this will really help you when you're creating your profile filling
in.
So you have somebody to model there.
And also even in terms of the boards that you create and the content that you pin you can really see
where people in your name sure are doing what they're successfully doing and that makes that process
so much easier for you.
So in order to find those top influencers in your nation they're cance what you can do is just type
in your topic into the search bar here in Pinterest and what you're going to see now here is all of
the pins so all of the images for that particular keyword what you might want to do is come across to
people and in here I can see then some of the top cance for my knee share.
So I can see the number of followers 30000 followers 17000 followers and 19000 followers etc..
So all I need to do is open up these all these accounts and we can even look at the marketing Philippines.
You can have a look around at some of these and maybe even just get a sense of which would be the best
ones to follow.
So all I need to do is have a look at their Pinterest account read their profile quickly.
Is this something that's going to be similar to what I want to do.
If yes you can just go ahead and follow their accounts and you can see if they've got 30000 followers
will they must be doing something right.
If we look here as well digital marketing publishing we can have a quick look at their content so they
seem quite a broad amount of different fidget spinner's amazing hair.
So maybe that's not exactly in account that I would want to follow.
Digital marketing consultants.
OK 19000 followers.
Content Marketing Social Media Marketing Pinterest marketing.
OK.
So I really like the way that he's laid out his profile here visual content is his deafening guy that
I could model my Pinterest account on.
So let's see digital marketing.
This looks like maybe an agency our revenues brain game logical puzzle.
So again maybe not the perfect type of a to follow.
Here is another one blogging online traffic online engagement e-commerce so I can even see by the way
that they've laid out their profile that looks pretty good.
And sometimes you might find when you type in just one term maybe the appropriate people.
So what you can do is you can actually click into even digital marketing tips you can use the Pinterest
search bar and the suggested search terms here to narrow down your search.
If you want to find something more specific and then look into people there.
Another cool thing that you can do is just go to Google and search in like top Pinterest the cance digital
marketing or whatever it is your keyword or knishes there and then let's see here we've got a list of
people 27 or some social media markers to follow on Pinterest.
So I can get this list a lot of pop ups here if I can get this list.
OK let's open up some of these
7000 followers.
OK.
She looks pretty good if you scroll down to Twitter for marketing.
Perfect.
If I go back to my profile Let's see how many people I followed there
got seven followers or seven people I'm following now so I've got one two three four maybe just want
to get one more so I can return to this list.
And that's what this person here
NYC 10000 followers.
Scroll down and see the boards.
OK this looks good as well.
So now I can see I'm following eight people are topics.
So I've got my five people here.
And actually I have my topics here that I set up in the setup process can actually follow those if you
want.
Now I'm just sorry you have that focus list of people to look at.
But already now just by following those top five influencers in my knees I have a much clearer idea
already about how I'm going to lay out my profile how I'm going to lay out my boards and even some of
the content that I'm going to put out there.
So I would highly recommend you do this.
I think this is the number one thing that you can do to accelerate your success on Pinterest.
Just model the people who are already successful on the platform and pull all the best ideas from their
profile.