In this video you're going to learn how to add a profile image link to your Web site and a short bio
on your Twitter profile.
And to do that you just want to click on the edit profile button on your Twitter profile you can see
that your profile image you can change the name of your Twitter account.
You can change your bio here or out of biol you can at a location on your Web site and even change your
team color if you wanted to.
And this video we're going to focus on a couple of key things on that profile image the bio and the
link to your Web site.
So before you start to get into this process I think a great way to speed this all up is to look at
the accounts that you were following.
Who are the top influencers in your knees and really look at their profile image the link to their website
on their bio and that can really accelerate the process for you.
So let's open up a few of these in a separate town.
And open that six top influences here that I've followed previously and we just want to have a look
at where they've set up their profiles so we can look at the profile image here.
It's a good head shot.
You can see he's kind of got something unique about himself the mustache that really stands out and
makes even from a small profile image here you can see that it's him.
So this is the key thing you want to keep in mind about your profile image that it is very small when
it's on a tweet like this and even on a mobile device we really want a close head shot.
If you are setting it up as a personal account so that people can recognize you from a distance.
If we look at the profile image for a company you can see it's just a simple logo.
It's two colors wide on kind of purple.
You can see that is very easy to recognize in a small tweet.
Let's have a look at another couple in their profile images.
Again this is a logo type profile two colors.
Very easy to see even on a small image like this which will even be smaller on a mobile phone.
We can see here again just more of a personal shot and close image.
Again similar type professional type looking photo smiling.
Pretty simple closeup head shot.
And finally here we go again self-tanner.
So quite a close head shot recognizable as well.
So for your own profile image you really want to either put it in your business logo or a close up shot
like that.
And to add your profile image you can just click on the button here upload the photo upload this from
my desktop and then it's going to come out as a circular type picture like that you can increase or
decrease the size of it.
And then just click apply so then we can refresh the profile just to see how it looks like and if you're
happy with that then we can move on to the next step which is really to add in a little bio about ourselves.
So this bio again we can just look at the top what are the top influencers dating.
They figure this stuff out.
Let's just take the best from them so we can see here is that this is more of a personal Twitter profile.
And he was the thirtysomething retiree and he writes about the need for Freeville life.
So in this bio you want to start to communicate some of the benefits of following your Twitter profile.
So writes about how to we can all live frugal yet bought us a life of pleasure so it kind of gives a
hint to watch.
And this profile is about why should I even follow this because he can give me some tips about how to
live frugally a badass life of leisure and you can see the stars and bring across some of the personality
of this page is all matching or the kind of crazy mustache and the personality of this profile is coming
across kind of scrawny.
Daphne catches attention.
Let's have a look at more professional type business bio.
Follow us.
So this is a great bio follow us to here on our thoughts in investing retiring savings Kaname and more.
This is a much more direct bio it's like why should you follow us on and saying exactly why.
And they're saying follow us we care call to action for people so people read this and they go follow
us.
Why.
OK.
Here are some of the reasons why.
And I have a couple of terms conditions here which they lay out probably for financial business that
is you know money anything you invest is on your own risk.
Etc. So let's have a look at some other one get rich slowly.
So why would I follow this profile because I could get rich slowly.
Names one of the best time magazine blogs.
OK so a little bit of social proof here and her sense of personal finance again including that type
the key word in the bio is another great way to include that.
Have a look at another one.
Personal finance again including the key word in the Buy a frugal living tweets by Ashley Jacobs.
And then it must be playing golf to her profile.
So you often see that as well.
People linking off to other profiles of other companies that they're running they often think of those
as well.
So we'll look at the last one.
OK.
Personal finance again the key word is in the bio.
And then he's using this space to promote his new book which is a pretty good idea.
Ok this book.
OK.
And it's and it's there.
Probably if it included it linked to that book would even be better.
But you can see that you can change this up.
You can use it to promote certain things that you're doing right now and even match that in maybe your
header image as well.
So look at your own bio and take some inspiration from the kinds that you've seen.
If it's more of a business expense or if it's more personal and you can't get across her personality
and include your keywords so I like that one follow us.
Her tips personal finance and maybe some other keywords that are related to your needs needs there as
well as I you can include location.
So Twitter's going to know this pretty much straight away based on where you're logging in from.
You can leave that as a country if he wants.
You don't have to put in location.
So this this company doesn't have it's kind of an online blog.
So maybe there's no need for all over the place and you can see really if location is a part of your
business if you're a local business or if you're based somewhere then that can be or if you're a personal
person you can put that in.
So I'm just going to put in Dublin where even just put in something like it in the country as well if
you want to if you think that's relevant.
And the next step is really to put in a link to your website so you can see there is just a link to
the Web site.
And what you can also do is if you if you don't want to send them to your home page you could put in
something like
you could put in something like offers or discounts on.
That just gives people a little bit more incentive to click on that link if they think they can get
something by clicking through.
And you might even mention that in your bio like Click below to get discounts.
That's another strategy that can be very successful.
So once you're happy with your bio.
Your location and your web site you just want to click Save to see those changes really come up.
And again you can change this any time you want.
For now just get something set up so that when people do start visiting your profile that there's a
profile image there's an explanation of why they should follow you.
Whether that's very direct or indirect and to include a link to your Web site if you have one as well.
So now that you know how to optimize your profile go ahead and do it for yourself and use those top
influencers that you followed as inspiration to accelerate this process.