In this video you're going to learn how to add your first five posts to your Facebook page.
So to get started what you wanted to do is make sure that if you're a brand new page you might be having
a couple of posts like this that show your cover image and profile that you've uploaded.
So while we want to do is actually just go ahead and delete these or hide them from the timeline because
we really wanted to.
The post that we show to our audience to be highly valuable so they understand why they should like
this page and why they should really want to see updates from us in their news feed.
So that's why it's very important.
Before you even go ahead to invite people to like your pages to create a base of content maybe three
to five posts that really show why somebody should follow your page.
So the first post that you could make is simply just a milestone post.
And what we want to do is select from the dropdown we can add a milestone to your page and you can just
say something like You know we open for business
than today's days location if that's relevant and
to say we're open for business.
OK.
So I've had it in a little bit of text there we're delighted to say that we're open for business.
Always check the spelling.
We look forward to engaging with you here on our brand new Facebook page.
Like this page to stay updated so you can say something simple like that a call to action like like
this page.
You could even include an option there to get people to go to your Web site.
You can upload a photo as well.
So does this photo online come in we're open.
You can adjust that as you want.
But the point is that you create a post that's a milestone posts.
We're open for business or our Facebook pages live whatever you want it to be.
But that's a very simple first post that you can make on Facebook.
Now in terms of what else you should be adding in here.
Well you can really add maybe a link to a blog article that you've written.
And if you're struggling to get ideas for what you could put down then a great thing to do is to look
at some competitor pages.
So just having a look at some
pages here so let's just imagine that I was opening a restaurant in my city what I could do is find
a couple of Facebook pages of restaurants that are here locally that are doing well on Facebook and
you can determine that by the number of followers and engagements on their posts.
Have a look at the type of posts that they're putting out.
So here's a great example and this could apply perfectly to a new business officially opened in Belfast
from 1:00 p.m. today finace at this address and there's a picture of people queuing at the door.
So as you can see this type of post got a lot of engagements particularly for local business this is
a great idea because anybody in the city then will be likely to tag friends or share this because they
know the address of where they're opening and even the city and what time it's opening.
And that could just be a photo from almost anywhere the location that could have been from a pre-party
that you set up and the official opening is today.
So it's quite a clever use and actually a great example of maybe a first post that you could put up.
Here's another one like free burgers get free burgers in our new Belfast's place at 3 p.m. tomorrow
Saturday until we run out dresses five fishtailed etc..
So especially for local businesses.
Your first posts are actually a brilliant opportunity to get the word out quickly.
Even if you can include something like a free offering could be a free consultation might not work for
your type of business trying be creative to get that buzz going so that a lot of people are going to
want to share that message in 0 7.
170 people obviously want to share free burgers.
Who doesn't like that.
So anything you can do in those initial posts creates an excitement and is a great idea.
So looking at some competitors that are doing well on Facebook is a great place to find new ideas.
Obviously it's going to be different for every type of business that you have but for your first couple
of shows come in and look what's working for them.
Why are they getting engagement.
What is the type of content.
Is it a GIF like this.
Is it competition's higher or are they really doing it.
Here's another example of a restaurant locally as well.
We come down to the post section here.
We can take another love.
So give us some good.
You could team at around the season.
December is just around the corner so get get booking at this address or this e-mail address.
Hopefully we'll see you soon and see quite a lot of engagement.
That's just a quick video.
Uploaded catches the attention.
And again they're just saying the last few days to catch this special moving up again last few days
to catch this special.
So obviously every of every business is going to be different.
But really look at those successful pages in order to get ideas for your first posts.
So comedy competitions just say we're opening could be links to your blog posts but you need to put
her in a room by three to five posts here before you start to invite anybody to your Facebook page so
that they have a reason to hit that like button.
In order to see future posts in their news feeds you have to give them a reason in order to do that.
And if you can give them a reason to engage with your content they're even better because that will
help get the word out and get them to use their social network to spread and market your business.