In this video you're going to learn how to create boards and on pins to them on Pinterest.
This is a key part of building your audience it's the most important step singing a walk you through
everything.
So first thing what what is a boy and what's the purpose of it.
Well I recommend that you look at some of the top influencers canes in your niche.
For example here for digital marketing you can see this guy has 20000 followers.
This is THE NATION I'm working in.
And if I just look at his profile and look at his boards and scroll down I can see that essentially
these boards act as different topics or subtopics so you can see that the main topic is digital marketing.
But obviously there's a lot of more specific topics within that like digital marketing strategies Social
Media Marketing Content marketing influence or marketing Pinterest marketing blogging tips etc..
So really these boards help to organize content for those subtopics.
Now let's look at it completely different each.
We can see this is an e-commerce store Moria's seal again a lot of followers over 900 Italians and you
can see that they have used these boards to organize into categories Eskin so their own store jewelry
Bohemia plants get fancy art home decor hotsync cetera.
And these boards are helpful to people because they might just be looking to get ideas about hats.
So it's better for them to come into these boards and see all of the content organized here and that
helps them get those ideas much much easier.
So essentially these boards just organize them and organize the content pretty much.
Now you can be quite creative with these boards like gifts soner 25 classes and sonis if Sundra a hundred
makeup and beauty even something like knives you think that is extremely nice.
But there's over a thousand pins on that scarves over the horizon pins so people really do like to get
specific on Pinterest because there's so much content there.
If people can organize it for them in boards they're going to want to follow that board to keep updated
on those ideas.
So this is how you add value on Pinterest by either organizing your own content in different boards
and I'm going to show you as well you can actually organize other other people's content into these
boards as well.
And finally let's look at this food blog pinch of Yum.
Same idea boards are used to organize content recipe videos appetizers baking bowls breakfast brunch
drinks healthy meals desserts pizza pasta etc..
So really looking at some topic can your needs is a great way to get ideas for even washboards to create
and how to lay them out.
Now I do want to give you a pretty cool tip as well as your boards can appear at the top of the search
engine and what you want to do is actually what this guy's done here he's done a pretty well.
You can see that the way he's named his boards is actually very specific.
So he's not just saying random things.
He's saying digital marketing strategy fails to open that up and actually see it in the link there.
So why is he named.
Well if I come into Pinterest and I search for Digital Marketing So that's the main topic in my niche.
Now what you can see underneath the search bar are these suggested search terms.
And this works the exact same way as Google Sink's suggested search.
They're going to put in other additional keywords here that are highly search.
So you know if these are appearing underneath here these are highly search terms.
And so if I click on strategy which is the number one term after digital or digital marketing I can
see that actually if I come across them boards I can see this guy ran sellers appearing right at the
top because he's named his board after the exact search term.
So when you're creating your boards you should really think about that as well.
Create your boards really around those search terms.
You can appear at the top of the search results and get more visibility for your boards.
It's a really good tip to grow quickly.
So now that we have a clear idea about what the boards are how to name them the next logical question
is What do you actually put in these boards.
Well the great news is is that you don't have to only put your own content in you might not have a ton
of content and so your thinking had a build up an audience on Pinterest.
Well the great thing that you can do is you can pin other people's content into your boards.
Now this is still valuable for people and people want to follow this.
As you can see here because essentially you're operating as an aggregator you're helping organize content
filtering for people.
And of course they're are going to want to follow that board if that's useful for them and saves them
time and searching for it all together.
Cetera.
So we can see if we look at these pins here and we look at the links at the bottom of the pins.
You can see these are all coming from actually different Web sites.
So essentially what this guy's done is just created a board that's helpful for people that organizes
content underneath those search terms.
And as a result 13000 followers is not a bad results from that.
So what I might want to do is not only add my own content but look on Pinterest for other content that
I could add to my boards and make it more valuable for the Pinterest users.
So now that we understand what boards are how to name them and what to put in pin in the boards.
That's actually go ahead and create a board for ourselves.
And actually what we do is we can pin something and create a board at the same time so I think we'll
go ahead and do that.
Now again what I'm going to do is look for my key word.
So
so digital marketing.
Now what I want to find out is well what can I create a board on then.
And if I look across have ideas social media money in for graphics for graphics is pretty interesting.
So what I might think of doing is maybe I can create a board about the best digital marketing and for
graphics is a good as you can see there a lot here and not all of them are are maybe that good.
So if I can create a board on the best ones that would appeal to people and they'd want to follow that
board and I can't because it be useful to them.
So what I can do then is go ahead.
Once I've decided on the kind of bored name I want to add some content to that board I don't have maybe
an info graphic right now.
So I'm just going to pin this piece of content to the board and I can create the board at the same time.
So what I'm going to do is best digital marketing infographics and you can make this a secret board
if you want so you don't have.
It doesn't have to be public.
You can hide it IDOLO the content and then publish it later.
But I think it's OK to just go ahead and publish it straight away and they're going to go ahead and
print create.
So now I can see that that pin has being created.
So the board is being created so if I come to my profile and come to the board and I can see that the
best digital marketing for graphics has been added there and it might take a little bit of time just
to load up what the pin will show up there eventually as well.
Now what I can also do as well as pinning other people's content and aggregating content like that that's
helpful for people I can also create my own contents.
And so what I can do is maybe create a pin and take it from the web and I can actually take content
from my own site and pin it in here.
So I'm just going to take an article from my blog and pasted in here.
When I click Next I'm going to see all of the images on that page that I can put into a show is the
image on Pinterest.
So I'll just take this one here.
Now I could put it under the best digital marketing for graphics and create a new board which I might
do is more something like marketing fundamentals so people who who just really want to understand the
fundamentals of marketing and I can create the board by that.
And so I can see it now.
What I should have now is keyboard's for going to my profile what I've got now is two pens and two different
boards there.
Now what I can do is to improve these even further is I can actually go ahead and add a description
to these boards.
And if you're stuck for that as well.
Once again what you can do is maybe just look at some top competitors and see where they are.
What type of descriptions that they are using.
So you can see this board is a collection of great tips and ideas for somebody learn how to do X Y Z.
And so you can take a you can even copy this paste it in there.
But he added it to this specific board.
So this board is the collection of the best digital marketing and for graphics on Pinterest and you
can include that in there.
And the reason you want to do that is that gives people another incentive for them to follow the board.
And you can also say what this board is about to make it clear to Pinterest as well.
So I could maybe put this as technology or other.
And then you can also add collaborators for these boards as well if you've got other team members that
you want to help work on now as well as adding a description to your boards what you can actually do
is add a description to any content that you pinch yourself as well.
So again telling people a little bit about why they should click through and what this post is about.
And again if we look at some examples here you can start to get a very good sense of what the type of
descriptions that people come put in here.
And then you can look at the best ones there and take some examples.
It's going to be slightly different sort of recap then in this video you've learned how to create boards
how to name those boards so you can appear at the top of the search engine.
You learn how to add content to those boards using other people's content so you can build a valuable
resource for your Pinterest followers or by adding your own content as well.
And by adding descriptions to those boards and those pins so that they give that incentive people to
click through and also that will help you appear higher in the search engine on Pinterest as well.
So what I would recommend you do is take a little bit of time maybe go ahead and create three boards
put a bad five pins in each and that is really going to set the foundation of content for your Pinterest
account.