In this video you're going to learn how to add an additional view to your Google Analytics.
It can't.
This is the best practice when you're setting up Google Analytics So you have a backup of your data.
And if we click up here on the top left corner you can see that by default you will have one view for
your Google Analytics account when you set it up.
However you're going to be adding filters segment's goals and other configurations like that to your
Google Analytics data.
So you want to have an unfiltered view an untouched view that you can always go back and look at just
in case anything does go wrong when you are adding those configurations on filters.
So to create an additional view you want to come into the admin section in the bottom left corner you
can see that in the view column here the options see all your views.
Right now we just have one what we're going to do is actually to rename the one view that we have right
now and we can just click into this year view settings
so as we scroll and we can see the new name and what I suggest you do here is just call it number one.
Master you now this is the view that you'll be using on a day to day basis.
So we can just say the now if we look at our views be screenings.
Page
So our master view.
Now we want to create our additional views and marketing them to create 2 new views.
We're going to call this one to test view what you can do with this test fuse.
If you're adding a filter a goal configuration you can test today in this view.
First maybe try it for a week see if all the data is being presented as you want it to be presented.
And then you can apply a filter or configuration to your master view.
And finally we do want that raw data view just so we always have the back of cohort data.
So call this number three and wrong.
The as you.
So there we go.
We have our three views once again are monster view is what we'll be using on a day to day basis and
remember a view is just a perspective.
So you get a little bit more advanced you can set up views to show the data that's only relevant say
to PPC manager or management in a company.
But for setup purposes you really want to use the view just to make sure that you have that raw data
backup.
So that's how you create a view.
It's your turn now.
Go ahead into the admin section and create a new view for your current.