In this video you are going to learn how to use hashtags to increase the visibility of your tweets.
So first off what is a hashtag.
Well when you go to tweet on Twitter you have the option to put in the Pankey and then maybe a key word
about what your tweet relates to seek he see personal finance.
You could say Monday motivation and you can see that when you start to type in hashtags here Twitter
will start to suggest some popular ones to you.
Now how does this increase your visibility on Twitter.
Well first of all people use the search bar to find tweets related to certain topics so if we type in
that same one personal finance while we can see now are all of the top tweets and latest tweets or people
photos videos news or broadcasts that relate to that topic and you can see even my searching for maybe
one hashtags that you think you could include and identify other ones that will be popular to include
as well on these hashtags really help to group conversations together together.
And that is a key thing that Twitter wants to do really to organize conversations and to group them
together.
And these hashtags are a key way to do this.
So you can not only Use these hashtags to be easily fanned through the search but you can also create
your own hashtags.
If you were running a certain campaign and you wanted to search and see how many people were talking
about your campaign online you'll probably see this often on TV shows.
They have the hashtag for the TV show and that enables people to tweet to include that hashtag.
Then the TV show can find those tweets easily on Twitter and then they're able to read tweet or engage
with them.
So it's the same strategy that other companies are using you can embrace that for yourself either create
a hashtag for your brand or for your individual company or just use these hashtags in order to group
your tweets into the larger conversation that's happening on Twitter.
Now also over here on the left hand side you can see the most popular tweets and usually these are shown
based on your location and by seeing the hashtags for your location you can participate in these larger
conversations that are happening on Twitter and that will help increase your visibility because you're
participating in these large local conversations online.
Now if you want to you can change the location select a more specific location maybe a city and you
can also get tailor trends.
So these are more the trends that are based on your interests rather than your locations.
So you can play around with that and really identify some of the hashtags that you could potentially
get involved in.
So the best advice is to maybe just include one or two hash tags per tweet so that you can be fan in
the search engines and also that he can be fanned as part of a lot larger conversations happening on
Twitter.
Either end your topic or arrange your location.