The Welcome back to the interest science course as we get our final tutorial the course conclusion.
So let's have a look at what we covered off the scores.
Here's is step by step process to getting into data science in 42 days.
And I really hope that after taking this course you know feel that it is possible that you can become
a data scientist and starting an aspiring data scientist just in six weeks.
And now let's quickly go through the topics that occurred.
Just to reiterate the things that we discussed about each one.
So throughout these tutorials we got a feel for all of these components.
We talked about statistics and the important elements of statistics that you need to get started.
And it's to say that you don't need to study any other statistics ever but you can just look at the
ones that we outlined the eight or the three the three core components three absolutely necessary components
that will help you avoid costly mistakes so the why behind this one is to help avoid mistakes that might
be associated with statistical significance and other interpretations of results.
And then as you go along in your career you can always Druim stay a little bit of statistics here and
there or pick up a few more concepts along the way maybe even the longest journey or off to the footy
today but you need to start off with those first three things at least that much then.
Then we had to look at the learn the data science process.
So we talked about what it's what it is and what are the five stages and that gave us a good overview
of what we'll be doing in their designs and that hopefully that helped see how all of these other components
fit into the bigger picture of a data science process.
So here we've got our own kind of process of learning but the data science processes the process you'll
be applying on pretty much any data science project that you'll be working on.
And that's why it was important to cover it off or then we touched on viz. that there's two types of
insulation.
There's a zation for data mining and viz. for presentation.
And here we allocate 10 days to this component because it is so powerful as you can see from this these
this case that you like and later further down in the course in section 2 we had a case study of isolation
for data mining and re-assessed customers of the bank and the likelihood take a product.
So from that case that you could see how powerful Weasel's issue can be already on its own and that's
why we're looking at 10 days so you have enough time to really get good at it and then be able to perform
simple data science projects and so here we actually have a checkpoint attempt your first science project
and that's exactly what was suggested so that you basically in those 10 days find some time to tend
to first date a science project and see how you go and actually spend a couple of days or some time
within a couple of days to perform that project to see what power results zation actually gives to you.
Then we talked about databases and that they are important in order to get access to more data to get
access to more information and you'll be able to analyze and replicate in five days here because it
is quite important and yet it's not that difficult to get grasp of a one of the four main rescue well
type databases and so you can pick one of your choosing one of your liking maybe it's the one that is
used at work.
Maybe it's the one that you prefer and then you can just jump into it learn how to use a database management
system that should probably take about five days.
That's how I think that's how long it took me to get into that world when I was just starting out.
Of course you as with all of these you will continue in increasing your knowledge as you go ahead further
down the track but just to get started.
How did you get up there and talked about statistical learning and I'd gave you his two favorite books
on the topic and that was his way of starting into data science.
It's an important steps step.
However we're allocating only two days to school learning because we don't want you to get carried away
is very easy to get either too excited about the world of learning or bogged down in it and either extreme
is not good because it is extreme and an extreme.
The best way is to just pick at least one type of algorithm that you want to really get to know quite
well and spend those two days learning it.
And so just based on that one example you'll understand what the statistical learning concepts behind
a machine learning algorithm and then it will be easier to pick up in your algorithm if you like or
you can spend the two days just reading the overuse of different statistical learning approaches and
that will often be good just so basically those two days should be enough to get an intro into the subject
so that if you ever need to pick it up and deep dive further you're already a bit more comfortable with
this whole area.
And then we dive into probably the biggest component 12 days as you can see that's out of all the days
6 7 5 to 12 to we've got 12 days for mission learning and that is because Machine learning is the new
data size or a lot of people might consider that of course there are other types of their science as
we can see with whistles.
And that's one of the reasons why we included this is Alsation for data mining because just to show
you that even if you are completely not comfortable machine learning or coding or you think that you
can still be successful with simply visualization techniques but nevertheless machine learning is indeed
empowering data scientists all around the world it is a very strong component in the data science skill
set and that's why I'm really counting 12 days so that you can go through and learn.
You don't have to learn all of the machine learning is very broad there's lots of algorithms.
But if you learn even some of the basic classification clustering regression techniques maybe some reinforcement
learning or some association learning.
If you look at that even the basics techniques in those 12 days and you learn and you get to practice
with four or five or six different algorithms for instance Spenny to algorithm two days per hour that
should be a great overview of the subject and in fact in this course we already give you two algorithms
so Adlon walked the walk you through two different algorithms.
In his practical examples with Python that hopefully showed you how easy it is to apply machine learning.
And so in those 12 days we suggest another check point to attempt and advanced data science project
and now by this point you already know some statistics zation databases that mystical learning and machine
learning and that should be sufficient to take on a more advanced science project.
Something almost as at the level of Kaggle or maybe at the level of Kaggle introductory type of projects
and of course you can find other sources for projects as well.
Then after that after those 12 days the next step is to learn more Python.
And the reason behind this the why behind this is to speed up your data science.
Your application of data set so you can apply machine learning in Python even if not knowing Python
as you could see you can just use templates or just so like lines of code.
It's kind of like building blocks out of Lego.
Whereas if you actually learn more Python that should take approximately five days to get a good grasp
of it understand the basics of functions variables and things like that.
If you learn that then your application of machine learning will become much more C and you will feel
like a fish in the water when you're flying these machine learning techniques in Python or spider or
Jupiter notebooks or wherever you are playing these machine learning algorithms.
And finally at the end of allocated two days to deep learning and that's to give you a general overview
of what people are doing is in this course we did the show showcased deep learning we showcased deep
learning with a natural language processing we're deploying computer vision people are as you can see
and it has potential if you spend a couple more days on deep learning even though you all probably won't
be ready to apply deep learning to challenge the problems you'll at least know in which direction to
think and when those challenges come up.
You'll be able to dig further and understand which deep learning algorithms apply and how to apply them
on the job already and your knowledge of machine learning will really help you out because the whole
concept of applying deep learning as just as building blocks as Lego bricks is very similar.
So you can just write a few lines of code and you can see how it can volitional kneeler neural networks
set up or artificial neural networks set up just for that analysis of your problem.
So there we go that's how we get to the final stage to day 42.
In data science and day 42 you are ready.
Conrads you made it.
If you get there then you can really set out.
You go and start looking at Kaggle competitions.
Set up your own upward profile and say that your day or your starting date assigns then bid for jobs.
Work or you can start approaching your first client and see how you can help them there.
So there you go.
All in all it takes 42 days if you're excited about this journey.
As excited as you are then we challenge you to take it on and see where you can get the steps.
There are lots of materials we offer lots of courses if you're ever interested.
We welcome you to check them out.
But that's not to say that there aren't other materials as lots of other online courses that you can
take what books that you can read.
You can watch YouTube videos.
There's tons of materials online where you can find all of this knowledge and hopefully this road map
to becoming a dangerous scientist will guide you and you will know what to learn what steps and checkpoints
to take and how much time is spent on each one.
Try to try to practice some rigorous self-control so that you don't get carried away spending too much
time.
But also when you know that you only have let's say five days to study databases then that should keep
but keep pushing you so that you don't let yourself stop and you know maybe take two or three weeks
on the subject when it's only you only need actually 5 days to cover it all.
So there we go.
Hopefully this will help you out.
And we're routing for you.
We're cheering for you.
We can't wait to see you among the ranks of the scientists.
Thank you so much for taking this course and we'll see you next.
Until then enjoy datasets.