My name is Carol or Maaco and along with the second instruction the scores.
I'd love that both of us.
We would like to extend a warm welcome to you into introduction to datasets.
We're so excited to have you on board.
This is going to be an amazing and fantastic journey.
We've been in data size and machine learning and artificial intelligence for quite some time now.
We've seen lots of students around the world become successful in this space and go from zero to hero.
And we really really all want the same success for you and that's why we've put this course together
to give you a roadmap of how to become successful.
And then this quick tutorial we just going to look at the structure of the course so you can understand
what it's all about and how to navigate it better.
So let's have a look.
And this course will have five sections in section one we're going to discuss the ultimate data science
guide here.
We will give you a roadmap of how to go about getting into this.
So if you're just starting out if this is your first time learning about their assets or you've only
seen little bits and piece of their science we will hope you have a structured way a structured path
through this.
And so you know exactly what you go through and how much time is spent on each topic so that you can
get to the end result in the most efficient way possible and learn everything you need to know to actually
start applying data science in your work.
In Section two we're going to give you a taste of data size with a specific tool called Tablo.
We'll give you a taste of a specific type of data science which is called visualization for data mining.
And this is specifically intended for you to get a feel for what it's like to be a data scientists were
actually going to solve a real world case study real world challenge and you will see what goes into
being and scientists would kind of thinking mindset skill sets are required so you can understand for
yourself if this is indeed the right profession and if indeed you are interested in pursuing this further.
And then in section 3 will give you another test for data size.
But this time for different tool will give a taste for designs with Python and Adlon here will walk
us through applying to different machine learning algorithms to two different Dennison's problem.
And I love the section because both these sections actually because they're a testament to how quickly
you can get started into datasets if you follow up with the scores within a few hours you'll be solving
some very interesting real world challenges with some quite advanced techniques for this.
For example Section 3 will be applying some one machine learning algorithm to solve an energy problem
and another machine learning algorithm to solve a health problem that can really impact people's lives
and impact different decisions that industries make.
Next in Section 4 we will talk about still signs of the cloud and we'll show you what this term is all
about why it's important.
And this is a quick quick overview because as a scientist you are likely to encounter the cloud and
some of your work will be in the closet and therefore want you to be prepared for what to expect from
this does come up in your career down the track.
And finally Section 5 will have a course conclusion where we'll run through everything that we've talked
about to make sure that we have a good recap and that you're ready to get on your way to becoming a
successful scientist.
So all in all a very exciting course.
We're super pumped to get started.
And for further ado let's dive straight into the next tutorial and I'll see you there.
And until next time enjoy Dallasites.