The StubInboundChannelAdapterConfig is a Spring configuration class.
It defines two channels.
The resevervationFromStubChannel is the channel to which
individual reservations will be published,
and the reservationListFromStubChannel is the channel to which a list of
reservations will be published from our stub message source.
The stubMessageSource method is a MessageSource bean that
returns a list of reservations and is annotated by the
InboundChannelAdaptor annotation,
which publishes messages to the
reservationListFromStubChannel and includes a 5‑second poller.
The method body creates a new message source using a Lambda expression.
It receives no arguments and returns a list of reservations
with two hard‑coded reservations in it.
The Splitter receives the list of reservations from the
reservationListFromStubChannel and publishes individual
reservations to the reservationFromStubChannel.
A reservation is a plain old Java object that manages an ID,
a name, a status, and a version number.
The reservation listener is a Spring service with a service activator that
listens for messages on the reservationFromStubChannel.
It has two gateways wired into it that we'll review shortly.
The publishReservationGateway is used to publish a
reservation to the reservation web service,
and the getReservationGateway is used to retrieve a
reservation from the reservation web service.
The handle reservation method extracts the reservation payload and logs it.
It then publishes a new message with the reservation as its
payload to the publishReservationGateway.
One important step that we add in here is that we need to set the
HTTP content type header to application/json.
The HttpRequestExecutingMessageHandler, which we'll see in a minute,
will automatically serialize the reservation to a JSON string,
but only if we set the message's CONTENT_TYPE header to application/json.
If we don't,
then it will see the reservation as a serialized Java object and
the whole serialization process will fail.
Finally,
after the published reservation method has successfully published
the reservation to the reservation web service,
we use the getReservationGateway to retrieve the reservation with the
specified ID from the reservation web service and log it.
The HttpOutboundChannelAdapterConfig is a Spring configuration class that
allows us to post a reservation to the reservation web service/ It defines a
toReservationServiceChannel and a MessageHandler bean with a service activator
that listens for messages on that channel.
We create a new HttpRequestExecutingMessageHandler,
specifying the URL upon which we want to operate.
If you started the reservation web service,
it should be running on localhost 7080,
and we're going to post a new reservation to the slash reservation resource.
Speaking of which, on the next line, we set the HttpMethod to post.
Finally, we set its ExpectReply value to false,
because we're not going to handle the response from the web service.
We create a messaging gateway named
PublishedReservationGateway that publishes a message with the
reservation payload to the toReservationServiceChannel.
That's all we need to do to invoke a web service call.
The HttpGatewayOutboundConfig is the Spring configuration
class that handles the retrieval of a reservation from
the reservation web service.
It's a little more complicated,
because we're going to include a variable in our URL,
and we're going to need to handle the response from the web service.
We define two channels,
the getReservationChannel is the channel to which we request a
reservation from the reservation web service,
and the getReservationReplyChannel is the channel to which the
MessageHandler will publish the response from the web service.
The httpOutboundGateway method creates a MessageHandler bean and
is annotated with a service activator that listens for messages
published to the getReservationChannel.
We create an HttpRequestExecutingMessageHandler specifying the
URL of the service that we want to invoke.
In this case, the URL contains a variable named reservationId,
which is denoted by curly braces.
We set these HTTP method to get and then we specify that we expect to reply,
and that reply should be of type reservation.
Next, we create a spring expression language expression,
part sir,
and then set the Docker variable expressions to resolve the
reservation IDE to the payload of the message.
Finally, we set the Output Channel,
which is the channel to which the message handler should publish the response
of the web service call to the getReservationReplyChannel.
Finally,
we create a messaging gateway named getReservationGateway that
publishes messages to the getReservationChannel and listens for
replies on the getReservationReplyChannel.
The getReservation method accepts the IDE of a reservation to retrieve,
which will become the payload of the message and is the reason
that our URI variable expression resolves the message payload to
the reservation ID variable and returns the reservation that it
receives in the reply channel.
The HTTPExampleApplication is a command line Spring Boot application.
All of the action will happen in the background,
so it's simply waits for 5 seconds and then exits.
Let's run the application and review the logs. From the logs, we
can see that the reservation listener received the reservation from
the channel, and published it to the reservation web service, and
then we can see that it was able to retrieve the reservation from
the web service.
And if we open a web browser to localhost 7080 /reservations, we
can see that the reservation web service does, in fact, have both reservations.