In this section,
we're going to review ActiveMQ in performing an integration
using the JMS support in Spring integration.
The definition of JMS from Oracle's website is,
"a messaging standard that allows application components based on the
Java Platform Enterprise Edition (Java EE) to create,
send, receive, and read messages.
It enables distributed communication that is loosely coupled,
reliable, and asynchronous." We looked at AMQP already,
so you might be curious about the differences between AMQP and JMS.
The main difference is that AMQP is a binary wire‑level protocol
used for integrating different systems that are potentially
built on different technology stacks,
whereas JMS is a Java API that abstracts Java programs from the underlying
complexities of communicating with the JMS provider,
much like JDBC does for databases.
Let's begin by looking at sending messages to and receiving messages from
ActiveMQ using inbound and outbound channel adapters.
Inbound requests are handled using the JmsMessageDrivenEndpoint,
which subscribes to a queue and publishes messages that it
receives to a channel asynchronously.
Outbound messages are published using the JmsSendingMessageHandler,
which will be triggered by a service activator when a
message is published to a channel.
In order to create an inbound channel adaptor, we create three beans.
First, we create a SimpleMessageListenerContainer,
as we did in the last section.
The container accepts a ConnectionFactory, which Spring will
create when it sees ActiveMQ in the class path.
We then create the SimpleMessageListenerContainer,
set its ConnectionFactory,
and set the destination queue name that we want to listen on. Again, the
SimpleMessage listenerContainer does the underlying work of subscribing to the
queue and managing the interactions with the JMS broker.
Next, we create a ChannelPublishingJmsMessageListener.
This is a JmsMessageListener that converts a JMS message into a Spring
integration message and sends that message to a channel.
Finally, we create a JmsMessageDrivenEndpoint.
The endpoint uses the listener container to listen for
messages published to the queue,
convert them to Spring integration messages using the
ChannelPublishingJmsMessageListener, and then publishes
them to the specified output channel.
In order to publish a message to ActiveMQ,
we create a new channel and then create a MessageHandler Bean that
is triggered by a ServiceActivator when a message is published to
that channel. The jmsMessageHandler Bean accepts a JmsTemplate,
which will be automatically created by Spring when it sees ActiveMQ
in the class path.
It creates a JmsSendingMessage handler with the JmsTemplate and then sets
the destination queue name to which to publish messages.
Finally,
we create a MessagingGateway that our application can use to
publish a message to the publishing channel.
This example is going to be the same as the example in the last section,
namely another reservation system, the bar reservation system, is going to
publish reservations to ActiveMQ, and we're going to handle them.
The bar reservation service will publish a bar reservation to a reservation
channel that will be published to ActiveMQ through a.
JMS sending message handler. The reservation will be published to a
queue and received by a JMS message driven endpoint, which will
publish it to a channel to be handled by the bar reservation
listener. Just as we did in the last section, we're going to run
ActiveMQ in a Docker container.
ActiveMQ has two major releases; the classic
version, which uses JMS, and Artemis,
which uses AMQP. Because we're viewing Spring integration's JMS support,
I opted to use the classic version.
The rmohr/activemq Docker image has over 10 million downloads and is one
of the most popular ActiveMQ images. We expose 2 ports; 61616 is the
standard port that JMS clients will connect to, and 8161, which is the
port to the HTTP management console.
You can start it with this command. With ActiveMQ running, let's
take a look at the code and see this in action.
Let's look at the configuration for our inbound channel adapter.
The ActiveMQInboundConfig class is a Spring configuration class.
It defines our destination queue name as reservation‑queue.
It creates a reservationConsumerChannel,
which is the channel to which messages publish to an ActiveMQ queue
will be delivered. Our goal is to subscribe to a queue, and when a
message is published to that queue to publish a message to a channel to
be handled by one of our components.
To do this,
we create a simpleMessageListenerContainer with a ConnectionFactory
that Spring automatically creates when it sees ActiveMQ in our class
path and then set its destination queue name. We create a
ChannelPublishingJmsMessage listener that converts a JMS message into
a Spring integration message.
And then we create a JmsMessageDrivenEndpoint that uses both the
simpleMessageListenerContainer to receive messages and the
channelPublishingJmsMessageListener to convert JMS messages to
Spring integration messages, and then to publish the message to the
reservationConsumerChannel.
The BarReservationListener is a Spring service that defines a
handleMessage method with a ServiceActivator that listens for
messages on the reservationConsumerChannel.
As we'll see shortly,
the BarReservationService will be publishing a BarReservation as a JSON string,
so we use the Jackson objectMapper to convert the string that we
receive into a BarReservation object and log it.
A BarReservation is a plain old Java object with two fields, an ID and a name.
Now let's look at the publisher.
The ActiveMQOutboundConfig class defines the same queue name,
reservation‑queue, and then creates two channels.
The first channel, reservationChannel, is the channel to which the
BarReservationService will publish its reservations.
It's delivered to the ObjectToJsonTransformer Bean,
which converts the reservation object to a JSON string.
The second channel, publishReservationToActiveMQ, is the channel to
which our transformer publishes the JSON string.
The jmsMessageHandler receives the message using the ServiceActivator and
publishes it to the destination queue specified by its name.
Finally,
the BarReservationGateway is a messaging gateway that publishes
a BarReservation to the ReservationChannel.
The BarReservationService is a Spring service with the
BarReservationGateway wired into it that publishes a BarReservation
to the ReservationChannel through the gateway.
The ActiveMQSampleApplication is a command‑line Spring boot
application with the BarReservationService wired into it that
publishes six reservations to ActiveMQ through the
BarReservationService with a 2‑second delay.
Let's run the application and review the logs. In the logs, we can see the
BarReservationService publishing each of its six reservations, and then we can see that the BarReservationListener receives each reservation.