In this section,
we reviewed how to create custom inbound and outbound channel adapters.
Throughout the various integrations that we built in this course,
we saw that inbound channel adapters typically work with MessageSources,
and outbound channel adapters typically work with MessageHandlers.
And we saw that we can build a custom inbound channel
adapter by extending the abstract MessageSource class and
overriding its doReceive method.
And we could build custom outbound channel adapters by
extending the abstract MessageHandler class and overriding
its handleMessage internal method.
So at this point,
you should understand how to build custom inbound and outbound channel adapters.
Throughout this course,
we reviewed several of the more popular integrations that Spring
Integration provides out of the box from AMQP and JMS message brokers to
Apache Kafka, to relational databases, and Mongo DB,
as well as RESTful web services.
Now that you understand custom inbound and outbound channel adapters,
you should be prepared to integrate with any system for which
Spring Integration does not provide native support, so happy coding.