In this section,
we're going to review how to integrate MongoDB into a
Spring integration application.
MongoDB is an open source, document‑based,
distributed database built for modern developers and for the cloud era.
It is open source, and you can use it for free.
It's document‑based,
meaning that it does not manage relational entities like a SQL database does.
Instead,
it manages JSON‑like objects that are stored in a binary form for performance.
It's distributed,
meaning that you can run it on a single machine or
across a cluster of dozens of machines,
and it's built for the cloud era to support cloud scale amounts of data.
In this section,
we're going to look at inbound and outbound channel adapters and outbound
gateways for MongoDB. To query MongoDB and publish the results to a message
channel, we're going to use the MongoDB message source class annotated with an
inbound channel adapter annotation and using a poller. To write data to
MongoDB, we're going to use the MongoDbStoringMessageHandler with a service
activator that receives the message and passes it to the message handler to
write to the database.
And finally, we're going to use the MongoDbOutboundGateway to
execute a query and publish the results to a channel.
Let's review how to create an inbound channel adapter for MongoDB.
First,
we create a new message source annotated with the
InboundChannelAdapter annotation that publishes messages to the
reservationListFromMongoChannel and defines a poller that
queries for new records every 3 seconds.
The mongoMessageSource method is passed a MongoTemplate that
Spring automatically creates for us when it sees the MongoDB
libraries in our class path.
We pass that MongoTemplate to the constructor of a MongoDbMessageSource,
along with the matching query that we want to execute.
MongoDB queries are that simple; return all records
with a status attribute set to None.
Then we set the collection name. MongoDB organizes its data
into collections similar to SQL tables, so in this case,
we want to retrieve records from the reservations collection.
Finally,
we set the Entity class to the class we want to deserialize the results
into, which will be the Reservation class in this example. Just like
with our JDBC example, the MongoDB messageSource publishes the results
of its query as a list of records, which,
in this case, are reservations.
So we create a splitter that receives the message and splits the
list into individual reservation objects and publishes them to
the reservationFromMongoChannel.
Creating an Outbound Channel Adapter is pretty easy.
We create a new message handler with a ServiceActivator that
listens for messages on the toMongoChannel.
We create a MongoDbStoringMessageHandler,
passing it the Mongo template that Spring creates for us,
and we set the collection name to the reservations collection.
The outbound gateway is a little more work.
We create a message handler with a ServiceActivator that listens
for messages on the getReservationChannel.
We create a MongoDbOutboundGateway,
passing it the MongoTemplate that, again, Spring creates for us, and we
specify the name of the collection that we want to query.
The QueryExpressionString is where we can extract data
from the message to build our query.
In this case, we set it to the entire message payload,
which gives us the flexibility to execute any query that we want. In this case,
we set the ExpectSingleResult to true; otherwise,
a response will be wrapped in a list of matching records. We specify that we
want to deserialize the record into a Reservation instance,
and then we set the utput channel to which to send our response.
We create a messaging gateway that will invoke our outbound gateway by
publishing messages to the getReservationChannel and listening for the
reply on the getReservationReplyChannel.
The query method accepts the query string to execute
and returns a single reservation.
For this example,
we're going to define a reservation service that publishes
reservations to MongoDB using a MongoDbStoringMessageHandler.
A MongoDB message source will be configured with a
poller querying MongoDB every 3 seconds,
and when it finds a reservation with a status of none,
it will publish those reservations to a reservation listener.
A step that's not shown here is that we're going to make an
additional call to update the status to processed,
and then the reservation listener will use the Query Reservation
Gateway to retrieve the updated reservation.
It will send a request to the MongoDB Outbound Gateway,
which will execute the query and publish the results to a reply channel that
will then be delivered back to the reservation listener.
So to summarize this workflow,
the reservation service writes a reservation to MongoDB.
That reservation is sent to the reservation listener that
marks the reservation as processed and then retrieves the
updated reservation back from MongoDB.
The official Docker image from MongoDB is simply mongo.
It has over 10 million downloads and is the official
image maintained by the Docker community.
I encourage you to visit the DockerHub page to
review the different configurations, but to run a simple MongoDB container,
execute docker run ‑d for daemon mode, ‑p to expose port
27017 on the container to port 27017 on the local host, and
mongo as the container name.
Note that this container will be ephemeral,
meaning that if you restart it, you'll lose all of your data.
You can store your data locally using the ‑v command‑line argument to
map a local path to the container/data/db folder,
which is explained on the DockerHub page. So let's dive into the code
and see this in action. We'll start by creating our application
components. Our inbound channel adapter that reads data from MongoDB,
our outbound channel adapter that writes data to MongoDB, and our
outbound gateway that queries MongoDB.
We'll execute the code and validate that records are written to and read from MongoDB.