The OutboundChannelAdapterConfig is a Spring
configuration class that defines two channels.
The reservationToMongoChannel is the channel that
we'll use to write data to Mongo,
and the updateReservationChannel is the channel that we'll use
to update a reservation status to processed.
For the first case,
we define a message handler with a service activator that listens
for messages on the reservationToMongoChannel.
We create a new MongoDbStoringMessageHandler,
passing it a Mongo template that Spring creates for us when it sees the
Mongo libraries in our class path, and then we set the collection name
to reservations. It expects an expression,
so because we want to pass a literal value, we wrap reservations
with a literal expression. We create a messaging gateway that
publishes messages to the reservationToMongoChannel when its
publishReservation method is called.
This is all we need to do in order to write a reservation to
the MongoDB's reservations collection.
For the second case, we use a different strategy,
one that we'll look at further when building custom channel adapters later in
the course. We create a message handler with a service activator that listens
for messages on the update reservation channel.
Rather than use a pre‑built message handler, we implement our own.
A message handler is a functional interface that defines one
method, handleMessage. Because it's a functional interface, we can
implement it using a lambda expression.
The expression we write is as follows: when we receive a message, we
extract its payload as a reservation, query for the reservations that
matched the specified query and then execute an update.
The Mongo template has a pretty simple mechanism for
defining both the query as well as the update.
We create a new query instance and add a criteria to it.
In this case,
we add a criteria where the id property of the record is equal to the
reservation's id. This should match only one record.
Then we create an Update instance and set the fields that we want to change.
In this case,
we want to update the name and the status with the values and the reservation.
Finally, we use the Mongo template by executing its updateFirst method,
passing it the query, the update and the entity class that we're updating,
namely our reservation. Other than seeing how to update a record in
MongoDB, the bigger thing to observe in this example is that we can
create a message handler with a lambda expression and do whatever
we'd like to do with the message.
Finally,
we create a messaging gateway that publishes messages to the
updateReservationChannel when it's updateReservation method is called. A
reservation is a plain old Java object that manages three fields, an id, a
name and a status. Notice that the id is of type ObjectId, which is the
MongoDB type that represents keys in its documents.
The reservation class is annotated with MongoDB's document annotation,
which means that it represents a document or record in MongoDB,
and it specifies that the reservation class represents a
document in the reservations collection.
The reservation service is a Spring service with the
MongoReservationGateway wired into it that publishes a reservation
through the gateway when its publishReservation method is called.
At this point,
we're able to insert a reservation into MongoDB, so let's
review how we're going to retrieve it.
The InboundChannelAdapterConfig is a Spring
configuration file that defines two channels.
The reservationFromMongoChannel is the channel to which
individual reservations will be published,
and the reservationListFromMongoChannel is the channel to which a list of
reservations loaded by our query will be published.
The mongoMessageSource method creates a message source bean with an
InboundChannelAdapter annotation that publishes messages to the
reservationListFromMongoChannel and defines a poller that invokes the
bean to execute the query every three seconds.
Inside the method,
we create a MongoDbMessageSource instance, passing it the Mongo template that
Spring creates for us and the query as a literal expression.
The query itself is searching for all documents in the reservations
collection with a status property value of none. We define the
collection name on the next line as reservations,
and then we set the entity class to which to deserialize
the response to the reservation class.
Finally, we may receive multiple documents from MongoDB, so we publish
the list of reservation documents to a splitter that extracts the
payload and returns the list of reservations.
The splitter will then publish each individual
reservation to the reservationFromMongoChannel.
All of this is to say that every three seconds, we execute the status' none
query publish, the list of results to a splitter that then sends each
individual reservation to the reservationFromMongoChannel.
The reservation listener is a Spring service that defines a
handleReservation method annotated with the ServiceActivator annotation
that listens for messages on the reservationFromMongoChannel.
It has two gateways wired into it. The UpdateReservationGateway is used to
publish an updated reservation to the updateReservationChannel,
which will be handled by the message handler that we created to
update a document in MongoDB, and the QueryReservationGateway,
which is used to retrieve the final updated reservation using a
MongoDB outbound gateway,
which we'll see in a minute. The handleReservation method logs the
reservation, then sets its status to processed and updates the
status of the reservation in MongoDB by sending it to the
UpdateReservationGateway, and finally,
it uses the QueryReservationGateway to retrieve the final
processed version of the reservation.
The QueryReservationGateway defines a query method to which we
can pass a query, so we specify that we want the document with
the id that matches our reservation id. Let's look at how the
MongoDbOutboundGateway works.
The OutboundGatewayConfig is a Spring configuration class. It
defines two channels, the getReservationChannel is the channel to
which we'll publish a query for our query, and the
getRreservationReplyChannel is the channel to which the
MongoDbOutboundGateway will publish its reply.
The MongoDbOutboundGateway method creates a message handler
bean with a service activator that listens for messages
published to the getReservationChannel.
We create a MongoDbOutboundGateway instance,
passing it a Mongo template. We specify the collection name as reservations,
and then we set a query expression string.
This uses the Spring expression language,
which in this case, we specify that we want it to use the full payload for
the query. We specify that we expect a single result and that we want to
deserialize the document into a reservation class,
and finally, we specify that we want it to publish its result to
the outbound channel named getReservationReply.
We create a QueryReservationGateway that publishes messages
to the getReservationChannel and listens for a reply on the
getReservationReplyChannel.
The query method accepts a string that contains the
MongoDB query and returns a reservation.
The MongoDbExampleApplication class is a Spring Boot command line
application with a reservation service wired into it that creates six
reservations and publishes them to the reservation service.
So let's run the code and review the logs. We can see that the
reservation service publishes a reservation,
which has an id of null.
Then we see the reservation listener receives the reservation with a
populated id, and then we see that the reservation listener receives its
final reservation with a status of processed.
In this section,
we reviewed integrating MongoDB into a Spring Integration application.
First,
we saw how the MongoDbMessageSource served the role of an inbound channel
adapter. We configured it with an InboundChannelAdapter annotation and a
poller to invoke it every three seconds.
It executes a query and publishes the results to a splitter that ultimately
publishes individual reservations to the reservation listener.
Then we saw how the MongoDbStoringMessageHandler served the role of an
outbound channel adapter. We created it with a service activator that
receives a reservation and writes it to MongoDB.
Finally,
we saw how the MongoDbOutboundGateway served the role of an outbound gateway.
It executes a query and publishes the results to a reply channel. In the next section, we'll wrap up this module and review what we learned.