In this section, we're going to review what we learned.
We reviewed how to integrate with two databases. MariaDB,
which uses JDBC. What you learned here should be applicable to
any relational database that supports JDBC,
such as Oracle, SQL Server, and MySQL. And MongoDB,
which is a document‑oriented NoSQL database.
We saw commonalities between how databases implement Inbound and
OutboundChannelAdapters. For InboundChannelAdapters, we saw that we create a
message source with a poller that queries the database and publishes the
results of that query to a message channel. And for OutboundChannelAdapters, we
saw that we create a message handler with a service activater that receives a
message and writes it to a database.
At this point,
you should understand how to integrate with databases using JDBC, you should
understand how to integrate with MongoDB, and more importantly,
you should understand the Spring integration model
for integrating with databases.
In the next module, we're going to review how to integrate with RESTful Web Services.