Welcome to my AWS Developer course, An Introduction to Lambda.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey, and in this module,
I'm excited to teach you about integrating third‑party APIs with AWS
Lambda. In this module, we'll be building out automated tweet
functionality for our imaginary client Globomantics Pet Care.
First,
we'll prepare this project by determining what functionality our
application will have. Then, we'll gather the credentials and libraries
that we need for this application and set our credentials in the Simple
Systems Manager Parameter Store.
After that,
we'll jump into a demo to write and test our function.
We'll modify a code skeleton for this project called
Sparrow that I've put together for you,
and we'll test it locally to make sure we're set up properly.
Next,
we'll deploy our project to AWS. Because we'll be using external
dependencies for this project, we'll need to create a function package
for our code and dependencies and then create and configure a Lambda
function inside of the AWS console.
So let's take a look at how this project will work. Similar to
our previous function, we'll be using a CloudWatch scheduled
event to trigger our function.
This will run our function code, which will do a few different things.
First,
it will get access to the Twitter API keys that'll be stored inside
of the Simple Systems Manager Parameter Store.
Now we'll be setting those API keys up in that service
before we deploy anything. After this,
we'll send some test tweets out locally to make sure our credentials are
working properly and also to play with the functionality of the library
Twython that we'll be using to interact with the Twitter API. From there,
we'll bake in some randomization to our app to avoid having our tweets
marked as spam by Twitter. And at that point, we'll send out one final
randomized test tweet before we deploy our project and test it in the AWS
console.
So now let's take a look at what prerequisites we need to gather
together before we can put together our function.
For most projects that interact with a third‑party API, you're
going to need some dependencies. For us, we'll start with a code
scaffold from a project called Sparrow,
which will allow us to interact with Twitter more easily and have
some prewritten code to help us get started with our own Twitter
bots. As a dependency of Sparrow,
we'll be using a Python wrapper for the Twitter API called Twython.
This will allow us to take different actions using the Twitter API,
like following users, liking posts, or, in this case,
posting to Twitter any of the tweets that we're randomly sending out.
We'll also need to gather Twitter API keys for our demo
account so we can tweet as a particular user.
So let's look at how we can store API keys and other secrets
that we want to use inside of Lambda functions.
There's a few different options that we'll be looking at for API key management.
This isn't an exhaustive list of what you might use,
but it's some of the services that you might take advantage of
inside of AWS for this purpose. In this project, we'll be working
with the AWS Systems Manager Parameter Store.
This will allow us to send parameter values into the Parameter Store and have
it encrypt them for us. And then, when we want to decrypt them and retrieve
them at runtime, we'll be able to make a call using the AWS SDKs to go get
those secret values Now, we could also use something called KMS, or the AWS Key
Management Service, but this would cost a little bit of money for us to create
our own custom keys in here. And by default, when we use the Systems Manager
Parameter Store,
we're going to be using KMS in the background as long as we're actually
encrypting the values that we're sending into the Parameter Store.
So we get the best of both worlds here without having to have a
lot of overhead managing the keys ourselves.
Don't worry. I'll explain how this works in more detail in the next video.