In this video,
I'll take you through the process of getting set up
with some of the code for this course.
You'll need to download the exercise files for the course if you
haven't already. Once you're done with this,
you can go to your Downloads folder and then unzip
the file that you just downloaded.
From there,
you'll be able to navigate in it, and you'll look for something
that references module four. In particular,
we'll be expecting inside of module four to see a folder called sparrow.
Go ahead and grab that folder, and drag it over to your Desktop
because that's where we'll be working with it.
For any of the other files you might need for the course,
you should be able to see them somewhere inside of this folder.
I've gone ahead and opened up my favorite code editor, VS Code.
Now, inside of this, I've loaded up the sparrow folder, but if you can't find it,
you should navigate to your Desktop and then change
directories into the sparrow folder.
Now, inside of here, let me clear the screen and list
out the contents of the directory.
You'll also see them on the left side of the screen here. Now, included in
these files will be a bunch of files to help us build our Lambda function
later on called setup.sh and windows_setup.bat.
Now these two files will happen a little bit later in the course, so right now,
let's focus on what we need to get our requirements set up.
This README.md file will be very useful if you want a written guide on
how to get started with some of these setup steps.
Now some of the steps you'll need to do will be to install Python 3 and pip.
Pip should be included with the latest version of Python 3,
so hopefully that won't be too much extra work.
After you install Python and pip,
you'll also need to install boto3. You should be able to do
this just by using pip3 install boto3.
Typically, I install this on my entire system if I plan to work with AWS a lot,
but you could also install it inside of a virtual environment,
and I'll explain what that means in a second. In step three,
you'll be installing the AWS CLI v1.
At the moment, there's a few different options for the CLI, v1 and v2; however,
v2 is still in beta mode,
so maybe it'll be workable in the future, but I wouldn't recommend it right
now. If you need the link to look for most recent installation instructions,
I've included that at the bottom of step three.
Now, when this has been completed,
I'll show you how to configure the AWS CLI with some AWS access keys.
So let's walk through the process of creating AWS access keys right now
inside of the AWS console. Back in the AWS console,
we're going to need to go back to Identity and Access Management,
or IAM.
We can only search for that in the Services
drop‑down to find it. Now, right now,
we're currently using the root account, but if we want to get CLI
credentials to run commands using the AWS CLI or the SDKs,
it's not best practice to use the root account for those
credentials. So we'll need to go and create a new administrator
user and create credentials for that administrator, and we'll use
that user in order to do this.
So first,
I'm going to go over to the Groups here because I want to
create this user with another best practice,
which is using groups.
So I'm going to create a new group.
I'm going to call this group admins because all the people in this
group will be admins. Then I'll click Next Step, and then I'll need
to associate a policy with this group.
So I'm going to pick the AdministratorAccess policy
and then click Next Step here.
And on this final page I'll click Create Group,
and we should have a new admins group that anybody we add to it will be an
administrator with that administrator access policy.
Now I'm going to go over to the Users section,
and I'm going to create a new user for myself.
This can just be your name.
I'll call myself fernando here, and for this fernando user, I'm
going to want to give them both programmatic access to the AWS
CLIs and SDKs so that they can use this to take actions without
having to log into the console.
And I'm also just going to give them AWS management console access
because it is best practice to use an administrator user rather
than consistently using the root user, which is what I'm currently signed in as.
After I check these two boxes,
I'm also going to need to say how I want this user to sign
into the AWS console for the first time.
Because this is just me, I'm going to set a custom password and paste
it in here so I can use it. Now, typically, it would be best practice
to require a password reset if I was sending this password to another
user, but in this case,
I'm creating this user for myself, so I'm going to uncheck this box.
You can definitely leave this selected if you're creating this
user for someone else. Now I'm going to click Next:
Permissions, and we'll associate this user with the group that
we want it to be associated with,
which is the admin group. So let's scroll back up, and let's keep
this box selected for adding this user to a group.
This is the best practice way of doing this.
I'm going to select admins, and now that I have admins selected,
I can move on to the next step.
The alternative methods would be to attach policies directly to
this user or copy policies from another user.
But this method is the best practice,
especially when you're working with many users.
Now I'm going to go over here and click Next: Tags and Next: Review,
and finally, at the end I'll create this user.
Now, on this next page,
pause for a second because this is your last chance to see the
credential values if you close out this page,
so make sure to copy down the access key ID value
here and the secret access key,
which will only appear when you click the Show button.
Now, again,
I'm going to delete this user after this course, so you
won't be able to use these credentials.
However, if I wasn't,
I'd be blurring these out, so make sure you keep
these safe and secret for yourself.
After I've copied down both these values or I've downloaded
the CSV file that contains this information,
I can press the Close button. Now, in this next page, it's
confirming that I have this user created,
so I should be good to go with this user and using the credentials for this
user to configure the AWS CLI. Now that I've created my credentials, back
over here on my VS Code editor and the terminal inside of VS Code, I can
install the AWS CLI. I'm going to use pip3,
which should come preinstalled with Python 3, and then
I'm going to run install awscli. Now,
this process should install v1 of the AWS CLI, so it should go through all
the prerequisite steps and get it installed in my system.
However, if this fails for you on your system,
make sure to read through the steps inside of the README that I
provided, or go directly to the AWS documentation to see how
they recommend you install the AWS CLI on your system, as it
definitely could be different.
So I'm going to clear the screen here, and now that
we have the AWS CLI installed,
we should be able to configure it with aws configure. Now,
this is going to prompt us to enter in the access key ID and the
secret that we just got when we were in the AWS console. So go ahead
and paste those values in here now. Again,
you'd be protecting these values with your life.
In my case,
I'm deleting these values right after I record these videos, so I'm
fine showing them to you inside of my demo here.
Now, the default region might not be set in your case,
so make sure you enter us‑east‑1 if you're using us‑east‑1. Again,
if you're not using this us‑east‑1 Northern Virginia region,
make sure to enter the code for your other region that you're deciding to use.
You can go ahead and check on this in the AWS console if you've
forgotten what it is or refer to the AWS documentation to get the
correct value. After you enter that in, you can press Enter one more time,
and you can leave the Default output format as None.
So now we should be all configured.
If we wanted to test this,
we could clear the screen and run a command to see what's going on inside
of our AWS account, something as simple as aws s3 ls to list out the
buckets inside of the Simple Storage Service.
Now, in this case, this is a brand‑new account,
so I don't see a result, and that's kind of expected.
But the fact that it didn't fail actually means that this worked as expected.
Now, from here,
we should be able to use these credentials that are set up with the
AWS CLI and automatically have them loaded into the boto3 SDK for
Python whenever we're working with it.
Now, if we wanted to make sure boto3 was installed,
we could clear the screen one more time and do
something like pip3 install boto3. Now,
there are other ways to do these installations with a virtual environment,
and I'll get to those later on when we deal with dependencies in our project.
But now that I know this is installed, I can clear the screen again,
and I can go into the Python 3 interpreter.
And in the next video,
we'll use some Python code, boto3, and the credentials we just created to send our Twitter API keys into the SSM Parameter Store.