In this video, I'll be helping you set all of the rest of your Twitter API
credentials into the SSM Parameter Store using boto3 and some of the Python
code that I've included in the ssm_secrets.py file.
Now,
if you've already done this in the AWS Console, you can skip ahead through
this part. If you haven't, this is a great way to do it and is a pretty fun
way to learn more about the AWS SDK for Python boto3. So let's start by
taking a closer look at the ssm_secrets.py file. Particularly, we're going
to be interested in one of the functions that I write towards the bottom
called put_secret. Now, at the very top, I've imported the boto3 library,
and we can do this in our terminal down here as we follow along with the
code.
So I'm going to run import boto3, and because we just installed that,
we should be able to use it in our Python code here.
Now the next thing we can do is to look at the put_secret function
that we have right here up above in the Python code.
Now put_secret takes a parameter_name and a parameter_value, and
essentially what it's going to let us do is the exact same thing we did in
the AWS Console when we were in the Parameter Store.
It's going to let us take the SSM client that we can create with boto3 and
then used the put_parameter method of that SSM client.
We'd have to provide it a name, which in this case is going to be the
input from parameter_name, and a value, which is the parameter_value
input, and then we're going to set the type of the parameter we're
creating called SecureString.
In this case,
the exact same encrypted value that we were setting
in the AWS Console. And finally, we set this Overwrite value equal to True,
essentially saying that if we see an already existing parameter name,
we're going to overwrite the value of whatever's in there.
Now if I scroll down a little further,
it's just going to print out some information about our
success, if we can run this correctly. Now,
I'm going to scroll down even further here, and you'll see that all of
this commented out code is an example of how we could use put_secret to
send in all our secrets to SSM Parameter Store.
So let's go ahead and try this now. I'm going to uncomment this entire code
block, and let's try setting it up to run in our interpreter.
Now,
first, we're going to need to rely on this put_secret function, so copy the
put_secret function and paste it into your Python interpreter. And hit Enter a
few times to make sure that it's been recorded there.
Now,
after you've done that, you can scroll down and start taking a
look at this example code that I've included.
Now what we're going to need to do is replace the REPLACE_ME
values with the values of your secrets.
Do not commit this code anywhere into GitHub or using Git in any sense
because this contains our secrets, and that's just why I've included it as
commented out code here as an example,. You really don't want to leave this
code inside of ssm_secrets.py. In fact,
let's actually copy this code piece by piece as we're adding it in.
So I'm going to copy this SECRETS = and then the open curly
brace here, and this will start off our dictionary
containing the information we need.
Now in the next line I'll use a tab,
and then I'll have the CONSUMER_KEY be the first name that I'll be using.
So let's go ahead and have that CONSUMER_KEY in there.
We may have already set this value previously,
but that's okay because we can overwrite it in this section too.
So I'm going to paste this in here. Instead of using
REPLACE_ME, I'm using the actual CONSUMER_KEY value,
and I'm not going to make you watch me do this,
but I'm going to fill the rest of the values in.
So now I've entered all those values in and created this SECRETS
dictionary here, that you can see if I type it in, and it'll be returned
to us. And this SECRETS dictionary will be used inside of these lines 33
and 34 here in order to get a parameter_name and a parameter_value
inside of that SECRETS dictionary and then put that secret into the AWS
SSM Parameter Store.
So let's just copy this section of code here
directly into our Python interpreter.
Now, I'm going to hit Enter here,
and this should run through all of the code we need it to do. Now this for
loop has successfully executed, and it's put a parameter with the name of
CONSUMER_KEY, CONSUMER_SECRET, ACCESS_TOKEN_ KEY, and ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET
all into SSM, and it looks like it'll work successfully. Now, if we wanted
to go back to AWS, we could actually check on this.
So back in the AWS Console we could navigate to the Systems Manager here.
And as long as we've configured everything inside of that same region,
in my case Northern Virginia,
us‑east‑1, if I go to the Parameter Store, I should see
all of the keys we just pushed in here.
Now you can see some of these don't have descriptions, and
that's because I didn't bother specifying a description using
the AWS SDK boto3. So now that we know these are in here and
we've successfully pushed them in,
let's see if we can get the values back from the Parameter Store.
So let's go back to my code here.
Now,
we don't actually need any of the previous code because we just
finished this step, so let's go ahead and just either delete or
comment out this section of code again since we don't need it. I'm
going to save the ssm_secrets.py file to make sure that none of this
runs while we're using it later on.
Now from here,
let's scroll back up, and let's see how we can use the
get_secret function to get secrets back out of boto3.
So let's copy it now from the top of get_secret to the bottom here, and
let's paste it into our interpreter and hit Enter.
Now let's see what it actually does by taking a closer look at it. Now,
first it's creating a ssm client like the other function we had, and
then it's using the ssm.get_parameter method to go and get the
parameter with a specific name and then decrypt the values inside of
that parameter to return to us.
So this should be as simple as going get_secret and then
typing in the name of the value that we want,
which in this case might be something like CONSUMER_KEY.
So let's make sure to quote that here and hit Enter.
Now we're getting back this value, so it looks like it's working properly.
Now, if we wanted to get any of the other values out,
we just need to make sure to get the name of that value that we wanted for
the parameter, and then we could use get_secret again and replace the
CONSUMER_KEY value here with the ACCESS_TOKEN_SECRET.
So this is everything that we need to get set up with our SSM secrets
here. In the next videos, we'll see how this will interact with sparrow.py to help us create our Twitter bot.