Now let's built our function package and upload it into the AWS Console.
There's two different setup files here.
There's a setup.sh file,
which contains all the steps that we'll need to create a function package on a
Mac or Linux system, and there's a windows_setup.bat file,
which will contain the same steps and commands, except on a Windows system.
So use the one that's appropriate for you.
In this case,
I'll be going through all the steps step by step in the setup.sh file,
but they'll be basically identical with a few different
commands as the windows_setup.bat file.
So, let's see what we do first. As our first step, we'll be creating a
virtual environment to install our dependencies inside of. Now,
if you had one previously created,
you could keep that one, but I'd suggest removing it using the rm command.
And if you're removing the virtual environment,
you're also going to have to use the recursive flag here and then specify .venv
if you already have it around like I do in this window on the left. So I'm
going to remove that there, and because I have the pycache directory around,
which I had from previous videos, this is also going to be something I could
remove just because I won't need it inside of my Lambda function package, so
I'll removed that too. You could do the same thing here if you have these
lingering, and if you still see the .venv on the side of your screen in your
terminal, you can always run the deactivate command,
and this will turn off the virtual environment, but it'll only
work when the virtual environment is turned on.
So with all of these steps out of the way,
let's go ahead and clear the screen here and start creating our function
package. First, we'll create a brand‑new virtual environment.
We use python3 ‑m venv and venv. Now this will create a
fresh virtual environment for us.
Then we'll need to turn this virtual environment on, in this case on
my Mac system, or if you're on a Linux system,
we could do source .venv/bin/activate.
Now,
with this virtual environment on, we can move on to the next step, which will
be creating a setup directory to install everything in.
So I'm gong to do mkdir setup here, and this will create
a brand‑new empty directory for us.
And now we're going to need to copy some of the things that
we'll be using in our function package.
So I'm going to copy sparrow.py into our setup folder here. I'm also going to
copy the ssm_secrets.py file into our setup folder here.
Now, after we are done with this,
let's go ahead and change directories into our setup folder here.
Now, from here,
I'm going to install dependencies that are required for this function package.
And if we look at what these are, they're included in requirements.txt.
And I've only listed twython here because, again, boto3,
while a requirement for ssm_secrets, because we import it
on that first line of that file,
it's not necessary because it's included for us in the Lambda runtime.
So really,
it's just this single dependency of twython. Instead of running
the pip install twython command, we'll use this requirements.txt
file to install the dependencies.
Let's look at this back in setup.sh. And let's run the pip install
command, but instead of the package name, we'll use ‑r to specify the
requirements file that we want to use.
Now,
this is above this directory of the setup directory inside of that
containing directory, and we'll look for requirements.txt, and then
we're also going to specify one more flag for ‑t.
Now, ‑t is telling us where we want to install all the dependencies.
Now I want to install them currently in the present directory
inside of setup, so I'm going to do that here,
and it should install all those dependencies in this local present directory.
Now if I list these out,
you'll see that they're all there, and I can also show you by
opening up the setup file, which now currently has a ton of
different dependencies that are all loaded in there.
And these should all be directly next to our
sparrow.py and ssm_secrets.py files.
This is because they're going to need to directly reference
these dependencies inside of the Lambda runtime.
So I'll close this out again, and we can clear the
screen and start the next step.
If we scroll down, this will be for us to zip up this into a package.zip file.
Now, on Windows, we might use something like 7‑Zip, but on Linux and Mac,
we can use the zip command‑line utility, so I'll use zip ‑r.
And then I want to specify the location to output what we're zipping,
which is going to be in the containing directory in package.zip, and then I'm
going to be able to also specify what I want included in this,
which is going to be every file in the present directory.
Now, importantly, I don't want to include the setup folder itself.
I just want to include everything inside of it.
So that's why I am doing ./ to refer to this directory,
and then I'm doing * to refer to all the contents of this directory,
not including the directory itself.
So let's run this, and this will really quickly
create us a package.zip file here.
Now, if I scroll down,
the last bits here are going to clean up our setup step. So I'm
going to change directories back up a level,
and then I can run rm ‑rf. And this is a command you should be
very careful with because it can delete things on your system
that you might not want to, so be very careful not to force
delete anything unless you mean to.
And we do want to delete this setup directory and all of its contents
because we just created the package that we need, so we can go ahead and
run this. And then we can turn our virtual environment off with the
deactivate command that I mentioned earlier, and now you see that the
.venv in parentheses has disappeared.
And finally, we can clean up our entire environment,
including the virtual environment, by doing rm ‑rf .venv.
Now, this will make our virtual environment disappear.
And finally,
what we could do if we wanted to just see what was
inside of here is run the open . command.
This would work on a Mac.
You might also have to use something like nautilus . on a Linux system,
depending on which Linux distribution you're using, and that would open
up the Finder window or the File Explorer window,
depending on your operating system, and show you where the package.zip file is.
So let's clear the screen here, and then let's do that now.
Now this has opened it another window, so let me go over there.
And now we have this package.zip file that we can
use and upload it to AWS Lambda.
So that's all we need to do inside of our text editor. We've used
this setup.sh file to create the package.zip file.
Now, instead of doing all those commands manually,
we could also actually clear the screen here, and let's remove
package.zip because it wasn't that hard to make it in the first
place, so we'll use the rm commend for that.
And now we can create it automatically just by running this script.
So I'm just going to run ./setup.sh, and this should run the entire
script and tell me what it's doing in the background.
And when it's done,
it should clean everything up for us and still output us the package.zip file.
Now,
on some machines, it'll also open up that Finder window and
show you where that package.zip file is.
But since I know where that is and I know that it's
appearing here my VS Code editor, I can go over to the AWS Console, and we can start the next step.