Welcome to this module of my AWS Developer course,
An Introduction to AWS Lambda, starting with Lambda functions.
Now that you're familiar with the AWS ecosystem and you've
looked at the Identity and Access Management console and learned
how to work with policies and roles that will be underpinning
our projects in this course,
we can jump into creating and deploying our first function in this module.
In this module,
you'll learn about current limitations to AWS Lambda and considerations
that you should have regarding those limitations.
First, we'll review the languages and runtimes supported by AWS Lambda.
Then we'll take a look at the resource limitations that it has,
including the maximum runtime lengths and total file size caps.
We'll also take a look at a few other considerations that we'll
need to keep in mind when making Lambda functions.
Next,
you'll learn the steps you need to take in order to deploy your function to AWS.
We'll learn about gathering function dependencies,
how to write our code locally, and also within the AWS editor in the console.
We'll also learn about function packages and how to
deploy them to Lambda. And finally,
we'll take a look at how we can debug our Lambda functions
effectively. With all this knowledge under our belts, we'll be
able to look at deploying our Lambda canary.
We'll walk through all of the steps required to do so and
set up our function on a regular schedule.
So let's start with some considerations and
limitations for working with AWS Lambda.
It's only a few years old,
which means that there are still a variety of
limitations when it comes to using it.
We'll take a look at some of the hard and soft limits that Lambda has, as well
as what it means for us when we're building applications.
One of the first considerations you'll need to make is
picking a runtime to run your code against.
Now, I want to quickly differentiate between a language, like Python,
Node.js, Java, or Go, and a runtime with a specific version number within
that language, like Python 3.8 or Node.js 12.13.0.
These different runtimes will have the features of the
language at that particular version and with the actual
software that's used to run your code.
Now, if you're writing your code against one particular runtime version,
you're going to need to make sure that you specify that version or that
it's actually supported by AWS Lambda before you use it.
Let's take a look at some of the AWS managed languages and runtimes.
These are runtimes that AWS will allow you to select from a drop‑down
window inside of the AWS console or from a simple configuration value
inside of the AWS CLI or SDKs. It includes things like two of the most
popular languages for programming with Lambda, like Node.js and Python,
and it also includes other supported languages like Ruby, Java, Go, and
.NET Core,
which contains within it C# and PowerShell and the
option to run code against both of those.
Now, these are just the ones that AWS negatively has
support for that they manage for you.
But there's also the option to have your own custom runtimes.
For example, if you really wanted to run your code using Rust,
C++, or PHP, there are ways to do this with Lambda; however,
it will take a little bit more configuration on your part to
get one of these runtimes up and running.
But once you pick a runtime,
you'll also need to take a few other considerations in mind,
starting with some size limitations for your Lambda functions.
Whenever you're making a Lambda function, you have to evaluate the
file size of your uncompressed code and dependencies.
The uncompressed file size must be less than 250 MB for
you to be able to deploy it into Lambda.
Additionally,
your compressed code and dependencies after you zip up your
function package must be less than 50 MB.
There are a few other file size limitations,
but one of the other important ones is that your total function packages
inside of an AWS region must remain less than 75 GB.
If you encounter any of these limitations as you continue working with Lambda,
keep in mind that for many of the size limitations,
there are a few workarounds.
I've found that when I encounter a library that is larger than I expect,
I can usually find a more succinct library with less
dependency bloat. This can frequently shave some needed
megabytes off my total function package size,
both when compressed and uncompressed.
In addition to searching for smaller libraries,
you can also make a more specific architectural decision. Rather than
having a massive code monolith that performs all the operations you need,
think about how you could break that out into discrete parts, like
microservice architectures, and how each could serve a component of the
work you need to do. For example,
pretend your application needed a few large image processing libraries
that each perform consecutive actions on some file. Rather than loading
all of those dependencies into the same function,
split them into separate functions that hand off the
partially processed files at each step.
This way, you don't have to worry about every library in every single function.
Another thing to consider is that maybe there's another language that offers a
more compact solution to the problem that you're working on.
If you're working with Python, take a look at how Node could handle the task.
If you're using Java, check out Python. There might not always be a
more concise solution in a different language,
but it is certainly worth a look, and some of the runtimes
like Java do tend to have higher amounts of dependencies
required to get the same things done.
There are several other resource limitations to keep in mind when using Lambda.
The first is the ephemeral storage limitation of 512 MB.
This means that if you need to work with local files on
the machine that your code executes on, they better not be bigger than 512 MB.
There's also a maximum execution duration on all of
your Lambda functions of 900 seconds.
This means after 900 seconds, your Lambda functions will time out.
This is important to note if you're running tasks that have
higher latencies or depend on other services. The 900‑second
timer is still running when Lambda is waiting on something like a
database query or in API request.
Additionally, you have a limit of 1000 concurrent Lambda functions.
This means that you can only execute 1000 functions at the same time.
Now this might sound like a relatively low number,
but keep in mind that many Lambda functions run
within a second or a few seconds.
Now if you do encounter any of these limitations,
there are a few ways to avoid being impacted by them.
Let's say you have a several gigabyte log file that you need processed.
Instead of being limited by the 512 MB of ephemeral storage,
consider splitting the file up into different parts in S3 and
then processing it in incremental chunks.
For example,
you could break up the log file into 500‑MB chunks for processing, and
then have the Lambda function handle each of these chunks to avoid
these limitations. In order to avoid running up against the maximum
execution duration of 900 seconds,
you could consider chaining functions together that are
discrete parts of your application logic.
For example,
let's say you'd like to use Lambda to assist in your data warehousing pipeline.
Instead of using a single function to extract,
transform, and load the data into your warehouse, use one Lambda function
to query and store raw data in S3, then use a second function to process
that raw data and store it in a new location,
and lastly,
used a third function to take the process data and
load it into your data warehouse.
Each of these discrete steps will be in different Lambda
functions that have separate 900‑second timeouts,
allowing you to effectively increase your limitations.
Lastly,
there are several cases in which AWS will simply increase the
limitations if you ask. If you're interested in getting more than 1000
concurrent Lambda functions running at the same time,
just contact AWS and see if they can change the restrictions on your account.
It never hurts to ask.
There are a few more things to keep in mind when configuring your Lambda
functions, the first of which is to make sure that you're allocating a
reasonable amount of memory to your Lambda function.
You can choose to give it anywhere from 128 MB to 3 GB of memory to use.
Now,
the CPU doesn't have a setting like that within the Lambda
configuration, but AWS says that it scales proportionately with the
amount of memory allocation that you give to your function.
So if you double the memory for your function,
you also double the available CPU.
Another thing to think about when using Lambda is if you needed to have
access to AWS resources within an AWS VPC, or virtual private cloud. A VPC
is a virtual network specifically for your AWS account that blocks access to
AWS services from outside of the VPC.
While Lambda runs within the AWS VPC by default,
it doesn't have access to resources within your private VPC.
This is because it isn't running on a virtual
machine instance within your own VPC.
Instead, it runs on AWS managed instances that live outside of your VPC.
Essentially,
keep in mind that if you want your Lambda function to be able to talk to
other resources, like databases in your private VPC such as Redshift or RDS
instances, you'll want to provide VPC access to Lambda. And as a final
caveat, if you're in an industry that requires you to run your code within
something called a dedicated VPC,
which is essentially a VPC that runs on physically separated hardware,
you're going to need to make sure that AWS will allow you to connect with
Lambda to anything inside of that VPC. At this time,
it might not be completely supported.
So what are some final considerations that you should have when
using AWS Lambda? Well, keep in mind that Lambda is purely event
driven, be that often AWS API requests, some file being uploaded to
S3, or a regularly scheduled event, triggering it at a preset time.
Now make sure your use case can fit within that.
Also, remember that there are those code and size limitations.
If you have a very complex and bulky application that doesn't seem to
have an easy way to decouple itself into smaller,
discrete parts,
you might run into some of the size limitations that we discussed earlier.
And think about how you can use Lambda as a component of a larger whole.
Lambda can be integrated with a variety of services,
which makes it ideal to power microservices and irregular workloads.
But keep in mind that you may need to refactor your
applications into more distinct Lambda functions rather than
a monolithic application architecture.
Also,
there are real performance limitations on Lambda. If you need
significant amounts of processing power altogether,
and there are no ways to break up your workloads into smaller
chunks, Lambda won't always be able to help you.
And lastly, if you have exceptionally long running workloads,
you might not be able to reconcile them with Lambda's timeout limitations.
So, with that context aside, let's take a look at what we need in order to deploy our first Lambda functions.