Welcome to this module of my AWS Developer course,
An Introduction to AWS Lambda.
My name is Fernando Medina Corey,
and I'm excited to get you up and running with Amazon Web Services. In this
module, you'll start by creating an AWS free tier account.
First, you'll learn what the AWS free tier is,
and then I'll walk you through the sign‑up process for an AWS account.
After that,
you'll also learn how to stick to 100% free services by using the AWS free tier.
But keep in mind that to really get the most out of this course
and out of AWS, you'll need to be willing to spend a few bucks
in the modules of this course.
If you're worried about that though,
you can follow along with some of these projects and then
immediately remove the resources associated with these projects
right after you create them and you're done with this course, and
then should keep your costs pretty limited.
Now, after we walk through this whole process,
we're going to look at navigating the AWS console.
Specifically, we'll highlight the service areas and menus
that will interact within the course,
and we'll take a look at the particular AWS services that we'll be using.
Lastly, we'll look at AWS Identity and Access Management, or IAM.
We'll learn the basics of roles and policies and set up IAM
policies that we'll be using later on in the course using
something called the AWS policy generator.
So let's get to it.
The AWS free tier is the single best way to get up and running with managed
infrastructure with little to no cost. With free tier,
you have access to a selection of AWS services at no charge as long as you
stay within certain usage thresholds. You can spin up a virtual machine on
Amazon EC2 or execute your code in Lambda functions.
You could also take advantage of Amazon's managed databases with either the
managed NoSQL DynamoDB database or a managed relational database running
inside of Amazon's RDS, or Relational Database Service.
This could be anything from MySQL to PosgreSQL or another of the
hosted database options that Amazon offers.
You could also take advantage of other services like the Simple
Email Service to build an email functionality to your applications
or Amazon's Simple Storage Service, S3, to easily store files and
other objects in the cloud.
Now, the best part of each of these services is that for the
first 12 months of using AWS with the free tier,
you get substantial utility at no cost.
That's not to say you can do anything with any of
these services for those 12 months,
but you're going to get a pretty substantial amount.
So let's take a look at some examples of using the AWS free tier.
We could run an EC2 instance for 750 hours a month.
Now, this instance would have to be of a particular size,
and it happens to be one of the smaller ones, but that would be
enough to let us use it for 24 hours a day,
7 days a week.
We could also execute up to 1 million Lambda functions a month or use 25 GB of
DynamoDB storage or 20 GB of a relational database storage.
You could also store up to 5 GB worth of files and other objects in S3,
and all of this would be included in the free tear,
along with a lot of other usage from different services and a few
aspects of these services like DynamoDB provisioned read and write
capacity that would be included in these examples.
Now, in this course,
I'll be trying to stick to the limitations of the AWS free
tier at the time this course is published.
But when we're using a service that isn't explicitly free,
I'll let you know so you can decide if you'd like to use it or not.
Keep in mind that you'll need to manage your own billing for
AWS, so be sure to read the service details and charges in
depth if you're concerned about costs,
especially because the free tier could change over time, and I can't guarantee
that what I'm showing you right now will always be the case.
So, what projects could you actually build with these
services and the AWS free tier?
Well, you could set up a static website without a custom domain name on S3,
and you can host this on the web for anyone to access. As long as you didn't
need to go to www.fernando.com in order to access the site,
you could have it hosted and available for anybody to access up in S3.
You can also create and use a relational database or a virtual
machine instance, and either one of these would let you do some
pretty cool stuff with your applications without having to pay
anything within that first year.
But for most of this course, we'll be taking advantage of the 1
million free Lambda function invocations that AWS provides, and
we'll also be taking advantage, in the later sections of this
course, of the free tier of API Gateway,
another service that AWS includes within that free tier. So enough talking about the AWS free tier. Let's go ahead and sign up ourselves.