Back in the AWS Console,
let's go ahead and create our Lambda function with this new function package.
We'll go to Lambda here, and then we'll create a new function.
We'll author it from scratch instead of using a blueprint or
the serverless app repository. Let's call this sparrow, and
let's pick a runtime for it.
In this case, we could use Python 3.8 or any Python 3 runtime.
Now there's differences between Python 3 and Python 2 that would end
up breaking our code, so let's make sure to select something like
Python 3.7 so that it works properly.
Now let's create an execution role for our Lambda function.
Now if we click on this, we can select an existing role,
select a new role that we create from AWS policy templates, or
create a new role with basic Lambda permissions.
Unfortunately for us,
we might want to create a custom role for this function because it's going
to need to use both the AWS SSM Parameter Store to go and get parameters,
and because those are encrypted parameters,
it'll also need access to the Key Management Service, KMS. So we could click
Create a new role from AWS policy templates, and then could scroll down, and in
this we could look for KMS here, but unfortunately,
KMS is the only preconfigured permission policy associated
with Lambda here, so we're also going to eventually need to
add some permissions for SSM.
So let's go ahead and clear that here,
and you'll see if we search for SSM or params, this is not going
to load us up any other pre‑canned policies,
so we won't be able to do anything other than set that KMS permission here.
So let's go ahead and give this a role though, and let's call it a sparrowRole.
And then let's scroll down and create this function.
So now that we've created this function and it's gone
back and created a role for us,
we should be able to go and edit that role to make sure
it'll have access to SSM Parameter Store.
So let's go to the Permissions section here now and fix that.
So now you see that we have the ability to access
the AWS Key Management service, and if you scroll down,
you'll see we have the ability to use the KMS decrypt operation.
Now this is good because we will need this permission
when we're working with SSM; however,
we don't currently have any permissions with the SSM Parameter Store,
so we'll need to change this.
We can click Manage these permissions on the IAM Console, and this will
take us to the IAM section with this sparrow role.
Now with this sparrow role,
we currently have permissions to use KMS and the basic
Lambda execution role, which will allow us to push to
CloudWatch the logs from our function.
But we're also going to want to attach another policy.
We're going to look for SSM here in the drop‑down, and
while we could grant this Lambda function full access to
SSM, that might be a bit much.
It's going to be a lot of different permissions that we
don't actually need for this function.
So let's leave that one off, and let's pick a little
bit of a more restrictive policy.
Let's look for a read‑only access role here for AmazonSSMReadOnlyAccess.
If I open this up and scroll down a little further, this
will allow us to get things from SSM, which will include
the GetParameters operation.
So let's attach this policy to our function instead.
So now that this policy has been attached, we can review the
permissions in this role, and it has the AmazonSSMReadOnlyAccess
policy, as well as this KMS policy, which will allow it to decrypt
the parameters that are stored in SSM.
So with these both set up here, we should have our sparrow role good to go.
So I'm going to close out of the IAM Management Console, and back
in the Lambda console we can navigate back over to our
configuration to keep configuring our function.
The next thing we'll need to do is add a trigger for
our function, so let's do that here.
And I want to select a trigger from the drop‑down,
and we can pick many of the different pre‑canned
triggers from this list of triggers here.
Now the one I'm really going to want in this case to run on a
schedule is the CloudWatch Events trigger.
So I'm going to click that here, and we can pick a role,
or we can create a new role.
If we wanted to use the canary role we created in a previous section,
we could do that,
or I could create a new rule if that's actually a little too
frequent for me. Let's call this rule name dailyTweet because
we're going to want to do this once a day.
Now this Rule description.
we'll just tweet to fire once a day,
and this will make sure that we know it's going to run once every single day.
Then let's use a schedule expression,
and let's have this be a rate of one day, so let's run this with a rate
of 1 day here, and now this should run every day. So let's scroll down a
little further, and let's click Add here.
So now that our Lambda function is created, we should be able to
confirm that the CloudWatch event is enabled,
and if we wanted to see how else we could configure this,
we would click then on the sparrow function instead of its event trigger.
Now, if we scroll down,
we should be able to review the function code for this function,
and you'll notice that while we have the runtime that we might want of
Python 3.7, the actual function code that's for this function is the
default code that AWS Lambda provides.
So we need to change this.
We're going to click the drop‑down next to Code entry type,
and we'll click Upload a .zip file. So we'll go to our Desktop,
which is where my sparrow folder is, and then inside of here we'll
pick out the package.zip file that was just created.
So let's open this up.
So now that we've opened the package.zip file,
we should be able to save this function so that it updates to
use the contents of our package.zip file.
Now, when we do this,
this function package should still be small enough for us to
review it in the code editor inside of AWS Lambda.
Now,
we're also going to need to change the handler for our function. Instead of
using the Lambda function for the beginning part of our handler,
we're going to need to change this to where our Lambda handler function will be,
which is inside of sparrow.py.
So, in order to do this,
I'm going to change the beginning to sparrow because that's where
our handler function is inside of it., and actually, inside of
sparrow.py, once this finishes loading,
we're going to need to reference the handler function, so let's
change that configuration value as well. We'll change this from
lambda_handler to handler so that we can correctly refer to the part
of code that we actually want to run.
Now,
I'm going to close out of this lambda_function.py here because this isn't in
our code anymore after we uploaded the ZIP package there. You'll also see
that we have all these dependencies that are included in our function
package so that our function can use them.
So let's go ahead and save this function one more time now that we've updated
the handler here, and it should be good to go every day.
But if we wanted to test this,
another thing we could do is scroll back up and configure a test event for
this. We could select a test event if we'd already created one,
or we can just press Test here, and Lambda will open up this
Configure test event console window here.
Now, instead of using the Hello World template here,
we could look for CloudWatch,
which is what we're creating our events from using Amazon
CloudWatch, and this would be a typical scheduled event. So we
could give this event an event name of dailytest,
and this would be basically what would come into the event
whenever we're triggering it on a daily basis.
Now,
we don't need to do much configuration here because our Lambda
function isn't processing anything inside of this event.
We're just using this to schedule it on a regular basis. So
I can scroll back down and click the Create button towards
the bottom of the window here.
From there,
I should be able to press the Test button on the function And it looks
like it has been successful, so let's go over here to the details of
our function invocation and scroll down,
and it looks like it just managed to complete successfully.
So let's go back over to Twitter here toward Globomantics Pet Care
account that I opened up in the background, and let's refresh this
page. So it looks like a few seconds ago our test events successfully
sent this tweet out to Twitter.
So now that we know that this is tweeting things out correctly,
we know that everything from the SSM parameters being loaded into
our function and KMS being used to decrypt the values inside of
them and everything inside of our sparrow file and our ssm_secrets
file is all working properly.
You've just gone through the process of making your first Twitter bot.
Feel free to update this and do more interesting things with the
Twython library and the Twitter APIs. Just make sure to review the
documentation on Twitter, and make sure that you're in line with any
of their terms of service.
So, congratulations! We've done a lot in this module.
We've used a third‑party API with Lambda to send things out to the
Twitter API. We've also created and deployed our own function package
and configure a Lambda function using it.
We also used libraries in our function for the first time and learned
how to bundle those up into a function package, as well as securely
managing and encrypting API keys with the SSM Parameter Store and KMS
and configuring our Lambda function to be able to decrypt them and use
them when it runs.
So what's next for us?
Well,
we're going to take a closer look at Lambda in combination with other AWS services, so I'll see you in the next module.