In this demo, we'll need to spend a little bit of extra time preparing things
before we can get started creating our function package.
We'll add some HTML templates to S3 using the Command Line Interface,
and then we'll verify some emails with the Simple Email Service.
After that,
we'll review the cuckoo.py file that contains all of our
function code. Then, we'll create an IAM role that we can
then assign to our Lambda function,
and that'll have to have all the permissions that we need to
access S3 and the Simple Email Service.
From there, we'll go about creating our Lambda function. We'll
install Jinja2 and then test out our code.
Then we'll run the setup.sh script to create our package.zip file, and
then we use the AWS CLI to create our function and also setup
everything else to trigger our function and have it run at a
particular time of day throughout the week.
So let's get started. Over here in my terminal,
I've gone ahead and loaded up all the code for this demo.
You can get this from the downloads for this course.
Just look for the cuckoo folder inside of the module files for this course.
Then go ahead and open up the cuckoo.py file.
I'm not going to look through the whole thing right now,
but one important thing that you'll need to change will be down here on line 33.
This will be the S3 bucket that you're creating,
and I'll show you how to do that right now. Inside of my command line,
I'm going to run aws s3 and then mb, for make bucket.
Then I'm going to specify the syntax for creating an S3 bucket,
which starts with s3://, and then we'll give this bucket a name.
Now, I want to make my bucket match what I have in my
cuckoo.py file, so I'm going to go gpc, for Globomantics Pet
Care, ‑email and then ‑templates.
Now,
one thing I want to distinguish here is that this bucket is globally
unique across AWS accounts, so you're not going to be able to create a
bucket with the same name. So keep that in mind. You're going to have to
go into this file in cuckoo.py and change the value of TEMPLATE_S3_BUCKET
to whatever you name your bucket.
In order to make sure that this command has been successful,
you can then run aws s3 ls, for list,
and this will tell you all the buckets that you
have created in your AWS account.
Now, from here,
you can move all the contents of your templates into
the S3 bucket you just created.
Now,
keep in mind that from now on you'll need to replace GPC email
templates with whatever the name of your bucket is.
Now, if you want help going through each of these commands,
I have a commands_help.txt file that should explain everything I'm doing
throughout this demo, step‑by‑step, and all of the commands associated with
it. It'll also give you notes on when to replace things, like the
TEMPLATE_S3_BUCKET value, inside of your commands.
So you can use that as a cheat sheet from here on out.
So now that I know this bucket has been created when I ran aws s3 ls,
we can run aws S3 cp, for copy, and then I'll need to specify where I
want the objects copied from. In this case,
I want to specify ./templates because I want everything inside of
this templates directory to be copied into S3.
Specifically,
I want the come_to_work and the daily_tasks and the pickup files all to be
moved into S3 to be used as email templates. The license and the notice here
I've included because these email templates are open source, and I'm required
to buy their license. Now from here,
after typing the aws s3 cp command and entering in the location of
everything we need, now we can enter where we want this to go.
In this case,
we'll need to start with s3:// to specify we want this to go into an S3 bucket.
Then we'll have to give the name of the bucket,
which in this case is gpc‑email‑templates.
Now, after we type that out,
we can just say that we want this to recursively copy everything in the
templates folder, and we'll do this with the ‑‑recursive flag here.
So now I can hit Enter and see this process copy
everything in templates into my S3 bucket.
Now, if I wanted to check if this process had worked,
I could run the aws s3 ls command and then specify the name of the
bucket that I wanted to see inside of; in this case,
gpc‑email‑templates.
Now I can hit Enter,
and I'll see all the different objects that I just uploaded into S3.
So this is exactly what we want, and now we can go back into the AWS Console and configure SES.