Now let's look at some of the most prominent providers of serverless
functions. In this section, we'll compare market leaders and mention a
few of the strengths of some niche players.
The two leaders in the serverless function space are
Amazon Web Services and Microsoft Azure.
Amazon is a fairly clear market leader in many spaces of
the Infrastructure as a Service category,
but Microsoft Azure has been catching up very rapidly,
especially in recent years.
Now,
because of this, much of the integration capacity of these
two different providers of AWS Lambda and Microsoft Azure
has started to kind of equalize.
Now this is a really important part of the serverless
function category because all those integrations really help
you develop applications more rapidly.
Now,
in addition to Microsoft Azure and Amazon Web Services,
there's also other niche players in the space.
Now, this has evolved over time, but it can include things like Iron.io,
Cloudflare, and OpenFaaS, among many other niche providers.
So let's take a look at some of these in more detail.
Let's start by looking at a comparison between AWS Lambda and
Microsoft Azure. But keep in mind that this can't be a perfect
comparison because the actual service and functionality of these two
different providers differs pretty substantially when you come down to
the details, so I've tried to give a few high‑level things to compare
these two providers.
The first is the runtimes that you can use with AWS Lambda and
Azure Functions. For both, you can use Node,
Python, Java, C#, PowerShell, and other runtimes,
but the differences are really depending on how you want to integrate these.
AWS Lambda has user‑provided runtimes to support plenty of other things,
like Rust and other languages that aren't supported directly as a
main instrument time, whereas Azure Functions will let you use
other executables and do basically the same thing. If you're
looking for a managed runtime,
I suggest just comparing the most recent supported runtimes
between Lambda and Azure Functions to check if that might be
something that could help you.
But if you're not really worried about that and you're interested in just the
standard most popular libraries for serverless computing,
which in this case are really Node and Python,
both of these two providers support both of these two languages.
The next thing I wanted to point out is that Lambda actually has
built‑in versioning for your serverless functions.
And depending on how you do your deployments and your deployment pipelines,
this could be something you might want to take advantage of.
Azure doesn't currently have anything to this exact capacity,
but there are other ways you could do versioning for your functions, so
this is one other thing to look at depending on how your process will
work. Now, for both Lambda and Azure Functions,
you're also going to be able to use HTTP endpoints via different resources. AWS
Lambda will let you do this with the AWS API Gateway, and Azure Functions will
help you do this with the API Management service.
Now,
both of these two different options would let you do things like
integrate APIs into your front‑end applications.
The next thing to look at is the runtime limit for these different
services. AWS Lambda has a hard runtime limit of 15 minutes.
This means that if you have some task that goes over 15
minutes, the Lambda function will need to do something to
put that task off until later,
maybe chain it to another Lambda function or another
process, or save its work and then restart it later on.
Whereas with Azure Functions, by default,
there's a 10 minute limit to function timeout; however,
they do have two other plans called the Premium plan
and a dedicated App Service plan,
which extend the limitations to 60 minutes and to an unlimited amount,
respectively, for that function timeout.
Keep in mind that in general, when you're working with serverless functions,
it's probably not a good idea to have long‑running processes that
go on for significant amounts of time like this.
Sometimes, in those cases,
it makes more sense to use other services for those long‑running jobs.
For AWS Lambda,
you have 1000 concurrent functions that you can run at the exact same time.
Now this is a soft limit, so if you asked AWS, they'd
probably be able to bump these limits for you.
Whereas with Azure Functions, this isn't really quite comparable, where
you'll have 10 concurrent instances that you can have running at the
same time underneath the Azure Functions,
but they're not going to limit how many specific
concurrent functions themselves you can have.
So this isn't really a one‑to‑on comparison either, just really
another point to look at if you're worried about how much capacity
each of these solutions can offer. Now,
if you go down the route of using these solutions extensively,
it's pretty likely that these cloud providers might give you
some wiggle room on increasing the capacity.
So now let's take a look at some niche providers in the space.
The first is Iron.io. Iron.io is actually one of the first companies to
develop what became the concept of serverless functions.
Iron.io has IronWorkers,
which function more or less like serverless functions
and support all major languages.
Also,
binary executables, and they have runtime limits of an hour compared to
the AWS and Azure runtime limits of 15 and 10 minutes.
The main drawback here is that the service integrations that they offer
are a little bit lacking when you compare them to all the services
inside of AWS or Microsoft Azure, and it's harder to consolidate your
infrastructure using IronWorkers,
especially if you already have a variety of other development needs,
like having multiple virtual machines running at the same time for
your applications, or maybe you already have containers spin up
somewhere that you need to keep around.
Another option might be something like Cloudflare Workers.
Cloudflare Workers will allow you to run JavaScript code close to
your users and distribute that around the globe.
Now this can help you run HTTP or HTTPs responses in response to users
loading your website or hitting your API end points much closer to them
to help you provide much faster responses.
AWS Lambda has a similar service called Lambda@Edge,
which you can also take a look at in the similar vein.
Now, in addition to these two options,
there's also something called OpenFaaS, and OpenFaaS, or Open Functions as
a Service, is what I'd say is one of several options in a space to try and
make the runtimes of these serverless computing options a bit more open
source and extensible between different cloud providers and potentially
on‑premises environments.
So definitely take a look at this if you're running containers or Kubernetes or you're curious about these options.