So let's review the application we'll be building in
this demo, the New Customers Service.
It'll start with an API Gateway request that then gets
routed over to a Lambda function.
That Lambda function will then validate the request, and if it looks correct,
save it in DynamoDB, essentially adding a new user to that DynamoDB table.
In this process,
the Lambda function will use bundled libraries in order to interact with
DynamoDB, and it'll also send an email to an administrator as soon as that
user has been saved correctly in DynamoDB.
So let's review exactly how this works in the demo
and the steps that it'll take.
We'll start by deploying our infrastructure using a boilerplate Lambda
function and in API Gateway event for that Lambda function. From there,
we'll learn how to add a DynamoDB resource,
and then we'll get started creating our actual function. We'll look at how
we can process the API Gateway event that's coming in,
and we'll look at how we can work with DynamoDB using the boto3 library.
So let's get started. Back over here in VS Code, I've loaded up
the application we created in the previous demo.
Now, in order to continue building onto this application,
I want to first remove the service that we just created with Serverless.
So I'll use the serverless remove command,
and this will go through the process of checking for
everything that I just deployed inside of AWS and
removing all of those different items.
In this case, it'll just be the Lambda function that I ended up deploying.
Now this isn't necessary every time you're working
with the Serverless Framework, but in this case,
we're building on the exact same application, so I just like to remove some
extraneous resources so we can start from scratch again.
So let's go ahead and go back into serverless.yml and start adding what
we need in order to get working with our user service.
The first thing I want to point out about serverless.yml is that we
have these app and org values at the top of our file, the
gpc‑api‑app and the org of pluralsightfernando.
Both of these are what's allowing us to hook into the Serverless Dashboard,
so you'll need to change these values to reflect whatever your app
and your org name are. These should've been added for you in this
example by default when you were following the bootstrapping process
in creating your own account.
But if they weren't,
you'll need update those. Now, the first step we'll need to take is
to add a section in the provider for the specific permissions we want
this function to have. Now, by default,
whatever is stored inside the provider section as an IAM role
statement will be applied to all the functions inside of this
Serverless Framework service.
So how can we set these IAM role permissions? We'll use an iamRoleStatements
section here, and then inside of this, we'll give it different attributes
that are related to the permissions that we need.
Now,
all of the code for this section is located inside of the
serverless_helper.txt file that I've provided for this module,
and you can also see the final code for this demo inside of the
course files for this course.
So take a look at that at any point if you'd like something to reference.
So I'm going to copy and paste in my iamRoleStatement here, and inside of
this iamRoleStatement, you can see that there is the Effect of Allow, the
Action of dynamodb:PutItem, and the Resource that corresponds to a
DynamoDB table called users in us‑east‑1.
Now we'll need to create that table in a later section of this
serverless.yml file. Later on, if we wanted to add more permissions,
we could go into this Action section and add something like dynamodb:GetItem,
and this might help us get items back out of DynamoDB.
We could also add the Query here if that's
something we were doing in our service.
But because this service is purely responsible for putting items
into DynamoDB and then alerting a user using SES,
we'll just keep this PutItem here for now.
Now,
we're also going to need to add permissions for the Simple Email Service,
so let's go ahead and add that here too. We'll do SES:* for all the
different actions underneath SES. You should feel free to go back in here
and trim down the permissions later on.
The next step, after adding the IAM permissions,
will be to add the configuration for the HTTP API that we'd like to create.
Now, in this case, we'd already created a function called hello.
I want to change this function name that we just removed to something
called createUser, and then I'm also going to want to change the
handler from handler.hello to handler.handler.
This will just mean that we'll need to change the function name inside of
handler.py to handler so that we can refer to it properly.
Now, after this,
I want to create an event for this function. So we could create events like the
scheduled events we saw in earlier sections of the course,
but in this case,
I want to do something that will allow me to create an
HTTP API and get triggered from that.
So I'm going to go in here and type this out,
and in this case, I want this to be http is my event type,
so I'll do that, and I'll have to add a few more spaces here,
and then I'll set up a path for this event.
So I want this path to start with user here, and then I also
want a method. Because we're going to be creating users, I
want to have a post method here,
and I also want to allow this to work across different
domains, so I'm going to do cross origin resource sharing
here and then set this up as true.
Now that this has all been set up here,
we should be able to deploy an API using this, but I'll need to go back into the
handler section here and change this from hello to handler.
Now, once I save that,
I should be able to close this out, and we can open back up our
terminal, and let's clear the screen from our stack removal from
previously, and now let's run serverless deploy again.
Now, so far, we have a serverless.yml file that's about 22 lines long.
Now if we wanted to compare this once again to what
CloudFormation would require us to build,
we can go in here to our cloudformation‑template and
see how long this ends up being.
Now it looks like just from what we added,
we've got a CloudFormation template that's around 616 lines.
So you can see again why I'm using the serverless.yml file instead
of using CloudFormation. It does compile to CloudFormation from
that serviceless.yml file, giving us the same benefits of the
Infrastructure as Code tool,
but it lets us write this in a simpler syntax without having to go in
and create every single individual AWS resource,
like all of the resources affiliated with the API Gateway.
So let's scroll up and see what our deployment is doing so far. It
looks like it's started packaging everything up in here, installed
everything it needed for the CloudFormation resource, and then it's
gone through and started uploading things to S3 and creating
everything in CloudFormation.
Now, once this process finishes,
we should also get an API endpoint that we could use inside
of something like Postman to send data in.
However, because we didn't update our handler to really do anything,
it's not really going to end up doing much.
Let's go over to the handler now and see what would happen. Now, inside of
here, it looks like our handler is going to create an event body, and then
it's just going to return some details to us.
So it looks like my deployment has finished, and if I wanted to,
I could review this in the Serverless Dashboard there, but I'm going
to scroll up and find this post endpoint here.
Now,
this is the HTTP API endpoint that was created for us automatically by
the Serverless Framework after it created all the API Gateway resources.
So I'm going to copy this here and go over to Postman, and inside of
Postman I'll create a new request here.
Now it's going to be for a POST endpoint, so let's put that in there.
And we shouldn't actually need to do much inside of
this POST endpoint to test it out.
I'm going to send this is a blank request here, and you'll see
that the function executed successfully.
Now,
the reason that this is returning everything like this, without us even
putting data into a JSON blob and sending it through to the endpoint, is
because the handler function that we defined has really just defined this
and sent some information back out. We're going to need to update that in
order to make sure that it can record information into DynamoDB and then
let us know that we have a new user in our database by sending an email out
to SES.
So let's take a look at how we could do that and how we could add a DynamoDB resource in the next video.