Back in my VS Code editor, I've opened up cuckoo.py.
Let's look at everything inside of this to make sure we know how it works.
At the very top, we're using in the datetime library.
Now,
this will be used to check what day of the week it is and send a
different email out based on the day of the week.
Then we'll use the boto3 library later in this section to send emails through
the SES, or the Simple Email Service, client, as well as getting objects from
S3, and we'll create a separate client for that.
Next,
we'll be using Jinja2 and the template that we import from it to load HTML
templates that we get from S3 and send them out through SES.
Now, in this file,
there are a few things you need to change, and those things start
around line 5, after all of these comments.
So here you'll see the FROM and REPLY_TO_ADDRESS. Make sure
that you've already changed these to the address that
you've already verified in SES.
You'll also need a few different email addresses that
you have here next to the email.
Now, make sure this email is also verified, as well
as the one for the employees.
From there, you'll be able to change the S3 bucket that
you're using to store your templates.
So whatever the name the S3 bucket is, update that as well.
And that should be the last thing that you need to change in
cuckoo.py. Everything else should be provided for you to work
properly, as long as you follow the previous steps.
But let's review what it does anyway.
There's a few different functions in here that each have their own purpose.
The first is the get_template_from_s3 function.
This is going to take a key, in this case,
the name of a template that's stored inside of S3. And it's
going to go out and get that template and then return it to
whatever is calling this function.
Now, it'll do this because we need to use these templates when we're
sending emails out to S3. In addition to this function,
if I scroll down further, we have this render_come_to_work_template.
Now, this will take a first name of our employee, so we can say something like,
Hello, Homer,
Please remember to come to work, instead of having a more boring
template. Now we'll get this template from the come_to_work.html
file in the AWS bucket we just created.
We'll also use this to return an HTML email in a plain text email.
The plain text email essentially is a more boring version of
the email we might send out that is rendered with pictures
and styles and everything else.
Now, if you wanted to review these templates,
you could go into the templates folder and look at
something like that come_to_work template.
It's a bunch of HTML that has a bunch of CSS styling in here, and
then towards the middle of the actual files will start to show you
what the actual content is. Now, it takes quite a while to get
through that CSS, so don't be surprised if you have to dive through
it. Feel free to update these.
Just keep in mind that inside of these templates,
there'll be things like this first_name property right here on
line 169. Now that's going to load in the first name, like Homer,
so that we can customize that email, and you'll see those
throughout the different templates.
Now,
I'm not going to make you review these templates because they're HTML code
that we don't need to work with too much, so I'll close this back out. Now,
in addition to the render_come_to_work_template,
there's also two other render functions, the render_daily_tasks_template,
which will set up daily tasks based on the day of the week.
Now, you'll see there's these different tasks that
differ depending on the day of the week.
For example, on Mondays, we have to clean the dog areas,
and on Thursdays we have to clean the dog areas again,
but on the other days of the week, we have different tasks,
so we'll use that depending on the day of the week using the
datetime library that we imported earlier to determine which
task we need to send out today.
This function will also render a plain text email,
which will be quite a bit more boring than the HTML email that
we have access to in the templates folder.
After this,
it'll just return both the HTML and the plain text email. The last template
will that we have here is called render_pickup_template,
and it's going to be a reminder to our clients to come pick
up their pets, so we'll pass in the first name of the client
and also the name of the pet.
Later on, we have the send_email function, which will take an HTML email,
a plain text email, a subject, and if we scroll to the right,
some recipients to send the email to. Now, inside of this, we'll be using the
boto3 library to create an SES, or Simple Email Service, client, and then we'll
be using the send_email method from that client.
Now it's going to take a bunch of information, like the
FROM_ADDRESS and the other properties we defined earlier, to
determine who the email is coming from,
who it's going to, and the types of emails that we're sending out,
ranging from the plain text email to the HTML email that
we were rendering with those templates.
Now, finally,
the last bit of functionality towards the bottom is
in the handler function here.
In this case, we're going to do something with the event data that comes in.
We'll create this event_trigger variable from the event resources and
the first thing in the event resources, and then we'll say that the
event has been triggered by this trigger.
Now, inside of that event trigger, we'll be searching for a different name.
So later, when we create these event triggers,
we'll need to make sure that we name them with either come_to_work,
daily_tasks, or, as the third option, pickup,
because we'll be searching for the name inside of these CloudWatch triggers in
order to determine which sort of email we're sending out.
If we see come_to_work inside of the event_trigger,
for example, we'll be sending out a reminder to our employees to come to work.
Or if we see daily_tasks in the event_trigger, we'll send a reminder
to our employees to get the tasks done for the day.
Finally, there's that last option of pickup,
which will send an email out to our clients
reminding them to pick up their pets.
So this is everything that happens in cuckoo.py.
Next, let's create our Identity and Access Management role so
that this cuckoo.py function will have the permissions that it needs to act on different AWS resources.