Over here on my serverless.yml file, let's get started adding a DynamoDB table
to this service. I'll need to hit Enter here, and I'll be copying and pasting
some code from the serverless_helper.txt file.
You're welcome to take a look at this in order to find this code instead of
copying it directly from the video here, or you can look at the final version
of this service inside of the examples as well.
So let me paste this in here,
and then I'll explain what's going on. At the very top, we're starting in
this resources section with a lowercase r, and this will be defining
CloudFormation resources that we want to use inside of our service. Inside of
the capital R Resources section, that's where we actually define these
resources. Now, this seems a bit redundant,
but that's because there's also the option to have, inside of the
resources section, something called Outputs.
Now, these outputs would allow us to reference these
resources from other services,
but we'd have to specify that with a capital O too. So
that's why it's a little redundant, but it's just the syntax we have.
So let me get rid of that, and let's look at what's
actually happening in the Resources section.
We start by adding this usersTable resource,
and we're going to make that a DynamoDB table resource.
It's going to have a few properties, which will
tell us how to create this table,
starting with the name of users and the attribute definitions of email,
which will be a string.
We know this because the AttributeType is an S here. And
then we define the key schema of our table,
which means how are we going to get things from our DynamoDB table?
I won't go into much detail with DynamoDB,
but essentially,
this means we need to provide an email in order to get
items out efficiently from DynamoDB.
This also isn't using other properties of DynamoDB like sort keys.
Instead,
this DynamoDB table has a simple primary key, which uses the
partition key of the email. And in order to define this,
we have this HASH value here for the KeyType.
The hash key is essentially the same as the partition key.
These are just two different words for that. At the very bottom, we
specify the provisioned throughput for the table.
Now,
this means how much capacity should this table have to read and write
things. I'm setting this to 1 because that's the lowest value here,
and it's also within the AWS free tier.
So after you've saved all of those contents in your
serverless.yml file, like I just did here,
let's go ahead and open up a terminal and redeploy our service.
So I'm going to run serverless deploy one more time.
Now,
this should pick up the new resource that we have in the
resources section and deploy it out in our service.
Now, once this deployment finishes,
we can test if this worked. Now that our deployment process is finished,
I'm going to clear the screen here, and let's run an AWS command‑line
interface command to check if we have a table in our AWS account. I'm
going to run aws dynamodb list‑tables,
and it looks like we now have a users table in our account.
That means that this process worked successfully to create this table, and we should be able to use it inside of this project here.