Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
In this part of this section we are going to be focusing on a new technique called fine tuning which
is directly connected to the transfer learning.
In a nutshell it is used after the transfer learning and sometimes it can improve upon the results achieved
using only France for learning for transfer learning.
We used a pre train network that we have frozen and just trained the custom part of it to be suited
for the task that we're trying to solve.
By the base network at this point it doesn't have any features connected to our specific task if we
have very specific task to solve.
It is handy to have features from the data set inside the base network as well enter fine tuning in
the fine tuning step.
We use the same heat texture that we did in the transfer learning although we unfreeze a few top players
from the base network.
This way we allow the network to learn even further about the custom data set.
There are a few pointers that I can give you a critical one.
Do not use fine tuning on the whole network.
Only a few top layers are enough.
In most cases they are more specialized.
When CNN is trained lower layers are going to learn general features lines edges corners and so on but
the top players will get more abstract features about the data set as well.
For example eyes tails ears and so on.
And the goal of fine tuning is to adopt those specific parts of the network to our custom data set and
the second point their data can give you is start with the fine tuning after you're finished with the
transfer learning step if we try to perform fine tuning immediately in our custom head is not trained
gradients will be much different between custom had and our unfrozen layers from the base network to
perform the fine tuning of the network.
The first step is to unfreeze a few top players and to achieve this.
We are going to unfreeze the whole thing so right base model dot trainable equals to true before we
choose how many layers to fine tune.
Let us count how many layers we have in our mobile Net.
You can copy this simple print statement from me or write her own execute a cell and as you can see
in our base model alone we have one hundred fifty five layers which is a lot define a variable called
fine tuned at this will store an index of the starting layer from which point on we are going to fine
tune for this task.
Let's set this to 100 so we are going to find you in all layers from 100 to 150 5 and to achieve this.
If you remember we unfrozen a whole network.
We need to freeze all areas before that so let's create the for loop that will iterate fruit all layers
in our base network.
So write for layer in base model both layers and in brackets just set column fine tuned at in this for
loop right.
Layer that trainable equals to false.
This code will freeze all layers up to 100 and that's it for this video.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.