Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial.
So far we've prepared everything to perform fine tuning step.
The goal for the fine tuning technique is to try to improve what thruster learning achieved.
In some cases it is going to help but in others it won't help at all.
It really depends on the data said architecture and so on.
Let's take a look at the code that we have for this lesson.
It is the same code that we used a few years ago to train our transfer learning model.
We are using the train generator for our training data.
Five e-books in volume generator for our validation data set if everything is clear.
Execute a cell.
It will take some time to train the model.
Therefore I will skip to the part where the model is trained.
And welcome back.
Well let's see the results that we have after the fine tuning step after the first e-book.
We have a 100 percent accuracy on the training set and the worst accuracy on the validation data set
about 94 percent.
The results indicate that our model or fitted in this case we didn't improve the accuracy by applying
the fine tuning technique which is still okay since we have fantastic results with the transfer learning
along in general.
When you have a small data set it is not a good idea to perform the fine tuning step since it will over
fit which we have proven with this case as well.
We came very far by applying these techniques and we created a remarkable network that saw the binary
classification we had state of the art results in the next story.
We are going to confirm our results from this review and that's it for now.
If you have any questions or comments please buzz them in the comments section.
Otherwise see in the next tutorial.