Hello everyone and welcome to this biting tutorial.
In this video we are going to pre process and prepared the data set for the training of our neural network.
So before we jump into the data set pre processing.
Well as this comes a few libraries that we have to import for the project the first one is ice.
It helps us with working with folders and perhaps the Jason library is maybe the most important library
for this section.
If you haven't worked with Jason before it is a way of receiving and sending data over the Internet.
It looks basically like a Python dictionary.
It will help us to send data to the model then we have the random library.
It will help us to choose random images from the data set to perform our predictions.
So process is a library to be working with multiple threads in the code.
Probably we won't use it at all in this section just imported in the case.
Then we have none by.
And as always it is a library of choice to work with math operations and matrices that the flow is here
to build neural networks and multiple partly to visualize the data set.
Images the data said that we are going to use for this project is safer than in the last line in this
cell with this percentage is called Magic command.
It is there to specify to note that all visualization should be kept inside of it.
And lastly we print the version of the tensor flow to make sure that we are using one point thirteen
point one since the tensor flows serving is not working well yet on the tensor flow 2.0.
But don't worry all the things that we are going to write for our dissection will work perfectly in
the tens of float 2.0 as well.
Let me jump to the data said processing the first thing for this lesson is to load the data set when
using the Load method for the tens of low data set it returns to outputs one for the training and other
one for testing.
Each can be split up into two more parts features and labels now that we know that.
Let's write in brackets X train y train comma.
Then getting brackets x test y test and that is equal to C for 10 that load data.
This function doesn't take any arguments just execute the cell and the function will download the data
set and stored and loaded in our environment OK.
The data set is downloaded and ready to be used in the meantime I've created this array of all class
names found in the separate end data set.
If you wonder how I knew what class names are you can find them on the C for 10 main page listed here
from airplane to the truck the next part of the dataset pre processing is to normalize images so let's
write x.
Train is equal to x train divided by two hundred fifty five point zero since this is the maximum value
of a pixel found in an image we are defining that to scale.
All images in the train said to be between 0 and 1 let's perform the same scaling method on the test
set as well right.
X test is equal to x test divided by two hundred fifty five point zero and we have all images scaled.
The last thing for this video is to track the shape of the data set right.
X train dart shape as you can see we have fifty thousand images in the training set each is thirty two
by forty two by three.
These free at the end is because we are working with colored images so our GP each will represent each
colour channel and that's it.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I've seen the next tutorial.