All right.
We are about to find out about the accuracy on the evaluation set which is the relevant set on which
you assess the performance of your model.
Right.
Because the accuracy we got here where on the training set but the training set is where our model learns
as opposed to the evaluation set where the model hasn't learned at all.
So basically we're going to measure the performance on brand new observations which is of course much
more relevant than on the training set.
So first of all I'm going to show you the syntax that allows you to evaluate your model on the test
set.
Here is the syntax.
It is simply another method from the sequential class to evaluate the method that you call of course
from your model object in which takes of course as input.
The two arguments test and whitest right of course x test contains all your input the input images of
the set well formatted into you know the one dimensional vector fed into the neural network and why
test which contains the real values.
You know the real classes of each of the images in x test.
But of course the model is not going to look at why test the model is going to return the predictions
of X test and we're going to compare these predictions to whiteness to finally measure the ratio of
correct predictions in the test.
And just before we look at the results.
Well since the Evaluate method actually returns two elements which are first the loss incurred in the
test set by the predictions of the model and also the accuracy and that's exactly what we want you know
we will have a better idea of how well our mole performed by looking at the accuracy.
So since it returns these two elements.
Well that's why you have these two variables introduced here Teslas and test accuracy.
All right.
And now well let's have a look at the final result on the test set.
Here we go.
And the final result is a brilliant accuracy of 87 percent.
So the same as in the training set actually.
And that's probably thanks to this drop out layer because this drag layer was used to protect us from
overfishing you know to prevent overfishing from happening.
Meaning that indeed we still get a great accuracy on new observations which are the observations of
the test set.
You know maybe you can try.
Maybe if we didn't at this drop out layer Well we would have obtained a lower accuracy on the test set
and a higher accuracy on the training set because this is exactly a situation of overfishing.
So there you go.
You have a great accuracy here on 10000 observations.
And maybe now you can improve it.
That's of course going to be part of the exercises you'll have for this section and feel free to share
your results especially if you get for example some accuracy is over 90 percent.
We will be very curious to see the architecture you figure it out.
All right.
And you know that's the purpose of this course.
We give you the notebooks.
We explain everything in the notebooks and then it's your turn.
You have to practice on all the series of exercises we give you.
So really try to do the exercises following this section and it does matter if you don't figure out
all the solutions you know.
What matters is that you practice try try and try.
And that's how you improve your skills.
And of course if you find solutions well congratulations.
Share them in the Q and A that will help the other students.
You know this is also a community where you not only learn from me but also where you help each other
so communicate as much as you can.
We will be happy to have a very dynamic communication in this course.
All right.
So I also provided this Prince you know if you don't want all the different information including the
less what we really want indeed is the accuracy.
That's why I added this final print with a test accuracy.
And you know this format syntax to return the real value of the accuracy which is eighty seven point
four percent.
All right.
So now your turn.
Practice well and as soon as you feel that you get the skills in artificial neural networks well you'll
be ready to tackle the next section about convolution on all networks.
And that's where we'll learn how to build a convolution on the one network with tens of low 2.0.
So I look forward to seeing you in the next section.
And until then have fun on the exercises and enjoy tensor flow.