Hello everyone and welcome to this python tutorial in the previous video we defined our classified image
function.
And with that part we are done with our class code and in this video we are going to start our flask
server to start our flask application.
Write an app because that is our name that we defined of the flask application.
To run in these dot run function takes a few arguments let's check them.
The first argument is the host which is known by default.
If you're running these application or server you would need to specify the server IP here the port
is maybe the most important argument here.
This argument defines on which port this application will run if we said the port that is already occupied
by some other application.
The flask ad will crash so at this stage it is essential to check whether or not the port is free.
You can overcome these by setting a board to be very high.
Let's say higher than 5000 and the last argument is debug.
If debug is set to None or fails the app will run in the production mode and all errors won't be printed
or the app won't stop since we are running this ad locally.
We won't provide the host.
So right port is equal to 5000 for a flat cap.
This is a default port to use but you can use any port that you want.
It only needs to be free if you are running this app on a server.
You would choose a port 80 or 88 for debug let's set it to false to test the application in the production
mode select the line of the code and executed.
And as you can see the app is running on the port 5000 in the production environment and now it is everything
ready for us to send the first API request.
Stay tuned for that for now.
If you have any questions or comments please post them in the comments section.
Otherwise I assume the next tutorial.