Hello and welcome back to the course on artificial intelligence.
I hope you in during the course so far and today we're talking about action selection policies.
All right.
Let's dive straight into it.
Previously we talked about adding a neural network to our simple core learning.
And so far we are getting quite into deep Q learning.
We've talked about the learning part quite a bit including adding some elements to it.
And today we're talking about this part we're talking about the acting.
So let's have a look.
So here we've got what we discussed about the acting that once you input the values the parameters or
the vector of describing the state the agent is currently in in that environment.
Then that is after all the learning is done or even before the learning is done.
Basically we get all the cue values so we're not interested in the learning right now we instrument
acting.
So once we have these key values how do we understand which one we need to use.
Well if you think about it.
Q values are simply these are predictions for the key values so as we did in the simple Q learning algorithm
what did we do we just selected the one with the best of the highest Q value.
Once we have the one with the highest value we just take that action because it just brings us the highest
values and we know that Q values calculators the immediate reward that we expect to receive plus the
decay factor terms the value of the next states and it's a recursive calculation.
So why not.
Why wouldn't you take the best Q value.
That's kind of the end of it.
But as you can see here it's not as simple here we're using a soft max function.
And this is where we're going to talk about action selection policies.
So here in reality we don't have to have just a soft max function.
We can have different action selection policies.
For example we've got Epsilon greedy Epsilon soft and we've got the soft Max.
And those are kind of like the most commonly used action selection policies of course there are others
for instance the most basic one is here is very simple actually selection policy just select the best.
The one with the highest Q value.
But why doesn't that action policy fly and why do we have different types of action policy action selection
policies.
Well it all boils down to exploration versus exploitation.
And that is the core of reinforcement learning because we've already talked about this a little bit
that your agent when it's operating an environment it might predict certain key values which which might
be good and it might and might not turn out great.
It might turn out that those core values are bad and we'll be forced to explore.
So if we for instance in this case predict that Q2 is the best one and then it takes two to take action
to add it.
So from here takes action too and then it gets it gets a very negative reward then the environment is
forcing the agent to go and explode because now it's going to learn that oh actually I thought Q2 is
going to be very good but it turned out very bad.
So so the results are not very bad.
So the network is going to update itself so next time he's in the state he's going to probably EMI my
soldiers Q2 if it was you know like if it was a very very favorable so you might think that that's like
you know he might need a couple of times a couple of penalties or punishments in order to learn a futures
about action but maybe he'll already soon learn that I'm going to take a different action and take this
action because now it has the best Q value so sometimes the environment forces the agent to take different
to explore different actions but sometimes the agent might get it find itself stuck in a local maximum
it might find that it falls like through through its initial exploration and found that oh this is a
political action like I'm going to go right here and that desperate collection.
But the problem is that it thinks is the best action simply because it hasn't explored is explored going
up is ghost blood going left as explored going right but it hasn't explored going down from that specific
state that it's in and now that it's kind of like biased towards this action and thinks too good actually
is gonna keep taken is going to keep getting it's going to keep taking this action is going to keep
getting a good reward but what if this action would have been even better if this action would have
been so much better that if it knew about this action it would actually switch to this action but because
it got stuck in a local maximum it getting these good rewards it's just going to be reinforced this
is going to keep reinforcing itself that or the environment's going to reinforce it that this is a good
action to take keep doing that but real in the reality is that there's this other action that hasn't
found yet or hasn't even explored that would have been much better as a what we want to do is we want
to come up with an action selection policy that allows our agent not to get stuck in a local maximum.
Yes it's important to keep doing the good actions that's the exploitation part we want to exploit what
we've found but at the same time we still want to explore we never want to stop exploring as like in
life you never want to stop learning you stop learning you die that's there's a saying like that that
when you're not growing you're dying or something.
So you want to keep learning and your agent wants to keep learning and that's where these action selection
policies come in.
So we've got three listed here.
So the first one is Epsilon greedy.
It's a very simple one it sounds pretty complex in the sense that like it's got a cool name and to do
things with several names are complex.
It's actually not.
So basically what it does is it will select the one with the best Q value and absolute like Epsilon.
You might hear in other places.
There's just like a selection policy.
So in this case we're using it to select sucked out of our queue values our actions so you'll select
the one with the highest Q value all the time except for Epsilon percent of the time.
So for instance if you set epsilon to 10 percent then you're going to or zero point one then 10 percent
of the time the action is going to be selected at random.
So 90 percent of the time you're still going to be selecting the best action based on the highest value
but 10 percent of the time is going to be selecting a random action uniform which is going to be absolutely
randomly taking an action or if you said Epsilon to zero point 5 4 0 0 5.
That means that 95 percent of the time the agent is going to be taking that action with the highest
value but 5 percent of the time it's still going to be selecting and a random action.
So it's going to be going out there and exploring.
So Epsilon soft is very similar no way the way that that's kind of like why it's called Epsilon greedy
because they're your greedily selecting the action the good action except for that little Epsilon percent
of the time so that the lower the Epsilon they'll lower the left Epsilon they're more greedily you're
selecting that kind of the action that is the optimal action and the less you're leaving the less chances
you're leaving for exploration Epsilon soft is the opposite.
So basically you're selecting at random you're selecting one minus epsilon percent of the time.
So if you're absent like zero point one or 10 percent then only 10 percent of the time you're taking
this action and why.
And 90 percent of the time you're selecting a random action.
So very very simple just inverted algorithms and a soft Max is kind of like the next step from or it's
a more advanced version I would say of epsilon of the Epsilon greedy algorithm although they both have
merit and they both have place.
We're going to be using soft Max in our coding in our practical side of things.
So that's why we're going to talk in a bit more detail about soft Max.
So let's have a look.
So let's move on to soft Max hopefully.
It's pretty clear about Epsilon greedy so it's a pretty straightforward algorithm.
Select the this one most of the time except for sometimes go and explore.
And now we also see why it's important to do that exploration so that we don't end up in local maximums
in our in our optimization process.
So now we're going to talk a bit more about South Max.
There's a tutorial on soft Max at the end of the course in I think it's an annex number two where we
talk about the concept behind soft Max.
I'm just going to refresh a little bit here so there we're talking about or neural networks and by the
way we're all going to be covering conversion and we're not covering coalition neural networks in this
section of the course in this section we're still using a vector but in the next section of the course
when we're we're creating an age play Doom we are going to be using conventional neural networks so
it could be beneficial for you to look at conventional neural networks and then take a soft Max function
or you can learn a bit more about soft Max after you take that and evolutionary neural networks annex
of course later on.
But here's a quick refresher so here we've got an evolution of neural network which decides whether
it's a dog or a cat.
So here we've got the voting process between these neurons and this one that says that it's a it's got
the features you know the fluffy ears.
What the pointed pointed face type of thing and the kind of like the features that other types of eyes
the eye the way their eyes look all these features that belong to dogs.
So it's a five percent chance that it's dog and the five percent chance that's a cat.
But the question is how did we get.
And in that Tora we're talking about how do we get these values to add up to one.
Well whatever the emotional or our whole neural networks are they can relational neural network plus
the fully connected layers wherever it's bad out whatever the values it spat out we applied is soft
makes functional here.
This is where we introduced them and found a formula for the soft max function is what it looks like.
And then we've got these values.
And so basically that's a quick refresher.
This is the formula for the soft Max.
It's what it does is it takes however many outputs you have doesn't matter.
It will take them and it will squash them all into values between 0 and 1 regardless of how big they
are just its form you can see that there is a total sum at the bottom so there's always going to be
zero bridges are in one and also the all these values are going to add up to one always And so that's
that's very beneficial for us because when we're using the soft max function what happens is we get
these Q values we select this best Q value but in reality what happens is these Q values that we get
there there are actual numbers right.
So this some kind of numbers they don't have to add up to 1 and I have to be between 0 and 1 just some
numbers but when we apply soft Max we don't just select the best one we actually get numbers like that
so we get numbers in the range between 0 and 1 and that are also that also add up to 1.
And so what other thing do we know that add up to 1.
Well probabilities we know that probabilities always have to add up to 1.
So that is why we can say here we've got key values but here all of a sudden we've got soft or we've
got probabilities.
So we can say that the likelihood of this being the best action is 90 percent.
This best being the other sections 5 percent 2 percent 3 percent because we know the higher your Q value
the better the action.
And so if we squash them to 0 to 1 then these become probabilities and we can deal with them as such
and therefore now is when the action is selected and that's how we come up with Q2.
But if you look at it closely this isn't a strict 100 percent and these are not strict zero percent.
So this is a 5 percent 2 percent 3 percent.
So the the most natural way to apply the soft Max in order to preserve exploration in the algorithm
is to use these exact probabilities as how often we're going to be taking that action.
So these probabilities actually represent the distribution of these actions that we're taking.
So basically soft Max makes it very easy for us to come up with a way to combine exploitation and exploration.
So the best the best action will always have the highest probability because it has high school value
and therefore here we're going to be just going to use these as our distribution we're going to say
okay we're going to be taking Q2 90 percent of the time but 5 percent of the time we're still gonna
be taking q 1 and 2 percent of time we get to do 3 and 3 percent of the time we're gonna be taking Q4.
And the beauty here is also that as these values UPDATE As then as the agent goes through the network
more and more and more it becomes more familiar with the environment and therefore these updates so
this value for instance might become like it might might ascertain that this values actually less or
this actually is higher.
And so these abilities will also change as an agent goes through.
So even though here we've got you to nobody is to say that sometimes 5 percent of the time to be more
precise we'll be selecting Q1 as the action to take and sometimes or action one will be taking action
one sometimes we'll be taking action through a 2 action 3 2 percent of the time and action 4 will be
taking about 3 percent.
So every action has a chance to play in this process as long as we have enough iterations an agent goes
through lots and lots of times through these states that they're in.
And that's that's how this that's how any kind of deep learning algorithm works that you want to do
this many many times so that you learn from experience and therefore as you can see here it's a very
natural transition to we're not just randomly like an absolute grid algorithm and not just randomly
selecting the actions we're selecting them based on their soft max values which makes it makes it like
has some logic behind it not just not just at random 10 percent of the time we're selecting a random
action but there's some logic behind how we're doing it and based on their the Q values that we've explored
and so that's the action selection policy that we're going to be using in this course.
You're welcome to definitely check out Epsilon greedy action section policy if you like but we're going
to be predominately using the soft Max action social policy and I've got an interesting reading for
you.
So this is called adaptive Epsilon greedy exploration in reinforcement learning based on value differences
it's the 2010 article and it's interesting because Mike Michelle I'm not sure how to pronounce it Michelle
and me Karl toxic introduces a different type of algorithm so an adjusted Epsilon greedy algorithm and
called the video video algorithm or Epsilon greedy VTB algorithm you can see it over here and he actually
compares computers to the absolute reading itself Max.
And it's an absolute greedy algorithm which basically the main idea behind it is to adjust the value
of epsilon depending on the state.
The agent is the answer if if the agent is very certain about this there and then Epsilon should be
smaller so there should be less exploration if the agent is uncertain.
Absence should be higher should be more exploration so it is a 2010 article.
I'm not sure if it's if this new proposed algorithm is widely used or is as being accepted in the community
or if artificial terms has moved kind of away from this.
This suggestion but nevertheless it will definitely help you reinforce your knowledge about action selection
policies which would discuss the absolute ingredient the soft Max I'll help you.
It'll give you an opportunity compare them side by side and also see in which direction people actually
think when they want to improve artificial intelligence.
So if you're ever planning on creating really interesting algorithms that are pushing the edge of ultra
artificial intelligence and pushing the envelope in this space then this could be a good way for you
to see in which direction people think sometimes when they're trying to improve the norms of artificial
intelligence or the norms that existed back then in 2010.
So there we go.
Hopefully you enjoyed today's tutorial about the action selection policies and we learned about Epsilon
greedy apps on soft and the soft Macs.
And now you're even more prepared for the practical side of things.
And on that note I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then enjoy a.