In this video we're going to start a new little project that's going to be focused around helping you
share secret messages with friends.
So let's take a look at a couple of mockups and understand what we're trying to build.
All right here we go.
So when a user first comes to our little web application we're gonna show them a text input on the screen
and prompt them to enter a secret message.
So this right here is a text input.
So I would imagine that I would type in something like my secret message or whatever else.
Well then click on that create button when we click on the create button the entire form is going to
change.
So we're going to swap out the form right there and show some different content.
Instead we're gonna show a new text input and inside there we're gonna show a U or L that a user can
share with a user or with one of their friends if anyone else goes to this very special little you U.R.L.
that we show right here.
We're going to show them a screen like this so essentially we're going to somehow figure out what the
secret message is and displayed on the screen when some other user or like a friend comes to the screen.
We're going to also show a little link at the bottom that says create your own message.
And if a user clicks on that they're going to go back to this initial page over here.
So again we enter some text.
We click on Create.
We get a link to be shared with a friend.
If a friend visits this link we're going to show them the original secret message.
Now you might could be kind of curious how this is all going to work.
Well look really closely at this are all right here.
So we're going to have a link to our application and all the very end.
We're going to have this kind of cryptic looking string so inside of that little cryptic string we're
going to essentially encode or secretly hide whatever the message is.
So that string right there we can imagine is going to represent somehow magically my secret message
so whenever a user clicks on that link inside the URL or in other words in the address bar we're going
to have access to that message inside of the friend's browser.
Now if all this doesn't really quite make sense just yet.
That's totally fine.
As we start to build the application you're going to very quickly understand how this is all put together.
So this is going to be a fun little app.
We're going to understand a lot more about handling navigation inside the browser.
So let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back the next video and start doing a little bit of project setup.