Well we finished writing out some code to check to see if the email is in use and to make sure that
the password and password confirmation match.
So now we need to start to actually understand how we're going to handle authentication inside of application.
So in this diagram I said Create an account for this user but there's some really deeper considerations
here in understanding how we really consider a user to be authenticated or signed into our application.
So in this video we're going to have a pretty long discussion about how the vast majority of authentication
works online.
Now I say vast majority because there are technically several different ways to handle authentication
inside of a web application.
But we're going to look at what is undoubtedly the vastly most popular way to handle authentication
in general.
The first thing we're going to have to understand is a little side topic called request cookies.
Once we understand how cookies work will then have a better idea of how we actually handle authentication
in general.
So just a quick side topic.
OK.
So in this diagram we've got our browser that is making requests to some server.
So here's the first request that occurs right here whenever a server responds back to our browser.
The server can optionally include or decide inside the request to include something called a cookie
it cookie is a very small string of characters that the server wants the browser to store so the server
is going to send over this very small string of characters and it's going to tell the browser please
include that small string of characters with every follow up request that has ever made it to that exact
same server.
When I use the term exact same server I mean any server at this particular domain.
So in other words like the server at Google dot com or the server at Airbnb Viacom or Facebook or wherever
else whenever the browser then makes a request to that same domain the browser is going to automatically
include that little small string of characters with the request that is being issued to that server
so the only thing you have to understand here about cookies is that the server can provide a cookie
a cookie is a small string of characters and the server can require that the browser sends that cookie
whenever it is making a followup request back to the server and this cookie is the absolute core of
the vast majority of authentication.
It is what is going to allow us inside of our application and many other applications out there in general
to identify users who are coming to an application and making some series of requests.
Let's take a look at a follow up diagram.
That's kind of built going to build on this idea there's kind of a core problem in handling authentication.
The whole idea of signing up and signing into an application really evolve revolves around a server
being able to identify who is making requests to that server.
Normally when your browser makes a request the server doesn't really have any inherent idea of who is
making requests.
Think about Google or Facebook or Airbnb and be Amazon or whoever else out there.
These companies have servers that have millions or else thousands of different requests being made to
each of these servers every single second.
And so these servers need to be able to positively and 100 percent identify exactly who is making the
request.
So in order to identify the person making a request a cookie is used here's what goes on when someone
signs into the application be at Rs or Facebook whoever else the server is going to compare that email
and password that is being provided if the email and password match a user account that is stored inside
the database the server is then going to send a cookie down to the browser that contains in a very encrypted
format the ID or some identifying token about the person who just signed in to the cookie you might
store some information like this cookie belongs to a user with an I.D. of one that is stored inside
of our database.
So then whenever the browser makes a follow up request to the server it's going to include that cookie
that has that little identifying piece of information inside of it.
So the server can read that piece of information see that the request is being made by a person with
an idea of one and then go look up inside of their data store or database whatever else and find the
user with I.D. one and so they then have some identifying piece of information from the database that
has all the relevant details about this very particular user.
So again it's all about the cookie.
Now a couple of things for you to understand.
The cookie is going to contain this user I.D. or some otherwise identifying piece of information inside
of an encrypted format.
So in general we never want users to exchange their cookies because if you got someone else's cookies
for say Google you would be able to very easily fake as though you were that other person and essentially
assume their identity or sign in with their account the cookies that are being assigned are always unique
for each domain.
So in other words if Google sends you a cookie to store inside of your browser that is a unique and
very different cookie than one that is being sent to you from Air B and B.
So for every different domain you visit you're going to have a different set of cookies.
Now the next day I want to do is show you this entire process in action so you can kind of see exactly
what is going on behind the scenes to give you a very simple demonstration.
I'm going to use a Web site called base camp.
Base camp is a free project management service.
I'd pick this Web site at random.
Nothing special about them.
I just figured Hey here's base camp.
Let's take a look at how they handle authentication.
I've already created an account for base camp so I'm gonna go ahead and sign in and we'll take a look
at the kind of cookies being exchanged along that process.
You do not have to create a base camp account or go through any of the steps that I'm about to go through.
Instead just take a look.
Sit back watch and I'll show you some of things we just discussed right in action OK.
So first off I'm gonna open up my network request lug and then going to attempt to sign in to base camp
with an account that I already created.
It's all enter in my email.
That is a random email right there.
I'm going to enter my password as well.
Now when I hit log in right here I'm essentially submitting this form in the exact same way that you
and I are submitting a form right now on our application.
So the email or that input right there and the password input the information inside that form is going
to be collected by the browser and submitted inside of a post request to the base camp servers so as
soon as I click log in I should see a request being issued with my form information right away.
OK so here we go.
And click log in and then right there very briefly you'll see a request to a router called session.
It looks like I mistyped my password.
We do that again.
That's better.
So anyways the very first request though is being issued was to an end point called session.
This is what logs you in to the base camp servers.
If I click on that request I can scroll down to the very bottom and see the information that was included
inside the forum.
You'll notice that I've got my user name right there.
That's the e-mail and my password.
Just you know that password I picked entirely at random based on something I had on my desk so I don't
use the password for anything else.
Don't try to sign my email with that you're going to be wasting your time.
There was a point is that I'm making a request with the data inside that form I can then take a look
at the response that is given to me by base camp servers.
If I scroll up a little bit and find the section inside of here called response headers instead of response
headers I'll see several sections marked as set cookie.
So these are the little identifying pieces of information that uniquely identify me to base camp servers.
So now any sign that my browser makes a follow up request to base camp servers is going to include each
of the cookies that I see inside of here.
So here's one cookie.
Here's another here's another in every case I'll see that they contain or essentially reference what
looks like a random string of characters.
So this seemingly random string of characters right here is what uniquely identifies me to base camp
servers so take note that the names of these different cookie properties in this case are identity I.D.
session token and Launchpad session.
I can now take a look at any other requests that is being made to base camp dot com.
In particular when I do so here's one right here.
I see the end point that essentially gives me this H HTML document I should be able to click on that
request.
Take a look at request headers in this case.
So here's request letters inside there is the cookie session or something cookie section and inside
of here is all the different cookies that base camp has told my browser to include with follow up requests
the inside of here I should see all the same property names that I saw that were being set back over
here just a second ago.
So I then the idea session token and Launchpad session so I should see inside of here somewhere inside
of your identity I.D..
I'm not going to look too long session I.D. and so on.
I don't see them right off the top of my head.
The reason for that is actually kind of interesting.
Well here's something in practice something I just noticed.
Remember when I told you just a moment ago.
Every different domain has its own set of cookies.
Well I've actually looked really closely here.
The initial log in request was being made to 37 Signals dot com and then the request that I just clicked
on by Ray had random was to base camp dot com.
So these two different domains actually have different sets of cookies and that's why I was not just
able to look at the set of cookies and see the same ones that were being made use of when actually it
logged back in.
Over there.
So that's why things were a little bit unexpected.
I'm going to try going to about this one right here.
This is where it looks like I get another set of cookies if I took a look in here.
There we go.
Some these are all a bit more easy to find so easy 3 identify D and B C 3 session verification token.
OK so now remembering those two names.
Let me go back to that request and now inside of here I'll see these three ident I.D. and session verification
token so we can see very plainly that the server gives me a cookie and then my browser chooses to automatically
append that cookie in every up request.
And again that is what identifies me to base camp servers and to really show you this stuff in action.
I'm going to pull up a little tool that I can use to make arbitrary network requests.
So this is a little tool called postman and it's all about making network requests and I can specifically
and very easily identify exactly what options I want to include with every request that I make.
So I mean zoom in on this thing really quickly so you can see it more easily alternate that sidebar.
So I can make a get request to some given your URL and they'll show me the response down here.
So I'm going to try to make a get request to the URL that I am currently at.
This will be essentially equivalent to if I type this URL into my browser so if I try to navigate to
that address I'm going to get back some amount of HCM although I see down here in white red away based
on that title.
You can see that I am being redirected or being told that I need to log in in order to see the content
at that your URL.
Of course I don't really have any way of logging in via this client here but I can kind of fake my identity
by including this exact same cookie information over here with the request that I make.
So if I just can manually take that cookie information and stick it in to this request client base camp
is essentially going to be tricked into thinking that I am someone who I am not so I'm going to take
all this cookie information that is saved to my browser I'm gonna cut it or simply copy it then paste
it in as a header inside of my API client under a heady header called Cookie and I'll give it the same
value of the entire cookie that is being sent along for my browser it's now I'm essentially tricking
base camp into thinking that I am the person who has all this information here.
So now if I make the same request I'm going to get a very different response.
Now you'll see that I got some different content here and it has a title of home so clearly I'm not
being asked to sign in or log in anymore.
So I have successfully tricked base camp into thinking that I am that person just by taking that cookie
and throwing it into the request.
So at the end of the day I knows a little bit rambling but at the end of the day the entire point here
is that the cookie is the absolute key for identifying myself to base camp servers and so it's gonna
be the exact same thing inside of our application as well.
Whenever a user signs up for an account with our application we're going to create a record inside of
our little data store that we just put together to say hey here's this person.
They signed up at this email and this password and then to actually consider that person to be logged
into our application.
We're going to give them a cookie to hold onto the cookie is going to be automatically managed by the
browser.
We don't have to write any javascript code on the browser side for that the browser is going to include
that cookie on every form request.
We're going to use that to automatically say OK this person is logged in.
They're good to go.
They can edit products delete products and so on.
That's the whole idea.
So now we've got a better idea of what's going on.
Quick pause right here and we'll start taking care of all this cookie stuff in the next video.