Our postwar quest handler is now receiving some data out of the form that the browser submitted.
It's now we can get back on track thinking about how we can actually create an account or something
to represent the person who just sent us some email and password combination.
The first thing we should probably think of is exactly what it means to create an account.
Well to me I think that means that we need to have some kind of record of this person coming to our
application entering their email and their password.
So it essentially means we need to store their email somewhere and record them as being a person who
has signed into our application or at least created an account in order to store this information.
We're going to have to have some persistent data store when I say persistence.
I mean if we ever happen to restart our application we need to make sure that all the information or
all the different accounts that have been created somehow get persisted into the next restart or startup
of our server.
In other words just go back over to your terminal and notice inside of here how we are getting our application
restarting over and over and over again if we were to store a list of accounts that had been created
inside of memory.
So inside of like just some javascript array we would be dumping that data every single time our server
restarted so we need to have some kind of mechanism to store some information about our users and products.
And we need to make sure that that information is going to persist across restarts of our server.
So let's talk about exactly what we're going to do.
So we're going to have our Express server interface with a data store this data store is going to store
a list of users who have created an account with our application and a list of products as well.
The data store itself is going to save all of its data to our harddrive in the form of Jason files.
So we're going to have a file called products not Jason that is going to store all the different products
that have been created.
We're going to have another file called User store Jason and that will store all the different users
who have signed up to our application as well you and I are going to implement this data store from
scratch.
So we're gonna figure out how to create the data store how to work with some data stored inside of a
file how to load it up all that kind of good stuff before we write any code for the state to store.
However there are a couple of things I wanna mention.
The data store that we're going to implement is really not suitable for production use in other words
if you go into some kind of job interview or something like that I would not recommend that you mentioned
this as being a good solution.
If you go into a job interview mentioned he put something like this together for fun but also point
out some of the reasons that you would not want to use a data store that saves information into files
on the hard drive.
The reasons that you would not want to do something like this in a production application are well if
we ever try to open the same file twice at the same time and write some information into it we're going
to get in there.
In addition this approach won't work if we have multiple different servers running on different machines
because they're all going to have their own version of a product.
Jason and user start JS on file.
In addition the performance of this will be relatively not that great because we have to write to the
file system every single time that we want to update some data inside of our app so looking at these
cons to this approach you might be thinking.
Steven why are we wasting time with this.
Remember everything in this course all is about JavaScript and so above all the opportunity to write
a date data store from scratch on her own that relies on some flat files really is some good experience
that's going to teach you some really interesting stuff around javascript and in particular we're even
going to see a really good example of code reuse using classes and inheritance with object oriented
programming.
So from the perspective of this course using the data store we're going to put together is like perfect.
Definitely something that you want to write from scratch at least once and understand how it works.
But on a real application this approach might not be the best in the world.
Okay.
So now that we have a vague idea at least of what we're trying to accomplish here let's pause right
here come back the next video and start working on our data store.