We were just able to verify that our validation was working but the error messages that we have right
now are and title and price aren't that great.
Let's very quickly just go to our validators such as file.
Here it is right here.
Going to find require title and require price and remember to customize an error message.
We can chain on a dot with message call.
I'm going to do that.
In both cases I'm going to find the comma that separates these two key value pairs of then chain on
a dot with message and for title.
I'll say must be between five and forty characters then for the price.
I will also cheat on a with message and say must be a number greater than one okay.
So let's save this.
I'm not going to do a full test of this.
Instead I'm just going to refresh the form and make sure that everything still appears.
If you just made a typo then you're going to see some error message something it says hey cannot connect
a server.
And so if you see an error message go back over to your terminal you'll see a reason of exactly what
went wrong.
Chances are obviously it's gonna be a typo related to that validators dot she has file okay.
So now in this video what I really want to focus in is the image upload right here.
So we've got something that we can click on it says choose file and then presumably inside of here we
can select some file to include with the form.
So the first thing I want to focus on is just how do we actually access that image.
How do we on our server write some code that says OK.
Take the image that the user just uploaded and save it somewhere or do something with it to give it
get a better idea of how to work that image.
I first want to try to access it in the same way that we access other properties contained inside of
our form so usually to access other properties inside of our form we can find our post request handler
going to delete the console log right here of errors and I will replace that with a console dot log
of DOT body.
Remember that's where we usually get information from our form from flushes console log that out in
C.
Well what got uploaded in place that image looking to see this file.
I'll go backwards.
My form I'm going to add in some title here like a product.
I'll make sure I put in a valid price as well.
Now I'll hit choose file and I'm going to upload a image of a quote.
Now obviously I'd sat down ahead of time got an image of a coat to actually upload.
So at this point you don't actually need an image of an actual product.
You just need an image to upload it can be any type of image.
So a JPEG a PMG even a bitmap.
It's totally up to you.
All you need is an image.
So hopefully you can find a image on your computer right now.
If you can't you can always hop over to Google image search and search for Cote and go to images and
just download one the images that you see on this page right here.
So some coats and you'll actually notice that the coat I used is was it not on here.
What was on here just a moment ago.
So whatever.
All we need right now is an image of something.
It's going to take that image throw it into that file picture and I'll hit submit OK.
So let's now go over to our terminal and see what got console logged out tobacco over here I can see.
OK.
I got the titled The Price in for that image property.
All I have is the name of the file that I just uploaded.
I don't have anything about well actually the image itself.
I don't have any image data.
I just have the name so that doesn't really appear to be that useful.
Another way that we can try to inspect the request that we're making is to go back over to our network
request tab inside the browser and take a look at the request was issued when we submitted our form.
If you don't have your network request tab open then make sure you open it up.
Go back to the form enter and a title and a price and reattach that image and then hit submit again.
And we should see the post request that is being made to our back end.
There it is right there.
Click on it.
I'll take a look at headers and if I scroll down to the bottom I'll see all the form data that was included.
So it's clear at this point by looking at this right here that when we submit a form or a default form
that has an image attached to it all that is getting communicated from our browser over to the server
is this image property that has the name of the image which is definitely definitely not useful at all.
So it's clear that the default behavior of a form is not really doing what we want.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to get a better idea of how we can actually take a file
that has been attached to a form and submit it and receive it on our back end server.