Hey welcome back everyone.
We've made it through all of the promises and a synchronous javascript callback hell stuff and we needed
to cover all of that so that we can start making requests.
We're gonna see how we can use javascript to get information from an API like load movie data or search
for planets in Star Wars or get a random joke which you could also apply to things like logging someone
in via Facebook or sending some data off to your own server to save to a database.
It's all the same process.
We send a request from the client side and we have to understand asynchronous javascript and promises
for a lot of the requests that we'll be sending because these requests take time.
We talked about that in the previous section.
These things aren't immediate.
It takes time.
They might fail they might.
I mean it could take 10 seconds.
It could take half a second.
It doesn't matter how long.
Exactly.
It just matters that it's not instantaneous.
So we have to worry about things like callbacks and promises.
So there are multiple ways of making requests.
We're going to start with the old school quite quite ugly and confusing and hard to remember way.
Example HDP requests which is standard across all browsers but a newer much more modern and simpler
syntax exists which is called fetch.
So we'll see both of those.
Then we'll talk about a library that's really really popular to help you make requests called axioms.
It's a third party script.
We can include it just simplifies the process so we're doing the same thing.
It's just a cleaner syntax but before we talk about any of those options we need to talk about this
idea of Ajax which is a term you may have heard if you're brand new to JavaScript you might have come
across this term Ajax.
It stands for asynchronous javascript and XM L which is kind of a misnomer because these days most of
the time we don't work with Excel.
We work with Jason.
Nobody says age judge but that's that's kind of what it is these days.
So if you don't know what Excel or Jason are we'll get there but let's just talked about this general
idea back in the day before Ajax was really a big thing before single page apps were common.
We had one standard flow for loading new data or getting information from a server which included a
page refresh.
Here's an example MDA n is not a single page app.
If I search for something here like react I don't know if they have much on react actually but if I
hit enter you'll see my page does change.
I go to a new U.R.L. and the page actually reloads one more time.
Let's look for div.
Watch this little bar here we go to a completely different page.
So what's happening here is the browser is sending a request for a new Web page and it's going off to
one of em DNS servers.
Depending on this U.R.L. this is the URL that we requested by hitting enter this you URL is then received
the request is received by the server NBN server wherever it is indeed compiles a new web page for us
including the amounts we assess in any relevant javascript.
It sends the entire page back our browser refreshes and this is what we see a whole new page.
Contrast that with what happens here.
This is a Web site called Can I use.
Let's go back to home and we'll search for something.
How about the gradient.
I mean a search for gradient.
The page never reloads.
I don't go anywhere else.
Data is being loaded.
There is communication with the server but it's happening behind the scenes.
It doesn't involve a whole page refresh.
We're not getting a new web page.
It's a it's a different approach for just getting some data.
Or can I use is asking for data from a server.
It comes back and then new elements are added to the page.
If I search for something else let's go back to transform.
You can see what happens.
I'm not moving the page is not changing.
Well the page is changing the contents are changing at least some of it but it's a single page that
we are staying on.
And this is really what Ajax is all about.
The idea of Ajax is using these requests that we can make via javascript asynchronously that's the asynchronous
javascript to load some data from a server or to send data to a server to save something to a database
whatever it is we're communicating with a server behind the scenes not in between page loads like we
had here where you know I search for something else in between those loads in between what a user sees
and the page refreshing.
That is when the communication is occurring with the server here the communication is happening while
I'm on this page it's happening in the background and the general process is a request is sent based
off of.
In this case keyboard events.
So if I type something else what's another.
How about Arrow functions.
So I finished typing.
There's some sort of D balance on here so it's not sending a request every single time I had a letter.
It's waiting until I finish a word or something.
It's sending a request based off of my keyboard input in the background it's happening.
We get some response from the server.
The response usually these days is in the form of something called Jason.
In the past it was ex AML which is what was most commonly used and where the name Ajax comes from.
But these days almost everyone uses Jason so Jason is just a format for sending data.
Imagine you have data representing all of this information we see here.
The elements themselves are not being sent as HMO or the CSF is not being sent.
All that's being sent is basically the text and some information that maybe doesn't show up.
You know what's supported what's not supported and it's being sent as text but rather than just plain
text.
It's turned into this Jason notation.
It's a way of representing data.
It's a protocol for communicating between servers or a protocol for formatting data and sending it to
another server or to another browser somewhere.
So we're going to talk about what it looks like in depth in the next video but if we open up our dev
tools here and you go to the Network tab it's gonna show you that we can see the request happening behind
the scenes.
Let's search for something else like spread and you'll see some activity over here.
This activity represents different requests that have been sent.
If we go to X H.R. which we haven't talked about yet but that's what we'll see next X H.R. here is going
to show us the requests that have been sent and we can see here is one sent to a can I use server.
If we open this up.
This was the umbrella was sent to search equals spread and some information was sent back.
This is the data that was sent back.
If we take a look at it here this is the data that came back from the server behind the scenes.
So we end up with some information.
Let's see.
DNC assessed properties box shadows spread radius.
So that represents this result.
Right here then we have another one operator spread spread in D structuring which is what we see here.
So this information was sent back from the server but it's not all of the information.
It looks like there was a second request sent and if we look at this it's a lot more.
But this is really the core of the browser support chart that is created.
So we get the titles back.
I guess they split it up maybe so you can get them faster.
I'm not positive.
Actually there's I'm sure there's a good reason why there are two requests instead of one that just
gets everything at once.
But here we can see a representation of the CSX property box shadow spread radius.
That's the title that we have here.
We have let's see support and under support we can see all the different browsers.
Here's all the support for Chrome and edge.
There's a lot of information here so we won't go into detail on what this actually looks like.
But the point is this is not h Tim L..
That's being sent.
It's not JavaScript itself.
It's not actually javascript it looks like javascript but it's actually called Jason.
It's simply a way of sharing data between a server and another server a server in a browser that we
can then use in JavaScript.
It's really easy to take Jason and turn it into javascript and do something with it.
So we send a request or in this case the Web site sends a request whenever I type something we can clear
all of the requests we see here.
Just like that we search for something else like what's another one.
S H came our property.
Mm hmm.
How is it so hard.
How about text decoration.
Okay.
So there we go.
Some requests were sent.
We've got the first one.
The second one.
It looks like it sent two requests.
I had text dash D and then it sent another follow up for text dash deck I must have been very slow and
then my typing there and we get information back.
This information is then passed via javascript javascript takes that information and turns it into elements
on the page it manipulates the DOM.
So it's all happening behind the scenes some event usually triggers it typing or hitting a button a
request is sent.
Life goes on in the browser while this request is is gone.
And while we're waiting for a response javascript doesn't just sit there doing nothing.
We talked about that in the last section how this all works with web APIs so the browser is sending
that request.
Information comes back then javascript takes the reins and decides what to do display some content.
In this case add some classes make some tables some whatever these are h 3s or something has them all
in the right order and we end up with this page.
Okay.
So next we're gonna talk about Jason in more detail and then we'll start making our own requests.