All right.
Welcome back.
So if we break down the topics we've covered into the main sort of core central ideas to JavaScript.
We had variables than we had conditionals than we did data structures arrays and objects.
Now we have another really key piece to any programming language which is looping.
How do we repeat code.
And it's not just about repeating constant log.
Hello.
Ten times.
There's so many different scenarios where we need logic to run multiple times where we need a game loop
to continue to loop and run code over and over and over intel.
Game over is true until the user wins.
We're going to see a bunch of different types of loops different ways of repeating functionality or
repeating logic in our scripts.
So we have a couple main goals here.
There are different types of loops we're going to talk about four main loops.
First of all the for loop we want to be able to write for loops understand the syntax do the same thing
with while loops a different type of a loop along the way we'll talk about infinite loops a very non
desirable outcome from a loop how they arise how to avoid them that sort of thing and then we'll shift
our focus to data structures with loops.
So how do we loop over an array or an object.
How do we do something.
Once per every item in an array or every value in an object.
Those are really really common use cases as well.
So these loops that we're going to write are all about doing things repeatedly taking some block of
code and running it over and over and over.
And it's not always the same outcome every single time.
It could be like if we were printing Hello 10 times we're always concerned about logging hello we would
use a loop just to shorten up our code instead of having to write 10 constant logs we can write one
and have it run ten times but then other times the outcomes or the iterations of the loop are different.
Like if we were going to sum every number in an array we would need to loop or iterate once for each
item in the array and add them into a total or a sum variable.
So each time the number we're adding in is different.
So it's not just constant logging Hello 10 times we're still changing what's happening each time through
the loop.
So there are multiple loop types for and while I mentioned those already.
We'll also see two more the four of loop and the four in loop and I'll wrap up with this intro video
with a quick example or two examples of where loops are used all over the place on the web on the web
on Web sites.
Here is one of my favorite sub it's artisan videos.
It's a very relaxing non stressful beautiful Sub Reddit.
I come to them and in a bad mood it's just videos of people who are really talented at their work woodworkers
Carver's calligrapher.
Anyway if you saw the underlying data structure behind each post here all the data we see on the page
there is an array of posts and each post looks something like this.
This is a very simplified version but we have an array of posts each post is an object and each post
has a title a link a user name of the person who submitted it.
There's also the number of upvotes there's all the comment information.
The date it was posted.
If it's been gilded or not.
So all of that information is contained in one object for each post and then all of those objects are
combined into one large array.
There is a loop behind the scenes that is going to iterate over every single post in that array and
display it on this web page.
Make some HDMI content for it.
Put an image there put the title here put the upvotes here.
That is all done with a loop.
None of it is hard coded so if there were 10 items to display that loop would run 10 times if there
were a thousand posts in that array.
It would run a thousand times so that's one type of loop where you're iterating over something you're
doing something a set number of times.
This is another type of loop where we have a game loop.
If you've never seen this game it's called 2048.
I wasted way too much.
My high school and college classes playing this game in the back.
It's really simple it doesn't really matter how it works but you combine powers of two together and
they form a new number so if I combine two and two I get four foreign for I get aid in eight I get 16
anyways I can keep playing this game there's logic that runs every time I hit one of these arrow keys
you can't see that I'm doing it but you might be able to hear it every time a hidden Cherokee something
happens on the page but there's going to be a point where I can't move anymore and at that point the
main loop of the game is over.
So the logic of this loop is something like if there are still playable moves.
If the board is not completely jammed up and locked then let the user keep playing and see what happens.
Listen for an event for a key press and you can see I just lost.
So at this point that logic is done that loop had been going and in my case I probably had a couple
hundred turns a couple hundred aero presses but it's possible you could have a much much longer game
or even a quick your game.
I don't know though.
I was just hitting it randomly.
It's probably a pretty bad strategy but I'm sure you could lose the game quicker.
So the point here is that we're not looping a set number of times for not repeating some code 20 times
every single time.
Instead it's dynamic and it's a loop that just continues to run some logic Intel a condition is met
so we'll see how to do both of these types of loops.
We're going to start with the for loop which is up next.