Well our project is looking pretty good with the exception of our project structure right now.
So at present we have got an incredible amount of code stacking up inside of our index not J.S. file.
We've got a couple of different root handlers and you can pretty easily imagine that if we continue
to build out our application in this fashion of really just stuffing everything into index dot J.S.
pretty soon this file is going to be really large and hard to read.
So in this video we're going to start to refactor out some of the code inside of here into separate
files inside of our project and then link it all back up inside the index dot J.S. file me first show
you a diagram to help you understand exactly how we're going to structure this project.
OK.
So here's the idea we're going to have three primary directories inside of our project.
We're gonna have a directory called Roots one called repositories which we technically already have
and one called views.
I bet you could guess what the repositories directory is all about.
That's where we're going to place the different repositories.
We have to work with data.
We've already got that for users.
We're going to create another one called products pretty soon because remember although we haven't really
discussed it in a while.
The goal of our project here is to build this kind of e-commerce application the next big directory
is going to be the roots directory inside there.
We're going to have a sub folder called admin so two files are going to be inside there.
One will be admin slash off which is going to handle all of our authentication related stuff.
Essentially all it could we've written so far and then another will be called products which has a couple
of different root handlers around allowing administrators to create edit and delete different products.
We'll also have a file for handling all the different routes around a user using products.
It's like essentially this screen right here and another file for showing our cart.
So essentially that screen right there that's what's going on inside of routes.
Last one is going to be views.
At present we've stuck a lot of each team l directly into our root handlers.
So in other words back inside of our index dot J as file we look at our sign up root handler right here.
We've got some H T mail right there.
Same thing inside of our sign and root handler.
We've got some H channel all right there as well.
As you can imagine our final design or like the final application we're going for all this stuff is
going to require a lot of H to out.
So if we try to stick all its h t mail directly inside of our root handlers things are going to get
insanely messy really quickly even if we split stuff out into these separate files so instead we're
going to eventually create a views directory and inside there we're going to have a couple of different
files that are responsible for the creation of all the different each time all that we need.
So we're going to call that stuff views because they're essentially the different viewable things inside
of our app.
So this is the end goal.
I just want to give you a preview of what we're going to head for right now.
Let's focus on creating some this root stuff specifically around handling the administrator outs for
authentication and reconciling moving some code inside their back with the index dot J.S. file.
So quick pause and we'll start that refactor in just a moment.