All right.
And this video now that we've gone through a lot of different testing stuff.
It is now time for us to write our own custom testing framework.
Now this is going to be a lot of fun.
We're going to take a lot of the knowledge that we've gained around no J.S. not around just this testing
stuff but also around the earlier projects where we tried to find all the different files and folders
inside of a directory and also the project where we learned how we could automatically rerun a project
or rerun some amount of code every single time a file changed as well.
So this really is a kind of culmination of a lot of no J.S. stuff.
The first thing we're going to do is lay out some requirements of the testing framework we're going
to build.
So this is going to describe some the different aspects of our testing framework.
The first thing I want to make sure is that we end up with a node based CLIA.
So some like tool that we can execute from our command line that's going to run all of our tests inside
of a project.
So we're not going to be running anything inside of a browser like we're doing just a moment ago with
Moka next note we have to be able to test browser based javascript applications.
And now here's where things start to get interesting you'll notice I put all the exclamations right
here because remember when you're talking about MOCA.
I had said we have to use MOCA inside the browser if we want to taste test some browser based javascript
code because node by default doesn't have any idea of a dom or of query selectors or of event listeners
or stuff like that.
So these two notes right here are at odds with each other.
I'm saying that I want to build a testing framework that runs with no J.S. but simultaneously we must
be able to test browser based javascript applications big enough to figure out some really clever way
to implement both these same things inside the same testing framework.
We're going to come back to this note in just a little bit and explain how we're going to tackle it.
Let's continue going over requirements right now so our next requirement is that there must be very
very little setup.
So in other words unlike that Moka web based project we just worked on where we had to create that index
dot or something the test on each demo file amended through a bunch of markup inside there for our command
line tool that we're going to build.
I want to be able to just essentially have one command that we can execute and have that run all the
different tests inside of our project.
So a little bit similar to the moka or the version of Moka that we used very briefly when we were testing
that high dash application.
Next up and this is going to be a critical one inside of the moka test that we just did inside the browser
we were testing one little widget just that autocomplete thing and we had to do a whole bunch of setup
to test that thing out and all that setup was really just to be able to test the autocomplete so it
would be really nice to yield to test multiple different things inside of our movie's application without
having to write a bunch of configuration code or anything like that again as a good example we should
in theory really be able to test that this little notice right here goes away any time that we search
as we search for something.
So I want to be able to test the entire application very easily as opposed to just that little widget
right there.
Next up these CLIA that we build should definitely have a watch mode of sorts.
So if we start up some testing suite and we then make any change to any file inside of our project I
want to automatically rerun our test suite and re execute all the tests we have.
So essentially this tool should be watching our file or our project directory consistently.
And if there is ever a newly saved added or deleted file we should rerun our tests.
So as you'd guess we're going to leverage some of our knowledge that we got from that earlier project
using that choke in our library and integrate that into our testing framework and then finally we're
going to also have to find all the files inside of our project that end with an extension of test dot
J.S. once we find any files with that name.
We're going to make sure that we execute them and we're going to make sure that we run any tests that
are present inside of those different files.
And so as you guessed this is also going to leverage some that earlier knowledge we got around finding
all the different files and folders inside of some directory OK.
So that's it.
That's the high level requirements but of course at this point I haven't really stated anything around
how we're going to do this implementation.
That's okay.
Let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back next video.
We're going to start to do a little bit of project setup and we'll discuss how we're going to tackle
each of these items.