In this section we're going to start to discuss one of my favorite topics in the world of JavaScript
and that is testing.
I'm really excited for this topic because it is something that's personally I find really interesting.
And as we start to discuss testing we're not only going to learn a lot about the subject but we're also
going to write some really interesting code along the way and also put together a project or two that
I think that you might end up using in the future at some point in time as well.
So with that mind let's get to it.
The first thing we're going to discuss is what the point of testing is and what it is in general.
So throughout this course so many times like a countless number of times throughout this course so far
we've written out some code inside of our Ed we then save the file and went back over the browser refreshed
the page and started to manually click around the screen.
So the idea there was that we were doing some manual testing we were trying to make sure that our code
worked the way we expected when we start to talk about testing and JavaScript.
We're talking about automating that entire process.
So we're going to end up writing code that takes a look at the code that we authored and we're going
to make sure that that code works as expected.
So the end goal here is that we should not have to go into our browser or run our program at the console
for writing a note application and have to like manually click around or manually setup some stuff and
then click around and make sure that it all works as expected.
Instead we're going to just run one command a testing command that's going to start up a little sub
program that we put together and that's going to make sure that all of our code works as expected.
And so at the end of the day this ends up being a huge amount of time savings for us as developers.
Yes of course we're going to invest a pretty good amount of time to write tests in the first place but
then down the line any time that we need to make sure that our app still works as expected we can just
run some tests.
We have already written in the past and we're good to go.
So at the end of the day testing is something that really starts to give you a lot of confidence as
a developer for the project that you're working on.
How many times have you worked on some piece of code and you started to write some stuff out and said
gee you know I don't I don't know about this this feels kind of weird or wrong.
And even if you're working on one part of a little application you might be breaking some code inside
of another part.
This happens all the time for thousands or millions of developers every single day.
So part of testing is to just give you the confidence to make changes to your application and still
say yes this thing this whole app overall still works and I don't have to go and verify every little
feature inside of it to make sure that that is the case.
That's going to take the high level goals of testing.
We want to make sure that we don't have to open up our app do some manual setup and click around just
to make sure that our code works.
Now having said that I want to give you kind of a low down so to speak on testing.
So these are some of my very personal thoughts about testing.
These are not can be shared with everyone in the community.
But hey at some point on this course I got to tell you what I think.
So anyways some quick notes here.
I personally believe that people spend a lot of time just setting up a testing framework like some third
party library to help you write tests more time gets spent on that half the time than people actually
spend writing tests.
So in other words there are a ton of open source solutions out there for writing tests inside of a job
script project.
A lot of these different solutions are kind of challenging and hard to set up.
And so I do see some people on projects spent so much time fighting the testing framework that they're
using trying to get it to do what they want it to do.
But at the end of the day all the different testing frameworks and libraries out there that are available
to us with JavaScript are essentially the same.
And I will prove that to you later.
They're all using some very similar syntax everything eventually at the end the day looks identical.
It's all done with the same style so rather than us spending a whole bunch of time worrying about doing
some setup of some testing library or anything like that.
We're going to take a slightly different approach.
We're going to say you know what.
We don't even have to use a testing library in order to test our code.
Now just so you know in the section we are going to use a very popular testing library.
Eventually I'm going to teach you like technically industry standard way of doing all this stuff but
the same time I want to show you that we don't have to use some testing library to really effectively
test our code OK.
So what does this all mean between the two diagrams.
What am I trying to say.
Well this is what it really comes down to.
I want to give you an outline of what we're going to accomplish inside this section.
So in order to get a better idea of how testing works and not get bogged down in a bunch of setup kind
of stuff or how these different frameworks work we're going to go through this series of steps we're
going to first write a very tiny little node project.
This is going to be essentially like one or two functions that we're going to want to test.
We're then going to figure out how to test that code inside this tiny no node project without any outside
testing library to recognize any outside test or any outside code whatsoever.
We're just going to put our own little custom testing solution together.
We're then going to come back and yes we are going to figure out how to test this stuff with a very
official very common very popular in the community testing framework.
Then after that we're going to take a look at a previous project that we built inside this course.
So a project that we built inside the browser if you did not work on the previous project that we're
going to use that is totally fine.
I'm going to give you a quick overview on how it works.
We're then going to test it once again using a very popular testing library.
So again yes I to teach you you know the industry standard way of doing this.
And then here's the fun part.
We're then going to write our own testing framework from scratch.
And it's going to work in like 80 percent of all projects that you might ever work on.
So it's not going to be like a fully featured testing framework but it's going to be relatively fully
featured enough for like the really important stuff that you really want out of a testing framework
so I don't know if you can tell from my voice but I'm pretty excited about this.
I think it's going to be a lot of fun.
So let's get started.
We're going to come back in the next video immediately start writing a very tiny little note project
and we're going to figure out how to test it without any outside testing library.