All right.
Welcome back.
We've got a big section here it includes a couple different topics.
By the end our main goal is to make each GDP requests from javascript from the client or from the browser
so load data from an API.
Send a request somewhere.
So very important stuff that you do all the time.
If you make single page apps and in the projects that we build later on there's at least a couple examples
where we're working with HDP requests in the browser.
But before we do that we'll talk about promises and how we use promises to manage asynchronous code
and make our life easier.
But before we do that we're going to talk about asynchronous code or async javascript.
What it actually means and in order to do that we need to understand how javascript works behind the
scenes.
At least we don't have to go crazy into detail.
But we need to understand the basics.
So that's where we're going to start.
In this video we're going to talk about something called the call stack.
So the call stack is a tool or a feature of JavaScript.
It's also something you see in tons of other programming languages.
What it does is it helps javascript keep track of where it is in your code.
If you have multiple functions and some of those functions may call other functions which often we have
functions that call functions that call functions that call stack is the mechanism by which the javascript
interpreter keeps track of its place.
It's how javascript knows which function is currently being run which functions are not done yet but
waiting on results or return values.
You can kind of think of it as this diagram here.
If your script with a bunch of function calls is a massive book the call stack is the bookmark or your
finger that you use to figure out where you are to keep track of your current place.
And before we go into any more detail let's talk about these stack part think Call in call stack makes
some sense it has to do with function calls which functions are being called what is or what's been
called what is waiting on a result to come back.
This stack part has to do with a data structure in computer science called a stack Stack is a very simple
data structure.
All you need to know is that just like a stack of books on your your desk or a stack of plates on your
or in your sink the last thing that you put in is going to be on top.
And that will be the first thing that you remove.
So the last thing that was added the most recently placed item in our case this apple on top will be
the first thing out you don't grab from the bottom of a stack of papers you grab from the top the most
recently added thing to that stack.
And that's important because that's how the call stack works.
So we're going to walk through a simple example.
Here's what you need to know when a script has some number of function calls.
The very first function call that the javascript interpreter hits or reaches will be added to the call
stack that function will be carried out.
And if there are any other function calls within that first function they will be added to the top of
the call stack.
And that continues until one of those functions returns a value at which point it's removed from the
stack.
It's gone.
And then the function that came before it will hopefully finish maybe there are some other function
calls in which case those are added to the top of the stack and then removed or popped off as they complete.
I think this will become clear if we have an example.
So on the left I have a couple different functions.
The first one is called is right triangle.
It accepts three different arguments a B and C three different numbers.
And it should return true if a and b if we square them and add them together you get C squared.
A squared plus b squared equals c squared.
So if something is a right triangle the third value here C would be the hypotenuse.
These two would be the other side's K remember what they're called.
But we have two sides on a triangle and then the hypotenuse in a right triangle.
So nine would be three times three sixteen four times four in twenty five five times five.
And that indeed would be a real right triangle nine plus sixteen does equal twenty five.
Okay.
So is right triangle is not a function that just returns something immediately it needs to call other
functions.
It's going to return if the square of a plus the square of B is triple equals to the square of C so
square of a needs to be called and that in turn calls multiply x times x.
So we pass in three multiply three times three which is a different function which returns to values
the product of them.
So when the interpreter encounters the very first function call is right triangle three four or five
it's added to the call stack which is what I'm representing over here and we can't just get a value
back immediately.
There are multiple function calls in here that happen first.
So square of a which is three in our case square of three we'll be the first thing to be added to the
call stack which is what this side is square of three does not turn anything either.
It calls a different function.
Multiply three comma three which I'm showing here.
So then multiply is added to the stack.
So this function has not finished running.
This one has not finished.
This one doesn't call any other functions so it returns three times three which is nine.
And when it returns a value it is removed from the stack.
The last thing in is the first thing out.
So then square of three.
Now has a value back from multiply which was nine.
So it can return that value.
So it's popped off now we end up with is right triangle.
That's the current function that is being executed.
It's been waiting a while because those I mean a while it's relative.
But I had to wait for two other function calls to return.
So now you can kind of fill in the blanks here.
The first part square of a square of three is nine.
We have a value.
Then it moves on.
All right.
Is there another function call.
Yep there is.
Square of four which is B so square of B so square is added to the top of the call stack.
And when I say top it's not really a top and bottom situation it's just a data structure.
Think of it kind of like an array but much simpler.
But I'm just using top and bottom here to help explain visually what's going on.
Like a stack of books.
So square a four doesn't return a value right away at least it has to call multiply for column A four.
So that's added to the top of the stack that does return a value X times Y four times for 16.
So that pops off the stack then square off for now has a value for this.
It fills in that blank sixteen which means that it's done because it returns sixteen and then we fill
in the blank in is right triangle.
We now have this done this done.
And then we have our triple equals square of C square five.
So five is added to the call stack that doesn't return a value yet it has to figure out what multiply
a five comma five is.
So that is the next function call added to the call stack that returns twenty five which means that
square now has value.
So both of those are popped off and then we end up with twenty five here no more function calls.
Now just some simple math.
And actually the order here it probably evaluates this first anyway nine plus 16.
It doesn't actually matter here.
We're just talking about function calls but we end up with nine for sixteen triple equals twenty five.
That is true.
So this function finally returns true at least in this case and it is popped off the stack call stack
is empty.
It returns true and we're done.
So that is a brief intro to the call stack in the next video I'll show you an example of how you can
actually see it using the dev tools or at least a representation of it with your own code and you can
step through it step by step.
All right.
So let's do that next.