We are able to run every function that is passed to in its statement but right now if anything goes
wrong inside of one these supplied functions.
So just be really clear F and right there would be like this functionally passed into the statement
or this function right here.
And if anything goes wrong.
So if we fail an assertion or we have a typo or whatever else that means that our entire test program
is going to fail entirely so this function call right here that's gonna run the IT statement if it goes
bad that's it.
Our entire test is done so we need to make sure that we handle any errors that occur while we are running
an individual test.
In theory an error is going to be occurring like all the time.
Anytime a test fails and as we're writing tests.
Yeah tests fail a lot.
So to handle an error from that let's do a try we're going to wrap that function call with a try catch
like so and we should probably add in some additional kind of reporting to the user.
In addition to this so how about right after we call f n if everything goes okay and we actually get
to the next line of code let's do a console log and just print out to the user that hey we just ran
this statement and everything was good to go.
So for that I'll do having it like a console log I'll use some string interpolation so I can use some
back text right here and I'll say OK.
Meaning this test was just ran successfully and then I'll print out the description like so
let's be really clear.
If anything goes wrong with the test we run that console log is not going to be invoked.
So if the f n throws an error or just horribly goes wrong we're going to automatically skip over the
console log and enter into the catch statement.
So now inside the catch statement if we enter this thing that means something just went wrong with the
test that we had the description for right here.
So let's print out a kind of equivalent error message to tell the user that something just went kind
of haywire they'll do a console dot log right here.
Once again do I set it back ticks.
I'll place an X to say hey something is not quite right.
I'll once again print out the description and then after that we'll do another console log as well and
we'll print out the air and that just occurred okay.
Let's save this and see how we're doing now.
One thing before we actually run this let's make sure we actually have a failing test.
So I'll go back to the.
For each dot test file I can go down to the bottom test right here and on the strict equal I'm gonna
change that three to a four just to make sure that test fails so we can see one test pass top one should
pass in the bottom one should fail yet.
So I'll go back over to me and now if we scroll up we'll see that we get in OK.
We ran that test successfully X that before each is time.
That one failed because we got three not equal to four.
Now the only problem here is that we print out the error message.
It shows this entire stack trace right here which is really just way too much information way more than
we would ever need.
So I think that we should try to kind of just condense down and show like a really abbreviated thing
and say hey here is specifically what went wrong.
You can go figure out what occurred or what happened incorrectly yourself to do so back inside of the
try catch we just set up we can find that console log where we console log out the air and we'll print
out just the errors message the message is essentially just like this part right here a very core message
of the air in addition writing from the error message as the first argument to console log I'm going
to put in a string
forward slash or zap backslash backslash sorry of t this is going to be interpreted by your terminal
as a tab character.
So it's just going to indent the error message make it a little bit easier to read as opposed to the
okays and the Xs is let's say this again run again.
Hey.
All right.
That's definitely a bit easier.
You'll notice that down here we've got that's like three not equal four.
That's not being indented.
We'll take care then just a moment.
But for right now it looks like everything else is turning up pretty good.
Now the next thing we should think about is where other errors might occur inside of our test runner.
The other thing that might go wrong is when we have a require statement right here when we call require.
We're gonna take a look at all the file or all the code inside of that given file.
We're gonna load up the file and execute everything inside of it.
So there actually is another source of errors that could occur inside of our program if we go back over
to our for each test file and go down to the very bottom down here.
Try throwing in just like a bunch of gibberish like so now whenever we require this file that's going
to immediately crash because there is some undefined variable inside of here.
We could also try to serve a kind of syntax error so I could just put in like say I don't know some
number of unbalanced parentheses or curly braces like so.
So definitely big errors inside this file now these errors or these typos we have inside of here are
not going to be caught by the try catch instead we're going to get an error thrown at the require statement
time because that's when the file actually gets executed.
So let's save that for each test file now run team again.
And now we'll see a big error that says hey there's a big typo inside of here.
So this is another thing that we should probably keep from holding up our entire test suite.
So to handle that lets us wrap the require statement inside of a try catch as well
and once again if something goes wrong we can use the same kind of error reporting syntax as what we
had up here.
So I'll do a console dot log I'll do a X and say error loading file
and then is the second argument let's put in the name of the file.
So file dot name and we'll also print out exactly what went wrong or what the type of was.
So I'll do a console log of air dot message.
Let's save this I'll flip back over we'll do it to me.
And there we go.
So now we can see.
OK.
Something really went wrong when we were trying to load that file.
We had a unexpected token now in this case our entire test suite still exits because a typo inside of
a file is really an unrecoverable error but at least now it's very clearly reported to us.
What went wrong and exactly what occurred.
You'll notice in this case we print out the error message.
We just get unexpected token and we're not told where that error actually occurred.
So in this scenario it might actually make sense to display the entire error message so if we do this
now after removing the DOT message from air now we're going to get the full stack trace and we'll tell
us exactly what went wrong.
In addition you'll notice that it actually gives us the entire file path right here and the line that
occurred on that's probably more useful than us trying to insert our own error message right here.
So I think we could get by with just doing a console log of the given error.
All right.
One last safe one last test it's all Tammy again.
And now I'm told very clearly exactly what just went wrong OK.
So this looks pretty good.
Definitely good improvement.
Now we're going to add in a little bit more stuff on the reporting here to make the report that comes
out just a little bit easier.
Let's add that in just a moment in the next video.