Next up more practice.
Let's write a function called Get card and get card is going to accept no arguments.
We don't pass anything in and it will return an object representing a playing card an object that has
a value like K for King or two for two and then a suit.
Clubs diamonds hearts or spades.
So all you need to do is pick one of these random values.
One two three four five six seven eight nine ten.
Jack queen king ace and you can just use letters there.
So return a string here.
So we'll be working with strings like the string one string A for value and then pick a random suit
clubs spades hearts diamonds.
Pick one of those and you return an object that has the key of value in the key of suit.
So you do not need to worry about making this a consistent deck where there's 52 cards and once you've
already picked the king of clubs you can't pick the king of clubs again.
It's entirely random.
There is no continuity.
There's no memory of what you called or what you picked last time.
It's just a random card every time.
So no arguments but return an object which we haven't done very much of if at all at this point.
Give it a shot or just watch.
Here's my attempt.
So I'm going to define a function called Get card.
You don't need to add any parameters and we know we need to pick a value.
We need to pick a suits and then return an object.
So let's start with picking a random value.
There are many ways of getting a random value from a list of values.
If this was all numbers instead of jack queen king and ace it would be easy we would just pick a random
number from one to ten using math at random but because we have these we need to make everything a string.
So the easiest option would probably be to turn this into an array where each element is one of these
strings and I'll make them strings.
OK.
So I made all of them strings that just put quotes around them and then I can make it in array.
I'll keep the commas.
Now we have an array here and let's make this just a variable called values.
OK.
So we have our array of values and then we want to pick one of them randomly and to pick something randomly
from an array.
We need to generate a random number that corresponds to an index.
So starting at zero index of 0 up to whatever this index is.
So we've seen math at random that gives us a decimal.
All we need to do is multiply it by the length of the array.
This is a decimal from 0 to 1 but not including 1.
So then I'm going to multiply that by values dot length and that will give me if my array is ten items
long will give me a decimal number from zero to nine point nine nine nine nine nine nine nine not including
ten.
And that's good because the last index we want is nine but we don't have fractional indices we don't
have decimals.
So we need to get rid of that which we've seen a couple of times now with math dot floor.
So this should give us a random index.
Let's make sure let's just make this a variable called I.D. X and then let's return I.D. X and just
make sure it's working let's call get card we get for twelve eleven ten.
How many items are in here one two three four five six seven eight nine ten eleven twelve thirteen fourteen.
Okay.
So the last index should be 13 which is what we got and we should not be able to get index of 14 which
is looking good.
This is not a conclusive test but we know that the way we've written this there's no way to get 14.
If our array has fourteen items this random number goes from zero to 1 but not including one we multiply
it by 14.
So we're going from zero to thirteen point nine 9 9 9 9 9 9 and then flooring it.
So we go from zero to 13.
All right.
So we now need to use this index to pick one of these values.
So we'll just instead return values of index.
Now this works we're not really completing the objective here.
We're not returning an object but this should at least give us one of those values so we get 5 1 A's
6 1 5 King.
Okay.
So we'll keep this in a variable we'll call it value.
Now we need to do the same thing for the suit.
So I'll add my suits here.
I'll just type this.
We have clubs spades hearts and diamonds.
And then we want to pick one of those and we can do the exact same thing.
We can't name it index.
I guess we could call it high or suit index.
Maybe that's what we'll do and we'll call this one Val index and make sure we replace this year with
Val index.
So now we have two different random numbers this one will go from zero to 13 and then this one will
go from zero to three because we have four items index of three is the greatest index in this array.
Then let's return let's counseled out log the suit that we get.
So we'll make another variable called Suit and set that to suits of suit index and then console that
log value and suit.
Let's see if we get one in undefined 0.
Well this is completely my fault and very stupid.
I never changed this suit index variable.
The code we're running is the exact same code we are using to get the values index at random value.
And I'm still using that values array even though I'm trying to access the suit's array with it.
So I need to adjust this to multiply by suit dot length.
So let's try running it again.
Now I get one clubs King of Hearts two of hearts nine of hearts.
King of Hearts.
OK so that's working.
Now we need to return an object.
This part's Nice and easy.
We just return an object and we're going to set suits to be suits and we'll set value to be value value
is the key and the value is this value.
Here it's a confusing sentence.
Suit is the key and resetting it to whatever suit we got randomly selected from the suits array.
Some of you might be aware of a shorter syntax to return an object where the key and the value have
the same name.
We will cover that later so we'll just ignore it for now.
OK so this works.
There's nothing wrong with this but we are repeating some logic.
We're picking a random number from this array.
So I'm going to take another stab at this but I'm actually going to write a second function.
Anytime we're repeating functionality we're doing something multiple times.
It's a good indication that you could make a new function and use that function here so we could make
a function called you get random element or pick which picks a random element from an array.
So we pass in an array and then we get a return value where some random element has been selected so
we could do that.
Let's call it Pick.
Function pick accepts an array and it should return a random element from an array.
So if it accepts this array we'll give it a parameter of a R.
That's the name we need to pick a random number that is within a Rs bounds which we've already seen
how to do any of these here.
So let's just copy this move it up.
Math top floor math out random time and then a r dot length the length of the array.
It could be 100 items it could be 20 items.
That's going to be our index so we'll make this variable called index and then we'll simply return array
at that index.
So if we try calling pick on an array of a comma B we'll get B or A each time randomly and if we tried
it on a different array like 1.
Let's not do strings.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 blows my array.
We get a random number each time from that array.
So we've now made this reusable function called Pick and let's use it down here.
So we no longer have to duplicate all of this code.
In fact we could get rid of pretty much all of this.
Let's start with the value we'll get rid of this here.
Now we'll set value to be pick our array called values.
So pick one of these
no semicolon then there and then we'll do the same thing for suits.
We have our suits variable and then we don't need to generate an index we'll just say suit is equal
to pick from suits.
Great.
Let's test it out.
Get card.
It's working two of diamonds six of diamonds.
King of Clubs two of diamonds.
And on and on and on.
We could even refactor this a bit more.
We don't really have to make these separate variables if we don't want to.
We could just do right in line pick value and pick suits just like that.
And now we can get rid of these two lines as well.
We simply have our variable declarations and then we're returning an object where value the key is set
to the return result of picking a value from this from our pick function and then suit.
The property is set to the same exact thing but with these suits array.
This needs to be suits plural for passing that into pick.
This gives us some random element from suits that return value is then used to set suit.
Let's test it out again.
Value is not defined values.
Try that again.
It needs to match the name of the array and the name if this array.
And now it's working.
It's relatively short.
The longest part is this hideous array that my editor is deciding to put on separate lines.
I have a preference that says for a super long array.
Make sure you spread it out onto different lines.
But on such short elements it's kind of ugly.
All right.
So I'll stop here.
There are many other ways you could approach this instead of turning all the values into an array.
We could have put them all in a single string and turn that string into an array using code dynamically.
We'll see a similar example.
Something relatively similar in the next exercise we're about to do.
But before I go I just want to call your attention to this part here.
We had some duplicated functionality we were doing the same thing twice.
A different array we were picking from First we're picking from values then we're picking from suits
but the same process.
So we moved it into a new function.
It doesn't really change anything about how your code behaves.
It's the same logic we've just made it generic.
We've generalized it into a function called pick which allows us to shorten our code and also it becomes
more readable.
When you look at it it's not just we're actually not shortening things in the long term we added more
lines.
I think if you were to count the total lines but it's much easier to look at and understand what's going
on.
Pick a value and pick a suit rather than just a bunch of variables and a bunch of master randoms.
We just have it up top.