Okay.
Our class timer's looking pretty good.
Believe it or not our start in paws methods are just about complete.
We're not going to really add any additional code to them so we're not going to start to focus our attention
on the tick method right here.
Remember the tick method is going to run once every second because we set up the interval to call it
once every 1000 milliseconds the inside of the tick method we're going to start to want to figure out
what we want to do every second.
I think that every second there's probably would be a pretty obvious thing we want to do.
We probably are going to want to reach into the DOM find whatever the current time is right there and
subtract one from it.
So if we start off with 18 seconds and then that tick method runs we'll probably want to decrease it
down to 17 then 16 15 14 13 and so on.
I want to remind you really quickly that this input or this element right here that's going to display
the current time is actually going to be a kind of invisible text input.
The reason we're making it a text input is that a user can very easily reach inside there and change
the current time or the duration of the timer so they could enter and three hundred and then hit play
and that would count down our timer from 300 seconds.
Now in this video I want to focus on a really interesting question.
Well at least it's interesting to me I suppose the question I want to focus on is inside the tick method.
We clearly at some point in time are going to have to write some code that looks like this.
This is gonna be pseudocode.
Don't write this just a quick example.
So we're definitely going to have to write out something like time remaining is time remaining minus
one.
Something like this to countdown our timer from whatever the current time is.
Subtract one second and then update the variable or the value of time remaining so we're going to write
out a line of code that looks like that.
But here's the interesting question and this is what I want to explore in this video.
Where does the variable time remaining live.
In other words where is this data actually being stored there's two kind of obvious or different ways
we can solve that.
Let's take a look at a diagram and understand that two different places that we can store the information
about how much time is remaining on our timer so the first way is kind of slightly more obvious one
I think and this is where if I would like really grilled you and asked you to figure this out this is
probably what you might come up with.
So an option number one in deciding where to store the time left on our timer we might decide to create
an instance variable on our timer instance called something like time left.
Then every single time that tick method ran we could subtract one from that value and then take that
value and update our text or submit our input element with it.
So in other words when we run it tick We'll count down twenty nine to twenty eight then take the value
of twenty eight and throw it into the input element does some code that looks like that might look like
this.
I'm going to very quickly write it.
I am going to delete this code very quickly so you don't have to write this as well.
So he might write out inside a constructor something like this dot time left equals thirty.
So whenever we create a class or a instance of timer our default value for time left will be 30 representing
30 seconds that inside of tick.
We could do something like this dot Time left is this dot time left minus one and then we could do something
like take our input element remember we've got a reference to it right there.
Duration input so we could say this dot duration input dot value is this dot time left.
So again take the current time subtract one from it then take that value and throw it into the duration
input and I would update the text on the screen.
So this is a definitely way that works without a doubt.
This is a method that works.
I'm going to delete this code really quickly and we're gonna take a look at option number two for where
we stored this data so in option number two we're going to kind of invert this control flow rather than
having our timer instance have seen some definition of what the time left is and stored inside the input
element or update the input element.
We're going to instead have the current time live inside of the input element so whatever the input
elements value is that is the time remaining.
And then at any time that our timer instance needs to know how much time is remaining it will reach
into the input element.
Figure out what the current value is.
So we're going to essentially take the value out of that input element and bring it back over to our
timer instance
so why would we ever go with this approach right here approach number one seemed like it was kind of
obvious.
Of course we've got a timer instance.
It's got some time left.
It's an instance variable really easy to get at that value right away.
So why would we ever use this approach right here.
Well the reason that we might use this approach is that it makes some you X or some actual like interactions
with the user a little bit easier to handle.
Remember at some point in time we want the user to be able to type in a new text value inside this input
right here.
So we want them to be able to click in there and type in like give me a timer that countdown counts
down from 10.
If we were storing all of our data inside of our class we would want to set up an event handler and
watch for any time a user changes that value.
So if user changes that from 300 down to 10 we would have to have an event listener that watches for
a changed event on that input when that occurs.
We would have to take that change value and go and update our time left but with this approach we don't
have to worry about any event handlers at all on that input element because anytime you want to figure
out what the current time remaining is we can just reach directly in get that value pull it back out
and make use of it inside of our timer instance and that's sounds like a very small and simple thing
but I just want to suggest that's maybe one reason that we would want to just have our timer instance
store the value or the time remaining inside of that input element.
There are going to be some other interactions that get a little bit easier as well when we start to
take this approach is in this approach but they're not going to be quite as obvious until we get a little
bit further along with this application now just at a higher level.
I want to mentioned that option number two we refer to this as storing our data inside of our dom.
So our application has some like critical data that is required to make it work correctly and we are
storing that data inside of different dom elements with option number one we're storing all of our data
inside of our javascript code.
So we've got a job skip class right here.
That class or that instance of the class has the data that is critical to making our application work
now.
Option number one is a little bit more popular these days.
All right.
To be totally honest you option one is definitely more popular these days.
Option number two used to be really popular.
So like years ago this used to be the way that we wrote javascript applications but it's definitely
pivoted towards option number one.
More recently.
Having said that we're going to use Option number two inside this application.
And the reason for that is I want you to see what this approach looks like.
I want you to see some of the downsides.
I want you to understand why we used to write code like this as javascript engineers years ago and why
we now instead use Option number one and stored data inside of our javascript code instead Dawn sorry
to kind of show you not the most modern or like technically correct way to do this stuff or what's really
popular right now but again it is important for you to understand why we take one approach over the
other hand the easiest way to do that is to write out the code in that older approach so you can see
some of the problems that start to arise.
So it's all in the mind.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to start to update our class and make sure that it can
very easily read some data out of that input element to figure out how many seconds are left on our
timer and then make sure that whenever our tick method gets called we're going to update the value of
that input element and subtract one from it.
So quick pause right here and I'll see you in just a minute.