Well our applications all finished up but it's kind of boring only being able to use it on our local
machine.
So in this video we're going to figure out how we can deploy this application to the open Internet.
We're going to deploy it using a free service called now so we're gonna go over to our terminal and
let's figure out how to do this.
Once at my terminal I'm going to navigate to my project directory.
I'm going to run the command NPCs now.
Now if you try to run this command and you see an error message.
Chances are you do not have no J.S. installed on your local machine.
There is another video inside of this course that will tell you how to install know J.S. to go and find
that video.
Walk through the installation process then come back here and try to run this command again so I can
run it right now.
And after a brief pause I'll be asked to log in.
We have to enter a valid email here.
This is going to send us a confirmation email that's going to allow us to deploy our application.
So I to put in my email and then after a brief pause I'm going to check my email and I should get an
email that tells me how to log into this account.
It's going to look something like this right here.
I'm going to pull up this e-mail.
I'm going to click on verify and then after a quick pause I'm told OK.
Everything is good to go so this service is then going to log me in and I'm going to once again run
MP.
Now once I do it's going to take a look at the different project files inside of my current working
directory.
It's then going to bundle all those different files up and send them over to the now service that's
going to make my application publicly available at the address that I get printed out right here.
So I can then take that address.
Go back over to my browser and paste it into a new tab.
And just like magic I'll see my deployed application.
So this is a link that you can actually share with your friends and they can see your app deployed.
Create messages and share messages as well.
So I'm gonna put in here my application is deployed I get my link and notice how we're getting the proper
link for our deployed application.
Copy that.
Open up another new browser tab visit that link and I'll see my application is deployed and then I can
once again hit create my own secret message to go back to create a message of my own.
Okay.
That's pretty much it.
Pretty straightforward deployment process.
Using the app now service is about as easy as it possibly gets.
So now that we've got this publicly available feel free to share with your friends and create your own
secret messages.
That's pretty much it for this application.
So let's pause here and continue on our next app in just a moment.