The next logical operator we have is.
Or so.
Or uses the pipe character which is located above the return key at least on every keyboard I've used
you hold shift and for me it's on the backslash character so shift and then backslash gives you those
pipes so those are not once or not ls they're not slashes they are pipes.
So you need to have them in a row and or is similar to and in that it takes two sides left and right
but it works differently if either side is true the entire thing is considered true so if we have true
or false.
Only one of them needs to be true for the whole thing to be true.
So if both of them are true that's fine.
It's not saying only one can be true it just needs one.
At a minimum to be true the left or the right.
And if that happens to be both of them if it's one of them it doesn't matter.
But in the event that neither side is true so we have false or false the entire thing is considered
false.
So again this is not how you would usually use it neither is this but this is slightly more complicated.
We're evaluating two expressions.
So is one equal or one not equal to one.
That would be false because one is equal to one.
So we have false or 10 equals 10.
That's true false or true is true zero or undefined.
Now remember we talked about truthiness and falseness.
Zero is considered falsely undefined is fallacy.
So we end up with false or false.
Neither side is true so the whole thing is false because the logical or.
Then we have the one in the middle 10 divided by two equals five.
That is true or no which is false falsely so true or false that evaluates to true.
So let's see an example where you would use this in practice.
Let's say we were running a community theater program and we're at the box office and recharging tickets
for people who are adults not children and we're defining children as people under the age of 6 and
senior citizens also get in for free.
So if you are one of those categories either under 6 years old or over 65 you get in for free.
Otherwise you don't you have to pay 10 dollars.
We could use or so we would write something like this and close it down a bit let age equals let's go
with 78.
If age is greater then let's go with a less than one first if age is less than 6 or age is greater than
or equal to sixty five at least in the US I think Sixty five year olds are considered seniors.
Depends on the place we'll consider log you get in for free and then we'll have our else you must pay.
Okay so we have two things.
And if either one is true you get in for free.
If age is under 6 you're free if age is under 65 or greater than or equal to 65.
You also get it for free.
Let's see what we get.
You get it for free.
If we change it to three years old you also get it for free.
But if you're 30 you have to pay.
So if we were to rewrite this without using the logical operator it would be something like if age is
less than six you get it for free.
And then we could also have an else if age is greater than or equal to sixty five.
You get it for free.
Else you have to pay.
So when we use or we can combine multiple pieces into one line or one expression and again one side
is all that is required in order to pass go in order for the expression to be true in our code to run.
We can also chain multiple boards together just like we can with and let's do a quick example.
There are many many colors out there in the world but fans of mine or longtime students know the best
color of all time is without a doubt purple.
So let's write some code that checks to see if the color is purple or if it's a shade of purple like
orchid or violets.
We'll go with three to start.
So if it's one of those we'll consider that log.
Congrats you picked purple or something like that.
So we need a variable.
We'll go with light color equals something.
We'll fill it in if color is equal to purple or color is equal to lilac or color is equal to Violet
or some other color.
Then we'll come to that log.
Great choice.
We could keep changing these on and on and make a very long statement.
But as you can see here colors empty string we don't get anything.
Let's set it to Violet.
Great choice.
So only one of these has to be true.
And in our case violet color was equal to Violet.
Even though these were false this was true.
So we print.
Great choice.
You can chain them together although there is a much better way of checking one value.
Like if we had a color and we had 10 valid options we wanted to make sure it was one of those options.
You would not need to change this 10 times.
There are other tools you can use once we talk about arrays and some other built in methods that come
with javascript that would make your life easier.
But we're not there.
So we would write it like this.
We're still just focusing on or so we've seen and and or they are similar in that they take a left and
a right side.
We often use them in conditional statements inside the print but they're very different in how they
behave when we have.
And both sides must be true in order to move on when we have or just one needs to be true.