Well we can definitely open up our project directory and then inside there do a node index start J.S.
and it looks like hey that's pretty much the whole project.
Yeah that's what we said we wanted to do.
We wanted to print out all the different files and folders inside of a given directory.
I can even go up on directory and then do a node list index.
J.S. hey still works.
I can go up even one further directory and do Rod list index dot J.S..
Of course this might command right here.
Very likely is not going to work for you.
I have a workspace directory called prod.
That's why I'm able to run this command.
But either way I'm going to run it and sure enough.
I once again see all the different files and folders inside this directory so it's clear that our program.
Well kind of works.
There's just one little issue we saw just a month ago as I did that last command that in order to run
our program from a very far removed directory I had to run node and then list out the exact path to
get back to this list project folder so if I wanted to run our program from some very far removed directory
on my machine I would have to end up typing out some really complicated path right here to navigate
back to the list directory.
Compare that to the normal command that we used to list different files and folders on a UNIX based
system we can run just simply s and everything just kind of magically works so it's very clear right
now that the Ellis command is way better than our implementation.
We're going to use the Ellis command.
Way more than we would ever run node and then tried to navigate back over to this project directory
just to run our program in this video and the next one we're gonna figure out how to fix this up we're
gonna figure out some way to be able to run simply an L s short for node L S.
So this is a little command that you and I are going to implement we're going to be able to run that
and have it print out the different files and folders on our machine and you can see that it already
works for me because I've already wired it up on my computer.
I just want to give you a quick demo so that's the goal I want to be able to run simply MLS and have
it you essentially do the same thing as that right there running node and then the really long path
to our project.
So how are we going to do this.
Well it's a multi-step process.
The first thing we're going to do is going to seem a little bit not related inside of my project directory.
I'm going to run the command NPM in it Dash y when I run this command.
It's going to generate a new file inside of my project directory.
This is a very special file that you're going to get extremely used to as a javascript developer.
It's going to go back over to my editor and find the new file that was generated.
It is called package dot Jason right there.
We'll talk about what this file is used for.
OK.
So this file overall describes some of the different qualities of your project as you can see right
away.
It lists out the name of your project a version the primary file inside of your project keywords your
author or your name right there as the author and the license of the project as well decides that there
are two extremely important uses for this package shot Jason file that you need to be aware of.
The first one is the script section right here inside the script section we're going to end up writing
out some different little essentially mini programs more or less.
These are going to be a little tiny scripts that do some automated tasks inside of our project.
So a example might be what you see right here even though it doesn't have an actual implementation.
We might create a script that automatically run some test inside of our project.
You might also have a another script that will try to just start up our project in a very special special
way or we might have another script that tries to package up or build our project and deploy it to some
outside Web site as well.
There are many different purposes or scripts so we add into this section and we're going to get some
really good experience with that script section later on INSIDE THE COURSE.
So we won't worry about it just yet.
Just be aware that we are going to eventually come back here and essentially write in some little mini
PROGRAMS CUSTOMIZED for just our project.
The other extremely important thing that the package that Jason File does is record dependencies that
our project has.
So if we ever decide to install someone else's code or a dependency into our project it will be automatically
recorded inside this package not just on file.
The reason that it gets recorded in here is so that if we ever decide to share our project with someone
else they can run a single command.
They will take a look at all the dependencies that get listed inside this file and automatically install
it for them as well.
That is another thing that we're going to get a lot of experience with very shortly to so that is the
primary goal of package star Jason and record some information about your project and the two most important
things are the script section and the dependency section which again we don't have yet but we will have
very shortly.
The other thing that we can do inside this package that Jason File is setup a little configuration section
that will allow us to do exactly what I just mentioned.
It will allow us to run some commands like whatever arbitrary command we want to call it and have it
run or trigger some code inside of our project to do so.
I'm gonna go back over to my pack and start Jason File at the very bottom here.
I'm going to put a comma at the end of license and then I'll do a set of double quotes.
I'll say in I'll open up an object I'll put another set of double quotes I'll say any less and then
a colon and index start j ust like so this section right here means that we have some binary or essentially
some executable thing that we want to be able to run inside of our project the name of that program
is an L S.
Again this stands for node l s like the normal ls command I made up this little name right here.
You can have this be whatever you want.
So for you if you want to build to run something like node dash L S at your terminal and have that printout
or essentially run our program you would change that key right there to node dash unless you can have
it be whatever you want.
I'm just going to choose to use an LSA because I think it's I don't know kind of reasonable then as
a value we specify index not g yes that means that whenever we run an L S at our terminal we want to
run the index stuff.
J.S. file okay.
So that's going to step one.
Unfortunately this is not the only thing we have to do.
There's one or two other steps.
Let's save this file for right now we'll take a pause come back in just a moment and do the other stuff
we need to do in order to run that L and L S command from our command line so could possible see you
in just a minute.