Back to our products listing right now we can show the different product titles but they're all kind
of ugly in nature.
In addition they don't really give us any links to the ability to edit create or delete any products
whatsoever as well so attached to this lecture.
You're going to once again find a template file you should see a zip file named something like AECOM
0 7 2 template.
That's it.
So inside of here is an upgrade to his products listing page.
Once again the only thing I've added in is a little bit of each e-mail and a couple of classes just
to apply some styling to what you see on the screen.
So I'm going to double click that file to extract it and I get an indexed J.
J ust file out.
That's going to be a replacement for our products index not J.S. file inside of our views directory
it's going to take that new file once again I'm going to drag and drop it into my editor I'm going gonna
take everything inside that new file copy it go to my old one delete everything inside there and then
paste you'll notice that the code structure inside of here is still just about identical.
We are still mapping our products array.
We get out some rendered products we join that together into one big string and then throw that stuff
into this table element.
So going to save this update what makeover refresh and we should see something a little bit closer to
this.
Now it might look like this kind of has all of our work done but once again there's still a couple of
things inside of here that we need to wire up.
In particular you'll notice that if we click on this edit button right here nothing really happens.
If we click on delete nothing happens and if we click on it new product.
Okay.
That one actually does work.
But needless to say we still have to put together this link to edit and link to delete as well.
So let's get started on this edit functionality in the next video.