In this video we're going to generate our verticals rate and our horizontals rate.
Once again quick reminder on what both those do so we have our verticals
array and horizontals
the verticals array is going to keep track of every vertical we while we have so those right there.
Remember that these arrays are gonna have some different dimensions than the grid array.
So in this case if we have a three by three verticals which only represents those labeled segments right
there is going to have three rows.
So there is one row there is row two and row three but in that side of there it's going to have two
columns.
So to start off we would have false false false false false and false.
So then if we started off randomly right there and decided to move right there we would find the corresponding
entry inside of verticals that represents that wall segment.
So that would be that one right there we would take out that false and update it to true instead then
horizontals is very similar nature horizontals is going to keep track.
Let's change to green here.
Of all these horizontal segments so likewise it's also going to start off as a 2D array it's going to
have two rows 0 1 and road 2 and then inside those two rows it will have three columns.
So we have false false false like so.
So then we can imagine if we started off in this cell right here on the very bottom left hand side the
matching element inside of our horizontals right.
Is that right there.
If we then go up we would change that to true to say that there is now an opening right there which
would represent something like that like so okay.
So with this reminder let's now go back over to our code.
We're gonna create verticals and horizontals and again the big thing we have to keep aware of or stay
aware of here is that these are gonna have slightly different dimensions.
The Andy grid array gets a makeover I accrete my array of verticals.
I'm going to create this array inside were with the same style that we used just a moment ago.
So for verticals I'm going to make an array as we just discussed this thing is going to have three rows
inside of it so the outer array is going to have length three because one two and three tobacco over
here are going to create an array with like three and then going to fill that up with no and then map
over those values and inside I'll create a new array.
Then here's where things get interesting.
The inner array is going to have like to this array right here.
Two elements to it.
So I'm gonna make sure that I do a map and I'm going to get an array with two elements inside.
I'm going to fill that thing up with the value of false.
Like so now I can repeat the same process for horizontals as well I'll do an array here once again horizontals
is only gonna have two rows so the outer array will have two elements to it.
I'm going to fill that up with annual value because we're going to replace it in just a moment.
I'm going gonna map I'll do an array and I bet you can guess what goes there.
The inner arrays on horizontals has 1 2 3 elements so I'm going to go back over.
I'm gonna make sure this thing has three elements.
I'm going to fill that thing up with false All right.
So let's now do a console log of verticals and just make sure we generate the thing correctly.
So I'll flip back over refresh it.
So I got verticals as the three rows and it's got the two columns for each that maps up perfectly because
we are representing that segment that segment all these like so that we can update our console log and
instead do a horizontals save it go back over to the refresh check this thing out gate and this looks
good as well.
So we're looking at horizontals Now remember that's gonna represent that that that that that and that.
And so we definitely want to have row one road two in each of those is gonna have three false values
inside of it okay.
So it looks like we've generated all of our data successfully Believe it or not this right here this
is definitely the hardest part.
Without a doubt just understanding with the purpose of these arrays it's now we have this stuff together
the rest the code we have to write is actually going to be kind of surprisingly easy.
Believe it or not it's really not the worst thing in the world.
There is one last change I want to make to this code however.
So quick pause we're gonna come back and you'll know so we've got the value 3 and 2 inside of here all
over the place.
Is going to make sure that we extract that out into a configuration variable just like we did with height
and with up here a little bit ago.
So quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.