All right so let's try building something with what we've learned so far.
We still haven't talked about events and making things interactive responding to input clicks drops
drags all that stuff.
But we do have the ability to create elements to manipulate existing elements.
And we're going to take advantage of that.
So I've included a starter file if you want to follow along so you can have the initial state.
What we're going to build is an NBA score table like what we have here based off of whatever input data
we get.
We could imagine it's coming from an API but I've actually hardcoded some game data where we have different
games.
It's an array.
We have an away team and a home team.
Each team has the team name.
Actually it's the city not the whole team points and is winner.
And what I want to do is create a table like this dynamically so not hardcoded in our each demo but
imagine we had 100 different games or we had 100 different there's not 100 teams but a bunch of different
teams.
We want to iterate over this data and create a table and we don't know how long it will be.
We don't know which cells are rich which rows will be green versus red.
We don't know what the values will be.
So we'll create dynamic elements and append them to the page using the dom.
So I live in the Bay Area.
We'll be doing Warriors games.
And I have named this array Warriors games.
But this should work with whatever data you pass in and eventually we'll see if we could connect something
like this to an API and get data coming from an API somewhere at NBA stats or a Premier League or La
Liga or whatever the sports league is we can get information and do something with it and make it visual
show something on the dom.
So what we're going to do to start is ignore the table tables are really annoying and each.
They're my least favorite things to create.
I mean if you inspect the markup here if you haven't made tables before you can see just how dense this
stuff is to make a single table we've got so many different nested rows and T.D. and T bars and teaches
and tea bodies and tables and table headers.
It's just uh it's a little overwhelming to have to create all of those elements with JavaScript and
append them.
I think it would bog down the important stuff here.
So we're gonna start with just a simple list.
Each game will be a list.
It will have the score.
It will have the home team.
So we'll start by making a simple list something like this where we'll have let's do it in our HDMI
file we'll have a UL an ally for each game and the home team will come second.
So the away team let's say it's a Houston at Golden State.
So we want to display it in the order where we have a wait team at sign home team.
So that will be dynamic.
We also want to have the score.
We have the away team score and then the home team.
So let's say Houston won this game one hundred to ninety four.
I want to bold this element here of the winning score so one hundred beats ninety four.
So dynamically figure out which team won or which number is higher.
Give it a bold tag.
And if we look at this right now it's not very impressive.
But then we also want to give a green or red color to this element depending on which perspective we're
looking at it from.
And like I said I live in the Bay Area.
So we will be looking at this as Warriors fans.
So this element would be red.
It's a loss for Golden State just like we have here.
So we have green on the games where Golden State won.
But if we went to the table the corresponding table for the Houston Rockets it's down here.
We have red for that very same game.
So different perspective.
Same data and we'll start with the perspective of warriors or the Warriors already.
So I'm going to delete this.
I think I'm going to start by adding in a well that I can append my data to.
We could also do this dynamically.
Maybe that's a better way of doing it.
Fine we'll do it from our app J.S..
We have our starter data.
A simple array with a couple of objects each object represents a game away team and home team.
And then each of those team objects has team points and is winner.
So why don't we start with something simple.
Let's get each team to print out or something like that as an ally on the page.
The first thing I will do is make a new element.
So I'll make the container.
We can call this or maybe just parent you all parents equals document that create elements of you all.
So that is where we will append a bunch of allies to.
And then what we want to do is iterate over all of these games so we can do that using a four of or
a for loop or for each.
But I'll do four let game of and I called my data Warriors game.
No Warrior Games.
What do they call it or winners games.
All right.
So for each game we want to extract home game or home team in a team.
They all have a home team and an away team.
So let's grab that from the object using our favorite D structuring concept home team comma away team
equals Game.
Game is each individual object for each element in the array called Warriors games.
And we could start simple we'll console that log home team dot let's actually let's do away team.
So away team DOT team which is the name of the team or the city actually or in the case of Golden State.
It's not even a city.
There is no as far as I know there's no Golden State City away team that team and then home team DOT
team let's run it.
And in our console there we go.
So we have Golden State at Houston Golden State Houston twice and then Houston at Golden State Houston
at Golden State.
And then after the first four games.
So this is the standard playoffs as far as I know in the NBA.
You have two games.
Home or away.
And then you flip for two games and then you alternate.
So that's accurate.
We're printing out the correct away team and home team.
Now let's start by making an ally.
So we want an ally for each game.
If that's what we're gonna do instead of a table at least to begin with so we'll make our new ally.
We'll call this game.
Ally equals documents that create elements.
Ally.
All right.
So we have that done next.
Let's go ahead and show some of this information.
Let's get the first part of the team names showing up.
So I'm gonna have Golden State at Houston.
If Houston is the home team Golden State is the away team.
So I want to take this format away team at home team and add that as the inter text on my ally.
We'll start there.
So game ally Scott enter text equals and I'll do a template literal.
Display the away team DOT team and then at sign and then another dollar sign.
Curly braces for home team DOT team.
So that should make me the ally and give me some inner text on the fly but nothing will show up because
we're not appending it.
And what does it not like my 97 0.
Obviously not valid javascript there.
So we won't see anything.
We need to append each ally to the well we've made are you well we'll append to that you will.
And we have a couple of choices we could do a pen child.
We could also use the newer append method.
But in this loop for each ally game Ally I'm going to call you L. parent.
So this is the empty Well I've created I'm now appending one ally and then next time through will append
a second ally and it will have some data about the away team and the home team.
So you add parent dots append child.
I'll do a pen child just in case some of you are using Internet Explorer.
Even though I prefer append and will append the game ally now is this enough.
Will we see anything.
No we will not because the.
Well we created is still not associated with the page at all.
It exists in JavaScript it's an object it has a bunch of children but we're never actually appending
it to the page.
So if I just wanted to show up in the body we could append it to the body.
That's fun where we could present it to the body to make it a little nicer.
I guess that's nothing wrong with that.
Put it above our script.
So I will select the body which is easy.
Document dump body.
I don't need to use query selector although I could query selector of body document dump body dot prepare
and if you are in i.e. you can just do a pen child but pre pens you l parent.
Let's see what we get here.
Hey there we go.
Golden State at Houston Golden State.
Houston.
Houston at Golden State.
Bob Bob Barr.
We now have what is this 7 Yes 7 allies appended to you Well appended to the body and none of that is
there when the page loads we're constructing it from scratch.
All right so next let's work on the scores what we want to do is first we can just display the home
team and the away team score I'll do the same format so a away team dot points dash home team dot points
and I'll start by making it its own string so I'll just call this concept score line equals and we want
to do this in its string template literal just to make it easier we'll do away team dot and then we
have points
and then I'll just do the dash and then home team dot points as well it's called points yes it is.
All right so we have a string now and we could console dot log that string to see the score line each
time through it won't be showing up on the actual page but here we go.
That looks accurate.
So what we want to do next is get that in the ally as well.
And we have a bunch of different options for how we actually approach this.
I think what will probably be easiest is if we just make two strings and then set the inner text at
once with those two strings.
So I'll make a new variable here and I'll call this one concept.
What do we want to call this team names maybe and then score line and then we can set game ally dot
enter text.
Or you could do text content equals.
And then I'll do another string template literal.
And add in my team names with a space.
And then again with the score line.
So instead of doing these together in one line it's kind of ugly to see all of those string template
literal brackets and dollar signs.
So I'll break it up into two variables with names and then add those in.
Okay.
Is it gonna work.
All right.
Looks like it's working so we can double check the first game.
Golden State had won 19.
Houston had 1 0 6.
Let's double check up top 1 19 for Golden State and Houston 1 0 6.
Golden State was the away team Houston was the home team and we were displaying it correctly.
Golden State away at Houston at home.
Okay next we have a couple of choices.
Why don't we start by selecting the score that has won the winning score and bolding it.
Which do they do that.
And they don't even do it on Wikipedia.
We're adding in functionality so we'll show the winning score with a bold tag around it.
So we're gonna have to calculate who won.
And that part's pretty easy.
We'll just compare the two away teamed up points and home teamed up points.
Why don't we start by cleaning this up a tad.
We'll need access to a way teamed up points and home teamed up points for a couple of different lines
because we need to calculate the winner and then display the points as well and figure out which class
to apply.
So I'm going to d structure team and points out of each object.
Out of a team and out of home team.
Now this is kind of annoying because to use these structuring I would do team and points equals home
team and that works fine.
But now I have the exact same thing for a weight team and that means I'll have team and points and then
I'm creating another variable called Team and points so we can use this syntax we saw earlier with D
structuring if we want to where we grab a particular value out of an object and we give it a new name.
So why don't we call this one home team with an H and H points.
So each team in H points and then away team and away points
okay.
And then we'll use that instead of away team doubt team we'll just do a team each team and then a points
and age points.
And nothing should have changed if everything went well.
We get the exact same output but now we have these variables.
I can reuse instead of having to access away teams out team away team that points over and over.
Not a huge change and also the way my V.S. code is formatting this it makes it look like a lot more
work than it actually is.
It's only one line really so we're going to come down here now and compare the two points so we'll have
a way points greater than home points.
Or we could do the other way around.
But if a waypoint is greater than home points then we know that a way team has won right.
So we'll do an if statement here.
If that's the case and if a waypoints does beat out home points then what we want to do is on our score
line.
We want a bold tag around eight points and we can just add that like this not right here but we can't
do it.
We can wrap away points in a bold tag so the simplest way to do this is if a waypoints is greater than
home points.
We'll take scoreline and just put it here on the same line or we can do it on multiple lines.
Doesn't matter and we'll add the bold tag around the first part.
The away points right here so we'll put our bold tag the closing bold tag and then we could have an.
Else we'll do the opposite concept score line equals and we'll move the bold tag over here around H
points and that should work.
We'll talk about refactoring this in the next video we'll see that we could move this to a function.
We don't have to declare contour score line.
We're not declaring it twice only one of these ever runs but we don't need to do it this way.
There are other options.
There is one problem with the way I've written this.
See if you can figure it out without running it.
It doesn't have to do with the actual data or the logic.
It has to do with scope we're using const and we remember that constant but are both blocks scoped.
So if I define score line in here it's scoped to this block so I can't use it down here.
So to fix that we can't just say const scoreline like this and not define it and then update it.
And the reason for that is made very clear you cannot initialize a concept or you can't declare a concept
variable without a value const high.
That doesn't work but with light I can.
So that's what we'll do for now until we write this as a separate function so we'll say scoreline just
exists.
It doesn't have a value then if a waypoints is greater than home points.
This is what score line should be.
Otherwise it should be this and then we'll appended.
And right now we're doing inter text which is not really going to work the way we want.
We end up with the B tag just being rendered as text.
So we'll do enter our AGM I'll try again haha.
There we go.
So let's verify.
1 19 is greater than 1 0 6.
That's correct.
It should be bolded 127 bolded 126.
Awesome.
So that's working.
The next step is to add a background color.
So from the Warriors perspective the first game should be green because the Warriors won the next game
should be red because the Warriors lost.
Houston won and we'll do that for each one.
So what I'm going to do is create a class and my class I'll have to actually win where I'll set background
color to be.
We could just start with red.
I think I want an RG be a color which will be full red.
No green no blue but I only want maybe like point three on the alpha channel so a transparent red and
it looks dark here.
But it's because the background of my editor is dark.
If we actually saw that color it's a transparent red.
So on a white background it looks sort of pinkish and then I'll duplicate this and make a loss class.
This one will be similar.
Oh why am I doing red for win.
That should be the other way around.
I want zero red.
I want 255 green and zero blue and then loss should be red.
Okay so I have those two classes.
Now we just need to decide which one to show which one to apply to the entire ally.
Now to figure out if the Warriors won a game because I'm doing this from the Warriors perspective.
I want the green win class to be applied.
If whichever object the Warriors are whichever one has Golden State rather than the Warriors Golden
State is what we're looking for.
We'll check if is winner is true then we'll apply this class of win.
Otherwise we apply loss so to figure out which team is Golden State.
We can do it in a sort of clunky way.
It's not that bad but we'll check just one of the teams.
It doesn't matter.
Home team or away team doc team and check if it's golden state.
So let's try it here.
Home team which we already have that variable.
Each team that we extracted or D structured each team equals Golden State and I'll do this as a ternary
question mark.
And if that's the case then the variable we want.
I'll call this warriors.
This will be a reference to the Warriors object here and we'll go with Warriors equals H team Golden
State.
If that's the case then the Warriors object it should be the home team.
Object this entire home team otherwise we'll set it to the away team
and if I console that log warriors right now we should get the Warriors information each time through
whether it's a way or home we should still see Golden State golden state.
Great.
So now we've identified Golden State we have a reference to it then we can simply access is winner so
warriors dot is winner is going to be true or false.
Now if it's true then we'll apply the class of win ups that should be a question mark.
Otherwise we'll apply the class of loss and we could save this to a variable like concept class name
and then use that class name or I could do it in a single line.
I want to apply my class to the game.
Ally so game ally dot.
Class list dot add this entire expression the ternary operator.
So we will either add win or loss as a class depending on warrior start is winner and the moment of
truth will refresh.
Hey check it out OK so it seems to be working.
Golden State at Houston we have Golden State one so it's green here.
Houston 1 so it's red and it's accurate the whole way through.
Notice Golden State has four total wins out of seven.
Yes they moved on.
Great job.
OK so this code we have right now is kind of gross.
Honestly I'm not very happy with it and that's OK.
To get something out on the page get something working but I definitely want to refactor this for two
reasons.
One we should break it up into different functions when applicable to make it just clean and easy to
understand but also this is all tied specifically to Golden State right now.
What if I wanted to make a different table with the same data from the perspective of Houston and I
wanted to append it down below.
I think it would be best to make our code team agnostic and we could write a function called generate
table or generate score chart or whatever this is where you pass an argument in of the team we pass
Golden State and we get this if we pass Houston in we would get the opposite.
As far as the colors so we could try that in the next video we'll do the refactoring we'll make it a
little bit nicer.