We just created our package such a sum file and added in that in Section.
So now we are saying essentially right here that we want to build to run the command and L S at our
terminal and run the index not just file as though it were some kind of executable creating this package
that Jason File and adding in that section is just step one and being able to run our project from anywhere
on our machine.
There's a couple of more steps we have to do these other steps a little bit esoteric or kind of mysterious.
So I want to very quickly show you a diagram to walk you through each of them okay.
So we just create the Pakistan Jason File with that bean section.
The next day we're going to do is change the permissions of the index not J.S. file.
This is going to allow us to run that file as though it were an actual executable.
You should not have to do this next step if you are on a Windows machine.
And in fact if you try to run the command we're about to run on a Windows machine you're probably going
to end up seeing an error that does not apply.
Of course if you are using Windows subsystem for Linux.
All right.
So to update the permissions I can go back over to my terminal find my list directory and I'll run it
see h mod plus X index dot J Yes and that's it.
That will now give us permission to run that file as though it were an executable and the next two we
have to do is open up the index not just file.
We're going to add a little comment at the very top that's going to allow us to run it like an executable.
So like something we can double click to execute directly without having to involve node at all to do
so I'm going to go back over to my editor open up the index dot ust file and at the very top I'm going
to put in a Hash character then an exclamation then slash U.S. are not user just USAR slash local or
C meet slash been slash EMV and then a space and Node like so this is essentially telling our computer
that we want to use node to execute this file as opposed to trying to execute this file directly.
All right.
It's now the very last thing we have to do is go back over to our terminal and we're going to do something
called linking our project.
So I'm going to go to my terminal once and get again inside the list directory and inside of here I'm
going to run NPM link.
This is essentially going to take our current project and make it available to everywhere or every directory
on our machine.
So it essentially going to take our project make it globally available everywhere else.
So I'll run that and we'll see some little printout like this right here and we're ready to go.
Now we should go to run an L S and see the output from our program.
Now we can change to any directory on our machine so I can go back to my very root directory on my machine
or run into less and I'll see all the files inside they're printed out and I can repeat that process
from anywhere else just running an L S directly so that's pretty much it.
That's how we can set up a no J ust project to be executed from anywhere.
Now as you would guess this is really only used for useful for kind of command line interface tools
or CLIA that we're putting together for ourselves or other engineers.
Nonetheless it is a nice little trick to have in the back pocket.
All right.
So our project definitely works.
But the last thing on I mentioned here is that the L S command like the normal one whenever we run it
we get this kind of nice color printout of all the different files and whatnot inside of our project
directory whereas our program is just doing this really ugly console log of an array.
So I would like to add in a couple little improvements to our program now and just make the output or
the console log a little bit more interesting.
And as we do so we're going to very quickly see that there's a couple other challenges for us to tackle
inside of our program.
So quick pause and we'll start that in the next video.