At the end of the last video I mentioned how he's got some hard coded values inside of here of threes
and twos.
So the values that we currently have inside of here work perfectly for a three by three maze.
Okay I've really drawn the heck out of this thing but you get the idea.
It only works for a three by three mates.
So if we ever wanted to have some different dimensions for our maze Well we would have to go back through
and start to update all these different values by hand and I can just about guarantee you that we would
make a typo somewhere and end up breaking our code.
So I think that we should abstract out these different numbers into a configuration variable.
So I got to go back up to the very top of the file and I going to create a new variable that I'll call
cells I can start this off as three.
Now the values cells right here is talking about either the number of cells in the horizontal edge or
the vertical edge.
So for right now we're going to imagine the variable cells is talking about the number of cells either
that way or that way because all of our mazes right now we're going to be square.
It doesn't really matter which dimension we're talking about.
Again we are going to eventually allow the creation of mazes that are not square.
So like a three by five.
But right now everything we create will be square.
So calling that variable cells right now is more or less okay but another engineer if they looked at
this they might think that this is the total number of cells that we have.
So the name isn't the best thing in the world.
Whatever we are going to change that and just a little bit as soon as we add support for rectangular
mazes so now we can use that variable to go back down and replace all the hard code numbers we have
inside of here.
So for example I can find three.
Change it to cells change two cells cells and cells and the two values of two.
Well as you might guess those are just going to be cells minus one.
Now you should not have any values of two or three inside of here at all one good thing to test right
now would be to try to change the value of cells and then console log out our grid verticals and horizontals
and just to make sure they still make sense.
I'm going to try to increase the value of cells to five instead I'll then go back down I'm gonna change
the console log to take a look at the grid so when I now console log the grid I would expect to see
a grid of five by five so five inner arrays each of which have five elements inside them if I go back
and refresh yep there is a five by five without a doubt I can also do the same thing for verticals and
refresh yep that definitely looks correct and I can do the same thing with horizontals and I've got
a four by five also looks correct now if you want to this is a good spot to pull out your pen and paper
and draw out what a five by five maze would actually look like and then just make sure that we actually
do have the correct dimensions on the verticals and the horizontals arrays so I'm not going to flip
back over and mangle my diagram anymore I'll let you do that just in case you want to double check those
values but okay I think overall this is looking good.
So now we can start to write in some code after these arrays right here where we're going to essentially
walk through that grid pick those random cells and figure out exactly how we're going to remove all
those walls from the verticals in horizontals arrays two quick pauses we'll start that up in the next
video.