The last thing we have to do around our sign in post request handler is to make sure that we take those
errors.
And if there is an error we need to make sure that we tried to re render and send down the sign and
template once again.
And when we show these sign and template for a second time we need to make sure that we pass in that
Eris object and print out the appropriate errors on the screen.
So once again the same thing that we just did for our sign up route so to get started inside of our
post request handler for Slash SIGN AND I'M GONNA DELETE THAT console log and I'll say if not errors
is empty.
So if there is an error then let's return early and we'll do a resort sent of our sign in template.
Well then make sure that we pass in an object that has the errors that we want to eventually show on
the screen.
So I'll put an errors is errors as usual.
Key and value are identical.
So a collapse it to just be errors like so now we can go back to our sign in view so views admin off
sign and J.S. we're going to receive that object with the errors inside of it.
So you're assigning J.S. going to d structure out errors and then just like we did inside of sign up
I can open up sign up really quickly your sign up inside the same directory we want to define the same
exact get error function so we can reach in there and try to find some appropriate error.
Then after that we're going to print out the appropriate error by passing in the errors object in the
property that we want to look up inside their it's a back inside of sine and J.S..
We'll do a concert get error will receive that errors object and the prop that we want to look up inside
of it or the property name we want to look up inside of it.
Then we'll do a try catch because remember we're kind of cheating here but it does technically work
just fine.
So we'll say return errors dot mapped look up that property and then return the message for it they'll
also put on the catch block here.
We don't really care if an error occurs inside of here.
If an error occurs it means we probably just tried to access a property that doesn't actually exist
but does return empty string from there.
Okay so now we can use to get error inside of our template it's inside the template right after we show
the input for the name.
I'm going to do the dollar sign curly brace and we'll do a get error with errors and a property name
of email and I'm going to copy paste that down underneath the other input and then the property that
we care about in this case is password so that should be at before we try to run this however I want
to point out a error that is going to very very quickly surface.
So if we go back to our off dot J.S. file let's take a look right here or we just added in this resource
sand with sine and template we threw in the object with errors so in this case we are calling sign and
template with an object that hasn't heirs property.
But if we go back up here to where we call sign and template right there we are calling sine and template
without any argument whatsoever.
So if we were to run our code right now we would very quickly get an error message something telling
us that in this scenario right here when we call sign and template and we run that function.
So here's sine and template right here we are trying to D structure a property from an argument that
doesn't exist because when we call sign and template from right here no argument is being passed in.
So the first argument is going to be undefined if we tried to D structure off of an argument that doesn't
exist.
We're just gonna end up getting a big error message so to fix this we could just say you know what.
Whenever we call a template function no matter what we're always going to pass in at least an empty
object.
Easy straightforward way to solve this it's going to make sure that sign and template right here I pass
in an empty object.
So now when I tried to D structure off of this thing there is a value to D structure off of.
There is no errors in this case but we've discussed that before.
That's totally fine if we don't find errors object.
That's why we set up the try catch inside of get error.
Okay.
So I think we're ready to actually test this out inside the browser.
So I'm going to go back to my browser or refresh.
Here's my sign in form.
I'm going to put in a email that I know exists.
Whoops I keep on doing Gmail but a incorrect password might sign in and I'm told invalid password.
Awesome I'll then put in a email that definitely doesn't exist in some random password and untold email
not found.
Then finally if I put in a valid email and a valid password and hit sign in.
I still am able to sign it.
Awesome OK.
Well this all works.
But before we move on there's one little improvement I want to make.
We've now written the get air function right here identically in two different files.
We have it inside of sine in which is where we're at right now and we have also written it out inside
of sign up at the very top any time that we duplicate a function.
It is just about always a sign we should probably extract that function into some other file and then
require it wherever we need it.
So let's create some kind of helper file inside of our views directory to store any utility function
like the get error function.
Right here inside my route views directory.
I'm going to make a new file called helpers dot J.S. inside of here.
I'll do a module dot exports are going to export an object that's eventually going to have many different
functions so any function that I want to reuse between all my different templates.
Right now there's only going to be one function the get error function so we'll just rewrite the implementation
right here.
We're going to receive some errors object in a property we'll set up a try catch that's the error that
we don't care about on the try case we'll do a return errors dot mapped we'll look up the property dot
message and then if we enter catch we'll return empty string instead okay.
So now that we've got this function put together inside of helpers J.S. we're going to go to sign in
and sign up we're gonna delete the get error function in both those and replace it with a required statement
to get the function we just put together right here so a first go to sign in J.S. I'm going to delete
get error I'll do a concert get error notice that we are just d structuring the only function that we
care about that helps us file I'm going to write out a required to go up into the admin directory up
into the view directory and then get helpers J.S. so up one directory up another helpers
we can then copy that require a statement go over to our sign up file I'll delete the get error function
we have inside of here and then paste the required statement for get error OK so let's say both these
files do one last quick test just to make sure we didn't introduce any typos so I'll go back to sign
in and I'll put in how about just add a quick invalid e-mail Hey very good.
Also go to sign up and I'll put in an email that already exists
and that works as well.
Okay well I think that that is pretty much it for functionality we've now really wrapped up the entire
authentication flow inside our application.
The only downside right now is that well our application is really really ugly.
So we're going to take a pause right here.
We're gonna come back the next video and start to add in a ton of styling to make this thing look way
better than it currently looks.
So quick possible tackle that in just a moment.