Next up I'd like to introduce a different feature of JavaScript.
It has to do with decision making and logic.
It's called the switch statement.
It's not as commonly used as the typical conditional with if else if and else but in certain scenarios
it's really useful.
So let me show you what it looks like or why you would use it.
Imagine we have a variable with a number representing the day of the week.
So let's go with day equals three.
If I wanted to translate a number going from one to seven to Sunday Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday
and so on depending on where you are in the world I think people use different start dates for the week.
I think outside of the U.S. and Canada it's stuck.
The week starts on Monday which makes a lot more sense than starting it on Sunday like we do in the
US.
So let's go with the international version using a standard conditional.
We would check if day is equal to one and all fast forward through this but we would cancel that log
Sunday or Monday have got a break that American habit or going with international standard.
And then we would have.
Else if day is to and I'll just type this out quickly.
Okay here we go.
It's quite long if day is 1 Monday to Tuesday and it's just a bunch of else ifs.
If I change the day to 2 we get Tuesday.
If I change the day to 7 we get Sunday.
Let's also add in a fallback so if you didn't enter a number from 1 to 7 we'll consider that log invalid
day.
All right.
So this is fine but it's a lot of work and each time we're really just checking day against one value.
Over and over and over until we find a match or until we don't find a match in the else runs we can
use a switch statement in a scenario like this where we're taking one value and we're just checking
it against multiple potential values.
So the syntax for switch is quite a bit different.
It looks like this switch and then the thing that we are checking.
So for us it would be day then we have our curly braces and then we have a bunch of cases so we would
have Case 1 meaning if day is 1 and inside of that we don't actually have to use curly braces.
We can cancel that log Monday and then we could have case to cancel that log Tuesday and let's just
start with that.
So let's make a day to refresh the page and we get Tuesday Tuesday as you can see here.
So I will flesh this out with the other days.
There we go.
So we have seven different cases.
One day is one do this day is to do this.
3 and so on.
I'll comment out the traditional conditional that we have appear there's a problem with our switch at
the moment and you'll see it day is set to two.
Let's see what we get when I refresh the page.
Oh jeez.
Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday.
We got everything except Monday.
What if we change day to be for refresh the page.
Now we get Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday.
So that's kind of odd.
It's giving us every value after it matches.
So if case is for it does this it does this does this and this if cases one it does all of them is k.
If case is 6 or if day is 6 we do this one and this one.
So the reason this happens it's kind of annoying but what's happening here is that as soon as one of
them matches in our case for so Day is 4.
This is true.
None of these other cases are tested and it's almost like it turns into this all of that code runs without
checking for a case.
So it's looking for the first match and then as soon as it finds it everything else runs.
And that seems like an odd choice.
We'll talk about why that happens in a moment.
The way to fix this if you only want one of these to run is to add a break after each statement after
each case.
So I'll make multiple cursors by holding option and clicking and then add break after each one.
Now if I refresh I only get the correct day.
So if day is 7 I only get Sunday.
If day is 1 I should only get Monday.
We still don't have our fallback so if we have something like 9 we had that else earlier.
We don't have an else the way we write the equivalent instead of.
Else we write default and default will run at the end.
So we would have invalid day and now we get invalid day if we have 7.
We get Sunday and it all works OK.
So this is odd but this is still much easier to read.
It's a lot of lines but it's much easier to read in my opinion than this.
We don't have to do all of these poor and the curly braces.
We don't have to check with triple equals over and over and over.
You can just look at this and pretty quickly understand what's going on.
If Day is one do this.
If Day is for do this as long as we have those breaks in there why do we have those breaks going to
show you another example.
I'll comment this out for a moment.
So here's a second example.
We are taking in a movie it's just a text description of an emotion like happy face and printing out
the corresponding color or the main color.
So happy faces yellow sad faces.
Yellow eggplant is Purple Heart is red.
And lips are also red.
So right now they're all going to run well everything after we find a match.
So a happy face gives us yellow yellow purple red red.
But if we add in our breaks as we've seen that fixes the problem.
But we do have some duplicated console logs.
We have multiple things that are red and we have multiple that are yellow.
We could rewrite this because of the way switch statements work because of how they're structured.
We can combine certain cases and the way we do it looks like this.
Let's do happy face and sad face.
I'm just going to delete this entire thing here input case.
Sad face right here.
Case sad face right above.
Happy Face and I don't have any code coming after it.
So what happens here is that sad face could be a match.
Let's say it is.
This is true.
There is no break right here.
And because there's no break it moves on and it runs this code and then it hits a break so we can do
the same thing for heart and lips will do.
Case lips and then we can remove what we had down below.
Right here so same thing if a emoji is heart.
This is not true.
Not.
Nope.
This is true.
And then there's no code to run but there wasn't a break.
So then it just runs this code as we saw.
If you don't use a break after one of these cases it's going to just run all the code that it sees.
So at this point let's try it out.
We get yellow for sad face let's do lips we get red if do heart.
We should also get red.
We don't have a default on this one and that's fine.
Sometimes you don't.
So that's pretty much it for switches the syntax is definitely a little different but if you have one
variable one thing that you are checking against multiple values like we're doing here it's a nice and
easy to understand way of writing that logic compared to doing a ton of else ifs.
There's just a couple gotchas as you saw you need to make sure there's really just one.
You have to use break when it makes sense.
Sometimes it doesn't.
If you're trying to have multiple cases that correspond to the same piece of code anyway that switch.