The next test we're going to write out is going to make sure that when we type something inside of here
we should after doing some search have our dropdown open up.
So this is going to be a little bit more involve test because we have to make sure that we can somehow
programmatically type something inside that input have our autocomplete recognize that and execute a
search.
After that it should then be pretty straightforward because we're really just gonna write the same assertion
we're ready put together but we're going to instead of say not we're going to say yes it should include
is active.
So let's figure out how to do this.
The first thing we have to do is write out another test statement.
So we've been working inside of it shows an autocomplete.
Let's go down to the bottom.
We're going to add in another statement down here and we'll give this something like after searching
dropdown opens up
now inside of here.
There's something to be aware of.
If we just start to write some assertions right here right away and like maybe write out some code that
says type something in and then check dropdown.
We would technically be reusing the same autocomplete that we had rendered during the previous step
usually between every different test that we put together.
We're going to essentially try to reset our environment and think about it for just a second.
If we had one test that came to this auto complete and type something in like so and had the auto complete
start opened and then the next test was something like the one we just put together right here that
expects the dropdown to start off as closed we would have our test failed right away.
In other words if we ran our tests in a different order from what we currently have.
If we moved this one up to the top everything would start to break.
If we tried to reuse the same widget between every test.
So rather than reusing the same widgets after every test we're going to delete the widget that is being
displayed on the screen and then recreate it from scratch for the next test to do so.
Moka gives us a little hook function at the very top of the file.
I'm going to call before each.
This is referred to as a hook the DB for each function is globally defined by Moka.
So we don't have to try to reference it especially Urs anything like that.
We can just reference it directly inside of before each.
We can write out some amount of code that's going to attempt to set up our testing environment for every
single test.
So as the name implies whatever code we write inside of here we'll be executed for every following its
statement.
So that makes this a perfect location to setup our auto complete widget.
So I going to take the create auto complete call that we currently have inside this test right here.
I'm going to cut the entire thing and I will paste it inside the before each.
In addition right before that I'm going to reference the div with IDF of targets and I'm going to delete
everything inside there manually.
So I'll do a document dot query selector pound target and I'll set the inter agency mail to empty string.
This is not strictly necessary.
It's just going to really make sure that whatever autocomplete widget is currently in there really gets
kicked out.
It's now before every single test we run we're going to delete whatever's inside that div and create
a new autocomplete widget from scratch.
And so now it should not make a difference what order we run our tests in as we're always going to have
a completely clean autocomplete widget every single time.
All right.
Now back down here I just noticed that the description for this test is not quite accurate anymore.
I'm going to update that description to say something like dropdown starts closed.
All right so let's now continue working on the tests we just put together.
So inside of here the first thing we need to do is somehow trigger or otherwise make a search by typing
in some text right there to do so.
We're going to essentially use some traditional DOM manipulation methods to show you how to do this.
All right out some code directly inside my console inside of my test page.
So in order to fake some test text being written inside there we can select that element first.
So to select it I'll do a document dot query selector of input if I hover over the results I will see
that yep it's that input right there to put some text in to an input.
We can forcibly set the value property of it so I'll do my document query selector dot value and I'll
say equals whatever I want to search for.
So like Avengers I'll see Avengers appears right away.
Now just setting the value like so unfortunately doesn't trigger any events.
Now remember that's how the vast majority of our javascript applications work we watch for different
elements.
We wait for some event to occur.
The input element right here is no different.
The autocomplete Widget Works by watching for in on inputs or he input event setting the value like
we're doing right here does not trigger that event.
So if we want to actually trigger a search we have to essentially manually bake that event.
Let me show you how we do that.
I want to once again get a reference to that input element and I'm going to call dispatch events so
this is how we fake an event out as the argument to it.
I'm going to pass in a new event and as an argument to the new event I'm going gonna pass in a string
of the event name that I want to fake.
Which in this case is the input event.
It's now any javascript code we have that is watching for an input event on his input is going to be
faked into thinking that that just occurred so let's run that and we get back true.
Now in this case we don't really see anything change right here because well we already did a search.
But if I refresh this page really quickly and rerun those last two lines of code.
So I'm first going to set the value and then triggered the event or dispatch the event.
There we go.
I then see the result occur.
So that's how we fake out an event.
We first set the value inside there.
Then we call dispatch event and pass in new events.
Let's add that code to our test so go back over.
I'm going to first get a reference to the input so I'll do a document dot query selector input.
I'll set the value to Avengers or whatever else and I'll do the input dot dispatch events and I'll pass
in New events and that type of event that I want to simulate is input okay.
So that should be at now.
After that in theory all we have to do is go ahead and find the dropdown and make sure now that it does
have the class is active.
Because remember the gold this test was to make sure that the dropdown was open to down here.
Well actually rather than typing all that stuff out let's just copy paste make life easy so I copy that
paste it down.
And then finally instead of saying that it should not include is active I'm going to remove the not
statement so it should be closing parental dot to OK.
Now what you know right now this code is not going to work because of a really subtle little issue but
nonetheless let's save this and run it.
So I'll flip back over I'm going to refresh and I see.
Yeah.
Sure enough we failed.
Well that's kind of unfortunate but it kind of leads us into a really interesting topic in the world
of testing.
So let's take a quick pause right here we'll come back the next video and figure out exactly what is
going wrong.