Well we now understand why this is kind of a bad approach or some bad code right here.
So now we're gonna start to take a look at a couple of different ways to fix this code.
We're going to ultimately refactor this into three different forms.
The reason we're going to do such an exhaustive refactor is I just want you to see many different ways
of writing out some code.
Many different styles and we want to do kind of an analysis or a pros and cons of each different way.
Moreover I really just want you to see different styles of writing code so that you kind of get a sense
of what code to write on your own.
There's always multiple ways of accomplishing something with JavaScript and it's just important for
you to understand the different ways that you can do something.
OK so let's get to it.
Let's talk about the different ways that we're going to refactor this.
So these are three different options three different ways we can go to kind of fix up the code that
we have right now.
The first two options are not really great solutions.
They are not perfect by any means.
They may have some really big drawbacks.
Nonetheless I still want you to see these possible solutions.
The third solution we're going to go over is in theory the right way to essentially do this stuff.
So we are going to eventually look at the right way.
But again I just want to show you some different options because these might be useful in some other
context or some other project or something that you're going to work on in the future.
We never really know.
OK.
So with option number one we're going to maintain a callback based approach.
So right now we have a callback based approach because well we're using callbacks so we're going to
use the same kind of callback based approach but we're going to make it work the way we expect.
In other words we're going to get the correct ordering of data and correct console logs or the ordering
of council logs at the very end of our function call or after our program runs that to do so we're going
to create an array to store the results from each else that call.
Then as we invoke each callback we're going to add the stats object that we get back to that array and
then eventually when the arrays fall and we have all the data we ever expect to have in the correct
order will then run some processing on it to actually log out every file name and whether or not is
a file now saying that just by reading it from this note right here.
Kind of unclear about what's going on.
So quick diagram.
All right.
So here's the idea.
We're still going to have the same kind of callback approach where we have this really mysterious ordering
of callbacks.
We have no idea ever what order these callbacks are going to be invoked in.
So as a solution at the very start before we do any calls to step what so ever we're going to create
an array that will call something like all stats the length of this array is going to be equal to the
number of L stack calls we expect to have.
So in this case for then inside that array every element is going to start off as normal.
Now here's the trick we're going to kind of sit around and wait for the first callback to be invoked
if we're going by this diagram.
It'll be callback number three because the third callback is being vote.
We're going to take the stats that we get back from that call and update the element at index 3 inside
the array.
And so I'm going to shove in my stats object into that thing or then going to run a little bit of code
to check to see if there are any null values in the array still if there is still a null value inside
of here.
That means so we don't have all the data we expect to get.
So we're going to say OK we don't have all the data we expect we're not going to do anything else.
Well then sit around and wait for a little bit for the next callback to be invoked.
So as he gets a B callback number two right here.
So because the second callback got invoked we would go to index number two right here.
Take the stats data that we got inside that callback and push it into index number two and then we would
check to see if there's still any null values inside of here.
Yep there are two.
So we're not going run any further processing than we will repeat for number four.
Still have no value.
Repeat for number one and then we'll check to see if there are any null values.
Now in this case nope.
Normal.
No more null values and that so that means that we have all the data we expect to ever get.
And so then at that point time we could do some processing and say OK like let's iterate through this
list of all stats we have all the data we expect to have.
And it is in the same order as the original l stat calls that we made.
Again this is one possible way to solve this.
The reason that this is not super ideal is that well although the logic I just laid out here kind of
makes sense and it works if we ever had something more complicated than this like maybe after doing
the El stack call we had to do another asynchronous call for some other function we ever had to add
on any additional layer of complexity.
This solution would just start to get really confusing really quickly.
So even though it works I'd still say it's not super ideal.
Nonetheless I still want to show you how this solution we've put together so quick pause right here.
We'll come back the next video and throw it together.
This implementation really quickly.