Next up there is a shortcut syntax that you can use in JavaScript for certain conditionals.
It's called the ternary operator.
It's a way of basically taking an F and an S and turning them into a single line of code.
It's called the ternary operator because there are three pieces instead of binary ternary is the term
for three.
As you can see there are three pieces here.
This is kind of the template for how you would read it.
There is a condition and a question mark.
So if this condition is true this code runs.
Otherwise if it was false this code runs.
So let's take a simple example.
Remember this only works if you're doing a simple yes or no.
And if and then else.
So no else ifs involved.
Let's say we have a number but num equal 7 and if num is equal to 7 will control that log.
Lucky
and then else we can control that log bad.
OK so here we have a simple if and then else we could rewrite this entire thing on one line.
If you wanted to using this syntax we have condition question mark so the condition is num equals seven
question mark.
Then the code we want to run if true.
We'll go there and then the code we want to run if false is separated by a colon.
So a question mark and then a colon colon control dot log that just like that.
I'll comment out the original code refresh the page and it still works.
We get lucky.
Let's change it to two.
We don't get lucky.
OK back to seven so we've taken this logic and just written written it as a single line that doesn't
mean that you should always do this even this is getting pretty long for a ternary mainly because of
these constant logs that I'll show you another example slightly different where we could actually use
the ternary operator to assign a value to a variable let's say we're making a chat app where you can
set yourself you can set a status to be online or offline.
So we'll have a status variable instead let's go with offline to start and then we want to have a color
that we use to show like a little bubble next to your name if this is a chat app a bubble that is either
red or green.
So it's red.
If you're offline and green if you're online we would have a variable like color and if we did it without
a ternary operator we would do if status equals off line then we would make color equal to red and then
else color is equal to green so we could write it this way or we could do it all in one line.
So I'll keep that there but I'm going to comment it out.
We could rewrite it as light color equals and then our ternary operator.
So the piece of logic is status equals off line question mark then one value would be red.
That's the true part remember condition expression if true expression is false.
So if true we want red.
Otherwise we want green.
And now we've rewritten this entire thing in one line.
So this is a pretty common use case.
If I run in we get red for color.
If I change this to be online or really anything else we're only checking for offline at this point.
We'll see that color is now green.
So it's a nice shortcut.
It can be kind of odd if you're not familiar with it which is why I wanted to show it to you now while
we're talking about conditionals it doesn't do anything new.
It just can shorten your code up.
So here is the original.
Here is the second version with ternary operator.
We have a condition question mark.
Something that happened if the condition is true and something that happened if the condition is false.
So the if and the else that's it.
There's no room for.
Else if it's just a yes or no do this or do this.