We just added in a bunch of e-mail directly to our index not a small file.
So now in theory we could go back over to our javascript code tried to select these different anchor
elements and then update the content inside them to show the movie poster and the title.
In theory that would work.
But before we do that we kind of have a choice to make here about how we're going to implement this
autocomplete widget.
Let me show you a diagram to help you understand the decision that we have to make OK so this is option
number one right here.
And this is kind of what the path is that we're walking down right now.
So right now in this kind of option we would write out all the each team all that is required or at
least as much as possible inside of our each HTML document.
So in other words we would write out that div with class dropdown we would write out the input inside
there.
Then the drop down menu the content and then eventually render out all the dropdown items inside there
and then inside of our indexed dot J.S. file we would write out some code that looks like this.
It would try to select probably like that div with class dropdown or some like autocomplete class or
something like that and then set up an event listener on the input inside there and then whenever a
user does a search we would then take the results generate all those options and throw all the different
results like all the different anchor tags into that dropdown content div and this right here might
seem like a really obvious way to do it right.
Like what other way is there.
Well there actually is another way to approach this problem.
One thing what to highlight about this is that we are making some really big assumptions between the
contents of our each e-mail file and the contents of our JavaScript file.
In other words our javascript code is not going to work correctly.
If our e-mail file doesn't have exactly the correct structure in other words this code this entire setup
would not work correctly at all if we did not have that input element.
If we accidentally delete it or move that input element our javascript code would probably not work
correctly.
Likewise if we did not have the correct spelling on this class right here if dropdown content which
is where we want to put all of our anchor elements that represent each individual video if we misspelled
that class name or moved it somewhere else instead of our project that's pretty much it.
Are javascript code is no longer going to work correctly either so in other words we've got a very distinct
coupling between our ace HTML document and our JavaScript file.
The two of them work very closely together and if we change either we might break our entire application
so that in mind let's take a look at another way of approaching this.
This would be option number two.
OK so an option number two we are going to have way less each team l inside of our index not a small
file so to represent our entire autocomplete widget.
Maybe we could get away with only creating one single element a div with a class of autocomplete or
something like that so in this scenario we would create just the beer root of our widget inside of our
e-mail documents and then instead of putting all the HMO inside there inside of our e-mail document
we would instead rely upon our javascript code to go through the process of creating all the HMO those
required for us.
So in other words we would try to maybe select this div right here and then we would run some code to
create an input in there for us we would then handle the input like in other words deal with change
events we would run our search on the API and then we would add in all the different HDL required to
show that dropdown so add in all the HDL or the drop down menu dropdown content and so on so in this
scenario read centrally dumping all the responsibility of producing HDL off to the javascript side of
our application that might sound like a lot more work on our side but in reality it kind of makes life
a little bit easier because no longer are we going to have a strong coupling between our indexed on
e-mail file and the javascript file.
Now all we have to do is make sure that we have got one div inside of here with a class of autocomplete
and then we should be able to just run some code inside our index not just file it will find that div
and setup our entire autocomplete widget inside there.
So no expectations whatsoever about the H SYMBOL that's inside of that div.
This right here is a way more flexible approach because with this approach you and I can much more easily
create reusable widgets that we can reuse between different projects.
It also makes it much more easy to share our code with other developers.
Imagine sharing both these options with some friend of yours who wants to implement the same kind of
autocomplete widgets.
If you were using option number one up here you would have to tell your friend.
OK.
First you're gonna go over to your age HTML document.
You're gonna put together this div and it has to have an input.
Make sure as input and it has to have these two days may have to be nested in this very particular way.
Just imagine trying to communicate that to some other engineer.
You know maybe it's as easy as just copy pasting them some snippet of HDL but at the end of the day
that's definitely a decent amount to communicate over to them however if you were using option number
two you could tell your friends Oh yeah just create this div with a class of autocomplete and then run
this javascript function run like some function called Create autocomplete and boom that's it everything
will be set up for that other engineer automatically so throughout this course we've largely been using
option number one but as we move forward we're going to be moving towards option number two.
We're going to try to limit the amount of coupling between our e-mail document and our JavaScript file.
And again the entire idea here is that it's going to lead to greater reuse of the different widgets
we put together.
And it's also going to lead to less coupling between our different files of our project.
OK.
So now we understand like why we're gonna take this kind of approach.
Obviously it's going to require us to add in a pretty good amount of additional javascript code and
we're going to have to make a couple of changes to our e-mail document.
And I want to kind of set you up and get you to understand why we're about to write all the code how
we're gonna write so quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.