We were just discussing how the weight for function will be really handy to use right here.
So let's start to implement it.
So again the idea is that we're going to receive some selector and we're going to essentially just wait
around until we see that thing up here on the screen.
It's gonna go up to the top of my file the very top and I'm going to define weight for
so this thing is going to receive an argument of a selector.
Now right away if you took a look at where we called it down here I use the awake keyword that is because
we want to have some asynchronous code inside of here and we want to essentially just wait for that
thing to process before we continue on and execute everything else inside.
That means that the wait for function must return a promise.
And that's how we're going to implement this or wait for function up here is going to return a new promise
recall how a promise works we call new promise.
We then pass in a function this functionally Parson is going to be called with two arguments resolve
and reject both these are arguing versus both these arguments are functions.
If we call resolve then the overall promise will be resolved.
And if we call reject the overall promise will be rejected and failed.
In this case if we call reject that is going to cause an error to be thrown which will cause an error
to be thrown down here.
And that will cause the overall test to fail as well so in other words if we don't see some elements
appear in within some amount of time we can just call reject and we should be good to go.
All right.
So inside of here there are several different ways that we can actually implement this logic but we're
going to use a very simple straightforward way.
We're going to create two different time outs.
One will be an interval and one will be a timeout.
So we're going to set up an interval which is gonna be a function that's going to run every so many
milliseconds inside the set interval.
We're gonna check to see if an element with that selector exists inside the document.
If it does that means that the element has appeared and we will resolve the promise.
The purpose of the set time out is to make sure that if we go for some amount of time without seeing
an element with that selector appear then we will automatically reject the premise instead.
So let's put this together.
I'm going to say set interval I'm gonna pass in a function and I want to run this function every say
30 milliseconds.
You can put just about any value that you want to write here.
This is just going to be how often we check the DOM to see if some element has appeared.
The lower technically the better technically our tests will run faster.
However if you take it really low you're going to be running this function really really don't often
and you'll end up burning through more spew than you need to.
So 30 totally reasonable then inside the interval every 30 milliseconds we're going to check and see
if an element with that selectors has appeared.
So I'll say if document dot query selector and then passing the selector that we're looking for.
So if that has appeared.
If we have found something with that call right there let's resolve the promise.
Now we need to also handle the case in which we go for some amount of time without seeing the selector.
If we go for like five seconds well chances are things not going to appear.
So we need to then reject that promise and just stop this entire waiting process.
So outside of the set interval here's the set interval right after it.
So make sure you're after it not inside.
Right after the interval we'll set up a time out as well
remember the difference between a interval and a time out interval is going to run that function every
somebody milliseconds time out is going to run a function just one time.
So in my case I'm going to say that I am willing to wait up to two thousand milliseconds or two seconds.
If the element doesn't appear within that amount of time I don't think it's ever going to appear.
And so I'm just going to reject the promise and say That's it.
We waited long enough.
I give up.
So inside the set time out I will call reject what we have right here.
Almost works.
There's just one last little thing.
When we call set time outs it's going to set a c a set interval it's going to run at function every
so many milliseconds for ever until we actually stop it at some point time.
Hopefully we're going to find the element.
Or maybe we don't.
But either way whether we find it or we don't.
We need to make sure that we stop that interval from running because otherwise it's just going to continue
running forever even after we resolve the promise.
In addition we probably want to make sure that after we reject the promise.
If that happens then we should make sure we stop the interval as well.
The reverse is opposite or skimming the reverse is true as well.
So if we decide to resolve the premise we probably wanna make sure that we stop the time out from ever
occurring and don't attempt to reject the promise.
We cannot actually reject a promise that has already been resolved but just for completion sake we're
going to add that check in.
Okay.
So long story short what we're really doing here.
We're gonna store a reference to the interval that gets created and a timeout that gets created as well.
And then in both cases whether we resolve or reject we're going to clear the interval and the timeout.
So we'll take care of reject first let's say clear interval.
Remember this is a function built into the browser and will pass in the interval that we want to stop
and then up here in the case right before we resolve.
We will clear the interval and we will also clear the time out.
In this case
okay.
That's it.
That is our wait for function.
I know this code is a little bit nasty but it definitely works pretty well and it's extremely handy
to have whenever testing something like this over here.
Okay so let's try this again.
I gonna go back down to the very bottom the file so now when our test runs we're going to enter some
value to the input dispatch that events were then going to wait for some element called dropdown dash
item to appear.
As soon as it does then we will run our expectation it's going to save all this put back over refresh
and I forgot for the millionth time inside this course to add the async keyword.
My mistake.
Sorry about that on the statement right here.
We're using the await keyword.
We need to mark the enclosing function as async.
That's it.
Yes I'll save that.
Back over.
Now we're good to go so it looks like the test is passing.
You'll also notice that the test is taking some amount of time to actually execute the waiting after
the user types something in there is 500 milliseconds so that's why we see it 511 right here it takes
slightly longer than five and a milliseconds so I can refresh and once again.
Yep looks good.
Okay.
So that's it.
All right well we still got like one or two more tests to run so quick pause right here and I'll see
you in just a minute.