We just spoke about the differences of creating a bunch of H mell to support a widget inside of our
each small file versus our javascript code.
Now one thing only mentioned here is that this discussion is really about the creation of JavaScript
heavy reusable widgets.
There's still going to be many times where you're going to want to create some eat smell inside of an
eight style document and that's totally fine.
We're really just thinking about moving a single generation over to our javascript code when we are
thinking about widgets that we want to make easily reusable between different projects or even on the
same project or this autocomplete.
We know that we need to show two different auto completes on the screen and so our options are to either
write out all that code like one time or that a small structure one time inside of our JavaScript file
or write it out twice inside the index dot each email file.
Definitely the easier thing to do is create some javascript code that can create this widget for us.
As many times as we want but there's definitely going to be some other elements that we're going to
throw directly into our each html file for example that header element that's already visible right
there.
That's not something that is quite appropriate to try to display from our javascript code so.
Cos that thing is like just there's only one there's not really any interactivity.
I don't expect to reuse it totally appropriate to create that inside of our HDD and I'll file OK so
back over.
We're gonna do a little bit of a refactor and move some of this e-mail generation to our javascript
so that involves essentially deleting a love the e-mail that we just wrote out here.
I know it's kind of a pain to delete some of the Asian all that we just wrote but I wanted to write
this out for two reasons.
First off so you understood the difference between option number one and option number two and secondly
it's that you just understood that if we use this e-mail structure right here with these very particular
class names we'll make CSX would kick in and style that stuff for us automatically.
So I apologize to the delete stuff we just wrote but again that's why we did it.
Okay so I got to find everything inside of class Container and delete it.
Now we're going to replace it with one single element instead.
I'm gonna do a deal with the class of auto complete like so now we can go back over to our javascript
code.
We're going to select that element so back over right above where we get that input.
I'm going to add in some code to select that thing I'm going to call it root because it kind of represents
the root element of our autocomplete widget so we'll do a query selector with DOT auto complete and
then immediately after that we're going to do a root dot in our HCM L and put in all the e-mail that
we need to make our auto complete was at work so essentially we're talking about adding in all the e-mail
that we just deleted from the ECMO file so it might seem like we're just kind of shoveling HMO creation
from one location to another that's totally accurate.
That is what we're doing.
Again the point is to reduce the coupling between these different files.
The HMO still has to be created somewhere.
We're just moving it over to the javascript side.
So inside of the thing we're going to add in pretty much the same structure we just had.
I'm going to put in one or two more elements and class names.
That's just going to kind of represent the final styling of this widget that we're going for it's going
to put in a label that has a B element to bold the text in here.
And for the text I'll say search for a movie.
I'll then close off the B element and close off the label after that I'll put down the input.
We still need an input.
I'm gonna give this one a class of inputs like so and then after that I'm going to start to show the
dropdown.
Now previously we wrapped up the input with a dropdown this time for like no great reason it can do
things slightly differently.
It's gonna put the dropdown right after the input element.
It's also a day with the class of dropdown gonna close that off inside there I'll do a deal with the
class up dropdown dash menu and close it off.
And then finally a div with the class of dropdown content.
And this time around I'm also gonna put in a class name of results.
That is just for some additional little styling does some C Ss no other special reason for that class
besides a little bit of styling okay.
So now we are creating all of our e-mail on the javascript side and that means we can create as many
of these autocomplete widgets as we want.
Eventually.
So now we're going to go through this and we're going to select a couple of the different elements inside
of here that we know that we're going to need.
We already have a selector for that input.
We're going to make sure that we also get a selector for that div right there that says dropdown content
because remember that's where we're going to eventually show all the different search results we get.
We're also going to get a selector for this div with class of dropdown as well.
The reason for that is that we can hide and show the drop down menu depending upon whether or not this
element has a class of is Dash active.
This is not some like magic javascript thing.
This is another little bit of styling from bonuses SS if we actually go back over to the documentation
over here.
You'll notice that the root element in their example has is active.
If that element has the class is active then the dropdown is going to be displayed.
Otherwise if the class is not there the dropdown will be hidden.
That is normal CSF behavior.
They just have a little CSF selector to say either apply a display of block or none to this thing to
show and hide it.
So we're going to leave off is active because by default we want this thing to be closed.
But like I said we're going to get a selector to that element so we can add that class on eventually
an open or closed the dropdown so next to our input element right here we're going to add in some more
selectors to get those two other elements we just discussed one to open the thing up and one to eventually
render some contents inside their going to add in a selector for dropdown and that will be document
query selector not dropdown
and I'll also get a we'll call it tab out results wrapper there'll be a document query selector or Dutch
results.
And as you would guess that's that element right there.
I'm calling it results wrapper because essentially it's going to wrap all the rendered results that
we're trying to show to the user.
Okay.
So this looks good.
Now this video is going a little bit long.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to update some of the code inside of our on input function
to make sure that we render some input or excuse me some output into these particular elements.
Took pause and I'll see you in just a minute.