We now have our neighboring coordinate pairs right here.
So now we need to take that list of coordinate pairs and randomize them.
This is going to make sure that there's a strong randomization factor inside of our maze if we always
use this same order to visit our neighbors.
Then ask maze is going to always look the exact same.
So this is what is going to generate our randomness inside of our maze now unfortunately the javascript
language does not have any functionality built into it to randomize the elements inside of an array.
So we're going to have to write out a little function to do that for us so I can go up to the top of
this section where I've got my maze generation comment and inside of here I'm going to define a new
function called shuffle.
So this is going to take some array and then randomly reorder all the elements inside of it.
We're going to write out the code for this pretty quickly and I'll explain what's going on along the
way instead of shuffle I'm going to first get the length of the array and assign it to a variable that
I'll call counter I'll then set up a while loop that I'm going to run until counter or while counter
is greater than 0 then inside the while loop I'm going to get a random index inside of the array so
I'll say let index or some constant X is math dot floor math dot random times counter that's going to
be a random index inside of the array and then going to decrease my counter variable by 1.
So Kanter minus minus.
And then finally I'm going to swap the elements that are at the array at element or at index of index
and at the index of counter.
So this is what is going to be the actual kind of swapping of elements to randomize the order it's all
say Collins temp short for temporary is a are at counter well then update the value at index of counter
to a r at index and I'll update the element at index to be whatever was previously at counter.
And then finally at the bottom I will return the array.
So again we're finding some random element side there and swapping whatever that random index is with
what it whatever is that counter that will ensure that we swap each element at least one time okay.
So let's go back down to where we generate all of our neighbors.
So right here I'm going to wrap that function with shuffle and then do a console log right after it's
not to really test this out and make sure that we've got some correct values being generated in that
they are in some random order we should probably stick in some starting row and column to our function
that we know is going to have some proper input or excuse me proper output so we know that if we start
at this 1 1 index right here we should see outputs of 0 1 1 0 1 2 and 2 1 so if we stick in 1 1 those
the outputs we should get but they should be in some a randomized order that's gonna make this a lot
easier to test than if we stick in the random start row and start column I'm going to update those two
values be 1 for just right now I'm going to change it back in just a moment I'm also going to remove
the console log of grid just so we can read the console a little bit more easily without seeing a bunch
of console log start to stack up all right so I'll save this I'm gonna go back over and refresh.
So here are the four coordinate pairs that are around 1 1 they should be in some randomized order let's
see I've got 1 0.
Let's check each of these off one by one I know it'll be a little bit disorienting but let's go through
it.
So 1 0.
That's the first one we've got that next is 0 1 right there next is 2 1 right there and then finally
1 2 right there.
So we definitely have all four.
Well that's fantastic.
Now the only other thing we have to do is make sure that they get randomized.
Each time they'll do a another refresh.
So I now see them in a very different order and another different order and another different order.
So I'd say that we definitely have this kind of shuffling logic down pat.
So this is looking pretty good.
I'm going to remove that console log.
We'll take a pause right here and when we come back the next video we're going to make sure that we
add in some logic to iterate through each of these different neighboring pairs and run some logic on
each of them.
So quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.