Well that's why we have to do is allow a user to click on this button right here and delete the given
item out of the shopping cart.
So the first thing we need to do is to make sure that clicking on that little button is going to submit
a POST request using a form element.
We're then going to implement a root handler inside our application to receive that post request and
use it to actually delete an item out of the cart.
So to get started I'm going to go and find where each of those buttons gets rendered.
So inside of my views carts showed up J.S. file.
Take a look at.
Rendered items.
This is where each of those items is being assembled inside there.
We can scroll down a little bit.
We'll see a David class remove inside there is a form element already and there's a button inside there
that has an icon inside of it.
So this is the form that is going to be submitted.
Anytime a user clicks on that red x button.
So this one right here so we need to add in some properties to the thing to make sure that our server
understands exactly which item we want to delete out of our cart.
You might recall that just a little bit ago when we were working on our views products index not J.S.
file we spoke about the form over here as well.
And we said that we needed to somehow communicate exactly what product we were trying to add to our
cart.
So in an identical scenario this time around as well we need to somehow communicate during this form
the middle which item needs to be removed.
There's two different ways we can do that.
As we discussed with the product stuff just a moment ago we can either reflect the items idea inside
of the form action property or essentially inside the U.R.L. of the post request we make the other way
we can communicate this is by adding in a hidden input element we can assign a value to this thing of
the ideas of the product that we want to remove out of our cart and then our server can take a look
at the form body or the body the post request to figure out exactly which item needs to be removed through
once again once again going to use this input strategy.
So inside the farm I can put an input element with hidden so the user doesn't see it for value I can't
specify the item I.D..
So this is going to be the idea of the item like this item right here that we want to remove out of
our cart.
I'm also gonna put a name on the thing of item IDEA AND THEN I'LL CLOSE OFF THE INPUT element like so
now.
One other thing I'm going to do on my form element I'm going to also define the action property.
Remember action specifies where we are going to make this post request to.
I'm going to put in an action of slash cart slash products slash delete.
This is not required at all.
The only reason I'm doing this is to make sure that's really clear to anyone who starts to look at this
form to understand that or to help them understand that submitting this form is going to trigger some
deletion of something and that's going to be evident by the fact that we're going to be referencing
a path here of slash delete
okay.
So let's go back over to our root handler file.
We're going to make sure that we've got a post request handler to handle a POST request made to cart
slash products slash delete so back inside of my routes cart start j ust file I'll find the last comment
we have inside of here and we'll add in router dot post and we're going to watch for a post request
to well we were just discussing cart products delete
then as a second argument I make sure that I put in my function for request in response we're definitely
gonna have some async code inside this thing so second market as async.
All right.
So right now let's just do a quick counsel log of req dot body dot item I.D..
So this should be the I.D. of the item inside of our current that we want to remove.
So again it's gonna be like that I.D. right there.
So we're going to have to iterate through a list of items find the appropriate object and just remove
it out of the list of items and save our card back to our repository it's going to save this.
And let's test this out really quickly.
Just make sure we can get that console log so I'll go back over I'm going to refresh the page and then
click on one of these red Xs when I did so the browser is just going to hang and that's just because
we're not doing inside of our request handler right now.
But if we go back over to our terminal we will see the idea of the item that we're trying to delete
console logged out right there.
OK.
That's definitely very good.
So let's take a another quick pause we'll come back and make sure that we implement the logic to actually
take a look at all the items inside of our carts and remove the appropriate item.