Well we've now seen many different ways of taking a built in function or a callback based function and
getting a premise based implementation of it.
The reason I'm going to leave these other methods on here is that at the very end of this option.
Option number two that we're currently working on this one right here.
We're going to try to uncommon these other L step declarations and try to run our same code with those
other alternate implementations as well.
And you're gonna see if they all work 100 percent equivalently okay.
So now inside of here we've got our reader function we get back our file names.
So now once again we're going to iterate over our file names and for every file name we will run the
L stats.
We're going to use the async await syntax which means that we're going to be only running one L step
function at a time.
So inside of my reader function I'll say for let file name of file names well then run my L stat so
I'll say const stats is a wait l stats on the file name I'm using the await keyword right here.
Which means I need to find the wrapping function and apply the async keyword to it.
So in this case the wrapping function is that right there.
So I need to add on a async to the Arrow function.
Now immediately after getting back our stats object we can right away do a quick console log for the
given file name and whether or not it is a file we'll say counselled but log file name and stats dot
is file and technically at this point we do not have the same kind of error handling code that we had
previously with the callback based implementation.
So to make this truly equivalent to the code we had just a moment ago I would wrap the await syntax
right here or excuse me the awake keyword in the console log after it with a try catch statement remember
a try catch statement is going to catch any errors that might arise while we are waiting on L stats
I'm going to say try to wrap that with a set of curly braces and then immediately after the closing
curly brace I'll say catch you are and then I'll do a console log of the air just to say hey something
went wrong and here's the error okay.
So that should be it.
So let's now save this.
I'm gonna go back over I'll do any less.
And there we go.
So I got empty folder false and I can run this many times and once again every single time I see the
exact same ordering of output.
So this definite looks like a pretty straightforward solution.
Now if we kind of ignore the time that we took in the last video to discuss like all this promise stuff.
Well the solution without a doubt is really really straightforward very easy to write pretty clear about
what's going on.
And well just wasn't that bad.
Now let's try really quickly to comment out the other L stat implementations or uncommon them and make
sure that our code still works with those alternate implementations as well.
And again I just want to do this to show you that there's a lot of different ways we can take these
annoying callback based functions and interact with them in a promise based format.
So I to comment that the number three uncommon method Number two I'm gonna save this go back over do
unless it still works I'll then comment out method Number two I'll go down to method number one and
comment it save it and less and yep it still works as well.
So overall.
Couple different implementations here.
I'd say it's pretty easy to read everything looks good but there is one really big issue with this with
this implementation.
Remember what I said just a moment ago.
This solution works but it's not ideal it's not like in theory the right way of doing this stat operation.
So what is wrong with this operation or what is wrong with this approach.
The problem is as we saw in the diagram back here everything is running in serial.
That means that we are only running one El stat operation at a time at any time.
So imagine what would happen if it took us like say 500 milliseconds or half a second to El start each
file and we had like a thousand files to go over or to run the stats function on that would end up taking
500 seconds.
So because we are only able to do one operation at a time we can only ever go as fast as it takes to
go through like well everything in series so we don't get to enjoy the benefit of any performance enhancement
from running multiple El stats in parallel.
So even though this is a really easy solution to read and look at it's still not the best because potentially
while this might be a very time intensive way of doing this El stat operation so that's going to lead
us into our solution.
Number three right here or option number three this is going to be very similar to option number two
but instead of just using a promise in async await syntax we're also going to use something called the
Promise dot all helper method that's going to allow us to process many different El stack calls in parallel
so that's probably gonna end up being a way better from the performance standpoint.
So let's take a pause right here we'll come back the next video and start to refactor towards this last
approach.