The next thing to know about arrays is that they are indexed just like with strings where each string
character has a corresponding index.
And I can access them.
One character at a time the first character the second the third the fourth and the indices start at
zero.
The numbering starts at zero.
Arrays are just like that every item in an array has a corresponding index and that index is what dictates
the order.
So if something is index zero it's at the beginning.
If something is index 1 it is the second item.
And just like with strings arrays also have a length property.
So here is a colors array I've made with red orange yellow green blue indigo and violet.
And if I look at colors dot length it has seven items and we use the exact same syntax to access individual
items from the array that we do with a string.
So to get the first item it's colors of 0 just like with the string colors of one gives me the second
one.
Colors of 3 gives me the fourth one which is green.
And remember there is no colors of 7 if the length is 7 and we're trying to access that colors of 7
we get undefined because the highest index goes up to length minus one.
If are seven items we start labelling at zero.
So this is going to have index of 6.
So to get the last one.
You could do this colors of colors dot length minus 1 and that gives us violet.
So that's pretty much it for accessing data out as long as you have an index.
And you know the number you're trying to access.
How do you square brackets after the name of the array.
And if you try and access something that is not there you get undefined.
Just like with a string string index of 1 2 3 is also undefined so that's great.
We can access data.
We can read it out next.
We have a lot to talk about as far as modifying a race data changes how do we add something new a new
common.
Or how do we reorder our playlist so that we have a new song at the beginning all of that stuff is coming
up.