Next up we have another nice new syntax addition to objects called computed properties so computed properties
are just an improvement for the object literal syntax where we can add a property with a dynamic key.
Right now if we want to make an object with a dynamic key.
For example if I WANT AN OBJECT WHERE I HAVE THE KEY set to the value of role which is host and then
the value for that key would be Jools Holland the variable person.
If I make my object const let's call this jobs or how about team.
If I tried to do roll and set that to person we've seen this before.
Early on we'll just end up with the key of role.
That's not what we want here.
If I look at team we have roles set to Jools Holland so person is evaluated.
This is computed if we get the Variable value and that stuck in the object but role is turned into a
string.
It's not checked if it's a variable.
It's not computed.
So what we've done in the past in order to make this work if we want a dynamic value for the key is
to go back after we initialize the object.
Do you square brackets team of role equals person.
And now if we look at team we have host set to Jools Holland and let's say I had one more concept role
two equals.
Uh how about director.
I don't have the actual per any person in mind with Person 2 equals.
JAMES CAMERON Okay.
And if I wanted to add this in as a pair I would need to then do team of role two equals person to and
now we have two properties with dynamic keys and we have to use these square brackets as we've seen.
If you tried to use the dot notation you're just adding the key of role.
But now with this new syntax for computed properties we can do this all at once.
We can define our object and then dynamically add in a key based off of some computed variable and expression.
The code will be evaluated first.
We'll retrieve the Variable value and use that as a key.
And this is what it looks like.
We use the same square brackets but we wrap it around the key in our property definition in the object's
literal.
So here you user will be evaluated first.
We get jewels and that's set to admin.
So if we try it over here we would have roll in those brackets set to person and then I could do a second
one roll to set to Person 2.
Let's take a look.
There we go.
The exact same object that we created up here but now we're doing it all at once.
All of our properties are in the object when we are defining it.
We're not having to do it after the fact.
We don't make an empty objects and then add a property and the second property we can just do it all
at once.
And that's kind of it and for computed properties you could also put in more complex expressions in
here.
For example I could do one plus six plus nine and set that equal to how about 16 if I evaluate this
and take a look.
We have 16 set to 16 so this is going to be evaluated and then turned into a string like all the keys
we've seen and then used as the key in the object.
Here's one more example let's make a function that accepts an object and will return a copy of that
object with a new property added in.
So we'll call this function add property or just add prop it will accept an object and then a key and
a value and we want it to return a new object based off of this Obi J parameter with a key and a value
pair added.
So without this computed properties new syntax we would do something like this make our copy of the
object all your spread Oh B.J..
That's an easy way to make a copy and then we would set a copy of k equals V and then return.
Copy and if I called this now I'll use my team variable.
It would do add up of team let's add in a new property.
We'll go with happy and then the corresponding string will be a happy face.
So we have a key and a value.
We'll save this to a variable const rez.
Let's look at results.
Okay so it worked.
We ended up adding in happy as a key and a happy face.
The string as the value.
This is not using computed properties.
So we had to make the object then we had to go ahead and update add in a new property with the dynamic
key and value.
If we instead wanted to rewrite this using computed properties we could do it on one line.
It would be an annoying one line but we could do it on one line.
I'll do an arrow function this time.
So const add prop equals object key value and then we'll return a new object that contains everything
from Obi J we're spreading it in or copying it and using square brackets compute the key and set it
equal to the corresponding value.
So this does fit on one line but when I saved my editor it decides to auto format it to multiple lines.
You could also use an implicit return to even shorten it more.
But let's just make sure it works.
Let's look at rez.
We get the same result.
So that's one use for a computed property.
When you are creating functions that either return objects or add things into objects it's pretty common
that you might want to add a dynamic key.
Now just as a bonus here.
We're done with the computer property stuff but if we wanted to refactor this to be a one line aero
function or at least an implicit return aero function.
Remember that when we return something implicitly we don't need the return keyword and we don't need
the curly braces.
So we could write it like this and then just move it all into one line except for the fact that JavaScript
will get confused because this looks like it's a function body it looks like the curly braces are for
a function it doesn't know that we're trying to implicitly return an object.
If we had something like five here this would implicitly return 5 but when we have an object it gets
confused.
So we do have to put parentheses around it and I'm pretty sure it's going to auto format to multiple
lines anyway but this is valid on one line.
Okay so that's computed properties.
We use the exact same square brackets syntax that we've been using so far but now we can use it directly
inside the object definition.