Let's try writing another function this time.
Something that doesn't just print grumpy text over and over and over.
Let's do something with some variation.
How about generating a random dice roll or a single die roll.
So a number from zero.
Nope.
There's no zero day 1 to 6.
And we'll name this function something that makes sense like roll die.
So we need function space roll die curly braces.
And now we need the logic to generate a random number from 0 to 6.
So let's roll equal.
And then we'll do math at random.
You know how much I'm not a fan of this syntax.
I thought random times 6.
And then we need to floor that math top floor.
Remember math at random gives us a decimal so it would be like zero point two.
And then we multiply by six in order to get a larger range.
So we're no longer just from zero to one.
We're going from zero to I guess right below six because the largest decimal will generate as point
nine something we multiply by six.
And then we floor it to get rid of the decimal.
So now we have a number from zero to five.
But our dice roll or die roll should be from 1 to 6.
So we add 1.
The logic is not all that important.
Really we're still focusing on the fact that every time we call it roll die.
This code runs.
This code happens to make a number from one to 6 a random number.
And then let's consider log rolled and then string template literal the roll refresh the page.
Nothing happens because we never executed this.
We just registered it.
We told javascript about it.
So we will now execute it once we get rolled to rolled 3 4 5.
Cool and we can do this within a loop if we wanted to.
We can even call functions within other functions so some games will have you roll a bunch of dice at
the same time like Yahtzee.
I think you roll five or six.
I know there's other a bunch of other games not much of a gambler but let's make up a function called.
How about throw dice and throw dice.
We'll simply call roll die.
How about six times.
We could do it like this or we could do it with a loop but just to make it simple and clear that it's
running six times.
I'll do it manually by writing it out six times a loop would probably make more sense if we wanted to
have throw dice in the future potentially change the number of roles so we could have throw dice to
throw dice 6 for different games but this is good enough we're not there yet.
We'll refresh the page nothing happens and that's because I haven't executed either function so I'm
going to call throw dice if I can spell it.
Which in turn calls roll die six different times each time this code runs and we get some number printed
out.
There we go.
4 6 1 4 2 2.
So we've seen more repetition of how we define a function but also the new component here is that we
can call functions from inside other functions.
We can call them in loops you can call them in conditionals we can call them pretty much anywhere.