Now that we've got no jazz installed we're going to set up a new little project and just figure out
how to run code with node inside of a workspace directory inside of my terminal inside of here.
I'm to make a new folder called simply node 0 then change into there and I'll start up my code editor
inside once I have my code editor open I'm gonna create a new file called index dot J.S. and inside
of here I'll do a very simple console log of hi there like so usually to run some javascript code that
we run right inside of our Ed throughout this course we've been creating an index on each team I'll
file but like we just said we don't have to worry about each HTML anymore now that we're making use
of node.
So in order to run this file we can now go back over to our terminal we can verify that the index dot
J.S. file is right there and then we can run node index dot J.S. like so that's going to read the contents
of the index dot J.S. file and execute everything inside of their I believe it or not.
This is just one way that we could run code with node is actually two different ways we can use the
node CLIA to run some javascript code.
The first is to run node and then the name of the file in the same directory.
We can technically execute files in different directories.
We just have to provide a relative path.
The vast majority of time however you're going to be running code inside of a file in the same directory.
That's how we run code inside of a file.
We can also run javascript code with node by entering the node rebel.
We can do this by just running the command node by itself.
So if I go back over to my terminal I can run node by itself without any file name you'll notice that
it kicks me to kind of a prompt right here.
So again this is called the node rebel and we can use this to execute one off javascript statements.
This is just about identical to the console that we've been making use of inside the browser throughout
this course.
So for example I can define some variable called say message sign it a string of Hi there and then print
out that string like so I can also add numbers or do just about anything else I can create a data object
just about anything you can possibly imagine.
We will very frequently be making use of the node rebel which we're using right now.
Any time that you want to just test out little snippets of code but usually in general we almost always
make use of node by executing a distinct file that has some amount of code inside of it.
Now one thing I want to mention right now and I'm going to mention this several times throughout the
course as we continue using Node if you ever want to stop a node program yet one is being executed through
a file or the rebel.
All you have to do is press control see on your keyboard.
So if I go back over and to the replay right here I can press control C twice and I get kicked back
over to my terminal.
All right now you've seen the basics of writing some code.
Well let's start to dive into some more advanced stuff around node in the next video.