We are able to update a product but as I just mentioned we still have this kind of big air around our
handle errors function.
It's only just reiterate what the issue is right now handle errors is going to receive the name of some
templates where the template function that we need to run if anything goes wrong with our validators.
So something goes wrong with the validator handle errors is going to invoke that template right there
it's going to render it and then return or send back to whoever made the request whatever is inside
that template.
So the big issue we are running into is that if we take a look at handle errors here's our middleware
such as file when we run the template function.
The only thing we pass in is art as an argument is the object that has the errors that occurred during
validation but in our case if we look at products at J.S. inside of our views directory you and I know
that this template expects to be called with some object that has a product property so our Middleware
is calling the template with just errors but the template wants to see product so whenever there is
an error in our temple gets rendered by handle errors product does not exist product is undefined.
So we then attempt to look up some properties like title and price on product which is undefined which
leads to the very classic error message that we're going to see in JavaScript all the time of cannot
read property title of undefined so in order to fix this error.
We need to figure out some way to essentially call handle errors right here back at our post request
handler but simultaneously tell it to render the template along with some extra data so we're going
to use a little trick to make this happen.
We're gonna write out a little bit of code the first iteration through this code that we write is gonna
be just a little bit confusing but as usual once we write it and go over it very confident that you
will understand what is going on.
So let's get to it.
We're going to start to change the signature of handle errors.
We're gonna say that handle errors still has to always receive a template as the first argument but
now optionally it can also receive a second argument.
This is a key to how we're going to fix this.
So for the second argument again it is optional.
We're going to say that it is going to be a function that is going to be executed only if something
went wrong with the validation step.
Inside of this optional second argument this function that we're gonna pass in we're going to return
an object that has some data that is going to be forwarded automatically onto our template.
So that's how we're going to fix it.
Now that's just a very quick like one sentence overview.
So I'd start to write some code and see what is really going on it's going to provide a callback function
here.
It's going to be async in nature and I'm going to expect that it's going to receive as the first argument
a wreck object.
It's like our actual request object then inside I'm going to look at the product that we were trying
to display or trying to edit.
In this case so I can look that up by doing a weight products repo get one and then to get the product
we actually care about we will call get one with the I.D. write it out of that you l remember we can
get access to whatever ideas right there by referencing rec not brands that idea and then we will return
an object that has product as the key in product as the value and as usual because those are the same.
I'll condense it down to just products like so OK.
So even if the purpose of this function is not clear right now I think you can agree with me that you
can probably understand what it does all it does is taken a request object it looks up in appropriate
product and then returns that product inside of an object.
So this object right here this is what we want to somehow get into our template let's now go over to
our middleware file.
We're gonna make some updates to handle errors inside there.
We're going to make sure that we run this function.
We take whatever gets returned and pass this return value right here.
This object as an additional piece of data into our template okay.
So I'll go to roots admin middleware start J.S. here's our handle errors middleware.
So going to first receive that second argument that we are now passing it now we'll call it data CV
short for data callback
then inside of my request body or some in the middleware body right after we decide to actually send
back some error to the user because hey something went wrong right here.
This right here like right here.
This is where we're going to call that data CB function.
So we're gonna call it function.
We're going to get whatever object or value gets returned and we're going to add that as some additional
data that goes into our template function so we do have to be aware that data CB is going to be an optional
argument.
So we first have to check and see if data CB was provided at all.
So I'll say if data CB So if data CV exists and it was passed in.
OK let's go ahead and call it and we're going to store the data that it returns they'll do in a weight
data CV and we know based on what we wrote over here that it expects a first argument of the request
object.
So when we call data CV I can make sure that I pass in the request which was given as an argument to
our middleware
so now we need to capture the value that comes back.
We can not use the concert keyword like so right here because now we have data defined on this Interscope
and we would not be able to access data outside of the if statement.
So instead I'm going to define right about the if statement using the left keyword a variable called
data and then rather than defining it inside the if statement I'm going to just update the value of
data.
Now I can freely access the data variable outside of that if statement
now finally that we have the data we care about.
So that's going to be an object that has a product key and a product value.
We're going to take that thing and we're going to merge it in with the existing object we have right
here it's right after errors I'll say comma dot dot dot data.
So essentially take whatever keys and values are inside of that data object and merge it in with this
existing one.
Now there is the possibility that data will be undefined.
So in other words if we define data right here by default it gets a default value of undefined if we
did not get a data callback then we're not going to run that if statement and the value of data will
never be updated.
And so we'll be trying to do a dot dot dot undefined that shouldn't result in error but just to prevent
that possibility of a default the value of data and assign it to an empty object.
So even if we don't have a data callback we won't be trying to spread in an undefined value right there.
Okay.
That should pretty much be at so once again all the way from the top here's our poster.
Quest handler.
If something goes wrong with validation we're going to invoke the callback function.
We then get this return value eventually of the object as a product inside of it.
Then our Middleware is going to check to see if a data callback was provided.
If it was it's going to call it.
It's going to take that value.
It's going to spread it into the ears object that eventually goes off to our template function.
And so now our template function will have access to the data we care about.
It will have access to the product and be able to show some details about that product again.
All right now before we test this one last quick change inside of here we just made use of the await
keyword.
Let's make sure that we mark the enclosing function as being async so I'll say return async right there.
Now we should be good to go.
Lastly I want to mention is that our template right now so products at.
J.S. is not using that ear's object just yet.
So even though we might fail validation I'm not going to expect to see any validation messages appear.
Okay.
Let's get to it.
I'll go back to my form and actually just to test out the entire flow offers go back to my products
listing and then hit edit and then on my title I mean just going to delete the title entirely.
So that's definitely in a fail validation.
I'll then submit it and I'm take back to the exact same form with the same default value being applied.
So it's clear that the validation just failed and my server chose to re render this edit form when it
rendered the edit form it tried to throw in the existing title once again into that input.
Now last thing to do.
Clearly this is working.
Last thing I to do is just make sure that we actually show some validation messages on our form so that
the user knows why they are being returned directly back to this form when they click submit so for
that we can go back to our views admin products and at DOT j ust file at the top will once again get
the helper function that we put together called get error.
So I'll get get error now require that from up to directories.
Right.
So yeah we're gonna go up to admin and then View's helpers
so we can call get error.
We'll make sure that we receive the errors object that's going to be passed in from our middleware
and then after our input we'll do some string interpolation we'll call it get error we'll pass on the
errors object and the property that we want to look at inside of it which is title a copy paste that's
for price as well okay.
Let's save this and do one last test.
So I'm going to go back to my product's listing page once again I'll attempt to edit and add delete
the title I'll hit submit.
And there we go there's our validation.
So I tried to submit a product or change the product that didn't have a title and so we saw the validation
appear.
I should also be able to delete the price entirely hit submit and see must be greater than 1 Okay.
So that definitely means that our edit functionality is working out just OK so this is looking pretty
good.
So let's take a pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to once again do a quick copy paste of a template just
to get some better styling on this edit form.