The first of this new group of array methods we'll talk about is called for each for each accepts a
callback and accepts a function.
And it calls it on every element in a given array.
It's an Array method.
So we call it on the array.
Here's my number array.
We do numbers for each.
Just like we would do num stock index of or NUM stop reverse both of the examples here are using anonymous
function expressions.
They're just one time things that I'm trying to do.
I could also create a function I could define it first and then pass the name of the function in.
But again the goal of for each is that it takes whatever function you give it.
And it calls it on each element it passes each value into that function so let's try a simple example.
I have an array called numbers not exciting I know 20 21 22 and so on if I call numbers for each and
I pass in a function we'll start with an anonymous function here.
I need to give it a parameter.
I can name this whatever I want but it is going to store it will represent one element at a time.
So the very first time for each runs the first iteration it will call whatever I have here.
This function and it will pass in the value of 20.
So I'll go with NUM or n.
It doesn't matter element l something descriptive.
And then I'll use num in here we'll start really simple will console that log NUM and if I run this
code there we go 20 21 all the way to twenty seven.
So for each.
Calls this function however many times it needs to and it passes each element in one at a time.
So we could also do consider that log Num Times to just as a quick example here and we get forty forty
two forty four.
Great.
We could have also written a function ahead of time let's do print double.
Let's do triple.
Just to have something a little different.
And it will accept a single number we'll call it n and it will cancel that log and times three.
So now I have a standalone function called Print triple.
And I can call numbers dot for each and pass in print triple.
Just like that.
So this is accomplishing the same thing.
Well we're tripling here instead of doubling but it's the same idea numbers that for each.
This function we're telling for each.
Here's the function I want you to call for each element.
So internally it would call print triple with 20 and then afterwards 21 and then afterwards 22.
And it does it until it hits the end of the array.
So if we double check this one now we get print triple 0 comment this out so we can just see it on its
own.
There we go.
60.
Down to eighty one twenty times three sixty.
Twenty seven times three is eighty one.
So two different ways of using for each javascript doesn't care.
They're both functions.
The main difference is that this is a function we can reuse if we needed to.
Which is great but a lot of the time with for each and a lot of these methods we'll see in this section
you're just trying to get some code to run you don't care about having a name for that function being
able to reuse it.
It's just a one time thing.
So in that case you would use an anonymous function or it would make sense to at least you don't have
to.
So we pass in that function it's called Let's do another example here.
I have a more complex array where each element is an object.
Let's say I want to print out every title.
We'll just start with that.
I want to print each title using for each.
I would call books which is the name of the array dot for each function and we'll call this place holder
this parameter B or book it represents one element in that array which in our case happens to be an
object and then to print the title.
I would just cancel that log book dot title and let's do dot to uppercase.
So if I refresh we now get four different book titles in all caps.
So for each is going to pass in each element.
In this case the element is an object.
It's not a single number like we had earlier it's a whole object and then we can do whatever we want
in here.
Now you might be thinking this doesn't seem that useful because we have things like for loops or for
of I could do the exact same thing using a four.
So I would do four let book of books control that log and I'll just copy that line over will comment
this one out and we get the same output.
And you're right this works.
It is different.
This is not identical obviously the syntax is different but the key difference as far as javascript
is concerned is here.
We have a function that's being called this is just a block that doesn't really mean much.
In this example but I just want you to understand there is a difference.
So yeah you could use a for of loop for each has been around much longer than four.
So we used to not have this option at all.
We had a regular for loop for let ie equals zero.
I is less than book book stout length.
I plus plus.
And then we would cancel this out but we don't have book we would have to do books of I got title to
uppercase and this would give us the same thing but it's just nicer in my opinion to do a for each or
a for of where we don't have to use IE if we don't care about the index we're not using the index except
to access each element then why use it.
So for each was the alternative we use for a long time.
People still use for each but we also now have four of you can use it to achieve the same end.
So here are all three versions doing the same thing.
Now there's one other thing to know about for each.
We can also add a second parameter to our callback to the function here if we want to use the index.
So if I wanted to print out each actually let's do it up here instead of books let's go back to numbers
if I wanted to print out the index and then the no using a for each.
I could do numbers for each pass in my callback.
We'll call this numb and then the second parameter.
This is how for each works the second parameter will be the index which we can call eye I.D. X index
and we'll just do a simple console that lug index comma num we run it and then we go zero element is
20 element 1 21 all the way down to element 7 twenty seven.
So this is nice.
If you need the index sometimes you do.
You could use a for each.
There's not an easy way to get an index.
If you're using a regular four up although if you use a regular for loop you definitely can't get it.
You have to generate it yourself using you know I and I less than whatever I plus plus with for each.
You get the index for free.
So what's happening here is that this function is being called each time for one element and for each
is passing in it not only the element but it passes in the index.
And if you don't use that index it's still being passed in for each.
Is just saying here's the number or here's the element and here's the index for that element.
You can ignore it.
You don't have to accept it or do anything with it but it's going to be passed in.
And so if you want it you can capture it as a parameter.
All right.
So that's for each.
Again it's the simplest of these methods we'll see it accepts a callback and it runs that callback once
per element in the array where that elements value will be an argument to the callback.