Before we move on.
There are some prerequisites some things that you need to be comfortable with before you can really
master the.
Before this content will make sense to you.
Those topics are basic.
Each team L and C assess the good news is that each team out and c assess are really pretty easy to
learn the basics of at least.
We're not talking about making beautiful websites we're not talking about crazy complex layouts that
are responsive.
You just need to understand how to create simple elements on a page had a nice things together how to
work with ideas and classes how to write simple CSF selectors to select based off of elements in classes
and ideas maybe attributes you need to understand how to change color to see assess and fonts and how
to resize something the basic properties.
So if you don't have that understanding right now I recommend you take an hour or two to go follow a
tutorial online.
You can check out my youtube channel.
I have a basic HD mounts SS intro but there are also tons of great courses paid and free and books and
free blog posts.
You don't need to go buy an expensive course or even buy anything just take some time and set it aside
so that this section in the next few sections actually makes sense to you because this stuff is really
exciting.
It's fun but if you don't have that understanding of HD humility RSS it's just going to be intimidating
and make it a lot more challenging than it needs to be because this dumb stuff is actually not hard
where it gets tricky is when people try and learn it before they understand each team L and C assess.
So I'm gonna do a little demo slash assessment that you can self assess based off of.
I'm going to write some simple h t amounts to assess to show you the level of understanding I'm looking
for.
So I have an HMO file already created.
I'm going to add some simple elements in here will add an H1 and this will say my webpage.
I'm going to add a simple l an unordered list with a couple of allies.
First thing second thing and third thing.
So I have an ally.
Here are three allies in an unordered list.
To add an image.
I'll set the source to be this nice grizzly bear image from on Splash dot com.
Nice images that we can use for free and I will also go ahead and add in maybe a paragraph tag or two
paragraphs just let's do some warm Epsom so I can just type lower them in V.S. code and then I'll add
another one of those Lorem just random text I'll add an idea to my image and I'll call this image.
We'll just call it bare photo.
So if you're still with me if this is all making sense and feels like very basic stuff that's good news.
If any of this is confusing you're not sure what these elements are.
You don't know what an idea's or a source.
Take some time.
Go learn that stuff because you'll need it.
You absolutely need it for the next couple of sections.
I don't want you to feel bad or get lost.
All right.
So we have our H one.
I'll also add a class to my allies.
Two of them at least this class will be called special okay.
So I have two paragraphs.
I have my H one I have allies that have a class of special I have an ally that doesn't and I have an
idea for my image of bare photo.
Now I'm gonna make a style sheet so I'll just make my file here.
I'll call it apt C Ss and I'm going to start by styling my H1.
Just something simple.
Color Purple font size 20.
That can be very small.
How about 60 pixels.
So I haven't connected my style sheet but let's just make sure my content is showing up all right now.
I'll connect my style sheet using a link tag and the address is app that see SS in my H1 should change
it's purple now and larger.
So if this syntax is new to you you haven't seen it.
You don't know what font size does or color.
I guess that's pretty self-explanatory but if you're not sure about the syntax here then take some time
and review that.
Let's also go and select the bear image.
So here's the first part of the assessment.
How would we styled this bear image to give it a width of two hundred and fifty pixels using the idea.
All right so I'm going to come in here and select it with Bear dash image and I need to make sure I
add in a bear photo.
Jeez horrible name I can even remember it.
Need to make sure I add in my hash symbol there to make it clear.
It's an I.D. and I'll give it a width of two hundred and fifty pixels refresh my page much more manageable.
The next part of the assessment I'd like for you to make the class of special these two allies.
I'd like them to be teal and 30 pixels font size and give them a 1 pixel border.
Also teal so we'll select the class which was called special.
I need to use the dot because it's a class and I'm going to start with color.
What do they say.
Teal and then font size.
I think I said 30 pixels and border was one pixel teal.
Let's see what we get.
All right so there is my special class so I've styled the H1 the image with the idea of bare photo and
the two items the two allies that have a class of special it looks horrendous.
It's very gross but this stuff is very important.
Don't worry about the styles but if you feel like any of this was new or confusing you need some clarity
on it.
Go look online and get some practice.
Now here's one more thing that you could use as a little assessment.
Let's add in a form.
All right so I'll add a form element right here and in this form I'm going to add an input type equals
text.
I'd like to give it a place holder of what should we do.
Bear name and then another input follow that.
And instead of type equals text what are our options here.
Well do you type equals.
How about password and then give it a place holder of password and then one more input will do type
equals submit or refresh.
And we have our form here.
What I'd like you to do is select only the input that has type of password and give it a different with
you can change it to smaller larger.
Just give it a different width and height so you'll have to select based off of the type not off of
input.
Don't add an I.D. don't add a class selected as is so I'm gonna do that over here.
If I just did input like I did for H1 that will target all three and if I do height let's do 50 pixels
with 100 pixels that does work but I only want to target this one right here so I can add in an attribute
selector type equals password and now only this one is affected the other inputs are unchanged.
So that's it for the stuff.
I mean that's not everything you need to know but that's a general sampling of the kind of H2 Mal and
c assess experience you need.
You need to be able to do basic styles understand CSF syntax.
Key value pairs semicolons selecting based off of classes ideas elements attributes.
There's a bunch of other selectors and we may come across some of them in the course but this is most
of what we'll be selecting based off of in our javascript.
And then as far as elements things like inputs definitely paragraph tags H ones all the headings buttons
list items all the different text elements paragraphs semantic elements like block quotes sections articles.
You don't have to be an expert in everything just I want you to be comfortable enough where you're not
focused on the H to mount to assess so much and trying to understand it that you're missing out on the
DOM stuff which is fun.
All right.
So now we're gonna move on to the DOM again please take this seriously.
I mean you're obviously able to make your own decision and do what you think is best and if you want
to just plow ahead without HMRC assess experience it's definitely possible you'll pick it all up at
once but for the best experience I recommend that you you get some practice first take some time away
if you're just a bit you're not going to miss out too much.
The course will still be here for you to get better with age demands to assess and then come back.
All right.
So let's get going.