Next up we have another property that is kind of similar to enter text and text content.
It's called inter HMO but it has a different name obviously and it has different purpose so inter HMO
is going to return or retrieve not only the text instead of an element but also all other tags inside
of a given element.
So if I were to call form if I select this form dot enter HMO I would get all of these elements.
If I were to do form dot in our text there is no in our text here.
So let's try to select the form.
I'll do a query selector document dot query selector of form.
There's only one form I'll get the first one I'll save it to a variable called form and then form dots
inner HMO.
All caps on it on the HMO portion see what I get here.
I'm getting a string that contains all of the elements inside.
So I get everything between those two tags.
It could be text.
It could be other tags.
It all just gets grouped in inter HMO.
If I were to try it on one more thing let's select the first.
Well we find I'll do.
Document the query selector.
You will save that to a variable.
Just give it the name of.
Well not very creative.
Do you well that inner text.
We saw this in the last video we get first thing second thing third thing and that's because that's
the entire text.
It's skipping the actual text.
Now if I do you well that inner HMO I get all of the content in there the ally and the text the ally
the text ally and the text all the attributes are there everything that I wrote in the HMO is showing
up and I can use inter HMO to update the insides of an element the the insides to change the content
in between the two tags.
If I wanted to sew for the form which is right here I could do this form dot enter HMO equals and then
just pass in some text if I wanted to and that entire form now only contains this text if I go to the
elements tab and I look at the form that's it everything that was there before is gone I kind of destroyed
it which is usually not what you want to do but sometimes maybe it is.
And if we were just sitting text then I would probably use enter text but we can also add HMO elements
in the annoying part is that we have to make them a string enter text enter HMO text content they all
return Strings so no objects are involved here except for the object that we're actually selecting.
I have my form that's an object of course but if I do inner city email again and I want to set it to
contain some other element I can pass in a string and write each team out in there.
So this is fine for simple elements but if you're doing something more complex it can be kind of annoying
to type it all as a giant string and we'll see another way of adding elements later on in the same section.
But just to show that it works let's do enter each team our equals what could we add inside the form.
How about a bold tag.
I am a bold tag close it correctly will hit enter.
Now we have a bold tag in there so enraged him allows us to pass in a string containing text containing
each came out elements and what it will do is actually pass this string and look for those text it's
it's going through it and figuring out OK what is an element here what is just text and then it reflects
those changes in the DOM.
And now if we look at form this is getting a bit ahead of ourselves but if we do a console that desire
of form and if we look at its children it has a new object as a child it has a bee object.
It's an element so it's not just about setting the text and the browser just inserting that in between
the the tags.
It's actually reading this and creating a bold object a bold tag object and that's what we see here.
So it does take more time because of that compared to enter text.
If you're just setting text but if you need to add elements you can do it this way.
But as I mentioned it gets obnoxious especially if you have attributes with quotation marks and you've
got to mix and match your quotes now with template literal strings.
It's not too bad but still there are other ways of adding elements we're just not there yet.
Now the last thing about inter HMO versus inter text let's select the H1 so document dot query selector.
I'm just going to stick to query selector for most of this because it's our Swiss Army knife.
It's so versatile.
We'll save it to a variable called H1.
I now have H1.
We'll look at Inter text.
We'll look at Inter HMO.
Great.
If I wanted to add something in to my Web page the first thing I'll show you that we haven't seen you
can do this.
You can do.
Plus equals.
If you don't want to completely override what's there you want to keep my web page.
And for some reason I also want to add is cool.
I'll put a space there because this string will just be added into what is already there.
And now we have my web page is cool.
Probably not that often that you would do it but you can.
But what I want to show you here is that there is a difference between inter HMO and inter text when
you are setting them.
When we retrieve them we've already seen the difference in our text does not give you the tags enter
each time Al does.
When you set them it seems like you could use either if I want to add an element into this each time
I'll tag it into his h1 tag let's say I want to.
I don't know.
Plus equals a bold tag with a bunch of exclamation points.
I could do H1 but enter each Timo plus equals and then I'll write my bold tag and then some exclamation
points like that close my quote and those are I guess it's kind of hard to tell what those are bolded
they're part of a heading but we can trust that they're bolded if we take a look at the H1 they are
inside of a bolt tag.
Now if I instead do this with inner text I'll just add more exclamation points.
Sure.
What do you think is going to happen.
That's what happens so it doesn't ignore the tags.
It just doesn't treat them as actual elements or tags for each team.
It doesn't pass them it doesn't understand that they are bold tags.
Instead it just takes this entire string and puts it in the element.
So we end up with the string of a bold tag.
So if you are trying to update HMO you're trying to add an element with inner HMO.
You need to use our HMO with Inter text.
You can't actually create new elements.
You can't tell the browser I want to insert a bold tag or an image.
It will just insert the text that you pass in the literal string.
All right.
So that's inner HMO.
Like I said there are other ways of creating elements.
So maybe not all that common they used once you see the other options but it's important to cover already.