All right.
Let's get started on the three factor in this video we're going to focus on extracting several different
root handlers from our index j ust file into a new routes admin off dot J File instead it's a back inside
my code.
Ed I'm going to create a new folder inside my project directory called Roots then inside there I'll
make another new folder called admin.
And finally inside of that folder I'll make a new file called off dot J.S. inside of here is where we're
going to essentially just cut and paste.
To be honest all the different root handlers that we put together so far are gonna open up the index
dot J S file I'm going to find our first root handler of app dot get sign up and I'm going to select
everything down to the end of our sign in route handle it.
So essentially just a right above the app dot listen I'm going to highlight all that stuff I'm going
to cut it over to off dot J J.S. and paste
OK.
So I've now got inside of here one 2 3 4 and 5 different root handlers.
Now we need to immediately start to require some different stuff into this file.
For example this file definitely relies upon the user's repo.
So we need to make sure that we require the user's repo into this update J.S. file.
Let's do that right away at the top.
I'm going to add in concept users repo is required and then remember any time that we require in a file
that you and I wrote we have to provide a relative path from this off dot J.S. file that we're currently
working in to the file that we want to get access to.
So in this case we have to go up into the roots directory and then into our home directory and then
into repositories and then get the users file but to do so we're going to go up into roots.
So dot dot slash up into the root rectory.
So another dot dot slash and go into repositories and then get users.
That's how we write out that require statement okay.
That looks good.
Next up we'll do a quick scan and see if there are any other things we need to require inside of here.
So I'm looking through really quickly I don't really see anything else that we are leaving out besides
users repo.
OK.
So that's a pretty easy fix aren't the require statements.
The next two we need to figure out.
That's gonna be a little bit more complicated is.
Well the root handlers themselves.
So all of our different root handlers we are changing on a different route to our app object but the
app object is created inside the index not J.S. file.
So how are we going to somehow associate all these different root handlers with that app object well
in order to get all these root handlers kind of migrated or linked back up inside of the index not just
file.
We're going to create something called a sub router inside of the order J.S. files so the one that we
just created a sub router is essentially the same kind of router that is built into the app that we
created back over here or we can create a separate router separately or less inside that off J.S. file
export it then require it into index not J.S. and link it up to at even though that might sound really
complicated.
Honestly at the end of the day you can imagine that we're really just going to create a second app inside
of here more or less associate our roots with it export that app required into indexed J.S. and link
it up to this one.
That's kind of what you can pretend what is happening.
It's really not going to be as bad as it might sound.
So here's what we're going to do at the very top I'm going to require in
Express and then after all of our require statements I'm gonna write out ruder equals express dot router.
Like so.
So even though I'm calling this router we really can think of it as being just like that app object.
It's essentially an object that's gonna keep track of all of the different root handlers that we set
up.
The only difference is that with this router object we can link it back up to our app inside the index
not just file so to make use of this router.
We're going to go to all five of our root handlers inside of Opt-Out J.S. and wherever we currently
have app we're going to replace it with router.
That's pretty much it.
Here's number one I'll replace app with router
here's an order to replace app with router
number three number four and number five and at the very bottom to file we'll do a module dot exports
of the router so we can make all these different root handlers available to other files inside of our
project.
Now to associate this router with our app we'll go back to index dot J.S. at the top.
I'm going to remove the user's repo require statement since we don't need that inside of here anymore.
Or then require in the router that we just created from that update J.S. file.
So I'll say off router is roots admin off and then to hook up that router with our app object and make
sure that all the routes so we bound to it are accessible just as they were before right after our apt
use cookie session.
Make sure it's right after really important that we add this after the two middleware so we've hooked
up so far we'll do app not use off router.
Like so and that's pretty much it.
So that is how we are going to extract different root handlers into different files.
All you have to do is create the other file inside that file.
We're going to create a router we'll associate some different root handlers with that router well then
import the router into our index dot J as file and do app dot use whatever the name of the router it's
not to make sure that we didn't break anything as usual.
Let's go back over to our browser.
I'll go to local those three thousand refresh and whatever your l I try to access here like sign up
I should still see the same forms that I saw before.
Log out or see me sign out my mistake and so on to make sure that all the same year ls so we've been
accessing so far still work with the of course obvious exception of the route routes we don't have anything
at our route route anymore.
We used to have our sign up form there but we extracted that into a separate u r l of slash sign up
okay.
That is a pretty good start for our refactor so quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're gonna start to extract a lot of the HD email that we're putting
together into a couple of different files that we're going to locate inside this abuse directory.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.