Now that we have a better idea of what we're trying to build.
Let's get started working on this application before we write any code however I want to go through
a couple of different steps here to make sure that we've got a really solid plan on how we're going
to tackle this application.
The first thing we're going to do is set up a little boilerplate for our project so attached to this
video there is a zip file that has some starter files inside of it.
If you haven't downloaded that zip file already and pause the video and download the zip file right
now I've already downloaded that zip file and I've extracted its contents onto my computer inside of
that zip file are three different files.
The index not HDL file a javascript file and a CSX file.
Once you get those files on your computer make sure you also open them up inside of your code.
Ed. So I've already done that right here.
Here's the small file.
The JavaScript file in the C Ss 1 then finally makes sure you open up the index not each email file
inside of your browser.
Once you do so you're going to see a initial screen like this right here OK.
So once you've got that all set up on a very quickly just mentioned exactly what this term boilerplate
is referring to when we talk about a boilerplate package we're talking about some essentially starter
code for a project usually a boilerplate.
We'll have a little bit of setup already done inside of it.
And usually it's going to have some code or h t mail or styling that is generally kind of repetitive
between different projects.
So it's really just a good starting point to begin from.
I know that sometimes using a starter package is kind of annoying and you might prefer to write out
everything from scratch.
So you really understand what is going on just so you know the only real setup that I've done inside
of this little boilerplate package is for the most part just some styling.
So just some C Ss to make sure that the end product that we end up with is going to look really nice.
This is of course about JavaScript and Nazi SS and that's why I did all these C Ss for you upfront.
You can't of course review that CSX file at the end of this application and get a better idea of what's
going on inside there if you want to OK.
So now that we've got a little bit of setup done let's take a pause right here and then identify some
challenging aspects of this project in the next video.