All right so there are two pieces a sink and a wait.
Two separate keywords.
We're gonna start with async so we use async in front of a function declaration or function expression.
We use it to designate a certain function as an async function.
And the key thing to understand about this keyword is when you put it in front of a function like I
have here.
This function behaves differently.
It's now going to return a promise.
So even though I never write new promise I don't explicitly say hey Return a promise.
I'm simply saying return a string because I put async there.
The function now returns a promise and I can show this to you.
Let's make a simple function we'll just call it greet function greet console about log.
Actually that's not console dot log let's return.
Hello.
Okay.
No surprise if I call greed right now it's not an async function we get a string back javascript 1 0
1 return a string we get a string.
Now if I duplicate this and put the async keyword in front of my function declaration.
Now when I call green what I get is a promise promise that was returned and resolved with the value
of Hello.
So whatever the value that I'm returning is the promise that will be returned from Greece will be resolved
with that value.
So I could do something like greet dot then and we'll just call this Val and then we can cancel that
log promise resolved with.
And then we can add in Val so I can chain on a dot then because greed is now going to return a promise.
Tested out.
There we go.
Promise resolved with Hello.
Let's say we have another function.
This one will be trivial as well.
Let's go with ADD and it takes an X and Y.
It returns the sum of X plus Y.
Right now if we don't make it async it just returns a number.
Assuming we pass in two numbers if we make it async by putting the async keyword first.
If I call add we get a resolved promise with the value that it's resolved with set to nine so I could
use a dot then these two simple functions make kind of no sense at all to use promises with or to make
async because they're not doing anything asynchronous.
Why use a promise.
But the next thing I want to mention is how do we return a promise that is not resolved.
So things go well.
We return a value return the string hello.
That promise returned from Greece is going to be resolved with Hello.
Or with the number nine in this case if we add four and five.
But sometimes we want to make promises where they might be rejected they might be resolved and instead
of an async function.
If we want to return a rejected promise all that we do is raise an exception.
So if we throw an exception we throw an error.
That promise will be rejected.
So if we use this add example let's check if X and Y are actually numbers.
If they're not we'll throw some sort of exception.
So we could just check if X do type of x equals number or if it's not equal to number let's do that.
Or type of y is not equal to number.
Then we can throw X and Y must be numbers OK so let's not make this an async function for a moment just
a regular old function.
If we run it and I call ad with E and I don't know 5 There we go uncut.
Exception X and Y must be numbers.
So the logic works.
No promises involved whatsoever.
We call it with numbers instead everything's good.
Now if I make it async tried again ad 4 and 5 we have a return value.
This code was running and so the promise is resolved with that return value.
If I call it with a string something that's not a number we still get a promise back.
But it's been rejected.
X and Y must be numbers so I could call add on E and R sure I can put on my dot.
Then let's go with Val console dot log and I just copy this here.
Promise resolves with Val and I can put a catch as well and promise rejected with and then we'll print
the error so I'm just calling ad but add is an async function which means it returns a promise.
It may be rejected.
It may be resolved.
I can handle it either way.
And if we take a look and run my code we get promise rejected with X and Y must be numbers.
So at this point async functions are what we've seen.
They're a nice way of returning a promise.
Take a moment and think of how you would write this yourself.
So without using an async function but by manually creating the promise and resolving slash rejecting
it here's what I would do.
It would look something like this function ad X come away.
Then we would return a new promise.
We have our resolve function parameter and reject.
And if none of this looks familiar to you.
Make sure you check out the promises section.
I can't say that enough.
It really helps.
So we have our new promise.
And then in here we can move this logic but we're going to change it a bit.
If type of x is not a number or type of y is not a number.
Instead of throwing we're going to reject that promise like that.
And then here we would resolve with X plus Y.
So if I comment out my async version and we take a look at our manual promise creation it's called add
this code should still work fine.
So I should be catching this error.
The rejected promise and we get the same output.
If I instead due to numbers like I don't know why I keep doing 4 and 5 6 and 7 refresh promise resolved
with 13.
All right.
So in async function on one level is just a short cut syntax to make a function that returns a promise
if you return a value like we do here that value will be the value the promise is resolved with.
If you throw an exception instead that promise will be rejected with this value.
So our dot then callback or our DOT catch callbacks still work.
But this is not all there is to async functions.
That is the async keyword.
And shortly we'll see the await keyword which makes things even more magical.