There is still another issue or two with our testing framework.
So in this video we're going to write out another test and very quickly determine what that other issue
is.
So the next test I want to work on is going to try to enter in some text right here like a valid email
and then submit the form to the test that we're going to write out is going to make sure that we eventually
see the text right here that says looks good.
So let's give this a shot back inside of my app dot test dot J J.S. file or write out another statement
so say it shows a success message with a valid email and I will make sure that I mark this function
as a sync of course so instead of here we're going to render the index not a single file once again.
So let's say con storm is a weight render index dot each email and now this time that you want to again
find the input element but this time we want to change its value and then attempt to submit the form
itself.
So first get a reference to the input element to do so we'll write out dorm window document not query
selector and we'll look for an input once we find that input we'll then try to change its value.
So say input dot value is some valid email so I'll put in some gibberish while Broadcom remember the
only check we're doing right now is for the at sign.
So whatever email you put in here it just needs to have an outside to be considered to be valid.
It's now that we've got that input all we have to do is trigger a form submission event for that we're
going to try to select the form element.
There's only one on our index not Asian Chanel file and we will manually dispatch an event of type submit.
So this will be very similar to that earlier thing that we did where we tried to convince some input
element that we were trying to imitate chain urged me to input the event on as well.
So we're going to first select the form so we'll do Dom window document and I'm going to indent your
on to the next line just to give myself a little bit of space to type because this entire line right
here is going to eventually be a very long it's all chained down a dot query selector and look for form.
And then once we find that form remember we're going to dispatch an event and then whenever we dispatch
the event we're going to pass in a new event object and that has to be loaded with the type of event
that we want to dispatch.
So we'll say new Dom dot window dot event and I want you to make sure this thing thinks that it's getting
a submit event so I'll put an submit right there.
All right then after that we'll go ahead and select our each one element and we should build to take
a look at the inner each symbol on it and verify that it has some text like looks good or something
similar.
So just like my H1 I'll declare an each one variable and we'll do once again Dom window document dot
query selector and I'll look for an H1 now before we actually write out an assertion statement like
that right there or anything similar luscious console log that each team l contained within this H1
and we'll run a test and just make sure that we can like manually inside of our terminal C that has
the correct inner each team out so I'll do a console log each one dot enter each CMO
All right.
This all like to me looks good.
We're rendering the Dom we are changing some input we're gonna submit the form and that should result
in the javascript code that we had written inside the index dot J has filed to be executed remember
in theory all this stuff right here is getting loaded up and executed by J.S. Dom and so when we dispatch
that event that code we wrote inside the index not J as files should see the form submission and then
do the validation and update that each one.
So again everything inside of here generally looks pretty good.
All right so let's say this I'm going to go back over to my terminal I'm gonna make sure I'm at once
again inside of sample web project and I'll run TMC inside there and OK.
Well it looks like both tests pass.
But remember a test passing just means that we did not throw an error during that test.
So you'll notice that there's a big gap right here.
That is the console log that we just added Let's met kind of update the console log right here.
I'll say contents of each one so we can really clearly see where that console log occurs so I'll save
that once again and now I can see contents of each one.
Nothing.
So it's very clear right now that are really our test is not working as expected or perhaps a better
way to say would be our application is not working as expected.
So again the code we have inside of this test file right here.
It looks good to me and just so you know like the test really is good.
The test is fine.
We don't really have changed the test any more than what you see.
So there's definitely some other issue that we need to figure out what's going on.
So we have to figure out what's happening here why we're not seeing the H1 content update and then put
together some fix.
So let's start to diagnose this problem in the next video.