All right.
Time for option number three here.
Interestingly option number three is kind of a combination of Option 1 and 2.
We're going to use a promise to kind of organize our code but simultaneously we're going to wait or
it can maintain a array of data and we're going to wait for every record inside that array to have some
data inside of it before we try to process anything but that kind of array collection process.
That was a very manual operation in option one right here is going to be done for us automatically with
this promise.
All helper method.
Let's talk about what that thing is really quickly OK so start all is a method that is built into javascript.
We're going to call it with an array of promise objects.
So essentially each of these promised one two three and four right here are going to be our different
l stack calls.
So it will really be like l stats with a file name I'll start with a file name and so on each of these
different promises are going to eventually resolve with some data that's gonna be our actual stats object
what promised not all does is wait for all these promises to be resolved as I'm going to take the data
from each of them throw all that data inside of an array and then give us that big array with all the
data.
So we make use of promised dot all anytime that we need to wait for many different operations to run
in parallel.
We want to wait for all them to resolve once they all resolve.
We get our information one thing that's really important to note here is that when we are making use
of promised all we only make use of the awake word on promised at all as opposed to each individual
El Stat call.
All right.
Let's now go back over to our editor in start to code up this solution all right.
I'm going to delete the or of loop that we have right here.
We'll start more or less from scratch.
I'm also gonna make sure that I have at least one of these El stack methods uncommitted so I'm gonna
go with the third one right here.
But it shouldn't make a difference as we saw in the last video which when we use so then inside my reader
statement I'm going to map over my file names array for each file name we're going to call El stat and
return the promise that gets created when we call it.
I'll say stat promises is file names dot map for each file name.
I'm going to return El stats with that given file name now stat promises is like this thing right here
is a big array with the promises from each El stat called So now we can pass that array to promised
at all.
So I'll say a weight room is not all and I'll pass in that array
so then promised not all is going to wait for all those different promises to resolve.
And it's going to eventually spit out a new array with all of our data inside of it.
So I will assign that to a variable called all stats like so
now stats has all of our stat objects inside of it.
We can once again iterate over it with a for loop.
So I'll say for let stats of all stats we once again are in a kind of a funny scenario here where these
stats object describes a file but it doesn't actually have a record of what that file name is.
So we have to get the index of each stats object and then use that index to look up the appropriate
file name inside the file names array as well let's say const index is all stats index of stats and
then we can do our final console log of the file name and whether it or not it is a file it's all due
console that log file names at index that's going to give us the appropriate file name and then stats
dot is file.
All right so that should be it.
So now we are once again doing all these different Elston operations in parallel which means we should
get way better performance.
Any time that we tried to run the stats operation on many different files at the same time let's now
save this thing to go back over to my terminal and run allez and hey everything still works and as usual
I can run MLS multiple different times and I'm going to see the output occur in the exact same order
every time as well.
Okay so that's pretty much it.
This right here is what we would call the good solution and in real life as a recording this video I'm
doing like little quote marks with my fingers.
The reason I'm saying that is that well the other solutions we had they worked.
We could definitely have the solutions we could write that code but this is in theory the right way
to do it because it doesn't have any of the downsides of the other approaches.
All right so this is looking pretty good.
But remember our original goal here of this entire application was to get all of our different file
names that we are retrieving to print out with some different colors depending on whether or not they
are a file or a folder.
So right now we're just doing a console log right here saying whether or not it is a file but instead
we want to do a console log with some different coloring of that text.
So one last thing to figure out.
Let's do that in just a moment.