Like I mentioned in the last video the real goal of our application is not to say true or false whether
something is a file but to color code all the different files and folders that we find here.
So in other words since empty folder is a folder it should be.
I don't know a different color or bolded or something like that.
So in order to figure out how to color code these things we can either go back to our council statement
right here and figure out how to make console log actually shows something with different colors.
Or alternatively we can have someone else figure that out for us.
Let me show you what I mean inside my browser.
I'm going to navigate to NPM J.S. dot com.
This is a repository or a registry of thousands and thousands of open source packages that we can very
easily add into our project NPM is included with the node j ust download number we downloaded and installed
node a little bit earlier NPM is a command line tool and also the name of this company that maintains
this repository so we can search through thousands of different packages and find one that will take
care of coloring at these console log statements for us.
I already took the liberty of looking up a package that we can use.
So we're going to search for something called Chuck c h a elk so the first result right here is Chuck.
If I click on it we're going to see some documentation for this package.
So this is a package that we can very easily install and use inside of our project as you can see right
here.
The entire goal of this package is to essentially format console log statements.
So we're going to use this to handle all this formatting of files and folders as opposed to figuring
out how to do it ourselves.
In order to make use this project we're going to install it into our project with the command npm install
and then the name of the package which in this case is Chuck if you look up here towards the top right
where it says install.
It says that another way of installing it is NPM.
I chuck NPM I chuck and npm install Chuck are the exact same commands you're going to see some documentation
refer to one or the other.
Again you can run either one second go back over to my terminal I'm going to make sure I'm inside my
project directory and then I will run npm install Chuck that's going to reach out to the NPM registry
download that package and add it into my project.
Let's not go back over to our project and see exactly what happened.
So back over here.
If I open up my package dot JS on file I'll see that I now have a cent section inside of your call dependencies.
And Chuck was added to it.
So this is telling anyone else who takes a look at my project that my project depends upon one outside
package and it's called Chuck.
And that is the version that my project needs to work correctly.
In addition to this update to the package dot J's on file I'll also find inside my folder Explorer here
on the left hand side that I've got a new folder called Node modules.
That is where all the dependencies that were installed for my project to get placed when we open up
that folder.
You'll see that there are many different entries inside there even though we only ran npm install for
a single project so the reason we see so many folders right here is that when we installed Chuck Chuck
itself has some dependencies that it requires to work correctly.
So the other folders we see inside of your are dependencies that are required by Chuck for it to work.
Now in order to use this package this Chuck package we can go back over to our indexed J.S. file at
the very top.
We're going to require it into this file just like we would a normal node standard library module just
like we've done with S and you till all say const Chuck is required.
Chuck and that's how we get access to this library now if you want to figure out how to actually use
it to console log some different colored strings out we can go and take a look at the documentation
so I can go back over to the docs I can scroll down a little bit and it will tell us exactly how to
use this thing.
So if we want to console log something out the color blue we will call choc dot blue.
Passing the string we want to log and then call it console log on the result.
So that is pretty much it.
Talk has support for many different colors.
We can look them up either through the documentation here or we can go down towards the bottom and see
all the different ways we can modify the different styles so we can add on some bold text we can italicized
underline and here's all the different colors so we can use as well.
So to delineate or distinguish between a file and a folder I'm just going to fold the folders.
You can definitely add in a color and you absolute can as a matter of fact I recommend you try out a
color but in my case I don't know if you are running a terminal with like a back black round or a white
one.
And so I do want to use some color here that's going to look really ugly on your machine.
So instead I'm just going to use bolt just to keep things nice and simple OK.
So I'm going to go back over to my editor.
I'm going to go down to where we have our console logs I'm going to change up the syntax here just a
little bit.
I'll say if stats dot is file and I want to print out that file name normally otherwise if it is not
a file so if it is a directory I'll do console dot log and then chalk dot bold file names at index and
I'm going to delete that previous console log that we had right there.
So now files should be printed out normally folders should be printed out with bold text instead going
to save this.
I'll go back over a run MLS and there we go.
It's kind of subtle to see right here but the folders that I have now empty folder and mode modules
are now just a little bit folder in the files of next day yes and so on are can normal text or standard
like I mentioned if you want to you can always add on some colors instead so you could use red yellow
blue whatever you want to try out.
But like I just mentioned I don't know what theme you are using.
So I don't want to show like using white here and then have you not able to see any of the actual text
that gets printed out so I'm going to stick with Bolt OK.
So that's pretty much it.
Well our project is looking good.
There is one last little thing we need to take care of however.
So quick pause and we'll tackle this last little item in just a moment.