Now that we are forming up the verticals and horizontals arrays correctly we know we are because we've
done a pretty good amount of testing.
We can now move on to the next neighboring cell and essentially recurs through all of our different
cells calling step through cell.
Each individual time remember the entire idea here of how we form the maze.
We start off at some individual location.
We then move on over here and then we repeat the same process for the cell going to all of its neighboring
cells as well that we have not yet visited.
So it is this recursion that's going to make sure that we walk through all the different cells of our
little maze okay.
So to do the iteration or some of the recursion we'll go back down to the if statements we are just
working on here they are right here and right after the if statement still inside the for loop I'm going
to call step through cell with next row and next column lights up.
So now let's save this.
We're going to go back over to the browser I'm going to refresh and I'll print out verticals and horizontals
and now in both these arrays.
We should see some number of values of both false and true.
I'm gonna take these false and true values and I'm going to go over to our little diagram right here
and I'm going to manually erase some of the walls and see if it forms an actual maze like the one that
we're trying to generate okay.
So we have verticals of I mean I'm just going to write this down really quickly.
TRUE FALSE FALSE TRUE.
AND THEN horizontals of False True True True False True.
So these are our verticals and these are our horizontals.
So again this kind of value right here corresponds to that one right there.
And for example that true down there responds to that wall right there.
So I'm going to go through any race all the true walls as remember.
True means that there is no wall available or no wall present.
So first we will take our verticals.
So going to delete that one and that one and that one and that one it's now the only verticals remaining
are that and that I can repeat the same process for horizontals as well.
So I've got on horizontals False.
True.
So that's open true that is open true and true and if we look at this pretty closely we can see.
Yeah.
Without a doubt we've got an actual maze here.
So that's pretty much it.
It looks like we have successfully formed up the vertical and horizontal arrays and we can now generate
a maze.
Remember one of the properties of our maze is that every single cell can be visited.
Essentially there are no portions of the maze that are completely blocked off or inaccessible.
And this is what is going to allow us to make sure that we can always have a starting position for the
ball that we're going to eventually show up there on the top left and the completion on the very bottom
right.
Like so.
All right.
So now that we are forming up the verticals in horizontals we can start to take all this data and render
it out onto our matter J.S. campus.
So let's take one last quick pause right here.
We'll come back the next video.
We're going to start to take our read verticals in horizontals.
We're going to iterate through all this stuff and we're going to figure out where we want to draw some
walls using matter J.S. so quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.