Now that we understand what the bug is we can't start to fix it.
So around fixing this issue with just I'm right here returning to soon I have some good news and bad
news.
The bad news is that there is nothing built into J.S. dam right now that will tell it to automatically
wait for all the different JavaScript files to be loaded and executed.
That's the bad news.
The good news is that we can write out some code to do that ourselves pretty darn easily.
We're gonna First write out a little bit of test code into our sample web project and I want to show
you how we can inside of a browser detect when all of our different JavaScript files have been loaded
and executed.
So let me show you how we're going to do this.
I'm going to first open up my index dot J.S. file inside of here right underneath our very selector
for the form right underneath that entire block.
I'm going to say window dot stuff loaded equals true
and I'm going to say this file and then going to go to my index dot each team l file inside the head
element I'm going to add in a little script tag
and inside that script I'll do a console dot log of window dot stuff loaded so now you can see that
I'm setting up one variable inside of index dot JSF and I'm trying to console log it inside of index
Dot.
Each team out.
Now I got a quick question for you.
If we were to save both these files right now and load it up inside the browser what would we expect
to see.
Console locked.
The answer is undefined.
The reason is that the way in which our browser executes stuff is it's going to first take a look at
everything inside this HMO file and it's going to essentially load and execute all these different tags
from top to bottom.
So the first thing that's going to be executed on the javascript side will be this script tag right
here.
So at that point in time we have not yet defined this property.
So we will see a console log of undefined then later on the browser will see the script tag right here
and we'll make an additional network request to get that file.
We will then execute everything inside the file including where we set up that property so in other
words right now when we refresh the browser I would expect to see a console log of undefined.
Let's test that really quickly so refresh and sure enough I see undefined so let's take a look at how
we can update the script tag right here and essentially say Hey don't run some little snippet of code
until all of our different JavaScript files have been loaded and executed to do so.
Inside that script tag I'm going to add in window that document and really my mistake we can really
just do document right here.
Document dot ad event listener.
And we're going to listen for an event of DRM content loaded now.
Really important here as I'm sure you can imagine.
Make sure you have capital D O M C and a capital L.
If you miss the capitalization This is not going to work as expected.
I'm not going to move my console log inside their we have now set up an event listener that's going
to watch for all the different things that we're referencing inside of our Dom to be loaded.
So in other words we're gonna wait for all the different scripts inside this H2 email structure to be
loaded and executed.
And once they are then the browser is going to call that callback function.
So if I save this now and go back to my browser new fresh NLC true right there which means that we did
successfully wait for the javascript file to be loaded before running that function so in general in
the browser.
That's how we can wait for stuff to be loaded.
How does this carry back over to j system.
However which is what we really care about.
Well remember when we make use of J.S. Dom we have a almost perfect replication of the browser available
to us inside of node so we show you how we can use this kind of technique to make sure that we're not
going to execute our tests until after all the appropriate files have been loaded.
Really quickly I'm going to delete that script tag right there and save the file.
I'll do the same thing back inside of index dot James I can remove that window about stuff loaded as
well and save it ok.
So now to actually implement this solution inside of our code base I'm gonna find the render dot J S
file.
So here's where we load up that file.
Now remember this Dom object right here is like a direct access to our entire documents so we can reach
inside there.
We could take a look at the DOM dot window dot document property and add an event listener to it of
Dom content loaded and then once we have access to that and we've got that event listener that's going
wait for or watch for all the different scripts to be loaded then we can eventually figure out some
way to delay our tests until after that event occurs.
So let me show you what I'm getting at.
We're gonna say Dom dot window that document.
So that's how we reference the document.
We've seen that once already inside of our tests.
We're gonna add that same kind of event listener to it of dumb content loaded we'll put in our callback
function and then for right now inside of here I'll do a console log of all done loading.
We're just gonna make sure this thing works first.
Let's save this and we'll go and run our tests again.
So right now our tests are still not going to work quite as expected.
I'm just going to expect to see this console log at some point time.
All I want to do right now is proof that this event right here does also get triggered when we're using
j ust on.
All right.
So back inside of sample what project will run to me.
And there we go.
All done loading.
Why do we see it twice.
Well it's because we are trying to render our index each null file two times once for each test.
Also very critically notice how those two console logs occur after our tests have been executed.
And so that really confirms what we were thinking of earlier in that we were trying to check the contents
of that H1 element before our javascript had even been executed.
So this is definitely proof that that's why our test is not working as expected.
All right.
So now we've got some signal of when everything is ready to get test started executing it's now need
to figure out how to somehow delay this function right here from returning until after this event has
been triggered or that we can wrap this statement right here inside of our own promise so we can wrap
it inside of a promise and we can say Let's not resolve that promise manually until after this event
gets triggered.
So to do so I'm going to create a new promise remember how we create our own promise we call new promise.
We pass in a callback function.
So this function is going to be invoked instantly.
It gets to arguments resolve and reject if everything inside the promise goes well.
Then we call resolve.
Otherwise anything goes wrong.
We call reject so we're going to move that event listener.
I'm going to cut it and paste it directly in
and then instead the console log will instead call resolve
and the last thing we need to do here because we are now going to essentially wait for this premise
to be resolved.
This promise is not going to or is when we call resolve.
We need to pass in some argument right here which is what is going to return from the entire overall
promise when the thing gets resolved.
So chances are we want to make that Dom variable exposed or accessible to the outside world.
So I'm going to resolve the promise with Dom.
Now finally instead of returning the DOM down here we'll return the promise that we just created.
Like so.
All right.
And that should be at
yet.
So let's save this.
I'm going to go back over.
I'm going to rerun TNT and now we can see the contents of each one says looks good.
Perfect.
So that means that our test is now going to be working as expected.
All right well I'd say this is definitely a good improvement.
Well we self to fix up and finish that test.
We're just writing because right now we just have that simple console log.
So as usual quick pause right here and we'll finish that thing up in just a moment.