The last video we tried to print out the files and folders from up one directory of our current one.
We very quickly cite an error message here.
So what's going on.
Well if we go back over to our Ed we are passing in some target directory to read into the reader function.
Then a moment after that we tried to run l stat right there and we passed in the file name but remember
what the file name is.
It is a simple string that is just indicating the name of the file that we want to get some stats for
when we call the L stat function.
We're really suppose to be passing in either a relative path to the file that we want to get the stats
for or the absolute path.
Right now we're just giving the file name and so else stat is going to look inside of our current working
directory and try to find a file inside there called file name.
That file doesn't exist in our case specifically when we run this command because this essentially means
go up one directory find all the files inside there and then we tried to run.
L stat assuming that those files are in the current directory.
So we need to somehow make sure that when we call l stats we pass in a relative path to that target
file so to do so I gonna go back over to my editor at the very top.
I'm going to add in an additional that require statement or something called path.
It's also path is require path like so this is another one of the modules inside the node standard library.
Let's take a look at the documentation for this module really quickly and get a better idea of what
it's for and how it's going to solve our problem so I gonna go back over to the node j ust documentation
on the left hand side scrolling down to half.
Here it is right here.
So this is an entire module all around helping you get file names or paths to files on your computer
put together in particular what's really nice about this path module is that it's going to handle all
the differences in cross platform compatibility.
So in other words handling differences between a Windows based file system and a Mac OS or Linux based
file system as well.
The function inside of here that we're going to look for in particular is called Path Dot.
Join this path dot joint function is going to take in some number of path parts or essentially parts
of a path to a file or a directory.
It's then going to join them altogether making sure that the final product is going to work equally
well whether we are on a Mac system or a Windows system.
We're going to use path dot join to create a path to the file that we are looking for.
It's going to go back over to my editor.
I'm gonna go down to where l stack call right here and instead of just directly passing it in the L
stat or seeing the file name to l stat I'm going to instead pass in half dot join and I'm going to join
together the target directory that we're looking for.
So Target dir and the file name like so.
So this is going to say look at whatever entry or whatever folder we're trying to find and append on
the file name to the very end not join is going to make sure that those two very different strings get
joined together in the correct fashion as well so let's now save this.
I'll go back over I'll run MLS again that's gonna once again give you my current working directory but
if I now try to go up one level I see all the files and folders from inside there correctly I can also
try to get everything from my home directory yep that looks good I can do everything from my root directory
and I think you get the idea okay.
Well I'd say that this command and allez is now working out pretty darn well.
So now that we've got this program all put together.
Let's take a pause right here and do a little wrap up in the next video.