Our app is now all complete.
So let's do a very quick wrap up.
I just want to touch on some really high points inside this project.
We just put together some of the high points were that we created a package that Jace on file inside
there.
We added a bean section and this defined a commands that we wanted to be able to run on our local machine
in order to execute the code inside the index not just file.
This is not normally required for a typical node project.
We only have to add this in if we specifically want to run our program from the command line using some
special commands like an illness or something like that.
Otherwise for a typical node project we will instead run it directly from our command line by using
node and then the name of the file that we want to execute the next thing we learned about was the package
not Jason.
In general it is used to configure a project.
The most important parts for a typical project are these script section which we haven't really touched
on yet.
And the dependency section which records all the different packages that our project relies upon when
we ran that npm install command the package that Jason on file was automatically updated.
And this dependency c section was automatically added in in addition when we installed this outside
package was installed into the node modules directory inside of our current working folder the next
big thing inside this project was to understand some of these different standard library modules that
we made use of.
So like F S you till and path we're going to make use of that F S module anytime we want to work with
our local file system.
The other big thing we learned about these different modules is that they expose a lot of different
functions and the vast majority of them always follow the same format we pass in some number of arguments
and then the last argument will be a callback function and that callback function is always going to
be called with the same order of arguments so we'll be some kind of error object if one occurred and
then the name or the actual data that we were looking for in this case.
So then inside that callback function we'll do some kind of check to see if there is an error and if
there was we'll handle it in some fashion.
Otherwise we'll continue on and use the data that we were actually looking for only the last big thing
we learned about was that we can take these different functions that rely upon callbacks and either
wrap them in a promise manually as we saw done here with method 1 or by using the promise of fi function
as we saw its method to or in some cases we can make use of a sub module and get access to a promise
based version of a given function directly.
This is not always available right here.
So sometimes we are going to have to fall back to method 2 or method 1 Okay.
So that's pretty much it for this project.
That's really the only big highlight items that I really want you to understand at this point everything
else so we might have discussed.
Well those are some topics that are going to be coming up again and again specifically some of the ideas
around how we actually handled data inside of here using callbacks versus promises versus promise not
all that stuff that we're going to get a lot of practice with over time.
And so I don't really expect you to be a total master with that stuff just yet.
All right.
Let's take a pause right here.
We'll come back in just a moment and start working on our next project.