In this video we're going to focus on showing the goal on the very bottom right corner of our maze.
The goal is always going to be exactly right.
You're on the bottom right hand corner.
So this calculation is going to be pretty straightforward.
We just have to be aware that we probably want to adjust the size of the goal based upon our unit length
or essentially the size of each individual cell.
So in other words if we have really large cells as we do right now we want to have a really large goal
that fills up most of that space.
But if we have some very small cells like back just a second ago when I showed cells of 20 or 30 then
in this case we want the goal down here to be really really small instead.
So essentially we just need the goal rectangle or the rectangle that represents the goal to be just
about scaling itself with the size of our different cells it's going go back over I can go down to the
very bottom and down here I'm going to create a new variable called goal.
This is going to be a body start rectangle and then right away I'm not gonna worry about the configuration
just yet.
Instead I'll add in the code to add this thing to our world so we'll say World dot add world and goal.
So let's think about how we're going to calculate the arguments for the rectangle.
Remember the first two arguments are going to be the x and y coordinates to the center of the goal okay.
So quick diagram 3 essentially saying that we just want to draw a rectangle like right here and we need
to find the coordinates to that point.
So something like this right here we can see how that lines up with the center and about this right
here again can see that kind of lines up with the center.
In this case it's really not going to be that hard.
We know that the overall width of this thing is our canvas with the that's the.
Like overall width and we know that the overall height is going to be height so we want to essentially
take the full width and the full height and then subtract the width of half of a cell.
That right there is one half of a cell and we are calling the variable that represents the cell dimension.
Remember we are calling that unit length so essentially the center point to that rectangle is going
to be our width of the overall canvas minus unit length divided by two and then the y components will
be the overall height minus
unit length divided by two.
And that's pretty much it so let's take that information go back over it and added in so the x coordinate
is going to be by with minus unit length divided by two.
And remember this with variable right here is a reference back to the overall width of our canvas and
my y will be the height minus unit length divided by two.
Once again I made a typo right there on unit length so I can get that fixed up.
All right.
And that's pretty much it.
So now we need to make sure that the size of this rectangle so its height and width which are the third
and fourth arguments also scale with the unit length.
You can imagine that if we always had a fixed height and width to the rectangle itself as soon as we
start to scale down the maze as we have right here.
Well the rectangle would be way too large inside of here.
But to make sure that this thing scales we can just do a unit length and then multiply that by like
point seven or something.
So that means I want the rectangle size to just scale with the size of a cell.
So I want the cell to essentially be 70 percent of the size of a cell.
I could do a unit like again times.
Point seven and finally I do want this thing to be static so I don't want it to move around they'll
say is static is true
yes I'll save this I'm going to make sure that my cell's variable back up at the top is back at three.
So we'll do a test with a very simple case to start I'll go back over refresh and there's our goal now
having the goal up here as this kind of outline and not that great.
It's really not clear to a user what that is all about re centrally going to add in a feel to it as
opposed to have it in a wireframe mode.
Once we add in a fill we can make the thing Green and will be a lot more obvious to our users that they're
trying to like navigate to that thing right there now that definitely looks good.
But I want to point out a little issue if we increase our cells right here to say like 15 and save then
it looks like it's just about impossible to actually get to that goal because our bottom border is overlapping
are kind of intersecting that actual goal that we're trying to get at.
But I think that at this point the borders that we have around the outside are way too thick.
We need to probably reduce their size so that they're not going to actually interfere with the different
elements of the maze itself therefore that's going to go back to the section where we created all of
our different walls remember we put on that helpful comment just to help ourselves find this thing in
the future and I want to change the 4D inside of here which represent the width of that wall going to
change all for them to about just to like so that's basically really really thin and we can just about
not see them but now they're not really actually conflicting with any of the elements inside of our
maze anymore.
I think that's definitely a better approach to take okay.
So that's our goal.
Now we do eventually have to add in some code to detect a collision between the ball that we're going
to place in that thing to decide when the user wins.
We'll take care of that just a little bit right now let's take a pause.
We'll come back.
We'll start to add in the ball that's going to start off at the top left corner so it could pass and
I'll see you in just a minute.