Attached to this video you're going to find a zip file called timer 0 2 5 templates a template in all
capitals.
There are probably two different files attached to this lecture so make sure you get the one with the
name template inside.
Once you get that file we're going to unzip it and then take a look at the two files inside.
So we've got an index stored HDMI file and a style that CSX.
So all I did we here was add in a couple of additional HD channel elements.
Some class names and some C Ss just to apply a little bit better styling to our timer.
The only reason I'm giving you this is that well this really is of course about JavaScript and so for
the most part we're going to skip over a lot of styling stuff.
I still want you to have some neat looking apps though which is why we're usually going to have some
HD email and CSX being provided to you to use these files.
I'm going to open up my editor and I'm going to first begin by dragging and dropping the index not a
single file into my editor.
So here's the small file that we were just given.
I'm going to select everything inside of here with a command or control a depending upon your operating
system.
Copy everything.
I'm going to go back over to my index not a shelf.
So the one that we've been working on for our project going to select everything inside of here.
Delete it and then paste now as we look through here we're going to see just about everything is the
same.
So we still have a SPG element.
We still have a circle the input the buttons and all that stuff.
Just a slightly different structure.
Next up I'm going to create a new file called style Nazi SS.
I'll go back over to where we have those two files from the zip file.
I'll find the style CSF SS that we just downloaded.
I got a drag and drop it into my editor.
I'll select everything inside copy it and then paste it into the style that's the SS file that we just
created and save.
All right.
So now that everything is saved and updated all flip back over to my browser or refresh and we get something
looks like this right here.
If I zoom back out to 1 percent you'll probably see something it looks like basically that now I can't
click in here to run the timer.
It's all the exact same logic that we just had.
Nothing changed.
All the job script is identical because well we didn't change any of it right.
And now I can click on that thing.
It is the actual text input there so I can click on it and change it to say 30 seconds and then run
it down.
I can posit change it again to say 60 seconds.
Run it down and so on.
That's pretty much it.
Know what they want to really highlight is that that really is a text input.
The only thing we did with some C Ss was make sure that it doesn't display a border.
And it also doesn't get highlighted when you actually select it.
So if I actually do a little bit of fancy stuff here really quickly you'll see that there is an outline
property being set inside the style that see SS file of none.
That's why it doesn't really look like an input but it technically is all right.
Well I hope you enjoyed this project.
We definitely learned a lot along the way about SB G's handling set intervals classes where to store
information in all that kind of stuff.
We still have a lot of code to write and a lot of projects to work on however.
So let's take a pause right here and start working on our next project in just a moment.