Now that we have our goal let's make sure that we show a ball as well that the user can manipulate by
pressing their keyboard keys.
I'm going to find where we just added in the golden moment to go.
I'm gonna add a comment right above it that says goal.
Just remind myself that that is what that code is for the variable name.
Kind of explains that but it's still a good practice to have a comment anyways.
So then underneath that section I'll add in ball.
So this is where we're going to draw our ball out going to first create a variable called ball we'll
do a bodies dot circle.
Because in this case we want to create a circle not a rectangle and inside of here we could definitely
have a fixed ball size.
But once again if we have a fixed ball size it might make a lot of sense on how large the ball is.
When we have only three cells but as we start to have a tighter and tighter maze if the ball is too
large it's not going to actually be able to make it through the maze at all.
So we probably just need to make sure that we kind of scale the size of the ball along with the unit
length.
The other thing we need to be aware of is that the first two arguments to circle is the x y Cornet of
the very center of the circle.
So we probably need to make sure that we also adjust that starting location to always be at the very
center of that first cell right there so let's get to it for the starting x y coordinates.
We're going to show the ball at unit length divided by two.
That essentially means take the with this first cell divided by two and put it right there in the very
center.
We're going to do that but for the x coordinate and Y cornet as well and for the diameter of the ball
we'll do a unit length so that's the width of one cell.
And we'll make the ball half the size of a cell so we can do a Times point five or divide by two as
well and I can go ahead and add that ball into the world.
So World dot ad worlds and ball X I'll save this I'll fly back over refresh and there we go.
Now the ball is looking just a little bit too large.
Well I think I just made a mistake here.
The third argument I do this on my own when I was actually writing this application as well.
The third argument I just assumed was the actual overall diameter.
It's actually the radius of the ball.
So right now a unit length divided by two means that the ball is going to be essentially exactly equal
to the width of a cell.
My mistake.
So the last argument here to be the radius correctly should actually be unit length divided by four
we'll try that again refresh and that's better.
Now the ball is half the width of a cell.
Now the last thing we really have to do is make sure that a ball can collide with the goal.
We need to make sure that we press on our keyboard keys up W.A. as indeed we apply some velocity or
movement to the ball as well.
Well first make sure that we can move the ball around.
Let's take care of that in the next video.