Now that we understand what is going wrong inside of our project let's talk about the absolute distinct
steps we're going to undergo to actually fix each of these issues.
So here's the idea right now we've got a lot of under usable code inside of our index not J.S. file.
We're going to start to refactor this into two separate files inside of our index not just file.
We're going to have some not reusable code so code that is very specific for our project.
Examples of code that is specific to our project is the process of fetching movies where the process
of deciding what an individual movie should look like inside the autocomplete in the code related to
deciding what to do when an option is clicked on then we're going to have a second file called autocomplete
J.S. inside there.
We're going to have some extremely reusable code that is all related to getting an autocomplete to display
on the screen successfully.
That file should be 100 percent reusable between different projects.
And so because of that we need to make sure that everything inside that file has zero knowledge of exactly
what a movie is or what that recipe is.
If we were building something around showing recipes or what a blog is and so on.
In addition we want to make sure that the code in this file can be executed several times successfully.
The idea there being that we want to have the ability to show several different auto completes on the
screen at the same time without having to do that crazy renaming of variables or anything like that
so let's make this happen.
We're going to create a function inside of auto complete J.S. that's going to take a configuration object.
It's going to process the options inside that configuration object and then render an auto complete
out onto the screen so inside of that configuration object that's going to be created inside of index
dot J.S. we're going to have to provide all the code that is like customized for the very specific application
of this auto complete.
So let me tell you about what our config object might look like.
I think that our config object is going to have three different properties inside of it.
It's going to have a function that is used to find movies a function that is used to render out an individual
option inside the auto complete a function that says exactly what to do when the user clicks on an option.
And finally an element that designates exactly where the autocomplete should be rendered to inside of
our final HMO document so because we are passing these three very or four very critical options inside
of a config object that object right there is essentially a wrapping up all the customized code specific
to our application that's going to pass it off to autocomplete dot J.S. auto complete digest and then
going to call some of those very specific functions whenever it needs to say get some data or decide
how to render out each option or what to do whenever user clicks on an option.
So in other words all the not reusable code gets defined inside of index not J.S. and all the reusable
code is inside of autocomplete dot J.S. then if we ever want to reuse all this stuff on another project
we're going to take autocomplete dot J.S. add it to the new project come up with a new config object
that has the exact same options inside of it and pass it into the same function so that's the idea.
That's how we're going to make our code reusable.
Now if I am explaining this right now and it makes zero sense that is totally okay and really very much
expected I really do not expect you to like look at this diagram and know exactly what is going on right
away.
This is just your first taste of what we're going to be doing and how we're going to make all this code
reusable in nature.
It's now that we have a vague idea of what we're going to do.
Let's take another pause right here.
We can come back the next video we're gonna start to create these two separate files and then split
apart all of our code into these separate different implementations.
So I'll see you in just a minute.