All right so let's revisit this slide where we talked about keys being converted to strings.
You can attempt to use a number as a key or a boolean as a key but it will be turned into a string even
if it doesn't appear that way.
So let's make another object we'll call this one numbers and it's going to convert a number like one
hundred into a word.
So the value will be one hundred and let's do one more here.
Let's do 16 which gives us 16 the string so to access any of those out.
We saw that this does not work numbers dot one hundred doesn't work it says unexpected number.
But we have a second syntax to access values out of an object which looks like this.
We use array brackets and then we put a key inside those brackets.
So if we tried that with numbers numbers of one hundred it does work.
And that might surprise you if you trust me when I say that all keys are converted to strings.
But what happens here is that 100 is also converted to a string and then it's used to see if there's
a matching key.
So inside of the object you can kind of think of it as looking like this where we have one in quotes
and we have 16 in quotes and then when I ask for numbers of one hundred it's going to look for 100 in
quotes because it turns it into a string.
And it finds it and it gives us one hundred and we can verify that this works because if I do numbers
of the string 100 we get the same result.
So it turns this into a string it's already a string and we get one hundred.
OK.
So why would you use square brackets aside from if you tried to store numbers as a key.
Why else would you use square brackets.
Well sometimes you have property names that may not be valid javascript identifiers now an identifier
in Javascript is like the name of a variable here is an invalid name of a variable.
Let my cat equal something that is not one identifier.
JavaScript is going to give me a syntax error.
I also can't do something like this.
Let 76 Trombones equals song
invalid identifier.
Well tells me invalid or unexpected token I cannot have a variable name start with a number.
But that doesn't mean we can't do that as a key in an object.
What we could do if we just give up on making this a cohesive object and we just want to put some random
stuff in there I could do this 76 Trombones as a key and the value could be great song.
Okay I'll refresh.
We'll look at numbers and we do have 76 Trombones in there.
Of course I can't access it with the dot notation ignoring the fact that it starts at the number.
It also has a space so a javascript get very confused.
If I tried to do this it's going to look for numbers dot 76.
Well that's an error already.
And then it's going to just try and find something called trombones a variable called trombones.
It doesn't work but if I instead use the square bracket notation and do 76 space trombones.
That works fine because the key has been stored as a string even if it's an invalid identifier which
means I can't use the dot notation.
I can pass it in to the square brackets and it works just fine.
So that's one reason you would use square brackets if you had something that syntactically was not valid
to use a dot notation with.
But here's another reason sometimes we want to use a dynamic value like a variable to access data from
an object.
So here's an example of that.
I have a colored palette object which is mapping an English word like Red to a color code which in general
are really hard to remember.
So this would allow you to quickly say what is the color code for blue.
And you would get palette of blue gives you this 3 0 3 3 6 B.
How do you not remember that.
So I've copied this over into my app J.S. file and we can do what we've already seen.
I can use the dot notation to get blue or yellow.
I could also use the square brackets so palette of and then I cannot do this.
I can't just type yellow inside those square brackets like this.
If I'd tried this it's going to look for a variable or something called the Yellow.
It's sort of like if I just typed yellow right here there is nothing yellow.
There is a property called yellow in the palette but I can't just type some identifier if it's not defined.
So when we use square brackets we would use quotes so I could do palette quote blue and that works.
But the main reason I'm showing this to you here is that we can also use a variable so if we had some
variable let's go with mystery color and maybe this is coming from some user input this is a Web site
and there's a color and the user is selecting a color and we're going to set mystery color to be one
of those colors.
Let's say they select yellow but it could also be blue it could be red.
If I want to access the corresponding color code I can use the square bracket notation to do palette
of mystery color.
I will need to refresh my page to get this to load since I saved it over here.
If I do palettes of mystery color with square brackets it works because it's going to look for the value
of mystery color which evaluates to yellow and then plugs that into palette instead tried that with
dot notation it would not work at all because now it's looking for a property actually called Mystery
color and there isn't one.
We only have red yellow and blue.
Those are the only keys.
So this is not going to work.
It doesn't throw an error.
It just tells us undefined.
Just like in an array if you trying to access something that does not exist in that array if I tried
to do an index of ninety nine we get undefined.
If I try to access a property that is not in this object undefined whether I use square brackets or
dot notation that does not exist.
So I get undefined.
So this is one of the main advantages of using the square bracket notation is if you have a variable
or some dynamic value that you need to use in order to retrieve information.
So I could even do something like this.
Not that you should but I could do palette of red.
Let's do actually those two B L plus you e and it's going to evaluate this code.
It will take the string blue or blue plus you and turn it into blue and then use that to retrieve the
correct code.
So my general rule of thumb is to try and use the dot notation whenever possible.
It is shorter it's nicer to look at in my opinion but when it's not possible whether it's because you
have a key name that is not valid as a identifier like the key name that we had earlier which I can't
even remember what it was but it was 76 Trombones.
That's not valid.
So we can't do that.
So we have to use square brackets or the other big reason is when you want to use a variable or some
dynamic value as your key you have to use square brackets.