Let's figure out how to test that code that we just wrote without using any outside library.
Now when I say outside library I'm talking about like any third party package or anything like that.
We are going to eventually still use the some functions out of the know jazz standard library but just
like one or two just to make our lives a little bit slightly easier.
OK so to get started I can go back over to my editor inside of my project directory.
I'm going to create a new file called index dot test dot J.S. but this is the first thing is kind of
interesting whenever you write some test related code.
We're always going to place it in a separate file completely separate from whatever code we are trying
to test.
The reason for this is that when we start to think about automated testing we're really talking about
running our entire application in two different contexts.
The first context would be like if we wanted to run our program as usual and actually make use of the
code inside of our very normal very usual type of program so if we were doing that for our project we
would run a node index J.S. at our command line and we would do that to specifically execute this file
right here as soon as we start to want to test this code.
However we would not want to put some code inside of here that's going to actually test this stuff and
just leave it inside of here.
Think about if we had that same approach we just discussed a moment ago where we had something like
this at the bottom to file if we'd left this code inside of here and then ran our project every single
time we ran our project we would see a console log of 1 2 3 and I would start to muddy up our program
really quickly because we would get some console logs and whatnot completely unrelated to the actual
purpose of our program.
It's solely testing code so whenever we write some testing code we're almost always going to it inside
of some other file very commonly in the community.
We're going to name these different testing files that we create as the name of the file that we're
trying to essentially test or make use of some code from dot test dot J.S. now putting in that extension
of dot test doesn't actually change the meaning of the file or anything like that.
It is solely an identifier.
We could just as easily called it something like index dash test not J.S. but again usually by convention
we will call it dot test J then inside of here in order to write a test without any outside library.
We're going to do it in the most simple basic straightforward way possible.
Let me tell you right now there is no secret to this.
There's no secret in order to write a very simple and straightforward test.
We're just going to require in our function we're going to call it.
We're going to get some results out and we're just going to make sure that the result that we got is
what we kind of expect.
So let me show you at the very top.
We will require in the before each function that we just wrote from the index file and then going to
call the for each function
and when I call it I'm going to pass in some totally reasonable arguments.
So like 1 2 and 3
then inside of here let's try to count up or sum up all the values inside the array in order to do so
let's create a counter variable right above.
So I'll call this like let's some equal and initialize it to zero then inside this for each function
I'll receive the value we are iterating over and I'm going to add it to some.
So I'll say some equals some plus value and we could condense this down technically to just some plus
equals value and then after that I will write out counseled out log some.
This right here is a totally valid test to some degree.
We're going to run our code and then console log out the results.
The only downside to this kind of approach right here is that we are just console logging the value.
And so it would still require you and I as developers to take a look at our terminal and verify that
the value that we got out the some variable is what we expected to be.
So you and I would really have to memorize that this test and inside of this test file is supposed to
return six because that's what one plus two plus three is.
So rather than making ourselves have to memorize that we should see a console log of six right here.
Let's instead just write a little automated check so I'll say something like if some does not equal
6.
Then that means something must be really wrong with our code.
So in that case I will throw a new error and say something like expected something array to equal 6
and that's it.
That is a valid test.
We didn't right use any framework.
We didn't use any outside library.
We just wrote our own code to run an art project in some automated fashion.
It's now to test this out.
We can go back over to our terminal and run the index test dot J as file so I'll go back over inside
of high dash I'll do node index dot test.
J.S. I did not see any console log or anything like that which means all my tests ran successfully.
It's now to really make sure that our tests are working the way we expect we can go back over and introduce
an intentional break inside of our code.
In other words I want to forcibly break my test right now to make sure that it kind of is technically
doing what I would expect.
So to make this thing break I'll change the some not equal six to some not equal seven so that's definitely
an incorrect answer.
So now I would expect to see a V air being thrown they'll say this go back over run it again.
And now I can see a big error message.
And so this is telling me that.
Okay.
Like yeah we are successfully running a test here okay.
So I'm gonna change these some not equals seven back to six.
Now why is this valuable.
Like what have we really achieved here.
Well this now means that we can go back to our index not just file and if we wanted to we could start
to try to refactor our for each function we could tried to re implement it in a totally different fashion
every single time we make a change to the code inside of here.
We could rerun the index dot test dot J.S. file and as long as we don't see any error message at all
it means that the changes that we just made two for each did not break anything inside of her at so
let's try doing that right now.
Let's try making a change to the for each function and see what effect it actually has.
So how about this.
How about instead of this kind of ugly classic for loop right here let's try using a different style
of loop.
Let's try using a for in loop gonna comment out the for loop that we have right there.
I'll do a four let value or index excuse me in a r.
There we go.
So remember there is a for of loop and a for in loop four of is usually what is used to iterate over
an array.
If we use a four of then we're going to receive each value inside the array.
But our our case we're going to use a four in because we do need to know the index of each element inside
the array so we can pass that in as the second argument to our callback function.
So that's why we're using index right here.
So now we can try to call our f n with the value at a r r Index as the second argument will once again
put in the index.
Now I can save this and rather than rewriting some test code down here to verify that it works as expected
instead I'll just go over to my terminal rerun node index test.
J.S. I don't see any errors and that means that even though I just made a huge colossal change to my
app or my implementation of for each I should say everything still works 100 percent as expected so
that is the value in testing we can do some really sizable re factors like the one you see right here.
And once again rather than writing out all the manual testing stuff down here and then taking a look
at some console log or something like that we instead just run one simple command we didn't get any
errors that means everything works as expected.
OK so now we've seen some basics around this.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to start to add in an additional function.
In addition to for each and start to look at some other different scenarios in testing as well.