Next up let's talk about those bottom for comparison operators that we skipped over.
They all have to do with equality.
It's the 21st century.
It's time we finally confront equality meaning the for equality operators that we ignored in the last
video.
They seem kind of similar.
At least two of them are two groups that seem similar.
We have equality which is to equal signs as you can see here and then another version of equality called
strict equality with three equal signs.
And then we have non equality with one into let's start by talking about double equals versus triple
equals.
What is the difference.
Well let's start with double equals double equals is just usually referred to as the equality operator.
It checks for equality of values but it doesn't care about type.
So the types of data that you're comparing don't matter.
It's going to coerce both values to a common type and cause it's just a fancy way of saying convert
spent to try and get them to be a the same type.
So it can compare them directly as one type.
And once they're converted if they have the same value then it returns true and evaluates to true.
Otherwise we get false.
Now this can lead to some unexpected results.
But let's take a look at some expected results first four equals four That makes sense.
What about a equals a great.
We could even do false equals false hope for an equals sign.
That is assigning something as we've already seen with variables.
That's how you assign a value to is comparison.
So that's true.
All right.
But as I mentioned things can get odd.
We have things like this.
If I take a number and I compare it to a string of the same number that's giving me true.
Now these aren't equal.
These are different values.
They are completely different in terms of JavaScript.
One is a number one is a string.
But remember double equals we'll try and get them to be a common type.
So it converts them to a common type and then it decides oh yeah they have the same value.
Same thing with some maybe less expected things zero and an empty string.
So zero double equals a string with S is false but an empty string is true behind the scenes.
JavaScript is converting these to a similar type and it decides they are equal.
We'll talk about why in just a bit.
Why is zero similar to an empty string.
Obviously true double equals false is going to be false but we also have things like zero clear this
zero double equals false.
Those are definitely different values.
One is the number one is a boolean but it still comes out true.
And then one more example.
No.
And undefined as we saw.
These are two distinct values two separate primitives but they are considered equal when we use two
equal sides.
All right.
So we're going to get to Tripoli calls in just a moment but we're going to take a detour to talk about
why some of this happens.
What is actually happening behind the scenes that makes javascript say zero is double equals to an empty
string or zero is double equal false.
It doesn't seem all that logical but there is some reasoning behind it.