All right I've opened up that index not each single file inside my browser.
Once I have that file open and then I'm going to open up my development console I'm going to keep this
open for a lot of the code that we're going to write because we're going to use a couple of different
tools inside of here just to get a better idea of the application that we're trying to build and then
going to go back over to my editor and find the index dot J.S. file inside of here.
I'm just going to do a very quick council log and say hi there.
Then save the file go back over to the browser and refresh and just make sure I see the console log.
I would just like you to do that to make sure that the javascript file got wired up successfully.
So once we verify that everything is ready to go we can start working on our application.
I think that the first thing we should do is try to just show a very simple form to the user like the
one that we see right here.
Once we add in the form we can then add in an event listener to it and watch for a submit event.
So as soon as the user submits this form right here we'll update some each e-mail and show the sherry
link with Fran text and show the text input with the link to copy inside of it as well.
The first let's add in some each symbol for the form element.
I'll go back over to my index dot HDL file instead of here.
We're going to add in a pretty good amount of HDL a lot of the e-mail that we're going to be writing
is going to use some class names and styling that we get from this materialize CSX library.
So it looks like I'm adding in a bunch of extra each team L and class names.
It's just for styling purposes.
So inside of here I'm going to create a div with the class of row
then inside there I'm gonna create a div with the class of L s eight offset dash as to so this class
right here with that kind of funny class name is just going to make sure that we've got some centered
content on the screen inside of there.
I'll create a div with a class of card dash panel.
This is going to give us an element that kind of looks like a card with a nice shadow behind it.
Again just for styling purposes.
Then finally inside there I can create a form inside the form I'll display a label that tells my user
exactly what I would like them to do inside of my app.
So I'm going to tell them enter a secret message.
Then after that I'll display an input that the user can enter some text into.
And then finally a button with a class of B10 and inside the button elements.
I'll say to the user create or create link or whatever else would be appropriate.
I think the word create is pretty good.
So I'm going to say this.
I'll go back over refresh and there we go.
So we can see that the nice outline here we get from that card panel class the element itself is centered
on the screen.
Because of that CIOL And the offset as to an essay eight classes that we added right around it now we
want to make sure that whenever a user enters and some texture and clicks on create we detect that Summit
event and handle it appropriately.
Let's make sure that we wire up a submit event handler on that form element that we just created to
do so I'll go back over to my index dot ust file I'm going to remove the console log then inside of
here I'm going to add a query selector for the form we just created.
It's a document not query selector form or do you add event listener and I'll watch for the submit event
and then as a second argument I'll pass in a callback function to run any time that a user submits that
form.
Remember that the callback function gets called with within event object even object.
We really only care about so we can call event dot prevent default on it just as a quick reminder the
way that the browser works by default is anytime that you submit a form the browser is going to take
all the information inside that form and automatically attempt to submit it to some back end server.
In our case we don't have any back in server to receive that information.
So we're going to call it prevent default to stop the default browser behavior which is to submit the
form.
Now if I save this if I go back over refresh enter some text and hit create I should not see the page
refresh or anything like that.
If the page is refreshing that means that the browser is still attempting to submit the form which is
again not what we want.
OK.
So then inside of here let's just write out a little bit of code to try to get the text inside of that
text input.
I'm gonna first just try to select the input with a selector it's all say const input is document dot
query selector input and I'll just do a console log of the message that I want to eventually somehow
encode and turn into a sort of secret message so I can get that with input that value like so it's let's
save this I'll go back over I'm going to refresh I'm going to test out the middle so I'll put in a secret
message I'll hit creates and I see the console log right there of exactly what I just had inside the
text input.
Very good.
OK.
So let's take a pause right here.
When we come back in just a moment we're going to figure out how we can somehow take that value right
there whatever the user just entered is somehow encoded into some secret string.
So I'll see you in just a minute.