We've seen how to create a.
You've seen how to access individual elements using an index.
Now let's talk about changing them.
We can use the exact same syntax we've already seen where we use an index and square brackets but we
can assign a new value and that will change whatever is at that index.
So unlike with a string where if we have haha as a variable let laugh equals haha.
If we access laugh of zero we get H.
Remember that strings are immutable so I can't change that to an uppercase H.
If we look at laugh it's still haha.
Arrays are different arrays are mutable we can change them whenever we want.
So if we make a new array let's go with shopping list again and let's start off with cheddar cheese
and one other item.
How about 2 percent milk.
Great.
So we've made an array.
We can access things out but now I want to change something.
So let's say I change my mind about the milk and I actually want whole milk.
I need to access that index which would be zero one index of one and then set that to whole milk and
save.
Let's take a look at shopping list it now only contains cheddar cheese and whole milk.
We'll zoom out a bit.
I could also go in and add something else into the array.
So this is how you could update a value to add something to the end.
I would need to know the last index so I could use a length.
Or we could just count manually.
So we know that there is zero.
There is one so index 2 would be the next index shopping list of 2 equals.
What else do I need.
How about ice cream we'll save refresh.
Shopping list now has three items cheddar cheese whole milk and ice cream at index of two.
So this works.
The problem with this approach right here is if you don't know how many items are in there it's a little
clunky.
You have to calculate it.
Let's say the shopping list is out of view.
It's written in in code dynamically.
Data is coming from a database or from users.
We don't know if there's 10 or 20 items.
We would have to do something like this to always add to the end shopping list of shopping list dot
length equals and then whatever we want to add to the end.
Let's go with tomatoes like that.
Is there any proof.
I don't know.
OK.
Yes there is.
Just had a minor stroke.
There isn't either.
And this should work no matter how long shopping list is.
This will always add to the end.
So let's refresh.
We'll look at shopping list again now has tomatoes at the end and I could do this multiple times further
so we could verify that instead of tomatoes.
Let's also add potatoes are fresh and it still works.
So this is great.
And it works but it's not ideal.
There are easier ways to add to the end which we'll see in the next video.
There is a built in method to help you add new items to the end of an array.
Really the only time I use this syntax is when I'm trying to change a value that's already in an array.
So instead of cheddar cheese or instead of 2 percent milk I want whole milk.
But I'm not adding in a brand new item even though this does work.
You just have to be very particular about where you put something and be cognizant of the fact that
when you add something at index of 1 or let's say something an index of 0 shopping list of 0.
I'm not putting this at the beginning and shifting everything over I am changing the very first item
so a shopping list of 0 is now going to be bread if we look at shopping list cheddar cheese is gone.
So I'm completely rewriting it or overwriting it.
There is a way to add to the beginning but we haven't seen it yet.
That's in the very next video.
So we've seen how you can use an index to change a value.
You can use a length to add to the end.
We're going to see a nicer way of doing this.
Up next.