Next up we have the Array method that I probably use the most out of all of them.
It's called Map.
Map is used to create a new array from an existing array.
It could be used to simply duplicate an array.
Though there are easier ways of doing it but it can also be used to extract portions of an array or
to somehow transform an array into a new array double every number in this array or reverse every string
in the original and make a new array with those reverse strings so it accepts a callback just like for
each.
It calls that callback with every element in the array but it builds a new array with those values.
So here's a simple example.
Here I have an array called texts.
We have a raffle L'Oréal AMG t t y l for strings lowercase and I'm calling texts dot map I'm passing
a callback function in the parameter name I settled on was t t represents each one of these strings
and I'm returning from this function T dot to uppercase and what this whole map does overall is it generates
a new array and I'm storing it in a variable called caps so it does not alter or update texts its original
values are still unchanged but I've mapped them over to a new array called caps so we'll take a look
at a bunch of examples.
I have two sample arrays to start nice and simple ones.
Let's work with numbers let's make a new array called doubles doubles will be an array where every value
is double this value the corresponding value in numbers.
So we'll call numbers dot map and we'll pass in a function.
Usually we use anonymous functions unless you have a predefined function that does exactly what you
need.
Usually these are one time use things and the callback parameter or go with is just num.
That makes sense it represents each number.
Now what I need to do from this function is return of value.
This is how map knows what value to add to the array.
If I don't return anything it won't work.
So let's return Num Times 2.
And if I run this right now we don't get anything or we don't see anything numbers is unchanged because
map does not mutate the original array it maps the values to a new array.
So I need to capture that value.
If I run this code on my console you can see that it returns map itself returns.
This new map array so I'll capture that in a variable cost doubles tried again.
And now if I look at doubles it exists and it's a double of this original array.
So if I don't return something I just console out log or I'm simply writing this expression here.
If we look at doubles it's an array full of undefined because MAB doesn't care what the return value
is it's going to take whatever is returned from our function and added into a new array eight times
because it ran our function eight times.
There's eight elements here and each time nothing was returned and when a function returns nothing the
value you get is undefined.
So it created an array of eight undefined.
So we need to return a value here.
There we go next let's do another example with numbers once again.
But instead of simply doubling the value let's decide if the number is even or odd.
And we're going to map them into a new array where the array will contain.
Let's have it contain an object for each element and we'll have the number set to 20 and then we'll
set is even 2 True or false and we'll do that for every single element in numbers so to do that we need
to call numbers dot map passenger callback function.
I'll go with N as a parameter this time instead of num and then we know we want to check if the value
is even and we want to return an object so we can return an object here.
We can do it all at once you don't have to make it in a variable first and then return it and we'll
set value to be n and then we'll set is even to be a bully and true or false based off of an mod 2 equals
zero.
So this if the remainder once you divide by two is zero that will return true if not it returns false.
So we'll end up with the is even property being true or false and then value is just the number itself.
And so if we try this and save it to a variable we'll go with const Mm num detail.
I don't know if it's not a great name.
Let's look at what we get num detail is an array of objects and each object has a value and is even
so we have value twenty one is even false value twenty two is even true.
So there is one example.
Now let's work with the array of strings I have all of these abbreviations and let's say I wanted to
format them different I want an array where each string is all caps and separated by periods like A.S.A.P.
should be formatted this way instead of A.S.A.P..
So I want to map them into a new array.
What I need to do here.
Well what I can do at least is use map if I didn't want to use map in all of these examples I could
do this manually I could make a loop for left word.
Let's go with numbers just to do this.
Doubles example for the NUM of numbers I need to make a results array so we'll make our array we'll
call it doubles to cost doubles to equals an empty array and then I need to push into doubles to push
numb times to so I'm doing the same thing effectively.
There's no function involved but I'm iterating over numbers for each number.
I'm multiplying it by two and pushing it into an array.
I'm actually doing the push one at a time versus when we use map.
All we do is write a function map calls that function takes the result and it puts it into a new array
for us automatically and it gives us that array.
But if we verify that this works doubles too.
There we go.
But again this is not calling a function for something simple like multiplying by 2.
This is easy but map is really really useful especially when we start to combine it with other methods
that we'll see.
So I don't want to give you the impression that you should do this.
This is easier because it's usually not.
I just wanted to kind of recreate the basics of what it's doing.
So it makes it array for us.
It starts empty and then it calls this function.
It gets a return value.
It pushes that into the array and then it does it again for the next element.
So back to our words we're going to call map where it stopped map.
I'll call this word the parameter here.
Now the logic to get this to be an abbreviation where we have all caps and a period after every letter
is a little tricky.
It's not hard but we're going to use a couple of different methods.
We're going to capitalize it first so we're gonna call word dot to uppercase.
Then the easiest way in my opinion to add a period after every character is to split the word into an
array.
So if we do it over here.
If we had A.S.A.P. dot to uppercase dot split split and wants to know where it should split and if we
give it an empty string it creates an array with each character from that string so each element is
one character.
So now I have an array.
Then I can call dot join on that array and tell it what to join those characters together with.
So take each element in this array that we just created using split and join it together into one string
separated by a period after each character.
And there we go.
So we can use that logic right here.
Word to uppercase dots put on the empty string which means but on every character that gives us an array
and we can call dot join on a period.
So this is not going to work.
What am I missing I'm missing.
Return.
We have to return this from our function.
And then let's capture the variable.
We'll call this a briefs abbreviations.
If we run it we look at the briefs.
We now have this array that we mapped.
We took this array of values and we map them into a new array.
The originals are unchanged but we now have a new array.
Remember for each is similar but we're not building an array with those values for each is like half
of map.
It calls a function on every element but it doesn't store them in an array.
It doesn't return a new array map does map takes that function it calls it and it takes the return value
and puts it in a new array which is how we end up with this.
Here's one more common use case for map.
If we have a slightly more complex data structure like this box array we have a bunch of properties
we have title authors rating.
If I wanted to create a new array that contained all the book titles in my library I could use map if
I want to just extract or isolate the title.
I don't care about authors I don't care about reading.
I can use math to do that.
I would map over books so book Stop map I pass in my callback and I'll call the parameter here.
Let's go with B for book and all I want to do is return the title so B dot title return.
Beat out title and that's it.
So I'm saying create a new array based off of this array and the value I'm going to return that you
should use to make that new Array is only the title so I'm whittling down this array of objects and
turning it into an array of strings turning it into a strong term I'm creating a new version based off
of it.
The original books is unchanged.
I'm mapping it.
So let's go with concept titles.
Let's look at titles.
And there we go.
I have whittled down the pieces I need I've extracted them.
I didn't change the original but this is a really common thing to do.
Sometimes you have complex data structures and you want an array of just one piece or just a couple
pieces you want a simplified form we can use map to do that without impacting the original.
We just return the piece or the pieces that we want to form a new array using so that's mapped.
Like I said it's very useful helps us take one array and map it into a new array.
We provide a callback function and that callback is executed once per element in the original array
and the return value of our callback is what is used to generate the new array.