The next new feature we'll take a look at is called spread and the first thing you should know about
spread is that like every other feature we're seeing in this section.
It's not supported in Internet Explorer.
However that shouldn't stop you from using it.
So spread is extremely useful but it's also not that easy to explain because it does many things depending
on the context.
This is the official definition from MDA and I guess it's not official but this is the MDA and definition
spreads syntax allows an era both such as an array to be expanded in places where zero or more arguments
for function calls or elements for array laterals are expected or an object expression to be expanded
in places where zero or more key value pairs for object laterals are expected.
You got it.
Okay so I think that's good enough right.
You understand at this point.
Yeah I know.
Very funny called.
There's a lot to spread.
The key word that I bolded here is expanded.
So in all scenarios there's really three use cases spread in a function call spread an array laterals
and spread an object laterals.
It all has to do with expanding some ignorable into some other places some destination.
So the word spread is a nice choice I think because that's kind of what we're doing.
We're spreading we're expanding something.
But I'm going to do is break it up into three videos one for each of the use cases and the first one
we'll see is spread in a function call so spread syntactically is always three dots here when we're
using it.
Function call here in an array literal three dots here and an object three dots always three dots but
they means something different or they they behave differently depending on where you use it at the
end of the day it all has to do with expanding and editable meaning an array a string.
There are many other edibles but those are the two main ones we've worked with expanding them into some
other destination.
And when we use it in a function call inside the parentheses it will take that it trouble and break
it up into individual arguments rather than passing in a single argument.
So the example I used with Matt was math Max which accepts multiple arguments
here's a bunch of arguments I just passed in and it returns the max.
So in this case the maximum argument was ninety nine.
There's also math dopamine which does the same thing except the other way around it tells me the smallest
argument was three but this only works if you pass them in as separate arguments.
If we have a list of numbers or an array of numbers it will not work.
It treats it as one argument and if I do math dot max of numbers I get not a number.
It expects each argument to be a number.
This argument that we passed in is not a number it's a list of numbers but itself is not a number.
So it does not work.
Instead we can use spread so spread allows us to break this up into five separate arguments.
It's the equivalent of passing in forty five comma thirty three.
Basically stripping away the array brackets.
So this is what it looks like.
Dot dot dot numbers just like that.
We are spreading this ignorable into individual arguments so again it's just like doing this forty five
twenty three thirty four seven and five and we get forty five so to show you the other side of it.
If you wanted to write a function let's call ours.
Give me four and this is going to be a useless function but at once for argument's sake ABC and D.
And then we'll just consider that log each one of them.
I'll do it like this a comma a and then duplicate this a couple times and then update this to be B and
then do the same thing for C and D.
All right.
So it's going to print out the arguments that we get.
Give me four I'll pass in four numbers four five six and seven and we see a is for B is five C a six
and D's seven.
If I had an array of numbers or an array of anything let's go with const colors we'll have red orange
yellow and green if I call Give me four and I pass in colors we're only passing in one argument.
So you see what we get a is set to this whole array B is undefined C and D are also undefined.
But if I instead use spread one two three dots we're now spreading that entire array into separate arguments.
So now those array braces are essentially gone from the function call.
We don't change the array in any way colors is exactly the same as it always was.
But when we pass those values in they now are for arguments so a is red B is orange C is yellow India's
green and if we had more arguments right now our function doesn't handle them.
It only wants four.
But if we had colors that had 10 things in there each one would be passed as an argument we just wouldn't
be using it in the function.
But shortly in this section we'll see how to write a function that accepts any number of arguments.
Right now we're having to hard code how many we want.
This is for if I want five arguments then I need to add in another parameter but we'll see how we can
add an N number and collect all arguments in a single array or a single structure.
That's coming up soon.
The other thing about spread is that it's not only applicable to arrays.
So we could also do something like this where we make some space here if I have a string concept we'll
just call it SDR equals How about goats.
Like that if I spread a string a string is actually an admirable.
What do you expect to happen here if I call.
Give me for dot dot dot as tr.
It passes each character as its own argument.
It iterate over this and it's ignorable.
We've done it before.
You iterate one character at a time and you end up with one character G being the first argument.
Then the second and the third and the fourth you can think of it as just like this.
Each value or each character is passed as its own argument.
And we would get the same result if we did it this way.
Give me four but the main difference is that this sucks to type and this is hardcoded if we use spread
this could be 20 characters it could be two characters.
It's not that common that you spread strings.
At least in my experience compared to arrays.
But whatever you're spreading when you spread it into a function call that editable is iterated over
each element is passed as a standalone separate argument.
So that's the first use case for spread.
We have two more to go.