The first feature of note that we're going to focus on is how to get code to share between multiple
different files.
So as we just mentioned a video or two ago when we usually run code inside the browser we can have multiple
different JavaScript files all the different variables objects functions or whatever else so we define
inside these separate files are essentially shared and we can make reference to them directly between
these different files.
Of course all the usual scope rules apply.
So for example if I declare a variable inside of my script dot J Yes and wrap it inside of a function
that is isn't a different or more contained scope.
And so it would not be accessible from index J.S. but let's just imagine the simplest case.
Let's imagine that in the browser we've got an h t mail file that loads up my script dot J.S. and index
dot J.S. if my script J S defines a variable called message and assigns it a value I can freely access
that variable from inside of index dot J.S..
The only requirement is that I define index dot J.S. inside of a script tag after my script.
That's pretty much it.
Now in note it is a very different situation.
Let's try creating these two separate files in node.
We're gonna try writing out some code like you see right here we're gonna very quickly see an error
and we'll figure out how we can fix it.
So I gonna go back over to my code editor I'm going to create a new file inside of here called my script
dot J.S. inside of here I'll do a variable declaration like so then I'll go back over to the index dot
J.S. file and back inside of index dot J.S. rather than console logging out that string directly I'm
going to instead tried to do console log the message variable that we just declared inside of my script
so I'll save this I'll make sure both files are saved I'll go then go back over to my terminal and I'll
run node index dot J.S. and sure enough I get a really big error here let me scroll out to so I can
see the error very easily but says that message is not defined so like we just said when we are running
code with node there's no automatic sharing of variables functions objects between different files instead
if we want to share stuff between different files we have to use something called the module system
so the module system is how we do code sharing between different files with node there's a little bit
of kind of arcane syntax here that's gonna be kind of hard to remember when you first start let's just
go over a quick example and then I'll show you a couple of diagrams to really help you understand exactly
what is going on behind the scenes let's imagine that we've got a my script dot J.S. file if we want
to make something or some like variable or object or function that is defined inside of here available
inside of another file we're going to take that variable or that value or whatever it is and we're going
to assign it to a very special variable called module dot exports when we assign a value to module dot
exports that makes that value available inside of other files inside of our project so inside of another
file we can write out something called a require statement require statement we're going to provide
a path to the file that we want to get some code from.
So in this case we would say it require some code from my script dot J.S. that will tell node to essentially
reach out to my script J.S. bind whatever was assigned to module dot exports and that is going to be
the result of the entire require statement so essentially we are taking to that string of high and assigning
to the variable of message.
Let's try implementing this inside of our code Ed and you'll see it in action.
Very quickly I want to repeat once again I'm going to show you a more complete diagram to really help
you internalize what's going on here.
But right now let's just do a quick experiment all right.
So I'll flip back over inside of my script.
J.S. I'm going to assign the variable that I want to make available to other files inside my project.
So I'll do a module dot exports and I'm going to assign message to it.
So now whatever message is referencing in this case the string is available to other files now I can
go back over to index dot J.S. at the top I can write out a require statement they'll say constant message
is require and then I'm going to write out a relative path to the file that I want to require some code
from a relative path would be dot slash my script dot J.S. dot slash on here means in the current directory
or in the same directory.
So in other words we're saying OK we're currently inside the index dot J as file in the same directory
find a file called my script dot J.S. whatever inside of that file is assigned to module dot exports
we want to have returned by this require statement.
So we're going to get back the string of high there in assign it to this variable of message and then
we console log it out it's save both files put back over to my terminal a run node index start J us
once again and sure enough we don't get an error anymore.
OK so that's definitely a very simple practical example but it would be really nice to have a better
idea of what's going on behind the scenes.
So let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video and until you a little bit more about how this require stuff and this
module does expert stuff is really working.