Now that we can detect a wind condition so whenever a user goes and hits that kind of completion area
right there it would be kind of fun to tell the user in a interesting way that they have won the game.
So something a bit more interesting than a console log.
I've got an idea for kind of an interesting way of doing that.
I think that when a user wins and they hit the ball against that kind of goal rectangle right there
let's try to turn gravity back on and simultaneously we'll also take all the different wall segments
we have and remove these static flag from them.
The net effect of both those changes is that essentially the entire maze is going to kind of fall apart
and fall down to the very bottom all to like the bottom edge of the screen.
So again we're just doing this to make sure it's really clear to a user when they win a game.
So let's give this a shot.
The first thing we'll do is find the if statement.
We were just working on going to replace that console log right there so inside of here I'm gonna turn
gravity back on by writing out world dot gravity dot y equals one that's going to accelerate all the
different shapes we have down towards the bottom edge of the screen next year I'm going to do is to
a loop over all the shapes inside of my world.
I'm going to try to find all the different wall segments.
So like these walls right here and I'm going to remove the static flag from each of them to make sure
that we can easily find all the different wall segments.
I'm going to go back up to where we create all of our walls so the two or each loops here's one right
here or verticals.
I'm going to find the options object and I'm going to add on a flag to it to say label of wall.
So as we saw just a second ago we can use labels that are being applied to a shape that we create to
easily figure out what type of shape it actually represents.
So if I save this just for verticals right now we can then go back over refresh and I can get a better
idea of exactly what shapes our verticals by printing out world dot bodies this is telling me that I
have ten different shapes inside the world and if I look at the different label properties or see the
label right there I'll see that one has a label of wall that represents the one vertical piece that
we have right there.
So we can repeat that same label and throw it onto our horizontals as well.
So I'll go back up to the horizontal section and I'll add into that option's object a label of wall.
It's now if we go back over again refresh print out world dot bodies we can see that we've got several
different walls inside of here.
There are many rectangles are the actual kind of barriers or borders around the outside edge of our
canvas.
And of course we have the goal and the ball as well so now whenever a user wins we can iterate over
world dot bodies and we can update the is static flag for each of the wall labels or these live wall
objects to false.
And that's going to essentially allow gravity to affect all the different wall segments that will cause
them to kind of collapse down to the bottom edge of the screen so to actually write out the code for
that.
I'll go back over.
I'm going to go back down to where we are computing our wind condition and after I update my gravity
I'm going to do a world dot bodies dot for each and for each body where I am iterating over I'll say
if body dot label is segment so this is awesome not a second but a wall.
I had previously used the word segment but figured Wald made a lot more sense so I'll stick with that.
And then to update the static property we're going to once again use that body object that we spoke
about just a little bit ago.
I'm going to call the set static method on it as you could guess that's going to update the static flag
on an object.
So we're gonna take the body and we're going to update the static flag to false to say this thing is
no longer static.
So gravity and other forces can now effect it going to save this go back over refresh.
And now if I go ahead and win everything kind of falls apart.
So again this is just kind of a fun little animation that a user can see once they actually win the
maze.
We will eventually put on a big message to the user that says hey you won right on the very center of
the screen to make sure that it's just super clear that they won but will add in one or two other features
before we take care of that.
Now for a really fun test we can go and update the number of cells we have so might go to like six or
so just to make my maze a bit more complex.
Now if I win
everything falls apart and then a user can still kind of mess around and move all these different segments
around okay.
So this is looking pretty good.
So the last really big thing that we have to accomplish inside this app is to make sure that it's not
limited to this fixed size right here at present.
We've been saying many times that the height and with are always going to be identical.
So we start to change one these values like let's say I change the height to a hundred and refresh well
everything doesn't quite work as expected so we're going to make sure that we can have rectangular mazes.
We're going to in particular make sure that we kind of a maze that fills up the entire screen.
And so we're going to have to update several sections of code to accommodate for that.
So let's take a quick pause right here and start that refactor in the next video.