Just make sure it's really clear why this refactor was so significant.
I want to show you how quickly we could change some the code inside these different options we're passing
in and get an autocomplete that works.
They very different source of data.
So just as a quick example you don't have to change your code here because I'm going to change my code
right back.
Again this is a very quick example.
I'm to go to Jason Place holder type I code dot com.
This is a fake API that can be used for testing purposes and just generally kind of messing around.
If I scroll down a little bit I can find a section called resources and inside there is an endpoint
that will serve me up a photo's collection.
Inside there is 5000 different photos.
So I encourage you not to click that link because it's going to load up a ton of data and might make
your browser hang.
Nonetheless I can go ahead and do it myself if I click on it after a second or so I will see it that
if I make a request to this endpoint I'll get back an array of objects where each object represents
one photo each photo has a title and a thumbnail.
You are l I'm going to try to make a request and get just 50 of these photos inside of my code and I'm
going to try to render each them in to that autocomplete that we just put together if I want to only
get 50 photos instead of the 5000 that it just fetched I could add on to the URL question mark album
I.D. equals one and that will give me only the first 50 photos inside of here.
So if I scroll down I'll see that I only get 50 photos total OK.
So to change my autocomplete to work with this source of data instead I would take this you URL and
again you don't have to make these changes I'm going to change my code back very quickly.
This is just a fast demonstration.
I would then go and update my fetch data function.
So instead of making a request to the OMD API I'm going to instead just paste that you are Ellen directly.
So slash photos album ideas equals one.
These programs are technically not going to be used but I can still just leave them in here.
The request is still going to work.
So I'll take him out just be sure just make sure it's really clear they'll take those out well then
make sure that when I get the response there is no longer a search property so I'll take out the DOT
search so this should work correctly to fetch the data.
Now all we would have to do is make sure that we update how each of these gets rendered that is controlled
inside of render option right here.
So instead of the current code I have I would instead say maybe just return
an image element with a source of movie dots and let me double check the name of the actual image thumbnail
you are El
and then I'll do the title which is title the movie that title
notice I'm still calling this argument movie it.
Now technically is like an image object but it's just not a good use time to change the variable name.
Okay.
So now I can save this put back over refresh in Nashville to just type anything inside of here.
Technically there's no longer any searching operation going on and I'll see this very different source
of data being used.
So now I've got each thumbnail which is the colored squares you see one with the title of each image
showing up next to it.
And I've got all 50 being rendered out right now.
That's pretty much it.
That's all we would have to do to make a significant change.
The autocomplete we just go back to these functions that we understand exactly what they do perfectly.
Know this one fetches data.
This one controls how each option gets rendered.
Make those very few changes and that's it.
We now have a widget that works a totally different context.
So that's just all I want to show you.
I'm gonna very quickly undo the changes I just made and go back to working with movies.
And there we go.
So now I'll do a quick test just to make sure I'm back and still works with movies.
So again just a quick examination of how you change things out.
Let's take another pause here.
Continue.
Yep.
In the next video.