In this video we're going to do a kind of nasty refactor.
So we're going to go through our code.
We're going to find every time that we had a reference to cells and remove it we're going to replace
it with a reference to cells horizontal or vertical.
We're also going to find every location that we had a reference to unit length X and we will replace
it with a reference to unit length X or Y.
I can tell you right now that the refactor we're about to do is going to be really nasty.
It's very likely that we're going to make a mistake somewhere along the way.
So I know that this is going to be kind of annoying refactor.
The reason that I decided to do this refactor at the end is that understanding all the maze generation
stuff is just a lot easier when the height and width of the maze was always identical.
And that's what we did from the get go.
There's a lot easier to take that approach and do the refactor later than to break out the separate
or different values of cells in the horizontal and vertical direction from the get go.
That would've been a lot more challenging right away.
So I apologize for this video in advance I can tell you right now.
But nonetheless we got to get it done.
So let's get to it one more time.
We're going to go round on every reference to cells and replace it with one of these two variables on
every reference to unit length and replace it with one of those two.
Let's start going to first take a look at the walls array right here.
Walls does not have any references to cells or unit length.
So no change is required.
Well then take a look at May's generation nothing inside of shuffle has any reference to those variables.
So no problem and we get to the first place so we need to start to do a refactor.
So where we create grid verticals in horizontals.
Let me give you a quick overview of why these things need to change now.
So here's a demonstration or a maze that we eventually want to have put together.
So in this case we have four columns and three rows.
So let's think about the grid array that we would create to represent this maze the grid would have
basically the same structure as the maze that we're looking at so we would have three rows
and inside of each of those rows there would be or elements one for each column.
So they would all start off as false.
So like false false false.
So overall the grid the outer array is length 3 the inner array is length 4.
So we need to update the values that we're passing in here to accommodate for that.
So the outer array that we're creating right there that is going to have the number of rows and our
number of rows to go all the way back up the top is cells vertical.
So cells vertical is the number of rows that we have so I'm going to update array cells.
The first call right there two cells vertical and then the second one will be cells horizontal because
remember the inner map or seeing the inner array right here we call it we have inside the map statement
is building out each inner row that's going to be the number of columns we have which is tracked by
the cells horizontal variable.
Now we can update the two other arrays we generate in an identical fashion.
The outer array will be cells vertical and down here on horizontal the outer arrays will be cells vertical
minus one then on verticals on the inner array instead of cells will have cells.
Horizontal and on this one right here inside of the horizontals we will have cells horizontal that step
one next up we need to find a random start row and a random start column rather than having this be
multiplied by just our total number of cells.
We now no longer have that variable of course.
So we need to calculate either a random number from 0 up to our cells horizontal or 0 2 cells vertical
depending upon whether we are trying to get a random row or column.
So again cells vertical corresponds to the number of rows that we have.
So I'm going to change the start row right here two cells vertical and the start column will be some
random number of times cells.
Horizontal Hey.
Next up will move to step through cell inside of here.
We have just one reference to or I guess two right here one place that we reference the cells variable
and that's where we check to see if we are out of bounds for next row right here.
We're going to make sure that we are not exceeding the total number of vertical cells we have.
So cells vertical with next column we're going to make sure we don't exceed the total number of columns
we have that these cells horizontal.
All right.
Just a little bit more.
Fortunately the next one is going to be really easy and straightforward I'm going to go down down down
to where we iterate through horizontals one side of horizontals we've got a ton of different references
to our unit length.
So we need to make sure we update each of these two other unit length X or Y but fortunately like I
said this is going to be really easy refactor remembered the ordering of arguments we pass into the
rectangle function the first argument is the center of the rectangle in the x direction.
So as you would probably guess we're going to update unit length both locations inside that first argument
to unit length x.
The second argument is the center point of the rectangle in the y direction.
So again as you would guess we're going to now multiply by unit length y and add in unit length Y then
the third argument is the length of the rectangle in the x direction so unit length X I take a look
at this line right here this block of code.
Make sure you do not have any references to the plane unit length variable.
They should all be either unit length X or Y so that's it for horizontals.
We'll repeat that same process for the verticals as well.
So again first line the unit length X and X second will be length Y and Y and this time the fourth argument
which is the height of the rectangle we are creating that needs to be of course the height.
So in the vertical direction.
So unit length Y
Okay.
Just a little bit more.
I know I said this is a nasty refactor but we're almost done with it so for the goal right here we are
multiplying by the unit length again we've got the same ordering of arguments.
So the first and third arguments need to take a look at the unit length the x direction.
Here's the first argument should go to X.
Third argument should go to X and then the second and fourth arguments are concerned with the y direction.
So we'll do unit length Y and Y so you don't think X Y then X and Y.
All right.
Last a little bit.
Here's our ball right here.
We've got three references to the unit length.
Remember the first and second are the x and y center points of the ball.
So we're going to change the first two X the second to Y and then the third argument right here is going
to be the radius of the ball.
So for the radius of the ball we might have a very different length the x direction in the y direction.
So we should really take the minimum of those two and use that to decide exactly what the radius should
be on the line right above.
I'm going to declare a new variable called Ball radius.
This will be math dot Min of the unit length in the x direction and the unit length in the y direction.
So find whichever of those two is lesser.
Now we're going to divide it by two
and then I'm going to take out a third argument right here and replace it with.
Ball radius you I just realized I made the same mistake I did before the ball.
We are providing a radius here.
So we actually want to do divided by four.
After the math Min
gets that should be it.
So now at this point time we should build to do a search on this file for unit length and if we search
around we should not find any reference to a variable that says just unit length by itself.
So as I go around I should see everywhere unit length X and unit length y I should yield to do the same
thing for cells as well I should build a search for cells and see everywhere other cells horizontal
or cells vertical once I've done that check.
I'll then save the file gonna go back over and refresh and that should be at I should now have my maze
showing up in a properly scaled fashion no matter what the dimensions of my window are if you refresh
and you see an error I can 100 percent guarantee you that you just made a typo.
So at some location you put in a reference to the wrong variable.
Take a look at the error message and take a look at what line it told you that the error occurred on.
You can then go to that line inside of your index not just file.
Now we'll tell you exactly where the typo is.
Again if you have an error where you didn't before.
No two ways about it.
I absolutely positively guarantee you.
You have a typo.
So just make sure you take a look and figure out where it is OK.
So again I know that refactor is painful but if we close our console and then refresh we're going to
see that we get this nicely scaled different sized maze.
Now we can do some really interesting things so we can have different number of cells in the horizontal
or vertical direction.
So for example I can have 14 cells in the horizontal and just 10 in the vertical if I save that.
There we go and now it doesn't appear that the maze is super squished or anything like that because
we are allowing for the different number of cells.
Now we can play this thing.
You don't have to watch me play it but I'm going to just solve it really quickly.
Come on.
Yeah.
If you want to watch just pause here.
Watch the next video.
But I've always got it.
There we go.
Done.
All right.
Let's say that looks pretty good.
Last thing I wanna do is just add in a little bit of color to this thing.
I also wanna throw a big message on the center of the screen whenever the user wins as well.
So last little test in the next video.