Next we have to do is to make sure that whenever we click on a video inside of our autocomplete we should
hide this tutorial right here and start to show some summary information about that movie on the appropriate
side.
Out of the left side or the right side so let's first take care of making sure that we just hide this
thing.
To do so I'm gonna go back over I'm gonna go into my config object and I'm going to find where we have
the callback of on option select.
Here it is right here.
So I'm going to replace on option selector excuse me I'm going to add to the code inside of it.
I'm going to get a selector for that kind of tutorial window that we just added in it's inside my H
and I'll file.
Here it is right here.
I'm gonna get a selector for a div with the class up tutorial and we're going to add a class to it that's
going to hide that thing on the screen so inside of on option select I'll do a document where he selector
with dots tutorial I'm going to look at its class list and I'm going to add in a class of is Dash hidden
like so this is another one of those classes that is coming from the bonus the SS framework.
So by just adding on that class that div that is continue the tutorial should be hidden on the screen.
Let's do a safe and a quick test so flip back over refresh look for Avengers click.
And the thing is gone.
That was an easy one and a quick pause right here and we'll continue with showing the two tutorials
on both sides.
In just a moment.