All right.
In this video we're going to make sure that we show a really big sign on the very center of the screen
that tells the user that they won once they actually will win but to do so.
Going to go back over to my index dot HDMI file inside of here.
We're going to add in a div element within each one inside of it.
Now as a quick reminder Hey I said a billion times this course is all about the javascript.
So this is mostly all about styling.
So we're going to kind of speed through a little bit of styling to make sure that this message shows
up in the correct location right above my script tag.
I'll add a div with a class of winner and hidden
and then inside the devil place in each one that says you win then inside my style tag right here I'm
going to add in some styling properties to just style that thing.
So first select during an add in is for the hidden class.
It's going to say that if an element has the hidden class then I don't want it to be displayed at all.
So I'll say display none.
Important to make sure 100 percent.
This thing should not show up on the screen and then go into it like the H1.
I'm gonna give it a color of white and a font size of how about thirty six pixels nice and large and
then finally to get this thing centered I'm going to select the winner.
Class that's essentially this div right here I'm going to add on a couple of different rules to it.
So going to say display of flex I'll add on a justify content to justify dash content of center and
a line dash items of center so that's what it's going to get it to be centered on the screen I'll give
it a position of absolute and a z index of 1 to make sure that shows up on top of our canvas element
and then finally I'll give it a height of 100 the H and a width of one hundred VW and that's going to
make sure that it stretches out a full height and width of the screen
it's and how we save this.
No need to go refresh because right now if we refresh we're not going to see anything because we've
got the hidden class on there.
Remember the hidden class hides that div and everything inside of it.
It's now in order to show this message to our user once they've hit our wind condition we just have
to select this element and remove the hidden class.
Now we'll get that div in each one side of it to be displayed there for that I'll go back over to my
index dot J.S. file.
I'm gonna go down to the very bottom where we are handling our win condition right now and then inside
of our if statement I'll add in a selector so document dot query selector I'm going to select the element
with a class of winner
I'll get the class list and I will remove the class of it in
all right I'm going to save both these files I'll go back over I'll refresh so I don't see it on the
screen right away I'm gonna chase change my maze dimensions so you don't have to sit here and watch
me solve this maze forever it's really quickly gonna change two cells horizontal of six and vertical
four there we go nice and easy to solve now I can go on over solve it and there we go.
I see you when I think that text could be a little bit larger so what the heck I'm going to dial up
that font size inside of our style tag right here I'll go to just a know 64 arbitrarily save that
when again and that's good enough I'd say Okay.
That's pretty much it.
That is our main game really downside to this thing is that once a user wins they essentially can't
do it do anything else until they refresh.
So one way you could easily fix that is to just add in a button maybe to recall or wrap all the code
we wrote together and throw that all into a function and then once the user wins maybe show a button
then a user can click to build out the entire grid and verticals and all that kind of stuff again but
I'm going to leave that up as a exercise to you you mean something that you can implement on your own
if you want to as we've definitely spent a pretty good amount of time on this application already.
Okay.
So I hope you enjoyed this app.
I think that it looks pretty interesting and hey who doesn't like a good mace to play around with so
let's take a break here and continue on the next video.