Last thing we have to do is make sure that we get a comparison going between all these different stats.
So back inside of my index dot J.S. file.
I'm going to find where we were just working on on maybe select.
We're going to eventually do a request inside of here.
Remember to get some follow up details about a particular movie.
Now one thing we should probably do inside of here is get a reference or store a reference to that response
that comes back so we can hold on to that reference that movie and all those different statistics so
we can do an easy comparison later on to right above on maybe select.
I'm going to define it two variables with the let keyword.
So I'll say let left movie and write movie then inside this function after we get some data back from
axioms let's make sure that we store the movie that we just fetched on the appropriate variable to do
so.
We're going to need to make sure that we pass in some additional argument here to indicate whether we
are receiving the movie on the left side or the right side.
So inside of both the functions where we call on movie select I'm going to pass in one last variable
here of left as a string and right as a string.
So now we know the context in which on movie select is being called inside of you're going to receive
that as a variable that also calls simply side and then right after we set that inner HMO we can say
something like If side equals left then let's update the left movie variable.
So I'll say left movie is response start data.
Else we must be working with the right side.
So I'll say right.
Movie is response not data.
Then after we update both those variables we should add in a check to see if both the left movie and
right movie are defined.
If both these variables are defined that means we have movie on both sides of the screen and it's time
to run the comparison so after those if else statements I'll say if it's left movie and rights movie
then let's run the comparison.
I'm going to stick all the code for doing the comparison into a helper function called appropriately
named run comparison and I'll define that as a helper function.
Right after
then inside of here we can iterate through are two different movies run all the comparisons and an update
the appropriate statistics on both sides of the screen so inside of here you're going to do a quick
console log for right now and say time for comparison just to make sure that we are running this code
at the appropriate time.
I'll then go back over refresh get that console open and then I'll do Avengers Rigo and Dark Knight
and after I click this movie it would then be in theory time to run the comparison.
So I'd expect to see the console lug appear at that time.
So click there and I do in fact see time for comparison.
So looks like we're off to a good start.
It's now another quick pause we'll come back the next video and figure out how we're going to actually
compare all these different statistics.