All right.
Welcome back.
This is part two of our taste of the dumb little demonstration.
So I'm going to go ahead and play around with Google the home page of Google again.
But I'm going to do something a little bit more visual more intense.
I'm going to take every element that you see on the screen and animated around randomly so it will just
end up being a huge mess to try and use.
And yeah just to show you that we can do things like change dials and move things around and animate
them.
So I'm going to open up my console almost their command option Jay.
There we go.
And the way I'm going to write my code instead of just typing it in the console because I'm going to
have probably 10 or 20 lines I'm going to make a snippet.
And in Chrome to make a snippet we go to sources.
And then there's a tab called snippets.
If it doesn't show up for you you can click the arrow and go to snippets.
This allows me to write some code.
I'm going to click new snippet I can write code and then run it at any point in the browser without
having to make a separate file and it will be evaluated and I can do things with the current web page.
So I'm just going to try something like console dot log two plus two.
I mean I save it and then I can run it either by hitting Where's that button right here clicking this
or using the shortcut which is what I use command enter on a Mac if you're on the P.C. it will tell
you what to use right there.
So I just ran it and if I look at my console you can see four was printed out.
So we're not going to be using console that logs or anything right now.
I'm instead going to interact with the elements over here on the DOM get rid of that triangle.
Some fun top Google searches how to make French toast jobs hiring and funny cat videos can argue with
that.
All right.
So the first thing I'll show you is that we can create new elements.
Super easy.
Well it's relatively easy.
Don't worry about any of this syntax will go into the details about how all of this works.
But I'm going to make a new image.
I'm going to give it a name.
My image.
I'm going to give it a source.
My image source equals and I have a you are all I've copied from on Splash a free image.
We can use.
And then I'm going to add this image to the DOM I'm going to insert it.
So I'll do document top body dot append my image and if I run this code I'll hit command enter.
Hope there's my image.
Very large image but it's showing up.
If I want to amend it to be smaller my image dot style dot with equals.
Let's do 200 pixels run this code again I'll have to refresh my page and run it.
Now we have this image of a dog wearing goggles.
OK.
So that's first.
But now if I want to move it around there's a lot of different ways of doing this.
The best way would be to do it mostly VSI RSS.
But what I want to do is in JavaScript I'm going to generate some random numbers an X and a y coordinate
or a position and use that to move the image to that location using a CSX transform.
So if you haven't seen transforms and CSX this is going to be new but it's really just a demo of cool
stuff we can do.
So don't worry about it.
What I'll do is get my image my image dot style dot transform and before I animate anything I'll just
assign a transform like.
How about translate and then I give it a number like three hundred karma two hundred.
Let's see how that looks.
If I run it up I think I forgot the pixels that I need to add three hundred and 200 pixels.
Let's try that again.
OK.
So now I transformed the image I moved it over here I translated it.
So that's how we can do it just once.
Now if I wanted to do this randomly and I want to repeat it I could do it using a set interval so set
interval I pass in my function I'll use an arrow function just for some diversity here.
And we also need the duration or how long that interval should be.
So every two seconds will run this code and we will transform that image.
But let's generate two random pixel values and I'm going to use the dimensions of the screen which I
can access using document dots body dot client width and client height height.
So that's something we will see and talk about in greater detail.
Document dot body dot client with times math dot random.
Make sure I add my parents and then I'll floor that whole thing as we've seen before to get a whole
number.
So this will give me a random number between 0 and whatever the width of the window is which changes
depending on the actual width.
So here we get a different width versus here we would be getting 400 pixels.
All right.
So mess up floor.
I'm going to save that to a variable called X and then duplicate this and do the same thing for a variable
called Y.
I'm just getting two random numbers.
Top for document out body.
I mean I do client height here and then I'm going to plug those numbers in right here.
So this does need to be a template literal not single quotes.
So I'll put that around my string and then interpolate X pixels and then Y pixels.
And the moment of truth Let's see what happens.
Okay we're getting something.
It's not pretty.
It's very jerky but every two seconds it is moving around.
And if I wanted to make it smoother in my CSX I would add in a transition property although right now
I don't have a CSI style sheet.
This is Google's website so I'll just show you that you can do it through javascript my image DOD style
dot transition equals and then I'll say one.
What is it.
All one second.
Let's do two seconds.
If this interval is two seconds I'll have it take two seconds to translate.
And does it work.
Oh look at that.
It's moving all over the place.
Okay.
So kind of fun.
We're picking a random X and Y on the screen and moving the image.
That image for the record was not there when the page loaded.
We're adding it in so we're seeing a whole bunch of different features already.
We created a new element.
We updated its source attribute.
We added it to the page.
Then we added some CSF to it.
We changed the width to make it smaller.
We changed the transition property to make it smoother when it moves.
And then in a interval we're picking random numbers and using that to generate a translation transform
across the screen every two seconds.
Now for the extra fun part let's do it to every single thing on the page.
So this same logic but I wanted to happen for every element and there's a lot of ways of doing this
but I'm going to do is select all the elements using this document dot body dot children.
Again this is getting to stuff where you have not seen we haven't seen any of this.
So please don't worry about it.
We will get to every every single line of code rewriting here.
We'll have at least a video addressing it and how it works.
So document updated our children will give me all the elements that we're seeing on the page.
I don't want to select every element in the DOM because there are elements like script tags and link
tags in the title tag.
We don't want those.
We want just the stuff showing up so document dump body dot children.
I'll just call this all else.
All elements.
And then I'm going to loop over all elements inside of my interval.
So for.
Let go of all else I'm going to pick an X and Y I'm going to use that x and y to update the transition
excuse me the transform of that element.
So let me make this easier to see instead of my image dot style.
I'm going to do l so I select everything on the page and then for each one I'm going to give it a new
transform with a new random x and y and we'll do it every two thousand seconds or two thousand milliseconds
we'll be here quite a long time if I did it to everyone else.
All right let's go back try it again.
Run my code fingers crossed.
All right.
So we only have the dog image that is transitioning smoothly.
Everything else is just jerking around.
Let's also rotate everything so we could pick a random rotation here we'll call this rotation which
needs to be a number between 0 and 360.
So we'll do math at random times 360.
That should give us a random rotation and then the way that transform works and CSX is that it wants
us to pass in a number of degrees so we'll do it just like this.
Dollar sign rotation and then afterwards we need to write DG for degrees like we had to do for pixels
and this should be rotating not rotation.
Let's try it out.
And there we go.
Things are rotating they're just not animated except for our one image.
So the last thing we'll do is apply a style to everything in the body will add a new part to the style
sheet and I'll just paste the code in for that.
Here what I'm saying is make a new CSF style sheet.
Basically that's what I'm saying and then adding a new selector select everything VRC assess give it
transition of two seconds and then I'll add that style sheet in again.
Don't worry about any of this code whatsoever but let's just see if it works.
I'm going to run it.
Fingers crossed.
Hey look at that.
Everything's all rotating and going crazy moving across the page.
It is kind of annoying that this whole thing is treated as one element.
This I think it's called viewport is the element.
So you might be able to break that up a bit.
Well you can see what I'm trying to show you is how we can select things we can screw with them in maybe
not so nice ways like animating them but these principles apply for everything we would do.
We can interact with the form get the value out or change an image source to make a slideshow widget
we can add events like we saw in the last video we can pick random things and mess with them with random
numbers and transformations maybe not all that often but you can't do that.
We can add new styles to a style sheet we can make things have a transition.
We can create an image out of nowhere and added to the page.
OK.
So I tweeted ever so slightly before what was happening so I was getting every element in the body which
is really just this one div and it contains everything and I was animating this one div.
So this whole piece of content was animating together.
But now what I've done is updated it so that I'm animating these elements inside that div instead which
you can see here.
This is what this line does.
If I run it now we end up with some independent rotation and moving around anyways the whole thing is
useless and silly but it illustrates this idea of changing objects and seeing those changes reflected
in the actual browser.
So everything we've done has been manipulating JavaScript objects hence the object model part of the
Dom.
So really really important idea behind all of this the page loads and all of the juicy content is run
through the DOM machine the DOM maker 3000 obviously not what it's called but it takes that content
it understands it digests it and it spits out a bunch of JavaScript objects some of which we interacted
with in order to make this happen and some of which we created from scratch and then told to the DOM
or told javascript to insert them with the rest of the content.
Okay so now that we've had is somewhat overwhelming taste of the Dom now we're going to go into the
basics and start from the beginning.
How do we do some of the stuff we just did it go into detail around selecting and changing styles and
different attributes and events.
There's a lot to talk about.