The next thing we're going to do inside of our repository is implement the get all method.
So back inside of my editor I'm going to find where I defined check for file right here.
Remember the only reason I mentioned that was to explain why we were going to define access sync and
right file sync inside the constructor and why we were using the sync version at all.
So I'm going to replace that with an async method called get all the inside of here.
Our goal is to open the file called this dot file name and of course not like specifically this dot
file name but whatever.
This dot file name variable is pointing to we're then going to read its contents.
We're going to pass the contents because we are storing Jason data here.
That's the entire idea and we're going to return the past data.
So that's our goal.
Now I wrote out for comments here but as you're going to very quickly see at the end of the day it's
going to end up being just like one line of code.
Let's first focus on this first task which is to open up the file called this dot file name and read
its contents.
Now open up that file.
We'll take a look at the no J.S. standard documentation again and again at the file system module.
Remember you can get here by going to no J S dot org slash API and on this page I'll do a search for
read file so right away I can see that there are at least two versions of read file available to us.
In reality there are three there's the callback based version there's the sync version and then later
on down the file is F S promises dot read file and this is the promised based version of the Read file
function.
In general we prefer to work with premises wherever possible.
So this is the function that we're going to use to open up that file and read its contents so click
it.
We're going to call f s dot promises not read file.
We're going to pass in the file name that we're trying to open.
And then the options object is going to have the encoding of the file that we're trying to open so let's
add in some code for that tobacco back here.
I'm going to say const contents is a weight f s not promises not read file pass in the file name of
this dot file name and the second argument will be an options object with an encoding property of UTF
8 strictly speaking the options object is optional in this case but I'm gonna throw it in here anyways
just for a kind of completion sake it's now if we were to console log out that contents variable we
should see it whatever is contained inside that file let's do a quick console log right here just to
verify
in order to test this function we need to either just call it directly at the very bottom or if we eventually
want to work with the data that gets returned.
We need to call get all with the awake keyword.
Let's try calling this like a very realistic fashion.
So I'm going to wrap our repo creation down here with a function that I'll call simply test because
it's gonna be running all of our test code.
I'm going to mark that function as async so I can use the awake.
You were inside of it.
I'll then call the test function right underneath and I'll make sure I do and await repo.
Dot get all now why do we create a separate function right here to test our code.
Well remember right now like as I'm recording this video no J.S. requires you to put async await code
inside of a function marked as async.
In other words we cannot have a top level variable inside of a file like so that makes use of a weight
right now.
This would result in an error now by the time you watch this video know Jesus might have support for
top level await statements.
They are technically available right now if you're on the latest version of node.
I'm going to assume that you might be running earlier version of No that doesn't have support for top
level async await.
That's the only reason I created this helper function right here called test OK.
Let's now save this file I'm to go back over to my terminal.
I'm still inside the repositories directory and I will run node users dot J.S. and make sure you do
dot J.S. not Jason.
Jason is our data center our file with all of our data inside of it.
So as soon as I run that I see a console log of an empty array.
The reason we see an empty array remember backup here inside of our constructor by default.
When we created the file we wrote in an empty array.
The reason that we wrote in the error empty array is that we are always working with an array of records
no matter what even if the files it is empty.
We will always be giving back a empty array or at least an array data structure so we can always assume
that there is an array inside there.
Okay this looks good.
So let's just take a quick pause when come back the next video we're going to add in a little bit more
code to make sure that we pass the contents because right now even though it appears that we are console
logging out just an array that technically is a string that contains the array characters are like the
square brackets so we can make sure that we pass the contents and then eventually return that pass data.