Next up we'll dive into our first for array methods.
Now there are more to come as you can see here.
But these first four are grouped together for a reason.
They're really commonly used and they all have to do with either adding content or removing content
or elements from an array.
So adding to the end removing from the end removing from the start adding to the start.
These are really common operations.
Before we take a look at them if you go to the documentation on empty end for array under javascript
reference array on the left hand side you can see that there is a really long list of methods just like
with strings every array comes with a bunch of built in actions.
And if you have questions about any of them you can click and read to learn more.
So let's say we wanted to start with push.
That's a good place to start.
This tells us push method ads or the push method adds one or more elements to the end of an array.
Okay.
And you can see an example here we have some elements in an array.
If we push the value cows now the array has cows at the end.
So we're gonna play around with these four methods.
Push pull.
Oh my God.
Push Pop.
Shift and on shift the array we'll use is called top songs.
It has four songs so far.
Notice that I spread it out on two different lines.
Totally valid and a much nicer choice when you have a lot of content or long lines.
It's really hard to understand or to read if it's all in one supermassive line.
So this works.
And let's say I want to add something into the end.
We saw how we could add to the end using that length.
So top songs and then square brackets top songs out.
I think that works.
It's just kind of annoying.
We can instead use push so top songs dot push is going to push a song or whatever we add in.
It could be a number.
It's going to push it to the very end of the array.
So top song stop push and let's go with fortunate son
okay.
Refresh the page.
And we now have top songs.
We're fortunate son is at the end.
We now have five items.
We had four before.
Now we have five.
If we pushed again top song stop push this time I'll just push true.
It doesn't make sense but I'll do it.
Notice what it's returning to me.
It's giving me a value back and that value is six.
That value is the new length of the array.
So it changes the array.
If we look at top songs
there is true at the end.
But in the process it also returns to us.
The new value will learn a lot more about return values and how we can return our own values and functions
later on.
But it's important to understand that that is what's happening here unlike with string methods where
if we had a string we wanted to uppercase it.
We weren't actually changing the original string as we've seen strings are not mutable they are immutable.
So if we had let S T R equals hello and we call as TR dot to uppercase it returns the uppercase version
and we have to capture it in a variable if we want the new version.
The upper case version because string is still unchanged with an array.
When you push you're actually changing you are mutating the array itself and so it returns something
else.
In this case it returns the number or the length for how many items are in there.
Okay so that's pushing push goes onto the end.
We also have Pop Pop.
We'll take a value from the end.
So when it clear my console here we have top songs.
I put that true on the end.
That seems stupid.
So let's remove it.
Top songs dot Pop Pop it's going to always remove the last item and it returns its value to you.
So this is useful.
The fact that it returns it to you if you were creating a list that was managing your to dos and you
always wanted to get the last to do on that list in order to do something with it you could pop it off
and then you would have that value returned to you so you could store it in a variable so I could do
top songs dot pop.
This is going to give me a song this time true is gone so it will give me fortunate son so we could
go with concert next song equals top song stop pop and if we look at next song it has fortunate son.
If we look at top songs it does not have fortunate son anymore.
Now as far as popping it and calling it next song we would be playing through these songs backwards.
If we are popping each time which is fine maybe we have the list reversed but you probably would be
playing songs in the beginning but also when you pop something off it's gone.
So it's more applicable to the first example I gave of a to do list where you pop something off you
do it and you don't need it anymore.
If this was actually a playlist we don't want to remove that song we don't want it to be gone from the
list we just want to play it.
So let's push and pop we can pop as many times as we want.
Now if we keep popping and so I'll do top songs that pop over and over and over until we have nothing
left it returns undefined and our array is just going to be completely empty.
So push and pop I think are relatively easy to remember.
You push your forcing something into the end you're pushing it in pop you're popping from the end and
maybe it just makes sense to me but I have a much easier time remembering these to push and pop than
I do.
The next two we'll talk about shift and on shift I always mix them up even five six seven years later
still drives me crazy but we're only focusing on pushing pop for now.
Again push add something to the end you pass into value to be added and it will add to the end and return
the new length.
Pop does the opposite.
You don't specify a value you just call it with empty parentheses.
It does the same thing every time it takes the last item out of the array.
It's not just getting you the value it is removing it and then returning it.