Next up let's talk about string methods so we haven't really talked about methods at all.
Methods are kind of like built in pieces of functionality built in actions that can be performed on
a certain thing a particular value or in our case on any string.
So we can do things like search for a particular string within a string.
Does this string contain a dollar sign we can replace parts of a string we can change case from lowercase
to uppercase to ALL CAPS.
We can remove Additional spacing if we want to get rid of spacing.
There's a bunch of these different features that come built in with every single string and they all
follow this format.
So we have a string dot some method name with opening and closing parentheses and to be clear strings
are not the only things that have methods.
There are no methods that are built in.
They're just not as useful.
So am I going to talk about them just yet.
String methods however are really useful.
So I'm going to cover some of the most important ones.
If we go to EMDIN And we look at string it's under the javascript reference built in objects string
on the left hand side you'll see a very long list of methods.
Each one of these is an action we can perform on every single string so we can take a look at one of
them like two upper case or two lower case like this one before I do that.
I just want to mention these thumbs down mean that you shouldn't really use these anymore.
They're deprecated.
They still work because javascript needs to support older Web sites.
They still need to work in the browser even though you're not really supposed to use these anymore.
But those withstanding there's still quite a few different methods that we have access to.
So here's one two uppercase and the way that we call it is on a certain string dot to uppercase open
closed prints.
So let's make a variable called message.
We'll set it to you are so grounded mister like that and go hit enter.
If we call message dot to uppercase I'm just going to use autocomplete.
So t o you.
Tab and then Prince.
This is what we get we get a new version a new string.
So to be clear the original is unchanged.
Remember that the strings are immutable.
We can't change the first character we can't change any character manually.
Same thing here if we uppercase a string we are creating a new string or we're getting a reference to
a new string.
That is the same content just uppercase.
So if we wanted to save that to the variable we could do message equals message dot to uppercase or
we could just make a new variable called yell or uppercase message or something like that.
Now I have a message and it's been updated.
Let's quickly talk about those perennials.
They're really really important.
If you leave them off it's not going to work.
They won't throw an error it won't break your code but you're not actually executing that action you're
just sort of asking javascript does that action exist.
So we also have a two lowercase and if I call it we get you are so grounded Mr. lowercase remember message
is now uppercase but if we do it without the Prince just message that to lowercase javascript just tells
me.
Yeah that's the thing.
There's some code for two lowercase it's an action a function.
Do you want me to call it.
It's not even asking if we want to call it.
That's kind of how I personify it.
And if you do want to call it you need those prints.
So that's two uppercase and two lowercase i have a slide on that as well.
Remember the original value is unchanged in less you manually set the variable using the return value
from two uppercase or two lowercase and then the second method will look at for now is called trim trim
is very simple it just removes trailing leading and trailing whitespace so spaces at the beginning and
end of a string when you call trim it returns a string where that space has been removed.
So it's not going to remove all spaces.
Let's do let color equals purple with some spaces in there.
I'll even hit tab a couple times just like that.
Now if I call color dot trim with parents it removes those spaces color is still unchanged of course
as we've seen before.
And another thing we can do is we can call trim.
And then on top of that we can chain on another method call like two upper case.
So trim will run first which takes this string and it returns a version with no spaces on either end.
Then we're basically calling purple this dot to uppercase.
So this goes first.
And then to uppercase runs on whatever this returned.
So we end up with purple no space and all caps.
Quick note about trim if you have spaces in the middle of the word like this it is not going to remove
those.
It only removes the leading and trailing spaces while keeping all other spaces intact.
Those are the first two string methods in the next video.
We have a different batch that works slightly differently.
But remember all these methods whether we're working with a string a number or something else like when
we get to arrays objects they all have a set of built in methods built in actions.
We call them by referencing a thing a string and array dot a method name with parents call.