We've now got an implementation of for each.
And we are reasonably confident that it works the way we expect because we have a test inside of our
index test JSF file it's now jammed in a little bit more code to our project.
Let's try to implement another function.
I want to try to implement another function that we are already familiar with and is also present inside
the load Ash library.
So I'm back here at the documentation once again I'm gonna take a look at the map function.
So this is the same kind of map function that we've used throughout the course the same kind of map
function that is built into all JavaScript arrays.
Remember load Ash was created before map belong to a race in the job script language and that's why
this library has it defined.
So we're going to re implement map from scratch with the same kind of style you see right here.
Yes we could absolutely use the map function built into our JavaScript arrays.
So what we're doing here is kind of pointless.
But again we're just doing it to have something to actually test the way that the load Ash map function
works is let's go down a little bit see an example.
So we're going to pass in an array.
The second argument is going to be some function that we want to run on every element in that array.
So in this case they're passing on the square function whatever it gets returned from that second argument
or that function right there when it gets called is going to be used to assemble a brand new Array.
So in this case you'll see they put in four and eight.
So that means that the value for is going to go into square they're going to multiply four by four and
they end up getting sixteen as then returned from the square function.
So internally map is going to collect that new value and add it to a brand new Array.
That same process gets very heated for the number eight eight times eight is 64.
And so the sum total or the output of the map function in this case would be 16 and 64.
So again that is a new array.
It has all the different values after they've been processed by the square function let's start to implement
this back inside of our project as well.
But you know what this time around let's do things a little bit differently.
Rather than writing out an implementation of our map function inside of index J.S. let's try to instead
write out a test first and that might sound crazy because hey we don't really know how the map function
is going to be put together.
That's true.
We don't really know how we're going to write out the map function.
However we do know exactly what arguments the map function requires.
And chances are we can guess what different output it is going to return so when we write out tests
we don't really care so much about the internal implementation of a chunk of code.
All we really care about is knowing what goes into it and what should come out with that knowledge alone.
We should be able to write a test to make sure that map works the way we expect so let's try to write
out a test first inside of our index not test out j ust file.
So I'm going to first try to require in a map function from index that map function doesn't exist yet.
So we're definitely going to have to define it.
We'll do that in just a moment.
Well let's write out some tests for it first.
So down underneath our existing test I'm going to create a new array of numbers once again.
So I call this how about what we call the original one we didn't actually assign to a variable let's
just call a map directly.
I'm gonna put in an array of 1 2 and 3 again I'll then put in my iterator function that's going to receive
every value inside there.
So let's try to do something really similar to that load Ash function.
I'm going to take the value I'm going to return value times to so when we call map we should get back
a result that are assigned to a variable result and results should look something like this should be
something equal to 2 4 and 6 so let's now write out some code to make sure that is the case make sure
that's the case with some code we can just do a series of IF statements like what we had up here.
So let's say if result at zero is not equal to two then let's throw an error has something just went
wrong it means that we did not put our map statement together correctly.
So throw a new error like expected to find two but found and then we could use some string interpolation
here to put the actual value that we found that would make it just a little bit easier for us to debug
if we ever saw this error at our terminal so in order to get a value inside there are to replace the
single quotes with back to X and then at the very end I'll put results at zero.
Now we can repeat this process so I will copy that if statement down twice for the second if statement
I'll check results at 1 so at that index it should be four for I'll update the a little check right
there.
And then finally on the third one we'll check resulted.
Two that one should be six and I'll update the text inside of our little message as well.
All right.
So we now have a test to make sure that map works the way we expect.
So now we can go back over to our terminal and run this test of course once we do so we're gonna see
a very big error really quickly.
Something like math is not a function because we haven't even defined that function yet.
But we at least now have something that we can run again and again specifically this test file to kind
of gauge our progress and make sure that we are implementing the map function correctly.
And by the end when we actually have implemented this thing in its entirety we will have some block
of code.
So like this stuff right here that will verify that the map function works as expected for all time.
Let's now go back over to our index dot just file we'll take a stab at implementing this map function
back over here.
I'm gonna put in a second property into my object called map so this will also be called with some array
and some function so inside of here we're gonna take a very similar approach to what we just did inside
of our for each so we're going to write out a for loop a real simple basic one like that right there
we're going to iterate over every value inside of our array and for every value we're gonna call that
callback function.
But this time around we're going to receive whatever the callback function returns and add it into a
brand new Array.
So let's write out the implementation really quickly at the very top I'll say results is going to be
an empty array.
So this is going to be the new array of values that we're going to add to as we iterate through our
array I'll then do a four let I equals zero I less than error length plus plus.
Well then do you just as we had before F N will pass in a r at I and as the second argument we'll throw
in the index as well.
And now because this is a map statement we're going to take whatever gets returned from that's an added
into our results array.
So I will wrap that entire statement with result thought push.
And then finally after the for loop we can't return that new array of results so there's our implementation.
Now once again if we were back like anywhere else inside this course to test this out we would have
gone down here and written out like Okay let's call a map with 1 2 3 let's do whatever.
And then eventually just do a console log and we would have to go to our terminal and verify that that
console lock were correctly instead let's just run the test file that we already put together.
So I'll go back over to my terminal.
I'm going to rerun node index dot test dot J.S. and I don't see any error whatsoever.
What does that mean.
It means that the code we just wrote worked perfectly.
Now in order to make sure that our test here isn't like a fluke or anything like that we could go back
over to our map statement and tried to introduce a bug to this thing on purpose.
The reason we would do this is to make sure that our code actually works as expected so I might change
the let I equals zero right here to let I equals 1.
So now we're not going to iterate through the whole array.
So I would now expect to see my test back inside of index not test.
J.S. I would expect to see a failure over here.
I would expect to see something go wrong.
That can go back to my internal rerun and sure enough I do see an error.
So I expected to find two but found four instead.
So now we know or we have some level of confidence that our test is working as expected because we introduced
a bug if we ever run a test and we don't see any errors at all.
It kind of makes you have to think well did the test actually run did actually work as expected.
And so very commonly when we run some testing code or write a test for the very first time we will introduce
a bug just to make sure that yeah the test actually is running okay.
So this looks pretty good.
So we've got a working implementation of that so at this point we've gone through and tested two different
functions and we wrote out the test for them in this separate companion file.
Now this approach it definitely works right.
We have proven that we can run some code inside this other file to make sure that our main application
works as expected.
But there are some very big downsides to this approach.
So in the next video I'm going to outline some big issues with our current approach of testing and we're
going to learn how we can fix it first by making a couple of changes to our project and then by eventually
using an outside testing library as well.
So quick pause right here and I'll see you in just a minute.