The last statistic we need to pass is the number of awards.
So how are we going to reduce this down to something that can be easily compared between different movies.
Well we're just going to take all the different awards or the total number of awards here.
We're gonna find all the different numbers in here.
Add them all together and we'll say whoever had the most numbers inside this statistic wins.
So technically one movie that has like one win but one hundred nominations will beat out a movie with
ten wins.
In theory the movie with ten wins and like zero nominations would be better but for our purposes or
the purposes of this application we're just going to say whoever had the most numbers in this thing
is the winner.
So let's write out some code that's going to take a look at that string and extract the total number
out of it.
Back over here inside of movie template I'm going to delete that comment up top.
I'm going to delete the console log and then we're going to declare a new variable called awards.
So for this one we'll take a look at movie detail.
We're going to look at the awards property which is that big long string.
We're going to first begin by splitting it on space.
This right here is going to give us an array where every element in the array is one of the different
actual words or numbers in here.
So essentially all the spaces go away and just the element words we get inside of an array so then we're
going to iterate through that array and we're going to say that for every actual number in there we're
going to keep some running total.
And then eventually return it and we're going to write this out in two different ways.
We're going to write it out first with a for each and we're going to refactor it to use a reduced statement
instead.
This is a perfect location to do a reduce but just as some quick practice just to get familiar because
we're already doing some hard enough things here.
Well first do a for each thread above.
I'm going to declare a variable called Count and start off with zero.
This is going to track the number of award values.
So in this case we'd have like about what 118 for this movie right here.
That's one plus seventy nine plus thirty eight.
So on split member that gives us an array.
So call for each and then I'm going to take each word inside of that sentence and I first need to see
if I am working with a number or not.
The first time that function gets called it's going to receive the word nominated.
That's obviously not a number.
So did check to see if we're working with a number or not.
We're going to first try to pass this thing so I'll say value is pass it with word if we try to pass
an int on a string that doesn't contain any number whatsoever.
We're going to get back a value of not a number.
Let's do a quick test of that inside of our console over here.
Very quickly just to get a reminder of that behavior.
So over here I'll do a percent of not a number and I get back and then which again stands for Not a
number.
If I do pass it on say nominated yep we definitely get back not a number that's how we're going to tell
if we're working with an actual number or not value is going to be not a number so to check to see if
we have a number or not.
We will say if is men N A N like so that's how we check to see if a value is not a number or not inside
of JavaScript.
That is a function that is built into the browser.
So we don't need to define it or anything like that.
We're going to say if this value is not a number then we're just going to stop the return saying right
here is just going to return from the inner function.
So in other words we're going to say don't try to add anything to count or anything like that.
Otherwise we'll do count is count plus value like so okay.
So now at the very end I'll do a console dot log of count and we'll test this thing out for that first
movie I'll refresh look up Avengers click it and there we go.
I get the one hundred eighteen so again that is the one plus thirty eight plus seventy nine so we could
stop there and just say oh yeah count is our variable but instead like I said let's try to refactor
this for each into a reduced statement instead because this really is a perfect place to make use of
reduce so with reduced remember we're going to change the for each to reduce then the second argument
to the reduced function the first is the actual function we want to run.
The second is going to be the starting value for our reduction.
So in our case are starting value is zero then the first argument that inner function is going to be
the previous value.
And the second will be the word that we are currently iterating over.
So then inside of this function body we need to make sure that we return the next value for the next
iteration through this loop so right here in the return case rather than just returning nothing we're
going to instead return previous.
So the value that we just are iterating over a year is not actually a number then just return whatever
our current counties.
Otherwise we're going to return the previous value that we got plus this new value okay.
So now we can't delete the let count up here and just to make sure this works correctly again I'm gonna
do a council like now of awards I'll save that.
Another quick test so refresh look up ventures look at and I still get the one 18.
All right.
So that is it we've now extracted some meaningful values out of all these different statistics.
Now the last thing we have to do is take these different values and inject them as data properties on
each of these different articles.
Once again once we do that we can then pull those values out later on when we decide that it is time
to compare these different statistics.
So quick pause right here and we'll take care of that in the next video.