All right.
Let's get to it.
Let's run our comparison on both sides.
The first thing you've to do is select all these different articles and we need to make sure that we
keep the two different sets separate as a quick reminder if we open up our element inspector again the
entire summary on the left hand side is enclosed inside of a div with an I.D. of left dash summary.
So if I want to get all the articles that have a statistic inside of there I can select a document query
selector I.D. left dash summary that's going to give me essentially the entire left side and then I
can find all of the elements inside there with a class of notification.
So I'll do inside of that a query selector of DOT notification.
I want to do a query selector.
My mistake on do a query selector.
All that will give me all of them.
There we go there's my list of five.
I've got all five on the left hand side the three clear we don't actually have to run the two separate
query selectors.
We could actually reduce that down to just one.
So I could do.
Document doc query selector all and then say inside of the Left summary element find all the elements
with notification and that will still give me all five on the left hand side.
So that's how we're going to make sure that we get all five on the left and all five on the right.
So back over here inside of run comparison we're going to get all the elements on the left and right
I'll say How about left side stats that's like the statistics being rendered out on the left hand side
will be document dot query selector all and then we want I.D. the left side would we call it left or
left summary my mistake not notification then we can do the same thing for right side stats.
Now the document dot query selector all right dash summary not notification.
All right.
So now we can loop over either one of these and at each step we can take the corresponding element from
the other pair or essentially you'd like the right hand side and we could do our comparison by retrieving
the data set values.
So I'm going to try to iterate over each element inside of left side stats.
So I'm going to do a left side stats dot for each so I'm going to get my callback function right here.
I'm going to receive each article element I will call them left stat.
So again that represents an article element that is going to have that data set value that we really
care about.
And I'm also going to get the index of that element inside of left side stats as well.
The reason I'm getting the index right there is that I can retrieve the appropriate corresponding stat
from right side stats.
So I'll say right stat is right side stats at index and then again just to make sure we're doing everything
correctly here I'll do a console log of left stat and right stat it's all safe.
Go back over to the refresh I'll look for Avengers Dark Knight and there we go.
We've got our console logs so we can see that each of these console log peers are the two corresponding
article elements that go with each other.
So like that one and that one and then the box office box office metal score metal score I'm DV rating
and so on.
Then inside of here we're going to do first get the actual value property off of each of these.
I'm gonna say left side value is going to be left stat and to get a data set property remember we refer
to data sets and then the name of that data property on that element.
So in our case we call the data property's value.
So we would reference that value property with data set dot value and then we can get the right hand
side with right side value is right side or something right stat dataset not value as well.
So now inside of here we can do our comparison directly between the two.
Again take note that this comparison process right here because we assign the stats up front inside
of our movie template we don't care about the order in which these different stats occur they can occur
in any different order.
We can have the box office value then the rating then the better score or the totally opposite.
And it just doesn't matter.
All we have to do is make sure that we are iterating through the same properties on both sides at the
same time some of the words we could not show like first of words over here and then first box office
over here.
That's the only thing that we could not do inside of here.
I'll say if right side value is greater than left side value that means the right side is greater.
And that means that we want to add a class to the left hand side.
That's going to turn it yellow instead of the default green.
So to make sure that we turn the left side yellow we would run left stat which remember is the actual
article element I you look at the class list I'm going to remove the is primary which is what makes
it green.
Again this is some class names coming from bonus SS and then on the left stat class list.
I will add in is Dash warning and that's what's going to turn yellow.
Now we can repeat the same process for the opposite case as well.
So I'll say else right stat class list remove is primary and right stat class list add is Dash warning
all right.
So that should be it.
So here it is.
This is our moment of truth.
This should be like the entire application all put together.
Let's do our final test so I will do a refresh.
I'm gonna look for Avengers look for dark knight.
There we go.
And all right that is it and it's looking pretty good.
So we can look through all these different stats and we should see that these stats that are green are
greater than the ones in yellow.
So first off we've got like 118 wins versus the like 300 and change.
So definitely the correct one is green while the Avengers had a higher box office value.
So that definitely won out.
However dark knight has a better medal score better idea rating and more votes as well.
So that's pretty much it.
That is the whole application.
Well I hope you enjoyed putting this thing together.
Let's take a quick pause right here when we come back next video we're going to do a quick review on
some of the important points around this application.