We just wrote out a pretty good amount of code and believe it or not there's actually a lot of functionality
packed into every line here.
So I want to take a look at a diagram that's going to help you get a better sense of what is really
going on behind the scenes.
So let's get to it.
OK so we just typed in local host colon 3000 into our browser.
When we did so our browser formulated a network request.
The browser itself is not responsible for actually issuing that network request.
Instead it hands the request off to your operating system in all the different network devices that
are connected to your operating system the request that was issued has a couple of different properties
tied to it.
First off the browser takes the URL that you entered right there and splits it into a couple of different
pieces.
First off there's the host property inside there.
The host property is essentially the domain that we are trying to access in our case it was local host
but it could have just as easily been something like Google dot com or Airbnb Wycombe or whatever else.
We also manually specified a port.
That is what the colon three thousand indicates.
We'll discuss what the port means in just a moment but for right now just understand that we manually
specified a port of three thousand when you make a request or when you type into your address bar Google
dot com.
If you put a h TTP at the start of the URL the default port is 80.
If you put an HDD P.S. the default port is 4 4 3 instead.
So that is why when we make a normal request with the oil we normally don't have this colon number right
here because usually there is a default value being used instead Next up is the path property we put
in local host colon 3000 by itself everything after that colon 3000 is interpreted to be the path that
we are trying to access on this remote server.
If we put in nothing at all a default of forward slash is used.
So in our case the path was forward slash and finally the request has a method as well.
When you put an address into your address bar and hit enter the method other requests by default is
get in all capitals.
There are several other methods of requests available to us.
The method of request indicates the intent of the request.
In other words is this a request that is attempting to get some information or retrieve information
is a request meant to create a record or delete a record or update a record all these different actions.
Have a method associated with them.
We'll discuss methods a good bit later on but right now just understand that the method other requests
we just made was get this request is taken and handed off to our operating system the operating system
is then in charge of accessing some network device that is connected to your computer and then sending
the request out over the open Internet.
I first want to consider the case in which we might be making a request to a host other than local host.
So something like say Google dot com.
So normally when you make a request to anything besides local host your operating system is going to
reach out to something called a DNS server this DNS server is some outside server on the Internet publicly
available.
It essentially has a mapping between different host names in IP addresses.
So if you make a request to Google dot com your operating system is going to make some initial request
over to this DNS server and say hey I'm trying to access Google dot com.
What is their IP address DNS server.
Well then take the IP address for Google dot com and send it back to your machine.
Your machine will then make a second request.
This is the actual real request to that IP address.
So in this case let's imagine was 1 9 4 4 8 while Bob was so your operating system would take that request
send off to that web server and then eventually get a response back.
Again that is the normal operation.
If we had a host other than local host.
But in this case.
Well we do have closed your operating system treats requests with the host of local hosts slightly differently
rather than reaching to some outside DNS server your operating system says Oh local host.
That means me.
And that's really what it means local host means the local computer so your operating system decides
should not do anything with this outside DNS server.
Instead it says I'm going to handle this request on my own because it's trying to access some server
that I am hosting your operating system is then going to take a look at the port that is specified inside
the request.
So it turns out that your computer has a huge array about 65000 different ports available to access
all these different ports are essentially little communication channels.
So on your computer you can have many many different running web servers at any point in time.
And each of these different ports can essentially take incoming requests and write them off to some
other program so your operating system sees local host 3000 and it sees a port of three thousand so
it says OK I'm going to handle this locally and I'm going to take this request and send it to whatever
piece of software is running on port three thousand.
So your operating system will take that request and send it off two or three thousand and that's where
our Express server comes into play.
Our express server is listening on port three thousand because we specifically configured it to do so.
The Express server can listen on just about any other port that is open or available for access on your
computer but usually as a development port like just total convention.
No good reason whatsoever besides this is what everyone does.
We use port three thousand.
We could just as easily use port three thousand one or two or three.
It really doesn't matter whatsoever.
Again usually just convention to do 3000 because Express is listening on port three thousand when your
operating system sends that request over.
Express is going to see or receive that incoming request so we can then imagine that express receives
that each to achieve your request and I've got inside the diagram right here by the time that the request
gets into Express.
Express doesn't really care about the hostname property so like the hostname over here or the port as
well.
Those pieces of information are available to express but we really just don't care about them whatsoever.
The host and the port are really about just getting this request to the appropriate server and we've
done that.
So at that point time we don't really care about the host or the port from then on but express does
care about is the path that we are trying to access and the method so inside of our code we saw that
we wrote out some little bit or a little statement that said app not get or add slash the doc get right
here means watch for incoming requests that have a method of get and the forward slash means watch for
incoming requests that have a route or a path of simply forward slash when we called app to get we set
up a root handler and that gets registered with something called a router the router is responsible
for taking these incoming requests looking at the path and the method and then calling the appropriate
callback function that we registered with the router so again when we called app dot get to set up our
root handler we essentially registered a route with a router object so anytime there's this incoming
request the router object is going to look at that request and says OK if this incoming request is a
get request and has a path of forward slash I'm going to run this function in this case it is that callback
function that we authored and passed in as the second argument we can also register multiple other root
handlers with the router as well and each of these other ones could be watching for a request with a
different path or a different method in every scenario.
If the router sees an incoming request with that appropriate path and method it's going to create a
request object of the request and hand it off to the callback function that we authored it is then up
to our callback function.
So that is this thing right there to take the incoming request and the outgoing response formulate some
kind of response and decide what information we want to send and call dot sent to express then formulates
a response and sends it back to whoever made the original request.
In this case our browser this entire kind of scenario right here of express listening on a port this
is not only what occurs on our local machine.
This also occurs if we had expressed in some kind of production environment where we were serving request
to some outside public users so this scenario right here.
Again this is exactly what happens in a production environment just in this case and this diagram shows
you can reflect how everything is working on your local computer okay.
So that gives you a little bit more information about what is going on inside this file that explains
what's going on with apt.
Listen 3000 right there.
That is us telling express to watch for incoming requests on port three thousand.
Again it could have just as easily been say 30 50 or 30 51 or whatever else but usually by convention
we use 3000.
It also experiment explains this segment right here.
We are registering a callback rate route handler so our router object that is inside of this app thing
is going to watch for any incoming requests if it ever sees a request with a method of get and a route
or a path of forward slash.
It will then run our callback function right there all right now we've got a better idea of what's going
on behind scenes.
Another quick pause and continue in just a moment.