Next up a very important topic how do we attach event listeners to multiple elements.
We've seen how we can attach multiple event listeners to one element.
We had a button and that Button had a click listener click handler and also a mouse over.
But how do we take every button on a page and add a click event handler.
Or how do we take every upvote arrow on Reddit and make it do something when you click upvote versus
downvote.
We don't attach those manually one at a time.
At least we don't hardcoded.
We use a loop.
So here are some examples.
This game we saw earlier on each one of these cards has some event functionality.
When I click it flips I click it flips when I hover.
That's probably done through C Ss so it's probably not a javascript event but it could be a mouse over.
But each time I click.
There is an event that's firing and it pertains to each one of these cards.
And there's no way.
I mean there's no I can't imagine that they're doing this manually where they have a variable button
one button to button three button four and they're calling at event listener on every single button.
That would be disastrous.
Here's another example a simple calendar widget.
It's not that simple.
Actually it's a good amount of code coming from code pen.
And every single day has some functionality I can click and stuff happens.
That's about it.
But we have some quick functionality on every date on this calendar.
So let's see how we do that.
I have my blank HCM page and rather than putting HD UML here to start with let's generate some with
our javascript so I'll delete what we had before and I'm gonna make just some colored boxes you'll see
why in a bit different colored boxes using an array of colors.
We can just do the standard boring rainbow colors red orange.
Okay I have an array of colors red orange yellow green blue purple indigo violet.
I want to loop over all of these colors and create a div on the page with that background color so I'll
do a for let color of colors.
We want to create a div or document that create element div save that to a variable.
I'll call it box and I'm going to do a couple of things first I'll actually define a class called box
in my C assess and I'll give it a width of.
Let's start with 200 pixels a height of 200 pixels and then let's create a container to insert all of
our boxes in our hmo.
So we'll create maybe a section give it an I.D. of foxes and that's where we'll attach all of these
boxes so we'll select that document that query selector using the I.D. sign boxes we'll call this the
container as the variable name.
We want to make a box.
We also want to assign that box dot style dots background color camel cased to be color from the loop.
So the first one will be an empty div with a background of red and then orange and so on and we'll append
them to the container.
So container dots append child or just regular append if you don't care about i.e. a pen child of box
and I also have that box class.
But let's let's see if it's showing up at all right now.
If we inspect we should see that we do have divs in there but they have no content and they don't have
a height or width because our class is not being used.
So let's add that class box dot class list dot add box refresh.
Hey there's our boxes and weighs them down again.
Okay so we've got these different boxes.
I'm quickly going to style them so in my C assess what I'm going to do is give the boxes I.D. which
is our container a display of flex if you're not familiar with Flex box.
Uh well we don't have time to talk about that in this video.
It's a relatively easy way of positioning elements on the page and divvying up space.
How do you justify content center a line items center.
Let's see if that works for us.
Okay awesome.
So we have this going now.
We have our boxes on the page now for the main event.
How do we add a click listener to each one.
Well the most obvious answer that you probably came up with is to use a loop and that's the right way
of doing it.
So we just loop over all those boxes we add an event to earn an event listener to each one.
But if we want to do something unique for each box.
If I wanted to print out the color that we're clicking on we have to add a little more code in but let's
start by adding in an event listener for each box.
So we could do a separate loop we could select all the boxes and using query selector all loop over
each box into box dot add event listener or we could just do it right here as we append it or after
we appended it doesn't matter.
I could do box dots add event listener remember this box variable is a new div each time through so
it will reference or it refers to the red box you see here and then next time around it's the orange
one then all the way down to the violet one so box that add event listener for click or add in our function
here.
And why don't we just cancel that log clicked a box.
So this is simple enough we should get a console dot log click the box clicked the box I'm clicking
if you can't hear that.
But what if I want to print out these specific color that was clicked or do something with that color
maybe change the background of the entire body.
It's actually not that bad in this loop we have box.
I could just access box I could console dialog box dot and then style dot background color and print
that out and let's refresh the page.
Red orange yellow green blue purple indigo violet Indigo.
I mean violet violet violet Indigo.
Anyway distracted here.
This works.
We have access to the variable box because we're inside the loop still.
But here's where it gets a little trickier.
Let's say that my code is getting really long and I want to break it into separate functions.
I don't want to have all of this all my logic contained in one loop.
I want to break it out.
Maybe this function here is 50 lines.
How could I make that work.
Well if I make a separate function let's call this function.
Let's do function expression.
We'll go with print color equals a function.
And in here what I want to do is print out the background color and I'll update my at event listener
to call print color like this.
So box that at event listener of click when there's a click on that box print color.
Right now I don't have a way to access box at all.
I could pass it in but I can't do that here because the function will execute right away.
If I were to pass box in so I guess I could rewrite this as a function like this and then call print
color and then pass it in box like this.
Let's see if that works instead of print color.
We'll accept a box as a parameter and constant dialog box dot style dot background again so I have this
function that runs and all it does is it calls print color up here.
Imagine we have a lot more code.
Okay.
So this does work.
We can pass that argument around of box but there's another option which doesn't involve having to add
a function in here.
I can simply pass print color and I'll have to change it because right now box will be completely undefined.
But what is the magical keyword I can use to reference the item that has been clicked it.
Is this the keyword this.
So if we console dot log this in print color we don't need to pass in a box.
Let's see what happens now red orange yellow.
This is referring to the individual div that was clicked on.
Remember that this instead of a method which is added on to an object.
This will refer to that object if you skipped over the section on this.
I highly recommend you go back and check it out.
It's not the sexiest thing ever in javascript but it is important.
We also could rewrite this to do something else instead of printing out the background color let's either
change the background color of the body or maybe we'll add an H1 in up top each one say pick a color
and we'll change the color of our H1 depending on what you click on.
And I'm going to give my H1 a text a line of center not text decoration.
So it's aligned in the middle and then in my javascript I'll select that H1 so const H1 equals document
dot query selector H1 and I'll put it in the function up top and instead of calling this print color
we'll go with change color we'll call change color down here and then what we want to do is update each
one dot style dot color to be this dot style dot background color.
So whichever div we clicked on we want to take the background color of that which is what we're doing
right here get that value and set the H1 which isn't on the page right now.
There it is set the H1 to be that color now change color is not defined let's see change color extra
E There we go.
Let's see if it works.
All right we've got red orange yellow green blue purple indigo violet.
Awesome.
So we've got this nice little off color picker.
Very simple but the point that I want to make here is that we can add event listeners to multiple elements
instead of a loop.
I'm not saying that you should use this pattern here where you always need to use the keyword this but
generally inside of an event handler like we have here.
This will refer to the individual element that the event listener has been added to.
So if I instead had instead of box that at event listener if I instead had document dump body out of
ADD event listener or I had a button this will refer to whatever I'm attaching that event listener to
so let's add one to our H one very quickly we have our H one I'll just select it up here now and do
H1 dot add event listener and we'll listen for maybe a mouse over no capital Oh that always gets me
and we'll add in our function why don't we just cancel that log this dot in our text and we'll see what
happens here and now when I mouse over that H1 we're getting pick a color this is referring to the H
one that the add event listener ran on her that we attached it to so I'll get rid of that we don't need
to add that mouse effect and we'll leave it at this no pun intended but already.
So we saw that we can add multiple click listeners to one click listener to multiple elements they are
separate out event listener calls it's not like we have one event that we're listening for We're attaching
eight or nine or however many different colors we have we're attaching that many event listeners it's
not like we just have one overarching event listener we have multiple.
All right.