I'm taking a look at the search results that we've just got back from the OMD API inside of here.
I'm looking at the very first results and I'm noticing that we've got just a couple of different properties
that represent this first search result one thing that's kind of interesting is that I don't see any
information related to a lot of the stuff that we need to actually make this application work correctly.
So for example we want to make sure that we eventually show a short summary of the movie and be box
office take the critic rating and so on.
But none of that information is visible inside of this search result right here.
This goes back to a discussion we had just two videos ago.
Usually whenever we make use of an API like this one we got a one in point for doing a searching or
index operation and we are adjusting a very limited set of information about every search result that
we just got.
So if we now want to get more information about a very particular movie and get like the revenue or
the rating or whatever else we have to do a follow up request.
So this would be referred to as a show action or a show request or something similar.
When we do this show request we should hopefully be able to get a lot more information about one particular
movie at a time.
Let's take another look at the own DP API documentation and figure out how we can do a request like
the one over here on the right hand side and get all that extra information that we know that our app
is going to need I'm going to once again go back to the documentation we were looking at by search previously.
This time I'm going to go up to buy I.D. or title so if we do a lookup or a single movie at a time which
is essentially this section right here we're going to get a bunch of information about just one particular
movie to do this request.
We're going to add in a new parameter called simply I lowercase i that is going to be the idea of a
movie that we've already found through our search request so to do this request right here.
We're gonna go back over to our code I'm no longer going to pass in that s String anymore.
That was if we wanted to do a search operation and now instead want to do a lookup operation it's going
to put in I like so and then I have to put in the idea of the movie that I want to look up to get the
idea of a movie.
I'm gonna go back to the search results that I was just looking at inside of my browser.
It looks like the idea of the movie The Avengers is t t 0 8 blah blah blah right there it's going to
copy that string and then paste it in as I like so so we no longer have an S.
Instead we just have an eye that indicates the exact movie that we want to get information about.
So now save this I'm gonna go back over to my browser once again refresh and now I get information about
just this single movie inside of here is way more information than what we got before and inside of
here is definitely all the information that we really need to make our application work.
So remember we need to eventually get the and a search straight or see excuse me synopsis right here.
We need to get the box office value and a critic ratings and so on and so inside of this result we can
see plot right here.
That is the kind of plot summary of the movie we can see the box office take right there so that's the
amount of money the movie made.
And I can also see a rating right there.
So that's essentially the critic rating.
There's also a medic a score right here which is another critic rating as well.
So again this is the request that we're going to have to do once the user selects on an individual movie
or clicks an individual movie and we want to show a lot of information about that single movie on the
screen okay.
So now that we understand the two different types of requests we have to make.
Let's take another pause right here.
We're going to start working on our UI in the next video.