Next up we'll see one of the keys to writing useful methods in our objects.
It's called the keyword.
This now the key word this is also pretty useful it comes up a lot once you get to DOM manipulation
which is right around the corner when we do things like add events click events and keyboard events
will sometimes reference that keyword this and you've probably come across it if you've ever attempted
to learn JavaScript.
It's a concept that has shown but this can be a major point of confusion and misery and hardship and
general suffering in the life of a new javascript developer at least that's the perception a lot of
people have.
There are courage posters like this one.
One of the most courageous decisions he'll ever make is to try and learn the javascript keyword this.
Well actually I just made this slide myself.
But the point is a lot of people have this perception of this being this terrifying confusing thing
when in reality it's not that bad.
What is tricky about the keyword this is that the value of it is sometimes it seems unpredictable.
It seems like you expected to do one thing and it behaves a different way but there is a set of concrete
rules that dictate what the value of this is.
At this point we haven't even talked about what this is.
What's the point.
So this is a keyword.
Think of it as a reference to the current execution scope.
It is going to give you an object back.
So depending on the scope and depending on the rules of how this works which is the confusing part that
object changes it could be a reference to the global scope which is what we're going to see right now
if we type a function let's call it say hi console dot log something in here.
Hi.
And then let's also console that log.
The value of this.
Remember.
Get an object here when we console that log it.
This is an object and it refers to the current execution scope.
So if I run my code here I call say hi we get high and then we see an object called the window.
So what is the window.
The window is the global scope in the browser.
We've been working with it stealthily or it spend stealthily looming over us this whole time when we
define a function like say hi.
It looks like it's floating on its own in the middle of nowhere.
We didn't put it in an object.
It's not a method like we called earlier we had math.
Dot had that was a method or lower case math in our case.
Say hi.
Looks like it's just floating in the middle of nowhere.
But if we look at this window object scroll all the way down here to the s..
Okay.
Lots and lots of methods.
Take a look at that.
Say hi.
So when we define say hi like this it is added as a prop..
It is a method on the window object.
The window is the global scope of our browser.
If I type a window at any point in my console we'll get the same thing.
So this instead of a function just a regular function normally refers to the window at least in the
browser in node.
It refers to something else but there is a global object.
It's not called the window but there's a global object in node.
But remember that this can change.
It's a bit of a shape shifter.
So it does depend on how it is called.
So I don't want you to leave thinking that anytime you write this in a function it refers to the window.
But in this function the way that we executed it it does refer to the window.
And just to talk more about the window for a moment here the window contains all sorts of different
properties we've been using different methods things like alert if we call alert we get our alert in
the browser.
It's a built in function and we call it like this but it's a property on the window.
So I could also call it like this window dot alert something and I still get the same result.
Another very important thing about the window when we declare a variable with var I'll go with var color
equals teal that color or that variable color is added to the window.
If I look at window again and I find color on here there you go.
It's added to the global scope.
It's added to the window.
So another way of referencing it.
Oh my gosh I regret this decision to scroll here.
Another way of referencing it is window down color.
But that does not apply for Latin content.
We'll just do one let's use it.
Let num equals 400.
If I try to access window dot num it's not there.
So Latin const are not added to the global scope.
They're not added to the window object in the browser while VAR is.
So none of that really matters at this point.
We're still just talking about functions.
The value of this instead of a regular old function you haven't put on an object just a function we've
defined like this one.
It could also be a function expression const.
How about Grete equals function.
And then if we don't need any arguments we'll just cancel that log.
This so we're not even greeting.
It's a lie but we'll just cancel out like this.
If I clear my console over here refresh the page.
I call greet.
This is still the window.
So in a function this is going to refer to the window except when it doesn't.
And that's coming up next.
So just remember that this is a reference to an object and that object represents the current execution
scope.
So this seems like it might not be that useful here.
And yeah it probably isn't that useful to reference the window because we could also just explicitly
write window if we wanted to print the window or do something with it.
But what we'll see in the next video is where this is extremely useful when we're working with methods
in an object.
So if you're confused if you're feeling like you need that courage from this slide right here if you're
feeling like this skull down here you need a bit more courage.
Just hang in there it will start to make sense as we see the other pieces okay.