All right.
So next up we're going to see an even better way of replicating the exact same functionality creating
a template for a color in our case where we have different properties like RG and B that are numbers
in this case.
And then we also add methods that are on the color prototype.
So there is only one copy of them across all instances of that color.
And this better option is the new class syntax.
So it is just syntactic sugar for exactly what we've been doing syntactic sugar remember is just like
AB cleaner cuter way of writing something that behind the scenes is going to turn into what we already
have here.
So you still have to understand prototypes and the keyword this I want to show you how we could rewrite
this as a single class and the main benefit in my opinion is that we don't have to add methods to the
prototype manually like we have here.
We don't have to break up the constructor function and then separately add methods.
I hate doing that because you end up with this nice little compact function that explains the properties
of your object and then you realize oh wait no there's all these other properties there on the prototype.
So you're defined separately and individually like this.
It just is kind of clunky.
So let's see the alternative come at this out and you'll have to hang in there with a bit of this syntax
upfront.
So we have a keyword called Class.
And then I can give my class a name and typically we use an uppercase letter to indicate that it is
a class or a constructor function.
It is a pattern for some sort of object just like we have XM LIHEAP request where the X is uppercase
normally in JavaScript for a function name you know document that query selector we don't capitalized
AQ but we do when we are creating classes or constructor functions.
So this gives us a class next.
Probably the most confusing part for beginners we always add in a constructor.
Now a constructor is a function that will execute immediately whenever a new color is created so it's
kind of like this constructor function here.
So we would add in three arguments and if I called this counseled out log R G and B and maybe also console
that log inside constructor like that if I create a new color we have to use the same syntax you've
already seen new color save it to a variable concept which should we call it C one very boring pass
in some numbers two five five six seven eight nine.
Okay.
And if I try running this in my browser refresh you can see my inside constructor console that log ran
immediately and I have RG and b be printed out.
So those arguments are passed through.
So I never said run the constructor I never called Dot constructor or anything like that.
It automatically runs as long as its name constructor.
So that is a must have whenever you define a class you have to have the class keyword.
You need to have the Constructor which will run immediately whenever we instantiate a new instance of
color or whatever the classes assemble HDP request or the Dog class or the alert class or Button class
you have to call it with new and you need to have a constructor there.
So usually in the constructor we're going to access this this dot a or this dot R equals are this dot
B equals B and this dot G equals G.
So these are going to be added as properties on this color object that we get returned just like we
had this here in our constructor function.
Same idea.
This will automatically refer to a new object.
So when we call new color it still follows those same steps even though it's in a class it's going to
make a new empty object and it sets the value of this to that object.
So this dot are will be whatever is passed in as are the Stop B will be whatever is passed into B and
this g the order doesn't matter but it's driving me crazy to have B before G.
So I would probably change that up but it won't change anything let's also add in a name for the color.
We can do that last.
Maybe this dot name equals.
And then this could be a name to describe that color.
So this dot name equals whatever name was passed in and you can change these.
You don't have to match.
Right.
We could have name and name it as color name instead.
But this is the property we are adding to the object.
And typically we use the exact same name very common to see that.
OK.
So as far as a name for this color what even is this color.
Let's just take a look using V.S. code here.
Let's just put our G.B. in front of that OK.
It's a reddish color.
We'll call that tomato.
So we'll pass that in tomato as a string like that.
OK.
So let's look at this.
See one when I run the code see one is an object.
It has a b a g a name and an R..
They were all set in this constructor so I never made an empty object myself just like I never did it
here.
The new keyword takes care of that.
All I did was say on this new object that will be created for me even though I am not ever seeing it
and it magically has stored in the value of this ad in our property set it to this argument or this
parameter are same for GP and name.
All right.
Now let's look at the prototype for this color.
This object.
You can see the constructor is set to color.
All right.
So we didn't do that either.
But by using new IT ALL TAKES CARE OF IT.
NOW WHAT ABOUT methods.
This is the real advantage in my opinion.
We don't have to do color dot prototype dot whatever like we did up here.
We could do something trivial like how about Greece.
I don't know why a color would have.
The easiest way to do this is with this adorable syntax that we can use instead of classes.
We can actually use this instead of objects in general.
We talked about it in our objects what we call it Secret Life of object section.
So a new shorthand syntax for defining a method and here I can just return.
Hello from a color.
And actually why don't we include the color name from.
I need to make this a template literal tactics.
This dot name and then will add an exclamation point at the end.
So this is now a method on every color but not on the instances.
This is a nice part.
It's just like we had done this here.
Color dot prototype dot greet equals some function but we don't have to type prototype.
We don't have to type color.
We just put it inside this class so we can group everything together which makes things much easier.
So let's try it.
We have this color one.
Let's open it up.
It does not have green showing here said Green is on the prototype.
There's only one copy of Grete.
See one dot greet.
Let's execute it.
Hello from tomato.
Let's make a different color new color.
Let's do 255 255 255.
And I think that's white.
Save that to a variable cost white.
Sure and call white dot greet hello from white.
All right.
So let's actually add in some methods that we would want like in our G.B. method.
We can copy the logic from what we did earlier.
We'll just return this string but we need to make sure we get our G and B.
And we have access to those just like we did here.
By using the keyword this.
So this anytime we're instead of a class this refers to the instance of the class the individual color
object.
So not the prototype or anything not the function not the window unless you're not using the new keyword
that is.
But if you use the new keyword this will refer to the individual object.
And then whenever we have an object a color like white dot greet White is a color object when we greet
the keyword.
This was used instead of greet got rid of it but we had this name.
This referred to the individual object the instance.
So we can do structure.
We could do this that are this that g this top b or just d structure our G and B from this.
Now if I call it we have c 1 C one dot R B gives me this nice RG B string take a look.
And we get that reddish tomato we color.
Let's add another method in let's go with this hex method.
So I'm just going to copy the logic and add hex and that relies on our G and B which we already have
on the object.
So I'm going to d structure again let's try that one out see one dot hex and did we have another color
white.
I think I defined that and refresh the page.
So let's define another color over here.
Let's call this one red.
And then another one which will be white and just have 255 255 255 now need to save that to a different
variable.
White OK so if we check here white dots hex we get f f f f f f f that's accurate.
And you know that one hex color and then if we do red dot hex we get a different outcome.
And if we compare them red dot hex not execute them but compare the references triple equals white dot
hex they are the same function because they're on the prototype they are not in the individual instance
they're over here and let's add in our our GPA as well.
Let's see.
This was our GPA.
We'll copy this logic but I think I'm going to refactor this.
If we look at our GPA it accepts a parameter called Alpha.
We set it to be 1.0 as a default value.
It returns something very similar to our G.B..
This right here is the same thing.
We just have a added after the fact in our GPA and we have our GPA at the start and Archie B at the
start of our B.
So we could make a separate function maybe call it enter RG B like that and all that I'll do there.
Nice and easy is return.
This part of the string so I'm just going to copy the whole thing over you'll see what I'm going for.
I'm just going to return this string.
No parents just a comma separated list.
So it would look like two five five common to five five comma two five five.
So if I called this from within another method I could easily do our B and put parental around that
or I could add in another number and do RGA around that.
So I just made a method that is going to help me out it's called inter GP and now we get the opportunity
to talk about how we would call one of these methods from within another instance method.
Another method on this class to do that we just reference this same thing so we could call this Dot's
inner our G.B.
that should give us a string that will go on the inside of our our GP right here and I need to escape
that with my dollar sign.
Curly braces let's make sure that works for our GP refresh the page white dot our GP that looks good
we can verify if we paste that down here it is white at least according to V.S. code.
Now we can rewrite RGA to do the same thing so I can get rid of that and replace it with this dot enter
our GP and executed it as a function and then we add RGA open Perrin and then closing per end at the
end as well as karma the alpha value so very similar because we're using the same function on the inside.
It just gives us a good opportunity to call a function from within our method to be more accurate from
within.
Another method on the class.
So does white that RG be a work that's going to be quite boring not as exciting as let's do read that
our GPA.
There we go.
And if he tries zero point four We get a more transparent color could do the same thing.
Document dad's body style that's background color equals red dot our GPA.
This is the full strength of that red color and this is half strength.
This is a tenth of the strength.
Cool.
So we've added a couple of methods and we've covered most of the basics of classes so far.
You define a class with the class keyword you usually capitalized that name.
You should always capitalize it although you don't have to.
You should.
And then instead of those curly braces the first thing we need to add is a constructor.
This function will run automatically whenever you instantiate a new instance of the class.
So we don't call it manually inside of that constructor and instead of the entire class if we're in
a method like I have here constructor or down here the keyword this will refer to the individual object.
So this dot are this dot gee this dot B I'm assigning properties to each color not to the prototype
but to the color then these methods I've added they are added to the prototype automatically.
So I don't have to do any of this colored up prototyped out blah blah blah.
I can keep everything together inside this class.
I don't have to have the separate constructor function.
Then later add my methods I can put it all in one happy family and defined my class defined my pattern
for every color every color has an RG and b in a name in every color has these four methods but they're
located on the prototype they look up to that one prototype template object.
Okay so we're gonna continue to add on to our class in the next video.