So far the string methods that we've seen all follow this pattern we call the method name with empty
parentheses.
We don't provide any information or values when we execute it.
Now we're going to see a different set of string methods.
They work in the exact same way the same syntax except instead of the parentheses we pass in additional
information to modify their behavior.
Methods are just actions uppercase this trim this lowercase this but some of them like replace require
additional information.
What are you replacing and what do you want to replace it with.
Or if we are searching for something we need to specify what we're searching for.
So those values that we pass in between the parentheses are called arguments.
We can pass in one argument and sometimes we pass in multiple as in the case of replace.
What are you replacing.
What do you want to replace it with.
So I'm going to show you a couple examples of these methods so they work the same way.
We just pass an information.
Here's the first one.
It's called index of index of.
We'll tell you where in a string a given string occurs substring.
So here I have cat dog as the variable TV show.
And if I call index of cat it returns 0 meaning cat comes at the very beginning of the string.
It's not just looking for C. It's looking for cat the entire substring the entire match S.A.T. starts
at index 0.
Then if we do dog index of dog we get three which means it starts at 0 1 2 3 index of 3 or the fourth
character.
Here's a quick example.
Baseball dot index of.
Let's look for where ball occurs in the string and it tells us it starts at index 4.
If I just did B This one is important because there are two B's it only tells me the first instance
of B the first occurrence which is at index 0 it is case sensitive.
So if I instead had baseball with capital B it ignores that one that's not a match but this one is a
match at index 4.
Now for looking for something that doesn't exist in the string like baseball that index of entertaining
which clearly entertaining does not exist instead of the world of baseball we get negative 1 so negative
1 is the representation of not found anytime you call index of with a value that is not found you'll
get negative 1 and you'll often see people use this once we talk about conditional logic people will
write code that checks if index of something equals negative one that means the thing you're looking
for is not there.
So that's pretty much it for index of it returns a number always sometimes it will be the index of something
you're looking for and if it's not found you get negative one.
The next method we'll take a look at is called Slice slice does kind of what it sounds like it takes
slices of an existing string and it gives you a piece of it and it works in a couple of different ways.
If we pass in a single number let's just keep working with baseball if we pass in a single number to
slice like maybe 4 it's going to take a slice starting an index for all the way to the end.
So in our case that's ball.
But remember strings are immutable just like all the methods we've seen so far this is not altering
baseball it's not changing the value if we had it in a variable like if we had let sport equal baseball
and then reduced sport that slice for sport is unchanged it's still baseball and we could save this
to a separate variable if we wanted it.
So that's one use for slice.
If you pass in a single number.
Also if we tried something like sport that slice 40 there is no index 40 we get an empty string when
we use slice we can also pass in two numbers to indices first one is where we should start the slice
and then the second one is where the slice should end.
So let's test it out.
We'll do this on super hero and if we do a dot slice going from index 0 and then we go into index 5
we'll end up with super notice that it is not inclusive because index 5 is 0 1 2 3 4 5.
That would be the H right here.
It stops right before that h so it starts at zero and it goes basically to 4 1 less than what we have
here.
So we end up with super.
If I wanted to slice let's go with he the word I guess it is not a very exciting word but two characters
in the middle.
We need to go from this index which is 0 1 2 3 4 5 and then we want to go and tell 7 and we get he let's
say I had a bunch of prices that people had written like fifty point six zero and I wanted to remove
a dollar sign on all of them what I could do is slice.
So just do you slice from one to the end.
And now I get the number isolated even though it's a string.
I could then turn it into a number which we haven't seen how to do yet but this is a common use case.
If you have data that follows a pattern and you're trying to isolate a certain portion of it you use
slice and then we have one more method that accepts arguments that we'll talk about.
There are many many others that come with a built in and JavaScript many string methods but the last
one we'll see is called replace and it also does what it sounds like.
You specify what you want to replace what string and what you want to replace it with.
So if I had the string baseball is entertaining and I called replace on it I could replace entertaining
if I wanted to with.
How about OK.
And now we get.
Baseball is OK if I try it with something like this Ha ha ha dark place and I want to replace ha with
which we'll replace it with.
How about hee hee hee hee.
Let's see what happens.
It only replaces the first one.
So there are ways of replacing all occurrences in a string but it involves a regular expression which
is something we have not talked about.
So we're not going to go into it but if you want to learn more go check it out on MDA and look up replace.
So it replaces the first occurrence and of course if it doesn't find the thing that you're trying to
replace.
Like if I tried to replace ha with he there is no ha.
So it's unchanged.
It doesn't give us an error.
Nothing really happens.
It just doesn't replace it.
So that's replace you pass in to values the thing that all of these methods have in common is that we
pass in at least one value.
So we had methods where we pass nothing in like trim or to lowercase to uppercase and we have methods
repast specific values in index of where we specify what we're looking for.
Tell me the index of cats.
Here we have slice.
You can pass in one number in order to go from one index to the end of the string or you can pass in
two numbers to get a specific slice.
And we had replaced where you pass in two values if we go back to the docs here I'm on Ambien right
now I'm on to uppercase for string.
But if we go to the left again we can see all the different methods.
If we look at slice just to give you an idea of how you read these docs if you look down right here
or it says syntax the syntax is string dot slice and then we must pass in a begin index.
So the starting index and then we have an end index.
But notice there's these brackets around it.
This is a way of telling you this is optional slice works.
If you only specify begin index as we've seen.
If we only pass in five it works.
But if you want you can also pass in an end index.
So if you see documentation like this on MDA and whenever you see these brackets under the syntax portion
of documentation page this is telling you it's optional.