Welcome back.
Next we'll get a bit more practice with a sink and a wait so I'm using code that I wrote back in the
promises section.
I know I've said this in pretty much every video so far in this async section but if you did not watch
the promises section highly highly recommend you go back and check it out or at least look at the code
in more detail.
Remember that everything we're seeing here with a sink and a weight it's all promises underneath there
behind the scenes.
It's just a little wallpaper on top or makeup on top or painter who knows it's something on top to decorate
it to make it nice and pretty.
So this function that we created a couple of sections ago is called Move X move X returns a promise.
And in this promise it will move an element a certain number of pixels horizontally or along the x axis
left or right depending on the number you pass in positive or negative.
And then it uses a delay.
So it waits one second or three seconds before it actually does that operation.
So it returns a promise set time out with a delay.
I'm using one second for all of them and then it moves some element that number of pixels using transform
in less.
We don't have enough room to keep moving.
So at that point the promise is rejected.
If we do have enough room the element is moved and the promise is resolved.
So we end up with something like this.
If I shrink my window down we can move a couple times and then the promise is rejected.
We caught it with our catch down here and we canceled out logged some information about the error.
This is what we had before this massive massive callbacks.
Success and Failure callbacks promises really helped us clean it up.
Now we'll see how we can continue to clean it up using async functions.
We won't have to write any of these events.
So what we'll start with is calling move x.
Guess I'll just come at this out.
We'll keep the button.
We do need that duplicated just so we have a record of the original.
We need to select the button and we'll call move X. But I'm going to do it from inside an async function
so I'll call this function.
How about animate.
Right.
It's not really a nice animation because it's so choppy.
But we'll call it intimate right.
We'll make it an async function and we'll pass an element then inside of here.
We will call move X which returns a promise I'll pass in that element I'll pass in an amount.
So let's just hard code this as a hundred pixels at a time every second 1000 milliseconds.
This returns a promise so I can await it.
And if I want to wait for this to finish before I run the next move X I don't need dot then I can just
await this first one and then do it again.
Fingers crossed hopefully we move twice as long as we pass in the correct button to animate.
Right.
So we'll call Animal Rights Beatty and refresh one jump to jump.
Awesome.
So if we wanted to move this many times we could do the exact same thing.
We just duplicate this every time and we await.
We say wait until that promise that is returned from move X has been resolved.
And if it's resolved then move on to the next one.
However right now we're not catching any errors so if we do hit that boundary and the promise is rejected
you'll see we get an error.
We'll take a look good.
It's waiting every time for that promise to be resolved and then boom uncut error.
We did not catch this anywhere.
We just talked about how we can catch errors.
We could add a try catch in our function but I would probably do is right here is at a catch for that
error.
And then we could just cancel that log.
All done.
Let's see if it works OK continue.
Awesome and all done.
Perfect.
OK.
So if we take a look at this compared to what we had here.
I mean it's not a massive improvement.
We don't have to write all the dot then we don't need these unnecessary callbacks anymore which I think
is definitely worth it.
And all we have to do is add in a wait and async.
Now this is relatively simple logic we're doing.
It's not much logic at all it's the same thing every time.
So it maybe isn't as clear but when we talk about making sequential requests which is what we'll see
next.
Making axes OS or fetch requests one after another where they depend on each other using async await
makes it much easier to read and understand what's going on.
Not to mention shorter so why don't we wrap this up instead of just intimating to the right why don't
we also once we hit the end estimate back to the left so we could change this estimate right to accept
an amount and then anytime I'm passing in one hundred there I'll replace it with amount and then here
when we get that error when we've hit the edge why don't we cancel that log and move the other direction
so counsel that log all done.
And then we can call animate writes same element PETN this time.
Here we need to say we're moving a hundred pixels this time let's move negative one hundred pixels.
Let's see if that works.
So we moved to the right and we're going to hit that edge we get all done.
And now we're moving back to the left.
Now we don't really have any error handling for the left side so we're just going to keep moving off
the screen because our logic right now in estimates or in move x is just checking the right boundary.
So I think that's a bit of an oversight but we now have this async function here that we can call it
returns a promise within it.
We can await any other thing that returns a promise and mimic synchronous code.
So next we'll see how we can do this with requests.
How can we have sequential requests and we'll also talk about parallel requests which is another way
of sending multiple requests where we don't have to wait for one to come back first.