All right.
Let's keep going.
On our get all function.
So we've now got our contents.
So we're going to now pass the contents to right here I'll say Constanta data is Jason dot PURSE AND
I'LL PASS IN contents like so so inside the file we're going to store all of our users as JS on data
which can be safely written out as a string.
Once we load information that file we first have it as a string.
So we need to take that string and pass it from Jason back into a normal javascript object or an array
of objects in this case so after we do that pass operation will then return our data not to test this
out.
Once again I'm going to remove that console log up there back down inside of my test function.
I'm going to take whatever we get back from get all and assign it to agreeable that I'll call users
and I'll do a console log of users.
So before like I mentioned we were doing technically a console log of just a string that had an array
or array characters inside of it.
Now when we do this console log we should be seeing an actual javascript array so I can make sure I
save that file and then do node users not just once again.
So now looks like we're the same thing but technically it now is actually an array OKAY.
SO THIS IS VERY GOOD.
NOW WE'VE GOT TO DO A LITTLE BIT OF A refactor of the statement right here.
We've got some extraneous variables being created.
So we're going to refactor this thing down to a single line of code or really a single expression in
order to get it down to a single expression.
I'm going to take where we call a weight F S dot read file right there and I'm going to wrap it with
Jason dot pass and I'll make sure I get a closing parentheses on the other side as well so now we can
just return the result of that expression and we don't have to go through creating all those extra variables.
So going to delete that comment I'm going to delete the stuff underneath and we are left with the same
functionality that we had before.
But it's much more compact so I'll save this do another quick test.
Yup still works OK.
So obviously console logging out in empty array is not super interesting or handy so we'll take another
pause right here when we come back in just a moment.
We're going to start to implement our create function which we're going to use to actually add new records
into our data store.
After that will then be all to really test the full flow of creating a record saving it and then returning
it eventually by retrieving it once again.
Let's take care of that in just a moment.