All right.
So it's time for our first official video in the the real learning part of this Dom stuff.
We saw some demos.
We got a little taste of the Dom talks about HD amounts to assess and what you need to know.
This is really video one of learning the dom.
So we're going to start with the most important part of the Dom the document.
Remember Dom stands for a document object model and the DOM is just a representation of an actual document
made with a bunch of objects and they're assembled into a tree.
This shape that we see over here there is a hierarchy.
They're not just sitting out there in some random order.
They're not in an array for example.
I mean they could be but then how would we know the relationships between parents and children and the
structure.
So they are put in a tree like structure here with branches and in every tree there is a top most piece
what we call the root of the tree which is kind of the opposite of a regular tree I guess the roots
down at the bottom.
But anyway we've got the root of the tree which when we work with the DOM is an object called document.
So document is an object you have in every single browser window that you ever open.
You can type document every web page.
Here's one of mine.
This one the simple each Tim LCROSS demo.
If I type document right here I get a annoying printout.
This is not what it actually is.
This is the dev tools just showing me the HCM L in the document.
But if I do console dot DNR document we can see the actual underlying object.
Now this object represents the entire page this entire document.
If I go to the MBNA page this is actually the docs for the document.
If I look at document and do the same thing console that desire instead we have another object and they
follow the same pattern.
They have a Euro right.
There's a Euro right there.
My euro is different over here on a file protocol.
I'm just viewing my HCM Al file versus here.
I'm looking at developer dot Mozilla dawg.
And the document contains tons of properties tons of methods.
This is really where we start with everything.
So all of the other objects all of the other pieces of the Dom are located within the documents somewhere.
It's all nested into a kind of large confusing structure.
If you are trying to navigate it yourself and if you recall from the last couple of videos everything
that I was doing I was typing document dot something document dot get element by I.D. document dot body
dot children document dot get elements by tag name there's all of these different methods and properties
and they're all contained within the document object.
So the document is the entry point that we use to access the DOM to manipulate things to just view the
content in the DOM but also to add events and add functionality it's all located instead of this one
objects the document and everything else stems from there.
So it's created for us automatically we don't just like we don't create the DOM ourselves the browser
does it when it loads the page same idea the document will be there for you when a page is opened in
the browser or when you view a web page.
If we take a look at my web page again here's the document that I printed out as an object.
We'll see a couple other things that might make sense right now.
How about images.
This is a collection of images on the page.
There's one image right now.
If I go to the MGM version and I look at document dot images
we have what 12 images on this page.
If we go back to my version and we instead look at something like how that document does.
All right here.
This is a property that contains every single element on the page.
Things we see and don't see.
So the title meta tags the head script tags if we have any.
They're all included here every single one is turned into a javascript object and itself has tons and
tons of properties.
And as you can see here if you were trying to navigate this manually and trying to understand it all
this is just completely overwhelming.
But fortunately we really don't need to know most of it.
So the main takeaway here is that we get all these objects for free.
We load up the web page in the browser whether it's a file or we're going to some Web site and the DOM
is created all of it is stored instead of one object called the document but the document has references
to all those other objects as you can see here.
If I go to document dot all this is just one way of looking at other elements.
I've got 12 now what 21 different elements.
If I do it on MDA in that document object dot all has holy cow eighteen thousand nine hundred and forty
elements in each one is going to be a big massive crazy object that has tons of stuff inside of it.
So that's it for now.
The document is our entry point and that's why all of these methods we run all of these properties will
look at or at least the majority of them start with document dot something document dot do something.
So we'll see our first batch of methods in the very next video.
Very exciting.
I think maybe.
Okay.
By.