All right.
Welcome back.
So we saw why callbacks are so important in JavaScript.
We passed a callback in to certain functions that the browser takes over.
Things like set time out set interval.
Also when you make requests different ways of making requests we haven't really covered yet.
The browser takes care of that and we pass in a callback but callbacks are not perfect.
They can get messy very quickly which is what I want to show you here.
I'm going to show you a way of doing something with callbacks and then we'll see how to refactor it
using promises.
So this is finally the ramp up to promises.
Let's write a simple function that will take a number of pixels and move our button over that number
of pixels and it will do it after a delay.
So we could do like after a second move and after another second move it and so on.
So I want to start by selecting the button.
It's the only button on the page.
So const PETN equals document that query selector button then all we're going to do is change button
that style.
I'll do it with transform this time.
I think a couple at some point in the course I did button that styled up left and top which is not really
the most performance way of changing position or moving an element around transform it's better.
And if you're curious why I have a YouTube video you can check out on it.
It's called the only to see us as properties you should animate the short story is that when you transform
something it happens much later in the browser's rendering process.
It's much easier for the browser to move something via transform rather than changing a left which causes
a render of a lot of different things anyway.
So I'm just going to do this we'll move it left to right.
So I'll just do translate X in passing a number like 100 pixels and let's just make sure it's moving.
Okay.
So now I want to do this instead of a set time out.
So it only happens after let's say one second.
So set time out and then I'll pass in a function just do an arrow function here my duration will be
1000 milliseconds and I'll move this right there.
So now I refresh it should start on the left and then one second later it moves.
That works great.
Now if I wanted to wait another second and then move again maybe 200 pixels this time or some other
number I would need to ness that function call the set timeout inside of this set timeout.
Otherwise I just have a second set time.
I mean I guess you could do this and just keep track of a number of seconds but this is not ideal.
Oh we'll see an expanded version of what we're doing now where this wouldn't work.
But yes technically if you want this to run after one second in this to run a second later you could
do two thousand milliseconds but we're not going to do that.
So in here we add another set time out.
Same thing we add in our callback our duration let's do 1000 seconds or let's do two thousand milliseconds
so two seconds and then the same line I'll just duplicate it and I need to change what we're translating
it to let's do 200 pixels so I'll refresh.
The second it moves another two seconds it should move again cool and I could keep duplicating this
I just have to keep nesting if I want to make sure that this is happening after this happens.
So we have our first set time out for 1000 milliseconds.
It does this.
And then as soon as that happens it sets another time out for two thousand milliseconds and then again
let's just do 1000 for each of these let's translate 300 pixels.
This isn't so bad because it's such a short thing that we're doing but it is a lot of nesting to achieve
this.
Let's go five levels deep.
OK.
So now I have five different set time outs all of them one second long.
Let's go.
One two three four hundred pixels and 500 pixels.
Let's check it out.
It should move across the screen 100 pixels at a time one second at a time.
OK.
So this is relatively readable.
That's not too bad.
It's kind of obnoxious to have to keep nesting them but that's not.
This is not as bad as it will get.
Let's put it that way.
So if I want to rewrite this as a function I'm doing kind of the same thing every time.
If I want to make this a separate function I could call what I need to do is first define my function
and come up with a reasonable name.
Let's call this move left.
No move right.
I would just move X because then we could pass in a negative number to go the other direction.
We'll do element the thing that is moving so our button in amounts and then a delay and then we'll do
a set time out and then in here our function will put the delay right here.
So that will be some number we pass in like 1000.
And then instead of button that style about transform it will be element that style dot transform equals
and then a string will do a string template literal translate X and then I'll put in my amount that
was passed in and then follow it by pixels.
Just like that so if I come at this out and I just call this one time move x of button let's go with
six hundred pixels of six hundred and after two seconds let's see if it works so two seconds go by okay.
It does move.
Now here's the tricky part.
If I want to then replicate this behavior where we could have something happen after this or after the
delay immediately after we change the transform I want another set time out.
It doesn't really help me if I just manually set it here.
What we would do instead is pass in a callback.
So we would write our function to accept a callback we could call it callback and then all we do is
execute that callback function inside the set time out.
After we do this we call the callback.
Same idea that we have here.
But now what we need to do is pass in a callback.
So we would pass in a function we'll do an arrow function ups like this and we'll just call move X again
button let's go 100 pixels this time we'll replicate the same behavior so one second another 200 pixels
after one second let's just see if that works we will run into an issue with what I have here because
I haven't passed in a callback so we could do something simple like if callback.
Okay.
Let's see what happens.
It appears to work right
so we did one hundred pixels and then 200 pixels after a second and we could pass in yet another callback
if we want to continue to change changes so move X button.
Let's go for 300 pixels one second and let's actually do four or five levels button.
And then four hundred pixels 1000 milliseconds.
And one last one move x button 500 pixels 1000 milliseconds.
No callback.
Here we go.
There we go.
Keep moving awesome.
OK.
So we wrote a function here that accepts that callback and a delay it does something after that delay
inside the set timeout that delay is variable right now they're all the same.
And then it executes a callback if we pass one it in our callbacks or these arrow functions.
So this is one callback.
This entire thing here from here from this curly brace to this curly brace No this curly brace to this
curly brace.
That is the callback for this first move x.
So this entire thing from this yellow curly brace down to here is the first callback for move X the
first time we call move X that function call those prints go all the way down.
Right.
This is our initial function call and then we have our callback in there.
And then that itself calls move X and then that has a massive callback.
All this nesting it's still not that horrible because we're just doing one thing each time you can look
at it it makes it clear you're doing this then this then this.
But here's where it's going to get trickier.
Let's rewrite our function so that we check if the element is going to go off the screen and if it does
go off the screen we can do something else maybe reverse it or just cancel that log or just stop.
We won't do anything.
And this is a really common pattern when we're working with asynchronous code often we'll send let's
say in HDP request the term is request for a reason.
We're attempting something we're asking for a web page.
We may get some successful response or the server might be down.
We might have an invalid you URL your internet might be down at home or on the computer.
So it's a request and that request.
Let's just say this is the name of a function to make a request hopes to complete there.
That request will accept two callbacks a success callback and a failure callback.
So you can have two different branches if the request works out.
Here's the code that runs if the request does not work.
Here is the code that runs the code to handle an error for example.
So why don't we mimic that functionality here for move X instead of just moving.
No matter what.
Let's check if we are going to move off the screen.
And if that's the case we won't do this.
We won't call the callback.
We won't move further.
We'll do something else.
We'll pass in a potential fallback or an error callback.
So I'm going to rewrite this here the logic to check if we're moving off the screen is not that important
to what I'm showing you here.
But basically we want to get the width of the screen document up body dot client width and we'll save
this to a variable let's call it const boundary body boundary or something.
Then I'll show you a new method we haven't seen before.
There is something called Get bounding client rect.
Let's test it out first in the browser.
So I have a button right here.
It's moved already I won't refresh the page if I call up that button variable and I call the museum
in here button gets bounding client rect which is a method for rectangle rect get.
Here we go.
It returns this object.
It's called a dom rect Dom rectangle.
And it tells us information about this element so we can see it's with two hundred and twenty five pixels
point eight seven five.
We can see it's right.
Let's see 733.
Is that correct.
Let's try moving it further.
So let's do the same thing don't we on our last step why don't we move 600 pixels over.
So instead of 400 we should be 600 or instead of 500 I mean we'll go 600.
So currently it's at seven thirty three point eight seven five.
If we refresh and let it let it do its thing just wait here.
Kill some time.
Let's see what we get now for the right.
The right is now eight hundred and thirty three point eight eight seven five.
And if we call move X again button we'll move eight hundred pixels and let's.
Now one second is fine.
No callback we wait one second.
Now let's look at our get founding client wrecked right.
Is 1033 and what is our entire width right now of the body document dump body.
Clients with not height but with eleven thirty two.
Okay so we're close.
What we want to do is compare those to the rights.
If we're going to the right place we're just worrying about moving to the right.
So we'll check if the rights is greater than or equal to this boundary here which we already have.
Document dump body duck client width and that will change depending on the screen.
And if I have a console open so it's not just the dimensions of the screen itself.
We've seen this before client with is going to update.
OK so let's grab that variable get bound bounding client rect and we want dot right.
So let's save this concept.
L right element right.
And let's rewrite our function before we go any further so that we don't have to pass in this absolute
number.
For example 100 than 200 and 300 than 400.
What if I could just say move one hundred and then another one hundred then another one hundred and
this would put us at three hundred pixels to the right of the initial position we would need to update
this ever so slightly.
So I'll just comment that out for now for amount we can keep that the same but instead of just setting
translate X to be that amount we can calculate the current transform or the current position on the
screen and then add to that whatever amount is passed in and use that to translate.
So the current amount if we want to find that is right here if we use get bounding client rect we have
the C left is eight hundred and eight and then we have a little bit of I believe his margin or padding
that added eight pixels.
It doesn't matter.
Let's we're not gonna be super precise.
I don't really care if this is going to be incredibly accurate I don't want to get too bogged down.
So let's use this left.
So whatever the left is well then add another 100 or 200 whatever the amount is we're trying to move
I'll make a new variable I'll get the left and save that to a variable called current left then here
I'll just translate X to amount plus currants left.
So now when I call this I hopefully can just say move 100 pixels at a time it's easier.
You don't have to keep track of if you've moved one hundred then you want to move two hundred if you
wanna move another one hundred.
You have to add it together and do three hundred.
Now I can just say one hundred every time or two hundred every time or mix it up but I don't have to
know how far we've already moved.
Okay.
So translate X let's just let's see if it works.
Refresh the page.
It's working it's moving 100 pixels every time.
Okay.
So now we can go back to checking if we've gone too far or if we're going to go too far.
We have our boundary we have the current right of the element and what we want to do is check if that
rights plus let's say we're moving 100 pixels.
If another hundred pixels to the right is going to be too far and we'll be off the screen then we don't
want to move.
So we could write a simple conditional if element right plus the amount we're trying to move is greater
than the body boundary what do we want to do.
Why don't we start with just concerned about logging done and I apparently cannot type greater than
what concerns out like done can't go up double quotes there can not go that far else.
We need the else.
Otherwise we'll just print this out and then run our code anyway.
So let's add and else we'll do the set timeout down here.
Oh boy OK.
So we try and move 100 pixels every time and if it's too far.
Like if I do the last one to try and move 500 pixels.
Let's see.
We should move four times two three four.
While I'm an idiot I move the screen.
Let's try and move a thousand pixels.
That should be enough for it to trigger.
OK so one hundred one hundred.
And now we try and move a thousand perfect cannot go that far.
Let's try one more time
and it doesn't move us any further.
That's it.
OK.
So that is working.
We now have this situation where we don't move anymore.
Otherwise we do this at.
Time out and everything else and we call a callback.
Now let's go back to this idea of having a success and a failure callback.
So I could pass in here's what I want you to do.
If we can keep moving.
Here's what I want you to do.
If we can't move anymore.
For example I could reset the position if we've gone all the way to the right or I could just alert
something the way that we would structure this.
And this is how a lot of older javascript libraries are actually written.
They have two callbacks you pass in so your request or whatever you're doing.
Oh my gosh autocomplete here.
Here you go.
And you pass in your success callback which you wouldn't write like this.
And then a fail callback.
So those are two functions as arguments.
So you would have your first function do something and then your second function do something else.
So let's try it.
Let's rewrite this.
So we have our first callback let's call this on success and on failure or on fail.
So down here if we've made it to this point that means we can keep moving so we'll call if on success
which I guess we can just assume our code let's just assume that it will be passed and to make our code
simpler.
We'll do on success right there and on failure.
We'll be right in here.
So now we have two branching patterns.
You try and move a certain number of pixels.
If that number is too too big of a gap to jump and you'll be off screen this element will be off the
screen.
We'll call the on failure callback.
Otherwise we'll actually do that movement after some delay that you pass in and then call your on success
callback.
So now we have to rewrite this whole thing to have two callbacks every time.
So when to leave the original and I'll call move x of our button let's move 100 pixels the first time
after one second 1000 milliseconds.
This is our success callback if we're successful we'll do something.
So I'll just write success.
Then we have to add our second callback here.
So a whole nother function.
And this is if you cannot move if this is too big of a jump to try and make what do we want to do.
Why don't we start with a simple alert cannot move further.
OK.
And so then if we're successful we'll do another move X this time why don't we move 400 pixels after
1 seconds here's our success callback we'll do something.
If success I'll label these success and then we have to add a fail callback to this function call.
And already it's getting quite messy.
So this would be our fail for the second callback or for the second attempt.
And here's our fail for the very first move X so fail here we'll do the exact same alert cannot move
further and if I say if it gets all formatted funky but this is a lot to just follow and try and read
with your human eyes it's really not pretty and this is only two levels so far just adding in that second
callback really complicates things.
This is relatively easy to look at and understand this happens then after this callback will happen
then this callback here when we have two callbacks at a time we pass in it's just clunky and ugly.
Okay.
So move x button let's see here's our success.
Let's do one more move x.
So if we move 100 pixels we're still good.
This calls or this is called we try and move 400 pixels.
If we're still good.
This function is called otherwise this fail is called Move X this time let's do button something very
large like 700 pixels that should do it for us at least if I shrink my screen down.
And then after a second again here's our success callback we'll just cancel dialogue really.
We still have screen left or something like that and then we pass in our failure callback here and this
one will just alert cannot move further.
Oh boy.
I mean look at this.
This is nasty to look at.
But let's just see if it works.
So we every single time we call move X we're now passing in two callbacks the one to call if things
work and we can move the one to call if we can't move that far.
We'll be moving off screen and then as soon as we start nesting them it just grows into this absolute
spaghetti mess.
So let's try it.
I'm going to refresh my page OK so it actually did work but when I'm when I hit enter and close this
alert you'll see what it's kind of behaving out the or it might seem like it's behaving oddly.
This is because of our set time out and what's happening if we go back.
We're moving a hundred pixels than 400 than 700.
If we can but because this code is running right away we're not doing it in the set time out.
It seems like we're stopping too soon.
But as you saw here OK it stops or it appears to stop.
But I hit enter it still moves.
So that alert is actually coming from this move.
When I moved over here we could fix this problem.
If we move our conditional into the set time out just to run through what's happening here we're moving
100 pixels.
But when we move a hundred pixels we're starting by checking can we continue to move.
All right we can.
So we don't run this and we set a timeout This time out takes one second if we pass in 1000 milliseconds
it takes 1000 milliseconds for it to run and then call on success.
But as soon as that on success is called this code runs immediately.
This is not part of the thousand millisecond delay for the next time around.
It's happening at the very beginning of the function.
So we could rewrite this by moving this code into our set timeout.
This isn't necessarily the best way of designing this.
It might be better just a short circuit and just check as soon as possible if we can't move further.
But this will make it easier to see when it's working for us.
So now we're doing basically running the code at the exact same time we're checking if we can go and
we're calling failure if we can't go we're calling success if we can move and we're doing it all within
the set time.
So now it moves and moves again and then it says OK I can't keep going.
So we had the same outcome last time.
It just was alerting us before we had actually moved.
OK so this is looking great.
It works right.
It's stopping when it should.
If I expand my screen all the way over here let's see it now should be able to make that jump.
And now we get really we still have screen left which is our success for our third move.
So you can see this is quite ugly and this is only three moves.
What we had here was five moves.
So when I take a second to recreate this I won't make you watch.
I'll just do it really quickly and through the magic of editing it will be done.
There you go.
So I decided to change it to 300 pixel jumps because I know some of you will have wider screens or you
won't have your console open like I have here.
So I wanted to make sure in most cases that this would hit the edge of the screen.
So I'm going three hundred three hundred three hundred three hundred three hundred and then each time
if it fails I have this failure callback.
It's just alerting cannot move further cannot move further cannot move further.
Oh my gosh can't talk five times I have to rewrite that code.
I don't have an easy way of getting around this.
I have to pass in that failure callback even if I'm just doing basically the same thing every single
time.
And then on our last success instead of continuing to move I'm just alerting you have a wide screen.
So let's see what happens.
Now we move one time two times three times four and then it stops cannot move further.
And if I close my console I think we'll be able to make it to the end.
Three four five and then the callback which is you have a wide screen.
OK.
So this has been a ton.
I know this is an incredibly long dense video.
I wanted to illustrate a situation where callbacks are useful.
We have to use callbacks with what we know so far in order to write a function like move X where we're
waiting for something to finish and then running some code we're using set time out all over the place
in our source as you see where are you set.
Time out.
And in order to make our functions work the way we've written them we have to pass callbacks.
So we have a on success and on failure.
Remember all of this stems from the fact that JavaScript does one thing at a time and the browser is
taking over when we call set timeout.
The browser is keeping track of time and then it tells javascript.
OK.
Time's up.
Run this function.
And within this function we have some logic and then we tell javascript which one of these to run based
off of some conditional logic.
So this all stems from javascript fundamental nature the fact that it's single threaded and we have
these browser API is a web API is that JavaScript works with to make a request to set a time out to
set an interval to add an event listener the browser takes care of that and then tells javascript.
Here's a function here's a callback that's great but it can get really messy when we start having different
outcomes and success in a failure which happens a lot when we make requests.
This is a very simple example but as you'll see shortly when we make requests real web HDP requests
we follow the same pattern.
We have some code to run when it when the request works we have other code to run.
If the request fails.
And so if we structure our code like this on success on failure we have two callbacks things get nested
ugly and very difficult to follow quickly.
I mean look at how separated our code is.
Yes part of it is the way that my V.S. code is formatting things.
But even if we don't have all this indentation it's still really difficult to know.
You know if you want to change the failure callback for this first move X you have to scroll down and
just make sure you're at the right level right.
You have to.
Here's the first one.
Here's the second failure.
Third failure it becomes hard to really follow and understand.
So this is where promises come in.
Promises allow us to rewrite a function like this or this function here so that we don't have to do
all this crazy nesting.
It's so much so much easier to read and that's why we're going to see in the next video.
So all of this has been set up for promises.
But as long as it's been this this video I know is probably the longest video in the course a real slog.
I congratulate you if you made it here and it will really help you understand why promises are worth
it.
Otherwise I just show you promises without showing you the struggle without promises it doesn't do promises
justice.
So that's coming up next.