In the last video it appeared that we saved a product into our product saw Jason File successfully.
Well like I said there's a very subtle bug inside of our request handler right now.
So I want to remind you right here we're getting access to that era's object or we're not actually doing
anything with it previously inside of our off dot J.S. root handler file going to open that up really
quickly.
We had taken the air's object would check to see if it was empty.
And then if it was we sent back the same form and displayed the appropriate errors inside the template.
We should probably make sure that we do the same thing inside of our product creation root handler as
well.
Otherwise doing all this validation stuff is just going to go to waste.
So as soon as we start to display these validation errors like I said we're going to very quickly see
an interesting little problem.
All right.
So right after we declare errors right there I'll say if not errors dot is empty.
So if we do have an error let's return before we tried to create an image or anything like that.
We're going to render the same template we've rendered just a moment ago.
Don't say red dot send.
We want to send back the products new template and remember when we do that we want to tell that template
about all the errors that just occurred.
So we're gonna pass on an object with the errors inside of it.
Now we have to also open up that new template file so I'll find View's admin products new DOT J.S..
We've already received that Aras object.
It's now we have to use the get error helper function to reach into that and print out the appropriate
errors inside of our form
so I'm going to do a string interpolation here so a dollar sign curly braces get error passing our errors
and then right here I want to print out whoops title I'll copy that and it for the second one I want
to do Bryce okay.
So let's now save this.
We're going to attempt to upload an image again and this is where we're going to see a really interesting
result.
I'm gonna go back to my form I'm going to enter in a valid title.
Remember we said that titles had to be had to be between five and 20 characters.
So I can enter in something like a special code and then our price has to be a number at least one.
It's all put in something like 20 and then I'm going to select one these random images and hit submit.
And as soon as I do so I'm going to see some errors here.
So this is kind of unexpected.
We just saw a moment ago just a moment ago we ran this same form submission and we were able to create
a product and inside of this product such as on file I clearly see a title and a price without a doubt
that information is inside of here however as soon as we added in the validation check this ear's object
seems to think that we have not provided the correct values here.
It seems to think that I didn't give a title that is between 5 and 40 characters.
And it seems to think that I didn't give a number that is greater than one as well.
Like I said something is just not quite right here.
The other thing I want to point out that is just a little bit mysterious is that if you look carefully
at the product Jace on file and you look really carefully at price right here.
You'll notice that price has been stored inside of our Jason File as a string but we specifically said
that we wanted our price to be a float really a number whenever we story number inside of Jason or inside
of a Jason File in this case the numbers should show up simply as a number and not as a string like
that.
It's like I said something is just not quite right here.
So we need to figure out what is going on.
So this is a very subtle bug.
I'm just going to tell you exactly what is going on if I take a look at my post request handler again
we've got require title and require price right here.
So we are running our validation step right there.
And then in the next step we are calling upload single with image.
Now this is where things get a little bit confusing.
Remember we made a really big point a couple of videos ago that inside of our index dot J.S. file we
had wired up that body parser with your URL encoded to pass the contents of a post request specifically
the body and give us access to that information inside of req dot body but we said that now that we
are doing this image upload we have a very different encoding type on our form.
And so this middle right here middleware that thing no longer applies.
It's no longer running for our incoming request.
So that thing is no longer passing the contents of the post request and throwing it into a wrecked body
so then that very quick quickly begs the question how in that case are we still able to reach in to
wrecked our body right here and still get title and price.
The reason is if we look very carefully at the multi-year documentation and remember we are making use
of multi-year to process this incoming post request that has a file inside of it.
If you take a very close look at the documentation you'll notice that it says that whenever we make
use of melter like as we are right here at this middleware it is not only going to take care of any
images or any files that have been uploaded but it's also going to pass all the different text fields
inside of the post requests body as well.
So in other words this line of code right here this middleware that is what is responsible now or handling
record dot body and getting our title in price inside.
So how does that result in the error that we currently have while the problem is the order of our Middleware
is the order in which our middleware functions are executed goes in a left to right order.
So right now when we get an incoming post request to admin products new we're going to first take the
request and throw it into require title usually for all of our other form submissions by the time a
request gets into our request handler.
It has already been subjected to our index not J.S. middleware as the ones we wired up right here.
So for all of the other post request handlers before the request shows up and goes through our different
middleware that request has already flown through expressed out static body parser hooky session and
so on.
So in all of our other middle where's the request shows up having already been passed by body parser.
But that is no longer the case here so when our request shows up for this validator of required title
and then require price nothing has passed the body of the incoming post request.
So there is no title or price property available on rect body for required title and require price to
actually operate upon.
And so as far as these validators are concerned we didn't provide a title we didn't provide a price
they don't exist yet on the request and that is why we end up seeing the validation errors over here.
As far as that validation stuff is concerned Nope title was provided no price was provided at all so
in order to fix this all we have to do is reorder our middleware.
So we're going to take a blow but single with image we're gonna cut it and put it right before our different
validators.
So now in our post request comes in it's going to first get past we're going to get access to our image
and wrecked out body and through that's our title in our price then the request is going to flow through
our validators of required title and require price and so those two validators are now going to have
access to the title and price.
Now they can successfully check to see if there are any errors now in this case.
Hopefully it's going to see OK there's a title in the price.
Hopefully they're going to be valid.
And so hopefully those validators are not going to say that there are any validation error and we will
get past this if statement.
Now yeah.
So let's now save this again in case you were skipping through this video I just want to point out that
we swapped the middleware right there going to go back over I'm going to refresh the forum enter in
a valid title like a special Cote and a valid price of 10 throwing an image hit submit.
And now I am able to submit my form.
So again I know this is a very subtle and small bug but the lesson here is that our middle peers operate
in a very specific order and because we're now submitting a different type of form and a different Middleware
is responsible for passing it we have to be very aware of the order in which our Middleware is executes
okay.
So overall that's pretty much it around our image upload stuff.
We are now able to receive an image.
We're doing some validation on the form we take the image convert it to a base64 string create the product
inside of our products repo.
And that's pretty much it.
We're good to go.
Let's save right here take a quick pause.
When we come back the next video we're going to add in a little bit of styling to the form that we just
put together.
So just like before I'm going to give you a zip file that has a s identical version of new J.S. with
a lot of additional markup inside of it.
And then after that we're going to start to work on our ability to list out all the different products
that have been created inside of our app.