Next up we'll continue to add on to our culture class so we can get more practice adding methods.
So I have a very long complicated function I found online.
I did not write this.
This function converts a RG B color into a H S L color HDL is a very interesting color system.
It stands for hue saturation and lightness.
And it looks like this HSA.
And then we have a hue at the beginning from zero to 360.
Like a degree around the color wheel.
So let's do one thirty.
Then we have saturation which is a percentage let's go with 50 percent and then we have lightness which
is also a percentage from zero to one hundred eighty percent.
So that is a result in color apparently if I change lightness to be 100 percent it's extremely light.
If I go to 20 percent it's a darker green.
Let's go to 40.
If I change saturation to 100 percent it's very saturated.
I go down 10 percent.
It is not at all saturated.
Let's go around 80 and then Hugh is interesting because I can completely change the value of that colored
the hue of the color by just affecting one value so I can do you know zero will give me red apparently
if I do 80 90 100 200 300 I'm making my way around the wheel all the way to 360 where I'm back to red
so I can change the color very easily I could make a more saturated color by impacting the second value
the saturation I could make a different value entirely I could go from red to the polar opposite by
adding 180 so a 30 is the hue I add 180 what is one 80 plus 30 to 10 which gives me this blue and I
can easily lighten something well one percent it will be white but I could do 90 percent to get a very
light blue or I could darken it to a very dark blue so let's make a function I already have the logic
that let's use it to create HSA l values and let's actually store H S and L on our class instances because
we could reuse them for different functions if I want to make a light and function or a darker or a
full saturation or something like that I want to use those s and now values.
All right so here's the function.
It's called calc H SL it expects three arguments and at the end we have three variables they're not
being returned but we could return H S and L as an array maybe we can make a string.
This has nothing to do with the class at the moment.
I'm going to move this into my class.
I'll put it down at the bottom because it's so long and ugly and I don't want to pass it.
RG And B I have access to them on this.
So my constructor runs right.
RG and B are set based off of whatever I passed in if I recall calc H SL.
RG and b will be on this then what I'm going to do is actually assign H S and L to the object to the
instance.
I'll do this that H equals H H is calculated up here s is calculated in the same function.
Again the logic does not matter.
I have not even glanced at it.
I just took it from a website.
What did I find this that come Stack Overflow.
But it does work who knows how elegant it is but it works.
So now h s no exist on the individual instances as long as I call calc H SL.
So let's try it.
I have my why we go with a white one because white is probably easiest for us to tell if it's working
somewhere to refresh this and called white dot calc H.S. L and I just look at white to begin with.
It only has four properties.
RG be a name if I call white dot calc H SL assignment to Constance my bad I think I can't use const
here because the way the function is written it is updating as you can see here divide equals slash
equals so I'll use light and now it should pick it to go all right.
So we don't return anything but if we look at white it now has H S and L and lightness is set to 100
which makes sense as we experimented with a couple minutes ago lightness of one hundred gives us white.
So now let's make a function called H SL that will actually display the H S L correct format string
and to start before I get there I'm going to show you that we can call a function from within the constructor
we can call one of these methods like this dot calc H SL we'll just call it immediately after we assign
RG be a name we'll call that function automatically whenever you make a new color we'll calculate the
H SL based off of the RG B that was passed in that we then added to the object.
This is called it looks up RG and B from the instance of the actual class the instance that was just
created and then it adds on it tags its own new properties onto that instance.
So let's make our function called just h SL and it will extract D structure H S and L from this and
then we can return our template literal which isn't going to be H S L we need parentheses then we have
the hue which is not a percentage goes from 0 to 360 then we have saturation which is a percentage that
we need to add the percent then we have lightness which is also a percentage.
Let's see if that works refresh over here we have our color white.
It was created and now it automatically has H S and L properties and I should be able to call white
dot H S L and get a string.
Let's verify on a different color.
We have Red let's verify that it works.
Document that body that style dot background color again
equals red dot H S L and it works.
OK so now we could have a little bit of fun and define some other methods like one that I'll show you.
We'll call opposite which will take H and generate an opposite color.
Remember to color wheel from zero to 360.
So I'll just add a method called opposed it and we can start by just duplicating this.
We're gonna want to use H but we're also going to want to make a new age new hue equals and what we'll
do is add 180.
So if we had 60.
Before we add 180.
If we had zero before we add 180 it's 180 degrees the other side directly across that circle the color
wheel.
But if we're above 180 then if we add another one eighty four at two hundred and you add 180 we're suddenly
at 380.
So what we can then do is modulo by 360 which will take us back to 20 if you're lost on the logic don't
worry too much.
It's not that important but we can do.
H plus 180 modulo 360 to keep us on that 360 degree wheel.
If we go too far we just start back at zero.
All right.
So then here we would put new hue instead of the existing hue H let's try it out.
So I'm going to refresh I'll run the same code red dot HSA l I lose the line.
Here we go to update the body.
Now let's do red dot opposite which gives us that color.
They are opposite on the color wheel at least as far as the hue the saturation and lightness are still
the same.
Let's do one last one.
Let's make one called full saturation and it's just going to have the existing hue the existing lightness
but set saturation to 100 full saturation or fully saturated all we need are H and L we don't care about
saturation because we're always going to return saturation set to 100 percent.
Let's see if that one works so we'll set the background color to red dot SL and then we'll update it
to a fully saturated and was it already at 100.
Well that's disappointing.
He's already one hundred saturation.
Let's try another example.
Here's a different color.
I'm giving it a name which I have been leaving off for the record which is actually not the best idea
so I should either add a default name which I can do just like any other default parameter or I should
just pass in a name like I did here.
Even though we're not using it anywhere it's just good to have on there.
We don't want to have just undefined all over the place so let's save that to variable const orange
and then we'll do the same thing where we change the background color but we'll change it to orange
dot HDL or RG.
It doesn't matter we should get the same thing.
Okay.
It's not 100.
Now let's do full saturated or fully saturated.
I don't know if you could see that but it did change.
If you go back to our GP or hex or any of these other ones slightly duller now fully saturated.
And how about opposite so be our last one a nice beautiful blue.
Okay.
So this is our color class.
A lot of the logic to calculate the HSA L to convert from Archie V to hex really doesn't matter.
Don't focus on that.
Focus on the interplay of the keyword.
This the idea of the constructor adding in values to this to the individual instance as properties calling
methods on this which allows us to access other methods in the same class and then using the new keyword
to instantiate new colors.