Rather than start working on our maze application right away I first want to try to recreate this demo
very quickly making this demo is actually easier than you might think.
And it's going to just get us a little bit more familiar with matter J.S. before we dive off the deep
end and start worrying about May's generation and a bunch of different crazy topics.
So in order to create this demo right here we're going to create a variety of different shapes.
We need to make sure that they can all be clicked on and dragged around with the mouse.
We also need to make sure that we show for rectangles along the edges of the canvas as well.
So I need one on top one on the right one at the bottom and one on the left.
The purpose of these different rectangles is to just keep our shapes from flying off to the outside
world.
If we go back over to our application right now and we turn off the is static write their song and commented
out and then refresh.
We saw that our shape can very easily just fall off the face of the earth.
So in order to keep this thing on the screen we just have to show some rectangles around the border
to make sure that it doesn't fall off.
That's pretty much it.
We're going to make sure that we can show a rectangle on the top right bottom and left so to do so.
I'm going to go back over to my index dot J.S. file.
I'm going to find where I'm creating a rectangle right now and I'm going to delete it and then I will
replace that with a comment that says simply walls.
As we start writing matter J.S. code we're going to be creating a variety of different shapes inside
of our index dot J as file over and over again.
And so it's usually very good practice to add in some comments to describe the bunch of shapes are about
to add right here because otherwise it's gonna be kind of challenging to remember exactly what code
creates what shapes then I'm going to create an array called walls like so and inside of here I'm going
to create the four different rectangles that we need going to first start with the top rectangle local
bodies dot rectangle.
Remember that the first two arguments are the x and y coordinates of the center of the rectangle.
And the third and fourth are the width and height of the rectangle but this very first one.
Let's take a look at a diagram and just make sure that it's really clear what numbers we're going to
put in here.
It's the rectangles right here represents our canvas as we saw just a moment ago our canvas is eight
hundred units wide the rectangle that we want to show is essentially going to be like this right here
noticed that the rectangle is not completely inside of our canvas and that's totally okay.
That is actually what is going on on the demonstration back over here.
We can see that this rectangle is actually halfway on the screen and that's evident because that little
red line right there the red line is essentially at the center point of the rectangle.
So the rectangle doesn't have to be all the way on the canvas.
It can be half on half off and that's what we're going to do as well just to make our code a little
bit easier to understand so we need to first provide the x y coordinate of the center of this rectangle.
So the center will be approximately right there or so so that's going to be for 100 units over and it's
going to be zero units down.
So a y of essentially zero then in total.
This thing's going to be eight hundred units wide and it's height Well the height doesn't really make
a big difference.
We just need to make sure that we have some kind of rectangle there we might use a height of like 40
or so but really it's totally up to us.
We can have any height whatsoever so long as it has a defined height.
It just can't be zero.
So let's now take those values back over to our Ed sit back over here.
I'm going to do a 400 that's 400 units over zero units down eight hundred units wide and 40 units tall.
And then I'll put on the options object which is static is true and then after that I'm going to make
sure that I add this wall's array to my world.
So just a second ago we saw that we could call world dot add with lowercase world and then whatever
our rectangle was.
So like bodies dots rectangle or whatever so we can pass either a single shape in to the world dot add
method or alternatively we could pass in an array of shapes as well.
And that's why I created this as a was array so gonna pass all these different walls that were gonna
create in at once it's going to save that go back over refresh and now I can see the top while on there.
Okay.
So that's a good start.
So now we can repeat that same process for the three other walls as well.
Only just very quickly draw out what the next two or three are going to be.
So for the next one.
Let me just do a little bit of erasing here just make sure things are nice and crystal clear easy to
read so we can do the bottom one next to once again this is going to be 400 units over it's going to
be now 600 units down because remember our overall canvas is a hundred by 600 it will be 800 wide and
once again we can use 40 tall so I'm going to call bodies dot rectangle again we're going to be 400
units over this time we're going to be 600 units down we're going to be 800 units wide and 40 tall then
is static is true so I'll once again save refresh and I can see the bottom border.
Hey let's get through the last two here really quickly.
I think you get the idea now but honestly we're going to have to do all this time mentioning stuff so
often for this application that it's kind of worth just putting in a little bit of time from the get
go to make sure that these different values are really clear plus new.
Now do our left barrier.
So this one will be slightly different.
So again we are a hundred by six hundred overall.
So we're now going to go down 300 units.
We're going to go over zero.
The thing is going to be 40 units wide now and 600 units tall and then something very similar for the
right hand side.
We're going to be 300 down
going to be 800 over.
So eight hundred to the right we'll have 600 tall and 40 wide.
Let's do both those Audi's dot rectangle that will do the left hand side first.
So this one is going to be zero over three hundred down 40 wide 600 tall.
And then finally the right hand side
so we'll do eight hundred over 300 down 40 wide 600 tall and I'll get the at is static true as well
okay.
So let's save that.
Hopefully I didn't make any mistakes if I did.
We'll do a little bit of troubleshooting very quickly refresh and.
OK.
It actually all was correct.
So I've got top bottom left and right now.
If we go back over once again and I add in one last rectangle like the same kind of plane rectangle
that we had before and this time rather than assigning it to a variable I'll just add it into the world
directly.
So I'll do a world dot ad with the world's bodies dot rectangle
and assume I'll do two hundred two hundred fifty fifty save this refresh and now a rectangle falls down
but it hits that other one and it just stops right there.
OK.
So that's definitely a good start.
So let's take a pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're going to throw in a ton of other shapes and we'll make sure that
we can drag them all around with our mouse so quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.