Next up we're moving on to our second type of loop in JavaScript.
It's called The while loop the while loop is syntactically simpler and it's more flexible than a for
loop in some ways.
So the basic syntax looks like this.
While some condition is true running this code in here so this condition can be anything you want and
then your code will run while that condition is true.
So if we wanted to rewrite a simple for loop where we have four let I equals zero I less than or equal
to five.
Plus plus and we're printing out i if we wanted to rewrite that in a comment this out where we simply
get zero through five print it out with a while loop we have to do a little bit more work upfront we
need to initialize a variable for our counter I could call it let's go with NUM let's go with J J start
set zero while J is less center equal to 5 in the loop we actually have to add 1 to J J plus plus and
let's consider log J See what we get zero one two three four five from the for loop zero one two three
four five from the while loop.
So in these scenarios where we're simply iterating through numbers zero to five.
I prefer a for loop because we don't have to make the variable up top separately and once we talk about
scope you'll understand why that is it's an advantage even if we stuff to write the same declaration
it's a better practice to not create a variable outside of a loop whenever possible.
So this is not the best use of a while loop but it does work this code in here is only going to run
when this is true.
So the first time through J is zero is zero less than or equal to 5.
Yes.
So we consider log J So we get our first zero then we add 1 to J.
So J is now 1 is J still less than or equal to 5.
Yep.
And you can probably see where I'm going with this.
It continues until J is 5.
That's still less than or equal to 5.
So we print out 5 then we add 1 to J.
It's now 6.
And now the loop is false.
J is 6 which is not less than or equal to 5.
So nothing happens.
Well not it's not that nothing happens nothing in the loop runs the loop is over and any other code
we had down here would run because the loop is complete.
You can think of a while loop sort of like an if statement a conditional plus a loop and if you're simply
trying to generate numbers I prefer to use a for loop.
Most people do but there are other situations where a while loop is great and we go into that in the
next video.