Let's start to implement this.
Create function to create function is going to take some attributes that a user should have.
We're then going to take that record stored inside of our data file somehow.
The first thing I want to discuss is the attributes property right here for our user creation or storing
and user.
We're probably going to want to save their email and password but we probably want to write out our
code in kind of a generic format so that if we ever decide to add in additional properties that a user
should have we can readily accept those.
So for example if a user object is supposed to now have a user name or something like that we just want
to make sure that create is written in such a way that it could take in those additional attributes
so I can once again go back over to my editor underneath get all I can to add an async create and this
will be called with some attributes that this new user record is going to have.
I'm going to shorten the name attributes right away to just adders just for abbreviations sake so adders
is going to be an object that maybe has like an email property with a email and a password that has
a password.
So we need to essentially take that object right there.
Add it into our big array of users and then write that update to our users not just on file one thing
on mention really quickly is that you'll notice that right now I'm kind of imagining that our password
is stored in plain text for the first iteration of our stuff we're going to assume that our passwords
are stored in plain text.
We are going to very quickly refactor it to store passwords in a much more secure fashion.
I just wanna mention that really quickly if all that doesn't make sense.
No problem.
We're gonna have a huge discussion later on about how to safely secure and store passwords okay.
So then inside of here in order to create an add a new user we're going to first load up the contents
of our user store Jason on file.
So essentially every single time we want to make a change to our list of users we're going to load our
file backup.
So we have the most recent collection or iteration of data available will then add in our new user to
that array and then write the file directly back to our harddrive so inside of here I'm going to say
const records is a wait.
This dot get all that's gonna give me my big existing list of users I'm then going to push in the records
not push the new user and then after that we need to write out some code that's going to write the updated
records array back to files dot or me.
Users dot Jason.
Well really for us this file name so for that we're going to do the exact opposite of read file up here.
We're going to instead use right file so we're going to take all of our information turn it back into
Jason data and then write that back to our hard drive.
Let's take a look at the documentation around right file again very quickly because this time around
we're going to use the promise based version as opposed to the sync based version we had before it's
back in my documentation.
I'll look for FSM dot promises dot right file.
Here it is right here.
So making use of this is really easy and straightforward.
We're going to call f s stop promises dot right file.
We're going to pass in the file name in the data to throw in their if the file already exists.
When we call right file we are not going to add on additional information.
Instead we're going to replace whatever is already inside the file so we can basically call it right
file as many times as we want to in a row with some new information.
It's a back over here.
We're gonna just take out that comment and I'll do an a wait f S. promises not right file the first
argument will be this dot file name.
The second argument is going to be the information that we want to store inside that file as a string.
So we're going to take our records variable which we just changed and add in that newsy user.
We're going to turn it into Jason and then pass it in as the second argument they'll do.
Jason not string of fi records.
And then there is an optional third argument we can pass in the options object with the encoding.
You'll notice once again the default encoding is UTF 8.
So we really don't have to pass it in because well we are using a default here.
So from this point on I'm just going to ignore that encoding argument because usually UTF 8 is the default
okay.
So that's pretty much it for creates.
Now we are going to eventually abstract out this right file line into a separate function because as
you're going to see we end up having to update our users not Jason File from many different locations
inside this repository class.
But if right now just for testing purposes we will leave that line directly inside of our create function
to now to test this out.
I'm gonna go back down to my test function right above where I call get all I will call repo not create
I'll put in the user properties I want to are the properties for this user that I want to save so I
can give them an email of test at test dot com and a password of password to create function is asynchronous
in nature.
So I can make sure that I also put the awake keyword right in front of it to think about what we're
now doing we're going to get access to our users repository we're gonna save a new record to it we're
then going to get all the records we have saved and console logged amount are going to save this and
we'll do another quick test.
I'll go back over to my terminal node users dot J.S. and I can see the console log of that one single
user.
In addition if I go over to my editor and OPEN UP THE USER start JS on file I'll see my plane data inside
there as well.
Okay.
So this is it.
This kind of proves that we can have some persistence of data and add in new records over time.
Now every single time that we run node user start we're going to add in a new user record.
So if I run to several times in a row I'm going to end up with a equivalent number of user objects if
I go back over to my users not just Jason File I'll see all those different records reflected inside
of here.
The nice benefit to this application or this style of creating a user's repository that stores all this
data inside of a file is that if you and I ever want to see what information is inside of our project
we can just open up the appropriate JS on file and we're pretty much good to go.
So this is a good improvement.
Let's take another pause right here and continue working on the remainder of our functions.