Next up it's time for a quick quiz on strings.
We've covered a lot so far around strings working with quote single and double quotes talking about
indices different methods.
So there are a few challenges here but they follow the same format as the other quizzes.
So I'll show you a little question I'd like to try and evaluate it without typing the code.
Pause if needed.
So here's the first one.
What is the value of age after this code runs.
And then here's the next one.
What does this evaluate to.
So no variable just what does this evaluate to.
If you were to run this in your console what would you get back.
The next one.
What does this evaluate to.
Same idea no variable but if you were to copy and paste this into your console which I hope you don't
do what would you get back.
And another one.
What is the value of the song variable after this code runs.
So after both lines are done.
If you typed song into the console what value will it hold next.
What is the value of the cleaned input variable.
There are two variables here.
I'm interested in what the value of the second one would hold her.
What does it hold.
After these lines run yet another one.
What is the value of the index variable here so we have two variables.
What is the value of index after this code runs.
And one more.
What is the value of index in this scenario.
Almost there.
We have two more.
Here's this one.
What is the value of index.
Same name.
But it's not related to the first one.
What is the value inside that variable.
When these lines are done and then the very last one slightly longer.
What does this evaluate to.
So no variables.
But if you were to run this line in your console what would you see.
All right.
So if you need to pause on any of those questions I highly highly recommend you take these.
And I want to say you take them seriously depending on your skill level.
These might be easy.
These might be challenging but take your time.
Make sure you can get through these.
And let's talk about the answers.
All right.
So this very first one when we take two strings and we add them together it is called concatenation
and we end up with a new string where those two strings have been shoved together.
So age if I can spell it not on message.
Our age ends up as 50 for OK.
This one.
We have the string pecan pie or pecan pie.
And we're looking for index seven.
So what does that give us.
Well I.
And the reason I chose this string is that I wanted to make sure that you understand it's not just letters
spaces and any character and a string counts.
We start at 0 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7.
Is I another similar question here.
What does this evaluate to.
This one is slightly different because there is no index of three in the string PUP the highest index
is two the length is three.
One two three.
But indexes start at zero.
So the highest index is two.
So we get undefined.
Next up what is the value of song.
So this one is it's kind of tricky I guess because we are upper casing song with two uppercase but we're
not actually storing the result anywhere.
We're not saving it to the song variable.
So song is actually unchanged.
We have let song equals London calling.
And then afterwards we are upper casing it.
So we do get this string returned to us but song is unaltered.
The song remains the same top notch led zeppelin reference there.
OK.
Next up what is the value of cleaned input.
So we have our string user input set to Todd at gmail dot com capitalized Todd.
There's space at the beginning and we are trimming it first.
So the space at the beginning will go away.
Then we are lower casing the results of that trim.
So lower casing it means everything will be lower cased.
So we'll have lower case Todd at gmail dot com instead of cleaned input.
So if we test it out
if I run it take a look at cleaned input that's what we get user input is unchanged.
Next up what is the value of index here.
So we have a variable called Park set to Yellowstone.
The string and then we have a variable called index which is the result of calling index of stone.
So the word Stone does occur instead of park but it's not an exact match.
Case does matter.
And I used an uppercase s for stone versus in the park variable the stone or the S in stone is lower
case.
So what does that mean.
We'll get index of negative 1.
We just tested out here we look at index it is negative 1 which is what index f returns when it doesn't
find that value.
Here's another index of example.
Yellow is a variable.
We set it to go away two exclamation points.
What is the value of index where index is a variable set to the result of yellow dot index of exclamation
point.
What does index of return when we pass an exclamation point.
There are two exclamation points.
I wanted to make sure you understand we only get the first matching index which is going to be this
character here and that has an index of 0 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 we can verify that here or not.
I use the variable index twice just to refresh the page and recall that line.
And now if we look at index we get seven and then we've got this last one.
What does this evaluate two slightly trickier.
We have garbage it's all caps so I guess it's garbage dot slice too.
So when we slice with one number one index we go from that index to the end of the string.
So index of 2 is 0 1 2.
So we end up with our beige garbage with the exclamation point that substring then we replace the B
with an empty string.
Now this is actually kind of hard to see here.
I didn't realize when I blew it up as the image here it looks like a space.
So that's my fault.
I'll have to add a note.
Anyway it is an empty string but if you treated it as a space as long as you understand how replace
works.
That's all good.
So what we should end up with here if we run it we have garbage we slice so we end up with our bridge
and then we replace the B with nothing an empty string which gives us rage.
So we go from garbage to hard rage and then that goes to rage with the exclamation point.
So if you treated it as a space we would end up with rage like this.
Either one is totally valid I apologize if that was confusing.
Now we've made it through the quiz.
We have a little bit more to talk about with strings and then we're gonna move on to undefined and no.
And then we're really going to open things up and get into conditional logic and adding real logic and
decision making into our code.