Next up we need to talk about something called the event object.
So when this function is called Let's go with the change colored function.
It's called When we click on a box or a user clicks on a box.
We're never executing change color ourself.
It's being called for us.
And it's actually passed a value it's past an event object in this event objects sometimes is extremely
useful to have access to in our callback in our event handler.
So we have access to it.
It's automatically passed every single time.
We're just not capturing it in change color.
We're ignoring it but if we were to add in a parameter here you could call it anything.
Usually you'll see E or event or even t any of them is fine.
I'll go with EVP.
Why don't we just see what it contains.
Console that log evey t I'll refresh my page.
We click on one of these and it's an event object which contains information about the particular event.
So it's a mouse event.
You can see where it occurred on my screen the screen X and screen y why we can see what else.
We have this property path which is kind of interesting.
It shows everything that we clicked on.
Yes we did click on a div with the class of box but it was instead of a section with the idea of boxes
and that's inside the body inside the chemo element inside the document inside the window.
We clicked on all of those other things like was the shift key depressed the timestamp for when it happened
after the page loaded all that stuff is contained in this one object if we instead had a different type
of event listener setup why don't we do a keyboard event a key press or a key up a key down let's add
in a simple input here or actually let's even just do it on the body.
So if you type any key while you're on this web page let's alert the key or do something with it.
So all select document dump body dot add event listener and we'll do a key press we'll talk more about
these events the particular key events and form events in the next video but I just want to show this
function we'll work with the event object we'll use it and why don't we just cancel that log the event
object so keep press on the body of the document so anywhere on this page if I type a key Okay I just
typed the key I typed another one and the reason I'm showing this key event is that often we need to
know which key has been pressed and that information is contained in the event object we don't say key
press of a key press of Z key we just say key press any key that is pressed we'll fire this event and
call this function.
So if we want to know was it the enter key was it the.
I don't know w a as D key was it an arrow key then we use the event object which is automatically passed
in and if we open it this time it is a keyboard event not a mouse event and we have a bunch of things
like key that is a very important one if you want to know just the basic key that was pressed although
it doesn't always work the way you might expect for example if I press shift my event is not firing
but if I instead do shift ah it does fire but we'll save that for the next video all you should know
is that we have access to information about the particular key that was pressed so ah or w p o i u and
so on.
Okay so the event object is a very useful part of working with events if you need information about
the events whether it's what was clicked on or what key was pressed what time after the page loaded
where on the screen the coordinates exactly.
There's a bunch of different pieces of information you can access using that event object.