Next up we have another new operator or feature in JavaScript called rest.
Now I wrote that it looks like spread but it's not because we use the exact same three dot syntax.
Dot dot dot but rest behaves very differently.
It's almost like the opposite of spread.
What it does is instead of spreading data out into arguments or into a new object or an array it actually
collects things down into a single array.
So it's used when we want to make functions that accept an unlimited number of arguments or a variable
number of arguments.
For example we've seen this method a couple times math dot Max where we can pass in as many arguments
as we want and it returns the maximum value.
So how would we write this.
How would we write code for a function let's call it max or let's do one called Sum instead.
Some will return the sum of any number of numbers.
So we could have two numbers passed in so we could add two parameters.
But what if we want to support one hundred or twenty or one we would have to do something like this
maybe a b c d e f g h i j k and even then we would eventually run out of letters and have to switch
it up and then how would it work.
Because sometimes they would be undefined if you only passed in three arguments.
So this is not the answer.
There is a way of doing this without rest.
It's called the arguments object.
So when every function we have access to something called arguments it's a special name.
Arguments and it kind of looks like an array but it is not an array.
It's 100 percent not an array.
We don't have things like push and pop and all the common array methods you might want but it is a list
where we have indices and we can loop over it with a for loop.
So this has been around for a long time.
This is not new for starting with the old way.
And then we'll see the new way with rest.
So using this is as I wrote here math it's not very it's not great.
It's annoying but I'm going to show it to you quickly instead of any function we have arguments so let's
just cancel about log arguments notice that my function does not have any parameters listed.
That doesn't matter if I call it right now some of one comma to come are three arguments prints out
and we can see it has three values in it one two and three if I call it with a whole bunch more arguments
six seven twenty three forty five 6 6 6 6 arguments has eight elements in it.
So if I wanted to make some actually work I wanted some all elements let's use reduce which we saw earlier
on we'll get some practice again with it we have arguments and what I might want to try is arguments
start reduce and then remember our syntax here we have the total and then each current Val let's go
with curve Val and we'll return total plus curve Val and let's see what we get here also we'll return
that this will give us the sum and then we return the sum if I try it though one two three four five
oh no arguments that reduce is not a function again arguments is not actually an array it's an array
like object it looks like an array because we can access arguments of zero or we can loop over it but
it does not have array methods if I wanted to make this work using the arguments object what I could
do is turn it into an array and one way of doing that we just saw is spread.
Dot dot dot arguments and then I could call this args array and then iterate over that args array.
Now if I tried again it works we get 15 right.
That's I think that's correct yes.
So that's one of the shortcomings of the arguments object.
Here's another situation where it's not ideal.
If I wanted to define a function called uh let's just go with the full name it accepts a first name
a last name and then a bunch of titles like optional titles someone could have like.
I don't know.
Order of the.
I'm making this up or if the Phoenix or royal bad ass or whatever titles there are I know there's a
bunch of them.
Oh Junior.
There we go.
Or the third and somebody could have I think you would just do this right.
So you do the third.
Somebody could have multiple titles but everyone needs to have a first and the last.
And then what I'd like to do is just have everything else.
Any titles that were passed and collected maybe in the arguments object but there isn't actually a way
of doing that.
If I do first and last in here if I console that log arguments it just contains everything.
So if I call a full name of Tom Jones and then pass and a couple other things like third and order of
the Phoenix.
Those are his titles.
If we look at arguments it just contains all four arguments so we could still implement this function.
We would just need to make sure to skip the first two if we're trying to get the titles that were passed
in Tom Jones the third order of the Phoenix.
We would want these two.
We already have first and last.
We still have access to those I can print out first.
I still have access to it.
You can see Tom.
It's just that arguments includes everything.
So I just have to be mindful of that and know that the first two in arguments are already first and
last with rest which we're about to see.
That's not a problem.
And there is one last issue with the arguments object it does not work in Arrow functions.
If I define an arrow function which I'll call multiply if I try and control that log.
Arguments we'll call it multiply pass in some numbers it does not work.
Argument is not defined so the arguments object is not a thing in Arrow functions.
So there's a couple shortcomings.
To sum this up first it's not a real array.
So you have to turn it into an array.
If you want array methods.
Next there is no functionality provided for collecting remaining arguments like we saw here.
Arguments contains every argument passed in.
Even if we captured the first two in parameter names.
And then lastly the arguments object does not exist at all in Arrow functions.
So we've set the stage to see the new fancy syntax using rest.
That's coming up next.