You've now got the ability to create new products and tie images to each product that we create.
Before we move on I want to open up our views admin products new DOT J.S. file.
So right now the form that we are displaying is very simple and kind of ugly to be honest so attached
to this lecture is going to be a zip file called something like AECOM 0 6 7 template that's it.
Make sure you download that file again it is attached to this lecture once you download that zip file
extract it and inside there you're going to see a new dot J.S. file.
So this is essentially the same exact new DOT J.S. file that we've been working on.
I just added in a couple more HDMI elements and some class names as well.
So I going to take that extracted file I'm going to drag and drop it into my editor right away we can
see that all the javascript is identical.
Just some additional markup I'm going to copy everything inside this file go to my old new DOT J.S.
here it is right here I'm going to select everything inside of here and delete it and then paste in
what I just copied that I'm going to save that's going to go back over to my browser and refresh the
page and I get something that looks like this right here.
So definitely a little bit better looking than what we had before all the validation still works.
So if I click on Create right now without any title or price we'll see some validation messages like
so it's just a little visual improvement and there's one last little thing that I want to fix up inside
of our post request handler so quick pause and we're gonna take care of that in just a moment.