All right.
We've made it.
We have one last important topic around classes in JavaScript.
It is the keyword extend along with keyword called super.
They both have to do with sub classing essentially inheritance.
This is a way of sharing functionality between classes.
So typically I would want to show something more realistic kind of what we did here.
This is nothing crazy but I mean I've used plenty of libraries that are color libraries.
They exist just to do this.
Some of them are more more fully featured.
But this is not totally unrealistic.
It's not the typical intro to classes idea of dog and cat or bank account or deck of cards.
It's something slightly better.
But for this video on inheritance and extends and subclasses and super I'm going to dial it down.
We're gonna go back to the basics.
The most cliche possible classes let's define a class called Cats.
I know and will pass in a name and an age about that.
All right.
And then we'll set this name to be name and then this dot age to be age.
So the reason I'm going simple so we can focus on the concepts not get too bogged down in the actual
logic of things.
The logic here will be incredibly simple.
So a cat class and we'll have a simple method called Eat.
And in here we will return the string.
Let's do this.
Don't name is eating OK so I can make a new class or a new cat new cat.
Save it to a variable const Monty equals new cat Monty who is technically dead but I'll say nine.
Let's look at Monty.
It has name of Monte age of nine.
I call Monty dog eat.
Monty is eating.
All right.
So now let's say I have a nother class.
This class is called Dog dog is very similar.
Surprise surprise.
It's almost like I'd planned it that way.
Now that was stupid.
Oh no I said that.
I'm sorry.
So a dog also has a name and an age.
We said This dog name to be name is that age to be age.
It also has an eat method.
It's just copy that over.
OK let's make a dog so I'll call new dog.
I'll pass in.
Why it concept why it equals new dog in an age.
He's also dead.
Yikes.
We look at why it's it's an object has a name and an age and it has a it method.
They're basically the same thing just different names but we could go ahead and add some method to cat
that doesn't exist on dog like meow and then it could just return meow and we could do the same thing
for dog.
We could have a method called bark which returns Wolf.
OK.
So now they're slightly different but there is a lot of duplicated functionality.
So one of the options we have in Javascript is to move this duplicated code from here and from Cat and
from dog into a separate standalone class that both of these classes could extend so you can think of
it as kind of like a parent child relationship.
We could have a parent class.
I'd call it probably animal or pet let's do pet class pet and let's just copy this entire thing here.
Like that and remove all of that from Cat.
All of that from dog.
So right now I'm not going to be able to make a new cat.
I won't be able to make a new dog.
I can make a new pet.
But if I try and rerun this code and make a new dog let's look at what why it is an empty object.
There's no constructor no constructor on dog and no constructor on cat.
So here is how we can tell cat and dog to include the functionality of pet to extend pet.
It's as simple as saying class cats extends pet.
I'll do the same thing for Dog class dog extends pet.
So now does it work.
Well let's see what happens when I make a new cat or a new dog all right.
I just made a new dog.
Look at that age and name.
We're already filled out but I don't have a constructor in dog.
Doesn't matter because I extended from pet.
It's going to use that constructor if it doesn't find one on my dog or on this dog class in which it
did it.
So it looked to the constructor from pet.
So we end up with age and name and take a look.
We also have bark bark which is defined on dog and even more exciting.
We have access to eat which is not defined on dog at all.
So we don't see it here.
Right.
We don't see it there.
I don't see eat here.
But if I look at this promo here and photo again.
There we go.
So we have dog.
This is a functionality from dog which is just bark.
Then we have the functionality from pet which is eat so I can call why it dog eat.
Even though I never defined eat on the dog class we are extending the functionality from pet both on
cat and dog.
So I could do it again with a cat.
Let's just make that Monty.
Where are you.
Here we go.
We have Monty dots.
He not to find on cat Monty dog meow is defined on cat.
That's the basics.
A couple of other things very important to note.
If I had another method on let's say on dog also called Eat and this one returned I need to use a string
template literal something else like this dog name scarfs his food like that and now I make a dog if
we call Wyatt dog eat.
Which version of Eat does it call.
It calls the dog version.
So if it doesn't find eat on dog on the dog prototype it will look up on the pet prototype where it
does find it and if it didn't find it there it would look on the object prototype if didn't find it
there.
It's going to be unhappy and it will let you know so I'll leave that there so you can see how it works.
The other important keyword here that we haven't talked about yet is called Super.
So sometimes you want to rely on the exact same constructor from your superclass from pet.
In this case cat extends pet we don't have a constructor but if I wanted to have some additional information
for cat like I don't know what else to pass in.
Let's say you pass in the name and age and we want to pass in about lives left which will default to
9.
Very good to cat 9 lives.
Okay.
And here I could manually set this dog name equals name this dot age equals age but I'm already doing
that here.
So really all I want to do is set this dot lives left equals lives left and if I don't want to duplicate
that I can use the super keyword super.
It's going to reference the class that we are extending from.
So if I call super instead of here and I pass in name and age it's going to call this constructor so
we can see this in action.
It's cancelled out log in cat constructor and then duplicate this appear in pet constructor and let's
see what happens we'll make a new cat I'll pass in a number of lives.
Actually I won't and will default to 9.
Take a look in cat constructor in pet constructor.
If we look at Monty Monty has a name Monty in age 9 and lives left with set tonight so we reuse the
functionality from this constructor but we added on our own for cat.
So very important.
Super is going to be a reference to the superclass.
It can be confusing definitely trips people up but it's a reference to what we're extending from which
is pet so we could do it.
We could use it instead of dog but just to save you time and not for you to death.
We'll keep it simple here.
So this is a common pattern.
You have some base class you have other classes that extend from it.
And in this case of dog we didn't add any new properties in it's the exact same constructor as pet.
And that's fine.
It will call that constructor automatically if we don't define our own but in the case of cat which
is common when we're building more realistic things we have other data.
Just a simple lives left which you want to add on to this.
So we call super.
We can take advantage of this constructor and then add on lives left as well.
And that's the basics of inheritance.
And mean you can continue to go multiple levels.
We could have pet extend from animal.
We could have animal extend from living thing.
There's so many different things we could do and you'll see this with things like HMO elements in the
DOM that extends from like five or six different classes.
But remember when you extend something and we need to find a class it's all just setting up these constructor
functions and calling it with new and adding methods to the prototype.
So this is all just nice syntactic sugar okay.