Next up we have yet another array method that expects you to pass in a callback.
It's called The Filter filter allows us to filter out subsets of an array.
Basically we re Passing a function which returns True or false.
A test function and if an element passes that function it will be added into the returned or the result
array.
So if we had an array of a bunch of numbers we want to create a new array with only the Evens we could
filter that evens out.
It doesn't update the original it doesn't mutate it so filtering it out makes it sound like we're removing
them.
We're really just creating a copy with specific targeted information or elements.
So let's do a couple of examples.
We'll start simple with numbers.
I know it's boring concept numbers equals and I'll just type some random numbers in here.
That's good enough there.
And if I wanted to filter so that I get a new array only with odd numbers I could call numbers or no
doubt filter and I'll use a single line arrow function implicit return and is my parameter and mod 2
equals 1.
That's how we know if something is odd.
So this function right here is a boolean function.
It's what's called a test function.
At least if you look at the docs for a filter it returns true or false.
So filter it's going to start with an empty array and it's going to try thirty four and pass it into
our test function.
Does that pass.
Do we get true.
No we do not.
Because this is even so it goes to 35 that does pass this test.
It returns true.
So thirty five is added to the result and then sixty seven would be added.
And then fifty four would not be added.
And then as soon as it hits the end of the array it returns this result.
So I can save this to a variable called odds.
Let's check it out.
There's odds it contains the four odd numbers.
If we look at numbers it's not altered in any way so we're not removing them.
We're simply creating a new array with those values we could do the same thing for evens.
It'd be very simple change name the variable evens and then say num mod two equals zero.
There's no remainder when we divide by two.
So numbers unchanged but now we have evens containing the even numbers.
If I wanted to get large numbers I'll call them big numbers.
I could do num stop filter with the parameter name of and again where n is greater than How about 50.
So this will give me an array of numbers where each number is larger than 50.
To save my code run it over here we'll look at big numbers and now we have sixty seven for 1 0 9 and
1 0 2.
So we write a function that returns true or false.
If that function returns true for an element it's added into the result that we get.
Otherwise it's ignored.
Let's do a few more complex examples.
I've updated this books array to include more books but also each book has some new properties.
We have a genre or genres property which is an array of genres.
We have more books that each have a rating.
And that's pretty much it.
There's what 10 or so books in here maybe eight.
Now imagine that we're actually creating a e-commerce bookstore or a Web site like good reads dot com
where you can search for books add them to your reading list and it's a show a social network for books.
A lot of the time we want to give users the ability to search for things to search for a book based
off of a title or to narrow down search results so that they could check a box that says rating you
know a four star or greater rating or only fantasy books.
We would use filter to narrow down the results that we're showing.
So let's do a couple examples.
Let's start with a simple one.
Let's select the ratings are the books that have high ratings so their rating is greater than maybe
four point three.
So that would be concept good books equals books dot filter for B we want b to be greater than four
point three.
Let's see what we get good books.
All right.
Well that's my fault.
I'm comparing the entire book.
This is an object I need to compare B that rating.
Try that again.
And now we have four books bone which has a rating of four point for two gentlemen in Moscow.
Great book four point thirty six.
Name of the wind.
Four point five four.
And the way of kings.
Four point six five.
Okay.
So we just grabbed the highest rated books.
But again books is unchanged.
It still has nine books in it.
If a user then wanted to pivot and look at let's say only fantasy books Let's filter where genre includes
fantasy.
So we have a couple of them here in order to do that.
We'll use filter so concept fantasy books equals book Stop filter.
This one is probably going to be a bit long for a single line so I'll do for each book or that would
be the name of the parameter.
I'll use an implicit return with parentheses.
We want book dot chakras.
Dot includes fantasy.
We could do this on one line but hopes no semicolon in there.
And let's see what we get.
Run it over here.
Fantasy books we get five books each one should include fantasy as one of its genres.
So this one has fantasy.
This one has fantasy American Gods.
Bowen has fantasy and good omens does as well.
Okay let's do another example where we filter for short form books where basically it's either essays
or short stories.
I don't know what you would call those small books made up of smaller pieces anthology books we'll call
it short form so const short form equals books that filter book is Our parameter name and then I'll
do another implicit return.
We want to check if book dot genres dot includes either short stories.
Just make sure it was short stories plural or I want essays so I'll do or book out genres that includes
essays.
Let's see what we get for short form.
We have two results.
The first one is changing my mind by Zadie Smith.
In genres we can see essays.
The second one is by Richard Powers called the over story really cool book short stories is in genres
as well.
So a whole bunch of different ways to filter just this one array of books.
Think of any e-commerce website you can filter by rating.
You can filter by searching for something so let's try that.
Let's search through a title and find books that contain I don't know the in their title so to mimic
a search box let's make a variable called query and this will be coming from a user.
We don't know what it is so I'll leave it blank for now and then we'll do books dot filter.
I'll save this to a variable called results and we'll filter where the book title includes that query
and to be extra sure.
We'll also down case everything so it's case insensitive so book we'll do book dot title dot to lower
case dot includes and then I want to make sure I'm lower casing the query as well query dot to lowercase
let's give this a bit more room and honestly in this scenario this is fine as a one liner but just for
some variety.
I'll break this up so I'll use a regular aero function where I need to explicitly return something so
I'll extract this to a variable I'll call it.
Title equals folks out title or book titled to lower case lowercase and then I'll just do return title
DOD includes query DOD not local lowercase regular lowercase.
All right so whatever the user searches for let's say they're searching for Mm hmm.
Is there anything we could get multiple results with.
I guess we've got the it's quite boring but if the user types the we're going to down case this right
here and we're going to compare it to every book title by down casing the title so that we don't care
about casing at all.
Then we'll just check as each title include that lower case query if it does this returns true.
It gets added to our results.
Let's run it let's get results.
We get 5.
They all contain the phone the complete as a complete journey complete story complete addition the name
of the wind the over story the way of kings and Lord of the Flies.
Here we don't have an upper case the here we do have uppercase.
So those are some examples of using filter.
It's a great method.
There's so many applications where you need to narrow down an array to smaller a smaller portion.
Remember you're not actually updating or mutating the original but it gives you a return value that
you can save and then work with.
So I use filter all the time.
It's relatively simple you pass in a test function that you write it returns true or false.
If it's true for a given element then that element is added to the filtered result array.