In the last video we spoke about how we can put some information after the hash character inside the
URL that is specific or intended to be shared with the browser.
That's what we're going to stick our encoded string.
Now we have to think about how we're going to get the first part of the url.
So in other words everything up to that hash character to do so.
I'm going to go back over to my application.
Open up the console and write out window dot location.
This is an object that has a bunch of different properties inside of it.
That describes the current year L that we are looking at.
So we want to take this current you are L right here and we essentially want to add onto the very end
that hash character to do so we can use a little trick with how window dot location behaves when we
print out just window location by itself.
You'll notice that it is a big object but if we tried to put window dot location into a string it's
going to automatically turn that object into essentially just the current year l.
Let me show you what I mean.
If I take a set of back ticks so I want to use a template string here.
So set it back ticks not single quotes and then do a dollar sign.
Curly brace and window dot location we'll see that instead of printing out a big object.
It's going to take just the current year L and put it inside of a string so to actually get the final
your l that we want to share with a user and allow them to give to our friend and get back to our application
with the hash at the end.
We're going to do something like window dot location hound and then our encrypted string at the very
end and that's going to generate our final your l that we want to share with the user.
So now we understand that let's go back over to our editor and update the code that is going to generate
that encrypted string and toss it into the link OK.
So I'm going to update where we assign the value to the input.
I'm going to use a set of tactics
then at the very start.
I'll do dollar sign curly brace window dot location then a pound right after outside the curly braces
and then a another dollar sign curly brace around encrypted I'll save this and it's gonna reformat it
just to make the line all that shorter okay.
So now let's save this.
I'll go back over and do another test I'll put in my secret message and there we go.
I've now got the full year L that I'm going to use to share with a friend and I can see that at the
very end there's the pound and then the actual encrypted string or kind of base64 string in this case.
Once again this link right here is only going to be usable by you and me for right now on our local
machine because we have a reference to a direct file on some folder on our computer.
But again we are going to eventually deploy this thing and get a version of this link that actually
can be shared with other friends.
All right.
So I think the last thing that would be kind of nice around this whenever user types in a message and
hits create or in the enter key a user asked you click into that input and then select all the text
inside and hit control C to copy it.
So I think that it might be kind of nice or just a little bit convenient for our users if after they
hit the enter key to generate the message we automatically select all the text in there for them so
that they can very easily hit control C on their keyboard themselves to copy that link to do so we can
add in another method call on the input element that we are setting the value on.
Let me show you what I mean rather than doing that select right there and then immediately setting a
value on it.
I'm going to instead assign the result of that selector to a new variable that I'm going to call input
or then update the line right after that to say input value.
And then finally right after that I'll do input dot select the select method right here is going to
select that input and all the text inside of it.
So that's what's going to make it really easy for a user to copy the link that we have generated for
them.
So going to say this again I'm gonna go back over refresh and loops I duplicated the input element declaration
you know change the name on the second one to link input that's better and I'll change both those as
well.
Much better yet refresh and I'll put in my secret message again.
And there we go.
Now that text is automatically selected.
So I would have to do is hit control C and then boom I've got the link that I can easily paste or share
with my other users.
All right.
That's definitely a good improvement.
Now the last thing we should probably do if we really look back at our mockups over here of what we're
trying to built after a user enter some text and hits that create button really supposed to hide that
existing form right there and show just the input and the text that says sure this link with the friend.
So essentially we just need to kind of toggle what is actually visible on the screen at any given time.
So let's take care of that in just a moment.