Next up we'll take a look at two built in methods that are kind of similar.
They have to do with searching or looking for a value in an array includes and index of how they sound
like they might do the same thing but they return different values.
So let's start with includes includes is relatively simple.
It is known as a boolean method.
It returns True or false.
It takes a value and it tells you if that array includes that value or not.
And that's it.
It doesn't tell you where it just is a yes or no.
It's a boolean method.
I have an example array over here called ingredients.
And if I wanted to call ingredients that includes does it include fish.
It does not.
As far as I remember it does include a slew of very odd ingredients and not sure what you could make
this for you quite nasty.
Shrimp and sugar and flour but you can see we get false if I tried ingredients that includes how about
shrimp we get true and that's kind of it.
It's relatively simple.
It does not check inside of each element.
So we're working with strings.
You might think if I tried to search for corn it would tell me true.
But it does not.
It's looking for an exact match.
Does the array have an element.
Corn not does the array contain elements that may contain corn in them.
It's looking for a direct match.
And it doesn't find corn in here.
There's corn starch but that's not the same as the string corn.
There is one optional thing we can pass in.
You can see here called from index from index is a way you can specify where to start searching from.
So for some reason I wanted to know if let's say a water was included in the second half of the array.
How many items long is this.
This is ingredients length.
It's eight items.
So index of seven.
So let's go with cheese as our middle point.
It's not exactly the middle but it has an index of three.
So I could do ingredients that includes water after index of three and that's false.
But if I remove that it's true if I say index of zero it's also true because it is index of zero it's
starting the search from here.
I don't often use this second optional thing we can pass in the from points or the search from index
but it is there figured I should show you and we'll do one quick example where we can take includes
and use it in a simple conditional.
So let's say someone is gluten free or gluten intolerant and they want to check if ingredients include
flour.
We could do if ingredients that includes flour and we don't have to check if that equals true because
it is a boolean method it returns true or false.
This whole thing becomes true or false.
And if that's the case if it is true we'll say I'm gluten free I can not eat that.
All right.
Refresh the page.
There we go.
That's kind of it.
Next up we have the second method index of in the note I wrote here is that it works just like string
that index of so it will search for a value and if it finds it it will return the index where it found
it versus includes which returns True or false.
And just like with a string if it does not find the value if it's not present it returns negative one.
So let's try it out over here ingredients dot index of heal and we get 6 0 1 2 3 4 5 and 6.
Good job javascript.
You're correct.
And if we try something that's not in there like maple syrup I mean it should be in there.
Right.
That would be great.
I need to say Todd index of who doesn't want shrimp with maple syrup and cheese.
It tells us.
Negative one.
So it works just like index of works on a string except in the context of an array.
It tells you where that value is in that array and just like with includes we can specify a from index
you're not really sure how often you end up doing that but just to make sure let's look for cheese after
the index of five.
It does not exist but if we change that to be index of two we do get three and that's correct 0 1 2
3.
OK so two different ways of looking for a value.
It really depends on what your purpose is or what your goal is.
If you're just trying to see if something is in there period and you don't need to know where then use
includes it makes your logic short.
You don't have to check if a value know if the index equals something which we would have to do if we
were to rewrite this using index of we would do something like ingredients dot index of flour is not
equal to negative 1 that means flower is in the ingredients array.
If you're just checking if a value is present includes is easier.
But if you need to know where.
Then he would use index up and you could use INDEX OF to find you know if Flower is in here and you
wanted to replace it with I don't know what do you want a gluten free people that use instead of flour.
Do they use corn flour so whatever it is you replace it with a substitute.
You need to know where it is and then you could change the value at that index using the return value
of index of.