So we just saw how to use a while loop essentially to recreate a for loop.
We printed the numbers 0 through 5 two different ways.
And that's great.
You can do that with a while loop but that's not how I use them that's not how most people use them.
You would just use a for loop if you need to generate a set range of numbers zero to 10 one hundred
to ten whatever where a while loop really excels is when you're writing a loop where you don't know
exactly how many times it's going to run.
We don't know that we're going from zero to 10.
We don't know we want this to run exactly 20 times.
Instead it might be something like the 2048 game example I showed you or a chess game where you continue
to have your game logic loop until there is a game over and for a good player that might happen in the
case of 2048 it might happen after hundreds or thousands of turns in a bad player like when I was playing
it might happen in a hundred turns or ten or twenty turns.
So you don't code that in.
You use a while loop and essentially it would look like while not.
Game over or while still alive or lives the left is greater than zero.
So you don't know exactly how many times it will run but at some point in this loop you will be changing
lives left or you will be setting game over to be true.
A simple version of this would be to make a number game and a guessing game where we won't even be guessing
ourselves our computer or JavaScript will generate a random number from one to 10 that will be the target
we're trying to guess.
Let's say 9.
Then we'll make a second random number which will also be from 1 to 10.
And we're trying to hit 9.
So maybe the first guess we'll be five.
We'll have a while loop that runs while the guess is not equal to the target.
And then as soon as they are equal meaning that we've guessed correctly the loop is over.
So let's start by generating a target number.
So that target and that can be a const equals.
And if you can recall back to how we do this we start with math not random.
That gives us a decimal between 0 and 1 like point nine point nine.
Five point six.
And then I'm going to multiply it by 10.
And then we floor that to chop off the decimal.
That will give us a whole number.
If you need some review you can go back in and watch the video or recovered this.
I think I said this then I am not a fan of how we generate random integers in JavaScript.
This is annoying.
Many other languages have a simple method like randomness but javascript does not.
OK.
So this gives us a target number.
Let's just verify that constant log target we get six OK.
We do it again we get nine.
Now let's duplicate this and generate a guess.
So we'll call this guess and I'm going to make this a lit variable not a constant because we're probably
going to have to guess again.
Meaning that the value will change.
That is stored in guess target will stay the same.
So we can make it cost guess is most likely going to change in we guess it.
Right.
The very first time.
So now we should have two variables.
We have target and we have guests guess is not the same.
We did not guess it correctly.
So now we can implement our logic our loop is going to look like while guess is not equal to target.
So while we have not guessed or generated the correct random number what do we need to do.
Well this is the really important part of any while loop you need to eventually have a way of making
this condition false so that the loop will stop.
Otherwise you end up with an infinite loop which we've seen before with for loops is not good not desirable.
We need some way of making this false eventually so we can break out and in our case it just means guessing
again.
So how would we guess again.
We would just copy this.
We don't need light because we're not trying to re declare.
We're not trying to make a new variable.
We're trying to update the existing guess.
So now we'll get a new random and let's consoles out log guest in here each time and just see what we
get going to refresh.
And it should loop a couple of times until eventually we get the correct answer.
That's at the bottom verify it will console dot log target
and we'll put the variable target right there using a template literal and then guess and we'll do the
same thing.
All right and you can see we started with our guests being eight.
That was incorrect.
So we made a new guess.
That time we got seven.
So this was still true.
They were not equal.
So we printed up seven.
We made a new guess this time guess was one.
And that was the target.
We can see here what was printed out.
Target 1 guess 1.
That means this is now false.
And it's done running.
So we go down to this line and that prints out Target 1 guess what.
Awesome.
So that works.
I would change this up a little bit.
It would be nice to see each guess the entire way through.
So right here I'll print this out here so we can see it.
And then at the bottom I'll instead say congrats you win.
Even though the user is not doing anything.
And let's also print out this down at the bottom one more time because right now what's happening is
when you do guest correctly you're when the guest is updated correctly.
This loop does not run.
So this line never prints out so we don't see what the target is and what the guesses.
So I'm putting it down here again and there we go.
So we have six was the target the whole time.
Eight was the first guest then nine.
Then we got six.
This line is printed after the loop right here.
And then congrats you win.
And that's pretty much it for this example.
This is a really common pattern.
So if I were to break down this pattern we have while some condition
in the loop update or attempt to make that condition false which is what we did here we attempted to
eventually make this condition false.
It might take 100 tries it might take a thousand tries.
Just like the 2048 game or a chess game you could play for hundreds of moves or it could happen really
quickly in a for loop doesn't easily accommodate that a for loop is great when you are just trying to
generate numbers from one index or one start point to a stop point.
It's not as great when you have this uncertainty around how many times something will run.
So that's when I like to use while loops.
Just remember if you do not update something that has the chance of making this false you'll get an
infinite loop.
If we didn't change guess and we only guessed one time this would go on forever and that's it for now.
There is a small change you could make potentially here.
You can see I'm duplicating the guests the initial guests and this guest down here.
I could just make guests undefined at the beginning and that would work although my first concert that
log would also print out undefined here which is not what we want.
So I'm just going to duplicate that code.
It's OK.