Now that we've collected all the different test files we care about we're going to iterate through them
and invoke each one of them in turn.
And that should run all the tests and each the given files.
So I'm gonna add in a new method to my class runner.
I'll call the new method run tests and notice that we're using the async keyword here because we're
definitely gonna eventually have some asynchronous code inside so inside of run tests we're going to
iterate through our test files so we'll do a four letter file of this dot test files.
And remember that file is going to be an object that has a name property and that name property is going
to be the absolute path of the file.
Now the question is how are you going to actually execute that file we care about.
You might think that we're going to use that same child process stuff that we used a little bit ago
on one of the previous projects.
The child process module inside the node standard library is all about creating a new and separate process
from the current program that we are running.
That's not what we want to do in this case.
In this case we want to take this file and execute all the code inside of it in the same context as
our runner stuff that's going to make it a lot easier to share information between the test file and
our test runner.
Once we start to write out a little bit more code here you'll start to understand what I'm getting at
when I say that in order to actually execute the file we will simply call require on it.
So we'll do file dot name so when we require in the file node is going to find a file load up all the
code inside of it and execute all the code inside.
So that's how we're going to run all of our different test files okay.
So at this point let's save this.
We're going to go back over to our index not just file.
We've got our little test harness right here.
So after we collect all of our different files I can remove that console log and we'll do a runner dot
run tests.
Now I gotta tell you right now as soon as we run this we're going to very quickly see an error message.
That's OK.
I just want to make sure that well we actually somewhat execute the code inside of the given file so
I can go back over to my terminal and again inside the movie's dash testing directory remember inside
of here we've got that test folder and inside of it is the autocomplete stuff that we just put together
a little bit ago so I'm going to run inside of movies testing our TMG command.
And sure enough I get a big error.
Well let's take a look at the air itself.
We scroll all the way up.
We're going to see reference error before each is not defined.
So what does this error mean.
Well if we go and open up that test file really quickly inside of movies testing.
So here's the autocomplete test start just file.
You will recall that inside of here we defined the before each function or we made use of it now before
each function is provided to us by Moka in the global scope.
So whenever we made use of Moka to run our test files Moka defined before each globally.
And so we were able to call it without any error.
So the error that we just saw a moment ago when we ran TMC means that we successfully executed everything
inside this file or at least attempted to.
But when we tried to execute everything we eventually got down to this before each statement.
And that's where node said hey wait before each isn't defined.
And so through the error message that we just saw before each is not defined anymore.
Because we're not running this file with Moka again Moka is what defined the before each function.
So in other words the error that we just saw this before each is not defined that is good.
That means that we have loaded up this file.
We've loaded up the autocomplete test out J File and executed everything inside there.
So really that's a huge step.
Now really the only other thing we have to do is start to grow implement some actual testing logic or
something to allow us to write tests.
So from here on out a lot of the logic that we're going to write is going to be very similar to that
first stab that we took at testing a little bit ago where we wrote out our own IT function or the our
own test function from scratch.
Let's take a pause right here and continue in just a moment.