Next up let's do some refactoring.
So first I'd like to change what we're actually requesting.
Right now we're getting the first 10 planets and then taking the first one of those 10 and getting the
first film you RL and requesting that if we look at the planets response that we get back among the
docs the API documentation for Star Wars API.
It gives us a visual.
It'll get nice representation that's interactive.
There is a property there's a next that we can access.
It's another U.R.L. to get more planets.
So Paige set to two.
So why don't we get the first ten planets.
And then when that finishes get the next 10 if there are 10 from page two we won't keep going.
I don't know how many pages there are but we'll just do the first two to start.
So we'll keep this first request to get the first ten planets.
We'll run this code.
But then here we'll do fetched all planets.
Sure let's print out each planet again.
So for let planets of data adopt results we'll console that log planet dot name and then instead of
a film you know what we'll do is get the next you are.
Which is just at the top of the Jason we get back.
It's called next.
We don't have to look inside of results.
It's simply data dot next.
So we'll save that to a variable called Mm next U.R.L. and then request that instead of film you U.R.L.
next you.
Then we have our same logic to check if the status code was not.
OK we'll throw an error.
Otherwise we call the Jason method which takes time it's a synchronous it returns a promise we return
that promise dot then then we'll change what we're doing down here fetched next ten planets and then
we'll just copy this logic right here to print out the name of each planet.
Let's cross our fingers.
Hope it works.
Cool.
So you can see the first 10 came back right there and then a split second later the next 10 so fetched
all 10.
There we go.
And then fetched next ten.
So yeah we don't technically need to have this happen one after another if we know the pattern for how
we fetch the next batch of results.
There is a pattern we just pass in this query string page equals two.
We changed it to three or four.
We get the next page.
So they're not really dependent but let's say that we don't know what this you are Atlas and we want
to send the first request and use this U.R.L..
So we're doing one after another.
Also it's just good practice with promises.
But now what I'd like to show you is how we can clean this up.
We have some duplicated logic.
First we are doing the same thing twice checking response that OK calling dot Jason.
We do it here right here and right here then we're also doing this right here.
It's pretty much the same where we are fetching planets.
So we could just write a separate function a standalone function called maybe check status and pass
a bit long of a name but that will work and we can move this logic into the function assuming that we
also add response as a parameter if we don't want to change this.
We could go with RES and update this to be reds and Reds rez.
What we'll do is pass this in to our dot then dot.
Then check status in parts so it doesn't matter if we have a named function that we have.
Well this isn't technically a named function but it's in a variable.
Slight difference.
That doesn't matter if we pass in a predefined function or an anonymous function.
The promise when it's resolved will be resolved with a value.
This function is called and that value will be passed in.
So why not move it out so we can clean up our code and not have to have these long dot pens with anonymous
functions.
We can replace this here as well dot then check status and pass as long as we return a promise which
we are.
We were already doing that.
So I just moved it out.
Let's see if it still works.
Refresh.
We got the first 10.
We got the second 10 call.
So this is a pretty good improvement but wouldn't it be nice if we could do something like this then
if we had this here fetch planet dot then check status and pass DOT then print planets then get 10 more
planets and then we could just duplicate this as many times as needed.
So what if we had a method or a function to print planets.
That's easy enough right.
What about getting 10 more planets.
Well it's relatively straightforward but there is one caveat.
In order for those documents to work they all need to return promises and something like printing a
planet or ten planets probably won't return promises.
But let me just show you what we could do.
So I'm going to start by defining a function called Print planet's
and we'll just have it expects some data the same data that we are expecting here I'm going to move
this logic out.
I'll replace the console log with loaded 10 more planets or something like that and then for each planet
of data that results.
We still consider log the planet name so I should be able to do a dot then print planet but then we'll
run into an issue here.
We should see the first ten planets print out let's verify.
There we go.
Then we get here.
Cannot read property next of undefined.
That error is coming from this next U.R.L..
That's what we're trying to get the next to our l equals data dot next.
Well there is no data that was passed in.
We never called this ourself.
Remember how then works.
It's run when the callback is run.
This callback is run when a promise is resolved but there's no promise being returned from print planets.
The only way we can change all of these together is if we return a promise.
So check status and pass that returns a promise.
This is a promise here.
This method returns promise itself.
We return that promise.
Print planets does not return a promise.
However we can fix that.
It's nice and easy.
We have a couple ways of doing it.
First the most obnoxious way would be new promise and go through the whole thing we've seen before.
So we have resolve and reject and we just want this promise to be resolved.
We've printed them we're not doing any checking of logic or error handling.
We just want to automatically resolve so we could do this concept.
I don't know.
P equals new promise resolve comma I reject.
And then we can just call resolve and return p.
So we have an automatically resolved promise that we're returning.
And what does not like missing a friend.
I forgot my arrow from doing an arrow function.
Now let's see what happens.
I'm returning a promise so we get our first 10 and then the last thing I need to do is make sure I resolve
with the data that this dot then callback is expecting.
Right.
We need to pass that data along.
So I would just do resolve data.
That's what we have here.
It's being passed in to print planets.
We use some of that data.
We print it out now.
I'm creating a new promise and resolving it with that same data and I'm returning that promise.
This is kind of clunky but it does work but there's an easier way.
There is a method called Promise dot resolve and this will create a brand new promise for you that is
resolved so we don't have to go through any of that stuff.
We can just return promise not resolve with data.
So then this returns a promise.
Which means I can change on a date.
Then afterwards and I'm resolving it with some data.
The same data we had passed in.
So I'm just passing it through again.
I'm not changing data.
It's being passed from check status in parts to this.
Then call back and then we're using it.
Passing it along as we resolve this promise which only exists to keep the chain of events moving.
Then we have this out then which we could turn into its own function as well.
So why don't we pre factor this.
We're doing the same thing.
We'll just do dot then print planet's does it work still do we get both sets printed out.
Yep.
Looks good.
So now what we could do is make another function called fetch more planets.
Or how about fetch next planets
and it will expect a U R L to be passed in and if we're expecting a U or L rather than the entire data
we could just do this data next and data.
Next is that you are all that we want to go back.
That's the euro.
So I'll just resolve with that value.
If all we want is that next U.R.L. instead of the next dot then callback.
That's what I'll do.
And this will simply return fetch of you.
So kind of simple not doing anything crazy.
I'm just putting a name on this function instead of using an anonymous function here.
So I should be able to just change this to fetch next planets and let's see if it works or returning
a promise.
We get our first 10 Hey and our second 10 looks get already very short neat and easy to read adorable
code and we could duplicate this as many times as we wanted.
All right if I want to get three pages I would print the planets and then fetch more planets check their
status and print those.
So now I should get 30 results awesome first 10 next 10 final 10 and we could even use fetch next planets
here instead of calling fetch if we wanted to.
It's not really going to make a difference for us but we could start we could do this.
Have you RL default to this.
You are well that should be the very first place you look for planets.
If you don't pass anything in and now I can just call fetch next planets with no argument.
This returns a promise returning fetch of this you are l if I don't pass an argument in that then all
of these other ones right here fetch next planets fetch fetch.
Next planets they will be past the specific you are out for page two or three or four and we should
be good to go.
Let's make sure 10 20 30.
Okay.
So nice little refactor.
Look at how adorable this is.
Super clean and easy and if I wanted to fetch a hundred pages of Planets I don't think there are that
many.
And the API would probably get pissed at me but if I wanted to my code would not be any harder to understand.
It would be longer but it would still remain completely flat compared to doing it like this.
It would be a nightmare to try and keep track of.
So that is why Fetch is so much better than X chars except Mal H TTP requests.
Also this is just a mouthful to repeat.
Fetch.
Much easier to say out loud.