Well I think that we both understand exactly how this autocomplete widget is going to work in general.
At least how we're going to interact with it.
So let's start writing out some code.
The first thing we're going to do or the first step is to just show a plain text input to the user.
Anytime a user types inside there we're going to initiate a search of our API and try to find some corresponding
list of movies.
So to get started I can go back over to my code editor and find my index dot each time I'll file at
the very bottom.
I'm gonna find a div inside of here with the class of container you and I are going to add all of our
each team l inside of this div the other each smell that you see right above it is responsible for just
showing the header and we're not going to have to mess with any of that stuff at all for this entire
application.
The inside of that container I'm going to add in an input element.
That's pretty much it.
That's all the asian all we have to add for right now.
Well then go back over to the index dot J.S. file and inside of here we'll add in a little bit of code
to select that input element that will add in an event listener and we'll say that anytime a user types
inside there we're going to run our fetch data function and try to search for some particular movie
so at the very bottom of the file I'm going to delete the fetch data function call because we no longer
want to search the API automatically when our application first starts.
Well then select my input and assign it to an input variable they'll say document dot query selector
input like so then I'll add on my event listener so I'll do an input dot add event listener.
Now we're going to watch for the input event the input event is triggered anytime that a user changes
the text inside that input and that's exactly what we want and as the second argument I'll put in my
callback function that's going to be called with some event object.
So now remember we can get access to that change text by referencing event not target not value that's
going to be whatever the user just typed into that input.
Now if we want to try to search the API we can take that variable right there and pass it as an argument
into fetch data we can then do a little bit of work on fetch data to make sure that it receives an argument
and he uses that as the query string or as the query for a search of the API so inside of my event listener
I'm going to call that data with the value from the inputs Well then make sure that I receive that as
an argument to this function.
So I call that.
How about search term like so and then we will make sure that we pass that in as a parameter right now.
Remember that we refactor this prams object to look up details about a very specific movie.
If we want to look up a collection different movies or do an actual search then instead of an S param
right there or something that I presume we will replace it with an s.
And that's just straight from the documentation that we are looking at.
We can go back over really quickly if you want to and look at the search documentation if we want to
do a search.
We're going to add in an S parameter so then instead of searching for that very particular movie I.D.
will instead search for search term and that should be at so let's say this file.
I'll go back over again to refresh the page I see my search input.
I'm also going to open up the network tab inside of my chrome console so that I can see all the different
requests that we're making to the API.
If I want to see only the requests that are javascript code or issuing we can click on the XY char button
right here and that's going to filter by just requests that are being created from our javascript code
well then start to type inside of your ad and we'll see what happens.
It's going to search for Avengers event.
Jurors like so okay.
As soon as I started typing I saw a collection of different requests being issued.
If I go to the very last request that was made I can click on it.
I'll see the query string right there inside the URL says s equals Avengers all right.
That's definitely good.
And if I click on preview I'll see that I definitely get some search results for the Avengers movie.
Perfect.
Well it definitely looks like it's working out pretty well so far but there's just one little issue.
We're doing a search of the API for every single key press.
Is that a problem.
I would say yes.
This is not really ideal.
The reason this is not ideal is that you and I only get to access the API 1000 times per day.
So we've got a hard cap on the number of times we can reach out to search for the Avengers.
I made a total of like twelve requests or so.
I even made a little typo in there which means I had to make an additional three requests or so as I
fix the typo so I just ate up 12 out of my 1000 possible requested I get to make for the entire day
with that one single query.
So what would be kind of nice is if we said Okay as soon as the user stops typing for a little bit of
time then let's go ahead and do the search automatically.
So in other words if I type out Avengers and then just sit here for like half a second and don't type
anything more let's make a request then as opposed to doing a request for every single key press that's
gonna be a little bit of complicated logic.
Let's take a quick pause right here and figure out how we will implement that in the next video.