In this video we're going to set up a project that we wrote earlier on INSIDE the course and get it
ready for doing a little bit of testing.
So attached to this video you're going to find a zip file called testing 0 0 8 app.
Make sure you download that file.
The project inside of here they were going to run some tests for is the movie comparison application
that we worked on a little bit ago.
Now if you skipped over that app don't sweat it.
I'll show you exactly how this thing works.
If you already wrote the app and you saw the source code from it I still recommend you grab the zip
file attached to this video just so you know that you're using exactly the same code as I so once you
grab that file and extract it we're gonna take that folder.
We're going to open it up inside of our code editor.
Now just really quickly I'm going to take that folder and drag it into my little workspace directory
right here.
That's totally optional at the end of the day.
All you really have to do is open up that file inside of your Ed it's going to change over to that new
folder
and I'll open up my code editor inside.
And then finally I'm going to go over to my browser.
I'm going to open up a new tab and I'm going to drag and drop the index dot HDL file from that folder
we just downloaded and open it up inside my browser.
So this is what we should see.
So make sure you see something like this right away.
I want you to type in this little search input.
Try putting in something like a come new movie title.
I'm gonna put in Avengers like so and very shortly after I do that I should see some output like this
appear.
If you don't see any output like this it means that there is a little error with the API key that I
included inside this project.
This project is using an outside API to get the list of movies to display on the screen that API key
that is included has a daily cap on the number of requests that can be issued.
So if you try to make that request and you don't see anything occur you can open up your console refresh
the page try to search for that movie title again and if you see an error right here that says something
specifically like a 400 error or a 4 or 1 or 4 or 3.
That means that there is likely something wrong with the API key that is told OK I will show you how
to generate your own API key to use inside this project.
Let's first take a very quick pause we'll come back the next video in the next video.
I'm going to show you how to generate that API key if you need one.
And we'll also do a very quick overview on how this application works.