We've now proven that we can execute all the code inside that given file.
Now at this point in time we've been toggling back and forth a little bit between the autocomplete or
that movie's testing directory and our actual project that we're working on right now.
I'm sure all this tapping back and forth is getting really confusing.
So in this video I want to very quickly assemble a new sub project just for the purposes of testing
inside of our team directory just so we don't have to flip between code editors back and forth back
and forth which like I said really confusing really quickly so inside of my team's directory I'm going
to make a new folder called sample project inside of here.
We're going to write out a very quick little program right one or two tests for it and we're going to
try to execute those tests using TMG.
So sample project is literally a sample project not really related to TMG.
It's just so we can have something that we can run Tumi with.
So inside of sample project and create a new file called index dot J.S. then inside of here I'll do
a module dot exports I'm going to export an object and just like we had on our first expand or our first
experience with testing we'll just define a very simple for each function inside of here and then eventually
write some tests around it so just like before or for each functional be called with some array and
some callback function to run for each element inside their WE'LL DO A SIMPLE FOR of loop.
So I'll say for let element of error let's call the function with that element.
We're not even going to worry about the index or anything like that.
Just some very simple test code right here then inside of my sample project I'll make another new folder
called test and inside of that test folder I'll make a file called for each.
Let's do the capitalization correctly dot test dot J.S. so inside of here we will write out a very quick
test that is going to use the same kind of syntax as what we saw previously with Moka.
So at the very top I'm going to require in for each
from up one directory index all then defined in its statement and I'll say something like it should
sum an array
and then inside of that function that's going to be ran for this test.
We'll put our actual testing code.
So let's create like a little array of numbers.
I'll say numbers is 1 2 3.
I'll make a total set it to 0.
Well then do for each with numbers we'll pass in our little iterator function that's going to take every
value and we'll say total plus equals value.
And then finally at the very bottom we need to make an actual assertion and say whether we're not our
code ran successfully so we can either do that classic if statement and say like if total does not equal
6.
There were an error but instead let's use that a cert module that we've seen several times now that
the very top I will require in a cert
that we can call a search dot strict equal and I will put in the actual value that we got which is total
and what we expect it to be which is six so this right here should work successfully with Moka and we're
going to make sure that it will work successfully with our test run a really quickly as well it's going
to go backwards my terminal I got change back to the TMT directory so we can stop messing around with
movies testing Here's Tumi I'm going to change into sample project
and if you installed Moka earlier inside this course with me you should now be to run Moka and have
that run the test inside there if you didn't install Moka don't sweat it if you run smoke and you see
something like Moka not found or something don't sweat it I just want to prove that there is a valid
test inside that file so now we want to see something very similar when we use our TNT program as well.
So I want to be able to run to me and see that same kind of test output appear naturally right now we
still see an error that says something like it is not defined as we made use of the IT function so that
test file but is not actually defined inside their okay.
So now we've got a much better testing harness to make use of another quick pause right here come back
the next video and figure out what goes on as we start to run each of our different test files.