Next up we'll make it a little tiny game where we have a player a little sprite of a guy walking in
a coin.
We're going to move the coin somewhere randomly on the screen and we'll use the arrow keys to make our
little avatar walk and pick up the coin at which point the coin will move somewhere else and you'll
keep moving towards the coin.
I guess it's a commentary on the pursuit of wealth and never being fulfilled.
And there's always a new coin to go chase.
OK.
So to do this we're going to take advantage of some of the key events we just learned.
We're going to use the arrow keys to move our little avatar.
And I've given you a starter code.
There is a folder that you can download called cone games starter.
It has the two images one for the player one for the coin and in the app yes.
It also has a function that I've given you just so that we don't have to spend too much time trying
to write this logic it's logic that will detect if two elements on the DOM two divs or images or whatever
are overlapping and we'll use that to figure out when the avatar is actually touching the coin and then
we can move the coin.
So this is straight from I think I found it on stack overflow and adapted it a tiny bit.
It's just kind of annoying to type ourselves.
And it's also the kind of thing that if I had to do this I would just Google it anyway which is what
I did.
So I'll be transparent about that.
I didn't write this from scratch just modified it.
And what we're going to do to start is just make it so we can move our player.
And I'll tell you now that to make a game a real game that performs well you would want to use canvas
in the browser which we're not going to talk about at least right now.
We're gonna just focus on the key events and we'll move the player by adjusting CSF properties top and
left.
So I'm going to start by selecting that image which has an idea of player.
So we'll do document that get.
We'll do query selector.
We could do get element by D2 we want just regular query selector.
The idea is called player cost player image or just player equals or how about Avatar.
And we also want to add an event for a key press or a key down or key up.
But we don't want it to be on one of these elements.
We we want to be able to just press a key like the Left Arrow the up arrow anywhere and to do that we
can attach it to the window and key press is not going to do what we need it to do here in most browsers.
Arrow keys are not considered key presses.
So we'll do key down or key up let's do key up for now we'll add event listener for key up function
we'll use the event object.
And why don't we console that log event key we'll refresh the page I'll open up my console and I'm going
to hit the down arrow.
There we go right left up.
Cool.
So we have those four different arrows that we want to work with.
Those are the keys that we care about event dot key.
And let's just take one of them.
Let's start with down.
So when you press down we want to add to the image or the avatar style so Avatar dot style dot top and
I could just hardcoded right now to be like two hundred pixels.
The initial C.S. s has top at one hundred.
So if we set it to two hundred it will move downwards.
And right now I'm doing this just whenever you press any key at all.
I'll refresh the page and I'll hit down or write.
And it does move down but only the first time every other time it's just being reset to two hundred
pixels.
So this is where it gets kind of annoying if you're not using canvas.
What we need to do is figure out the current value whether it's 200 or 100 or some other value.
But this is a string.
So we need to remove the pixels.
We want to turn that into an actual number like two hundred.
Then we want to add some amount let's say we're adding 50 pixels then we want to take 250 and turn it
into a string.
Then we want to take that and add p x and use that to update Avatar dot style dot top.
So what I'm going to do is probably make a separate function we'll call this concept extract.
Mm hmm.
What do we want to call it extract position and we'll pass in a string.
We'll call this pause and to use it.
We would do something like this extract pause of and then Avatar dot style dot top.
And that would be something like two hundred pixels.
And we want to get two hundred back from this function.
So we'll start by getting rid of the P X and we can use slice to do that.
If I have two hundred P X dot slice and I go from zero to negative 2 I'll get rid of those last two
characters even if my string is a lot longer we'll just remove the last two we're not actually removing
it but we're creating a new string.
So we'll do that here pause dot slice zero comma negative 2 and then we want to make sure that we turn
this into a number and to do that we can do pass int
and let's just copy this over here let's make a variable called pause equals three fifty P x and then
call pass it of that pause position we get three fifty if we set pause to be something larger p x and
run that again we get a number.
Okay so we want to return this and I think I'll just do an implicit return on a single line like that.
So now we have that function extract position and we'll save that to a variable const current top and
then we'll just take it current top we'll add in let's say 50 and then we want to add pixels the string
p x so what I'll do is set Avatar DOD style dot top to be current top of the string interpolation here
with a template literal current top plus 50 and then P x outside of those brackets and that should do
it for me.
Let's see now this is going to fire every time I press any key.
Mm hmm.
Does not seem to be working the way I'm expecting.
Let's take a look.
So we have our image.
Let's see what Avatar style dot top is.
Let's console that log Avatar dot style dot top every time I press the key
I'm not getting anything.
So is this returning Avatar dot style dot top.
OK.
So here's what's going on figured out our issue initially on our image the very first time it loads.
We don't have an inline top set so even though we have it set and see assess I actually went over this
in hopes of preventing these issues for you guys early on in the DOM sections and then I completely
forgot about it here.
So what's going on is that avatar that style about top initially is an empty string and when I'm trying
to extract a position from that we're getting not a number.
And then every time after that we're working with not a number which is not working well.
You might think that we could do this give a default value if position is not passed in or if it's empty
string or undefined set it to be 10 pixels will extract 10.
Or we could do zero pixels and turn that into just zero.
The problem is that if I tried out those default parameters don't run.
If I do extract position of an empty string it doesn't work.
If I passed in nothing while we're not returning anything.
So that's a problem.
But if I do return something
I would get zero.
But if I pass an empty string and we still get not a number.
So this default parameter won't work.
What we could probably just do.
It's kind of clunky.
It's not that bad.
Say if not position because an empty string is still false see even though it won't trigger a default
parameter value will simply return zero.
So if currently Avatar does style dot top is an empty string then we'll return zero and then use that.
OK.
So that should work better for us and then we're setting Avatar style dot top.
Using that let's make sure though double check and I'll refresh the page and it looks like it's working
on our time okay cool.
So now let's make it so it doesn't do this every single key that is ever pressed.
Let's make sure it's only if event the key is equal to erode down.
This is moving us down.
I did do some research and figured out that in Internet Explorer the arrow keys are actually just left
right up and down instead of arrow left arrow down.
So we could account for that as well.
We would just need to do if event Ducky equals arrow down or event at key or e dot key equals down then
we'll run this code where we're adding to the top.
So adding more pixels to the top moves us down.
Let's get the other direction going.
So else if event at key equals arrow up or e dot key equals up for Internet Explorer and edge we'll
do something similar and we can refactor this later we'll just do some very explicit long code.
We'll get the current top and then we'll set the avatar dot style dot top to just subtract 50 pixels
let's test it out refresh.
So I'm going to hit down I'll hit up I'll hit right.
Nothing happens.
Left.
So that's working pretty well.
There is one issue with the work around I added in for the very first time we pressed the key and when
it hit down we actually move up and that's happening because my initial style for the top is one hundred
pixels and then left is 10 pixels.
So I could either go to my app J.S. and change this instead of returning zero.
We could return one hundred.
So we're matching with the current top is.
And let's see if that works.
I'm gonna hit down.
There we go.
So we don't have that issue anymore.
Okay.
So we've got up and down.
Now how about left and right.
Well it's the same idea but we're gonna have to change it up just a tiny bit.
So let's duplicate our else if and let's do if the user hits the oh let's do the right arrow so right
arrow or if key equals right for those windows browsers or Microsoft browsers we don't want the top.
We'll get the current left and we want to extract that number from Avatar style dot left and then this
is gonna be annoying again.
We're returning one hundred one and I just say the original left is also one hundred.
So we're in sync and then we'll set Avatar dot style dot left equals current left plus fifty and then
one more we want an LC.
If we don't want an.
Else because we have a million other keys that could be triggering this.
We only want this group of four so else is not what we want.
This will be a left arrow and we'll check if it equals left and then we'll do current life.
That's the same.
We'll just subtract and we'll cross our fingers.
Let's see.
So I'm going to hit the right arrow in the left arrow.
It's not working.
So what's going on.
Event up key equals huh.
Well that was one of the dumber things I've ever done.
That's a complete lie.
I've done far dumber things but this was very silly.
Hopefully you've caught it before me.
Arrow down arrow up.
This needs to be arrow right.
Not right arrow.
And then same thing here we need arrow left.
All right.
Let's try again.
Hey I can move.
I can go down.
I can go up.
All right.
So one fun thing we can do is make it so that when we're moving to the left our image is facing to the
left.
And to do that I can just show you here if we do image that style.
Have it selected dot transform.
And we set scale to be negative one comma one up image is not defined.
That should have an avatar.
Try that again.
We're now facing left.
So we've scaled the image on the x axis.
If we pass negative one it basically flips the image and then to go back the other way we would just
go scale one comma one so we could just copy this.
And when you're moving to the right.
Well let's start with the left.
When you move to the left we'll set Avatar dot style dot transform to be scale of negative 1 come a
1.
And then when you move back to the right next time we'll go back to one comma one refresh.
I'll go down to the right and stay the same left.
We're now facing the correct direction.
So obviously this movement kind of sucks it's based off of having to press the key over and over and
over.
If I just hold one of the arrow keys it's not going to do it for me and that's OK.
This is not really how you would build a game for the most part.
I mean this could be a little demo but you would use canvas.
You would use some library to help you out with physics where you had coordinates.
So it's a lot easier.
But this is a good enough demo.
So why don't we figure out now how to move the coin to a random place on the page and then when you
touch that coin will move the coin again.
So to move the coin why don't we just make a function to do that.
We'll call it const move coin equals.
We don't need any arguments.
I guess we could pass in the thing we're trying to move but we'll just do move.
Coin will select the coin why have it selected.
No.
So const coin and I think I'm going to select this up top with our avatar equals document that query
selector with the idea of coin then down here.
We'll want to pick a random position to move that coin to and then move that going to it using top in
left.
So we'll pick some random numbers based off of window dot inner height which we saw sometime in this
course already a couple videos ago.
If I call window dot inner height or let's do it or with it tells me I have nine hundred twenty eight
pixels of will I shrink that down more and call it again.
Now it's one seventy five.
So we don't want to move the coin somewhere way off the screen if the window is not large enough because
you could have a large screen.
We don't want to do.
What is it body window that screen.
We don't want to use this because this is the available width for the window on my monitor It's 1920.
But I might only have one hundred something pixels available.
So we'll use those window dot enter height and I'll do a math at random.
We'll multiply it by window dot enter height and I'll floor that.
So we'll get a whole number and we'll save that to a variable called for doing height.
We'll call that y and then duplicate it make another variable called X math that random window dot enter
with.
So we have those two variables.
Now I want to take the coin and do coin dot style dot top equals and then I'll do a string where we
we don't even have to do a query string.
We could use concatenation and just plus sine pixels at the end.
But I'll do string template literal so for the top we want why this is based off of the height so height
p x and then for the left we'll do x p x and let's just try calling move coin from over here.
So move I mean make some more space here.
Move coin.
Let's see if it works and it appears to be working.
Okay.
So we're moving the coin around.
I'm sure you know it's not perfect our logic may end up moving it off the screen at some point but it's
simple enough for now.
So that moves the coin.
Now all that's left to do is to initially move the coin at the beginning when our code runs so we can
just put that somewhere maybe put our function definitions so we could just call that early on.
So we could just execute that and move coin at the beginning so that when you refresh the page the coin
is somewhere else and then we'll move to try and go get it and nothing's going to happen.
So the last thing to do is figure out when we've collided which I've thankfully given us a nice helper
function that computes that it's called is touching and all we do here inside of this event listener
after we've moved the the avatar.
If necessary we can just check if we want to check is touching that function that I gave you we'll pass
in the Avatar and that coin.
And if that's the case we'll just call move coin again.
So if this returns true we pass in two items it returns true if they are touching then we'll call move
coin.
Let's try it.
OK.
So so far it's touching has been called a couple of times but we're not actually touching it but there
we go.
It moved.
Let's try again.
And it appears to be working so very very entertaining game but it's kind of fun.
It's a little demo here and we get that fancy change of direction.
We're halfway to like a very basic basic game except we don't have anything fun.
All right.
So if you wanted to you could definitely refactor this a bit with the arrow down arrow up arrow right
arrow left you could consider making an object to hold the different functions to call you could make
a function called Move left move right move up move down.
That could be kind of fun.
So here's one option I'd make a couple of different functions called move up or we could even just call
this move vertical and then we'll take the thing.
So we'll call it element and then the amount
and what am I doing.
I want this to be an error function.
So we'll do that.
And we would call this for example here if we're trying to move down we would do move vertical pass
in our element that had moved.
Let's just go with Avatar and then positive 50 and then here to move up we could pass in negative 50
and we would basically move this logic in here.
So for move vertical we're going to do instead of Avatar.
We'll do element which is the parameter name.
So this could work for any element that we're passing it not just the avatar element style but top.
And then sets element that style dot top to be current top plus a mount
and the moment of truth.
Let's try deleting that.
Let's see if up and down still work.
It looks like they still work.
So let's do the same thing.
We'll make another function called Move horizontal and you could make one to handle all of this but
I think this will help keep them a little shorter and easier to understand if you're looking over the
code.
So here we want current left equals extract element that style the left element dot style dot left equals
curve left plus amounts and then we'll just call it if we're moving to the right we want to add 50 we'll
pass an avatar.
Make sure we're calling move horizontal and then the same thing for the left except we'll do minus 50
OK.
Let's try it.
It still works.
Except I deleted that one part where we flipped our avatar.
So I guess I'll undo that for a moment I get too eager there.
Do it like this.
So move horizontal Avatar negative 50 and then set the scale to negative one comma one here.
We'll set it back to one comma one.
Does it work now to the right to the left.
Down up.
Awesome.
And if we touch the coin find the pursuit of money.
Have to keep going.
Maybe more money.
Maybe I'll be happier now.
No.
How about over here.
I think this is the one if I just make a little bit more.
Get that treasure.
Oh man.
All right.
Next time awesome.
So if you want some extra features that you could add definitely one would be a score count or a scorekeeper.
Just a little chart up top or even just a paragraph in each one that tells you how many times you've
collected this.
Also you could create a whole bunch of coins different coins different values give them a different
color.
You could do that with a CSX filter.
You can make some of the coins larger to make them worth five.
You could also have the coins move if you wanted to get fancier but if you're gonna do a bunch of animations
I would look into canvas to make something a little bit more or a lot more performance.
All right.
So that was mainly just about the arrow keys but I thought it'd be fun to put something together where
we're using a lot of the stuff we've seen events we're talking about selecting.
We're talking about style properties creating elements.
All right.