Let's do some practice with functions.
So in this example I'd like you to write a function called average a v g or just average the word which
accepts an array of numbers and you can assume it's all numbers.
You don't have to check to see if each thing is a number.
So it accepts an array of numbers and it should return.
The average value of all those numbers.
So in a simple case like 0 and 50 it should return twenty five but it should work for an array of any
length one hundred numbers twenty numbers two numbers return the average.
Okay.
So give it a shot.
There's many ways of doing this.
There's many ways of doing this including some functions and some helpers we haven't covered yet.
That would make this even easier but we're just gonna start with a good old fashioned loop and division.
So let's define our function function a veggie and let's give the parameter a name of array a r r so
are you can also call it names values and our main approach here is going to be loop over each num add
them together divide by number of numbers divide by the length of the array.
So we need a place where we can tally or sum all of the values we give.
We need a variable.
So I'm going to make a variable called Total and I'll start it at 0.
Then we're going to loop over each number.
We could do a for loop.
I like 4 of so 4 let num call it num or X or Val value of the array we want to take that NUM and add
it into total so total plus equals num.
So we start with 0 and 50 total starts at 0 num is 0.
The first time we add 0 to 0 then now is now 50.
So we're going to add 50 to total total is now 50 and we've hit the end so we're not done because right
now we would be returning the entire sum if we returned to total.
What we need to do instead is return the total divided by the number of elements in the array so we
can do this.
We can make a variable left result equal total divided by a write out length and then return result
or rez.
Let's see if it works.
Average of 0 and fifty is twenty five eighty five point two for this array of test scores.
We could also just return this line without a variable.
It's clear enough we're just taking the total dividing by the length of the array and that's it.
We start with a total of zero.
We loop over each element we add that into the total.
So we end up with this sum and then we return that sum divided by the number of elements.
Like I said there's many ways of doing this.
You could have used a for loop at regular for loop instead if you know about things like for each which
we haven't covered you could use that but the main idea is use some things together using a loop and
then divide.