Next up a third way of selecting not by I.D. not by tag name but by class name.
So we use a lot of classes traditionally in our markup so we can style them with CSX.
And if we want to select based off of those classes we have a special method to do just that document
dots get elements it's plural again not singular like I.D. get element by class name and that s right
there the plurals as on elements tells us that we'll get a collection back we'll get multiple elements
or we could get one element but it will be in a collection just like we had in the last video.
So what classes do I have.
I've got a class called special on two allies so I could use that.
And I think that's the only class I have.
Maybe I'll add something to my H1 here.
Let's go with class equals header okay.
And I will refresh my page to get that changed.
Now if I run document I get elements by class name of header we get that H1 notice it's in an h t mail
collection once again another array impostor.
It looks like an array but we don't get any of those array methods.
We could also select multiple.
So we have this class called special.
If we select using that class name we get two elements each one.
Once again it's an object has a bunch of stuff in it and if I select something that is not found like
the class name of chickens nothing has a class name.
We get an empty collection if I try and select based off of an I.D. We had an I.D. called What Do We
Have Maine.
It's not going to work.
There is nothing with a class name of Maine.
There's something with the idea of Maine.
Different methods different goals.
And that's pretty much it.
Get elements my class name does what it sounds like.
It's very similar to get elements by tag name except it uses a different criteria tag name versus class
name.
We can iterate over it using a for loop.
You can use a regular for loop a for of loop.
One last thing I'll show you.
It has to do with all of the methods we've seen so far is that you don't have to call them only on the
document.
If I had a very complex document let's say with like thousands and thousands of elements.
If I wanted to select one element and then further search within that one element I could do that.
So here's an example let's say I have the class of special somewhere else on my page.
Let's do it.
I don't know.
I'll just put it here.
I'll make a paragraph with the class of special and just put some stuff in there.
Refresh my page if I want to search for elements with the class of special.
If I do document that get elements by class name special I'm getting all three.
If I only want to get the elements with that class instead of this well I can first select the UL so
I could do that with get elements by tag name get elements by tag name and I want you all that gives
me a list so I'm going to take the first one from that collection and save it to a variable called you
will.
So now I have this variable UL which is an object and it has its own copy of Get elements by class name
or tag name so I could search within this well and pass in special and now I only get those two allies
that have the class of special because I narrowed it down I'd narrowed my search first to the UL I started
in a variable and then I searched for special as a class within that UL versus earlier I looked for
all elements in the document with that class and I got 3 so I could mix it up and you know use tag name
again instead of the UL you l doubt get elements by tag name and then pass in Ally and I get the same
thing and now I get three elements because there are three allies I'm not using class I'm looking for
any ally in the UL one very important note here is that good element by D does not work this way because
ideas are supposed to be unique across the entire document there should only be one element with whatever
ideas bear photo there's no functionality to search within another element you don't need that you just
search based off of the entire document so we don't have access to you l dot get element by D we only
have well I mistyped it if I type get ELA men you can see you get elements by class name and by tag
name we don't have I.D. All right so you can win it with down like that you can find one element save
it to a variable search within that if you need to and that's it for these three basic ways of selecting
get element by d Get elements by class name get elements by tag name next we're going to see a whole
new way of doing it a little bit of an improvement a nicer way of selecting where you only need one
method.