We just put together our create method and it definitely works ok but there's one little thing that
we missed while we were putting it together back inside of my users dot J's on file inside the repositories
directory.
I want you to notice that right now all of our different records have the exact same email and password.
Now in the context of saving users this doesn't make a lot of sense.
Usually every different user who signs up to our application has to have a different and unique email.
Think about this from the world of products.
If we were trying to store different products inside of here maybe every product would have like a title
property and in the world of products or things that we sell it is entirely possible for different products
to have the same title.
Think about like maybe bottled water or scissors.
There's probably some scissors out there that have the name scissors and that is just the name of the
product.
No other name whatsoever.
So we want to have the ability to support different records that have some identical properties but
we'd still need some way to identify them separately so in order to do so we're going to make sure that
every record that we ever save into our data store gets assigned a randomized I.D..
And for that we're going to create a method called random I.D. then whenever we call create to save
some new data we're going to take in the attributes that are being provided.
We're gonna add in a random I.D. as the I.D. property into that object.
So let's give this a shot.
Let's think about how we're going to generate a random I.D..
Now of course well let's first begin by creating our method.
So I'll say random I.D. This actually doesn't need to be async by mistake.
So I'm going to remove that so instead of here we could of course just like return math thought random
and then multiply that by some really big number.
But there's a slightly better way to handle the idea generation and in particular a way using the node
j asked in a library once again.
So I can go over to the documentation once more over here I'm going to find the crypto module.
So crypto stands for cryptography or cryptographic inside of here there are a ton of different functions
related to handling and siphoning encrypting and decrypting data.
We're going to eventually use this module to store passwords or at least help store passwords securely
inside of our application at some point as well.
Right now we're going to use this module to generate a random string of characters that are going to
serve as our I.D. So on this page I'm going to search for random bytes we're looking for a crypto not
random bytes so we can call this thing with some size that's going to give us back something called
once again a buffer and we can think of a buffer as being like an array that has some raw data inside
of it.
More importantly that buffer is going to have some very randomized data which we can use as the basis
for our random ideas you'll notice that the code example right here shows it being called asynchronously
or in other words with a callback.
We do not have to provide a callback if we don't then we could call random bytes and immediately get
some result return back to us in order to show you how this function works.
I'm going to go directly back over to my terminal and enter the node rebel by writing out note we'll
just try calling that random bytes function directly and see how it works once I start up the rebel.
I'll then first require in the crypto module so say const crypto is require crypto so then I can call
it crypto not random bytes and I'm going to say that I want for date bytes of data.
If I call that I then get back this buffer again it's like an array that has some random data inside
or something some raw data inside in this case because I said four bytes I get back at sixty five.
That's one byte 7 A that's byte 2 15 and 1 D so Byte 0 1 2 and 3 obviously we probably want this printed
out as a string so we can actually use it as an I.D..
So in order to do so we can once again call it random bytes and then on the end we can chain to String
x so that will give us these values in a string hex format there we go.
So this right here will be our idea.
We're going to call this function every single time that we want to randomly generate an I.D..
And as you'd guess every single time we call this it's gonna give us back a random string of numbers
and letters it's going to go back over to my editor at the top.
I'm going to require in crypto
I'll then go back down to the random idea function and write here.
I will call crypto random bytes.
Give me four bytes to string hex
then we'll go back to our create function.
Here it is right here and we're going to make sure that whatever attributes object that we get right
here we're going to attach an I.D. property to it and to that I.D. property will assign the result of
calling random I.D. so I'll say adders dot I.D. is this dot random bytes or sweet random I.D.
okay that looks good.
It's now to test this out.
I'm going to go back to my repositories directory inside my code editor I'm going to find that users
dot Jason file and delete it.
So we're gonna start off from scratch delete everything we have.
And from this point on every user that we create should have an I.D. assigned to it.
This to allay any confusion by the way and also get to delete the user dot Jason file that's inside
of my root project directory.
It's all make sure I save this file.
I'll go back over to my terminal to exit out of the node rebel.
Remember we can hit control see I'll then run node user start J.S. and there is the record that was
created.
So now we have an email password and a randomly generated I.D. If I run this again I'll get a second
user and it should have a very different idea than the first.
Yes this definitely looks good.
Well quick falls right here.
And as your guests move on to our next function in just a moment.