All right.
One last thing inside of our post request handler to create a new product inside of here.
You'll note that we've got the code right here to handle a validation results from our different validators
and just like we've done several times before now we check to see if there are any errors and if they
are are then we immediately render our form template.
In passing those errors we've got some code just about identical to this inside of our roots.
Adnan off dot J.S. file as well.
So here's that file by scroll down to either of the post request handlers instead of here I'm going
to see a just about identical code block.
So here's our sign up.
Yep just about identical here's the sign in just about identical right there as well.
So in this video I want to try to create our own custom middleware function.
The goal of our middleware function is going to be to check to see if any error occurred when our validators
ran if it did.
We're then going to go ahead and automatically send back the appropriate template.
We're going to feed in all the heirs to that template as well.
So in other words I want to extract those lines of code right there.
I want to take them out of all of our different request handlers and put them into some reusable middleware
function instead.
That's the goal though to do so let's find our roots admin folder inside there going to make a new file
called Middleware is dot J.S. so the idea behind this file is that we're going to locate all the middleware
is inside of here tied to our administration panel so inside of here I'm going to first require in that
validation result function from the Express validator library because we know that we're still going
to have to at some point time take a look at each request and see if there was an error that occurred
and inside of here I'm going to do a module dot exports and send back an object.
We're going to end up the same structure inside this file as we had inside of validators.
So we're going to export an object that has a couple of different functions so we can reuse throughout
all of our different routes or at least the admin ones in this case because of where we put this file.
Right now the only function that we're going to export is one that we will call.
How about handle errors.
So this is going to be our middleware function.
We're going to put the code inside of here that we have duplicated several times between all of our
different root handlers are then going to call that function like right about there or so.
So we're going to call that function before we actually run our real request handler and the one thing
that's gonna make this just a little bit confusing.
Remember that the only difference between each of these different code blocks in each of the three locations
we have it is the template that we used to send back to the user.
So in the case of our sign in handler we've got the assign and template in the case of the products
new handler.
We've got the products new templates.
So we're going to say that anytime that we want to use this middleware function that we're writing right
here we're going to pass in a template function as an argument to it.
So we're going to receive a function that we're going to call at some future point time when we need
to render out all those errors inside the form so going to received that template function as an argument
that I'll call template func short for function
then inside of here we're going to return a function.
The reason that we are returning a function is that all Middleware is must be functions.
So we're going to return the function that's going to be executed every single time that a request comes
in.
So I'm going to return a function that is going to be called automatically by express with the request
the response and the next function.
We very briefly spoke about this next argument much earlier inside this project.
Whenever we author a middleware function which this is right here this is the actual middleware function
that's going to be called repeatedly.
We get it called with our request our and next next is like a reference to a function to say to express
that hey we're all done with the computation we're doing inside of here.
You can continue processing this request remember Express was originally written before promises or
async await was really popular.
And so we see this idea of callbacks like next right here all over the place as one the primary control
mechanisms
okay.
So then inside of here we're gonna write all the same kind of validation handling stuff that we've got
currently inside of our different request handlers.
So we'll say const ears is validation results with our request and then if not errors dot is empty.
So if there is an area if that thing is not empty let's return early and we'll call Red Dot sent.
We're going to invoke our template funk that was passed in as an argument
and as the argument to it we're gonna pass an object with the ears inside of it so that our template
functions still get all the relevant errors.
Now we need to also handle the case in which everything goes as expected and we don't have any errors.
So to handle that underneath our if statement we will call next.
Which once again is a sign to say hey everything went well.
Call the next middleware or invoke our actual root handler.
Note that we only called next if we did not have any errors.
So if any errors occurred we're going to return early right there and we never call the next root handler
in the chain okay.
So that's pretty much our whole middleware function.
So I'm gonna save this file.
Well then go back over to product start J.S. and we're going to add the middleware to our post request
handler right here.
Let's first make sure that we require in that middleware at the very top of the file so up here I'm
going to do you can't handle errors I'm going to require that from middleware as notice that we still
have a require statement right here for validation result.
Well we don't need it inside of products.
J ust anymore because we have handled calling validation result inside of the middleware that we just
put together so we can remove that require statement because we're going to delete the reference to
validation errors in just a moment as we go down to that root handler.
Let's do that right now.
I'm gonna go down to the root handler so we don't need to run all this logic inside of here anymore.
We're going to delete that in just a second but first let's put in our middleware so after handling
the upload and passing the incoming request and after doing the validation we're then going to check
to see if any errors occurred and if they did we're going to return early before we even hit that root
handler right here.
I'm going to call handle errors and I'm going to pass in the template function that we want to eventually
call which is products new template it's all say products new template notice that there are no parentheses
after that there are no parentheses because we are passing a reference to that function so that can
be called at some point time in the future repeatedly every time that request comes in now that handle
errors is dealing with those validation stuff we don't need that validation logic inside of here anymore
and so take a look at that now that we're handling the validation outside of our root handler and handling
any errors that might occur.
Now the root handler itself is incredibly simple is just forward lines of code or so.
And so it's a lot easier to read and understand than anything that we had before so this is definitely
looking pretty good.
Now the other thing I want to mention really quickly here is why we were returning a function from handle
errors don't you.
Hopefully it's a little bit more obvious now when we actually make use of handle errors in a wired up
as a middleware.
We are invoking it to throw in the template and we want to eventually use to we're calling this thing
right here but whenever we provide a middleware to express it might be a function where it has to be
a function.
And that's why inside of our middleware handle errors we are returning a function right here.
This is what is actually getting passed into router post so that is going to be the function right there
that gets called over and over and over every time we have a request coming into our application.
So this looks good.
Let's save this.
We're going to go over to off J.S. inside of our admin directory and we're going to do the same refactor
with both request handlers inside of here as well that are handling those requests.
Well we'll do these much more quickly.
So at the top I'm going to delete the existing express validator require statement and I'll get to handle
errors from the middle where file all then go down to our sign up post requesting Adler.
Right after all the validators will call handle errors and we'll pass in the template to use which is
sign up template
we can then delete all the error handling stuff.
Like so also note that we no longer need the password confirmation property inside of you anymore.
So I'm also going to just do a little bit of cleanup right there.
Right so now we can go down to our retro top post for signing after the validators will do handle errors.
We're going to pass in our template which is sign and template and then once again we can delete all
that error handling logic.
So that's it.
So notice once again that both these root handlers are now way easier to read and understand because
we have extracted all that logic let's them make sure that we saved all these files and we're going
to go do a very quick test inside the browser so I can go back over to my application.
I'm to first try to create a new product so I should be able to just like hit create right here and
see some errors appear and yet looks like the validation is still working.
I'm also going to try out our sign up route.
I'll hit submit Whoops I've got some built in validation on this forum so I do need to put in some kind
of email and passwords bugging me make sure the passwords don't match Yep.
Okay.
Looks good.
I'll make sure that my validation works on sign in as well so I'll put in some random email and random
password.
Very good.
Okay.
That's pretty much it.
So abstracting all this stuff out into that middleware definitely worked out pretty well.
Okay.
So to get back on track we'll take a pause right here.
When come back the next video we'll make sure that we start to list out all of our products inside of
admin slash products.
So I'll see you in just a minute.