The next thing to know about promises is that when you reject or resolve a promise you can reject or
resolve it with a value and you'll have access to that value in your callback that you pass into then
or catch.
Which is really really useful because most of the time we're not just waiting on some resolve or reject
it happens arbitrarily like a random resolve or reject.
We want to know why was something rejected for example in the case of a HDP request.
Why did this fail and if it didn't fail if it was resolved.
What is the data that we got back.
That's the point of making a request at least most of the time is you're trying to get some information.
So we are going to make a fake request function here.
We'll call it const fake request and we'll pass in a new URL so we'll call this like fake request read
it dot com or something.
Or actually that's just do relative U.R.L. so slash dogs or slash log in and it's going to take some
time so we know that it's going to return a promise because it takes some time.
So let's do return new promise and then we have our callback in here.
The I think it's called an execute or function executor function on the docs at least it doesn't really
matter.
But we have our resolve parameter and our reject and then we'll do a set time out.
And how long should this timeout take.
Let's say it takes three seconds to make a request which is a pretty long time to make a request and
then our callback that goes here for set time out and what do we want to do in here.
Let's pick a random number and decide randomly if this request worked or not.
And we'll resolve it or reject sort of the same thing we've done before math out random we'll save that
to a variable const Rand and then we'll check if Rand.
We don't want it to fail half the time so let's say if Rand is less than zero point three we will reject
to start like this and then else we will resolve.
So so far nothing new.
We've already seen how to do this.
If we call fake request we don't even need to pass in a U RL Because we're not using it at the moment.
So fake request DOD let's just do it then a simple one and a catch we will cancel that log request worked
and then in our DOT catch we'll do a console dot log request failed.
So this is kind of a recap of what we already know.
It's the same idea a set time out faking something in the last video we were doing a dog promise but
it was the same thing except I think there's a 50 50 chance.
Now we have it 30 70.
So if we run this should take 3 seconds and we'll see either requests worked or requests failed and
I won't keep going.
Hopefully we get a request.
OK one more chance to give it one more chance.
All right well you always have to trust me.
Requests will fail at some point so this video is about how we can reject and resolve with a value we
can pass information in to the resolve or reject calls.
So let's start with reject.
If we reject why don't we pass in a status code.
So a typical HDP response includes a status code you've probably seen two hundred four OK or definitely
most likely at least seen for 0 4 not found.
Why don't we just pass that through.
So reject and then let's pass an object in where status is set to 4 0 4.
So now instead of our catch if something is rejected our callback instead of catch will run to we can
add a parameter and now could call it data or response and then we can look at Red Dot status console
dot log Reg status and if this ever fails let's do one second just to make it easier.
Come on.
It worked.
Okay.
There we go.
Four or four requests failed so we have access to this data that we pass through a single variable or
it's not even a variable a single value we could pass more things like reject it with this object and
then I don't know what else would make sense in this context but we could put whatever we want in here
we could also pass in to and then we just have a second parameter we could call it No.
Now as far as resolving with a value or multiple values it's the same process.
Why don't we do something a bit more useful like when we call fake requests will pass into a U.R.L..
How about slash users and then we'll use that you are all to decide what to respond with.
We're pretending to be an HP request.
We're mocking it out.
We're adding the delay.
Why don't we start with a variable we'll call this.
Mm hmm.
What should we call this maybe data or pages.
Sure it will be an object where we map you around like Slash users to some information.
And how about our users will be an array an array of objects where we have an idea for each one let's
just say idea of one user name is Bilbo and we'll just have two users in here to keep it simple ideas
of five.
Username will be how about as morale.
Okay so whatever you are L is passed in.
We will use that you are our parameter to access information out of pages.
Let's just add a second page in here.
This one will be slash about and it will just be a string of text.
This is the about page.
Okay so if you pass and slash users what we'll do is take that you URL and resolve with pages of your
RL Let's just call this data concept data and then we'll resolve it with an object maybe so that we
can include a status code of 200 which means.
OK and then we'll also include data and I'll just use a shorthand instead of data call and data.
I'll just add data so if we check it out we pass in slash users.
Let's start with something easier How about slash about Dot.
Then we'll go with response maybe reds again and we'll console that log.
Let's go with status code red dot status and then duplicate that and do red dot data which is the second
thing right.
We have status and data that we resolve with and we'll go with data here.
Let's see what we get.
If it does resolve and it did.
Status Code 200 data.
This is the about page.
Now instead of randomly resolving or rejecting let's get rid of a random number and instead will reject
if the you or L is invalid if it's not contained within pages.
So we'll get rid of all this or almost all of.
We'll just get rid of all of it.
And what we'll do here is check within the set time out so we're still going to wait a full second or
three seconds or whatever.
We'll check if the euro was in pages.
So if data right we're just plugging this you are all in.
If data we will resolve with this that we already have else will reject
with the object that has status set to four or four which means not found which makes sense.
You are all you passed and was not found in our fake or fake application.
It has two end points right now.
Why don't we test this out now.
So if I do about we'll see if that one works it should still work.
I'll change it to users actually.
And then if we try another one this time fake request it will do slash dogs which does not exist in
our pages.
So if you are Elliot's dogs this line should be undefined so this won't run and instead will reject.
Let's double check cool.
So our first one worked.
We got status code 200 from the dog then call back right here.
Red Dot data where these two users.
And then the second request did not work.
We got four or four requests failed already.
So in this video we saw that we can resolve and reject with data we can pass through some argument there.
In this case it was an object in both the resolving and rejecting scenarios and then instead of our
dot then callback we can add a parameter give it whatever name we want and it will have that data.
It will be passed whatever the promise was resolved with and then same thing for dot catch except when
the promise is rejected.
This function will run and this parameter will have whatever value we passed.
All right.
So we're almost done with the basics of promises.
We have one other really important topic to cover which is chaining multiple promises.
What if we wanted to make another request after the first one.
We have a really nice way of doing it.
So that's coming up next.