Next up group two methods together that honestly don't really have much to do with each other except
that they are straightforward and there's not a lot to talk about.
Join and reverse reverse is especially straightforward it does exactly what it sounds like.
It reverses an array in place.
That's the one key thing is that it does not make a copy.
It actually impacts it mutates the original array so I can show it to you.
It's very straightforward here I have an array called Letters.
If I call letters dot reverse like that it does return the new version of the array.
But if we look at letters as well it is changed so it used to be TCE P.
Now it's RSP easy as you can see here.
Okay.
That's kind of it.
It's going to reverse whatever the contents are.
If it's instead mixed its numbers and billions and other numbers and a string dot reverse it doesn't
matter.
It reverses it.
Okay.
Next we have join which is a little bit different.
Well you know it's.
That's a lie.
It's very different.
Has nothing to do with reverse.
It's a little trickier but it's still very straightforward.
What joining will do is it takes an array and it spits out a string where it joins.
All of the elements in that array into one single string so you can see right here.
Fire air and water three different values in this array.
When you join them together it gives you a single string so if we tried it with letters over here.
If I refresh we could do letters dot join.
If I just do it like this the default separator between the values is a comma but we can change that.
I could say letters dot join and I want you to join it on an ampersand.
And there we go TNC and E and P and so on.
Now we could combine them and do letters dot reverse dot join and then join on maybe a period and look
at that ISB T.
Or we could join on a dash.
Oh I re reversed it I can see that reverse does actually mutate the array so I need to do it one more
time to get our ISP with the dashes.
Now one question I've seen before is what happens if you try and join things that are not strings like
these are strings in an array.
We're joining them together.
What if we have numbers twelve point three and then 60 and then maybe a boolean like false.
What happens if we join those it turns them into a string.
So it's going to figure out what this twelve point three looks like as a string.
Well it's just twelve point three instead of quotes.
What's this false look like.
It's just the string false and it joined them.
So it's going to turn them into a string put them into one string and then separate them by some character
the default is a comma.
But you can specify something else.
You could even specify more than one character we could do a space with I don't know hash sign and another
space and then an arrow and it inserts that between all of them and returns a new string and that's
it for reverse and join relatively simple ones.