Let's make sure that whenever a user enters some secret message we hide that existing form and instead
showed this stuff over here.
Also inside of a kind of card element.
So let's get to it.
I'm gonna flip back over to my editor.
I'm going to open up my index dot each team I'll file it inside of here.
We're going to add add on a couple of different ideas in some choose locations and then use those ideas
to toggle some visibility on some different elements to get started.
I'm going to first make sure that my dear down here that says sure this link with a friend also gets
wrapped with a div with a class of card dash panel that's going to make sure that shows up at that nice
kind of card looking wrapper around it's also going to add on a class to this thing of hide you hide.
Class is included with the materialized the SS library that we wired up a little bit ago.
If we are on a course of hide to some element then it's not going to show up on the screen at all.
So we can now save this go back over and do a quick test and we'll see that we only see that form by
default now once the user hits that enter key.
We're going to want to take the high class off of this element and add it onto that one up there.
So that's going to hide the first card and show the second.
We should probably add on some ideas just to make selecting these different elements a little bit easier.
So on the first card panel I'll add on an I.D. of how about message dash form and then on the second
div with a card panel class I'll add an I.D. of about link dash form it's now we can select both these
elements really easily we'll go back over to my index dot J.S. file at the very top.
Right away I'm going to try to select
the first one which was message dashboard so I'll do a pound message dash form a look at the class list
and I'll add the high class and I'll do the same thing.
And I'll get the link dash form I'll look at the class list but this time I'm going to remove the hide
class.
So again just going to toggle visibility s let's save and do yet another test here refresh a secret
message hit enter and it all swaps out.
And I have that link automatically selected.
OK so this is definitely the correct behavior.
It's exactly what we want.
Lastly we should probably do from a styling perspective is just make sure that the kind of card that
we're showing here gets drawn a little bit down the screen.
Right now it's at the very top.
It would be nice to have this thing just like maybe a third of the way down or even centered on the
screen just so it's a little bit more prominent to someone who's taking a look at our application so
that we can add in a little bit of custom styling directly to our e-mail file.
So I got to go back to index dot H team email at the very top.
I'll find my head tag and right after the link I'm going to add in a style element I'm going to select
this row right here.
So going to just say select the row and we're going to add some margin on the top of it just to push
everything down by some amount they'll do it.
Dot row I'll give it a margin top of twenty five.
The H.
Which essentially means 25 percent of the total height of the screen.
All right.
So going to save that go back over refresh and that's better.
So now I can do my message and enter and I get the link Well I'd say this looks pretty good.
It's not the last thing we do is make sure that if someone comes to our application and there is some
kind of encoded string in the URL we don't want to show this form at all like we do want to show that
form.
We do want to show the link we want to show the actual unencrypted message.
So if a user comes to our application with that hash in the URL This is what we want to show to the
user instead.
All right so let's tackle that in just a moment.