We just put together our logic to salt and hash a password.
So now we just have to implement the logic that's going to take a password supplied by the user.
Add on the salt to it.
Run hashing algorithm on it and then compare the output against what was stored inside of our database.
So let's get to it.
I'm gonna go back over to my users repository file.
I'll find the create method.
We were just working on and then right after it I'm going to add in a new method that I would call compare
passwords so they compare passwords function is going to be called with some saved password that we
have from our database and some supplied password that the user just gave us.
Now I'm gonna add in some comments here just to really make sure it's super clear about the nature of
these two arguments.
So the safe password is going to be password saved in our database.
And remember its format is going to look something like this.
It's going to be a string it's going to have the hashed portion and then a period and then the salt
at the very end.
Then we're also going to get the supplied which is the password given to us by to us by a user trying
to sign it then inside this function we need to take that stored password from our database.
It has that separator character in there.
So we're gonna call split on it to get both the hash password and the salt.
We're then gonna take that salt join it onto the one supplied by the user.
We're gonna hash the output and once again do that comparison okay.
So I'll go back over so over here.
I'm gonna go ahead and call saved dot split on period I'll assign the results of that to results.
It's now results is going to be an array with two strings inside of it.
The first element will be our hash password.
The second element will be the salt so I can get access to those two elements by doing hash is resulted
0 and salt as result at 1 you're technically is a much nicer way to write out these three lines of code
right here.
It just involves a little bit of more complex javascript syntax so I can rewrite those three lines with
a single line.
By doing this I'll say const an array hashed and salt is saved dot split on period.
So again these three lines 100 percent equivalent to that single line right there.
So on the single line we are saying okay when we call save dot split we're going to get back in array
with two elements.
So we're going to d structure that array we're going to reach into the array we're going to try to pull
out the first element and assign it to a variable called hash Well then pull out the second element
and sign it to a variable called salt.
Remember that by putting the square brackets on the left hand side that equals sine we are not creating
a new array here.
Instead we are trying to do some D structuring.
So this is assigned to javascript that we want to reach into an array and pull some values out of it.
So we're going to go with that slightly more compact version because less code is usually better code
okay.
So now we've got the hash password which remember is the hash plus altered password.
It's like the purple square from this diagram.
And we've got the salt which is the random string of characters we had previously created.
And that is like the red box from this diagram.
It's now we're going to take the password that the user supplied.
We're going to hash it along with the salt that we had saved inside of our database language to say
hash supplied is await a script we'll put in the supplied password as the password and the salt as the
second argument.
And then once again we'll put in the key length of 64 without worrying too much about exactly what that
does.
Whatever happens just make sure that the number you put in right there is equal to the number that we've
got backup here inside of create
then after that we'll do our comparison.
So this is where we are going to take these purple boxes and just compare them together.
So I'm going to return the results of comparing the hash faster password against the hash supplied password
so we're gonna say do a comparison that's gonna return true or false.
It's going to take the results of that expression and just return it directly from compare passwords
okay.
So that's pretty much it for compare passwords.
So I going to save this file and now all we have to do is add in some code to our index not just file.
We're going to make sure that we call that computer passwords method instead of doing this a very simple
comparison that we currently have inside of our post request handler for dealing with a sign in attempts.
Let's take a quick pause.
Come back the next video and update that comparison right there.