Next up we'll see that we can use these structuring to unpack values from an object into standalone
variables just like we could for an array.
But the main difference is that in an array we would unpack based off of position the index.
So the first variable would be the first element.
Second would be the second and so on in an object.
We make the variables based off of the name of the property.
So here's an example.
I have an object called a runner.
I'm still going at the marathon theme we've got first is Elliot last name is Kip pro-gay.
Country is Kenya and title.
This is pretty crazy.
I was checking out his Wikipedia page and he had this after his name.
Elder of the Order of the Golden Heart of Kenya.
That's a pretty awesome title elder of the Order of the Golden Heart of Kenya.
It's a little long but pretty cool if I wanted to create variables for let's say first and last.
All I need to do is follow the same pattern where instead of an array bracket I use object curly braces
and I'll set it equal to runner and then I single out the properties that I want.
The order doesn't matter at all.
It's just the name that matters first and last.
Let's run the code and we'll see that first.
Is that to to.
And last is set to keep it.
So if it finds this property based off of that name it will take the value and stored in a variable
with the same name.
So first and last were both found and runner is unchanged.
It's still the same object.
We could also try something like about time which is not in this object.
What do you think time will be set to undefined so no error.
We just made a new variable called time it still made the variable it's just set to undefined with what
we've seen so far.
The variable names must be existing key names in the object but we can give them new names if we wanted
to.
I'll do something similar.
Let's try concept and let's grab the country but instead save it to a variable called nation.
To do that it looks like this country.
Colon nation equals runner.
So this will make a variable called nation based off of the value found in country if we take a look
at nation.
Now if I run my code over here it's set to Kenya so I could try one more.
Let's also do title will be another name.
We might want to use instead of title.
I think this is also called an honorific.
So we'll go with that title but we want to make a variable named called Honor.
RICK Okay so fine title in this object if you do find it and then make a variable with that value called
honorific.
Let's run it.
We've got honorific over here.
Yep we do.
So title it's not a variable.
Neither is country.
We just use those keys to access data from runner in a super nice short syntax.
The one other thing that I'll show you here with objects at least is that we can use the rest.
OPERATOR Just like we did with arrays I could single out country or first or last and then collect everything
else in a new variable so I'll just do a const first last and then dot dot dot others again or just
other equals runner all save.
Refresh the page.
So we still have first we have last but now I have a variable called other which contains the other
two properties.
We didn't claim we didn't unpack them into their own variable so we put them in the other variable thanks
to rest.
If I left the dot dot dot off it's a totally different meaning.
It's trying to find a value or a key rather in runner called other.
But that doesn't exist.
All right.
So that's the basics of object D structuring similar to arrays similar concept but rather than using
position we're using the property name to D structure to unpack.