All right.
And we've got our action function put together and we've seen that this args object is going to possibly
have a file name inside of it.
Let's start to move some code around and start progressing our program forward.
So to get started I'm going to delete the console log of ARGs that we have inside there.
I'm going to uncommon all the code we have at the bottom.
I'm going to cut all of it and place it into the action function then inside this code where we set
up our token our watcher right now.
If there's ever a change event or a deletion event we're just running that little console log function
let's update that and instead call starts.
So we're gonna start be the place where we start up a users program or once we detect a change or whatever
else stop the existing version that program and then restart its so rather than doing the console log
right there and delete that function and replace it with start and I'll do the same thing with unlink
as well
OK.
So now inside of action the next time we should probably do is decide whether or not we are going to
use the file name that the user provided or if we're going to default to running the index dot J.S.
file instead.
Remember that's why we made this argument optional.
We said that if the user does not provide a file name we'll just try to see if there is an index not
just file if there is we'll default to using that instead so inside of you're going to first check to
see if we have a file name being provided we can access that by referencing our export file name or
alternatively we can just do some D structuring out of the args object which would just reduce the amount
of code we write inside of here by a very small amount.
So let's try that instead I'm going to delete args replace it with a set of parentheses then add a set
of curly braces and do file name like so
OK so now we need to check to see if this file name exists.
If it does not exist we will default to using index dot J.S..
And finally whatever file name we end up with we need to make sure that that file actually exists inside
the directory that our program is being called from.
Because if a user tries to run a file that doesn't exist.
Well we probably want to show an error or something similar.
Let's first check and see whether or not the user provided a file name.
So I'll simply say about name is going to be a file name or index dot J.S. it's a very simply here we
are going to say OK if we don't get the file name we will default to a string of index dot J.S. so the
next up we need to check and see whether or not this file actually exists to do so.
We're gonna go back to the FSA standard library.
It's going to go back to my node documentation.
Remember you can find it at no J S dot org slash API.
Well then go down to the file system section and inside of here we're going to look for a function called
Access remember there are multiple different versions of a lot of the different functions inside of
here.
There are the callback based versions which is what I'm looking at right here and there are also the
promise based versions as well for our application.
We want to use the promise based version so I'm not going to click on the first access I see right here.
Instead I'm going to hit enter one more time and find the FSA promises version of Access so we can work
with this function as through a promise once I find that I'll click that link.
The purpose of this function is essentially just to check and see whether or not a file exists on the
hard drive.
It can also be used to see whether or not the user has permission to read or write to that file as well.
But the default behavior is just to see if the file even exists.
So we can use this function to ensure that the file exists before we tried to actually run it.
So let's require in the FSA module to our project we're going to use access and just make sure that
the file exists I'm going to go back over at the top I'm going gonna add in a require statement for
F S
then after we get the name of the file that we are looking for let's do in a wait.
F S dot promises not access name like so because we are using the await keyword inside of here.
We need to make sure that we mark the enclosing function as async so I'll do that right away.
So now if this name file does not exist then this entire Steven right here is going to throw an error.
So we should probably wrap that statement with a try catch statement so we can grab that error and handle
it appropriately so I'm going to wrap that with a try I'll put the closing curly braces on the other
side.
I'll say catch air then instead of here.
We don't really care so much about the air object that comes back.
If anything goes wrong whatsoever with the access function chances are it's because the user either
doesn't have access to the file or it just plain doesn't exist.
So rather than trying to interpret the error that comes back I'm just going to immediately throw a new
error right here.
That explains exactly what went wrong to the user.
So I'm going to say throw new error
and then we'll put its here something like could not find the file and it will put in the name of the
file so we can either do a plus name or alternatively a little bit better way would TV use a template
string.
So rather than using the single quotes right here are replace with back to X delete the plus name at
the end and then do the dollar sign curly brace and put name in like so okay.
Let's say this go back over to our eternal and test out.
We're just going to make sure that if we try to run some kind of file with our watch it tool that doesn't
exist we should see an error like the one right there.
So I gonna go back over to my terminal Iran watch it.
Else put in some random string for a file that doesn't exist at all.
And as soon as I do so I see the appropriate Error Could not find the file blah blah blah.
Okay well that definitely looks like it works.
So let's take a quick pause right here.
We now know that if we get past this tri catch statement that the file actually does exist.
And so the next thing we need to do is add in some code to our start function to actually run the user's
file using no J.S..
And then watch it.
Anything for changes anytime a change occurs will stop the existing process and start a new one.
A quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.