Now that we have that idea assigned to every record that we save we can start to implement some other
functions list inside of here such as get one which is going to retrieve a user or a record based upon
an idea that is provided we can do update and delete as well.
Let's first take care of get one back inside my editor.
I'll go down to the bottom of our class
and I'll define async get one.
So when we call get one we're gonna pass them the I.D. of the record that we want to retrieve.
Then inside of here there's not really any magic to this.
We're going to essentially get all of our records out of the users not just on file.
So that involves calling get all which we had defined up here.
We're then going to iterate through that different array of records and we're going to find the user
with the particular I.D. or then going to return it if it exists inside of get one.
I'm going to first get my records with a wait.
This dot get all of then use the find array helper method.
So I'll do return records not find I'm going to iterate through each record and I want to return true
for the first record that we iterate through that has an I.D. property equal to the idea that was passed
in.
So I will say record dot I.D. equals I.D.
it's now to test this out.
We're going to have to make a little update to our test function down inside of this thing.
I'm going to delete the line where we are creating a new user.
I'm going to delete the line where we get all of our users and I'll say const user is a wait repo.
I get one and I have to pass in the I.D. to an actual user inside of my user store J's on file.
So at this point you need to open up your user stop Jason File.
You need to find one of the ideas listed inside of here and copy of that I.D. obviously you cannot use
the same idea as I am because you likely have users with very different ideas.
So I got a copy that I d go back over and I will call repo dot get one with that I.D. then inside the
console log I'll make sure that I console log out user instead of users because the is variable doesn't
exist anymore.
All right.
Quick safe back over run the file and I get a user back with the appropriate I.D. Now we should probably
also test this and see what happens if we can not find a user with a given I.D. So I got to just put
in an arbitrarily different I.D. to the thing whatever just some random string of characters save it
go back over and now we get undefined which indicates sorry but we were not able to find a user with
that given I.D. gets a definite looks good so another quick pause come back in just a moment and we'll
move on to our next method.