Next up another practice problem with functions so this one involves something called a pan gram not
a palindrome not a ten gram but pan gram and a pen Gram is a sentence that contains every letter of
the alphabet.
The most famous one at least in English is the quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog so there is at
least one A one B one C all the way through C in this sentence that doesn't mean there's only one A
and only one B there just has to be at least one quick side note there is such a thing as a perfect
pan gram where each letter is only used one time but in English apparently it's impossible unless you
use abbreviations like P HD and G.
Q So we're not worried about those.
We're focusing on a traditional Pentagram where each letter can be used more than once so quick brown
fox.
What else.
Sphinx of black courts judge my vow.
Pack my box with five dozen liquor jugs.
So I'd like for you to write a function called is pen gram which accepts a sentence we can assume it
is a string.
You don't need to check to see if it's a number or anything like that and it should return true or false
depending on whether that input string does in fact contain every letter in the English alphabet.
So ABC all the way through Z and it should not care about casing.
So as an example this string right here the 5 boxing wizards jump quickly.
This is a pan gram.
It does include every letter.
It's an upper case T.
At the beginning not a lowercase t.
It should still return true.
So you don't need to manually check does it contain uppercase D does it contain lowercase t.
You can get around that pretty easily.
And then here's an example where it's almost the same sentence but it's missing the L and the Y at the
end so it does not have every letter.
It returns false.
Okay so pause give it a shot if you'd like and here's my attempt I'll define a function called is Pan
Graham and it takes.
How about sentence or phrase as tr.
String and then what we need to do essentially is loop over every letter in the alphabet and check if
that letter is in sentence.
The naive approach would be if sentence and then we have multiple ways to check for the existence of
a character.
We could do index of and we want to make sure it's not equal to negative 1.
So if we could do that and then do it for B and C and D and E and our code would be quite long.
So instead we can do it dynamically using a loop but how do we loop over every character in the alphabet.
Aside from creating an array from scratch and putting every letter in there as a string.
An easier way in my opinion is to just loop over a string so we still have to type every character ABC
d e f g h i j k l m n o p q r s t u hate w x y and z we have it now in a single string and we can loop
over this.
You can put this in a variable or we could just do for let let's go with character of ABC tizzy just
to make sure it works.
We can control that log character.
We do need to use a 4 of or a regular for loop that would work with an eye.
It's just annoying to deal with the index if we don't need to.
We'll just use each individual character.
Let's try running it is Pan gram and we do get every letter.
OK so that's working.
Now we just want to check if the butter is in sentence and as soon as we find one that is not in the
sentence we want to return false.
That means it's not a pan gram.
It just takes one letter not being there for the whole thing to return false.
So we could use index of if sentence dot index of character.
Remember index of returns.
Negative one.
If it can't find that character.
So if it's equal to negative 1 we could return false.
And then where do you put the return true.
All the way after the entire loop.
If we make it all the way here it means every character was found as soon as one character is not found.
We return false.
So down here that means every character is there.
Let's verify it refresh over here is Pan gram.
I'll pass in this string although there is a problem with this string.
We have a capital T at the beginning so I do need to update that for now to a lower case d and we get
true.
Let's try deleting a single letter.
We now get false some other letter still false.
OK it appears to be working.
Now let's make it work with all string casings.
I don't know why I said all uppercase and lowercase letters.
The easiest way to account for different casings is just to equalize them so our string right here is
all lowercase letters.
So let's make a sentence all lowercase as well.
So let's call sentence start to lowercase but remember this does not update sentence the string itself
is immutable it returns a lowercase version of sentence.
So let's save that to a variable let's call it lower cased and then instead of doing a sentence that
index of will do lower cased dot index.
So all we did was now use a lower case version of whatever sentence is passed in and compare it to only
lowercase letters and we could go the other way.
We could make it all caps and then this string would need to be a b c d in all caps as well.
Let's see if it works again.
Here is the original all lowercase it still works.
Let's make an uppercase why it still works but if that Y is missing it's false it's not a paragraph.
Cool.
There is another small change we could make instead of using index of we could use a different method
like includes includes is great but the downside is it's not supported in i.e. internet explorer.
It's a newer method but let's just write it anyway.
I think it makes the code easier to read instead of this index of equals negative one.
We could rewrite it as lowercase.
That includes character but we want to say if it does not include that character return false.
In my opinion this is a little cleaner than index of character.
Equals equals equals negative one.
It's not a big deal obviously but since includes is a boolean method it returns true or false right
away.
They don't have to do a comparison and will return False if the string does not include it.
Let's make sure it works.
It does.
We remove that why it does not work.
We'll put the Y back and remove something else.
If we add in extra characters as long as I put that I back it still should work.
We're not looking for a perfect pentagram.
All right.