Next up let's talk about using forms.
So we saw how we could use the key down key press key up events to run some code when a user types in
a single input.
But what if we want to do something when a user submits an entire form.
So let's start with a simple form that will add in.
Let's do a couple of different inputs.
We'll have an input type equals text.
What should we do for this one let's go with place holder equals credit card number.
Sure.
This is not going to be a real credit card form.
We'll do another input.
This one will be type equals.
Let's do a checkbox and let's put a label around it.
So I'll move it inside the label.
I don't need a four if I'm embedding my input inside the label.
I'll put some text in here.
Let's do a checkbox.
I agree to sell my soul to your company and we don't need a place holder for a checkbox.
Let's also do.
How about a select a select where we have different options.
If you're not super familiar with a select it's how you can get a drop down menu basically.
So why don't we pick some options.
We'll just do something boring.
Let's do vegetables eggplants and asparagus and carrot.
All right.
So I'll put corresponding values and we'll do eggplant there.
OK.
So we have a couple different inputs now and I'll also add in a button to submit this input type equals
submit and let's see what we end up with when I open it up here.
Kind of an ugly form but we have a couple different inputs.
We've got a select.
We've got a checkbox and we have our credit card input which is just a text input.
No validations and then our submit.
Now if you're familiar with forms you'll know what happens when I click Submit the page refreshes.
A form is made to take data that we get from an input and submit it or send it somewhere.
Traditionally we would submit our data to one you or some you are like Slash sign up.
So this would be an end point on our own server.
The data would be sent to slash sign up and then on our server side we would do something.
Create a new user in the database and then respond with a new page that would load.
And so you would end up going to a completely new page but with JavaScript and the rise of single page
apps and things like react in angular and view or just vanilla J.S. we can work with forms in a slightly
different way.
What we'll do is submit the form or when it's submitted we'll intercepted and say Don't send that request
don't refresh the page just to show you right now if I submit this I have to refresh to get that new
attribute if I submit this right now it takes me to slash sign up which doesn't exist.
So what we'll do with javascript is take the form when it's submitted we'll say Stop don't actually
send a request.
Don't take us anywhere else.
I just want to capture that event.
I want to trigger some javascript code when the user submits a form then we can extract the information
we want and do something with it whether it's simply to display it back to the user whatever we're doing
here or maybe we'll send the data to a database somewhere to a server but we won't actually refresh
the page we'll do it using javascript on the same page we're currently on and we could maintain a single
page application.
So we're not really at the point where we're sending requests right now but you'll see where we could
easily add that.
So there is a form event called submit.
You could attach an on submit which I don't recommend doing with any of those on events.
Those properties are just not ideal but in our javascript if we select our form let's call this a sign
up form as the I.D. and then select it and so document that query selector the I.D. sign and then sign
up form save that to a variable we can add in a form dots add event listener for the submit event and
we'll use the event object why don't I start by alerting submitted the form and let's see what happens.
So I'll refresh my page.
Click Submit.
OK.
So we get that event triggering but then our page reloads.
I don't know if you can tell that if I go back to what I had before I gave it an action equal slash.
No let's do that and we'll do method equals get.
This is a traditional form.
If I submit it now we get our alert from the event handler but then it still continues on.
It does what it did earlier.
It takes me to a different page.
So we are capturing that event we're doing something when that event is triggered but we're not preventing
the typical form behavior.
And if I want to capture the data but not go to a new page and not send a request we have a way of doing
it.
There is a method on the event object.
It's called prevent default.
So e if I'm calling my event Object e dot prevent defaults.
And what this will do when we execute it is prevent the default behavior and the default behavior in
this case with a form when it's submitted is to continue sending on your data sending a request to whatever
you are.
We specified in our case slash No.
As a GET request.
So now if we try it let's see if it works.
I click submit we get the alert and we don't go anywhere.
Our form has not actually submitted the submit event has run but we haven't actually submitted data
anywhere.
And this leaves us free to now extract data if we wanted to get all the data at once and send it to
an API using Ajax using a client side request again something we haven't learned yet.
But the point is we have the flexibility to do something with the data and we can still capture the
submit event and what's nice about doing it this way as opposed to capturing each input as it changes
every single time like we could have a key down or key press on here.
And anytime this input changes we could create a variable in our javascript that is in sync with that.
And anytime you select a different option we could immediately update that variable or a second variable
but that means attaching a bunch of event listeners.
We need to attach one here one to the checkbox one here and then one for the submission as well but
by adding a submit event listener there's just one event we're waiting for we tell it not to behave
the way it normally behaves.
And then we can extract our data in here.
So why don't we take a look at the event object for just a moment.
I'll open up my console we'll click submit.
Let's put some data right there.
Let's select carrot submit we get our alert.
Here's the event.
Notice it has type set to submit and then we have the target here.
Target is the form that was submitted.
And we also have this property called default prevented which is set to TRUE because we did prevent
default.
All righty.
Now that we have the submit event and we're preventing default let's extract the data from the form
and do something kind of trivial with it.
So to extract the data we need to be able to select the individual elements.
So we've got an input another input with type equals checkbox and then we select.
So why don't we start with the text input that went.
Easy enough.
I'll select them all.
So const what we call it credit card number.
Let's go with credit card equals document Dot's query selector and we give ideas to these inputs will
be easiest if we just do an I.D. let's do credit card or C.C. for the checkbox.
Let's go with whom I agree to sell my soul to your company terms check or something or just terms.
And for our select let's go with I.D. of veggie
and then we'll go into our app J.S. we'll select based off of that I.D. credit card and we'll also select
the other options.
So we had credit card then we had terms check.
What are we gonna call that in terms checkbox credit card input maybe just to be more descriptive.
And this was the idea of terms and then we have the veggie select with the idea of veggie.
So now we have our three inputs what we would do and here is probably just access each one of those
input values although they do differ a little bit because we have a regular input text input.
So why don't we control that log credit card input that value and maybe we'll just add C.C. comma so
we can see both of them.
So we can see what we're printing out then to get the checkbox.
How do we get the value from a checkbox.
Well why don't we start with just doing terms checkbox or printout terms and then for the last one we
have veggie select veggie select and then here we'll do veggie select dot value.
Let's see what we get.
So I'll refresh let's fill something out in here.
Credit card number just make up fake number.
Then we'll do let's do agree and go with asparagus submit and here's what we have credit card.
We got the value out correctly four terms.
We got on.
Which is the checkbox here.
I submit again.
We still get on even though it's not checked anymore so value maybe isn't what we want to use.
I'll show you the.
The better attribute.
In just a moment the better property.
And then very select.
We did get asparagus.
Notice we're getting the value we set.
So it's eggplant with a capital E..
But the value I gave as an attribute was eggplant lowercase E.
So this is what we're getting we're not getting this here.
And if we go back to our app J.S. instead of printing out terms checkbox that value there is a property
called checked on inputs with type equaled check your type equal to check.
And it's a boolean property.
So we've got false.
Now we've got Drew cool so we have our data.
We could put it in variables.
I won't spend too much time here doing that because it really just depends on what you're trying to
do with it.
But we have access to the data from that form.
But the point here is that we can stop prevent default from a form submission and then tap into the
form or to the inputs get the values we want and then do something else.
We could send form data to database or append something to page using form data.
It's totally up to you.
But the process looks like this.
We have a submit event on a form.
We prevent the defaults which I like to put up top just so it's clear you can see it's still working
the way we had it written but it makes it very obvious what we're doing first we're stopping default
submission behavior for a form and then we're extracting the information we want.