The next thing to know about conditionals is that we can nest them inside of one another so we can have
multiple layers deep of conditionals where we're checking for a certain condition to be true and we
can nest them as much as we want whether it's if and elses.
We can throw an LC FS we just nest them inside the curly braces so let's try an example we'll go with
this example I've been using in the slides of a password so let's say a user type some password and
we don't know what it is.
So that's gonna be invalid.
Just gonna make it undefined for now let's say we don't know what it is we want to make sure the password
is long enough so we would check if password dot length is let's say it's greater than or equal to maybe
6 8.
Not super strong.
It should be longer but just to make our lives easier if it is greater than or equal to 6.
We'll check something if it's not.
We'll consider it log.
Password must be longer.
Great but if it is greater than or equal to 6.
We're not done.
We also want to make sure there's no spaces in a password so we can check if password and the easiest
way to check if there's a space anywhere in there.
At least with what we know right now would be to do an index of the space character.
So that's an empty string.
There's a space and remember if it is found in the string password we'll get an index like two or seven
or twenty or zero.
If it's not found we'll get negative 1.
So if we find negative one that means there is a space.
So if password that index of space is equal to negative one that means there is no space.
We can then console that log.
Valid password
and then otherwise we can consider that log password is long enough but can not contain spaces.
So let's test it out right now password is undefined.
Let's give it a value password will be Hello Kitty.
So that is long enough but if I refresh we see password is long enough but can cannot contain spaces
and there is at least one space in there.
If I get rid of that refresh valid password now if I get rid of some of these characters it's too short
we get password must be longer.
So the main takeaway from this video should be that we can nest conditionals instead of other conditionals.
We could add in another.
Else if somewhere although I don't really think I can't think of a good scenario at least now with a
password or an else it would make sense but we could continue to nest instead of else instead of if
but there is a point where it becomes a little bit difficult to read.
If your code is super nested and there are different solutions or strategies you can take to alleviate
that we're about to start learning one of them at least where something like this could actually be
written as a single condition because in order for a password to be valid we need the length to be greater
than 6 and we want there to be no spaces.
That means it's valid.
What if we could just write a single conditional that said if it's long enough and there aren't spaces
it's valid.
That's what we'll see how to do next.
There's nothing wrong with nesting.
Sometimes you cannot get around it but you just don't want to have like five levels of nested conditionals
especially if they all have if an elses.
It just can be a bit of a headache to understand so that's nesting.