Next up let's see how we can use X years to make multiple change requests just like we did with fetch
where we refactor our code so it's nice and clean but we're still having to repeat a couple of things
over and over.
We start by fetching the first ten planets which is right here where are you right there.
Then we check the status code.
If it's not 200 we trigger the catch callback otherwise we continue on we pass to Jason that returns
a promise.
Then we print the planets afterwards and we had to work with this promised resolve right here to print
the planets so that we could chain on a dot.
Then again so we could fetch more planets and keep the whole chain of promises going.
Each one of these functions here returns a promise to rewrite this with axioms.
It saves us a little bit of code so I still have axioms included.
Change the title here x CEOs change requests we'll start by running an X yos dot get call which returns
a promise we need to put Are you are all in there then our DOT.
Then we don't have to pass.
So all we need to do after that is print out the planets.
So we'll go with reds.
Sure.
And actually if all we want is the data.
I'm just going to do red dot data.
I can use the restructuring right here to grab the data out and we'll consider that log data to make
sure it's showing up
refresh the page.
Awesome.
So now we can print each planet for let planet.
Same thing we've seen before.
Planet of data dot results console dot logged planet dot name or something like that hopefully that
works.
There we go.
We're getting the first ten planets.
Then we have that data Dot.
Next you are well if we look in our data next right there we make a request to that you are.
So it would just be axioms to get and then and here rather than passing in a string you RL that we create
we'll just pass in data dot next which is a you RL And if we want to chain on a dot then out here rather
than right here.
I mean I can do this.
This is totally fine could just copy this entire thing.
I could make a second request this way and let's just make sure that works and I'll print the data out
both times and I'll consider it like each planet name.
Does it work all right.
So our first 10 and our second 10 but as we've seen we can change then by returning a promise.
So I don't have to nest the dot then like I have here I could move this out.
If I return x yo stack Get Data next which itself returns a promise so I can put the dot then like this
which is a little cleaner and simpler refresh.
Same thing.
So that's kind of it if you want to make one request and then another request using Acciona.
We don't have to worry about parsing we don't have to worry about checking the status code.
Otherwise it's pretty much the same as using fetch returns a promise put out.
Then continue the dot then chain as long as we want to make these sequential requests.
So this happens here.
Then this then this.
So the only way we make this request is if the first one was successful and we don't have a dog catch
right now so we could add that in dot catch error.
And what should we do here.
Console dot log error.
Sure.
Something like that.
So if we want to refactor this in the same way that we created this nice chain of promises where we
just call a function each time it's a pass in a function name each time to dot then instead of having
to use these inline anonymous functions we can do that.
I think I would go with what would we call it the same thing.
So fetch next planets and then print planets and then fetch next print planets and so on.
So let's try that we can start with concept fetch next planets equals function will accept a U.R.L.
and it will default to this you are l the first set of planets that we want to fetch just like we did
earlier right here and then all we do is return axioms that get you out.
Okay.
So at this point I should be able to rewrite at least my very first exit stack get as just fetch next
planets and I won't pass anything in we'll use the default initial.
You know just make sure that part works.
We should get the first ones.
Okay.
And it still continues to work because we're not ever calling fetch next planets again and then we can
replace this with fetch next planets as well if we wanted to.
Although we will update this shortly will pass and data dot next.
The same URL that we had before.
Refresh it still works.
We get first 10 the second 10.
Now let's make a print.
Next planets function print planets equals.
And as a parameter the way that this would work ideally is that we could call fetch next planets then
print planets.
Now fetch next planets is just returning axiom stock get of that you are relevant returns the entire
promise and that promise is resolved with the entire response.
As we've seen and we're extracting the data so why don't we do the same thing D structured data here
and then we can move our console that log can move all of our code right there and then print the name
out of each planet in data dot results and then we return fetch.
Next planets again.
So now I should be able to rewrite this then print planets then fetch next planets then print planets.
There is one thing we have to pay attention to in order for this to work the way we've written it which
is that we need to manually resolve our promise return a resolved promise just like we did here.
Back when we did a similar refactor with fetch we returned promised resolve data next which then calls
the dot then that is the ensuing dot.
Then we'll do the same thing promised dot resolve and then we'll just pass in data dot next whatever
this value is will be used and passed into the dot then callback.
So if this is print planets we'll print out all the planets.
Then we return a resolved promise with the value of data dot next which is a you are well then that
is passed into fetch next planets because it's the next dot then callback fetch next planets is expecting
a U or L to be passed in and it is.
So we don't use a default.
Now we would use that.
Next you around make sure it works.
And there we go.
Our first 10 and our second 10.
So we could continue to fetch and print as many as we wanted.
Do one more round so I'm printing I should fetch and then print one more time.
You could also move this.
Each pair into its own function called fetch in print and then that would return a promise and you could
chain multiple fetch and prints together but this is pretty clean.
And if we compare it to what we had before.
The only difference is that we had to check for a status code and pass but with Xs we don't.
So it's just slightly cleaner slightly quicker and easier to use.
We don't have to worry about the fact that we get a stream back when we're working with fetch and we
have to pass to Jason and that itself takes time it's a synchronous it returns a promise.
We just get the data back when it's ready and it's pre passed for us.
So that's a brief introduction to axioms.
You will definitely get a lot more experience with it throughout the project part of this course.
We use expos in a couple of projects to make requests both on the client and server side.