[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone,
and welcome to my course Spring Framework Spring Data Model Baby.
My name is Daniel Boone, and I'm a passionate,
softer developer, clean code enthusiast and blogger.
We can find you a line on Twitter at Romanian coder or or my blogged
Romanian coder dot com have been working with Monk OTB for the past seven
years and used it with all the major technology stocks,
including java, dot net and Note Mom, Would it be is a trending technology.
In fact, it occupies the fifth position in that village.
This course is not about becoming proficient using nobody
be in enterprise spring applications.
Some of the major topics that will cover include connecting
a spring application removal database,
implemented quite operations and using mobile repositories,
managing relationships between documents,
handling that immigrations and adding integration tests for the Mongo data.
Access left by you know discourse.
You learn how to tackle all aspects off their
persistence using spring framework, and nobody be.
In fact, you'll be able to use your skills in real project right away.
Before beginning his course.
You should be familiar with my body be Java and spring framework.
Some basic knowledge of spring Boot and J Unit will be a plus,
but it's not mandatory.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to integrate mobile TB in
enterprise spring applications with a Spring Framework Spring Data Manga TV course at Pro Sight.