[Autogenerated] in this module will take a look at how to
implement queries in spring among ______ B.
More precisely, we look and understand the _______ object,
the star off today's module.
Then we learn how to create an execute.
Queries will see how to implement full text search.
And finally,
we'll wrap it up with the demo in which will implement
bongo queries in spring applications.
Before we get started.
I like to take a note and talk a little bit about Cory execution.
You can execute queries or fetch data in toys with indexes and without indexes.
Both have pros and cons, but when you're not using indexes,
you're basically forcing Mongo to perform a collection scan.
It's a document is evaluated, and if it passes your criteria, it is returned.
This results in slow searches, however, you get fast inserts and on Bates.
On the other hand, when used index is,
mongo is not forced to scan every document in collecting.
So a collection scan is not performed,
was results in fast searches but decreases your
performance for inserts and updates.
There is no magic bullet or magic recipe on how we should prepare your queries
for execution My advice is to try out various combination of indexes and see
which one works best for your particular application.
Now let's go back to the star of this module.
The Mongo create object.
The query object is the most powerful and flexible
component for Mongo crab operation.
To understand it better, let's take a look at the quarry components,
and they're free components that make up a query.
First of all, you have the criteria for filtering daytime.
Then you have the sorting definition for ordering the time,
and they have paging definition for splitting data.
Obviously, the last two are optional.
The 1st 1 is kind of mandatory, but enough talking.
Let's see a natural example.
This is how among go quickly looks like in a spring application.
We define the query using the query class.
Give it a meaningful name, Mrs by age.
Then we defined the three components that we discussed
about earlier have the criteria over here,
which dictates that you want to filter other persons whose age is greater than
18 and then we have the sorting direction in the row below.
You want to sort them descending Lee by age and last but
not least we have the page request, which were instructing,
you know, spring to give us the first page and on Lee 10 documents.
As a result, As you can see, we can define queries using this fluent interface,
and this makes reading them and constructing them pretty easy.
Let's take a closer look at the criteria definition again.
We can define criteria in a flood banner, and we have free components.
As we're here, we have the left operas,
which is the data field on which you want to perform the filtering.
We have the operator in our case.
Is this one greater than GT?
And then we have the right operator, which is the filter value,
the value by which you want to perform the filter.
In this case, it is 18.
That's a typical criteria definition looks like.
And of course, we have multiple operators.
We have a fitness for equality, is or not.
Tickles,
have filters for less than or less than and equals for
greater than or greater than equals.
We also have a filter for determining if our value is present business list,
and that's the infielder,
which have a filter that it terms if a field has
any value and this one is exists,
and we can also apply Rex patterns in our criteria,
the query object is pretty useful for defining the query.
You can look at it as the meta data off the quake,
But how do we execute this query against a Mongol database in Sprink?
That's where the Mongol tempered comes in.
Manga template is the class or component that
executes requests to among go database.
Mongo Template is a simple injectable class,
following the standard template pattern in spring.
It allows us to perform crowd operations on data it allows us to
execute commands against among go database.
And last but not least, it's very, very powerful but also a little bit low level.
So even though it might take you a while to get used to it,
it is extremely powerful,
and it allows you to perform almost anything on any mongo database.
Not that they have this 10,000 feet overview. Let's learn howto actually implement queries using some examples