[Autogenerated] it's time to look at one of the most exciting features.
His spring data.
Mongo, Debbie Life Second events are a bit underrated,
but they are extremely powerful ways to implement custom logic in key moments.
Left tackle events are hooks that your application can respond to by
registering special beings in the spring application context,
we have many life cycle events to which you can respond to.
First of all,
we have the before events as I call them on before convert
on before save and on before delete.
Then you also have the after events on after convert on after save on after
load and on after delete so plenty of options available.
Let's look at the process at how these events get cold,
where you want to save or update a document.
Usually call center safe in a model template or among the depository.
In this case, the first event that gets cold is on before convert,
and it is called before your Java object is converted to
a document by the Mongo converter,
then on before Safe is called before inserting,
receiving the document in the Devil Rays.
Lastly, we have on after safe,
which is called after the document was inserted or saved in the database.
If you want to load a document,
then usually you call a fine method on a Mongol template or among report story,
the first event that gets triggered his own after load,
which is called after the document, has been retrieved from the database.
Then we have on after Convert,
which is called after the document has been converted into a job object.
There are also events when you're deleting documents each time you call,
you move on among go template on before the fleet is called just before
the document gets needed and on after delete is called just after the
document has been deleted from the database.
I think it's also worth mentioning that life cycle events
are emitted only for root level types.
Sub documents are not subject Steven publication unless
they're annotated with at the B ref.
Also, it is all happening in an a synchronous fashion.
You have no guarantee toe when an event is processed,
it's surely going to get processed,
but we don't know exactly when that's going to happen.
All right, at this point, you might be wondering,
Why would I ever want to hook into these events.
They seem so low level.
Well, let me give you some really use cases.
First of all, if you're trying to implement cascading,
go save a life cycle, events are the way to go.
If you want to trigger some job or action in different systems,
when some persistence is happening in your system like you're
saving a document or he have removal document.
Then again, let's cycle events are great and has been a list.
If you want to implement security auditing,
then there's no better way than implementing its using lifecycle events.
These are real use cases that you will come across in applications.
All right, how can I hook it to these events and execute to my own custom logic?
Well, I'm glad you asked.
It all starts from the abstract mongo event Listener class.
This class exposes methods which we can override to implement our cast.
AJ,
you can see what you have on after convert on after
delete on after load and the list goes on,
have a method for each lifecycle event.
In order to implement our own custom logic,
we need to extend the abstract Munguia event,
listener class.
That's what we're doing here.
We're trying to create Ah, before converts non event.
We're extending this class and then we wantto
override the own before convert method.
We have the at overhead imitation, and then we get other cast a magic over here.
Last but not least, we also need to register this bean.
You can do that.
Using annotations is ending right here with that component.
Or you can just quit being in a configuration class.
Either way, it's going to work just fine.
Before we conclude this part, I would like to give you one last piece of advice.
Try to create an event listener.
Poor feature.
Don't create this generic or global mongo lifecycle listeners where
you override all the methods and at cast a magic in there because
they become a maintenance nightmare.
Instead.
Think about the future or trying to implement aren't
trying to implement cascading, then create a cascade of a listener.
I'm tryingto also add auditing,
then create another auditing event listener and register it don't put order things in a global listener because that is not maintainable