[Autogenerated] Let's discuss about spring Mongol data.
Annotations,
data annotations are meta data that you cannot toe our
classes or feels to let spring date.
I know howto control the persistence in a mongo database.
If you've ever worked a GP before the news,
annotations will fear very, very familiar.
And that's because the people working on the spring framework have done a
great job in keeping the learning curve the minimal.
And you're using some of the terminology.
I want to focus on the most important mongo D B annotations,
the ones that you'd use in 95% of cases we have at a document at I.
D at Field at Transient and wait.
There's more we also have at indexed at Texting next at
compounding Dex and at the B ref this.
Take a closer look at them and get to know them in detail.
Let's start with that document.
A document is one of the most used annotations we're working with Mongo.
Maybe we can use it on classes,
and it lets the Mongol driver know that it can save objects of type
aircraft as Mongol documents in a particular collection.
In fact,
it is very similar with the at entity annotation used by GPS
when you're working with relational databases.
But what is the name of the collection that these documents will be saved into?
Well,
if you was a document like this in the name of the collection is
deduced from the class name in our case aircraft.
However,
we can also specify the collection name by using the
collection attributes on this annotation.
In this case,
objects of type aircraft will be saved in a collection called her Place.
Very useful when you want to control the collection name or when you
want to get data on existing databases that have different names than
the ones in your classes and another case,
it's a very good practice to separate the name of her classes
from the actual name off your collections.
Every document in a mongo collection should have an I.
D field.
This idea field is unique, and it is indexed.
It's very similar to a primary key in traditional databases.
In fact, in GP, we have the exact same meditation on entities at I D.
Now decided feels in a Mongol.
Databases are usually stored as an object I deem
type and this type resembles good.
So when you're serializing and issue rising objects from among our database,
your I d feels will probably be goods now that without defined an I D.
What happens with model a number of seats,
which are properties off the aircraft class,
they will automatically get serialized.
However, if you want to control that's realization,
we can use the at field annotation as Field is very similar to
a document but works on the property level.
It instructs the framework on howto persist properties in
our objects as feels in Mongol documents.
And if you feel like this, it won't make any difference.
However,
we can use the name attribute on the ATF field annotation
to control the name off the field in which this property
is going to get stored again.
A very good practice to separate the name off the properties in
classes from the names off the fields in mongo D.
B.
But what if you want to exclude a particular
property from being persisted at all?
What if our model has some properties that it needs internally,
but it doesn't need to persist?
Then we can use the at transient annotation in this case will try to save
objects off type aircraft idea and model will be persisted,
but number of seats will not be persisted,
even if it has a value.
Also, when we dis your allies objects from Mongo,
number of seats will have a default value unless otherwise specified.
We most certainly want to execute filters,
enquiries against Armando documents and to speed things up.
We will definitely need to use index is well.
In order to define indexes,
we can use the at indexed annotation on the field that you want to index Now.
In this case,
let's assume that you want to make a lot off queries on the aircraft model.
It makes sense, then tow.
Annotate it with at indexed.
And, of course, like most of the spring date,
among connotations at indexed can be customized.
For example, we can specify the direction off the index ascending or descending,
and we can also specify if this field should be unique.
Feels that are unique cannot have the same value in a mongo
that our best collection you'll get an error if you try to
insert fields that have the same value.
For example, I D is an implicitly indexed field,
which is also unique by default.
In our case, we let unique equals false.
There is also texting.
Next we'll discuss more about its.
We will implement full text search.
Just know that if you want to include feels in a foot X search,
then you need to annotate them with at text indexed.
In this case, model will be included in a full deck search.
And, of course, you can text index as many fields as you want.
At Compound Index allows us to create an indexed from
multiple fields within our document.
Instead of creating an index for each field,
we have a single index, which is linked to multiple properties.
This is great for optimization Sze.
In this case, our compound index is based on the model in an ascending manner.
Notice the one over there and a number of seats in descending notes.
The minus one.
Over here, it's a shorthand notation for ascending and descending.
Like I said, pretty useful for optimization Sze.
And finally we have at the B ref.
If you're familiar with relational databases at tbe,
ref acts someone like a joint in our particular case,
a debrief is used to link multiple documents Together.
We have a manufacturer property and his property is off type manufacturer.
But you do not want to start a manufacturer as part of the aircraft document.
Instead, we want to link it to an existing document.
That's what added the brief is all about.
It thinks the value over here toe on existing
document in a different collection.
And when we look at the right at the manufacturer,
we can see that it's a completely different document with
its own I D and its own properties.
Relationships between documents are very important and interesting topic, and we'll discuss more about them in a future module.