[Autogenerated] we can't call his model,
complete without a discussion about mongo converters.
Among go converter is the feature used to map all Java types to and
from the corresponding mongo that are based objects.
So it's all about mapping Java types to mongo database types,
and by default, Spring is very smart.
He knows how to map most of the Java types for us, you know, so to map.
Usually these are strings object ladies,
you know, so to map java integers or doubles numbers,
how to embed objects and so on and so forth.
If Spring is so smart, then why are we having this conversation?
Well,
because sometimes you might want to change the way
that this conversion is taking place.
You might want to change how particular Java type is
mapped to its corresponding manga type,
and that's where converters coming to play.
Luckily for us, it's extremely easy to create a custom converter.
The first step is to create a right converter,
so from the Java type to the Mongol type,
then you have to create the opposite converter,
the reed converter from a manga, a type to the Java type and last but not least,
have to register these converters as a spring bean,
and this will allow you to spring application to pick these up and
use them when performing these type conversions.
Let's look at a particular example.
We have this person class with three fields.
I D.
Name and address Person is a document and address is
a sub document and by default, without touching converters,
you know,
you can see on the right how this object is going to be saved in spring,
so address is going to be any better document.
However, let's assume that you want to serialize address as a string HQ.
We have address as an object in Java,
but you want to convert it to a string in Mongo and then,
when we are achieving it from uncle,
want to convert it from a string to this address object.
That's where a Mongol converter can help us a lot,
so let's go ahead and implementers converters.
Like I said, we have to convert this a right converter and the reed converter.
When you're creating a custom monger converter,
we have to implement the converter interface.
The converter interface needs two types,
the source and the destination when we're creating a right converter.
The source is the type in Java, and the destination is the type in Mongol.
Then we have this convert method which converts an address to a string.
This is a very simple logic.
We are returning address dot Get city on.
We're concatenation gated address that get country Now in the rich converter,
the source is the string because that's what saved the mongo.
And the destination is the address.
Because that's what you have defines knowledge of a class again.
We have this convert method,
and this time we're splitting the string and there may be
creating a new address object and returning it.
All right, we have defined the converters, and now we need to register them.
We have to register this mongo custom conversions type.
So we annotated with that bean.
And here we're creating an interest of converters.
And we're adding in the address, right converter and the address,
right converter,
and then be returning a new instance of Manco Causton conversions and
we're passing in the converters that we just created.
Now we can register this being in any class which is
annotated with that configuration.
If you're using spin boot, then it can be the main application.
Plus,
else know any class identity without configuration
can Support is being definition.
When we're persisting person objects,
the address is going to be stored as a string in Mongo and as an object in Java, which is exactly what we expected.