Hey, everyone, welcome back to the bonus section, where we'll be looking at integrating Google Maps
into our applications so that we can get live information from Google about these places.
Now, in order for us to do this, we're going to be using something called Firebase Functions, which
enable us to run a mobile backend without the need to manage servers, meaning we're going to be deploying
code that's going to run on the cloud in Firebase.
And it's going to expose to us an end point from which we will receive information that comes from Google.
Now, you can read up on firebase functions over here and in actuality, what it basically is, it's
a little piece of code that's going to run on a server and it's going to do an API call for us to Google
in order to do our search and retrieval of information.
Now, a very, very important note we need to make here.
Very important for this portion of the course.
We are going to be upgrading from the free plan to the pay as you go plan, which also has free limits.
It has free limits, up to two million invocations a month, 400000 requests of gigabits per second.
Now, the free tier does not allow us to run functions unless we use node version eight.
This is a big limitation as node has moved way beyond and will potentially later on be removed.
So we want to be able to use Firebase in a way that allows us to deploy these functions properly.
This means you will have to update your plan to pay as you go and means you need payment information.
And the same is true for Google Maps in order for us to use Google Maps.
There is a pay scale.
It is pay as you go.
Now, Google Maps also has a free amount of requests.
You can do up to 200 dollars per month of requests, but.
Just note here that in order to do the complete section of the firebase and Google Maps integration,
you will need payment information and we are not liable for any cost you may incur.
However, we will teach you how to set up the cloud environment and teach you how to run your fire function
locally so that you can limit the amount of live costs you may incur.
That being said, things can happen.
I myself, during development, made a small mistake over here in the Google Maps platform and I incurred
sixty five thousand requests worth of costs.
Now, that was that was a stressful evening right there.
But luckily I reached out to the Google platform team and they helped me out.
They helped me fix everything.
And they also gave me some tips and tricks that I'm going to be passing along to you in terms of setting
up quotations, making sure that your Google cloud is set up so that you can limit the amount of costs
you can incur.
That being said, nothing is one hundred percent fail proof.
That's why you have to link payment information.
You may incur some costs.
You may not.
It depends on how you utilize this section.
And we're going to teach you as much as possible about how to use these services.
If you do not have payment information, however, and you cannot do this bonus section, don't be afraid.
You can run your fire function, your firebase function, you can run it locally.
You will not be able to do the full integration to Google as you need payment information to talk to
Google.
But we will be migrating our mock information to a server environment, which you can invoke locally.
Now, that said, this will mean that your app will be reliant on the server.
So you have to be careful in how you approach this section because if you cannot push your fire function
to the cloud, your app will only work locally because you will only locally have the firebase function
so you can test the section out even if you don't have payment information up to a point.
It is important to, though, realize that you do need payment information in order to complete this
entire section.
So with that said and that out of the way, let's take a look at everything we need to put in place
in order to set up our firebase functions to build out a server.