We've built the great app so far, and we kind of went through the motion of using a system like syntax
to kind of put together the UI and go through the motions of, hey, this is the UI we're going to build.
This is roughly how we're going to use these properties to put them in the right place.
And maybe in your past you've done X, maybe you're completely new to all of this together.
But if you've done this in the past, you may have felt like, hey, react native.
This kind of feels like CSFs kind of familiar.
Well, it's not really successful and we must really make that distinction.
We must step away from thinking of it as excess because it's a flexible layout engine and it's called
yoga now.
Yoga because it's flexible, get the pun.
And then in case the whole purpose of yoga is to build flexible layouts on any platform with highly
optimized open source layout engine.
So, OK, what does that mean?
Well, kind of like you want to put the pieces of a puzzle in the right order.
Layouts need to be built in certain ways.
And so you want spacing between items and you want this to be this far from that in this to be this
far from that and all that stuff.
And so usually in if you've done CSFs, it's quite the process.
If you're completely new to this, you may have a blank slate and that's great.
That said, laying out an engine or doing a layout engine is quite an endeavor.
And so yoga is being used by Riak native as the layout engine.
Now, you may or may not have heard of flex box flex boxes of specification in which we're trying to
achieve this layout structure with minimal effort.
We're trying to minimize what you need to know, the language you need to know in order to achieve being
able to layout things in a logical way.
And flex box has certain properties.
Now, this is flex box, like if you've done CSFs, it's kind of like CSFs Flex Box, but it differs
a bit and it won't act exactly the same.
So don't be afraid of things don't actually pan out the same way that they do in CSFs.
Now you have absolute and relative layouts.
You have alignment of content, rapping, direction, aspect ratio, justify content, flexibility,
all of these obscure things that you're basically using to put things in the right place on the screen.
That's all they do.
All they do is make sure that you can put things on the right screen at the right place.
So now that we know that, now that we know that this yoga thing is a thing and that it's laying out
stuff on the right spot on the screen and it has all of these properties that help us do this, what
exactly does it look like?
Well, let's take a look at that.