What we just discussed here can become a bit confusing, so I want to boil it down in a diagram that
will help simplify what exactly it is we're doing when we're adding data in a normal circumstance,
when we're talking about talking to Google, what our phone is doing in actuality is going to Google
and asking it, hey, give me some of your maps information.
And by doing that, what Google will send back is the information about the restaurants and the location.
Now, in actuality, how we're building this out is as follows, our phone is having an application
that's built in Riak native Riak native is built in to react.
And so when we determine that we're going to work with any type of data in this specific situation,
because it's global data, because the restaurant's data is global data, what we're seeing is that,
in fact, we're going to leverage something called react context and we're going to build a service
layer consisting of these two parts, a service and the context, the context serves to share the data
globally within the riak need of application.
And the service itself stems to determine what methods we want in order to get data from the external
service.
So the service file operates as a layer in between the context, the Riak native application and the
external service provider, in this case, Google.
And what we're doing on top of that is we're saying, well, right now we can't really implement the
Google API called.
There's way more that needs to go into that.
So what we're doing is we're faking it.
We're not really integrating against Google, but we're having local files that have the information
that's structured in the same way that Google would send this back information.
But we're storing them locally on the phone.
And that way we can build our implementation as if we were talking to Google.
And later on, when we actually do talk to Google, it's going to be a question of just switching some
things around, because the way that our app understands the information is already there.
So to boil that down.
In reality, if we're talking about a global integration, our phone talks to Google, but in our implementation,
since we're using react native, we're going to be using the react context.
We're going to have a service file that's going to operate as an intermediate between our app and the
external service.
In this case, we're going to mock the external service.
We're not going to make it as if the external service is real.
And to do that, we need to build out this service oriented architecture, this service layer.
And for every subsequent feature, we will be using something relatively similar, although we might
change it up a bit based on the situation.
Now that we understand this, we can get into building out our mock implementation of talking to the
Google Service API.