Welcome back.
We've just done our first contribution, which wasn't that crazy, right?
We just went to the start here guideline and added our names to the contributors list.
But let's actually contribute to an open source project now, now in our community, every month we
do coding challenges.
Now, you can search for coding challenges here, but this month is a special event because we're actually
doing.
A half tober fest event, and this happens once a year in our community in October.
And you can see that if we click on the October 1st, 2019 link, so depending on when you watch this,
you might have a different ear.
You see that we've provided for you an opportunity to contribute to an open source project.
We actually have Animation Nation.
We have a Santa fied project and also a python.
And you can contribute to any one of these.
So if we look at Animation Nation, well, people have contributed their success animations here.
This one looks nice.
We also have the Santa fied project, so people have created a little Santa website, that's kind of
nice.
Very, very cool, and then we also have the Python art project that actually does something really
cool if I go to the website here.
The laxly turn an image into ASCII art, which is really, really cool.
Now there's tons of projects that you can do, but let's try and do this animation nation project.
So the first thing I'm going to do is go to the project repository.
And follow the steps that we've done before, that is we foresee the repository.
We now clone this repository, let's get clone.
And while that is being cloned, let's look at the instructions.
Now, most open source projects will have instructions on how you can contribute.
In our case, we have a nice step by step guide, so in the directory, create a directory named after
yourself.
OK, that's nice and easy to do.
So let's say CD into the animation.
Nation project.
Let's open it up and sublime.
And we see that there's an art folder and in here we have to create our own name or our own folder with
our name.
I've actually already created a folder called Animatronic that has.
A little success, our project with an extra and access, so just to show you, let's move this.
Or just to show you.
This is my little animation using some simple index ASML access, nothing too crazy.
Now all we need to do is move this into the art folder, as the instructions have given us.
And now we've added our project, let's see where's animatronic?
There it is.
That's my project over there.
Is to well within this folder, make sure we create two files, an e-mail file and a file and link the
file to your e-mail.
Using only e-mail access, create a work of art, so I've actually already done that again, if we go
back to the project, I have an index HTML file, very, very simple.
That's linked to a stylesheet.
And this is my style about it for my animation that.
These little lines now the last part here is to add my own card to this section to the include dodgiest
file.
So let's just copy this.
Go to the.
Includes or include dogs, and you see, this is where everybody enters their information.
And right here, we can just add while we copy and paste it, make sure the indentation is proper,
so the name is going to be called animatronic.
Page link is going to be while the name of our folder so animatronic.
Index HMO.
And then the gift name, which.
They suggested that we include a gift.
So if I remember correctly, the.
Gafney.
Was transport gift again, I just created a little gif of my animation.
So we'll call it transport gif author is.
Andre and the GitHub link is my GitHub link.
All right, so that should be good.
Let's now make a pull request.
Now, notice here how I did all these changes on M..
Ideally, we created these changes on a new branch so we can actually just do that now.
Get check out be.
And call it animatronic.
So if I do get status now.
I see that I have two changes, that's good.
Let's do get add.
Get commit.
Adding my arsenis to the project.
And then finally get push of origin animatronic.
All right, if we go back to the project.
We see that we actually now have a little icon that says compare, pull request.
If I go back to the forked repo zero to Mastery.
You see right over here that I also have this yellow banner, so if I click on this.
Please add me to this list and we'll link to this is Joy, who's one of the managers.
So I'm just going to say, please add me to the list.
We actually don't even need to tag her because she will check this occasionally.
So I'm going to create a pull request.
It's now opened.
That's awesome.
So please allow me to the list, if I look at my file changes, you can see that these are what I've
added to the project.
So if I now merge, pull request again, you won't be able to do this, but some of our management team
people who are managing the open source projects will be able to merge for you.
We can delete the branch since we have merged everything and now let's see if the changes have been
made.
If I go to the zero to Masari Animation Nation, so if I now look for my project, hey, look at that.
There's my little animation project that.
Well, there it is, there's my access that's beautiful.
The way this project is designed, it randomly selects the next animation, so it might not show all
of them at the same time.
So you might have to refresh this a few times.
But just like that, I made my opensource contribution.
Now, there's a ton of projects here that you can join.
And like I said, this is a playground for you to test, make mistakes, because this isn't a real workplace.
We want to practice these skills before we actually go into work and make big dangerous changes.
And that's opensource.
I highly, highly recommend that you get involved.
It's a great way to work with others.
It's a great way to learn how Git and GitHub really work.
There's no doubt that there's a lot that an individual programmer can do.
However, the progress and scale that something can be built is really compounded when many people work
on something together.
Go make your first opensource contribution and have fun building things with your fellow programmers.
It may one day lead to impress a potential employer.
See in the next one by.