So that designer comes to you and says, hey, Moe, in my case or in your case, whatever your name
is, but hey Moe.
I get that, you know, you went for a different color pattern, but you have orange tabs, you have
a purple menu and you have blue buttons, I really like the purple.
Could we could we just stick with the purple?
And you're like, we sure can.
So we go over to our colors, dot jazz and we look at our brand colors and they say, oh, OK, you
set up a theme, you set this up with a proper brand strategy.
OK, so could we change the primary color to six nine six, a C three?
And that will allow us a deep nice purple.
And for the secondary color, how about we go with a five d six six six and they're speaking to us in
hex code because I guess that's how designers speak.
But you get it and you fill it in and now you go into your app and you say, oh, now everything that
I did as brand primary blue is purple and the buttons are purple.
And if we go over here, oh, we're missing an avatar.
So we go we quickly go over to our settings screen and we say to ourselves, oh, our avatar icon has
a background color that is not set to a color.
So we quickly go and say colors.
That brand dot primary and we import colors over here, so we say import colors from.
Infrastructure theme colors, and by doing that now, if we go to the settings screen that's set up
to be consistent about our tab menu is also not consistent.
So we go to App Navigator and we say, well, let's import colors here as well.
So we import colors from.
Dot, dot, dot, dot.
Infrastructure theme, and then we say colors, and then over here we say that well.
What color should we pick?
So we go down here and we say, when it's active, let's do colors, not brand thought primary, and
then when it's inactive, let's do colors, dot, brand, dot muted.
And if we go look at that, what we can see is that the muted color is.
Kind of in line, it's kind of a pastel blue that bleeds into the purple and the designers are like,
oh, well, that looks pretty nice, that's pretty decent.
And so the app is now fully well, I guess you could call Purplest.
And so if we log out, we can also see that our buttons are now purple, all of our buttons.
And just with those simple, simple changes, we change the whole aesthetic of our app with no code
at all.
We created consistency when we thought there was none possible when we were freaking out.
Remember when we were freaking out in the previous video?
I was freaking out in the previous video, but it was this simple to change everything and it was no
sweat at all.
That's what happens when you set up your code for scale and it's amazing.
OK, so now that we have that going for us, what's going on over here in the cart?
Well, let's quickly fill in an order.
Let's do Moaveni and let's quickly do a payment.
And we can see that when we pay, an error is happening and everything is working as intended and the
other icons will automatically turn to purple and our map still works as intended.
Everything is good, just small couple tweaks to the code and we have created beautiful consistency.