I know what you're thinking.
Mo, cut all of the fluff and just get to the point.
How do I upgrade?
What do I need to do?
Well, let's get straight into it.
Over here, I have the meals to go running as it is today.
If you want to run the same exact version, I'm running.
I am running a specific branch called full with mock and polish.
Now, if you go to our GitHub link and you go to the meals to go, then what you'll see over here on
the main page is I have a branch full mark with Polish and you can just grab this branch install and
you're good to go.
You have to fill in some of the information around your specific setup with Firebase.
But other than that, you can get going now.
You have to have finished the course in order to get to this point.
So make sure you've finished the course.
And then from there, what we're going to need is expo.
Now, if you've done the course as of today, you should have this and stop if you're coming back to
the course from a longer period of time.
You know, just make sure you have it installed globally and you can do that by npm.
Install Xposed Houli Global, right minus G.
We've been through this.
Once we have that, what we need to do is we need to go over to our Seelye over here.
And what we'll do is I'll just open a new window and so we'll go to projects meals to go and what we
need to do here.
And before we get to this, what we need, especially global.
Don't forget that because otherwise your command will fail.
All we need to fill in here is expo.
Upgrade and what this is going to do is it's going to say, Hey, oh, my working branch is dirty,
that means I currently already have changes.
Huh?
OK.
Would you like to proceed?
No.
So let's see what I have here.
Oh, I edited my app that ships with my personal information for my meals to go up.
So let me go over here.
Let me kill the app real quick.
Let's make sure we don't have the app running while we go through an upgrade that would be, you know,
dangerous.
Now that we have our branch in a good state, it's as simple as typing an export upgrade, and it'll
take you through the prompts to actually upgrade.
So what is it asking us saying you're currently running a sticky version 40?
Would you like to update to 43?
And of course, we're going to say yes, and then it's going to install Expo 43 as the first package.
And what it's subsequently going to do is it's going to go through the packages that are also installed
and it's going to update the packages to the compatible versions where it knows that there are expo
packages installed in your repository.
So any package that is expo compatible is also automatically upgraded to the latest version.
How cool is that?
How simple is that they make it so easy for you to keep everything up to date and then they'll tell
you, OK, we updated the following packages so async storage is up to date safe area context reanimated
the gesture handler, the status bar, the SVG, you know, Lordi.
All of these things just came out of the box and then saying, OK, well, these packages weren't updated.
Also, it upgraded React and React Dom, which is very key.
But then it says we didn't update the following packages, right?
Which packages didn't it?
Update?
Well, it didn't update the fonts.
OK, that's fine, you know?
Do we need to update the fonts?
What's going to really change about font?
Then it didn't update the mask for you.
Oh, that's the one that you know, we utilize for the credit card, I think.
Or Oh, what was that?
Oh yeah, it's one of those packages that introduced a mask for you.
OK, well, the current version, as long as it's working, that's good.
And then a lot of react navigation stuff.
Firebase, of course.
You know, that's something that we need to manually keep in mind.
React native paper, which is our design system.
OK, that's fine.
Styles components.
Sure, you should update that because that can break all of the styling.
These are things that we manually need to look at and manually to upgrade prettier and Iceland.
So it made all of the right decisions.
It didn't update things it didn't know about.
It didn't update things that could break the core of the app, like the navigation, the styling, you
know, our design system, all of the things that we manually may need to intervene to update.
And it only updated the core of our app.
So the app is at its core, up to date.
Like everything that keeps the app from the foundational standpoint, running is all updated and everything
that is an add on isn't.
So our foundation is always going to be in a good state and we can decide from there whether or not,
you know, it's a good idea to go through an upgrade of south components or, you know, our design
system or react navigation for that.
And so from here, because our foundation has been updated, we should go ahead and look at what actually
happened to the app.
So let's take a look at.