You may have asked yourself through this entire prelude of architecture and all this other stuff, what
his stripe, what is it?
What does it do?
Well, it's payment infrastructure for the Internet.
Now, their main offering is to allow users and clients to scale their payment infrastructure.
So outsourcing the payment gateway directly to Stripe.
And they charge fees for this, of course.
But the whole point of scaling to external services is to take out of your hands the management and
all of the things that come with building your own.
And so they have partnerships with Amazon, Slack, Zoom, Lyft, Google, Salesforce, insert the card,
Shopify.
And if Stripe is good enough for all of these juggernauts, it's good enough for you.
And the reason for that is it helps you scale without having to think about all of these security concerns
that go into payments.
Payments are so painful, so, so painful because they come with so many regulations and costs and all
of these things that you need to do.
And companies left and right have been outsourcing this to companies that have done this for years and
years.
And Stripe is just one of those companies that has taken the Internet by storm.
And they've come with so many features, including the ability to link back to your customers, to your
products, generate reports and all of this good stuff.
They have so many features.
It's the one of the world's most powerful APIs when it comes to payments and will be looking at a straight
shot integration into credit card payments.
Now, in order to do this, what we need to do is register ourselves for the stripe integration.
And if you go over to dashboard and you look here is going to ask you to sign into your account.
Now, if you do not have an account for Stripe, I want you to sign up for one meaning.
You have to fill in your own email, your own name, your own country, your own password, and then
create an account.
And once you've created an account, we can log in and I already have an account.
So over here I'm going to go over to sign in and I'm going to login.
Now, once you log in, what you're going to do is you're going to be redirected and that redirection
is going to take you to your actual dashboard, your actual stripe dashboard.
Now, when you come over here, it's going to give you this overview of getting started with Stripe.
Now, you don't need any credit card information to set up straight.
It'll come out of the box in a sandbox mode, in a test mode, and it'll ask you to activate your account
to be able to create a live.
Integration and so you can see here I have processed eight hundred and seventy two dollars in payments
in my test environment.
Now you will have access to your Test API because this is a publishable API key.
And then over here you can see the secret key, which they hide and they hide this for a very specific
reason.
This is very, very sensitive information.
This is not a key that you just want out floating into the wild.
When you bootstrap servers and you set up those providers, you will give this key to that server in
order to be able to process payments on your behalf.
The publishable key is what is used by the clients.
So are react native app or a Web application or any other type of application to link itself to the
payment provider.
Right.
There are certain things we need to do on the client side and there are certain things we need to do
on the server side and both interplay together to be able to process a payment.
And eventually what we'll be able to see in the end is that will be processing successful as well as
failed payments with specific payment tokens, specific users for specific amounts.
That's what we're aiming for.
And now that you have Stripe's set up, we can move over and we can look at the rest of the integration
that needs to happen.
Just keep in mind that these two keys over here are going to be extremely important in the following
videos.