Now that we have our fire base in a state in which we can deploy functions, the question becomes more.
How do we deploy functions and what's important here is to realize that the docs point us in really,
really solid directions.
If we go to Firebase Google dot com and we go to functions, get started, it tells us basically everything
we need to know about how to get started.
Now, we already have a firebase project so we can skip step one.
But when we go to step two, it says, set up no jass and firebases like, well, we already have no
just set up but Firebase Seelie, huh?
And so over here, it says you'll need no gas to write functions and you'll need Firebase CLI to deploy
the functions to the cloud function runtime, meaning that any code that we write, we need to be able
to push it up to Firebase so that Firebase can run it for us later on.
OK, now here's the star or the important section.
The important section is that NOGs versions 10, 12 and 14 are supported, 14 is under beta.
However, I have tested it and I find that it works just fine for what we are will be doing.
So we will be using version 14 of your own version 10 or 12.
That is fine as well.
But it's always best to be on the most recent LTE version, long term support version.
So it also says Theset runtime docs for important information regarding ongoing support.
So let's go over there C runtime options and it's going to tell us over here what runtime options are
available.
As you can see nogs, eight is deprecated as of June 8th.
Twenty twenty.
So that way we can keep track of what is supported by Firebase if a newer version is supported here,
please go ahead and take the newer version.
Now with that, once we have node and installed, which we do, we need to install Firebase Clive through
our preferred method.
So over here, they give us a command NPM install minus G firebase tools.
So let's copy that command.
And if we go over to our terminal and we open up a new terminal, what we can do is we can run that
command that will install the firebase tools globally and by installing them globally, we will in effect
have.
Access to the firebase command.
Now, it also says if this command fails, you may need to change your NPM permissions.
So if you're unable to run this command, you may need to change some permissions.
And if we click this link, it will take us to help documentation that will outline what we may be seeing.
And if this outlines what you may be seeing, you may want to follow these steps over here to resolve
it.
And that will allow you to set up your computer in a better place to be able to run this command if
it still feels, please reach out on our Dischord community or on the section.
But the discourse community often has a lot of students who have a lot of prior experience with dealing
with certain errors, and we help each other out.
So that's always a good option.
Now, if we go back over to the docks where we can see here is after we run NPM install firebase tools,
it says here in many cases, the new features and bug fixes are available only with the latest version
of Firebase Seelie.
So we'll want to update the Firebase Functions SDK.
And so to frequently update these, you will have to run the following functions inside of our project.
We can run NPM, install firebase functions at latest firebase admin, the latest.
Now, once we set this up, we will get the latest version.
But that being said, you may run into an instance where later on, if you leave the project for a while,
if it stagnates, you may have to come back to it and run these two commands in order to upgrade and
get the latest version of firebase functions.
OK, so once we have that, we can run something called Firebase Login.
Interesting when you initialize the firebase SDK for cloud functions to create an empty object before
we even go into that, we need to log in through the command line.
So let's go over here and let's say, OK, it's installed.
We've installed firebase tools at nine point one point zero.
So if we do firebase the minus minus help, what we'll see is that we have Firebase as a command available.
Now that we know that we have it available as a command, we can run firebase login and this will say
already logged in as McGeeney.
So if I do Firebase log out.
Then I will log out as Bobigny, and if I do log in again, what it's going to do, it's going to ask
me if it wants to collect error reporting information.
I'm going to say no right now.
It's going to take me into my browser and it's going to ask me to select an account with which I want
to log in.
So I will log in with Moaveni that.
Now, this will ask from fire basically certain permissions view and manage data across the Google cloud
platform, administer your firebase data and take control of cloud platform projects.
So we'll allow that.
Once we've allowed that, it will say firebases Ally Log-in is successful, you are now logged into
firebase command line and if we go back over to our command line success, you logged in as Mobeen.
Awesome.
Now that we are certain that we have access to our firebase cloud and we are authenticated, well,
over here you can see that step two and three.
It says go to your firebase project directory.
So our firebase project is meals to go.
And it says run firebase in a fire firestorm.
Well, we're not going to use the fire storm, so let's skip this one and then it says Firebase in it
functions, huh?
Well, we're going to use functions.
OK, so let's go ahead and do that now.
Let's go ahead.
Take this over here and run this in the command line.
Now it's going to ask us a bunch of questions and it's going to say, well, do you want to use an existing
project in your firebase to link the functions to or do you want to create a new project or do you want
to add it to an existing cloud platform project?
What do you want to do?
So we're going to say use an existing project.
And over here, you can see I have two miles to go, you most likely have one and you can link it to
that Miles to go project I only have two because I've tested meals to go a couple of times.
So we're going to link it to meals to go.
And by linking, it is going to ask us in what language do you want to write your cloud functions?
Well.
JavaScript, of course, so lets select JavaScript, do you want Esslin to catch problems and for style
we're going to say no here because we already have excellent configured in our project and it will take
over lintang for us in the project.
So we're going to say no here and it's going to say that is going to write the following files.
So it wrote a package, JSON, an index to get ignore and it's asking us if we want to install our dependencies.
We're going to say no here because we're going to install our dependencies ourself.
But first and foremost, what we want to do is over here.
We want to see what it's added.
It's added a firebase that Jason awesome.
That's empty.
It's added a firebase RC in which our project has been specified.
And so if we open up our functions folder, we can see that it's added a bunch of different information
for us.
It's added functions from firebase functions which haven't been installed yet, and the next Jass and
all that good stuff.
Now, what we want to do is we want to go inside our get ignored and first and foremost, let's add
the node modules of the subfolder.
And then let's add like that same, but we're going to also say that it can't track the node modules
of the subfolder, let's do get status.
And what we can see here is that it's tracking these three folders now.
Awesome.
OK, so with that, we're now ignoring the node modules inside of here.
And if we go inside of functions, what we can do is we can run yarn.
And then it's going to say, huh, the engine node is not compatible with this module expected version
12.
Well, what node version am I running?
Oh, I'm running 14.
OK, so let's go inside our functions.
Let's go inside our package, JSON, and let's update this to 14.
You may need to update this to the node version you are currently running.
So always remember to run node minus V, and if we then do yarn, it will install all of the dependencies
for the firebase function.
And if we do get status here now, we can see that everything is being tracked inside of our folder
if we go one level up.
So we're tracking our see the JSON and the functions folder.
If we look at exactly what is inside of our index function currently there is no firebase function available,
but we've set up everything in a good spot so that in the next video, let's take a look at how we run
this actual function and what goes into it.