Now comes a pivotal question here, you thinking, Mo, if this yoga web thing can make me lay out everything
and teach me how to put things in the proper position, why don't I just use that to build the whole
UI?
Theoretically, you could it's not as pleasant an experience to play around in the playground and build
complex UI, but understanding how these properties right direction alignment and justifying content
and all the stuff, understanding how it will work will help you understand how to layout things.
Right.
Because in Riak native, laying out with box is all about understanding kind of how Fleck's works.
And once things are in the right space, they will typically be in the right space across multiple phones.
Now, this doesn't mean that you won't maybe have to do adjustments for Android versus iOS or for a
specific screen size.
These things do tend to happen and we'll get into that as we build out the course.
But what's important to know here is all of these first principles in React Native, they have a place
and they have documentation.
Often times developers will come from the WebSphere and they will treat liying out inflects box the
same way they treat access.
But it isn't the same.
It is the same with a few exceptions.
Now, if you have never written CSFs, you don't know what is.
I highly recommend you take our react course as well.
But what we need to understand here is Riak native, although it says react in the name.
And if you've heard of react, it behaves a bit differently.
Now we're targeting mobile phones, right?
So at the end of the day, what we need to know here is that.
REAC Netiv is targeting Android and iOS and the way that we're going to lay out what Fleck's is determining
how we're going to fill the area that we have available.
And so if we go to the Riak native dock's for Xbox.
What we'll see here is a high level documentation of how Fleck's interacts, not only that, how every
property works.
So if you really apply yourself to this material and dig deep and try to understand how all of these
things work, I promise you you will master react native like no one else.
Now, the awesome, awesome, awesome thing about the Riak native DOCSIS, whenever you go look up a
principle, whether it be Fleck's box or a specific element, they have revealed their documentation
with Grade A material as well as Snax directly embedded into the docks.
You see this over here.
This is code.
It's being rendered in the UI and you can go so far as to run it on your own device if you wanted to,
and play around with the properties here and regenerate this QR code and try things out for yourself.
It's amazing.
We can take all of these first principles that we're looking at and we can literally practice them until
our face turns blue.
Now, don't do that.
But I'm just saying, like the ability for the cross pollination between documentation and live examples
with something as complex as mobile development is absolutely astonishing.
And so they have examples for all different types of things.
The first principles, how to do, call them, reverse what the layout direction means, what justifying
the content does and all that good stuff.
Right.
You see these three blocks here with the space in between.
Absolutely.
Mind boggling, isn't it?
But you can do that all with Flex and with very basic properties.
And so by understanding this, we're going to start understanding how to layer UI like a cake, a delicious
cake at that.
And so what I want to point out here is that Riak native documentation is absolutely amazing and you
should always reach to it to learn first principles.
And we will continue to reach out to it throughout the course to solidify our knowledge, but also look
at how properties work, because we don't just want to leave you with a beautiful app.
We want to leave you with a beautiful foundation of knowledge that's going to help you throughout your
career.