So why should we build something in React Native?
There's three main reasons why.
One is that it has a big community.
Whenever you are using a technology, you want to make sure that there's enough documentation out there
for you.
Let's say you encounter a problem.
You want to be able to Google it and find solutions that perhaps others have discovered.
You want to be able to find solutions on stack overflow.
You want to find libraries or tools that others have built that you can use.
If you're using a brand new tool, then it's going to be really hard for you to solve those issues when
nobody else in the world has had them.
So react native out of Flutter or Samarian has the biggest community.
That means there's a lot of tools, a lot of components, a lot of libraries that you can use with react
native to make your life easier.
And we'll see that throughout the course.
Next is that big companies are using it.
You want to use a technology that has been tested, that has scaled, for example, some of the companies
that are using Riak native Facebook because they've created it uses Riak native for their Facebook ads
manager.
Their Uber eats app uses react native.
So does discord.
So does Instagram, so does Skype.
And React Native is backed by really big companies like Shopify, Walmart, but also Microsoft, who
has Zammar and have actually made a commitment to react native and have invested a lot into this framework.
As a matter of fact, if we look at hiring trends.
Now, this is hiring trends on Hacker News, one of the most popular programmer sites in the world,
you can see a clear distinction here between job interest and job posting for Riak native versus something
like Samarian or flutter.
Companies are using it and companies are hiring for it, which at the end of the day is always a good
sign.
But finally, the most important point, because with these two points, I would argue that you should
use native Swift or Colline to build your iOS and Android apps.
But the big thing that Riak native really helps us with is this idea of cross platform.
Instead of as a company hiring two separate teams, maintaining two separate apps, both on iOS and
Android, you could write in, react native ones and have it run both on iOS and Android.
And whenever there's cases where there's differences for Android or iOS, you can still do that with
REAC native.
You see, Riak native apps are infinitely extensible.
What that means is that you're not actually constrained to react native and coding in JavaScript.
If you want, you can always write in pure native code like Swift and Colin in your app, in your native
app, if you want to do something outside the framework so you can always use Riak native with Swift
if you want to create something that needs to be really, really performing.
So there you have it.
I guess what I'm saying is you picked the right technology to learn, but we've been talking a lot and
I think it's time for us to actually learn instead of just hearing me blabbering on.
So let's get started.