Let's start off by building our request, so first off, in our restaurant service, we're going to
have CONSED restaurant request and this is going to be a request to get restaurants right.
So any time you do this, you need to think, OK, what is my restaurant request need in order to get
the information?
For the restaurants, well, the first thing we need is the location, and so by getting the location,
we'll be able to retrieve.
Whether or not it's Toronto, Chicago or anything else, now, if we go look at our Mock's, they're
based on a longitude latitude.
So this is a position on a map.
And so that is going to be the location that will be requesting by so any time we get a location.
And so we'll put our default location to San Francisco just for now, will say that in the service,
the default location is equal to San Francisco.
What we can do inside of here is we can say, OK, well, I need to import my MOCs.
And I need to import those from Dotts Mock's so we can do index or we can just do this, which will
pull the index.
So now that we have our Mock's, we can console that log mocs.
OK, so how do we run this?
Well, first of all.
We can't really run it right now because we don't have any availability, we haven't imported this anywhere,
so the way that we can quickly and easily test this is we can, for instance, import it at the top
level so we could say like import something like import restaurants request.
And then we could say from.
This is not the final implementation, but this is just for us to, like, see what's going on, that's
source slash services, slash restaurants, and then we'll do restaurant service.
And over here we have to make sure that we export this right, because we're importing this specifically.
And so now we can go to our terminal and we can see what is going on here.
So when we run this, what we can see is all of the mock's that are available and they're massive,
massive, massive objects.
So.
If we were to say that we wanted a specific mosque, we could take our location and we could say, let's
call our location.
So our location is this, and we know that this massive object takes the location as a key, so if we
did Mock's location, we should get an object.
Right.
And sure enough, we do.
And we know that it's San Francisco because of the places that are coming back from it.
So with that, we now have a mock of a location.
OK, so we have a mock of a location.
And so with that mock of a location, we now know that we can pull specific mock information from specific
spots as long as we have the right key.
So our mock information is already set up for us properly over here.
So in this case.
What we need to do is whenever we do an API call, it's going to be something called a promise, and
a promise is something that you have to await.
It's something that runs asynchronously.
It's something that happens in the future.
And so because we want our request to mimic as close to a real API as possible, what we need to do
here is, well, the Mock's location returns almost immediately because it's local, right?
So we have to mimic as if it was a promise.
So we'll return new promise and then we'll do a new promise, takes a resolve and a reject function.
And what we'll do is we'll go inside the function of this and we'll say, get the mark so Consed Mark
is equal to Mark's location and then we'll say, if you don't have a mark for this location, reject
and say no location.
Not found.
Right.
That's the first thing we got to do.
And then once we do that, it becomes pretty easy.
If we do have a mock, will resolve the mock.
OK, so now that we have this, what's going to happen over here is.
What is our Consolo going to give us?
Well, this is now going to be a then.
Right.
So any time you create a promise, it is now deniable.
So it's awaiting something in the future.
This is a way of basically saying a restaurant request is not going to return immediately.
It's going to return sometime in the future.
So we're doing that then.
And that then returns us the result.
As an inner function, so by doing this, syntax will be resolving the inner function and will have
the result, and if we don't do a log result, we'll retrieve the result now.
So now we can see that we have our result again.
So we're getting the actual return of San Francisco information.
Now, if we did not catch, we could see what would happen if we got an error.
So if we got an error console log error.
Right.
We would see what would go on if we actually got the error, so if we filled in a location here that
doesn't exist like something random, what we're going to see over here at the bottom is an error case
happen, right?
Error, error.
Now, what is the error?
Well, the error is not found because it can't find this location.
This does not exist.
So.
With that, we have to know now that we're mimicking a real API in a very, very simple fashion.
OK, so in the next video, we'll look at the shape of the data and what it's returning us.