The designer comes back to you and says, hey, for the restaurant info card, could we adjust that
a bit?
Because I don't like the way that it's filling in the entire with.
And you're like, sure we can.
So what you do is you go to a restaurant info card styles, and we're looking at the restaurant card
and you say, what exactly do you want?
Well, shorten it a bit.
So you say, OK, with ninety five percent.
All right, so we do that and, oh, well, let's align it to the center aligned south center and so
now it's aligning itself perfectly in the center.
The others like, oh, yeah, that looks much better.
And then they ask you, hey, on this detail screen, right on the detail screen, could you adjust?
The dividers between the different menu items, and you're like, sure, so you go and you research
and research and you find that reacclimated favor has a divider item.
And so we go.
And what we do is between each accordion, we decide that we're going to put a divider.
Right.
So we put a divider between the items right here.
And by doing that now, every item inside the menu has a divider, but subsequently we also put them
between the accordion's.
So by doing that now, we can create logical groupings between each and every section as well as each
and every individual item inside of the menu.
So we'll put them between the accordion's and put them between each and every menu item.
There we go.
And then right here between coffee.
Te Modelo Coke, and there we go.
And by doing this, we now have dividers dividing up very lightly the menu to create this nice flow
of the UI so that we have a clear separation of items between groups and otherwise.
Awesome.
All right, that was simple enough, no muss, no fuss.