If everything went to plan, really nothing should have changed at all.
Right.
Because we only updated the foundation.
So if the upgrade is successful and it should be really our app should just continue to work as it is.
So let's take a look at the.
Let's go ahead and run the app.
And by doing this, we'll start our bundler.
And what we'll do is over here.
Will Reload, which will grab the bundle from the Metro BUNLAR, which is now running on version 43
of Expo.
And if everything has gone to plan, what we should see here is a fully functioning app.
I'm already logged in.
My mock data is loading in and.
Seems like my app works perfectly fine, right?
We always have to do a smoke test after an upgrade and ensure the functionality works as intended right,
and that everything that we put together is actually up to date.
And so by doing this, we will always, always, always ensure that our upgrades are successful.
Now what can you do for smoke tests?
Well, there's manual testing where you take the team and you say, Look, OK, here's the branch where
upgraded, and let's go through it together.
Or you can run automated tests with something like detox.
There's many, many ways to smoke test an application, but nothing passes the test like a quick run
through of the core functionalities.
And so as we can see here, our app is fully up to date.
We're running the new version of React.
We're running the new version of Expo.
The foundation of our app is set and everything just continued to work, as is.
That's amazing, right?
And so that's how you go through a secure upgrade.
And so if you wanted to upgrade any of the other parts of the app, like the navigation, the new design
system, any of those additional like perks, you would go and grab the migration guide from that package,
the regularly published the migration guides, and they'll tell you how to go through it, what code
you need to change.
But it's so nice that would expo an expo, especially.
We went through a full foundational upgrade of React Expo, a bunch of core fundamental packages, and
our app continued to work.
Now, is this always going to be this way?
No.
Sometimes some things will break and then you'll have to go and you'll have to look at, you know,
the breaking changes guides that they link over here when you did the upgrade, right?
Remember when we said the following packages were updated, the following weren't well, they'll always
refer you to the release notes, right?
If there are any breaking changes or if you're skipping a couple of versions, what the prior versions
breaking changes were so that you can go through the documentation and kind of see.
All right.
Where do I need to adjust things?
What do I need to update?
And that's very important.