Congratulations.
This is a big day for you, why?
Well, you just got hired at the biggest tech firm in the world.
That's right.
You know it.
I know it.
It's Kako Corp. They do a bunch of things.
They're a big Silicon Valley tech startup.
And they recently created their mobile division.
Right here in this new mobile division is going to create some amazing apps that are going to take over
the world.
And lucky for you, Bruno, right here with the perfect hair, just hired you as the lead of their mobile
division and.
Classic Bruno.
He has a great idea, you know what people love?
People love to be on their phones.
You know what else people love?
They love food.
People need to eat food.
So he's combining the two ideas and says, hey, let's build a mobile app that allows our customers
to discover new restaurants, new food places, new takeout options.
He thinks this is going to be the next big idea and he wants you to build it.
But here's the thing, you're just starting out, sure, you passed the interview and Bruno hired you,
but how do you actually build a mobile app?
What technology does how do you even get started?
And this course is all about that.
We're going to take you from scratch to building a fully production ready mobile app and making our
boss, Bruno, happy, because I have a feeling that when things don't go his way, he's going to be
very angry with us.
But don't worry, we got you covered.
We're going to start from the beginning.
Learn the basics, figure out how we're going to build the app.
Hint, hint.
We're going to use react native and then build an app that will take over the world.
Exciting times ahead.
Let's get started.