So far, we've done a lot of the initial setup, but we haven't run our application just yet.
And so one of the crucial components of running Riak native is something called Node James.
And so when we use NOGs, we can install it locally on our computer.
Now, we always want to go for the ELTs.
This is the long term support version.
It is the most stable and it's recommended for most users.
If you go to the one with the latest features, you may run into potential issues.
But that being said, would react native.
You never know what version it's going to need.
It may need later versions or or whatnot.
For now, with the ELTs, we should be good.
So let's allow that to download.
And if you already have node installed, just set it to fourteen point fifteen point zero.
If you have a version manager or reinstall it with the newest version like we're doing over here, we're
going to go through the installation pretty quickly and just accept, accept, accept, because all
of this is pretty standard.
And so it's going to start writing files, routing files and we're good.
Now it's going to say the package was installed over here.
Make sure that user local bin is in your path.
Interesting.
What does that mean?
Well, let's go look, let's move that to the trash and let's do something called Echo Path.
Well.
As we can see, it echoed out Yusra, local, Ben and all of the stuff and it said, make sure the user
local bin is available.
Well, it is.
OK, so how do we know that it works?
Well, let's do node minus Phee.
Oh, fourteen point five point zero, we have node installed, amazing, amazing, amazing, amazing.
OK, so now that we have node installed, we're halfway there.
But the next thing we need is something called Yorn.
And what is yourn?
Well, it's not a ball of yarn, I can tell you that much.
It is a package manager that works to get our packages.
Now this one is developed by Facebook and you could just as easily use something called NPM, which
ships standard with node.
It's also a different type of package manager.
But since this one is built by Facebook, right.
Jaan is built by Facebook and since React Native is built by Facebook, I've always found that yarn
has been more reliable with Riak native projects.
So we want to make it as easy as possible.
So how do we get started?
Well, if we go through the getting started and we go to installation, it's going to tell us to do
NPM install minus Gihan and I just told you about NPM.
NPM is a different package manager.
Will AMPM ship's standard with node.
So if we did node minus Phee, we're gonna have fourteen point five points here.
And if we did AMPM minus five, it's going to tell us we have six point fourteen point eight.
So NPM shipped with the node installation.
Now what we're going to do is we're going to do something called NPM Install minus G yarn.
This is a global installation.
If we run that command, what's going to happen?
Access denied, permissions denied all of the stuff.
Now, why is it doing that?
Well, that's because we don't have root possibilities.
So should we run it with pseudo.
Well if we run it with Suto now it will have access.
Sudo is kind of like the ability to run something as a super user.
And so now if we do yard minus Phee, we're going to have one point twenty two point zero.
Now, you could also do this with homebrew, but it's best to do it this way.
And now that we have this one point twenty two point zero, we're making sure that we're in the focus
folder that we created and we're going to do something called the yarn.
It's now it's going to start installing all of the different dependencies that you need and feel free
to slow this video down, go back, follow the commands step by step.
If you run into any issues, please reach out on our Dischord community.
That being said, the majority of this, if you're coming from a clean install, should be pretty straightforward.
This particular MacBook that we're doing this on has had a clean install, so we're starting fresh,
just like anyone who doesn't have prior packages, be aware that if you do have prior known versions
and versions, make sure to align them with the versions that we showed in this video.