Hopefully with that example, it all went pretty smoothly for you, but now let's take a look at how
we can implement this.
So the first thing we need to do is we need to import camera from XPO camera.
And this is going to allow us to utilize the camera functionality.
Now, let's open up and let's do a return function where inside of a return function we're going to
implement the camera.
And this camera screen is what's going to show to the user.
We're going to give it a particular style.
We're going to give it width of one hundred percent, height of 100 percent, so we can already see
here that we're going to need a custom component.
So let's go ahead and import styled from styled components native.
And what we'll do is we'll say CONSED profile camera is equal to styled camera and we'll put in our
width of one hundred percent and height of one hundred percent.
And by doing this now, we can actually use profile camera.
No more inline styles over here.
And let's close off profile camera.
Now, another thing that we need to do is you could technically decide to have a pivot between the front
and back camera for this particular feature, I've decided solely to use the front camera since it's
supposed to be a profile picture, a selfie seemed most appropriate.
Now, the way that we do that is we give the camera a type.
And so that type is type of camera that constants, but type that front.
And this is going to set the camera to always be the front camera.
Now, we're also going to give this a ref, so we're going to import use ref from.
React and we'll say consed camera ref.
Is equal to use ref of.
Inside of here will say Raif is equal to and will open the Brace's will declare a function of our and
we'll see over here that camera ref dot current is equal to R so that we can always know that we could
also just call this camera to make it more declarative.
And so now we know that camera ref is always going to reference the component over here.
OK, so having done this, what can we see in our app right now?
Can we see anything?
Well, let's go take a look.
And if we open up our settings and we go to hear what we can see is that, oh, it's not rendering out
on our simulator, of course not.
Our simulator does not have the ability to render out the camera module.
So let's go ahead and do this on the phone.
And so over here on the right hand side, you can now see my phone and if we go over to our profile
page and we tap the icon, huh, the camera's still rendering black.
Why is that?
What we haven't requested any permissions of the user.
So over here, if we go over to the permissions section, we can see that they're using, in effect,
to determine if the user has permission.
So let's copy this line.
Let's import use state.
And what we'll do is we'll above the use ref has permission set, set permission and we'll copy the
effect.
So we'll also import use effect.
And by doing that now, we can put this over here and.
Permissions are needed, huh?
We're getting our permissions, so if you press allow.
What's going to happen now?
Well, let us quickly reload the app, because it's probably in a faulty state and then what we'll do
is we'll go back to the settings, we'll go over here and, oh, the camera's working because we've
set our permission.
Now, of course, this only works if our permission has been set now.
So we also need to take into account, if you do not have a permission, if the permission is false,
we need to take those states into account.
So down here, we're going to have this where we render an empty view.
Now, what we can do is we can import view from react native.
Import view.
From React Native, and we'll just.
Render an empty view in the meanwhile and for text, well, we know that we can import text from our
components, so we'll import text from dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, slash components, slash
typography, slash text.
And so now if we do not grant permission, we also let the user know, hey, you do not have access
to the camera.
So we have a little bit of air handling in here.
And so with that, we now have the full flow working for our application because we can render out the
camera and we can take a picture just yet.
But what we can do is we can see ourselves.
So now that we have that set up and we have the permissions set up and we have the first part of our
solution, let's take a look at how we can take a picture, store the image.