All right, it's spring time and it's time to clean out the closet.
I'm joking.
Of course, what we're going to do now is now that we've set up our meals to go repository, what we
really need to do here is we need to go ahead and we need to clear out all of the cruft that was left
behind by XPO.
Now, XPO puts a lot of things by default in our project, and so we need to go ahead and we need to
you know, I like to look at it as a clean canvas.
You don't want to paint on a canvas that's already been painted on.
So you kind of want to start off with nothing but a few.
OK, now that we have cleared out our apologies file, what else do we need to do?
First of all, let's go into our app, Jason, and this is where we will control sort of what we would
call the metadata of an application here using metadata.
Well, it's the data that actually controls kind of the name of the app when it goes to the App Store,
the icon that you will see when you install your application on your phone, the splash screen that
will originally come in and all that stuff.
We just want to go through here.
We want to look at these properties and we want to make sure that everything is, you know, up to snuff.
Is this the name that we want to have for our application?
Is it the version?
Right.
We could go ahead and say, like, well, we're not a version of a point out where we're literally just
starting out.
So maybe we're at zero point zero point one.
Right.
And we could set the orientation.
We could do all of that good stuff.
So it's important to know that this file is here.
And at first glance, everything is good in here.
That's what spring cleaning is about, just looking around what was set up for us and what is all available.
And we can see that there is an icon of fabrication because this also is set up to run on the Web.
But we're not focusing on that outcome.
We're focusing mainly on Android and iOS.
But there is this movement in the Riak native space to also cross pollinate it to Web.
But for the intents and purposes of this course, we're focusing solely on the specifics of mobile development.
And the reason that my voice kind of sounds like skeptical is I believe that every platform has a specific
usability concern.
Right.
When we're on the mobile phone, we're concerned with the mobile user experience.
We're concerned with what users see and hear and how they interact with this blank canvas.
Whereas when we're on the Web, we have so much more space to deal with.
We have so much more things that we can do.
And so going and trying to tailor something that's meant to fit on this small screen and trying to fit
it on this big a screen.
Right.
My desktop screen just doesn't feel right now.
It's not to say that you can't go and do that.
It's to say that everything has a proper purpose.
And so for some use cases, you may go ahead and maybe try to build a react native app and target all
three platforms.
I prefer to when I use Riak native target mobile only.
OK, so we've we've held our spring cleaning here.
We know kind of what's around here and we want to create a new folder.
Not in here, obviously, so let's create a new folder at the top level, and what we want to do is
we want to select Abcess and then we'll create a folder and we're going to call it source, just like
we did with focus time.
And so inside of source is where the bulk of our code is going to live.
And now that we've created that.
We're going to set up a couple more folders, so let's set up components, if we look over here, we're
going to create a folder in components, but we want to click over here on Source and we're going to
create one more folder.
We're going to call it utils.
OK, so now that we have these two folders.
We basically want to make sure that something is rendering on our screen, if anything, so we're going
to say text.
Our react native blank canvas, and this is where the magic is going to start.
This is where we start our adventure.
Oh, wait, it's all the way up here.
What's going on?
Well.
Just like we said, if you don't give your container a style, it's going to not center the items right.
And so if we do a line items center and we say flex one.
Where does it end up?
Where's our text?
Where did it disappear to what is going on here?
So if we say here, justify content center.
Oh, there's our content.
Where did it disappear to before we had this, it was just gone.
What happened?
It's just not here.
Well, it's off the screen, obviously, so right now we have our react native blank canvas, and so
with this blank canvas, what we want to do is we want to start building our app.