All right, let's get coding, we are going to hit the ground running and I mean that in the most figurative
way possible because when we code, we are not actually going to run, but.
We are going to build focus time, and so in order to do that, I've highlighted the process in three
simple steps.
What we're going to achieve in this video, we are going to create an export account.
Then we are going to get a snack.
And no, I don't mean potato chips, although you can go and get those.
And it's always nice to have a snack while coding.
But what I mean here is that we are going to create a snack, an ex-post snack, a little environment
in which we are all individually going to build focus time.
And then finally we're going to get into coding focus time.
Now, not all of these are going to be achieved in this one video, but we should be able to get one
and two out of the way to get you focused on number three.
So let's move over to XPO.
So over here, we're on Facebook, and the number one thing we need to do is we need to go over to the
menu.
And if I log out real quick, what we want to achieve here is that I want each and every one of you
to sign up.
And so you're going to fill in your own email address, your own username and password, and you're
going to enroll into the developer services.
And then once you create the account, well, then we're going to log in.
And so over here, you can see that I filled out my username and password, and once I login, I will
be welcome back into XPO.
And so you'll be greeted with this developer page in which you can go and you can see your home, your
builds, your snacks, you're setting all of these things that we're going to get into.
But the number one thing that I pointed out is that we need to get a snack.
And again, not potato chips, although I do recommend if we go over to snacks, what we're going to
see here is that I have my own focused IMAP, but I want each and every one of you to create your own
snack.
And I want you to call it focus time.
And then when you save that, well, now you have a completed stack.
And this sneck.
You can run, you can run it over here in this right hand pain, and the whole point of this is that
Expo's giving you this entire environment that you can run a Riak native app and call in at the same
time.
So if we go over here to iOS, we say tap to play.
We're going to run the app that we are currently looking at, and so it says over here, hey, change
the code in the editor and watch it change on the phone.
So if I change it over here to change and I'm not coding in the most clean way you can see over here,
it changed to change.
So this is the environment in which we are going to create focus time.
So now that you're set up, well, now we can get to coding.
We can dive deep into creating focus time, our first fully fledged mobile iOS and Android app.
I am excited.