While our bill is running, we can also go and look at the specific logs so we can see what it's going
through, what it's doing, starting the build process, getting the icons, resolving the native modules,
reading the manifest, and then going through the gradle build, which is Android's build tool of choice.
That's going to take all of the information, all of the native code, all of our JavaScript code and
build the output of our application.
And once that is done, what we'll see is a built artifact.
So what we have to do right now is wait for all eight steps to complete once it's gone through all the
steps.
What we have here is what's called a build artifact.
So it's taken all of our code and it's built out that apk that Android package that we can now install
on our phones.
And if we look over here, we can see the logs of the build and see specifically what happened with
the build.
And what we can see over here in our builds is the actual artifact.
So we're able now to download this by pressing this button and what we'll get is the actual app.
So this is the downloadable file of our application.
If we go to download and we take that app and we drag it into our emulator or you send it to your phone,
it's going to install meals to go on our phone as a production build.
So we're going to be able to now see over here meals to go as a standalone application.
It's no longer inside of that XML framework.
And if we press that, it's going to launch missiles to go for us as a native app.
So we can see here is our splash screen coming in and it's loading and optimizing all of the assets.
We can see our app come in here with a nice background feed.
And if we click login, what we can see is Moe at Beeny, Dot Io.
And if we press password test one, two, three and we hit login will come into our application and
we'll be able to see all of our information that we had previously loaded.
And so now that our information is loading on our apk and we have everything ready for Android, one
shortcoming that I need to show you is our settings panel will work as intended.
But when we click the maps integration in a production level build standalone app, we're running into
an error.
It won't render out the map.
It just basically crashes the app.
And this is because if we go over here to our map, USDA deploying a standalone app to Android, you
have to integrate something called Google Sinon or a Google Maps API key.
If you've done the bonus section on the integration of Google Maps into our application, you know that
you require payment information in order to set up Google Cloud in order to do this.
And this highlights all of the steps that you would need to go through in order to integrate that Google
Maps API key step by step and put it in your app, JSON, in order to get that crash to go away.
Now we're trying to showcase the app release procedure and so we don't want to integrate this just for
now, but be aware that certain packages that we use, for instance, the Google Maps package in order
to render our app when we want to release to the Google Play store, will have the additional requirement
of needing to integrate Google Cloud as well and integrate the API key.
And so you can always come back here and go through these steps specifically if you want to release
a production grade app with a maps integration to the app and play store.