Now they come back and they say, hey, well, the restaurant info card component, right, restaurant
info card.
Well, this component is basically elevating, and I don't like how far to drop shadow is, could you
lessen that?
So you say, yeah, sure, let's just put it to two.
And by sending it to two and quickly refreshing, we quickly notice that the bleed is way less in there,
like, oh, that looks amazing.
Crisp.
They're also like, hey, the map screen.
So you go to the map screen, could you zoom in a bit more and you say, well, I've researched this
for a long time and the lowest level that we could give it is zero point zero one, which is potentially
a bit closer, but but not by much.
And so they're like, OK, OK, that's fine.
How about looking at the cart?
You're like, well, what about the card?
So you look at the checkout screen and you're like, what about the carts?
Wrong.
And so you quickly notice, oh, we forgot something here.
Just a code wise.
You're like, oh, we forgot to add a key.
So you say key is equal to and then you say item dash.
I and you quickly add the index here and so.
Another react warning on not really something the designer was concerned with, but you noticed it because
you were looking at the coat and so they're like.
Well, in the checkout, could we potentially add a divider before the name and put like, sure we can,
so you go ahead and from react native paper, you grab the divider.
And down here by the name and put.
Right here, they say, OK, add the divider, so you add it and there you go, the visualisations is
there, they're like, oh, could you add a bit more spacing in your like?
Sure I can.
I have a spacer.
So you quickly put a spacer before the divider and they're like, OK, that looks much better.
Great, that looks clean.
And you're like, thank you.
So then they're looking at the favorites screen, right, the favorites bar, rather, and they're looking
at it and they're they're asking themselves, hey, well, when I add favorites, when I look at the
favorites bar, it's kind of weird that it's breaking the UI while we're scrolling.
Right.
That shouldn't happen.
And so you go ahead and you think to yourself, huh, huh, how am I going to fix that?
Well, you go to the favorite bar.
And you think to yourself, well, right now the favorite rapper is a view.
Huh?
OK, well, you know, let's get react native people in here, maybe I can use something from there.
So you go ahead and you test something out, you say, well, let's grab a card.
And you say, well, let's wrap styled with a card instead and we'll leave the padding.
We'll add a Z index of nine nine nine.
And you put an elevation of three.
And so they go ahead and they look at it and they're like, oh, that divide is way nicer.
At least I can see now where the favorite spa begins and ends.
Great.
But could you potentially add some rounding to the corners?
And you say, sure.
So you do border radius of 15, 15 pixels, rather.
And so at that point, the rounding is happening here very subtly in the corners to create even more
visual separation.
And they say, oh, that looks great.
That looks pretty good.
Amazing.
Just with those couple of lines of changes, we've visually reinterred faced our app almost right.
The purple theme, the small adjustments here and there.
And that is what good UI setup allows you to do.