In the last video we left off doing XPO in it, Miles, to go, an expert in meals to go was going through
the command line interface of XPO and showing us.
How to set up a project and we're able to use our arrow keys to choose a specific version.
Now, the default, the blank, the empty canvas is what we want.
And we want to do it in the managed workflow, because in XPO you have a managed and Abair workflow.
Now, a managed workflow is where explosive is going to do a lot of stuff for you and manage your project.
A better workflow is where you're going to go bare bones.
Just get the essentials.
Now we want the managed approach because it gives us a lot more of exposed tooling and expertise and
backing to build quickly.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to choose blank and that's going to set up, download
and install all of the dependencies for meals to go.
And you can see in my projects folder now meals to go exists and it's setting it up for us.
So once it's done, installing all of the dependencies and going through the process of getting everything
ready, we'll be ready to hit the ground running for our master project.
Amazing.
It's that easy.
All right.
I'll see you in the next video.