Right now, we have our focus time running locally on an Iowa simulator, and we got that far, but
now the next step is, well, how do we get it running locally on an Android simulator?
And that's a good question.
First of all, to do Android development, you need something called the Android SDK, but in order
to download the Android estimate, there are multiple, multiple ways we're going to show you the simplest
path forward.
And that's something called Android Studio, the fastest tool for building on every type of Android
device.
And this is made in conjunction with jet brains.
And this free tool is basically what a lot of developers use to develop Android applications and it
ships with all of the information that you need.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to press download under a studio.
We're going to say I have read and agreed to the above terms and we're going to download it for Mac.
We're going to allow the download to come through.
And once it's downloaded, we're going to run through the installation process.
All right, so another downloader we're going to see something called Android Studio ID, we're going
to press that in a press that download and it's going to start opening that download file.
And once that's fully opened up, what we're going to see is the start of the installation procedure.
So what we're going to do is we're going to drag Android studio into applications.
And that's going to put all the necessary files in place for us to be able to use Android studio.
All right, amazing, now that we've downloaded and applied and receiving applications, let's see what
other steps we need to take.