The moment is upon us.
We're about to code and I'm going to give you your very, very first exercise.
Now, this exercise may seem simple from the get go, but what we're trying to do here is set up the
layout for our restaurant list components.
So we're building our very first feature.
And the very first feature is we're going to build a restaurant list and it's going to have the ability
to search for a specific location and then load the restaurants in that location.
Now, before we get ahead of ourselves, we need to first go back to first principles.
How do we render out the spacing for the search and the spacing for the list?
Now, keep in mind, this will change as we go along and shift and change and as we play around with
properties.
But for our first exercise, what I want you to do is I want you to render two views, a search for
you with a green background and a list view with a blue background.
And I want you to space them apart.
And as you can see, it's a little hint here.
There seems to be a little bit of spacing around searching around list.
Could that be padding?
And another thing to notice here is that there's white at the top and white at the bottom.
So it's like we're avoiding.
The parts of the screen that the user still has to interact with in order to do things interesting,
so.
Another tip here, could that be something called safe area of you, who knows, take away from this
exercise that we need to go look at the docks of safe area of you and we need to position two views
with text that look exactly like this.
And in the next video, I'll show you how I solved it.
Now, again, it's not to say that you can't build the user interface in different ways with different
properties and different spacing.
I fully applaud you in taking whatever we build here and giving it your own flair.
But I'm going to show you the way that I'm going to build the UI and the properties that I will apply.
And in the end, we'll have a great product.
And you may have slightly differing styling and that's completely OK as long as it works on all the
phones you're testing on.
But for now, we're going to try to focus on first principles.
So let's try to get this output going.
All right.