So in the previous video, we mentioned that, hey, whatever we called in here, whatever we do at
all, we can run it on our own device.
We don't need to use these iOS and Android tabs and Web tabs.
We can run it on our own device.
Now, how do we go about that?
Well, if you were to go into the App Store, what we would be searching for and this is the exact same
for both iOS and Android, just the different store, whether or not you use the play store or the Apple
App Store, you're going to be searching for XPO.
And what you're specifically going to be looking for is the client and you're going to download that.
And as you can see, I already have it installed.
So that's great.
And so now, just because I have the app, I can actually go directly into my camera and I can scan
this QR code and it's going to say, hey, open it and XPO.
And then when I open it and XPO now I can suddenly see all of my code changes.
Now it's opening my project locally and it's saying device connected.
So at any given point, if I make these changes and I save them, you can now see them happen live.
Right.
And it is absolutely amazing.
We can just see this live on our device.
No need for anything other than the app.
And a quick QR scan.
That's how easy it is.
And hey, if you're having some difficulties, we can always go back to the U.S. and Android app and
make it easy on ourselves.
So there's multiple ways to see what you're doing if you only have a nice device.
Well, here you have the Android app.
You only have an Android device.
Well, let's run it on iOS as well to just see what we're doing.
That is the power of an XPO snack.
It's better than a bag of potato chips, I promise you that.