Now that we have our request in our transform function down, one of the things that we really need
to look at is more or less the component that we built.
So in the component we built, we had these two properties is closed temporarily and is open now.
Now, these are properties that if we go look at our actual data, right, our mark data, we don't
really have and is closed temporarily.
Right.
Or is underscore closed temporarily.
What we have is an opening hours and then an open now property on it.
That's true or false.
And the same is true for a closed.
We have a business status which is equal to close temporarily.
So in this case, what we have to do is we have to do a transform and not transform.
Is part of this so Canalis is the first part of this transform, but in order for us to actually figure
out what needs to happen, we need to first and foremost map the results.
Right.
So what is the result?
Well, the result that we're trying to get at here is an array.
So it's the array of results.
OK, well, good to know.
So first of all, what we need to look at here is.
Our result has a result that results that length, and if we open our terminal over here, what we'll
see now is that it has a length of 20.
So that is the actual restaurant results.
OK, good to know.
So we know that result has results on it and we'll default that to an empty array.
Because that's the one that we want and then we'll know now that we can call results at length, which
is 20.
OK, now, caramelizing will be the last step, caramelizing will be the step that we do from the output.
So first of all, let's return results.
But what we want to do is we want to say consed mapped results is equal to results.
Dot map and a map is a function that will iterate over every individual restaurant and will return us
if we return like for instance, one and we consult the logs map results.
Right.
Then we're going to see that we're going to see one second there seems to be a small problem here.
Well, I put it at the wrong spot, so right here, that's going to and then we'll cancel that log.
I have to put this in here, I was outside of the function body and then what we'll see is that at the
bottom here, right?
What else do we have?
Consolo logging.
So let's remove this for a second.
And what we'll see is that we're printing one 20 times.
OK, so why are we printing one 120 times?
Because we're returning one.
So what we want to do here is we want to return the original restaurant.
But we also want to adapt some properties, so what we're going to say now is that we're going to have
a property is closed.
Temporarily.
And this is going to check if.
The business status is set to temporarily closed, so we're going to say restaurant.
That business status is equal to closed temporarily and then we're going to have is open now as well,
is open now and that is going to say, well, if the restaurant, the DOT and then we'll say opening
hours.
And and restaurants are opening hours that open now.
Then we know if it's open now or not.
OK, so what's going on here now?
Well, what we can say is that our map results have additional properties, is open now, is false because
open now is false and is closed temporarily is false.
So we add a D and now what we need to do is we need to take our mapped results and return those and
we're going to caramelize those specifically.
So we're going to take the original information.
We're not stripping it away.
We're adding additional properties and we're caramelizing the rest of the results.
And so that in itself allows us to look at the information.
Be assured that the information that we're looking at here is of the right type, so if we scroll up
beyond the errors here and I add back my console log down here, what we're going to see is now we have
the business status, which is upper case.
So we're leaving the original information, but we're also adding information.
We're adding to properties is close temporarily and is open now, which are two boolean flags that we
need for the rest of the information.
Awesome.
So we have our request and we have our transformer, but now the question becomes, well, how do I
utilize this?
And that's a good question.
So first and foremost, what we need to do is we need to go inside of here and we need to remove this
restaurant request because that's not the place that we want to use it.
We don't want to use it over here and we don't want to console that log.
Let's take the restaurant.
Restaurant request, request, where is it, where did I use it so oh yeah, because I imported it already
worked, OK.
So with that, now that we've removed that here and we don't need this anymore because we're going to
use this somewhere else, we now have our request and our transform ready to use, but we have to figure
out how to use it.
So in the next video, we'll be setting up our context, which is going to be doing the request for
us and also exposing the data globally.