Now that we got all of that out of the way, and now that you fully understand the snack interface and
how snacks work before we dive very deep into coding, there's one thing I want you to do.
Over here on my snack, you can see that I have something called the Focus Time demo.
Now, the one thing I want you to do is very simply go to your camera app point and click at this QR
code and open it in the Expo app.
And now what you're going to be able to do is play around with the app that we built.
And be able to work with the demo that is available to you, so let's say mowing the lawn and we say,
OK, that's good.
Let's add that.
And now we can play around with the demo that I showed you in the very first video.
And so you can get a feel of what exactly it is we're building and you can get a feel of, hey, what
is exactly what's going on here?
And if we close this and I reinstall it, what exactly is going to happen?
And you can try this again and again and you can always come back to this demo.
And because it's in your XPO app, you can also see, hey, mowing the lawn stayed around.
This is also a feature we're going to build.
It's called Storing the focus items.
We're going to do that.
And we can also clear them so that, hey, they're not a problem anymore.
We focused on too many items.
So we're going to be able to run this demo locally on our phone.
We're going to be able to understand what exactly it is we're building.
And while you're building your application, you can always reach back to our demo just to get a better
understanding of, hey, what exactly is it we're building?
And so over here at this you URL, this is where you can find the snack and we'll make sure to put this
in the resources on the video so that you can reach to it.