All right, so it's time for the solution.
OK, so I kind of gave you some tips as we went along.
I told you about safe area of you, and I also told you about the potential of this needing padding
for it to breathe.
So if we go look at our solution here, what we're seeing in the code is the ability for.
Safe area of you to wrap the views that contain both the search and the list.
Now, why use safe area of you?
Well, let's go look at the docks.
Right.
So if we look at the docks and we look at Sieff, area of you will safe area of you is the purpose of
it is to render content within the safe area boundaries of the device.
It is currently only applicable to iOS devices with iOS version 11 or Leeta.
So safe area of you Nest's the content and renders the proportion that is not covered by navigation
bars.
The tab bars, the tool bars and all that good stuff.
Now we saw that right because we see over here in iOS at the bottom here and at the top here.
Right.
It's not interfering with the top in the bottom, so it's rendering the content in the safe area.
So this is what we would consider the safe area from here to here.
Amazing.
OK, so then we go look at what actually needs to happen within it.
So we put a view here and we said the padding needed to be 16.
Why did the padding need to be 16?
Because if we set it to zero, all the search bar doesn't have any breathing room.
Oh, that's so intense.
So we'll set it to 16.
Right.
And now it feels better.
Now it feels like it has adequate space to fill content in.
And so I don't like to give things fixed heights because I like to see how things grow before I go and
say, hey, you need this height or you need this height.
I like to see things dynamically grow and I like to use flex to kind of position things and see how
things fit on the screen first.
OK, we said that the safe area of view.
Was going to give us, well, the safe area, right, safe area here, safe area here.
Why did we need to give it Fleck's one?
What was the purpose of that?
Well, like we said, if we have a root container.
And we don't give it a flex property by default, it's just going to grow with the content that's inside
it, it's not going to assume any type of height.
But when we give it flex one, what we're saying is, hey, Phil, your parent in this case, the parent
is the app.
So we're saying, hey, if any of you make sure you always fill the parent and then we're saying, OK,
this view, we're not really going to give it a flex property because we don't really care about it's
Flexner's.
We're just going to say, hey, whatever goes in here is going to grow dynamically.
What are we decide to put five searches or we decide to put one search.
It's just going to grow based on on the demand.
And so with that list, we'll get smaller on its own.
It's not going to overflow.
We're telling it to fill the parent.
And OK, so it's filling the parent, but it's not overflowing in any way, shape or form.
It's saying, well, I have this thing above me, so I'll basically taken the rest of the space.
Well, that looks good.
We gave it a padding of 16 pixels and we gave it a background color of blue.
Now, you could have done this in a very different way.
You could have said, well, hey, you know, the height here is going to be one hundred percent and
all that good stuff.
And that would have worked just as well.
But now, look, it's overflowing.
It's not really constraining itself to the boundaries.
It kind of flows over.
Right.
So Flex one is basically telling it, hey, stick to the constraints of the screen.
That's why we use it.
Now, you could have done something more flexible and said, like, I'm going to give it a fixed height,
I'm going to give it a height of three hundred or I'm going to give it five hundred and I'm going to
I'm going to keep going until it gets to the right spot.
But this isn't really dynamic.
It's not really going to fill with the phone.
So you can see how Flex is super powerful here and why we use it.
So we put the status bar over here at the bottom.
And as you can see, we wrapped it with these two fragment columns.
And so for those of you who are not familiar with fragments, they allow us to render two elements side
by side without having to wrap it in a specific other container.
For instance, if we said, well, let's put a view around this, well, now everything's broken because
this view does not have style flecks, one to tell it to fill the parent container.
And then this one needs to fill the parent of the parent.
Because if we remove this here, well, now suddenly this is just going to take in the space of this
one.
So it's important to determine, hey, what is our container and what is it trying to fill?
Is it trying to fill the space of the parent of itself?
And so I like to give background colors to the things that are trying to fill certain areas.
Right.
Like you could have gone and said, well, let's give this a height of one hundred percent, but now
you don't really see it.
But once you give it a background color of orange, you're going to see it do some odd things right.
It's going to overflow in the safe area boundaries.
It's overflowing in the safe area boundary.
So we don't want to do that either.
So Fleck's one respects the proportionality of the application.
Important to note here.
Now let's look at what that looks like on Android.
Oh, no, oh, no.
Look at this here, it's not respecting it's not respecting the safe area.
Why is that?
Well, like we said, the safe area of you only supports AOS.
So how do we go about solving this?
Well, that's a good question.
Let's look at that in the next video.