Hey, now that we've got our Strib client all set up and ready to rock and roll and we're ready to start
building out this integration that we put together here, where we're going to first pull in the credit
card info, create the Strib token and pass it to the checkout and so forth, like any other feature.
Let's start with the simple things we can put together.
And if we look here at our fully integrated app, what we can see is that over here at the bottom,
we have this checkout tap and this checkout tab shows us where we're checking out from what we're ordering.
We can potentially clear the cart, show an empty cart and all of that good stuff.
Now, as with everything else, this comes from a place of configuration.
So let's step back, put together the building blocks for this route and for everything that needs to
be put in place for us to build out the holistic feature.
And if we look at that from a point of view of getting everything ready, what we need to do is use
our App Navigator in order to set up the screen.
So let's get to that.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to create a tab screen called Checkout.
And that checkout screen is going to accept the component called checkout screen.
That checkout screen is going to come from the same place where we take all our screens.
So we're going to duplicate this line.
We're going to take checkout screen, but we're not going to take it from features map.
No, we're going to say features, checkout screens, checkout dot screen, and that's where we're going
to get checkout screen from.
And so that checkout screen is going to.
Render out where we're going to build checkout now over here in the Tabbaa icon, we can obviously note
that checkout isn't going to necessarily be a map, know what it's going to be as an MD cart.
And by doing this, we're setting ourselves up for success.
Now, let's see, is our app running?
So over here, what we want to do is start.
And then once we start up our client, what we can do over here is go over to the loaded app that's
running locally.
And by utilizing that, we can figure out what exactly we've just put on the screen.
Whoops.
Oh, can't resolve.
Check out that screen.
Well, that's obvious.
We don't have it set up yet.
So what we need to do is we need to create a new folder called Checkout and Features.
And in checkout, we've got to create a new folder called Screens.
And then inside of screens will create checkout dot screen dogs.
And so we'll import react from react.
And we'll just quickly say export content checkout screen is equal to the return of no.
And if we return null, then we'll temporarily just render out nothing or reload here.
And what we'll be able to see is that our app should load up just fine.
And if we then go ahead and log in, what we're going to see is that our app is going to load test one,
two, three and we log in.
But there's a problem here.
We're not retrieving any data and that's because our is mark is set to false.
So let's go ahead and set that to true.
And on top of that, what we need to do is make sure that our local firebase is running.
So let's go ahead and do that.
And so if you are running in Android mode, what you're going to want to do is you're going to want
to run deploy these functions in order to be able to run the app.
And you're going to want to set the live host to always be the available host because otherwise it will
not work.
Now, if if this is tricky for you, please reach back to the videos where we did the Google integration
to refresh your memory on how to get this working.
Now, there were in the functions folder, let's go ahead and look how we start up our functions.
So in the package, Jason, you can see here that we have an enhanced surf command.
So we'll do yard surf and by doing that, will serve up our emulators in order for our functions to
run locally on our computer.
And we're going to be running them in a mock mode.
Now, your functions could not be passed due to an issue with your node modules.
So let's make sure that we install all of the modules that are required and then serve up our emulators
once more.
And as we can see here, our functions are now running on Port Thousand.
Our app is running.
And if we go ahead and refresh our app over here like I did right, we all know how to do this.
You'll see that the mock data comes and populates itself.
And what we can also see is that our checkout route is now rendering its rendering.
Nothing, of course, and nothing is visual right here, right now.
But we have our route, our screen and our tabs set up.
So we have the canvas on which we can start painting our feature.
So let's get to that.