In our last video, we left off being able to take a picture and we know that the photo has particular
properties that enable us to know where a photo is being stored.
We have a photo uteri.
Now the question becomes, well, how are we going to store this photo and where should we store this
photo?
And if we store the photo, will we actually be able to access it properly?
Now, the way that I went about starting the photo is the same way that we saw the favorites, I stored
them on the phone against a reference of the user.
And by doing that, I now know every time that this user logs into this phone that they'll have the
photo linked to their account by their unique identifier.
And the way that I did that is, again, we need to use async storage, so let's go take a look at how
we utilized async storage to begin with in the services favourite's.
We are the favorites context in the favorites context.
We imported something called async storage.
So if we take that property and we import it inside of our camera component, we can now utilize that
in order to store the photo information for the user.
I hear you asking MOED, shouldn't this be a service?
We followed the service pattern everywhere in this context pattern.
Here's the separation that I see.
Favourite's was used practically globally.
It could be used anywhere in the application.
Authentication is used globally.
Locations use globally, restaurants is used globally.
But the profile picture, the picture of the user is only used on the settings screen inside of the
settings feature.
Therefore, I view it as a local consideration of the settings feature in order to store and retrieve
its async storage information for this profile camera feature.
What we'll do then is when we take the photo, we now know that we can utilize async storage and so
what we'll do is say async storage, that set item, and we'll set the item based on the user user ID
dash photo.
So the user ID photo.
And we'll know now that photo Dorai is part of that user ID photo.
OK, well, how do we get how do we get the user ID?
Well, first we need to bring in the authentication context because without the authentication context,
we can't get the user's information.
And then what we do is at the top over here underneath camera will say const user is use context of
authentication context, which we need to pull in from react in order to utilize.
So now we have the user's information and we can reference user that user ID.
And by doing this, we know that we'll have a user because you're only enabled to go to the settings
screen when you're logged in, you won't be able to utilize the settings screen otherwise.
So over here, we've basically implemented the saving of the photo and by saving the photo, now, what
we've done is save that photo.
You are right that that storage of that picture element.
We need to retrieve it somewhere, and that's going to be inside of the setting screen, so we'll pull
an async storage there as well at the top.
And what we need to do in the setting screen is we need to pull in the actual implementation of async
storage, get item down here somewhere.
Now, how are we going to go about that?
Well, it's a good question.
We could we could use a bunch of different things.
What I want to use is use effect and by using use effect, what we can do is any time the user comes
in to this screen will do use effect.
And we'll render out their profile image now, should we do this only on render?
Yeah, that sounds right.
We'll do it every time this screen renders because we should only ever load it once.
Well, maybe we should do it if the user changes, because that would make more sense.
Any time the user changes, we should technically get the new profile picture, right?
Yeah, that's that seems like a better idea.
So what we'll do is we'll write a function called.
Get profile picture and what we'll see here is that it's an async function again, because it's going
to work with async storage.
And that async function is going to say consed photo.
Is equal to a weight of async storage target item.
And the get item is going to retrieve this identifier right here, let's make sure that we copy the
correct portion and if we just put that inside of it, we get item call.
Now we're insured that we get the photo uteri.
So let's call that photo uteri.
And once we have the photo, you or I, we can use state.
So we'll store the photo.
You are I, you state and we'll say const.
Set photo is equal to you state.
And then when we set the photo here to photo you or I will be ensured that once the photo is actually
loaded, so we'll do get a profile picture here.
Once the photo is loaded, we'll know whether or not we should render an Avatar icon or something else.
So if we don't have a photo, render out the Avatar icon.
Right.
But if we do have a photo.
Well, what do we need to render out in that case?
Well, there's something else that Avatar exposes and that is Avatar, that image.
And instead of an icon, what we'll give it is a you are I saw a source and we'll say just like an image
and we'll say you are I is photo.
The only difference here is that we'll do it when we do have a photo, and by doing this, we've now
created the end to end feature for the photo.
So let's test it out.
If I go over here and I take a picture and then I go back, it's not loading.
Why is it not loading?
Well, first of all, over here we have a dependency.
So we're putting in user, but we're not putting in get a profile picture.
So that's our first error.
And then over here, this is using the user.
So we have to invert.
This will give the user to get profile picture instead of just getting it like that.
So we'll say current user.
And we'll give it as a dependency and we'll see over here current user user ID.
And then the other thing we should give it is the ability to render, because, as you can see now it
rendered.
And it actually took in the photo.
Now, that is interesting, it took in the photo, but when we take a photo over here and we go back,
let's let's take a photo of something else, because otherwise it's just going to look let's take a
photo like this.
What we can see over here is it's not changing.
And that's because use effect only gets triggered if this re mounts.
So there's something else that we could use is something called use focus effect, use focus.
Effect is an effect from react native navigation rather than use effect where any time the.
The screen gets back into focus through navigation or the user changes, we're going to enable get profile
picture to trigger.
So if we go over to settings and we then take a picture here and we go back and we take a picture again
and we go back, we can see that our picture is being triggered every time we get back into focus of
the setting screen.
So this is a Riak native navigation feature that is kind of like use effect, but it only triggers it
triggers every time the screen is back into focus.
So any time we go back and forth between screens, we're going to trigger this as well as when the user
changes.
So we have both situations covered.
OK.
So we have our debt profile picture, which is the async function that takes in the parameter of user
so that any time the user changes were ensured, that user is being given to the get item so that we
get the item.
We have use focus effect that ensures any time a navigation event happens that we're going to trigger
the jet profile picture as well, because any time we take a picture, it's going to update.
But one thing we don't have here is when SNAP happens, when SNAP is happening, we're not navigating
back.
So let's take in navigation here because this is a screen.
And let's say once we set an item, let's do navigation, but go back.
And by doing navigation that go back will enable the screen once we take a picture to go back and thus
enable the full fledged feature of the camera taking experience.
And that's exactly what we want.
So any time the user takes a picture, they'll go back, they'll take the picture if we log them out
here and we log into a different user model plus two.
And we need audio.
And let's say test one, two, three, and we log them in, what we can see over here is that in the
settings they don't have a picture.
But if we load a picture like this where we take a specific picture of that now, they're going to have
this picture.
If we go and we log in at NMO at Beedi, that we do test one, two, three and we log in.
What we're going to see in the settings panel, the picture is loading and if we go back to MO plus
to add beneath audio.
And we do test one, two, three.
We're going to load that specific picture for MO plus two, and that is exactly what we want.
We want to load the specific picture for the specific user that's being logged in at that moment.
Awesome.
So we have the full end to end feature working now, and it only took this much coat, just a couple
of lines, a good back and forth between the camera screen and the settings screen.
And we now have the ability to store and retrieve the picture that the user takes any time they go back
and forth between the screens.