We have our geocode function mocked and working in a local firebase function.
Next up, we have a second API that we have to emulate or mimic right now, and that is the police's
nearby search request.
Currently, we have a bunch of mock information from this API in a certain shape that mimics it, that
we that we are returning to our application.
But now we want to integrate this.
But before we integrate it, we want to also move our mock into our firebase function so that we can
prove that our app continues to work and move the request into the firebase function that acts like
a server locally.
Now, how are we going to do that?
Well, first off, we need to go over here into our functions folder and we need to go to our index.
And over here you see exports start geocode.
Now, this is what is releasing a geocode function over here.
If we look at our functions, we have a geocode that will be executed.
OK, so we're going to create a second function and we're going to call it places nearby.
Now, places nearby is what's going to give us the ability to basically do a places request.
So we're going to create a places request and this is going to come from places.
So we need to create a places folder.
And once we create a places folder, we'll create an index file inside of that places folder and we'll
module exports thought, places request.
And that's going to take in request and response.
And now we can do response dots and places request.
Once we do this, what we can do is we can go over to our terminal and we can see here places nearby
has been released.
Now, if we go down here, we can see that functions, index, et cetera, et cetera.
We were unable to load your code because they cannot find the module places.
So places that index index here.
Let's just quickly reload.
And then let's reload over here and we can see that it has, in fact loaded now.
So if we go to this URL, what we're going to see is here is our placeholder for our places request
now that we have our placeholder for our places request.
Well, the next thing we need to do is we need to go look at how we were doing our request originally.
Originally, our restaurant request was a request that was just taking the box and the mock images from
Moch.
OK, so let's get rid of this.
We know that we are going to need this, but let's get rid of this code and then let's remove the mock
folder and let's move the mock folder all the way up to the Places folder.
And we're going to need to do some massaging to the information that's in here, first of all, all
of these imports need to become requires because the node cannot understand import, but it does understand
require.
So we're going to change it all to be required.
So now that we're requiring Antwerp, Jason in Chicago, Jason, we're going to change the Jason files
to be just regular old JavaScript files, because that's a bit easier to understand for note.
And we'll do module exports, dot marks over here and we're going to just leave this as const Mok's
for now because we're going to do something interesting.
Now what we need to do is we need to change our JSON file to actually be a JavaScript file.
So we're going to rename every single one of them to dogs.
And once we do that, what we're going to do is we're going to say module exports.
So we're going to do a default export.
Over here, and we're going to save this file, and if we save it, you'll see that prettier in Iceland
will take over and we'll rename this file and once we rename that file, we'll do the same at the top,
will say Modula, our exports, and we'll do this for every file.
And this is just so that Noad can better understand the file.
The reason we use the initial use JSON is because it was the original format of the information.
But you could just as well just export an object in a JavaScript file and it will work the exact same
way.
So over here will change this to Toronto docs and then will module that exports.
And once we do that, we're basically good to go over here now that we have all of this information,
what we need to do is in our places in next year, we now need to import our mocs.
So we can't do an import, we need to do consed Mock's is equal to the require of thought.
Mark.
And then once we have our marks, what we can do is we can say, well, how are we going to get a specific
mark?
Our specific markets are Antwerp's, Chicago, et cetera, et cetera, and they're based on this longitude,
latitude string.
Well, if we go back to our geocode request over here, what we saw in the Geocode request is that we
were able to get Querrey parameters off of the URL.
So how about we do the same thing?
We'll do a places.
We'll do we'll do a parsing and we'll look for something called location on the URL.
Now we also need to import the euro currency.
Consuelo's require euro.
And once we do that, we can say location over here, so let's go take a look at what that looks like.
So if we say now, questionmark, location equals location, something like that.
Well, that currently our server is probably crashing on some error, so let's go look at the terminal
and what we can see is that export consed mock images is currently breaking, which is why this should
be consed.
And once we do that, we can just restart our function here.
And once we restart that, we can reload here and we can say location equals location.
And then we can say some location.
And we can see that we're rendering out the query parameter now, once we have that query parameter,
what we can do over here is we can go inside of here and we can say, well, then return me marks of
the location.
And when we do that, if I do this for some location, obviously I'm not going to get anything, but
if I go over here to the index and I copy this and I put this as the location, well, now I'm getting
information back because this matches the information that is required as the key of the information.
If I change this to Sam.
And I just said save and I did over here, Sam, let's let's say location and then empty.
And I said, well, now the key is sand.
So it's going to load that key.
So now the location is going to be a long itude latitude, comma, separated.
Great.
Now that we have that working, there was one more thing that we needed to do over here in our service.
When we did our transform, we were changing the photos of the restaurants in the results.
So let's take that away, because that's a very specific change that we should be doing on the server
for the market information.
And what we'll do is we'll see module thought exports that add mock images is equal to taking in the
restaurant.
And then we'll say that it does restaurant photos.
Instead of doing a map here, we're just going to return one singular array and we'll do this, will
remove this.
That should do it for us.
I believe.
Now, this one closes that one.
Remove that and now we have a restaurant that photos is equal to a specific mock image, const random
image.
Let's do this bit more readable and we'll say that restaurant photos is equal to some random image.
And then we'll return.
The restaurant itself, now, what we can do is we can go inside of our function.
And we can say that CONSED data is equal to the Marks location and we can say data that results is equal
to.
Data, dot results, dot map.
And then we'll say add mock image.
Now, is that what I specifically called it?
I will say add image.
So then what we'll do is we'll import ADNOC image, and once we do that, we'll do respon start JSON
of data.
So now we overwrote data results and we made sure that we add the mock image in case we need it.
OK, so now if I reload this, what's going to happen?
Well.
Let's go ahead and restart our emulators, and once we do that, what I can do is reload here and it
says cannot read properly results of undefined.
So we should only do this if data is available.
So if we have data, then we'll do this.
And then if we refresh, that should work, so let's go grab a long itude lattitude.
And we'll grab Antwerp.
And we'll put that in and what we can see here is that Footies is now being put in as the image, OK?
So with all of that, do you think her appeal just work out of the box?
Have we migrated it properly?
Well, let's go reload over here and let's see.
So finish geocode and then, oh.
Oh, we still need to implement the service call here, we don't have a request happening, so let's
go over here and let's take the same thing that we did over here.
And let me show you how simple this is.
We'll do a fetch, but instead of the Geocode, we'll do it to places nearby and we'll say that the
city location is equal to location.
And by doing this now, what we're able to see is that our app works with Moqtada that is now coming
from the server.
So we've moved all of our mock information.
All of that is now a server call.
It is coming specifically from the API.
Now, another thing that we should probably do if we're going to do this is over here in our location
service.
What we did is we have a council log here.
And in our context, I believe that in one of these requests, either the restaurants or something else,
we put a set time out around the request, which we shouldn't do anymore because we did this because
we were trying to emulate it, loading from a server.
Now that it is loading from a server, we shouldn't do that anymore.
And what we can see here is that we'll have instant returns.
It's still loading.
It's a bit slower than just getting it locally because it's getting it from the firebase function that's
running locally, but it's still pretty fast.
So if we go to Antwerp here now, we'll see it loads.
It loads for half a second and then we get our mock information back.
And just like that, all of our services have been migrated to a firebase function that can now be deployed.