We've set up our canvas to start painting our feature.
Now, I know I'm not Picasso.
I get it, but I think we can build a pretty awesome checkout feature.
And the way that we're going to do it is we're going to take all of the principles that we've learned
so far and we're going to start thinking about what we need to do.
Now, if we go back over here and we look at our diagram, what we're going to see is that the user
needs to input their credit card information in order for us to create a payment.
Now we've set up our checkout canvas on which we are going to start our payment process.
But in order for us to do our payment process, credit card info needs to be fed into this feature right
there.
Not it's not so much that this user flow is independent, right?
It's not that checkout happens here.
Credit card info happens here where we're talking about what the user interacts with.
So the user fills in their credit card info, gets the token, and then you start your checkout flow.
But the credit card information is still being inputted on the checkout screen.
So in order for us to do this, what we're going to need to do is get some type of credit card input
visualized on the screen so that we can start building on our.
Feature to get the straight talking going before we set up Stripe.
Well, the first thing we're going to need is some type of credit card.
So let's take a look at that.
Now, let's go ahead and take what we have here, go over to our code base and install it like we've
installed so, so many packages throughout the course.
So I'm going to open up a new terminal.
And what I'm going to do is Yorn react native credit card input, Yahav rather raclette credit card
input.
That's going to add it to my code base.
And once it's been added, then I can go ahead and use it.
Now, the way that we need to use this is a bit different than what you may think.
What we're going to do is we're going to go inside our features folder, check out, and we're going
to create a new folder inside of Check-Out called Components and inside of Components.
We're going to create a component called the credit card component.
Component, but, yes, now this credit card component is going to be the baseline where we're going
to utilize our credit card information.
So the way that we do that is we're going to say export CONSED credit card input.
Is equal to and then we're going to render out null for now, let's close this up here and let's focus
on the code we're going to import react from react.
And then we're going to focus on some of the imports that we need, so we're going to import from the
library.
We're going to import the light creditcard input and we're going to do the like credit card input from
react need of credit card input.
Now, why the light credit card?
Well, the light credit card in and it seems I have a small typo here, the light credit card input
looks a little bit like this right here.
We don't want the big juggernaut of a card doing all its stuff.
No, we want the simple, simplistic kind of look.
So let's not that we have that.
Let's look at what we can do inside of our render function.
So inside of our render function, what we're going to do is we're going to do a return here and inside
of the return.
Well, what we need to return is the light credit card input, but we need to give it some functions
to hook into.
And that function, as you can see here, is the on change function.
So we need to give it an on change.
Now, what is on change going to do necessarily for us?
Well, let's let's give it our own change function here and let's declare our own change function outside
of the render.
And let's say const on change is equal to a function.
And then what is it going to give us?
Well, it's going to give us something called Form detA.
So if we cancel that log that.
We're going to see the form data come in.
And once we've gone so long that now what we need to do is we need to go inside of our checkout screen
and we need to import the credit card and put.
Parts, components.
Credit card component.
And so now we have our credit card input and so let's give that over here to the render function.
And of course, we need to declare it like it's an actual component and we can go see here.
Oh, it's not in a safe area.
Well, we know how to take care of that, don't we?
So let's go up here and let's import safe area.
From, you guessed it, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, slash components.
And then we'll take utility and we'll take Sieff area.
And by doing this now, we can wrap our component with the safe area.
If we wrap that around here, what we're going to see is that our credit card input is now going to
be a focus.
And if we open up our console here in the terminal and we go over to where the app is rendering, what
we can see here is if we go ahead and reload.
We'll create some clean space between the previous errors we had and over here, what we can do is we
can say four two four two four two four two four two.
And you can see it's coming in in the log.
So we can see the number coming in the expiry, the CBC, the type.
It's all coming into our values.
Awesome.
So we're getting all of the values that we input into our credit card component.
And that is exactly what we need.
We need all of that information in order for us to make decisions about what should happen now.
For us to do that, we can see over here that there is a valid field, right?
There's a valid field coming back in this object and it's telling us, hey, is this valid, yes or
no?
But there's also statuses linked to each individual field.
Is the quick complete, is the expiry complete?
Is the number complete?
If none of those are complete, we can't really do anything with it.
Right.
So now that we have all of this information, what we can do is we can build out a status check.
So in our on change function, we could, for instance, say something like const values is equal to
form data.
So we're structuring we're taking values right here off of the form data.
But on top of that, what we need to do is we need to determine a state so we'll say CONSED is incomplete,
is equal to and what we can say is object dot values.
Now, this is a function in JavaScript which will take the values off of form data values.
And what we can say is that will also take the status, right, so we need the status, so we have values.
So let's also take the status.
So what we're going to do is we're going to see object out values of status.
So we're going to get these three values.
And we want to make sure that they're all complete, right?
That's that's the state we're looking for.
So if we say object about values, that includes incomplete.
Then we know that.
All of our statuses haven't reached complete yet because this object contains all of these property,
CVC expiry number and by using object thought values, what we're doing is we're saying, hey, just
take the values off of this object.
So we're going to say incomplete, incomplete, incomplete.
Right.
Those are the three values that we currently have here.
So that's what we're doing.
We're transforming it into an array here.
And by transforming it into this array, we can now use something that is not includes.
So if we did something like this, that includes.
Right.
And we and we wrapped all of these with text, what we could see is if we did that includes complete.
We're going to get false.
If we did not include incomplete.
This would return true.
So by doing this now, we know when our status has reached completion.
If we log that out instead of form data, what we can do now is we can go over here, we can reload
and by reloading, going to checkout and starting to fill it out.
What we're going to see is once we start filling it out here at the bottom, it's incomplete.
It's incomplete, it's incomplete.
It's incomplete and so forth and so forth.
But now, due to too high its return, this false, it's finally complete because we filled out all
of the information.
So we have our status checks.
We have our values.
Now, the next thing that we need to do here, now that we have our credit card input, we're able to
get credit card info.
How about we register a straight token?
Right.
Because over here in our diagram, well, the users inputted their credit card info.
So the next thing we logically can do is create the stripe payment token.
So let's look at that in the next video.