Now that we've tested our app bundle on our simulator, the question becomes, well, how do we tested
on our device, but also how do we release it to the App Store?
And so if you go to App Store, connect dot apple dot com and you log into your account, here is where
you will do your submission.
This is where you submit your app to the App Store.
And if we go over to my apps, you can create an app, a new app, and you can go through the submission
process.
As we can see here, I've set up meals to go.
And if we click on this and we go over into test flight.
We can see that this is where we can set up build testing for our IPPEI file.
Remember the eBay file we downloaded that came inside the original build that we did not the test run
that we did in our simulator?
Well, in order to test that file, we need to upload the build over here and Appstore connect the test
flight.
So if we click on C upload tools, this is how you upload an IP to apps or connect.
You can upload your binary with Xcode, you can upload them with the E.
L tool and you can upload them with the transporter app.
Now, all of these different ways are basically similar, but you need a Mac app in order to do this.
So if we go over here and we say download the transporter app and we say open in the App Store.
What we can see over here in the App Store is the ability to install the transporter app, which is
going to upload the file into test flight.
And so once we've installed this app, what will basically do is we'll go through the process of uploading
the IPPEI file into test flight and then testing it on our phone.
So opening that up will agree to the terms of service will sign in and we'll say our account information
will fill that in, fill in our password.
And then once we've signed into our Apple ID, what it's going to do is it's going to get through App
Store Connect.
We're going to add an app.
Right, add up and what we can do over here is we can say over in our downloads folder we have.
The date modified and we have our IPPEI file, and if we open that IPPEI file, what we'll be able to
do is upload that so now we can click deliver.
And so it's going to send it over to app or connect.
Currently, it's verifying and analyzing the app output that was generated by XPO.
And then once it's done doing that based on the identifier and everything around that, it's going to
send it over into our Appstore connect over here and we'll be able to see it in our test flight built.
We'll be able to select it.
And so, as you can see, it's currently uploading the app to App Store Connect.
And once it's uploaded the app, that's where we can go and connect our builds into test flight.
So right now it's delivering the app.
And if we go over here and we see.
What happened in the log?
It basically uploaded.
Now, if we go over here into test flight, what will be able to do is when we reload, we'll see version
zero point zero point one.
So we now uploaded a version into Appstore Connect.
And the way that it was connected is through that bundle identifier.
One expo built the version of the app and built it with the same identifier that we set up when we initially
set up our app in the Apple developer platform.
OK, so how do I test this on my phone now?
So the way that we allow people to test our application is over here in the Iowas built section of test
flight, we can see that our build is currently processing.
But if we go over here to the internal and external groups, what we can see is that as if we click
on Appstore Connect users, App Store Connect users can use test flight on all devices and all active
builds.
So if we add a tester, what we need to do is we need to add our admin account as a tester.
Now, no builds are currently available as the current build is still processing.
Once this build has been processed, it will become available in the test flight app.
So we have to wait in order for the processing to be done.
And once it's done, we can test out our application.
Once our build has been processed by test flight, we now will get a confirmation email of an invite
to test meals to go, because when there are no active builds, you will not get the invite.
But once there is an active built to test, you will get an email inviting you to test.
And if we save you in test flight, this will allow us to accept the invite to test our meals to go,
which will install it locally on our production phone.
And once we've installed meals to go, we can then go ahead and test it as if it was downloaded live
from the App Store.
So we're basically through test flight, going to install and download the version that is going live
on the App Store.
And so if we test that out, might be that I.
And we do test one, two, three, what we can see here is that the app is the same that we were testing
in development mode, but now it's a production build.
It's very smooth and it's very capable of allowing us to test out all of the different functionality
that we would see in a production app.
We were able to give feedback through test flight, test flight is basically an app for quality assurance.
It is what is going to go on to the App Store, but it's before the distribution to the App Store.
So you can invite multiple testers, you can invite a bunch of different people before your app is actually
submitted to the App Store to test it out.
And the way that you would do that is to invite more testers.
They would install test flight on their app and then they would have the ability to test out the versions
that are available.
And so the version that we have right here can also be the version that we distribute over here.
Right.
We could select the build and so we can now submit multiple builds to test flight and then we can eventually
choose which one we're going to send with the submission for the App Store for review.
And so the process here is kind of more rigorous and more secure than what you would see with, for
instance, the Google Play store.
And that is intentional.
The Apple ecosystem has more security parameters in place, a lot more process, but the flow is very
similar in terms of all the information you have to supply in order to submit your application and all
of these extra things you need to do to get your app ready for deployment.
And so with that, we've seen how we can build for Android and deploy that on an iPhone to test.
And we saw where we can deploy on the Google Play store and all the information we need to fill in.
We've seen how we can test on an Iowa simulator production version of the app, as well as how to upload
our app to the App Store Kinect, test our app through test flight on a live production phone, and
also go through the motions of seeing how those builds can be sent to different people to test and adding
testers and adding the ability to kind of have a more holistic process.
So very different ecosystems, very different distribution processes, very different in general.
But we built one code base and now all we had to do was build two different outputs and follow the processes
that are in place for both stores.
Now, this is usually a process that is handled by a different department or by a more senior member
of your team, so forth, and so forward or even automated, because you only do it once and once you
do it from there on, it's just about distributing updates.
I hope this was useful.
Always reach to the documentation of Expo as it is very detailed and very useful for you to go through
the process of the detailed steps that you may need to take.