Before we build out search, I wanted to add some polish here because we have our restaurants loading.
Right, we have it all loading, but the issue is that when we reload, we're not really getting any
feedback about if it's loading or not.
So one of the things that we can do is we can go look at react native pepper.
And react native people, and if we go look at the docks here, if we look for activity in the Kater.
The activity indicator is this indicator that shows if you are having progress or not, and so an exercise
that I want us to go through is I want us to take the usage case of this activity indicator and create
an activity indicator that's going to show while the data is loading.
So we have our is loading property here.
And while this is true, I want us to show an activity indicator in the UI.
And so in the next video, we'll look at a solution.