One of the last things that we need to do to set you up on Mac is we need to give you a place to code.
Now, we're not going to have the ED that we originally had on XPO Sneck.
And now that we're running locally, the code that we wrote on Snack Expo DOT.
Right, if we go to our snack, this is a random snack, for instance, the code that we brought in
here isn't going to work locally.
This runs inside of the browser.
So we need an environment specifically for us to write code on our machine, on our computer.
And for that, we're going to use Visual Studio Code.
This is a code editor and it says Code editing redefined.
And that's an understatement because this is a tool that once you master, it's used in many, many,
many workplaces.
It's used in a variety of different tech industries, whether it be front and back end and even Python
developers.
You can use it for pretty much anything at these days because it is so basic and can be enriched through
something called plugins.
But for our purposes, we just need the basic version.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to download it for Mac and that's going to initiate the
download of Visual Studio Code.
And then once it's done downloading, what you're going to see is that it is going to become available
to drag and drop in your applications folder once you do that.
So it's going to be in a zip file.
And then once you undo that zip file, what you're going to see here is that you have something called
Visual Studio Code or Visual Studio Code, too, because I've downloaded it multiple times at this point.
And what you do is you can drag and drop that right into your applications folder where you keep all
of your applications.
Now, I already have a drag and drop in there.
So once you drag and drop it in there, when you open it up for the very first time, what you are going
to see is this interface and this interface is what we're going to work with throughout this course.
Now, don't be overwhelmed here.
Like there's a lot going on, but we're going to go through it step by step.
Now, over here, you can see on the left hand side, there is a panel in each one of these icons goes
to a different place.
This goes to the Explorer file explorer.
If we were to open a folder here, we could see all of the files.
This is for searching for specific text or whatever else.
If you're trying to search through your code, here is source control.
So remember when we installed Git, you can control everything that has to do with get from here and
we're going to control everything from here.
This is going to be our one stop solution to handle everything.
We're not going to try to go outside of this.
This is going to be where we do the bulk of our stuff or rewrite our code and where we do everything.
Now it has a bunch of different tools.
You can install extensions and everything else, but we don't need very many of those.
Basically, with just this installation, we can write code, we can write our master project.
And so now you are basically set up to hit the ground running.
Isn't that amazing?