Hey, all, so I wanted to go over something really quickly that I may have gone over fairly quickly
in the previous video with Android, and that is the menus that you can pull up inside of Expo.
So when we're inside of these apps, if we go and we say, shake the device, we're going to be pulling
up this menu or we can press command em.
And on Windows, the equivalent will be Control I and so that will pull up the menu.
And that menu is available for us to do multiple things.
We can reload the app if we want to.
We can copy the link for our app.
We can go home, we can disable the fast refresh, which is the refresh that happens when you save a
file.
We can go into a debugging mode, which we won't be using right now.
We can show a performance monitor that's basically going to allow us to see certain things.
Now, on Android, you do need to allow an overlay.
So once we allow that, we'll be able to show our UI so we can see that we're running 60 FPS.
And on iOS, you can kind of move it around on an android.
It's static, but it can show you while the UI is rendering at 60 frames per second and the jazzes is
rendering a 60 frames per second.
So we have these cool debug tools that are kind of useful.
And like I showed you, you also have the element, Inspector, that, you know, can show us different
styles of different things, which is super useful.
Right.
And so with that element, Inspector, let's just hide the performance monitor while we do this, if
we show the element Inspector, we can tap in on certain things and we can see what exactly they're
doing.
And on Android, we can do the same thing.
We can go look at list and search and all that good stuff.
So these tools are there to help you figure out what exactly is going on in your UI and my rendering
as fast as I should be.
Are there any others?
Are there any dropoffs?
What are my elements looking like?
How are they laid out?
These Dybbuk tools are just as important as first principles, and I just wanted to highlight them once
again.
For those of you who haven't touched them just yet or haven't seen them, they're an important tool
in our tool belt.
So just making sure that we all have everything we need to hit the ground running and know what to do
when we're building layouts.