Hey, all I wanted to give a quick note on something that is going to be extremely important as you
go through the course, so as we go through the course, every time we reach a milestone or we do some
type of configuration or add something, I will be providing a branch a you role for you in the resources
section of that video.
In the resources section of that video, there will be a call to my GitHub.
And what you will see is that you will be pointed to a specific point in time at which we did this thing.
So if you get stuck at all or if your code isn't running, what you can do when I give you this URL
is you can go over here, you can go to code and you can say download zip.
And that's going to download you that snapshot in time of what we did so far.
And so you can take that, you can put that folder somewhere and you can do the same steps that we did
during setup to get that code up and running.
Or you can just verify the code inside of here against what you wrote to make sure that you're on the
same path and you have the same things going on.
Because if you get lost anywhere along the way with what you're doing or what's going on, this is a
good way for you to take that snapshot in time and continue on or verify it against what you're doing.
We want to give this to you as an opportunity to continuously follow along with the code that is being
written and what is happening.