As I promised, the project we're building here is not only going to teach you react native, but it's
also going to use industry standards in order for you to be more focused on tools that are effectively
used in a day to day job.
Two of those tools.
Are prettier and Eastlands, and we are going to set those up right now.
Now, you may be wondering what's the.
Well, Iceland is this tooling infrastructure to find and fix problems in your JavaScript code, it's
this extensible type of framework that you can basically use to find and fix problems, and it can even
fix them automatically.
And you can customize it to find errors in specifically your code.
If you prefer certain styles, it can enforce code styles.
And so they have a whole section on getting started, what rules they have, what kind of different
interactions you can use.
And they have a developer guide for contributing and setting it up and running unit tests.
It's a huge, huge ecosystem.
And if you've never heard about it, it's honestly amazing.
They even talk about their architecture and how it fits into the big picture and what exactly it does.
It's a great read and a great tool, but setting it up is easier than you would expect because we're
going to do is we're going to use the react native communities pre configured react native setup.
So they have put together for us all of the tooling and all of the rules that we need for Riak native.
So we don't even need to go into detail of what all the different rules are.
Here's a preset pre configured lintang.
So Lintang is the process of going through your code and making sure that it adheres to the style.
So they've gone ahead and they've configured it.
So they have baseline configuration and so they use also something called prettier and prettier.
Pretty hard, James is an opinionated code formatter, so prettier is also an industry standard at this
point because what we want is consistency in code.
And prettier is basically one of those things where you see the code here on the left, how it's being
formatted and how it's not that readable.
Will Prettier will do this to it.
It will enforce a code style that always looks the same.
It'll format your code to always, always, always look the same.
And so these two tools, prettier in conjunction with Iceland, are two of the main tools that teams
use in order to create consistency in an ecosystem that has so much entropy, entropy, meaning there's
so many different people that code in a code based on a team.
Well, these two tools enforce you to write similar code to each other and have the rules in place for
you as a team to know, hey, I prefer this or I prefer that.
And the discussion arises and you kind of come upon rules.
Now, the react native community has gone ahead and given us a preset amount of rules that we will use.
So all we have to do is go to react native community and run this command.
So will press command.
SISA will copy that.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to go over to our visual studio code and remember how
we ran the terminal.
Well, you can go up here if you don't have a terminal running a new terminal or if you have a terminal
already running, you can hit this icon here.
This will open up the console here and you can hit terminal.
And this will also allow you to get to a terminal.
Now, don't worry about the errors that I see here.
Those are for my system.
But you may not see anything like that.
Now, here, we want to run this command, right?
So let's go ahead and run that, and that's going to install all of the dependencies that we basically
need.
And then on top of that, we need to create a new file while this is installing and we're going to call
it Dot Esslin RC.
And in that Esslin Darsey, we're going to copy paste these lines.
And by copying these lines, we're telling, excellent, hey, you're going to use the riak need of
community configuration.
Awesome.
OK, so now that that's done, we're basically set up or are we?
Well, let's take a look at that in the next video.