All right, we're about to start our journey in developing locally on windows.
Now, what does that mean?
What does that mean for the majority of the time?
Now, we have been coding in this Web browser, but it's time to say goodbye to the old and say hello
to the new new being developing on our computer locally.
Now, how do we go about that?
Well, first of all, we want to take this app that we already know works that we've set up here in
this way.
And we want to take that and make sure that we can run it locally because it's our baseline right at
the end of the day.
We just built this and we know it works.
So what better way to validate that?
What we're doing is going to work than taking this app, setting everything up locally and making sure
that we can run this app because that will verify to us that we've done everything correctly.
So the first thing we need to do here is we need to press these three dots over here, right there,
and you're going to see three options import, import, export.
Now, what do you think we're going to do?
Ding, ding, ding.
We're going to export we're going to export our products so that we have it locally.
That's what we want to do here.
So we'll hit export.
And what we'll get is.
Well, a reminder to protect our computer, but but we'll get down here if we're on edge, if you're
in any other browser, will say, do you want to save the focus?
Time says it.
So we'll say save.
And once we save that, we can open the folder that it's saved then and what you'll see over here is
focus time.
One now I obviously already downloaded once before, if we right click that and we say open a new window,
basically we'll get the ability to get the folder focused time, which will have all of our assets.
So we're opening the zip file.
This is a zip file, so we've opened it here.
Now, what I want you to do is I want you over here in this window.
If you have two windows are open, a second window.
I want you to go to your documents folder and in your documents folder.
What I want you to do here is I want you to drag and drop focus time from within the zip that we opened.
I want you to drag that folder and I want you to release it inside documents.
And so in documents now, we have focused time and with focus time there, we have all of the information
that made our application run inside of Expo, all of the code that was in here, all the code that
we wrote, all the code that made our application work is now on our computer inside of the focus time
folder, inside of documents.
So make sure that all that code is there.
And then once you have that ready, we can move on to the next step.