We have hello world rendering.
Now it begs the question, how do we actually get our content to always stay within the frame?
And so over here, you can see that we had the style is equal to styles that container.
And we say over here, well, the padding is 50 and the padding being 50 means that we're padding from
the left, right, top and bottom.
So we're essentially crimping the entire screen.
Now, not every phone has the same exact notch placement or notch size, and the pixels over here,
they aren't actually true pixels, their density based pixels.
So it also depends on the density of your screen.
So this 50 could look different on an iOS device.
It could look different on an Android device.
It could look different on a bunch of different devices.
Well, how would we solve that?
Well, we could say, let's take in platform platform is a specific library within React Native that
allows you to target iOS and Android separately.
So what we could see here is, hey, if Platform Dot OS is equal to iOS, let's put 50 density pixels
and otherwise, you know, let's put 100.
And if we look at that, that would mean that basically on Android, we would, you know, push it down
even further.
Now we don't want it to go from all sides.
So maybe we just say from the top, OK, let's just push it down from the top.
Well, now one hundred seems excessive.
Fifty feels about right for us.
But you might be asking yourself, Hey, what is the best way for us to achieve this?
This kind of feels.
Hacky, this kind of feels like it's not the right way to consistently push down.
The content in a nice way now it is nice because this is, you know, the top level view in our app
right now, right?
We only have app, there's one view.
And so if we say that everything renders inside of this, everything will get the exact same padding.
But there must be a nicer way to achieve this.
And so enter safe area view.
The purpose of a safe area of view is to render the content within the safe area.
Bounds of a device is currently only applicable to iOS devices with iOS version 11 or later, right?
So when we apply safe area view, what it's basically going to do is it's going to implement its own
padding behavior, which means that it will not take in our padding behavior.
OK, so let's take a look at them.
If we take in safe area of you and then we say, Hey, let's remove this over here and let's use that
and let's get rid of Styles container.
And let's apply to see if any of you.
And then we can see, hey, nothing really, oh, it jumped up a tiny smidge.
And why is that the case?
Well, it's because see if any of you implement its own planning rules.
It's basically saying, Hey, I'm going to determine the safe area for you to render your contact when
you don't have to worry about that.
And anything you render within me will always be within the bounds of the screen.
Now you may be asking yourself the question How would this work on Android?
Let's take a look at that.