I want to ask you a question, have you ever been in the situation maybe you haven't quoted any time
previously, but have you ever been in the situation where you're working on a document, whether it
be a word document, an Excel document or whatever else, and something happens, boom file gone?
Well, in coding, we have methods to avoid this happening once and for all.
And on top of that, that methodology extends to working in teams and all of these other nice things.
Well, what is this methodology I speak of?
What is this black magic memo?
It's called Get and what get is it is an open source version control system distributed.
I'm oh, you're you're throwing a lot of words at me here, whatever.
What does that mean?
Well, I'll tell you what it means.
Basically what it is, it's an ability for you locally to keep revisions of your work.
So just like a word document, you're saving, you're saving your work.
But it goes beyond that.
It allows you also to keep a history of your work.
Now, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
How does it do that?
Well, it's a very complicated technology under the hood, but what basically we need to get out of
it and what you need to remember about it is that it is going to take care of us saving our work and
keeping a history of what we've done.
Have you ever worked at, like a factory or something where you have to take your card when you come
in and you go out?
It's kind of like taking that cart.
You know, when you ticked all, will you take them at seven, 10, seven fifteen, seven twenty will
get is kind of the same way.
You're checking in what you've changed at specific times.
So we're going to save our work, but we're going to save it in a way that we know what we've done and
what the history was and when we did it.
And that's going to be important for us, not for the short term, but for the long term, because everyone
can work on projects individually.
But it's when you want to start collaborating or when you want to start keeping more complicated changes
or you want to branch off and try something real quick, things like that when you want to experiment
and all that good stuff.
Once you get or once you install get, for instance, you're going to open a whole new world of possibilities
for yourself.
So what we're going to do here, we're going to press, download, get for Windows and downloading it
for Windows.
We're going to hit the save button.
Boom, run the security skin were good, now it's going to give you this gett installation, you're
going to double click that.
And once you double click that, that's going to ask you if you want to run it.
We're going to say yes.
And then once we start running that, what we're going to do is we're going to go through the installation
step by step.
So first it's going to give you a whole bunch of information.
Let's say we read it.
You don't have to actually scroll to the bottom.
But then we're going to press next.
We're going to say where we're going to save it.
Always leave this wherever originally decides if you're a more advanced user, you can obviously change
this.
But for all intents and purposes, we're going to store it on our C drive or C drivers of our hard drive.
This is what when those calls it, we're going to save it in the folder program files.
This is where software is saved on your computer and we're going to save it in the folder.
Get all right.
Don't change that.
Now we're going to press next and by default, it's going to install all of these things, all of these
things.
Now, do we need anything else?
Well, we can add desktop icon.
Sure.
Add a desktop icon and then you can check for updates daily if you want.
That would be useful if you're going to end up using this in the longer term and you can install a font
optionally if you want to.
I'm not going to do that today.
OK, so now it's going to take you and say, hey, create shortcuts.
Well, let's create a shortcut.
All right.
So in this next step, it's going to ask us to choose the default editor that we won't forget.
Now, Vim is the default editor for it, for Windows only for historical reason.
And it's highly recommended that you switch.
So what we're going to do is we're going to switch because it already says here the verm, which is
powerful, can be hard to use.
We don't want we don't want hard to use.
I like simple things.
Simple things are good.
So we're going to switch to something called Visual Studio Code.
So let's download that as well, because as you can see here, it won't let us press next just yet.
So let's save that.
And then once that saved, will quickly install visual studio code, so we're pausing our gett installation
right here and we're going to run this.
And once we run this, we're going to say I accept the agreement.
So right now, we're installing visual studio code, which is going to be used by GIT.
So let's slow this down.
What is Visual Studio Code even?
Well, Visual Studio Code is where we're going to code.
It is the environment in which we're going to put all of our code.
We're going to write our code and we're going to do a whole bunch more stuff.
So it's good that we're installing this already and it's good that the git installation kind of told
us, hey, you need this switch.
So we're going to do that.
So we're going to press next, next, next and create a desktop icon and we're going to press, install
and then once Visual Studios installation is complete, hopefully we can go to the next step in our
gett installation.
So bada bing, ba boom, this is installed.
We can launch Visual Studio code.
This is looking good.
So this is Visual Studio Code, but we'll get back to that later.
Now, what is happening over here?
Can we press next?
Well, we can't.
OK, so you can see here when I pressed back.
Originally, the next button was still great out when I pressed back and forward again.
Now, when I use visual studio code because I went a bit quickly, right, so it's great out again.
Why is it great out?
Well, let's press back and let's press forward.
And now it figured out that Visual Studio code is there.
So let's press next again.
And let's leave this to let get the side, this is adjusting the name of the judicial branch.
Let's let's just, you know, let's let's get the side.
And so adjusting the path environment, so let's just leave this as this let's leave it on the recommended
setting, if you're a more advanced user, go ahead and try things out.
But let's leave it on the recommended settings for now.
Now.
Choosing the https transport back end, what does that mean?
Let's just leave it to open SSL, the default now configuring line ending conversions, these are all
very complicated things, but, you know, just leave it to what it's selected.
OK, now choose a terminal emulator.
What?
What not.
Well, we'll leave it to the default selected as well.
And here, choose the behavior of git pull.
We're going to leave it again to what it's set as default.
Now, what credential helper would you want again?
We'll leave it to what it has selected by default and you can always click more information here to
see what it's referring to.
To get credential manager is just a software that they're giving.
You will leave it with the selected because you can see here deprecated.
We don't want that or none.
We want to credential help.
So let's just leave it at where they left it and they will file system caching.
Let's also enable symbolic links.
Let's enable that as well.
And now experimental support, we don't like experimental, we don't like it, so let's press install
and we're finally through it.
I was a whole bunch of different stuff we had to go through.
And I understand that a lot of it may have been kind of obscure.
You may not understand all of it, but don't worry, once this installation is behind us, we can finally
get to the good stuff, which is what we're going to use it for.
And what we're going to use get for is more important than all of the tiny details and steps we have
to go through in the installation.
So.
First thing we're going to do, we're going to hit launch, get bash, and then we're going to hit finish
and this is going to launch this interface Min GW 64.
If you're on a 32 bit system, it may be a bit different.
We recommend 64 bit system, though, so we've installed get what do we do now?
All right.
Well, let's go through that.