In the previous video, we successfully installed and set up prettier and excellent, but now now comes
a time where we actually need to use it because hey Mo, what is it doing?
Well, not very much by the looks of it, because we don't really see anything happening.
So the way we're going to set this up is we're going to go inside our package, Jason, and what we're
going to do over here is we're going to run or create a new script.
We're going to call it Lintz, and we're going to say that Lente is excellent.
And we're going to put DOT so that it's going to check everything and we're going to do that.
He dodges and this in itself is calling the Esslin package and saying, hey, check my whole directory,
but only for the jazz files.
And if we go ahead and we go to our terminal and we say, hey, run that command.
And the command is a yarn lint, so if we run that well, we're going to see is whoa, it's telling
us a bunch of stuff.
We have 11 problems, one error and 10 warnings.
And so here we get into kind of an odd space.
Let me explain.
We have prettier, which is a code formatter and we have excellent which is a linta, so the thing is
looking at the code and saying, hey, this is the code format I want you to follow and Prettier is
looking at the code and saying, hey, this is the consistency.
I want your code to be formatted.
But both can have overlapping rules.
So over here at the bottom, you see this is giving me a hard core error.
It's saying replace Bable Preset XPO with single quotes to double quotes.
So if I go to the Bible config and I say, hey, put this into double quotes, OK, well, we're going
to see the error go away from prettier, but we're going to see this.
Yes, Slint is going to be warning us, Esslin, to saying String's must be single quote.
So there is a conflict between what Prettier wants to see and what it wants to see.
And so to alleviate that, what we're going to do is we're going to add a rule and we're going to add
our own rule.
It's an override.
It's going to say rules.
And then we're opening the object and then we're going to say quotes.
We're going to say two, and then we're going to say double instead of single and we're going to avoid
the escape.
With this rule now, what we can do is we can run Yarmolenko again.
And now we only have five problems, what problems do we have?
Well, platform is defined, but it's not being used.
So this one is defined but not used.
And we have an inline style.
Fleck's one.
Right, Fleck's one.
We have padding in background color over here.
And we have padding, background, color.
Over here, so we did these inline styles, right, and then we have this one down here that we never
assign the style.
So what we can do is we can move these styles into the styles.
So that's what it's preferring us to do.
So if we take this and we said that this was empty for now and we went down here and we said container.
And we put these in here.
And then we went up here and we said, styles dot container.
Now we're getting into a good spot, right, so we're moving our inline styles into what we would call
the stylesheet.
And this has benefits, as we explained, in terms of memorization and all that good stuff, so we're
going to call this search.
And we're going to put the styles in there and then we're going to have list and we're going to put
the styles in there.
So let's take that and let's say styles start search and then we're going to create a list and we're
going to put that in there.
So let's do that.
And now we're good.
So we'll put styles that list great.
OK, so now if we were on the list, what happens if we run yarn lint?
What's going to happen?
Well, we have a bunch of other errors, Prettier is complaining, and Iceland is complaining that we
can't have trailing spaces, so let's run.
It would fix bakdash fix.
And so it's going to go through our code and try to format it for us and fix it, and now all of the
errors are gone, no more errors, right?
So if we run lenth again, again, no more errors, we fix them all just with running the Esslin Fix
Command.
OK, so now that we understand what Iceland is doing for us, it's looking at our code, it's figuring
out how the code style needs to work, and it's looking at how to apply these rules consistently.
We can now throughout our entire project write consistent code.
And I would say, hey, run this command that early and often as possible.
But we're also going to look at how to integrate it into this code.
So let's do that next video.