Last we left it, we were left with this obscure screen, this thing that that came installed would
get that kind of looks like the Matrix.
Well, first and foremost, I want to tell you, we don't need to use this on windows.
If you're a more advanced user and you know how to use command line, go for it.
But we installed Visual Studio Code.
So let's take a look at how that thing works, because that's what we're going to base all of our knowledge
on.
OK, so over here, if you go to file, you can say open folder.
And if you open the folder to the documents folder and the focus time folder that we said if you select
that folder, it's going to open up here.
Now, what you can see over here is that it opened up focus time at the top.
You can see the folder name and then you can see the folders assets, you can see the source folder,
you can see the features folder.
You see the utilities that we need.
You know, all very great stuff.
If we open the app, Gorgias, you can see that it's going to colorize everything and make it nice and
pretty.
And all of our code is here.
Everything we did in our snack is here and now.
Our objective is simple.
Get it to run on windows.
So we're going to do that.
But before we do that, I want to teach you this thing.
And so I promised you that I was going to teach you how to use get.
Now, for that, one of the two things we need to do.
Is it works with something called repositories, a git repositories kind of like a box, and you're
going to say like in this box, we're going to keep our code and we're going to keep revisions of our
code.
So every time we change something, we're going to put a new folder and we're going to see the folder
for today is here, the folder for an hour like when I last did.
It is here.
The folder for tomorrow is here.
We're going to organize our code in in this git repository.
So if you press this little symbol here, if you hover over it, it's going to say source control.
So we're going to click that.
And what that's going to say is the folder that is currently open does not have a git repository.
This folder that we downloaded from XPO Stack is not get enabled.
OK, so what we want to do is we want to initialize it, right, right, right.
So, yeah, we want to initialize it.
So we're going to hit this initialise button.
And what that's going to do is, whoa, what just happened here?
What what is all this?
Well, it's showing us everything that changed all of the files that have changed in our folder.
And all of these are green suddenly.
What does green mean.
Green means that they're new.
Green means that they haven't been in our repository yet.
It's it's kind of like get is going through everything we've done and saying, I know this or I don't
know this.
It's kind of like an auditor.
If you've ever been audited, horrible experience, don't go through it.
But what is basically doing is going through all of your files and saying, hey, I haven't seen this
before.
What is this?
Is this new?
It's probably new.
I haven't seen this before.
So over here you can see it has a little thing called 19.
What does nineteen refer to?
Well, it's found 19 files are folders that are new to it that it hasn't tracked yet.
And when we talk about tracking its debt, doesn't know this file.
So it's the very first time that it's seen it.
So if it's the very first time that it's seen it, it doesn't have any history yet.
OK, so if we go over here and we look at these 19 files, these 19 changes, what is going to do now
is it's going to say we can stage the changes so we can tell get hey, track this or we can undo it
and it's going to remove it.
It's going to say, hey, don't keep this file, remove it.
We don't want to remove anything.
Don't press that.
Or at the top here, we can press the pause button, so if we press the button, we can see that there's
this new column over here, stage changes.
So now suddenly get knows about get ignored and the EU changed into an E.
So it's starting to track it.
OK, so we're learning we're seeing that get ignored.
Went from not anything at all to what we put in it.
So we're going to be able to see how files change as we go along.
OK, so if we press this plus here at the top, it's going to stage everything, we can stage them one
by one or we can stage them all together.
And what we want to do is we want to stage them all together.
OK, so now everything is staged.
What is staged mean?
Well, staged means that now everything is going to be tracked by Gitte.
And so the little symbol is now an AI instead of a you write the and you is neither here nor there.
But just know that new files are going to be green because the changes haven't been tracked yet.
So now we have 19 files that went from I don't know what they are to hey get is now going to stage these
changes.
So now we have three things over here.
We have a toggle view mode which is going to toggle different types of use for us to look at the files.
And and that's just going to show us different ways of looking at it.
We have a commit button and we have a refresh button and we have the three dots over here that's going
to do a bunch of other stuff.
All right.
So now that we've staged all of our changes in the next video, we're going to go look at how we're
going to actually put these online.