Before we get deep into integration of Google Cloud, I wanted to tell you a cautionary story and it's
a hell of a story I almost vomited when this happened.
Now, I've seen this happen many, many times in my job working for different clients when they're implementing
Google cloud provider services.
And this is just a cautionary tale.
It's not that you need to be deathly afraid of working with cloud service providers, but you you have
to pay attention.
It's not something you want to play around with.
And I'll tell you why.
On December the 6th, right back over here, the number five to six, it was an evening like any other.
I was just coding.
I was coding away, building meals to go.
And I was going through the motions of kind of working through all of the different parts that I needed
to do.
And so I was doing some traffic to Google Cloud building out to the infrastructure.
And I had built out a function, a search function that was going to hit the Google Cloud API and the
geocoding API specifically in the places API and I had put a function somewhere inside of Orender body
just to test it out quickly.
And I had forgotten about it.
I just didn't pay attention.
And then I hit a use case where I was trying something out and it was silently rendering the components
started rendering without me knowing and I didn't notice because the app was just there.
Nothing was happening.
I didn't have any logs anywhere.
And so I went away for like two or three minutes, got some water, came back and looked at my dashboard.
To my surprise, I had done 86000 requests to the geocoding API.
It had silently been rendering for those five minutes.
And it I've been hitting the geocoding API continuously and continuously, continuously, continuously
hadn't stopped.
Needless to say, when I saw this, I almost puked.
Because you go into panic mode, what would I do, where is this happening?
I didn't I don't remember doing any of this.
And when I found my mistake, just leaving a stray function call somewhere inside of a body of a component,
which is a bad practice to start with.
But I was just testing something out when I'd found my mistake.
I was mortified.
But it happens.
These things happen.
And what are you going to do?
Well, first of all, I had a panic attack.
And to be honest, like at that point, well, my first reaction was to contact Google.
And luckily enough, they helped me out.
They gave me a credit on my bill, they saw that all of the usage was incurred in the same exact moment,
on the same exact day, in the same exact hour, and that it was a fluke and they helped me out.
But it's better to prevent the need to get through the situation where you need to go and look at this
usage and say, well, now I have a five hundred U.S. dollar bill.
So with that, they gave me some strategies, strategies that I already knew I just hadn't implemented.
And we're going to go through that so that you can prevent making a similar mistake.
And I've seen this happen at clients as well.
But instead of 86000 or cost, we're talking about millions, millions of requests.
So you need to be very cautious about how you set everything up when you use a cloud provider.
Safety is the most important thing.
You need to understand what you're doing, configuring everything to the most granular quota that you
can set.
And that's what we'll be looking at as well, but this is a cautionary tale just so that you know that
mistakes can happen and there's tales about this all over the Internet.
And I'm just saying this because I want you to know that you need to pay attention.
You need to pay attention, because although you have a three hundred dollar free quota, if you start
a new account and you have this two hundred dollar quota for the places in the geocoding it by free
usage, it's very easy if you don't set up the proper guardrails to go over.
Now, with that, don't be too afraid of using cloud providers.
It is honestly fine.
You just need to be careful about how your coding.
So with that, that was my mistake.