Now, when we run out on Android, we can see that, hey, the safe air of you really didn't do anything
for us, and if we go look at safe area of you, well, it says only applicable to iOS devices with
iOS version 11 or later.
See if a review renders nested content automatically and applies the padding.
OK.
And then in the example O to use it, wrap the top level view at a safe review with a Flex one style
applied to it.
Well, that's something we accidentally removed, isn't it?
We need to add back style is equal to Styles dark container because we want to make sure that the content
rendered within apply reflects one.
Now, this really isn't going to change anything for Android, but it's important to note that the documentation
in React Native often tells you how to use something, and so it's very imperative to read through the
documentation now.
It says over here, as padding is used to implement the behavior of the component, padding rules and
styles apply to safe air if you will be ignored as they can cause different results, depending on the
platform.
So that means an iOS, any type of padding rules, which we proved are going to be ignored.
But for Android, for Android specifically, well over here we can see that's causing an issue.
So if we say padding top and we say, 10, what's that going to do, huh?
Well, it pushes it down.
That tells us that safe area view in Android doesn't actually apply the same rules as it does on iOS.
So the documentation says this only works for iOS 11 or later, and it's going to ignore padding rules.
So what is it doing on Android?
Well, in Android, we can assume that it's actually falling back to a view component behind the scenes.
So this safe area, if you want Android's actually just rendering a view, which means over here we
can do something pretty cool.
Remember when I showed you platform?
Well, we can take that again, and we can also get something called status bar.
These are two libraries that come from React Native, and what we can say is here platform Dot OS is
equal to Android.
Then we're going to do something specific.
What we're going to do is we're going to give it padding 10 or zero.
We're going to say, Hey, apply a padding.
If you are on Android specifically, so right over here we can go back to devices, we can reload the
apps.
And so what we'll see here is that the content was actually pushed out about 10, so if we put 20,
then we'll see it pushed down about 20.
Now Status Bar comes with a very interesting property.
You can do status bar dot.
Current height and status bar reflects to the status bar over here, so it internally is going to the
native code of the Android device and saying, Hey, get me your status bars actual height in density
pixels so that I can always offset it the right amount.
And so now what we have is a safe area view that is usable for both Android and iOS.
Because on iOS, we know for a fact that this is actually pushing it beyond the notch.