Last we left off, we had staged all of our changes, but we were so far from actually saving just yet,
we hadn't saved anything yet.
OK, so why haven't we saved anything yet?
Well, in order to save something over here at the top, you're going to see this little input bar and
that's going to allow you to write a message.
And that message is going to be a message that you're going to link to these specific changes.
So these 19 file changes.
So anything that isn't staged when we write the message, it's going to say, hey, this is what all
of these were.
So we're going to say, well, this is my initial entry.
And my initial entry is like me saying, I'm going to put these 19 files, start tracking them.
So I'll press this.
Huh?
We're getting an error, make sure you configure your username and email and get what is that all about?
What is this it's saying no email was given in auto detection is disabled, yadda, yadda, yadda.
It's asking us, please tell me who you are.
Irmo.
How do I tell you what's going to ask us will run this, run what?
Run, get config, dash, dash, global user dot email.
And then you're at example outcome.
What is this?
Well, this is what we would call a command and a command is something that we would run in command
line.
Now, you remember that that screen that looks like the matrix that we got when we initially installed.
What we're going to do is we're going to copy this very first line.
And we're going to go here to the start and we're going to say get bash.
So when we open our get bash, what we're going to have here is an interface that looks like the Matrix.
Now, if we pieced what we it looks like I can't paste in here.
Looks like you do not have the ability to paste.
So we're going to have to type this out.
So what does it say?
Get space config, space dash, dash, global space user dot email space.
We're going to type.
How do I type these seams on my keyboard is in a different setting over here, so I have to make sure
those in us.
All right, so we want these double quotes and we're going to say Mo Adine that.
And when we run this, it's going to set that and then we're going to do get config Ashutosh global
user name and we're going to say Mo Beeny.
All right.
So you want these double quotes for sure.
Put these double quotes.
These double quotes are around the text.
This is to identify myself.
So we're going to hit enter on that one as well.
And then we're going to close this window because we don't want to use it to too much.
It's too powerful.
We're going to use this interface that simplifies things and doesn't make it look like we're doing voodoo
magic and is understandable.
All right, let's close this output.
We don't want to see no errors.
When we go back, we have staged our changes, we had 19 files here and we had said that our message
was going to be initial entry.
OK, so let's hit commit again.
There we go, we have now committed our files to get and it is tracking them now.
What does this mean?
Well, if I go into Afghanistan now and I, for instance, go inside of app and over here, I, I do
something like console log, YOLO.
You only live once because, well, you really only do live once.
But anyways, that aside, that stupid little quirky thing aside, if we go here into the get, what
we're going to see is that no files have changed yet.
Well of course they have.
And I have to actually save the file and now that I've saved the file.
Well, if we go here and we hit refresh.
We hit refresh, then we'll see that Abduh changed and we can see that, oh, we added a line so we're
able to see what we actually changed in a file.
This is so powerful because when you're coding along and you accidentally run into a bug, how do you
know what you changed?
Well, get gives you the ability to view your changes and viewing your changes allows you to see what
you changed and what caused the issue.
So, so powerful and with great power finish that comes great responsibility.
OK, I'm calling I'm being corny anyways.
So right now, this console log is not something we want.
We don't want this file change.
So something we can do.
I showed you how to stage the change, but I can also show you how to discard the change.
And if we discard the change, you're going to get this big yellow box.
You sure you want to discard the change?
Doesn't have to be very, very, very, very, very careful when you discard changes because you're
not going to get them back.
I can assure you you will not get them back.
So make sure you want to discard what you want to discard because there's no way to undo it.
And we're going to discard this console log because we don't want this change.
OK, so now that we've discarded this, what is the next thing we want to do?
OK, well, the next thing we want to do is we actually want to save this somewhere.
So not right now.
We're tracking the history on our computer.
OK, so everything we've done here so far is all inside of.
The folder inside of documents focused time, so everything we've done is inside of here.
I can hear you asking more like what are you talking about?
Like, OK, I understand this this whole gadget thing where we can see the changes and and Eustache
and you can and whatever all this magic.
But like, how is it doing this?
Well, if we go to view and we say, you know, hidden items, then we can see that Gett actually created
a gett folder, a hidden folder.
Now, don't mess around with this folder.
I would strongly advise that you hide these folders again.
But inside of that hidden folder is what Gett would call what it tracks.
So if you go inside of here, it's tracking a lot of different things.
Your current changes, your past changes where, what, how and all of that good stuff.
So get is something that's going to track the history of the changes.
And so it's doing it all inside of that folder.
OK, OK, so now now we have get installed and we're able to track our history.
We're able to we know how to commit.
Now we know that when we make a change, we can fill in a nice message here.
We can say like if we add the console, log back into into here.
If we go back into Appalachia's and we said, hey, I want to add that console log again.
You know, YOLO, then we could go inside of the version control if we saved this file and be refreshed
here, we could add a nice Kimmett message saying I added a console log and if we chose to commit that,
that is now in our history.
And so we'll know when it was changed, why it was changed, what message came with, what it changed.
Super, super powerful stuff.
And so what we want to do now is we want to host somewhere and where we want to host that is get hub
dot com.
And if we go to get hub dotcom, this is where the world built software.
You may have heard of it.
You may have seen it.
We're going to use it.
We're going to use it to store our code.