Now that we know everything there is to know about Google Cloud and all the safety measures we need
to take, we also understand that Google Maps is one of the foremost providers.
So right now, what we want to do is create a new project.
And by creating a new project, we're going to call it meals to go.
And this project is going to be where we get our information from how we're going to configure APIs.
So for me, it's going to be in an organization.
For you, it won't probably be in an organization.
You'll be on your individual account, but just create the project and then.
What you will have is the ability to choose that project.
I have two projects from meals to go.
I'm going to show you in this project that is now being set up how to set up the corresponding APIs
that we will need in order to integrate.
So now that it is set up, if we go over here, what we can see is that on the dashboard, everything
is set up with our billing and so forth.
And what we can do now is we can go look at what products we need.
So the first product we're going to need is the Places API.
So we're going to search for places and we're like the places API.
Then we'll select enabled and once we enable that API, it is now available on our Google cloud for
us to configure.
The second thing we'll need is the Geocode API now the Geocode API is one that we'll use to translate
location Balochi, a city into a location, latitude, longitude and so enabling that will allow us
to basically do requests to get that information.
There's two things we need to do.
First off, we need to set credentials and second off, we need to set quotas, so let's go ahead and
set quotas ahead of them right here.
I'm in the geocoding API, which I've enabled places API in the geocoding API, and I can also configure
it for all of the maps platform.
But you have to set quotas on the specific API, so we'll go to geocoding API and then we'll go to our
requests.
And what are you going to see here is that currently it is configured for unlimited requests per day,
3000 requests per minute and requests per minute, per user unlimited.
This is what can catch you when you, for instance, have no limitations set.
It will not stop the requests from coming in, meaning that you need to set limits for the amount of
requests you want to do per day so that your costs will be caught if you make a mistake.
So what we're going to do is we're going to see four requests per day.
We're going to disable Unlimited and we're going to set it to one thousand.
And then we're going to say we're sure we're reducing the quota for requests per minute.
We're also going to change it and we're going to configure it to be amount of requests per minute that
is more reasonable.
So we'll set that to one hundred requests per minute.
That way, we're sure that if we hit a limitation within that minute time frame, we can cancel out.
And then on top of that, what we'll do is we'll set requests per user per minute also to a thousand.
And here, reduce the quota, we can always adjust these based on usage, if we're hitting limitations,
the API will send us an error and we can adjust our quota.
These are just there in place so that we can be careful.
And then on top of that, what we'll do is we'll go to our other API here, the Places API, and we're
going to set quotas in place for that as well.
Now, it's extremely important that you do this step.
If you don't do this step, you're not going to have the safety net of configuring Google Cloud properly.
So we're going to set requests per day to a thousand as well.
We're going to get requests per minute to a thousand as well.
And then we're going to set requests per minute per user to a thousand as well, so all of these are
going to be one thousand so that we are sure that we won't go overboard.
And once we've configured all of these, what we can do is we can go ahead and configure the credentials
that will need.
So the last one will need to do is over here, set up from a limited to a quota of a thousand.
And once we've saved that, we've now configured Google Cloud for the safety measure of the quota.
But we'll need to do next is we'll need to go look at credentials and what we'll see here is that in
order to configure our authentication, we're going to need something named the nitpicky.
So it's going to say currently we have no API keys.
What we'll do is we'll go to credentials and the API services.
And what we'll need to click here is create credentials and we're going to create an API and by creating
an epic, we're going to create an epic that we can use to talk to Google.
This is going to be our unique identifier that we use to talk to Google.
And when we want to do next is we want to restrict the key and by restricting the key, will disable
it from being able to be used with certain API.
So we're going to say this epic is only for polices and geocoding and will limiting its use specifically
to those two APIs.
That's another layer of protection that we're adding in.
And now that we've saved this, we have our API key available and we can now use it to do our calls.
Make sure you keep that close because we're going to be using it to set up other services and our connection
to Google.