We've looked a lot at how Iceland fits into the picture and how we're going to lend our code and figure
out errors in our code and consistent styling in our code, but we really haven't looked at how to make
our code adjust itself in the format that prettier gives us.
You see, prettier is integrated into Iceland.
So Iceland is going to tell us and complain about things that Prettier wants to fix.
But we really don't have a way yet to enforce the code style.
So if we go here back to Extension's and we looked for prettier, what we're going to find is that.
Well, there's a very popular package downloaded over nine million times.
Wow, and it's the prettier formatter for visual studio coat.
It's the opinionated formatter, right.
So what it's going to do is it's going to allow us to write our code however we want to.
And when we save, it's going to adjust the code.
So if we hit install on this, it's now enabled globally.
But how does it work?
Well, let's say that I went over into my code and I put a bunch of these over there and over there.
Well, now biosolids is going to play with prettier and like when we hover over the problem, we can
just press quick fix.
And we can say fix this pretty prettier problem, so we see how we can adjust every individual line.
Now, if we want to fix all of the issues, let's say I had multiple lines out of order, you know,
I can hover, I can peak the problem, I can see what the problem is or I can hover again.
I can do the quick fix and I can fix all fixable problems.
But what I want to teach you is if we go to code preferences settings and we search for format on save
and we turn on this option format on save, you want to turn it on.
Right.
And once it's on and I did a bunch of issues, my file is now in a noncommitted state.
So if I do this and I do this and I make this out of order and I do that and.
To come here for some reason?
Well, if I press command or control now, if you're on windows, it auto fixes all of the issues.
It's auto fixing everything.
It's applying prettier, right?
That is honestly awesome, because format on save is going to run prettier every time we save a file,
and that's going to save us a lot of time and a lot of effort in formatting our code.
All right, so now that we know that now that we've set up and set up prettier, we're basically in
a good state in our project to have consistent formatting and consistent styling for our code.
And that's awesome.
That's something that the industry also always looks for.