Time for us to enhance our feature now, as you can see, we built a search bar.
Well, we built a search view.
We built the view in which the search bar is going to live.
Now, with that comes well, we can't really fill anything into this or to this.
It's kind of just a static view.
Right.
And what we need is, you guessed it, another package.
Now, I promise all of these packages have a purpose, and the purpose is to make development easier
for us.
And as we go through the setup, things will become more and more easy as we gain more and more of these
packages.
Now, that being said, one of the packages that we need to add is called react need of paper and its
cross platform material designed for react native.
Now, as you know, React Native comes with a bunch of items like a view, a textfield, a button field,
but they're not really styled for us.
And so we can go through the motion of styling them or we can use a predefined package that has all
of these components already built out for us so that we can leverage them, which sounds easier.
Now, this is most often used in the industry because we don't want to reinvent the wheel.
Oftentimes theming is done.
So customizing the colors and the palette and the sizing and the spacing, but rebuilding all of these
very, very granular components is something that isn't really done.
So if we go and we say try a demo out on XPO Snack.
We can see here that we can go ahead and load a example of all of these components and how they work
in react need of paper, and I would suggest you go and try this out so that you can get a feel for
all of the different components that react native people will give you.
Now, that said, we need to get started.
And so to get started, what we want to do is yarn, add react native paper.
So you guessed it.
We're going to go into visual studio code, we're going to open our terminal and we're going to run
that good old command again.
Yarn ad react native paper.
And so by doing that, we're going to be adding react native paper to our package, Jason, in which
will now have the ability to use, react need of paper.
So that's awesome, right?
So we already added prettier and excellent and all of that good stuff.
And so now what react native paper, we're going to get access to all of these components and you can
already guess it, what do we need to do here?
Well, we want a search bar.
So what would we look for here?
Would we look for text?
Not really.
Would we look for search?
Oh, there's a search bar component.
Amazing, so they have a search bar component that has an input box where in which you can put search
queries.
Sick, so now we're going to utilize this, this is going to be the exercise, implement the search
bar from riak native people in the view where we put the green search field.
And try a couple of things out.
Let's see how it pans out and one of the things that we want to do here is just make sure that it's
there and it looks nice.
That's about it.
We'll get into the customization in the solution.
And so now that we've added react native paper, you can see it's available here now and it's up version
four point five point zero.
You don't have to exactly match the versions because as the course progresses, packages may update
as well.
We're on XPO version 40.
And when you start this course, we may be a version forty one.
OK, so that said, we want to implement the search bar from Riak native paper in the search view,
so let's get to that.