All right, we're getting closer and closer to having our app look like this, but we clearly see that
we have a search box here.
So in this video, we're going to work on having this interactive.
Looking back at our app, we see that what we definitely need a title and the search box, so let's
create that.
If I go to Index Dot, James, I think now that we're officially building an app instead of having the
Carlist component here, we should have one big component called app.
And this app will be the father of all our children, all our components.
Let's do that.
Let's build the app component first.
And this app component, again, will import react from react.
Well, equal.
The card list component, which we can just copy and put in here.
And again, changing this to Bable, we want to import.
The card list component.
And we also want to have our robots actually imported.
In here, so we have access to it.
And then finally, we now just want to render the app component so we can just bring this back to the
way it was.
We need to obviously export our app, so we'll say.
Export.
Default app.
Save this.
Let's go back, yeah.
Everything is still working now within the Scarless, we also have a header, so we'll do hattar one
that will say Wrobel friends.
And again, remember that we need to return just one single parent, so we need to do something like
a div to wrap it.
And I need to close this H1 tag.
All right, I have my Rabois friends title, and we also need a search box, and although each one was
easy and we didn't have to build a component for it, it sounds like we probably want to create a search
box component.
For this app, so let's do that.
I'm going to say.
Import search box.
From a file that will create called Search Box.
We will create a new file.
And this file will have.
Imports react from react.
And the search box.
We'll have a function that returns us, think about what it returns.
Well, it definitely returns and input, right, that is type of search and let's also have a placeholder.
Let's close this and a placeholder.
That says search robots.
We close this and safe and we have to export export default.
Save compiled successfully.
All right, we have our search box, but, well, it's not searching anything right now.
Let's add this on a new line.
Just so it looks nicer and it's always a good idea, just in case you want to add more things to the
search box to wrap everything in a div.
So I'm going to do that right now.
And this day, we'll just have a class name of padding to, again, using tachyons and with the input
we can do a class name.
And I just know these look good.
So I'm just going to copy and paste.
You're just padding or with background.
Lightest blue if I do this.
And let's go back.
All right.
This looks better.
We want to center everything.
So maybe in the app we can just add a class name.
Equals to.
Tax center, see if that works.
There you go.
That's much better.
I like this already.
Now, how can we make this interactive?
Up until now, we've just had this static websites, but real websites are interactive, right?
Let's think about this logically, we have an app.
We have a search box.
And we have a card list.
But the search box component needs to communicate with the Carlist and same with the Carlist, Carlist
needs to know what is in the search box so that it can filter out robots accordingly.
Let's go back to our image that we have of one way dataflow.
Looking at this, we have the app component and then the card list component that has cards and then
the search box component that doesn't have any children now.
But in order for these two to communicate, we have a one way dataflow that is they need to send their
information to their parent and the parent tells them what to do.
Now, how can we do that?
Up until now, we just had some data that we just trickled down, but we never had it where one of the
children had to modify data or communicate with a neighbor.
Well, in order to do this, React has an idea of something called state, up until now, we learned
about props such as properties that we keep passing down, but we've never changed them because of react
just with the props.
If I go to Carlist, it just with the props that it receives and it just renders something.
And this one way dataflow is really nice because this card list is a pure function.
It receives an input and then it always returns the same output.
So if robots are always the same, it's always going to return the same thing.
It's deterministic, pure functions, and it's something that we've talked about before.
And this is a really, really good thing.
These components are what's called pure components, and some even call it dumb components.
It just means that they don't really need to know about anything other than the fact that they're pure
functions that receive something and return something.
And this is really nice because we always know what this is going to look like.
And that's all we had up until this point, but now we have to worry about something other than props.
Props never change.
Props are always just inputs that we get and we've never modified them.
But in this case, we need a memory in our app.
We need this to communicate with this and also change and update accordingly.
And that's what state is in react state.
And you'll hear this in computer programming.
A lot simply means the description of your app.
A state is simply an object, an object that describes your application.
And this state which describes our application is the robots and whatever is entered in the search box.
And state is able to change, we're able to change the value of the search box, the value of the input,
and we're able to change what robots ouray means, what gets displayed.
This is a rule that you just have to remember, props are simply things that come out of state.
So a parent feeds state into a child component, and as soon as the child component component receives
a state, it's a property that child can never change that property.
The parent just tells it what the state is and the child receives it as robots.
So the first thing we need to do is to start being able to use state in our app, the description of
what our state should be.
So let's just do a constant state for now and show you that our state needs to have a robust array and
it needs to have let's call it.
And this is just whatever our search field needs, but in order to use state, we have to go back to
our original way that we created Rijad components.
If you remember this, when we first did create react tap.
We create a class.
And we do that.
By saying export default or export.
Extends react dot component.
It extends the component class and again, we can use shorthand here and just say.
So now we can just remove reac from here.
And this always has a render function.
That has to return something, which is this.
Again, is just the syntax that you have to.
Get used to.
If I say this and I made a mistake here, instead of export, this should say class, so yeah, class
app extends component and then we do export default app.
So again, we're just declaring a class I save and we just have something that says state is assigned
a value but never used.
That's because that's pretty true.
We don't use it, so how can we add state will and react?
We simply do a constructor.
You might remember this from when we spoke about object.
And this constructor in here, we can declare the state.
We simply say this state equals.
And in here, we just put whatever we want our state to have.
So if I save this.
I get this is not allowed before super again, something that you might remember from the Advanced Objects
video, in order to use this, we have to do this weird thing where we call super, which calls the
constructor of component.
If I do this.
And safe, everything's working fine.
And now we have our state, which is robots and search field.
And this state, as I said before, is what describes our app, these are the things that can change
and that's what it is state is something that can change and affect our app.
And they usually live in the parent component, the component that is the parent that just kind of passes
state to different components.
Now, I can access robots not from here, but from this DOD state dot robots and again, just react
syntax that you'll have to get used to.
All right, so everything is working as expected, and you see that our state, which is robots, is
now passed down as props.
So card list accepts robots as props, even though in the app dogs, it's state.
And like I said, because app now owns state, that includes robots, it's allowed to change it.
OK, now the way we can communicate them, we have these two values and ideally in the search box.
I have something called on search change, which, again, is a function that I'm just going to make
up.
This is just a random name that I've created.
And on search change, I want to say that every time the input changes, just like we did with dumb
manipulation, we get an event.
And within this event, I'm going to console dialog, this event.
Created a function.
And I want to any time this input changes to trigger console Dahlborg so we can pass this actually now
I can say.
Search change is on search change, but again, because this is an object we have to say this dot so
that it says this, which is the app dot on search change is searching.
If I save this.
And now go to the search box.
I now have search change.
As a function, so I can just say just like an e-mail, remember, and him all he can do on change HTML.
It's an event we're just listening to any time the input changes, I can say on change equals.
Let's see if that works, I'm getting no errors, if I go back to my app, I open up the console and
I type in something like that, I'm getting the event.
And this is just something you have to remember is that with an event we always have event dot target
dot value, which should give us the value of the.
Let's save that.
And type in something here.
Look at that, we're now noticing the difference as we type.
So let's go over one more time, what just happened?
And again, I know this is tough, this took me a while to get when we first started, but this diagram
really explains it well.
I have my app component, my search box and my card list.
Any time the search bloc changes on change, I'm going to run the function, I'm going to.
Call this function, and the way we call it is we add this remember how when we did Dom events, we
defined the function and then every time the event happens, it would call it.
So we are saying every time the on change event is triggered, called the.
Search function, and if you remember, the search function, which is a prop, is the on search change
function that is defined in the app.
That's how we communicate with the parent.
It triggers the event.
The parent says help run this function and now this function.
Gets read, but now that I have the value of the search input, I can now directly communicate that
search input to the robot's list.
Let's see how that works.
We can create a variable, let's say, filtered robots.
And this will equal the this state.
And these robots, which is Zeray, again, this is how we access state.
Is going to use the filter filtering our way, we give it robots, and now our array will have to return
a condition and the conditions are going to be robots dot name.
And we're going to do something that we haven't seen before, which is to.
Lower case, and this is a method that comes with all strengths and it just makes everything lower case,
and this is good for comparison.
So we don't have to compare capitalized or lowercase.
And if the name of robots, which is now lowercase.
Includes.
Is another method, and again, it's pre-built into JavaScript if it includes the search field.
And again, we want to do two lower case in case, well, in case we use capitals or lower case, it
works both ways and there it is.
If the name of the robots in lowercase includes.
And this does the comparison, if anything, in the string includes two lower case, well then only
return the robots that returns.
True to this, let's save.
Oh, and you see here the how I get the search field there, because, well, it's part of the state.
I have to do this state search field if I save this.
I get that filter robots is assigned a value but never used, but don't worry, we can now console log
this and see what we get.
Let's go back to our app, and if I see something here, I get an error and this is an error that is
very, very confusing.
It is tricky the first time.
But bear with me here.
The problem right now is that the value of this well, it's not referring to the app because the event
happened in the input.
The value of this is well, the input and input doesn't have state robots.
And this is a trick that you always forget.
But just keep this in mind as a rule of thumb.
With anything that comes from react so constructor and render our pre-built and react, any time you
make your own methods on a component, use this syntax.
So error functions.
And this makes sure that the this value is according to where it was created, which is the app.
I know it's confusing.
You can read up more about it.
I'll leave resource for it.
It's a tough topic to get.
But again, rule of thumb, use the arrows if I do this now and I click.
There you go.
I now get.
But here's the thing.
Search field right now, you see that I still have 10 robots, it's not really filtering anything and
that is because my search field is always an empty string in order to update state again, another rule
of react is to do this dot set state.
And it's, again, a method that comes with react.
And any time you want to change state, you always do this.
You don't do this dot state search field equals you never do that.
You have to do this dot.
And within here, we just say search field is and again, we're using an object, so search field is
now going to be event dot target, dot valley.
If I say this.
And go back.
You see that now everything is being filtered.
I'm changing the state so that the search field always gets updated and now we're filtering the robots
according to the changed search field.
OK, so one last thing.
Looking at this, we have the fact that filter robots is still not assigned, and you're right, if
we look at this, we've now communicated the search box with the app and we have the search field constantly
changing.
So now we need to communicate it to the filtered robots.
What we can do is that filtered robots can now be used as props instead of this state, that robots.
So let's do that.
Let's move this down here.
And now we have access to filter robots, and instead of passing this stuff, state that robots, we
simply pass filtered robots.
If I see this, make sure the search bar is saved as well.
And now I go back.
I'm going to close the tab and let's check it out.
Look at that, we have our app working.
How cool is that?
Let's go over it one more time to show you exactly what it does.
We have our app component that has two states.
Robots and search field and because app owns the state, any component that has state uses the class
syntax so they can use the constructor function to create this DOT state and this state is what changes
in an app.
It's what describes the app.
Remember when I said the virtual dorm is just a JavaScript object?
The virtual dom is just an object that collects this entire state and we act uses this state to render
and pass them down as props to these components so that these components that are just pure functions
can just render.
And we always know that the app is going to look the same because, well, they're just simple, pure
functions.
We manage the state and here the app is the only thing that can change the state, but it can pass down
things such as props.
So we pass down on social change to the search box and the search box.
Every time there's an odd change on the input, it lets the app know, hey, there was a change on this
function.
It runs the function with the event and updates the state of the search feel to whatever we type.
Now, with the information that we have from the search box, we can now communicate to the card list
and tell it, hey, I want you to filter the robot's state to now have only what includes in the search
field.
And instead of passing the this state, our robots, we just passed the filtered robots.
You might be asking yourself what robots never really changes, does it?
We always just create a new array called filtered robots and we always pass that down.
Does this need to be part of the state and right now?
Not really, because we're just have a hardcoded robot.
But when we get later on into the course, you'll see that that's not the case.
Most of the time you're getting the users or robots from another place over the Internet, in which
case we will need robots to change from an empty array to an array after we go and grab all of our users.
All right, that was a lot I know, I know it's a lot of information, a lot of new syntax, but as
you can see with a few lines of code, we build a pretty awesome app.
In the next video, we're going to finish this up and finalize our app.
So it looks as pretty as this.
I'll see in that one by.