Now that we've mastered what git is on our local system, be it Mac, be it Windows.
Whatever the case, what we want to do is we want to store our code somewhere.
Now, you may be saying I'm storing it on my computer and that's all good and well.
But if your computer fails, what happens?
Well, what happens is you lose your coat.
And so what GitHub is, is this little space man.
No, it's not.
Literally, GitHub is a place where 56 million developers, three million organizations and 100 million
git repositories live.
Now, what does that mean?
Well, it is the place where you code, you collaborate, you develop, you automate, you secure and
you have a community of developers.
Now, for those of you who have never used it before.
I don't blame you.
It's it's something that developers are very inundated with.
And if you're not in the developer sphere, just they're just getting started.
All of this may be very new.
Now, that said, GitHub is the place we want to be.
And once you get into this community, once you get into what they call open source.
That's where all the magic happens.
Now, don't trust me, trust the 70 million developers that are on here or whatever the number was.
But that being said, well, we need to do is we need to take our code and we need to publicize it.
We need not public.
You can make it public.
You can make it private.
You can make it whatever you want.
But we want to store it somewhere for backup purposes, but also for sharing purposes, but also for
a nice place to go.
Look at your code purpose.
So if you're on the go and you want to go look at a piece of code or whatnot, you know, somewhere
to store it online.
OK, so what I want you to do here is I want you to sign up for GitHub if my sales pitch wasn't enough.
Well, I don't know, but I need you to sign up for it.
So go ahead and create an account for GitHub, go through the process of verifying your account.
And once you're all good and logged in, choose a username, fill in your own email address, fill in
your own password.
And once all of that is done, create your account, write.
Let's say I made some random account, right, and I did like test password.
We could go through the process right now.
There seems to be an issue here, but I guess if I refresh, it may be OK.
There seems to be a small bug over here.
Try a different browser, for instance.
We could try Internet Explorer.
So let's go to that Internet Explorer.
Who would have known I would ever go to Internet Explorer to try things out, but you may see this happen.
Don't get scared.
If you do, things can go wrong with the sign up process.
And so once you've signed up for get what I need you to do is I need you to sign in to your account.
So that's what I'll do over here.
And so you can see here that I need a two factor authentication key.
And this is because I have two factor enabled.
And if I verify that now I'm logged in to my GitHub.
And so once we're here, we're good to go.
You just want to be logged in to GitHub.