In this video, we're going to focus on adding a text input to input what we want to focus on because,
you know, having text focus feature really doesn't do much for us.
So let's go ahead and remove that.
And let's start focusing on what exactly we want.
So if we want a text input, text input is something that we're going to take from a library called
React Native Paper.
So we're going to take this.
We're going to say text input and we're going to say from React native paper.
Now you may be thinking, Mo, what is React native paper?
Well, React Native paper is a library that gives us.
A bunch of components out of the box, and so like if we go ahead and we say, Hey, let's go look at
React native paper.
It's a cross-platform material design for React Native, so it gives you a punch, a punch, a punch,
it components out of the box that you can use to build mobile apps.
And.
Create you guys that fit the eye of people using them, because we want to enable you to build components
that match what you want and what the user expects from mobile apps.
So for 11 to is the latest release now, if we go look over here in our snack, we can see that, hey,
do we actually have react native paper?
So we go, look at our packages and oh, it looks like it was already added as a dependency, but the
dependency is set.
The four point nine point two and four point eleven point two is the newest.
So what we can do here is we can simply update this and Expo will go and install the latest version
out of the box.
Now if we go back over here.
Inside of React native paper, what we can see is that if we go and look for text input.
It will show us what a text input will look like on top of that, it will show us how to use text input.
Do we add a label?
Do we add a value?
How do we add on change text?
It'll show us what props are all available.
It kind of is the general overview of how you can use this component.
And so if we go to our snack and we say, Hey, I have a text input and let me give it the label focus
item.
Let's say that we set that as the focus item, and we quickly switch her device here and we tap to play,
then what we'll see is the text input come in with a focus item as the label.
So we're quickly opening our project and here we go.
Focus item.
And when we click on it, it pops up, so the label pops up.
Now, if we don't add a label at all, then we'll see that it will render just the same, but it won't
prompt us.
Right?
So what we can see here is instead of focus item, we can say, what would you like to focus on?
Question mark.
We can put it in a sentence.
And then when we tap it, boom.
What would you like to focus on?
A little nice to have.
Now the placement of this is very key.
Right now, it's kind of in the middle.
So let's take our time to create the correct layout for our input, so let's put input container and
let's create it as Flex one.
And let's add some padding padding.
Let's do 50 and we'll say Justified Content Center.
Center.
And now if we go here, let's wrap our text input would have you.
And let's wrap it if we go, and what we'll see here is a few style is equal to styles thought input
container.
There we go.
Now we'll see what happens.
Oh, looks like I missed a comma here.
So by adding that there we go, Oh, this is going all the way to the bottom.
Why is that the case?
Well, this container has Flex one and this container has Flex one.
So this is now centering along the screen.
So if we say zero point five, let's give it half of the screen.
What we'll see is that, OK, now it's actually taken up half of the screen and it's centered itself
within that.
So now let's just say justified content top.
And that looks good.
But let's adjust our panning a bit.
Let's make our focus and put a bit nicer.
And then when we click on it, it asks us, what would you like to focus on?
And now if I input something in here?
Right.
You can see that it's filling itself in.
Now we need to store that input.
So let's look at that.