So in order to set a variable, we're going to run firebase functions, config, set some service keys
equal to this study.
But before we do that, let's see what we have in our current environment configuration.
And so the way to do that is to do firebase functions config yet.
So if you run this well, we're going to see.
Is that currently well.
First of all, we have to copy paste that, correct?
Well, we're going to see we have an empty object.
And so now if we do, firebase functions can fix that some service key and we set it to some key.
What's going to happen is now when we run our get command, we're going to see that our local cache
is storing some service key.
In the next time we deploy, these keys will be pushed up.
Now, I don't want some service Stotsky so I can do something called unset.
I can do unset some service and this will remove this from my firebase configuration.
So that removes it.
And if we do the get now, we're back to an empty object.
OK, so what do I want us to do?
Well, I want us to do the set command, but I want us to do it in a very specific way.
I want us to set Google dot key and I want you to set that equal to your API key.
So in between these brackets, I want you to fill in your EPIK, not specifically what I'm typing right
here.
I want you to go copy paste your APIC from the credentials and I want you to piece that between here.
Then I want you to run that.
And then we'll be able to see it once you do again.
So if I said something like something here and then we went and did firebase functions that get I want
you to be able to see instead of something, I want you to see the API that you have right here between
these brackets or the string.
All right.
So I'm going to go do that real quick.
All right, so I set mine to Stormi Epic, I hope you did the same, and now the question becomes,
well, how do we utilize it now?
How do we utilize it in our code?
And that's a good question.
The way that we're going to do that is we're going to import something called CONSED functions, and
so we're going to import that directly into here and we're going to utilize functions that config,
that some service already.
But instead of calling some service that ID, what we're going to call is Google dot key.
And now if we go over to our meals to go and we say mock false O cannot read property key of undefined
by geocode request.
Interesting.
Well if we did our config yet we saw our configuration available locally.
Right.
We saw it in the firebase functions config get.
So why isn't it available to us.
Well the reason for that is right now it's only stored in memory as part of the availability to push
it up to Firebase.
It is not currently available to our functions project for the purposes of locally using it.
So in order to do that, we're going to have to do something special.
What we're going to do is we're going to open up our command line again, our terminal, but we're going
to go into the functions folder and now what we're going to do is we're going to do the same firebase
functions, get command, but we're going to use the greater than sign and we're going to say DOT runtime
config.
Dort, Jason.
And so this is going to be the file, so we're going to take our configuration, we're going to put
it in runtime config that Jason and once we do that, we'll have created a file runtime config that
Jason.
You'll see it over here, it'll be available and we're going to add that to our get ignore a very important
step, we need to add DOT runtime config JSON to our git ignore.
And so now it won't be pushed up when we push up our changes.
But this contains the configuration that we can see with firebase functions get.
Now, if we go back into our terminal and we go to the terminal two and we quickly restart because you
have to restart now.
It has to load in the runtime config that JSON when we do this, what is going to do now is it's going
to read this file and it's going to populate the functions config with that runtime config.
And if we go over to meals to go five thousand one, what we can see now is, wow, we're getting the
data back directly from Google Maps.
And so now I know this because while Chicago was something we had available, but let's fill in something
we didn't have available.
Let's fill in Montreal.
And when we do Montreal now we're getting Montreal's information, geocode it to us.
And the way that I can prove that we're actually using the actual API is if we go to our API overview
here, we can see that in the last hour.
In the last six hours, rather, we just hit some usage.
Now, it may take some time to update actually it may not have immediately updated it right here, but
in a couple of minutes, you will be able to see our usage here.
The most interesting part is that we're actually utilizing and getting back information from the Geocode
API.
So let's go take a look at our app, because that should be able to do that now, right?
If we fill in Chicago right here, should we get back our information?
Well, let's try it out.
Chicago.
And if we do, Chicago will that currently is not working.
So let's go take a look.
If we go take a look at location service and we take this host, Jason, that we get back.
And we say console dialogue result.
What we'll see is that we are getting back the location information directly from Chicago, and the
same is true for Portugal.
If we did Portugal, where we're going to see is that we're getting back the location information for
Portugal.
But why aren't we getting back?
Are restaurants on the cities that we already set up, Mo?
Well, the location information may differ.
And so the information isn't matching up to the longitude latitude that is being sent back by Google.
And so what we need to do now is we need to integrate the actual police's search because the mock data
only worked against the mock locations, not the live locations that we're getting back from Google
results.
And that's what I meant when I said the mock information is just the mock information.
It does not work between live API and non live API.
Just to prove that we're running live on the live API, we can do New York and by filling in New York,
we now know the location, longitude, latitude of New York.
It's right over here, the northeast southwest boundary and the longitude latitude.
OK.
So we've proven that our geocode implementation works just worked out of the box, it's just working
because we're not currently running our location service right here against Moch.
Now, the way that I can prove that is if we said over here and Mark is equal to true.
Well, now, if we reload our app, what we're going to see is that when we fill in San Francisco,
it works.
When we fill in Chicago, it's going to work.
When we fill in Toronto, it's going to work.
When we fill in New York, it's going to break.
And that is because it is not receiving any information currently because it's running in mock mode.
All right, so we've proven that our app works live awesome, so the next part is how do we implement
the polices API?
Well, let's take a look at that.