All right, so we built our search of our feature, but next up is this amazing, amazing list for you
now, this list for you, this list of restaurants in our facility is something that we're going to
have to build out.
But first and foremost, what we have to do is we have to build out these individual items.
Right.
We have to build out this little card view that is over here and lay out all of the information as it
comes in.
So that's the first thing we're going to build out.
We're going to build out this visual.
And in order to do that, we're going to have to go step by step.
So first and foremost, we need to make sure that we have the right data in place and we have to determine,
hey, what all is going into this view?
Will we have the name?
We have the reading.
We have the address we have, whether it's open or not, we have a picture.
OK, so all of that are the things that we're going to build out.
We're not necessarily going to focus yet on the little favorite icon here.
We don't have that feature just yet.
And we also have whether a restaurant is what type it is.
So we have the type as well.
If it's a diner or if it's something else, we have this little icon to distinguish whether it's a cafe
or a restaurant.
So that's good.
OK, so let's go and see how we determine that shape.
Now that we've seen what it looks like, we can go ahead and start building it out.