In this video will be focusing on getting the input from the text input to be a stored value and by
stored value, I mean, we're going to be keeping track of what's been input into here.
And for that, we're going to use the hook use state.
This use the hook is a hook from React that allows us to store values during the component lifecycle,
so as long as the component is mounted.
So if we do this and we go over here and then we say return.
What we're going to do is we're going to hit prayer here real quick, and we're going to say can't.
And the syntax is an array.
And we're going to see subject and then we're going to say set subject, we're going to say is equal
to use state.
And we're going to set no as the default value.
And by doing this, what we can do now is we can say here text input, hmm, how would I go about this?
Well, let's go look at the box.
If we look at the box and we look at usage, we can see here that they have this on change text property
that gives us the text as it changes.
So if we go back over here and we say on change text, what we can see here is.
That this prop.
Is equal to a function that has the value that is being input, and let's just go ahead and console
dot log that value.
Now, what you can see here is that I declared the prop, as would all props I put in the brackets and
then inside of that I declare the function that is going to output something.
So if I go on my phone here and I say hello.
Students.
We can see here that.
Hello, students is being console locked.
So what we can do here instead of doing this is we know that the value is the first property that is
returned in the function.
So all we have to put inside of here is.
Set subject, because set subject is a function that takes in a value, right?
And by doing that, if we call it with like, hello, it will set hello.
So by calling it this way, it's basically a shorthand for us saying.
Val is equal to set.
Subject of Val, that's the shorthand that we're doing, I think on change sex is equal to that subject.
Now if we go over here, what we can say outside of here is console log subject and then we'll be seeing
the same exact thing happening, right?
So if we do this now, we can see that, hey.
Right.
All of these emojis are being input into the subject, so we're now storing it in the state parameter.
And we now have it available for us to use in any given way we see fit.
That's awesome.
OK, fairly fairly simple, right?
Like, we already have so much done and it's kind of only like 20 lines of code.
Awesome.
So with that, we can now store our focus object.
And let's just go ahead and clean up some of the debt styling over here and in next video.
What we're going to do is we're going to try to save this subject.
We're going to try to save it so that our app knows about.