Welcome back.
In this video, we're going to talk a bit about something advanced and we haven't covered it much in
this course and we definitely will in the next section.
But I want to get started with it so that even though it might be new and confusing at first, by the
time we get into the next section, we'll come back and review exactly what we're doing.
I want to make this app more realistic in a real life app, we wouldn't necessarily have these robots
ridden like I have here and robots, dogs, I've just created this file.
But in real life, well, we're not manually entering users.
We would use something like an API.
And what that means?
Well, we want when this website gets loaded to make a request somewhere out there in the world of the
Internet and grab these robots from a server.
Well, we can actually do that we have over here something called Jason Placeholder, and you don't
need to worry too much about it, but they actually have a really nice y'all that we can use and they
return what we need a name and I.D. and a username.
The rest of the information, well, we don't really need it.
But as you can see, just by typing in this, your URL.
I get this, so using this, we're going to make our app a little bit more realistic.
If I close my successful, since we don't need them anymore.
And let's suppose the rest of the tabs as well.
Looking at this app component, we see that it is what we call a smart component, unlike the search
box or car list that are just pure functions, as you can see here.
APTA James actually has state.
A piece of data that describes our app and because they have stayed, we call them smart components.
And smart companies tend to have this class syntax now in real life, when we start up this app, this
robots would actually be an empty array because there's nothing there.
We haven't grabbed the user's.
So most likely if I save this.
Robots wouldn't display until I load the website, and then as soon as the website gets loaded, I ask
for the user's from somewhere over the Internet.
Somewhere, hopefully here.
So let's do that.
React comes with a few other things inside of components that we can use, and they're called.
Life cycle methods.
And it looks something like this.
Don't get too overwhelmed.
These are just methods that we can use in here that comes with react.
And they're called Life-cycle Hooks, because what they do is if we run these, it will automatically
trigger when this app gets loaded on the website.
Let me explain.
We see that we have three sections we have mounting, updating and mounting.
The way we act works is we do something called mounting when I click refresh here, the app component.
This component right here gets mounted.
Into the document with the idea of route, if we go back to our index HTML file, well.
Our Web page is nothing but a div with an idea of root when we say we mount a component, we're replacing
this and adding our entire app that's mounting.
So mounting is the start of the app.
Now, with mounting these are the life cycle hooks that get hit and they're in order, so the first
thing is it checks.
Hey, does this component have a constructor wall?
Does I have a constructor?
Yes.
OK, then run this piece of code.
Does it have component Wilmont?
No, it doesn't.
Then ignore it, does it have render?
Yes, it has rencher run this does it have component did mount no, it doesn't have component amount.
Ignore it and it just runs through this every time.
It also has something called updating, and that is whenever a component changes.
For example, when we had the list.
Well, every time I type something.
The Carlist component gets rendered because we have new information, the function receives new inputs.
Same with the input component.
So again, within those components, if we wanted to.
We can add component will receive props, should component update, so on and so forth.
And finally, with and mounting is when a component is removed from a page, for example, if we change
to a different page here, the component will unmount, the app component will get deleted from the
page.
These are called lifecycle hooks because they get run every time a component does something and it comes
with react.
So you can just put them in into your class component and they will automatically get triggered.
You don't have to worry about calling them.
Let me demonstrate this.
We want to use component did mount, which gets called out to render.
This says that, yes, the app component is mounted on the Web page and it's render that is it's displaying
something.
Well, we can do that by saying.
Component.
Did mount.
And because this is part of react, notice that I'm not using air functions here.
Now, within component amount, I can say console, dot, log.
If I refresh this.
And open up the console, you'll see that I have check.
If I refresh, there you go.
That was really quick, but you see that that gets called automatically, even though I haven't said
anything.
Using this, we can do something interesting now when component does mount, I can say this dot set
St..
To now have robots to the robots that we get from JavaScript file.
If I do this and save.
Let's refresh and see what happens.
It's really, really fast, but you see that.
We're getting our robots, I am saying run the constructor with an empty array just to show you the
order of execution here.
If I had a console log and we'll just say.
One here.
We'll say to you here.
And we'll just say.
Three, if I say this.
And open up the console.
I have one, three, two, three.
We have one.
Then three, which is render.
Then, too, which is component did mount and then three runs again, actually changed this to actual
words so that you see better what is actually happening.
If we save and refresh.
Look at that, we have constructor that Arun's first, then render, then component did mount just like
this order.
But we now also have render why did render run again.
Well, if you remember, we created the constructor, we ran Brender, and then we updated the state
and component did mount, so because we updated the state every time the state changes.
Remember, we go to the life cycle, it's updating Iran's render again.
So because it goes from an empty array to a robot's list, render gets rerun and the virtual DOM notices
that there's a difference and repaints our Web browser to include the robots.
Knowing what we just did, we can remove this.
And finally, make this more realistic, instead of using the robots file, I'm actually going to remove
this.
And in here, I'm going to show you a cool way to grab this list from here.
I'm going to copy the link.
And I'm going to say fetch, which we'll learn about in the next section.
We're just saying make this HTTP request.
And Fetch receives this again, we're just saying, go to here, dot, then.
This is going to receive a response.
And this response is, well, this part is a little tricky, you just have to get used to it.
Jason, we just have to convert the response into, again, something that we'll talk about in the next
session for now, just you can copy and paste this follow along.
We'll come back to this and explain what's happening.
And from here, let's add this on a new line so we know exactly what's happening.
We'll say then robots or we can say users, because in this case, we're getting users and in here we
can say.
This says state robots to equal users, and we have to make sure that we return this.
Safe.
Let's see if that works.
Look at that, let's refresh.
And you see that little lag.
So in here, we can actually make this smaller and reduce it to one line.
We should remember how to do that.
And we see that we're simply.
Updating state.
After we fetch, so we fetch whatever the users are, we're getting a response, we're doing some magic
here with Jason, which we'll talk about later, and then we're getting the users and updating the users
with set St..
So if I refresh again.
If I don't do this, let's say I just here don't do anything and return an empty object.
You see that I don't receive the robots, I only receive the robots after I update with these users.
How cool is that?
All right, that was a lot, and this probably looks pretty scary to make you feel a little bit more
comfortable because I'm using fetch and there's nothing attached to it.
Does this mean that it's part of the window object?
Let's check.
If I open up the console and I do window dot fetch.
Yeah, look at that.
Fetch is a method on the window object.
It comes with all browsers.
Now it is a tool for us to make requests.
To service and as you can see, this is a server that returns for us when we do slash users, a list
of users that we can use, which is perfect for our wrap.
And finally, you're wondering what if this was really slow?
What if this took, I don't know, five seconds and we had a whole ton of users?
Well, in that case, you can do something like an if statement if.
Robots that lenth is.
Zero.
In that case, we can return.
An H1 that says loading.
Or else we can just say return.
This, again, is just JavaScript, that's a beauty and the.
Oh, and you see, how I get robots is not defined because it's this DOD state robots, again, we're
referring to the state of the app.
And here, if I refresh, let's just say that we're not updating the state and I'm going to just return
an empty object.
Well, in that case.
I just get loading.
Very cool.
And this is how you build real apps with react, you have a loading bar they can just add here, make
requests on component did mount.
And interact with component's.
You know what we have ourselves here at?
There is one last thing I'm going to show you with React, and you've learned the basics and react,
you can take this now to build any app that you want.
So one more thing to go, one more little piece to get our react knowledge completed.
I'll see in the next one by.