I always think to myself, when I build the future, hey, how difficult is this really going to be
at any time, check out flaws thrown at me.
Get excited because they're so difficult, like, sure, we're decomposing this into a simple way,
but to be honest, payment flows are one of the most complex things you may run into.
And in this particular scenario, we're giving you the grassroots implementation of one that you can
build upon, that you can make more complex, that you can add and remove from and all of that good
stuff.
And that that makes me excited.
Now, over here, are you guys built to the extent that the credit card information can be filled in,
but we want to add some more sush to it, right?
We want to judge it up, if that's a term at all.
We want to make it prettier and more nice.
But in any case, over here, after the last section, we have our total and then we have a spacer in
our credit card input.
But we want to add some more interactivity here again, should it up now in order for us to do that,
what we need to do is also implement the name input.
Right.
Because in the credit card component, we need to take in the name of the person.
Right now, we just hardcoded it, but let's get rid of that.
So let's go back to our checkout screen and let's figure out how we're going to get that name input
going.
So the first thing we'll need is we're going to need a name over here, name and set name.
And that's going to be equal to use state.
And we're going to give it an empty text.
Right.
That's what we're going to input here.
And the reason that we're going to do it that way will actually, you know, let's let's give it.
No, let's not let's not even give it a value at all.
And so the reason we're going to do that is because right here before credit card input, we're going
to build something called a name input.
And that name input is going to be very important because if we do not have a name, we're not going
to show the credit card.
We're going to hide it until you fill in a name that's going to give it a little bit of, you guessed
it, judge.
Oh, God.
I'll stop now, but it's going to make it a bit more interactive and a bit prettier.
So now that we know that we're going to build name input, where's that going to come from?
Well, it's going to come over here from our components in the styles, Check-Out Styles and the name
input in checkout styles is going to be very important to us.
So right over here, what we're going to do is build out export consed name input and that's going to
be equal to a styled text input.
And what we're going to give it is kind of a nice margin around it.
Let's let's go ahead and grab margin and let's say props and we'll say props, dot theme thought space
and let's see three.
There we go.
Where is text.
But if we're going to come from the well that's going to come from react need of paper.
You guessed it.
Right.
And so now if we go look at our checkout flow, there we go.
A nice name input, but why isn't our name hiding?
Oh, well, we have to make sure that we have a name value not not have a name value.
OK, so the logic is important there.
So now I feel in MO, is it going to show.
Oh but yeah.
Well we haven't really added any interactivity to it of course.
So how would that work.
What is that going to look like.
First of all, let's give the name and put a label and let's call it name.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to say the value is equal to name.
And then what we're going to do is we're going to say on change text, we're going to get some type
of text value.
Right.
And we're going to call that and then we're going to say set name to T.
And so now we've linked the name input into our set name.
And that means now when I fill in MO here, any time I fill in anything, oh, text strings must be
rendered with a text component.
That's not good.
That means that when we delete our name right over here, it's breaking.
So what we need to do is we need to say over here.
Ifti.
Right, so if text length.
If that length.
Otherwise, we're going to set name.
To not and by doing this, what we're going to enable ourselves to do right here, I seem to have a
small issue.
There we go.
Let's do this and that.
And then let's put this here where we go.
So we're going to say over here and on change text, if the text has a length, set the name to the
text, otherwise set it to not.
And this will allow us the following.
If we add this to CART, we fill in MO here.
Now it's going to show, but if we delete, it's going to hide.
And that's because we're setting the name to not in this case.
What it was setting the name to over here was this.
And if you set the name to an empty string, well, now this is going to break.
Another way to get around that is, for instance, we could remove this logic completely.
Right.
And what we could do up here is we could say set name by default to an empty string and then here if
name the length.
And that way now if we go look, huh, must be rendered with a text component, so let's do greater
than zero and there we go at and if we put Moe here now, it's going to show if we remove it, it's
going to hide.
Mau Mau Mau, Mau Mau Mau Mau.
There we go.
So we have the interactivity there for the name and put.
Next up, we're going to link this back into the credit card input.
So we're going to say name is equal to name.
And now when we fill in a credit card input, we're going to get the name that we fill in to this field
to come in to the credit card input.
So if you fill in Rubini Mobeen, he's going to come into the credit card input.
OK, so now that we've made it here, next up, we should look at how to process the payment, what
what that button is going to look like and how to clear the card.