Last we left off, we had geocode working and we were certain that we were getting the right geocode
information, but when we moved towards the live API of Geocode, our mock places, API didn't function
because of the longitude latitudes not matching up necessarily with what Google was returning us as.
Google doesn't necessarily return us specifically the same longitude latitudes that we see in our mock
information now for us to fix that.
Well, there's only one way we need to implement the police's search request now in order for us to
do that.
If we go look over here at our Google Maps SDK and we go over to source places, places nearby, we
can see that there's a places nearby request that we can do on the client that takes in parameters that
will do the call to the places nearby and the parameters it takes our location, which is longitude,
latitude, a potential radius, digital keyword language, Monoprice, Max Price, all of these different
parameters that will narrow down our search.
And so now I'm going to show you how easy it is to actually implement this, because with a couple of
lines of code, we're basically going to integrate, fully integrate our application directly against
Google places.
Now, over here, we need to do something similar in the places request that we did to the geocode request,
which is we need to check if it is Mark equal to true.
We're going to check and only return the mock information in that case, otherwise what we're going
to do is we're going to do a client dot places nearby.
We're going to open up that function invocation and we're going to give it the information that it needs,
so it's going to take in parameters and then it's also going to take a time out of one second.
We're going to do our daughton were similarly to what we did in our geocode.
We do a then and a catch right in here and we'll copy paste that because.
Why rewrite, so now we're set up to give it to put together our parameters, now we have to take in
client as a parameter, make sure that we're passing it in at the next stress level.
So over here, make sure you're passing your client to your places request.
Once we've checked that and we know everything's right, we're going to give it location of, well,
you guessed it, location.
So we're going to give it, say, location, location.
You could shorten this to just say location.
It doesn't really make a difference in it working.
We're going to heart set the radius to be 15 kilometers.
This is set in meters, radius is set and meter.
So you can set whatever radius you want in meters and then we're going to say the type is equal to restaurants.
So we're going to search specifically for restaurants.
And then like we did on our geocode request, we're going to give it the key, which is the Google now
we have to make sure that we're importing the firebase functions so that we can utilize the config that
is coming in from runtime config and in the live environment will just come in through Firebase.
So now we're hard linking this.
And now that we have all of this going on.
What we can try is we can try to load our up against live information.
Now, it should be hitting places nearby.
Well, is it?
Actually, I shut down my server just to make sure during my development that I wouldn't hit any infinite
loops, error cases and I could have full control.
So always shut down your server when it's not in use.
Now, if we reload over here.
It's seeing that Jason value, height, HTML attributions, et cetera, et cetera, is not valid.
Well, if we go over here and we did a places nearby request with a hard fixed location, what we're
going to see is that in the photosphere, we're going to have an array, but it's going to contain an
object with a height, an HTML attribution photo reference and all different types of information.
So it's not really a photo.
It's a bunch of information to get a photo, but it isn't the photo itself.
Interestingly enough, what we can do here is we can say, well.
Let's just remove the photos or we can do something similar to what we did in our mock call, which
is Abde, the mock images to the results.
So over here, we can say Rez thought data that results is equal to restart data that results that map.
And we'll add the mock image to each individual restaurant that is returned.
And what we'll see then is when we add the mock image to each individual restaurant that is returned,
we can now search for specific places in the world and we'll get the information from that place, from
cities we haven't been able to do before and will be able to see on the map that we are in that city.
So we've now linked end to end our entire application live to Google Information, and we can search
for all types of different cities.
We could go for Hong Kong and then we'll load up Hong Kong and we'll see that.
Where Google is searching is right here in this center from where it considers Hong Kong to be.
And the same is true if we did Sydney, Australia, if we did Sydney, we're going to load up Sydney.
And we can see here that we can zoom in and see all of the restaurants that it's looking for in Sydney.
But the images aren't right, we've done the end to end integration, but all of our images are Mock's.
Honestly, we've completed our end to end integration against Google.
So that's amazing.
But the one thing that is left for us to do is to make sure that we can get those images correctly from
Google so that we can have our images come in that are actually the restaurant fronts.
Let's take a look at that.