One thing we are seeing happening in the app is everything is rendering properly, but the address,
the address doesn't look right.
And so here's where I would challenge you.
If we go look at the mock data and we go look at where the address is actually being defined.
Right.
If we look at kind of the police I.D., the scope, the reference, and then we we look here address
isn't called address.
It's called vicinity.
That was a miss on our part, wasn't it?
Or rather sometimes sometimes in an application.
What you want is you want to translate what the API is giving you, just like we created these extra
properties is open now, is closed temporarily.
Sometimes you want to translate a property to a different name.
And so what's important to know here is that it's not that facility is wrong.
It's rather that we want to name it address so we could do something like address is restaurant dot
facility and that would give us the address as a variable.
Now, vicinity is still on the object, obviously, because we're spreading restaurant and we could
do something like removing the key.
Right.
We could delete the key.
We could go through that transformation step and we can look at that later.
Once we add utility functions to clean up some of the things that we're doing in here.
For now, we're just going to leave it as is.
And so if we go inside and we save this and we go back inside our app, what we can see is, oh, OK,
now the addresses are rendering properly.
So we had a bug, but it was an intentional bug because we had changed the shape of what we expect it
to come back.
But we hadn't checked our mock data properly enough to realize that address was actually named vicinity
in the data.
And so this is part of the trickery of when working with APIs.
The API may give you something.
You may expect it to be named something else.
You may set up a component in a specific shape.
But that shape doesn't match the reality of the data, and so this is why I'm doing this specifically
to show you the power of separating out.
First of all, we separated out our request and then separating out the transformation and pushing it
to the edge of the system because we have full control here over what's coming in and what it's supposed
to look like.
And we have changed it with one line of code and suddenly the UI has all of the benefit of it because
it's rendering out properly now.
Right, and so that's extremely important to note here.