We're getting into our first feature built, and so like we did in focus time, we're going to set the
stage for us to be able to build proper components.
And in order to do that, what we want to do is we want to create a new features folder.
And in that features folder, we want to create a different folder called restaurants.
Now, next to restaurants will also be building other different features.
But inside of restaurants, what I want is a components folder.
And other than a component's folder, we also need a screens folder, so we're going to also build a
new folder screens.
This is going to be useful for when we get into how navigation is going to work.
But for now, we're just going to leave that alone.
Now another.
Feature that we will be building is the account feature and the settings feature, but for now we're
focusing on restaurants.
So the very first component we're going to build is going to be a restaurant info dot component thought
jazz.
And we're also going to be already building out the screen restaurants.
Dot screen dot, yes.
OK, so we have our our info component and we have our screen component.
And so right now all we've been doing is building directly inside Appalachia's.
But the thing that we want to do here now is we kind of want to move things over into the feature itself
because we don't want things to live here for the long term.
Right.
That wouldn't be useful.
So we're going to take our safe area of you and everything to do with that.
And what we're going to put here is restaurants screen, and that's going to be the screen that we will
be rendering.
So right now, we're going to see a bunch of red.
But right here in this file, in the restaurant's screen file.
Right, what we're going to do is we're going to import react from react and we're going to export CONSE
restaurants screen.
And that's going to be a feature in which we're going to render out everything that we already had,
so in here you can see that, well, we need to do a bunch of imports.
So we're going to go back to our APGAR'S file and we're going to grab everything that we had here from
these imports and we're going to put them at the top.
Now, we can already see that we we need our stylesheet as well.
So we're going to grab that because we're not going to use it over here.
We're going to use it in here.
And once we have our stylesheet right, we have to look at everything that we have in here and our restaurant
screen is basically ready to consume at this point.
So if we go back to Appalachia's, what we need to do now is we need to look like we're not using any
of these.
We're not using the search bar.
So let's go ahead and do an import.
So we're going to import restaurants screened from that source slash and then we're going to go to features.
We're going to go to restaurants and we're going to go to screens and we're going to go to restaurants
screen.
So this is the screen that we want to render out.
And once we do that, what we're going to see here is that we're now rendering the same exact thing,
but we're structuring our code.
So we're structuring our code so that we're set up for the long term success.
Now, inside of here, what we basically need to do is we need to build out what the list is going to
look like.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to get rid of the blue background, although it's
beautiful.
Well, let's leave it for now.
What we want to do here is inside of lists.
What we're going to do is we're going to render out restaurant info, which is a component that we're
going to build out inside of here.
So we're going to import, react from react.
And again, we're going to export CONSED restaurant info.
And that's going to render out.
For now, a text that says restaurant info, text, and we're going to make sure that we import what
we need to import, so we need to import.
From React Native.
And so that in itself, we now need to import inside a restaurant screen because we don't have the import
here, right?
We don't have this file.
So what we do here is we say import restaurant info from THARTHAR components, restaurant info component.
Right.
And so now what we're going to see here is restaurant info.
So we've set the stage to start building out restaurant info component and building out the card view
that's going to show the information of the restaurant info.
So in the next video, we'll start building that out.