There's this thing that keeps bothering me, and it's that we keep seeing this error, this warning
popping up, each child should have a unique Kiprop check, the render method of restaurant info card.
And so what I want to do now is I want to go and solve that because it's starting to bother me, isn't
it bothering you?
And so if we go to restaurant info card component, what we're going to see here is if we go to the
render method, we'll see.
Well, what exactly is it complaining about?
Oh, over here, we put together a rating array, but we didn't give a key to each individual star,
that can be a problem.
So what we want to do here is we want to take the index of the array, which is not a great way to give
a key.
Right.
Any time you give an index as a key, it's not guaranteed to update correctly.
But what we're going to do here is we're going to use the index as part of the key.
So we're going to say key is equal to and we're going to construct the key.
We're going to say.
Star Dash, and then we're going to pick a property off of here, right, so we have a name orating
Placide ID.
So let's go look at the data.
Well, if we go look at our services and we go look at our mock data, we can see here in the mock data
that we have a police ID.
So that's equal to some place ID.
Usually this is kind of like a random string right now.
I put it as kind of this now will take that place ID and remember we Camil Keystart.
So it's going to look like this and we're going to say Star Police id dash I just to make sure that
it is completely unique.
And so by doing this now, what we'll see happen inside of our terminal when we run our code is if we
scroll all the way to the bottom.
And we refresh here.
What we're going to see is that we will no longer have this key issue popping up any more.
OK, that's great.
So by doing this, what we've basically achieved is the removal of a warning.
These can pop up anywhere, any time you do any type of map, any time you do any type of iteration
where you're trying to render the same element multiple times, you have to make sure that you're generating
unique IDs.
Now, in this case, Placide is guaranteed to be something unique because it's coming from an API at
some point and it should usually be one concurrent string that's going to work well.
And then the AI is going to allow us to iterate and say, well, that's the start one to start to the
start, three in the start for it's a combination of things that make it unique.