I hear you wondering, Moe, I get it get is important, but it's also optional to push to get huben
all these things.
But it's I get in school too.
I hear you saying motorcycle to school to.
All right.
But now.
What's up, what's what's going on here?
What are we going to do, like I get the whole revision tracking, I get that the files go up into the
cloud and can come back to me and I can see what's changing and all of that good stuff.
So I have a proper idea of how to do changes to my code and keep track of the changes.
OK, well, now now comes the good part.
Now we're going to run focus time locally.
But there's one thing I do need to tell you.
As a Windows user, you come with a massive disadvantage, and that is that the Mac ecosystem, Apple,
they only allow Apple computers to build four I OS, which means that at the end of the day, we're
only going to be able to run on Android.
OK, what kind of disadvantage does this give me?
Well, don't be afraid.
If you have your own iPhone, you can still run your focused time app on your iPhone directly through
the QR code that I'll show you.
But if you want to run something called an emulator and an emulator is defined as a piece of software
that is going to act as the phone on your computer.
If you want to run software on your computer, that's going to act like a phone, act like an iPhone,
act like an Android phone while on Windows.
You're only going to have the ability to do that with Android.
So we're going to install something called Android Studio.
And this is the one stop shop for Android developers.
Hands down one of the greatest tools for Android development, if you're doing it natively, but in
this case, we're not doing native Android developer.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
We're doing react native development, which is so much cooler because we write once targeted both platforms
so much cooler than just writing for one platform.
But OK, why do I need Android studio then?
You just said it's for Android developers.
It comes with tools that are required on your machine locally in order for you to be able to build on
your local machine to target Android.
You see, when we were running everything inside of the browser inside of the Expo snack, behind the
scenes, a lot of heavy lifting was going on for us.
And we didn't really have to concern ourselves with all of these tools and all of this set up and all
of this yada, yada, yada, yada, yada, yada, yada.
But now the data is important.
Now we have to go and we have to get the tools that we need in order to build on our computer to push
these changes.
Or build these changes, rather, for Android.
OK, so this is a rather large package and it may take a minute or two, but what we can see here is
that Android studio is going to give us software.
And this software we're not really going to use is going to be behind the scenes doing some heavy lifting
for us.
We're not really going to interact with it all too much.
We're going to simplify things and build things.
But we need to set it up in order to make sure that we can build out the right way.
OK, so once this installation or this download has finished, we're going to start the installation
of Android studio and I'll be back for the UIF.
I felt like that took hours and made depending on your Internet speed, unfortunately.
So now that Android studio is ready to rock and roll, we're going to click it and when we click it,
it's going to start the installation procedure.
Now, this may be a longer process, so you have to be patient.
And this is where things can go wrong.
And depending on your system, you may run into cases.
Now, Google is always a good place to go look, but we always recommend reaching out to our community
first on this score.
So join our Dischord community.
Join it now.
It's amazing people will help you because with these types of setups, things can go wrong and you want
the best help out there and our community is the best help out.
Now, what we want to select well, we want to select Android studio and we want the Android virtual
device, we're going to roll with the basic settings, roll with the basic settings, and now it's going
to go through the installation procedure, which may take a while, and it's going to go through extracting
a bunch of files, installing a bunch of files, putting things in the right place for us.
These files that you're seeing happen and all this stuff.
This is all software that is used by Android to build Android apps.
It's the native stuff.
It's the guts of Android and what it needs to to build Android apps that it's installing for us right
now.
So when we press next.
What's going to happen here is it's going to say, hey, import settings, we don't have any settings.
All right.
Well, if we don't have any settings, what do we have?
Well, we have Android studio now, which is what exactly what we need is going to ask us today to share.
We're going to say, if you want to sense the sticks, you can send statistics.
It's going to take us through this wizard.
And this wizard is to set up our development environment.
So we're going to press next and we're going to select standard and always big dark thing.
Just always pick the dark thing.
It's so much nicer.
OK, so it's going to install it's going to now install all of the real guts that it needs.
So it's going to install something called an SDK or a software development kit.
And so it's going to take one point sixty nine gigabytes of space.
Make sure you have that space and it's going to install all of these SDK and all of this good stuff
that we need.
OK, so press finish and now it's going to go through the process of downloading these things and putting
them in the right place.
And if you press show details, it'll tell you exactly what it's doing.
It's unzipping a bunch of stuff.
It's going to pull a bunch of stuff from online.
It's going to install a bunch of stuff.
This may take a while, so be patient and once it's done, we'll be back at it.
So I went through my installation process and I saw this unable to install internal hardware acceleration.
Manager, your CPU does not support it and that's completely fine.
That's OK if you see that.
So let's finish.
And now we have Android studio, so I want you to configure and I want you to go to avoid manager,
this is the Android virtual device manager.
Now I want you to hit play on the emulator.
And it's going to say cannot start, why could it not start, right, what's happening here?
Why could it not start?
What's what?
What why?
Well, your computer does not support hardware, accelerated graphics.
So here are some of your options.
Use a physical device for testing, develop on a Windows X computer that has intel processor develop
on a Linux computer, use an Android virtual device based on an R.M. image.
This is ten times slower.
OK, so if your computer does not have this well, as we can see here, this default.
Is set up with something we don't have.
So this may work for you if you have hardware, accelerated management graphics, but.
This one doesn't, so let's go over here and let's go down here and let's say let me take a Nexus five,
right.
And I'm going to go next.
And what I can say is, what are my other images, which ones do I have?
Right.
So I have this one over here, the R in the 86.
Huh?
Is this the one I need?
Probably so let's press next while it's saying my CPU does not support Vertex, while can I use the
stun?
Looks like I have to go to other images, right, and I have to download an Arem based one.
So let's go ahead and let's download that except next.
And once this installation is complete, we'll be able to create a virtual device that is supported
by.
Devices that don't have a virtual like an intel processor.
All right, so we have an ARMM 64 beast image of Android now, and so basically what's going on here
is the infinite war between Intel and non intel devices.
Machine I'm running on does not have Intel.
So it may very well be true that a default Android virtual device that was set up may work for you.
It did not for me.
And that's why we're going through this setup.
Do not go through this portion if that play button initially worked for you.
OK, so now we have this, so let's press next.
Next, is this OK, we have an are all that good stuff.
It's an area based one, good, good.
Let's go to advanced settings.
And then let's say down here, is everything good?
Is everything good?
Everything looks good.
So let's finish.
And let's try the air in Beast one, and so that one was killed, why was it killed?
Well, it's guilt specifically because I'm technically running on parallels.
And because I'm running on parallels, some of these functionalities do not work on parallels, but
I was showing you how you could possibly go about doing this.
Now, if you have an Android device or an iPod device, you're still good.
I'm just trying to show you how to do this.
If this is still a showstopper, you can use your mobile phone to still do the app development.
Don't worry about that.
I'm trying to show you this.
So let me show you how it would look like on Mac.
If we went into Android studio here.
Android studio.
And we opened that up on Makk, for instance, which is the default device, and we went into a city
manager, you can see here that when I pressed the button.
Is basically what you should see, this device should boot up and this is what you should have available.
This is not what's happening on the parallels machine that I am running on.
And this is a limitation due to the software that Windows is running inside.
But just trust, if you press the button, you'll be able to launch an android.
And if it's if it's not possible, you can still use your mobile phone.
And that is completely fine.
Now, you do not need the virtual devices to run.
What you need is, is Android to be available.
And so we have gone through the Android installation.
Now, the next part of the installation is we need node and yourn.
What's that going to look like?