Now, before we get into the nitty gritty of the second feature that we're going to build, one of the
things that I want to point out is that we've kind of been using sizing all over the place with different
types of numbers.
Right here we have 25, then we have margin 10, we have size 50.
We don't really have a consistent basis here and these magic numbers, they won't scale as your code
base scales just in general.
Now I know that this is just a code along and that a lot of these things may seem.
A bit over the top in terms of structure, or you may not do it this way, and that's completely fine,
but what I like to do is on top of a coloured utility.
Usually I'll have a Size's utility where I'll just grab kind of the most general sizes that are used,
right, whether it be font sizes, based sizes, and you can go ahead and export konst font sizes.
And we kind of use that as an object, and then I'll have expert cost spacing and I'll have that as
an object.
And what those basically will be for is kind of to do spacing parameters like so.
And I'll do similar for the font sizes, and that way we can consistently use parameters like font size
is that small medium large x large.
And so there's semantic meaning that we're adding here.
And if we go look at, for instance, our focus object, one of the things that we could do here is
we could import spacing.
From and then we'll do dot dot slash utils sizes, and what we can do then is we can, for instance,
say spacing dot small and oh, that moved over to pixels because sizing small eight.
And over here we can say spacing dot.
Large.
And let's go look at what that is, and our large is 24.
So it's off by one, but they kind of increment in times eight likes or eight, 16, 24, it's always
plus eight.
So it's consistent.
And by doing this, we now add semantic meaning.
Now, if we wanted to do kind of the sizing over here, we'd probably be looking at an XXL or even an
XL.
But for the button, I'm OK to leave it like this as a 50 because it's inside of the render cycle.
So we're saying, Hey, this this button here that's being run out, just give it 50.
But for the styles, I like to be consistent and use the semantic meaning of sizes.
Yes.
So that's just, you know, a little insight in how to clean up some of the magic numbers that we throw
around here and there.