I want to add one final thing that we've kind of overlooked up until this point, because, well, I
don't want to bog you down with too many things if we take a look at our project.
Well, it's.
It's a lot of files.
Even though it's a simple app, you can imagine how bigger and bigger and bigger this source file can
get, an organization is a big part of working on projects.
Most applications will be way bigger than the ones that we've built, and we need a good way to organize
these.
And folder structure is one of the most important things.
So let's clean up this code.
I'll show you what I would do if I was working on this application.
And I want to make it more accessible.
That is cleaner.
So when other people come on the team, they understand it.
And also I can keep growing this code base.
First thing I will do is I'll create a few folders one.
Is going to be called.
Components and these are the components that we've built, such as Carlist search box and Skrull, the
second one is going to be called containers and containers.
Are these smart components, the containing components that have state in them, that have lifecycle
hooks, that have the class syntax, you see these components or these containers.
We can't use a pure function with them because technically they're not pure.
They have state that they modify within these functions.
And that's OK.
It's impossible to have just pure functions because most of the time, while we may need to make requests
to the outside world.
But these components are special.
We're going to call them containers, they contain things, and they just passed out state to components.
Now we can just say that we're going to move.
Access to now be in containers.
We're also going to say, yes, we're going to move it to be in.
Containers as well.
And then the components, the simple functions, pure functions that we've created, search box, Skrull
and Cardless, well, these can be in components.
Let's just open up the folder and make this simpler.
Going to close the tab, open up Wrobel friends, and let's open up source will say that scroll search
box.
Card and card list, which are just pure functions, are inside of components.
Now, if you remember, our font is also part of the app file, so we'll move that in there as well
because it's defined in their.
With that, let's go back to our map and, well, now we have a lot of fails because.
These now refer to different parts.
We don't app well, lives in a different folder than Carlist in search box and scroll.
The way we do that is we use dot dot, which means leave the folder or go to the folder and then from
there.
Go into the containers.
Or sorry, go into from the containers, so we're apt jazzes, I'm going to leave, which is dot dot
and then once I got here, the folder level, I'm going to say component's.
And I can do the same for the rest of them as well.
Safe.
And we also have.
Index thugs that now is referring to app that lives in containers, so again, because we're now leaving
a folder, we're in the same neighborhood while we can just do dot containers.
And I spelled out wrong good spelling by me.
Everything looks fine.
Let's go back to our website.
There you go.
Everything is scrolling nicely.
OK, so we have a nice folder structure here, things have cleaned up and we also have scroll down and
I think we just have an extra copy of it so we can just.
Might have made a copy of that.
Make sure everything still works, yeah, everything still works.
We want to remove a couple of spaces here that we've done, we also notice a few areas, so not necessarily
areas, but stylistic things.
For example, with the filter, I say filter the robots and iterate through the robots.
That doesn't really make sense, does it?
Should be.
Each item is a robot user that we get.
Still the same, no errors.
I also see a bit of cleaning that can be done with.
With using this state a lot, we can just say again, using the structure, we can say const.
Robots and search field, we're doing the structuring.
He calls this.
Dot St..
And now I can remove this state from here, I can't remove this dust from here and from.
All the other places that we're using this state and the render by save.
Everything still works, but the code is much cleaner.
We also noticed that within here, a robust length equals zero.
There's actually an easy way of doing this and again is just stylistic.
This is going to equal zero.
So if this is zero, that's going to evaluate in JavaScript to false, so we can just say the opposite.
Remember the syntax.
So if this is zero, which is going to be false, turn it into true so that if there's no robots, we're
loading.
Safe, and that's just still work, and then finally, if you see NFL statement.
Well, we can do a ternary can we we can say.
We turn robots if there's robots.
Return this.
Let's see if that still works.
We don't need that extra.
Look at that, it still works and you can see now that things are much cleaner.
We have an app.
That renders all our things for us and to finish off remember package Dodgson, how we had some pre-built
scripts and we had this build command.
If I stop this now and I do npm build or npm run build.
While this is building, they've created a new folder called Built and Within Here.
We have all our files, but this time optimized, what does that mean?
Well, if we go to static and go to James, look at that.
Everything is minified for us.
Our success is optimized and everything that we need to deploy the website is in this folder so we can
now take this built folder and put it anywhere.
So it's on the Internet and it even gives you some good information.
So now we have this optimized build.
We don't have to minifie it.
We don't have to do all these optimization.
It goes through Bable so that we can use import statements in the browsers and now this build folder
can now be deployed anywhere.
Like I said, create react app takes away all the pain of the setup, everything is done for you.
You can just write code, use, react components from around the web to build beautiful websites.
I hope you're excited about react as I am, this is why it's such a popular tool and this is why so
many companies now are using it.
I'll see in the next one, bye bye.