It's time to get into our next major feature, as you can see in our current app.
We have a full search functionality.
We can figure out where, what, how we can search a location.
We can get the restaurants in that location.
We have nice random images and information rendering for every location.
We can even show if they're closed temporarily or not.
We have set up all of this amazing infrastructure.
But the one thing we don't have that the real app currently does have well, there's a couple of features
that we still need to work through.
But one of the big features is we need a detailed screen.
We need to be able to show a detailed screen with a nice, smooth, scrollable action.
Right.
That screen is going to showcase the card information that we currently have.
But what is also going to showcase is kind of a static menu.
And that static menu is there as a purpose to kind of categorize what kind of details we could show
at a restaurant.
Now, Google doesn't send us back the menu information, unfortunately.
So this entire feature is going to be static for the menu.
And there is no real API out there that can go and figure out the menu per restaurant without doing
some type of scraping action or kind of like some more advanced types of things that extend way beyond
the capabilities of what Google supplies us or otherwise.
So with that, this feature inside of here for the menu is a static feature, but the restaurant information
is dynamic and all of the information around the restaurant is dynamic.
And the modal feature is here to showcase from a UI perspective kind of that usability aspect of that
that finish that you would expect from a mobile application that you can showcase in the workplace.
In the production level.
Apps also require production level.
Apps require this smooth transition, this buttery, smooth kind of feel, as well as this nice UI separation
with the drop shadow from the menu.
And that in itself, that holistic feature is what we'll be focusing on now.