Dissolution is a bit more involved, and it combines everything that we've seen so far in a way that
addresses a lot of the things that we will be going through in this course and again, will be learing
this like a cake will be introducing more and more complex concepts as we go along.
So first and foremost, let's look at what the solution looks like.
So the solution looks something like this over here.
You can see that we imported card from Riak native paper and we imported stylesheet from Riak native.
Then what we did.
It's in the return function, we implemented a card and I gave it an elevation of five because that
felt about right visually when I was looking at it and I implemented a style in styles like card, so
I created a style sheet and I gave it a background color white.
And then I took a card cover, which is an image.
I gave it the key of the restaurant name and I gave it a style styles cover and I gave that a padding
of about 20.
You could play around with this whatever looks right to you that you don't have to take the exact numbers
that I put in here.
It's whatever feels right aesthetically to you.
And I also gave it a background color of white.
And then beneath it, I put a text name, so I put a text field and I gave it the property name, and
so this is how we put text from props between.
The text component, so this is at its finest, and so what you can notice here is that next to the
Styles cover, I also gave it a source.
So this is considered an image component and I gave it a source.
And I said in the inner object, in the inner object, I said that the URAI is going to be equal to
photos zero.
So photo zero because photos up here is an array.
The very first photo is what we are going to use as a.
Cover photo.
And the reason for this and the reason that we're using this structure is because eventually again will
be implementing against an API of Google and we want to kind of keep close to the shape that will be
returning us.
We may change some properties around for ourselves, like it is closed temporarily and is open now.
We're not using these properties just yet.
But in any case, what we've done so far is we've built out this nice little cover item that is spaced
correctly in between the blue.
So giving this the blue background really gives us the ability to see what is happening.
And we could go even farther and we could say style equals style title.
And we could say that title over here has a padding of 16.
We could do that.
We could say that.
And that way the restaurant gets a bit more breathing room.
And that's obviously nice.
But you can see that here it's not really taking into account.
Why is that?
So let's go and let's show the element, Inspector.
And we can see here that the text well, looks like I made a typo.
It has to be style.
And there we go.
Now it's taking into a court padding.
So you have to make sure that you use the right property names as well.
And so otherwise.
Otherwise, visualization may not render you may not even get an error.
If you do get an error, you can always see it in the console.
So in the console, it will basically show you any errors that you may be going through.
If you're running the app, if you have any errors of the app isn't rendering, it'll show you the error.
So, yeah, a nifty little feature that we built just there very quickly.
And look how nice it already looks.