We've covered the full end to end implementation of our Google Maps integration, but there's a couple
of loose ends we need to tie up, first of all, over here in our location requests and our geocode
request.
And as well, our places request, we kind of never turn on moch mode ever again, and this is a problem
for many reasons.
First of all, what if we want to develop in mock mode?
So what we can say is over here and Mark is equal to is Mark and we're going to declare in is mock inside
of the environment that we're going to be able to set to true or false.
Now, we're going to do this both for the location service as well as for the restaurant service.
And what we'll do here is import is Mark.
And we'll set it here at the end by saying, and Mark is equal to is Mark.
By doing this now, what we can do is when we turn on our server right here in terminal and we go over
here to level three yard serve and we serve up.
Environment.
What we'll be able to see over here is that if we say export consed is moch false.
Now, what it will do if we refresh here is it will go and pull from the live information, so it will
go get live places information, which is great.
But now if we set it to true now, it will fetch more information.
And that just closes the loop for us on being able to develop in mock mode versus non mode, which is
honestly a great way of going back and forth.
But there's still one problem we have.
Remember when I told you that Android did not have the ability to use the FTP local instance?
Well, I told you, you can definitely use the live host and you can deploy.
But we didn't really make it easy on ourselves.
We would have to do this.
And that doesn't really feel super nice.
So what we can also do here is we can say import platform.
From React Native and we can say consed export const.
Is Android and will say platform talk os equal, equal, equal to Android.
So what we need to do now is we need to determine a way to tell the host to use the live host in case
it is Android.
So what we're going to do is we're going to invert over here.
We're going to say if it is not development.
Or it is Android.
Use the live host or otherwise use the localhost.
And this should enable us on Android to be able to directly link to the cloud functions.