So we've reached the end of set up or have we?
Now, one thing to note would react native here is that issues may arise with your set up for random
reasons.
This may be due to a faulty state.
Something went wrong inside of the package for all types of things can happen.
So I want to give you some simple debug steps to help you along the way, because it can be frustrating
when you're first starting out to get all of this set up and get all of this in the right order.
So there are a couple of solid steps that we can always take in order to make sure that everything is
running as intended.
First and foremost, make sure that your packager is running.
And to do that, you can always run yard, start to make sure it's running.
And when you run, you start, the packager will run and it should bring up this localhost.
Nineteen thousand and two screen.
That's the very first step.
Now, if for some reason you're hitting any errors inside of here or it won't even get to that step.
Well, then there's something else we need to do, also remember to exit any process you can press control,
see?
OK, so here's the thing, let's say for some reason you can't start already.
ERARD Well, what we would need to do here in this case is if we go to Visual Studio Code.
What we would tend to do in this case is, for instance, if we look at our code here, the first thing
we would do is we would delete the node modules folder and by deleting the node modules folder will
be able to basically get to a place where we can restart everything.
So you can you can do that in different ways.
You can right.
Click here and press delete or if you're in a terminal, it depends.
You could run R.M. node modules if you're on windows.
This may be a bit different.
And if we do that, we have to do minus R node modules.
And so that's going to delete the entire node modules folder.
This may take a minute.
This is a very large folder.
Even when you right click to delete it, it can take a while.
But once that's deleted, what we want to make sure is that we run yarn again.
And this is going to reinstall all of our packages.
So always make sure that if you're running into any issues, you clean node modules and rerun it from
the start.
Another debug step that is very, very important is, you know, from time to time, if you're using
simulators, close them and reopen them because they can get slow as time goes on, they can be consuming
memory.
So you may want to shut them down and restart them the way that we showed you, too.
That's another important debug step.
And if you're hitting certain errors that are just blocking you and you don't know what's happening.
Well, what I would suggest is always taking that error right, whatever the error may be, and going
to expose GitHub, page the issues and remove this here and try to search for your issue, use different
keywords.
You can search for bundler not starting.
You can search for the specific error that is happening.
And there may be different issues here that come up that could help you.
Another way is to go straight to Google and just copy paste part of your error.
Selecting part of your error may help you or doing react native XPO bundler not launching, not starting.
That can put you on the right track.
If all of that fails, always reach out to either the section or directly to the community.
We prefer reaching out directly to the community on our amazing discord because we will help you out,
whether it be myself as the instructor MO or some of our awesome students that may have run into the
same problems, because, again, all of what we're learning here is new and set up can be difficult.
So it's important to reach out and program along with your peers because this is a learning experience
and we want to make the most of it.
And you can learn from the others in the community and you can teach something to the others in the
community.
If you find something, it's always nice to share knowledge and receive knowledge from others that have
done the same thing.
All right.
So with that, we'll get into the set up of our master project.