Where do we start?
Well, first of all, you can go ahead and try out the snack by XPO for reac freestyler components and
that will help you kind of understand what's going on.
Now, the snack is already breaking and this is because it's out of date.
So one of the dependencies that we need to add is styled components.
Native, and we'll give that a star.
And then once we do that, it still is feeling on styled components itself, so we need to add that
as well.
And down here will add the dependancy.
And right now, we can see that it is loading.
And if we change this to blue, it will change to blue, and so you can see over here that originally
we would go and import text, right?
We would import text and then we would say, hey, text has a style where the color is blue.
Right.
And then we would say, hello, world.
Text, OK, so you can see here this does the exact same thing, right, but style text has defined
its styles above.
So we could do something like name this title and then we could put title here and we would know that
title has these certain styles.
So we're separating the styles from the component and it does it in a very easy way so that we can kind
of decouple the styling and also give the styles a certain name at the component level rather than at
the stylesheet level where we have to do stylesheet create, then say, oh, this is the container or
this is the title, and then you would have a text component where you would have a style that title
and then you would not really know what this text is unless you go look at the style.
Well, now it's a first class citizen because it's become a component.
Now, you could very easily do this by defining a Capone and going down this whole rabbit hole.
But you can you see the power of styled components because we're able to use this syntax.
And the syntax is basically saying, hey, take styled and styled from styled native exposes all of
the components that Riak native exposes.
And with this syntax, this is called template string, template string is basically a way to have dynamic
strings.
But what we're basically doing here is we're seeing between this dynamic string, make the color blue
and we can kind of take what we were writing in here and write it as a more familiar style, write it
access.
So if we were to do background color instead of doing background color blue, right.
We could do that.
And that would also work.
First of all, I need to make sure that I need my title title.
We could do that.
That would still work.
But you could also now write it, asks if you wanted to so you could very easily copy paste your styles.
You could say this one is yellow.
Maybe that would work a bit better so that we could see both.
And so you can write your styles more dynamically.
If you're used to CSFs, you can write it this way.
But the original style intent from Riak native will also continue to work.
So you could do read the power of this is to be able to give meaning to the components that are being
styled.
OK, so now that we've tested this out, let's get into the installation.