Now that we have the full end to end payment, slow processing.
In less than 26 lines of code and in total, maybe one hundred fifty end to end, we've done a great
job.
We see Paghman Show up and Stripe and we have a solid foundation on which we can build the most complex
of Chekov's right.
And so with that, one thing is missing.
We don't see anything happening when we do any of this right now, all of this is contingent on us actually
having utilization.
And so by utilization, I mean utilizing this promise to trigger the UI to do OK.
Well, with that said, there's a couple of things that we need to we need to do right now.
First of all, we need to process the response of this.
So you you heard we thought then and with the dot then we can get the result.
And with the dot catch, we can get the error.
And now we could also go ahead and use an async away here to try catch.
That's completely fine as well.
I'm choosing to do it this way in this case.
And when we get the result, well, what are we going to do, because we don't necessarily know what's
going on.
So first of all, let's add some voting state, let's say is loading and let's say set is loading.
And let's set that to false, and then once you start your payment request, we're going to set is loading
to true.
And while it's loading, if it succeeds, we're going to set is loading the false.
And if it airs, we're also going to set is loading to false.
OK, so in both those scenarios, we're caught up.
If it errors, we'll have a const error that's going to catch the error potentially, but rather than
do that, maybe we should do something else, maybe we should have a more holistic approach to this.
So, first of all, let's let's take our voting state and let's let's just complete that.
So if we're loading let's put it right here is loading.
Then we want to do something if we are loading, we want to show a payment processing.
Component, that payment processing component is going to come from, you guessed it, checkout styles
now over here, what we're going to need to do is we're going to need to export a component.
So we're going to say export const payment processing, and that's going to be a styled activity indicator.
An activity indicator is going to come from.
Riak made of paper, so we're going to put it right here and then what we're going to do is we're going
to import that in our checkout screen.
So in checkout screen, we're going to import payment processing.
And so now we can utilize that.
So let's go back to checkout styles and what we need to do inside of checkout Styles's.
We need to set certain attributes for this and styles.
So we're going to do that attributes and we're going to say that the size is going to be one hundred
twenty eight.
And we're also going to say that the animating is true and color should be colors thought blue.
Three hundred.
Now color is going to come from.
Colors from Riak native pepper.
And some of the styles that we need to give this are as follows, we need to say that this is going
to have a position absolute we're going to give it a top of 50 percent.
We're going to say from the left that it's going to come in at thirty five percent and we're going to
give it a Z index of nine nine nine.
And so by doing this now, if we do more.
And Beanie and we just hit pay, we're going to see this start to animate and now our payment will start
processing, but clearly it isn't ever going to false.
So if we go to checkout screen, something is clearly going wrong in the catch and the thought then.
So clearly, we aren't hitting these scenarios like we should be right.
Something inside of here isn't happening.
And so we're hitting this use case.
So we also have to set in.
Is loading false over here because we don't have a car ID otherwise loading will continue to spin.
So if we reload here.
And then we go into order special and now we fill in Mo Beeny and we pay for only we won't even see
it flash because it won't happen.
So if we do four to four to four to four to four, two and so forth, and then we hit pay, now we'll
see it come up and it'll process to true our it'll process the false once it hits one of these scenarios.
Now, one other thing I want to do is while this is loading, I want to disable these two functions
because there's nothing worse than having to handle a button state while something is happening.
So we want to disable these buttons as quickly as we can.
So we're going to disable them while it is loading.
And the same is true for the payment, but we're going to disable it while it's loading.
And so what will happen here is now if I press pay, both of them will turn off until the payment has
returned.
Right.
So they're basically turning themselves off while the payment this process.
Amazing.
So with those states, though, what else can we achieve?
Well, maybe we should add some navigation for a success and an error case, because those would be
quite useful for us in order to know what exactly happened after the payment process.
So let's look at how to do that.