Now that we have our countdown timer set up and ready to go, the next phase of this is to actually
add some visualizations that add proper indications to the user.
So one thing we would want to know is, Hey, what am I actually focusing on?
And in order to do that, well, what we're going to need to do is we're going to add a few in between
the button wrapper and the countdown wrapper, and that view is going to serve as where we're going
to store the indications.
So we're going to give that a style and we're going to say, Hey, padding top is equal to spacing about
x x l.
Let's do XXL.
And we need to import spacing over here.
So let's go over up here and let's say import spacing from.
And then slash it.
We'll go get sizes.
And by doing that now we have a properly spaced view over here and we need to put some text in here.
So we'll grab text from React Native.
And what we'll do is we'll create a text.
That has the style.
Of styles about title, which will create and will create a text that has a subtitle view or task view.
Let's go with this and then let's do prettier.
And let's put PASC, let's go down here to our styles and let's see title.
And then let's say task.
And so over here, four title and task, what we want to do is we want to grab our colors, so let's
import colors.
From then thought out slash utils colors.
Let's run prettier again.
Entitled What we'll say is that the color is colors that white.
In task, we'll say that colors, those colors thought white.
Now, the only thing we need to do here is potentially give them.
Font weight.
So let's say font weight and let's say bold and then over here for the task.
Hmm.
Actually, let's also fill in some text here and see what we actually have.
So we're just going to say focusing on.
And then over here, we'll put task.
What task is actually the focus object will see?
And so now we have bold.
So let's say over here that we put text the line.
And let's center it.
And over here, let's put text align and let's center it, and let's run prettier once more.
And now we have our focusing on parameter.
And by doing this, we now know exactly what we're focusing on at all times.
OK, so what now?
Well, I'd also like to have a progress bar of sorts, something to kind of report to progress over
here so that I know exactly what's going on.
Now, one thing I'll note here is that spacing XXL seems like a lot, so let's do spacing large.
I think it was large, but do we put in spacing?
Let's go.
Look.
So sizes algae.
So let's go back to the tamer.
Let's put algae.
So now it's going very far.
So that doesn't look right to me.
So let's put small.
And it's jumped a little bit.
Now, one thing you'll note here is that it's really pushed down over here, so what would happen if
we put this in side of the view that has the countdown timer and we ran for a year?
Well, now it's closer to here.
So now maybe XXL makes sense.
Oh, yeah.
Now it's pushed it down.
Now it looks in a nice position, and that's pretty good.
So you have to play around with your views.
And here's the thing you need to know about views is the more you play around with them, the more that
you'll find that different combinations of styles with views here, and we'll learn all about Flexbox
when we get into meals to go.
The different combination of styles that you use because it's kind of like a flex orientation will yield
different results.
Now we'll get into the details of all of this and how the flex containers work when we get into meals
to go.
We're trying to kind of shorten the amount of time you need to build an app here.
The styles are an extremely important part of this as we're learning because we have, you know, all
of these flex properties that we're using and we have these spacing variables.
But the placement of those views can make a difference in terms of what the visual layout will look
like, and sometimes you'll have to play around with it is what I'm trying to get at.
So in the next video, we'll look at adding a progress bar.