So I hear you thinking like, OK, how do we install this?
Well, like what steps do we go through?
So first of all, let's go in here and let's create a new terminal.
And in that new terminal, what we're going to do is we're going to do Jaan add.
Well, what do we can't add?
Well, let's go over here, let's go over to the installation guide and let's take styled components,
right.
Oftentimes you'll see NPM install.
This is a different package manager.
We're using yarn.
Do not ever do an NPM install because that will put your project in a weird state.
And so what we want to do here is we want to go over here and we want to say you can't add styled components,
OK, so styled components is now being installed.
And once we have styled components, I can show you the true power of what we can achieve with style
components in our existing feature, because with style components installed, we can very easily go
and change what we've already written.
To be more meaningful, and that's what we want, we want our code to be meaningful, we want to understand
at a glance what exactly is going on.
S components has been installed.
Let me close this real quick.
And here at the top, we can now go up here and we can say import styled from styled components, Netiv.
OK, and now I hear you're thinking, OK, what are we going to do?
OK, well, first of all, let's change this title, so let's do a concert up here, concert title equals
styled thought text and we can open the template strings, right.
These are two special types of strings.
You'll find this under the escape key next to the tilde.
It's a special type.
Don't try to use quotes because that won't work.
It has to be template.
So once we have these, what we can do is we can go down here and we can take what we have.
So padding 16, right?
Padding 16.
And we can kind of write this as CSFs, so when we put pixels behind it, it's basically going to use
a translation to react native ecosystem.
So we write everything as if we were to write Quesnel, which is more familiar for Web developers as
well.
And that's better for bigger teams.
So if we did this title and instead of doing text here, we did title title and we saved this, what
would happen to our app?
Let's go look at that.
So if we were to go look over here and we said title title.
OK, what if we did color red?
What would happen?
Well, now it changes to red, but now the semantic reasoning is that we have a way to write success
in react native or CSFs like styles, and they'll be translated for us.
And this is extremely important.
But we'll get into the bigger, broader benefits because we're again, we're layering it like a cake.
The first step is we have solid components and now we can give our components styles very easily.
But also our components now have semantic reasoning.
You can see the benefit of reading, oh, this is a title instead of oh, this is a text with the style
or Styles title.
And so we can get rid of this.
And behind the scenes, it's already doing all the good stuff that Stylesheet Create is doing for us.
So we have all of these benefits and a way simpler syntax and semantic reasoning about our components.
So we know that this is a title now amazing.
All that benefit from just one library installation and a very, very core library to the industry.