A quick note on what you'll be seeing throughout the course, throughout the course will be linking
both the branch where the changes are happening.
So you'll be able to take the code that is written in that shape, write the specific check point in
time, as we explained before, where we've added this specific step, but also will be linking the
changes that have happened between every checkpoint.
So if you're following along and you're seeing the code as the videos moves along, we've created this
nice visualization, these checkpoints, so to speak, where you can see, hey, this is the code that
was written in that specific video, and this is the code that was there before that specific video.
Now, you don't have to be making these checkpoints yourselves.
Don't worry about that.
But these checkpoints show you where the previous video left off and where the next video landed in
terms of changes.
And so if you're having a difficulty finding the template strings, you could, for instance, come
here and you could copy paste what is in here and kind of get an idea of why your syntax may be failing
or whatnot.
So don't get frustrated.
Just look in the resources folder and you can see the code that I wrote in order to help you out.
Also, something to keep in mind when you look at these changes is that there may be changes to files
like the lock file where you're seeing all of this gibberish.
Don't worry about this file.
Don't worry about the files where you don't understand what exactly is happening.
This file is generated by the yarn commands that we're running and it keeps track of the resources that
are being added.
So we don't pay attention to this yarn log file.
We need to pay attention to the code that has been written.
So when you're looking at this screen and you don't understand what's going on down here, don't get
flustered.
This is not something in our control.
But this code right here and this package, JSON file, this is in our control.
So sometimes you'll see changes in here that you may not quite understand.
But don't worry, it's just for reference.
Usually you can just check out the code and run it that way if you need to.
Also, as you're going through these resources that we link, you may notice that we have a number in
each of these checkpoints.
Don't pay attention specifically to the number, because these may not be consistent throughout the
course, but rather follow the resource link to the specific checkpoint.
And that will always be correct.
But don't use the number as a reference.