All right.
Next up, what we're going to do is we're going to hook up the timer, the actual countdown timer,
because it can take the property minutes.
And right now we're defaulting to the amount of minutes that is predetermined in the countdown component,
which is the default equal to zero point one.
But we want our timer to actually set the minutes, so let's say Konst Minutes.
Is equal to set minutes and then is equal to use state, and then we'll put zero point one as a default
value for now.
But now you can see if I control it here, I can use zero point two and so forth.
Now the control here is basically to have the ability to add buttons down here, a leader.
But this video is focusing on one this.
And then the other part is on the end of the countdown.
We want vibration and so react native exports.
This nice library called vibration vibration, vibrates the device very simple at this very, very simple.
And so if we look at the usage of vibration, it's basically it takes a pattern.
And so that pattern is you give it an amount of seconds and then you given an array of numbers.
And that array of numbers corresponds to, hey, vibrate this then vibrate that the vibrate that.
So it's going to vibrate at the first second, there's going to wait two seconds, then it can vibrate
again.
There's going to wait three seconds, then it's going to vibrate again.
So if we take this pattern over here and we put it over here at the top now, we don't want to define
this in our component because we're not going to change it at all.
We're not changing the vibration pattern.
It's kind of set.
Now what I want to say here is that the pattern is now vibrate after one second vibrate after two seconds
and then vibrate after three seconds.
We want it to vibrate five times.
After each second, that's what we want to do, because we want to prompt the user, Hey, the time
is over.
And then if we go, look at what actually needs to be done, it is vibration that vibrate and you just
give it the pattern.
Now, if we do that here in our own end, what we'll see is that when we start our timer at the end
of our timer, our phone will start vibrating.
And so that is a tactile feel now you can't feel it, but it's vibrating in my hand, right?
And it's vibrating five times after each second, which is pretty nice, pretty simple, pretty straightforward.
Now if we go, look here.
In Android, you may need to request for an Android permission with the use permission now in Exposicion
default this.
And over here, you can see reference methods to be able to cancel.
How vibration specifically works on Android, on Android, the default vibrations, 400 milliseconds
and so forth, and specifically on Android, the odds of a pattern array to represent the vibration
duration.
So there's differences on how on Android, the odd indices of the pattern represent the vibration on
iOS.
The number in the pattern area represents the vibration.
So the odd in this here represents the vibration.
So if we look at our pattern on Android, what's going to happen is one, three and five are going to
vibrate.
And even in this are going to wait.
So there's differences in how vibration happens on each device.
And that's why it's extremely important to always reach to the React native documentation to understand
how these libraries work.
What specifically we can do with them because they can also change as a react need of upgrades.
They may implement specific custom behaviors.
Now here they stuck with the behavior of the phone, but it's important to note here.
So we've added vibrations to our timer.