Let's add one more tool to our knowledge and react.
And React 16, which was a new version of React, introduced something called error boundaries, and
it solved the problem that reactor had previously, which was if there was some sort of an air within
a component, for whatever reason, there wasn't a graceful way to handle it.
On the next render, you'd get all these cryptic errors and things just wouldn't work out nicely.
And for a user, you want to make sure that even if a part of your componentry breaks, you can still
have a nice UI experience.
Maybe a piece of text says something went wrong but not have the app break.
So in this video we're going to talk about er boundaries and apply it to our friends up.
The first thing I want to do is in the component, I'm going to add a new file and we'll call this component
error boundry.
And just serves as a reminder, you do need Riak 16 or higher for this to work, so make sure that in
your package, that JSON file, that you have the right version of react.
Now, in here, we can do our regular import react.
Component, and we're importing that from the react package and then finally, we have a class of error
boundary that extends the rear component.
And within here, we have the constructor.
And again, we call super here, and just so we have access to the props.
We'll have to within the constructor.
Have the props parameter and then finally for this state, we're going to create a property called has
error and for now it's going to be false.
And let's also not forget to export default Arab boundaries, so we have access to it.
And have our default render here that will return for us.
Hmm, what should I return?
Well, ideally, with this er boundry component, we can wrap the component or we can wrap a component
such as the Kahless component with an error boundary component.
And if the Kahless component fails, we can catch it in the error boundary.
I know this is a little bit hard to follow, react does have really good documentation on this, so
you can always read up on it later.
But stick with me, trust me, it's going to make sense.
So the first thing we want to do is we want to check if this thought state dot has there is equal to
true.
So if there is some sort of an error, then we want to return this default state of how can we gracefully?
Display something to the user that makes it meaningful to them, even though we weren't able to display
what we intended originally in our case, we can just say.
That we have an H1 of groups that is not good for the user to see.
So we're saying here that if for some reason there's an air.
We're going to just spit out an H1 tag.
Otherwise, and we could just do a return here.
We're going to say that this props dot children Warrender again, remember, because children will be
anything that's in between error, boundry in our case is probably probably going to be the Carlist.
So render the children whatever is inside of our boundry, otherwise render each one.
Now, how are we going to be able to change?
This has er well with Riak 16 we have a new Life-cycle method that was introduced.
And it's called Component Did Catch.
And this component, Dick Catch is kind of like the tri cash block in JavaScript, if anything airs
out.
Ill run this life-cycle hook and this life-cycle hook actually gets a couple of parameters, that is
the error and the info.
But in our case, we just want to say that that this set state is going to now, if this component arose
out, is going to have has error equal to true.
So if that ever gets triggered, we're going to render the H1 tag.
All right, let's save.
And let's go to James, let's import our air boundaries.
From our component's.
And now we can use this let's use it over here for the card list, so if something goes on with the
card list, we want to have some sort of a graceful exit bounce.
So we'll say our boundry.
And because we're rendering this props our children, if we wrap it like this.
And nothing goes on, it'll still render card list, so let's say let's see if we made any mistakes.
So far, so good.
Let's go back to our app.
And all right, let's look at the console, no errors here if we refresh, no errors here.
If I type stuff, no errors, that's good.
Now, with this air boundary, if anything in the Carlist fails, it's going to catch it and display
our error message.
So let's see what I mean.
If I go in to Carlist here and now and here, if we say if for now, we'll just say true.
We're going to assume that, Cardless, there was an error so we can do that by saying throw a new error,
we'll say no.
If we save this, everything is still working, if I go back, you see that I'm still getting the air,
says uncute error.
No, and at the bottom it says the above error occurred in the Kahless component.
Reacts will try to recreate this componentry from scratch using the air boundary you provided everybody.
OK, that's great.
But I still see the error.
And that is because we're running right now in development mode for a reactor up.
They want to show us whenever there's an error in our component.
Airborne drugs are really useful when you put your apps into production where you don't have this detailed
logs of what errors you have, your users are never going to see this.
So if I refresh you really fast, do you see that right over here?
How is said?
Oops, that is not good.
So in production, users are going to see that.
But for our case, the intended behavior for Creative React app in development is to show us the errors.
But with air boundaries, we have that extra safety during production.
That's it for now.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.