Now that we've set up our stock navigator to allow the restaurants tap to contain multiple screens,
what we're going to do now is we're going to say the restaurant stacked up restaurant detail is going
to be equal to a no.
Right.
Let's well, let's not do not.
Let's import text from Riak native.
Right, and let's put TextField in there that says restaurant detail.
OK, so now that we have this, what we can do is we can go ahead and we can try to navigate to there
from the restaurant screen.
Now, one of the things that you get when you link a component to a restaurant, stack that screen,
what this is going to guarantee you is that this component is going to pass a prop into restaurant screen
at the top level.
So whatever component is in this component field automatically gets a prop.
Now, what does that prop will that prop is the prop navigate?
So any time a component is given to this, what we're going to see here is that you're going to have
a prop navigate at this level anywhere deeper inside, like restaurant list isn't going to have navigate
search isn't going to have navigate, but the restaurant screen is going to have to navigate because
it's injected right here.
So any of the components that are in this field are guaranteed to get the prop navigate.
OK.
And of course, it's called navigation, not navigate.
So if we give it navigation, what we're going to see is that navigation should have the properties
and listener can go back dangerously, get parent.
All these different things jump to push, too.
And so what we can do with it now is we can make it push to a different screen or navigate to a different
screen.
So the way that we're going to do this is we're going to go ahead and do a on click right now.
How are we going to do this on Click?
Well, right around here, around this restaurant info card, we want to add an arm press handler.
So we're going to import something special.
So what we'll do is we'll import Pressel from here and then we'll wrap our.
Component over here with a principal and then principal and what we'll do is our own press function
will be navigation navigate and we'll go to restaurant detail.
And so over here, it's expecting a curly brace.
I believe that should do it.
And so now any time we press on one of these, we're going to restaurant detail.
Well, we're going to restaurant detail.
And so now these have a press action.
Now, we could have also used touchable opacity.
We could have used a bunch of different things.
But this press API allows us now to hit our card and transfer to the restaurant detail screen.
But there's something that's not quite satisfying here.
You see, we're kind of stuck navigating in a direction that's left to right, but I want the detail
to pop up from the bottom.
So how would we achieve that?
Well, let's look at that.