Here's our next exercise.
So for our next exercise, I want us to transfer all of the styles that we have in the style sheet,
create across all the files that we have.
And I want us to make specific components that are going to highlight the styles and have a specific
name.
For instance, don't worry, I'm going to show you because we can do style text, right.
And we can also do style dot view and we can do we can do all of that stuff.
But what if we wanted to style the card, for instance?
What if we wanted to style the card?
So if we wanted to style the card, we could say something like CONSED Restaurant Card and we could
say styled and we could open the parentheses here right in between the parentheses we can put card.
And so now we can specifically style an element that isn't exported this way.
We could also import text from Riak native and do it like this.
Right.
So we could do that as well.
Now styled components native by default will export all the things that Riak native has or the majority
of them.
Right.
But if we want to style something very specifically, we can follow this syntax as well, where we put
it between the parentheses.
So, for instance, here we're taking a card and we're putting card between the parentheses.
Right.
And if we wanted to do cardboard cover, we could do restaurant card cover and we could do cardboard
cover.
And so now we can style the specific card cover.
OK, so with that, I want you to take these and migrate the styles that we put in stylesheet create.
And I want you to do the same for restaurant screen and I want you to do the same for Appalachia's Belnap
Dodgiest.
We don't have anything right now, OK?
And in the next video, we'll look at the solution.