All right, so now that we have all of that hooked up, you know, our timer ends, we vibrate the phone,
it's looking nice.
One of the things I want to add here now is the ability to select timings.
And by timings, I mean, the ability to have different times, because once you start with a focus
subject, right?
We don't want to predefined a time for you, like right now, we're pretty defining it to six seconds.
Now, obviously, that's not going to be it's not going to be perfect for you.
Maybe you want something like 20 minutes as a default range.
And you know, that's all great.
Like if we pre default this.
But what if we had some buttons that allowed us to choose and we had three choices five, 10, 15 minutes?
Wouldn't that make it a lot easier?
So let's go over here at the bottom and right below our start button is where we're going to say we're
going to take a view.
And we're going to see Slash for you.
And let's make it take the style button wrapper as well, which may push some stuff up right here.
And as you can see, it will push some stuff up because this is zero point five flex.
This is zero point three, and we're adding another zero point three, so zero point six plus zero point
five is one point one.
That won't really work, so we want to flex goes up to one, so we'll want to put this down to a zero
point four, which is great.
And then what we'll do over here is will add something called timing.
And will say change time is equal to and then we'll just say, set minutes.
Actually, let's say on changed time.
And then every time timing changes, we're going to set the minutes.
So let's go over here and our features folder and let's create a new file called timing tags and timing
that yes, is going to import react from react.
And then we're going to export contest timing.
And what timing is going to do is it's going to return, and then what we'll need here is to import
view from React Native.
Sweet.
So now we'll out of you here, and we'll add another view.
And let's take a minute to think here.
So we want timing buttons and we want them to look right.
So maybe we'll import our rounded button and we'll import that from the iPod slash and we'll grab our
rounded.
But because we want to have some rounded buttons as some changes.
And in here, we'll take the prop on changed time that we defined.
And this will be what sets the time fairly, fairly simple.
Now, if we went to the fine view.
Well, we're going to need some styles, so let's add a style sheet here.
And over down here, let's go see a concert.
Styles is equal to stylesheet thought create thing we're all familiar with.
And let's say that we create something called a timing button.
And let's give that a flex of one hand and a line items of center.
OK, now let's say that this has the style of a style start timing button and then inside of that will
add a rounded button, and we'll say that the size is seventy five.
And we'll say that the title is ten minutes and on press is equal to.
On changed time.
Of 10, because we're sending it to 10 minutes.
Great.
Now we need to close our component over here and then over here in timer, we need to go and actually
import timing.
So let's go say import.
Timing.
From.
Thoughts.
Timing.
Boom.
And there we go, we have our button 10th now, free press it.
Our timer has become 10 minutes, right?
And so that's kind of the goal we're going for now.
Do we want our timing bottoms at the bottom or at the top?
You know, you can really decide that I think maybe I'd like them a bit more if they were over here.
Also, like they seem to be taking up a lot of space.
So let's say timing rapper.
And let's put this back to zero point five.
And let's say that timing wrapper is flecks of zero point one.
And let's try to add that at that point.
OK, so let's add some padding to it over here.
We still had a padding.
So let's add spacing that medium and let's give this spacing up medium as well.
And maybe this needs a spacing of large.
Now, do I want them at the bottom?
Let's add this as padding top, I don't want that to pad the bottom because it's pushing down the content
below it a little too far and maybe we'll give it XXL.
There we go.
Now, do I want the Start button in this position?
Like over here or do I want it up here?
And do I want the timing buttons below?
And again, it's playing around with it, like I play around with UI all the time, especially when
I'm designing it.
Maybe I'll have a design ahead of time, but in general, like, you know, you kind of want to get
a sense of what exactly is necessary.
And so if I do that, then I probably don't need this padding, which will pull up the button 10 15.
No, actually, I think I prefer it at the top.
And so I'll go and put it back over here at the top because I liked the idea of, Hey, let me decide
to make this ten minutes, five minutes or whatever.
But now I need to add more timing buttons.
So what I can do over here is I can use something called a fragment in React, which allows me to define
multiple elements without needing to define them inside the same view.
So now I can just create three buttons and I can say 15, and then I can say 20.
And if I do that.
Then over here in my timer, if I refresh.
What we're going to see is that, hey, they're overlapping each other.
Why is that the case?
Well, over here we need to actually give it Flex Direction Row so that it renders in a row.
And that will allow them to space out in a row sequence.
So now I can select 10, 10, 10, oh, I forgot to update my timing values.
So 15, 20, amazing.
Now I have three buttons that have the ability to change my time accordingly to what I need.
And the last thing that we may want to add is a clear button, right?
Like let's say we want to cancel this timer completely.
How would we add a cancel button?
Well, down here, we could probably add a rounded button, and we could say that the size is equal
to 50 and then we can say the title is equal to, you know, minus sign and then on press will do something
eventually.
For now, we'll just leave it as empty and empty function.
And let's see what that looks like.
OK, well, that's not positioning itself correctly, so we'll need a wrapper around it.
And then if we prettier that oh, we'll need a clear subject rapper.
And then we can go down to our styles again here and we can say clear subject wrapper.
And now we've got to think about here.
What is clear subject look like?
Well, it's not positioning itself to the middle.
So let's give it a flex direction row.
And then, let's say Justify Content Center.
And now it's centered along the content.
Amazing.
So now we have, you know, 10, 15, 20 minutes, we can start the timer.
It'll start counting now and we can pause a timer and then we need to determine what do we actually
do on clear?
Well, if we go back to our app level, we had this clear subject prop that we were passing to the timer.
And so basically, we want that to do is we want it to set the current subject to no, and that's what
it will do.
And then if we go back to our timer, we'll need to pull in the clear subject.
And then over here, we can just call clear subject on press, and so if we do 10 15 and we press start
right here, if I don't, if I pause it, I posit if I start again, I start again.
But if I press the minus, I cleared the subject.
I go back to the home view.
That's amazing.
And we did all of that.
We had a timing button and we were able to clear the subject to go back to the home you and start focusing
on something else.
All in that short amount quote awesome.