Hey, everybody, we have our robo friends app now on GitHub, and you should be able to put up your
robo friends project on GitHub.
But here's the thing, would it be nice if we can use GitHub pages to actually check out our robo friends
app without having us to clone, download, NPM install, just like we've done with simple HTML projects?
Well, with the Korea reactor, there's actually a way to do this.
Using GitHub pages now, I'll link to this resource so that you can follow step by step, but let's
just go through it and see how easy it is.
I have the project right here.
It says that I need to add a home page to package that, Jason, so let's do that.
I'm going to copy this.
And added in our package, God, Jason, it doesn't matter where it is, let's had it right after the
name.
Make this a little bit bigger.
I'm going to add my username here, and this is the repository name in our case.
What was it?
It was Wrobel friends, so again, use your GitHub username and then in here add.
Your GitHub project name next.
If we go through the steps.
It says that I need to install GitHub pages, this package, and then added to my deploy script, so
let's just copy and paste this.
So if you're using AMPM, you can do that if you're using your yard.
This is the command.
So let's install GitHub pages.
And while that's getting installed, let's go back here and it shows here that we need to add these
two lines, a pre deploy and deploy in our scripts.
So once again, go to our scripts.
And then copy and paste this line, so we have the pre deploy and the deploy, so the pre deploy runs
NPM Run Build, which we know what that does.
It builds our project.
It creates a production version of our project and creates a built folder, and then the deploy is going
to use this GitHub pages so that we just installed and use our built folder.
Let's go back.
All right, and then finally, we had to deploy this site by running NPM run, deploy.
So let's do that.
Let me save.
And then and here.
Do let's clear this do npm run.
Which is this script, and remember, the pre deploy is going to be run before it, so if I run, this
looks like I have an error in my JSON package.
Let's see, what am I missing here?
Well, I have a comma at the end here, which I don't need.
Let's.
Run that again.
You see that the build folder was just created, it's creating an optimized production bill, that's
great.
And there we have it.
Our project is now published.
Now, all we have to do is go back to our repository, go to settings.
And if we scroll all the way down to GitHub pages.
We have to change the source to GitHub pages branch.
Now, you might have to wait a couple of minutes or even refresh the page to make sure that the changes
have been applied and if all goes well, remember, we're selecting the GitHub pages branch and I click
on this link.
And I refresh there you go, our robo friends app is now live at this URL, so I can just copy this
URL.
Click, edit, and then add our website right here.
So next time anybody comes and checks out our repository, they can just click here to see the live
project.
How cool is that?
Nice and simple.
And just like that, we have a production ready app.
Because remember, Krave wrapped up for us, optimises everything and keeps everything really, really
tiny for production.
Our JavaScript files, while they're minimized, they look very small and well, nothing like we had
before with containers and components.
All of that because we use query, ACTTAB gets optimized for production.
Congratulations, go show off to your friends.
I'll see you in the next one.
Bye bye.