I hope you all got through that, but there were a couple of obstacles in our way here that I've pointed
out rudimentary, but we're going to go deeper into now.
So for restaurant card cover, we kind of went the route of doing the rap style with the parentheses
over here.
And as you can see, all of our styles have applied.
So how do we go about that?
OK, so let's take it step by step.
So for restaurant card cover, we took the styled and we wrapped it with parentheses because we're wrapping
a custom component that styled probably doesn't have U.S. styled system, again, exports a certain
amount of elements.
For instance, text you could do text thought for you.
You could not do something like a dot card dot cover because styled will basically complain and say,
hey, I don't have anything like that that doesn't exist for me.
What is this thing?
But you could give it specifically the card, the cover that we imported from Riak native paper because
it comes from a different library.
So by using the parentheses, we can give it external components that it can style as well.
And so with that, we gave it padding 20 pixels.
So you may be asking yourself most, why do I need to fill in pixels here all of a sudden?
Like, what is this about?
Why pixels?
Well, let's look at that.
If we go look at styled components and we look at how it works.
It supports complex styles, but it uses something called success to react netiv in the background and
ceases to react native is basically how styled component's works for Riak native.
It takes what we would write in excess and converts it to the Riak native equivalents.
So when we fill in pixels, it's just converting it back to the regular number.
So from now on, we're going to write our Riak native styles as if we were writing excess and we can
try it out here, right?
We could write CSFs to react native.
It also does Jaysus conversions, which is different library altogether, but we could try out all of
the different things that we would want to write so you can see here.
If we wrote font size 20 pixels, well, it's going to translate the font size 20 and if we wrote background
color red, right, it would translate it to background color red.
And that for us, well, if we did this.
It's going to do a weird translation, so we really need to do this, and so here you can test out the
properties that you would normally write and see what they would become and react native.
Now, that said.
Style commonness is using this under the hood to do the translation to the object that we would write
in the style sheet create.
Awesome, right, so we can go ahead and we can write our styles this way and by using pixels is basically
going to transfer to the rack native equivalent that would not have it.
Now, if we don't write the pixels here, it's basically going to complain.
Failed to pass Declaration 20 because it doesn't understand it.
It needs the pixels.
Now, that said.
We need to reload.
It seems like my meal to go isn't refreshing properly, so let's save that, and it didn't take into
account that I added back the pixels so this can happen.
So if I remove the pixels, it's going to crash.
Right.
And if I add back the pixels, it will no longer crash, but it's not taking into account immediately.
So we need to make sure that we save properly.
OK, keeping that in mind, we're always going to add pixels to whatever number we add and background
color we're going to write in this certain way.
OK, so now we've translated everything to styled components.
And now down here, we can see well, that's pretty nice.
We now can read well, we have a restaurant card, we have a restaurant card cover, we have a title,
and that's all.
And if we go to a restaurant screen, we also have to translate this Tiriac native.
And if we look at the outcome, we can see here that we have a safe area because we created our own
safe area.
We have a search container because we now have a search container wrapping our search bar that's going
to create the spacing.
Here we have a restaurant list container and we have the restaurant info card.
And so if we look at how this was made, there was a little bit of trickery going on here, which was
how were we going to do status bar that current height, because we're writing it in this weird template
syntax.
And if you've never seen this before, well, it becomes a bit confusing because when we did stylesheet
create.
Right.
Stylesheet thought create, we could do an object and we could say safe area.
And then inside of a safe area, we could have done like margin top and we would have copy paste this.
And that's how it would have worked.
Right.
Like we wouldn't have to care about anything because this is the way it worked now, because everything
here is written as a string.
The power of the template strings lies in the fact that you can reference variables.
And the way that we do that is this little syntax here where you do sign this.
And between these two brackets, we can automatically put a variable from outside.
So we know that we need a status bar, that current height, but we also need it to add pixels to the
end of it, because if we don't add pixels to the end of it, woops, we're breaking it.
So we need to add pixels to the end of it and then it'll work.
OK, well that's good.
And then we added our surge container padding, 16 pixels, we added our list container and we moved
the styles over.
And so now our restaurant screen looks so much cleaner we don't have any crazy props for styling being
passed in.
We can just read it as if they were nested elements.
We know we have a search container inside of the search container.
We have the search bar, restaurant list container.
So we're creating this readable code in this good infrastructure and these good practices with which
we can style our react native app in a consistent way.
But there's another level to this consistency that we'll get to later.
For now, we've migrated everything successfully to styled components.