Now that we've reached a clickable state and we're able to render the restaurant details specifically
for each and every restaurant that we click, what I want us to do is I want us to render out the card,
the information card that we have here on this screen when we click it.
Now, in order to achieve that, what we need to do is we need to go to react navigation.
And if we go to react navigation, what we can see here is that when we go towards passing parameters
to routes, what we all know is said, remember when I said there's more?
Well, parameters is a part of navigation where when we do navigation, not navigate to a specific route.
Mhm.
We can pass parameters to go along with that route and will we are able to read those parameters when
we go into that specific sub screen by reading the property or the prop route.
Prem's so we can do something along the lines of when we do the touchable opacity on press, we can
pass parameters in here.
So I want you to try to pass the parameters and then.
What I want is for us to build out a restaurant detail, screen, a restaurant detail screen in the
restaurant screens folder, so a restaurant detail screen, pass that in here and then read out the
property route that Prem's and try to render out the card.
In the next video, we'll look at the solution.