We should be really proud of what we accomplished here, because basically what we have here is an app
that allows us to focus on tasks as we go along.
Now one of the things that I wanted to point out here is that, you know, focus time and the timer
itself.
It's all great having, you know, long times and long timeouts and being able to focus for 20 minutes.
But really, what is important here is the phone staying awake.
And the phone staying awake is something that is vital to us having the countdown, we don't want the
phone to fall asleep in the middle of our countdown.
We want to see the time proactively contact.
I may want to take my phone and put it in, leaned against something to see how much focus time I have
left.
And so what we want to do is use something called Expo, keep awake.
And Expo Keep Awake is a library that expo gives us out of the box, and what it allows us to do is
just use keep awake very simple.
It's just a hook.
You put it in there, you pop it in there and I remember the boom.
Your phone will stay active.
Now, if we go ahead and take this important statement of use, keep awake.
And then what we can do is, oh, we don't have this.
So what do we do?
Well, down here, we just add the dependency and it says XPO Keep Awake is not defined as the dependency
and dependency.
And now it is installing it.
And now all we need to do is add it here to the top use.
Keep awake.
Boom!
Our app will stay awake for the entire time that the timer runs.
That's how simple it is.
Amazing.
All right.
In the next video, we're going to look at tying up some loose knots, creating like, you know, an
overview of what we focus on and so forth.