Hopefully that window right now, let's look at how I solved it.
So first of all, in the Restaurant Navigator, what we needed to accomplish was we needed to remove
our text input here from the restaurant screen, rendering an inline function causes react navigation
not to work properly.
So we need to import a named component.
And we created the name component restaurant detail screen here.
We can remove this import and we import restaurant detail screen from our features folder where we created
a screen called Restaurant Detail.
Dot screen, restaurant detail.
Dot screen is a screen that contains three things.
First of all, we need to import react.
Then we need to import the restaurant info card.
Then we import the safe area view from the utility safe area component because we want to make sure
we render in the safe area, even if it's a modal.
Inside of that safe area, what we're going to do is render the restaurant info card, the restaurant
info card is going to be part of the holistic approach that we're taking to rendering out the details.
We want to show the exact same detail card without the same exact interactions just yet.
And so what we need to take in as props is the root.
Now, the root is coming in because it's part of Restaurant Navigator, because it's defined as a component
on the stock screen, restaurant details screen now gets information from its route in order to be able
to pull information.
Some of the information we need to pull is off of route programs, as you saw in the documentation route
that allows us to pass information around.
And so the program we're pulling off is restaurant.
And as we pass that into the restaurant info card, we pass restaurant is equal to restaurant.
We also needed to adjust the restaurant screen in order to pass that parameter.
And the parameter that we passed is on navigation that navigate.
We put in the path we're going to navigate to which is restaurant detail.
Then we add comma.
We opened up an object and we said the restaurant was equal to item because as you remember, item is
our restaurant.
So we're passing restaurant en route to restaurant detail as we go over there.
And if we look at that from a solution perspective, if we go over to our phone, what we can see here
is now if we click on our restaurant, will pop up the detail screen and it will show the information
that is required inside of the safe area of you with the restaurant detail card.
So the restaurant detail card is the first part of the detailed screen that we've now built out.
And we've been able to successfully past the restaurant information each time that it's clicked into
the restaurant detail screen.
So we're in a good state here to start building out our menu.