Welcome back.
Let's learn about Hooke's and also teach you how the process should be when you learn something new
with a library, because, again, your job as a programmer is to be really good at problem solving,
be able to adapt to changes and solve problems.
So let's say Hooke's was just introduced to react.
The very first thing I would recommend to do is to read the documentation, but more importantly, read
the motivation.
Why did the library add this?
Why did react decide to add this thing called Hooke's?
Now we see over here that there are new additions as of sixteen point eight.
And if you're watching this video now, there's probably a way later version of REACT.
So as long as you're using this version or higher, you're going to be able to use this new feature.
Now, I'm not going to read through the entire documentation for you, but I do want to point out one
thing.
The number one thing I do when I look at her library and see some of the new changes, I want to look
at the motivation.
Why did they add it?
So if I scroll down.
Look at that, they have the motivation, why do we need Hooke's in the first place now?
Sometimes to learn what the motivation is, you have to actually understand the library and have used
it before and hopefully by now you're comfortable with react.
So let's just go through the motivation quickly and then we'll get to coding, because I know that's
the exciting part and that's when we'll actually learn.
But the three things to keep in mind.
Is that one with the ways that we've used react up until now, it's really hard to do this reuse stateful
logic.
What does that mean?
Well, if we had some logic of, let's say, changing state in our class components, sometimes if we
want to do something similar in another component, it's a little harder to do with the way that we
had it before.
Hooks makes this a little bit easier, again, something that we'll see shortly.
Next is that complex components become hard to understand, you see, as components become bigger and
bigger, especially class ones with component Dedman component did update component Will Armont, all
these Life-cycle Hock's things that can happen within a component.
Hooks make things a little bit cleaner.
You can see over here, Hooke's let you split one component into smaller functions based on what pieces
are related.
Again, hard to really understand unless we code it.
But the biggest motivation, and I think this is something that a lot of people overlook when talking
about hooks, is that some people find classis confusing the this key word, the BINDE function that
we have to do.
Classes are just daunting for some people, such as doing super props.
Why do we do that in a class so.
Hooks allow us to not use classis, not use the this keyword in our REACT applications, and another
major reason that is overlooked is that REACT wants to do something called Ahead of Time compilation
one day, hopefully for performance, something that things like svelte, angular and Glymour do.
And by not having classes, it makes this easier for them to do so.
But you know what?
This is a lot of talk, a lot of gibberish may be hard to understand.
I think the best way to learn about hooks is to actually convert our robo friends out from using class
components to using hooks.
And I'll show you what that means and the next video, Bhabhi.