All right, let's convert our robo friends app from using classes to using hooks and learn about what
the differences are.
So the very first thing I want to do is, well, clone this repository.
So we'll use our robo friends example and I'll just say get clone and grab this repository from GitHub
or you can use your existing project.
Now, I'm going to go into the Robo Friends Directory.
And the very first thing I always want to do when I clone a repository is obviously npm install.
So let's round that to install all of our dependencies.
All right, NPM install worked now one of the things that will happen, and this is something we've
already talked about, is that whenever you're revisiting an old project or grabbing a project from
GitHub that has been around for a while, is that while you'll get a lot of vulnerabilities because
libraries haven't been updated.
So the first two commands that I always like to do after NPM install is NPM update to update my libraries.
All right, only one low severity vulnerability after the NPM update, and sometimes I also like to
run NPM Audit Fix just to make sure that we're not missing anything and looks like we're good to go.
You see here that there is one vulnerability that requires manual review, so we'll have to manually
update those.
But for now, I think everything's good.
Everything's up to date so we can start using hooks.
Now, the very first thing I want to do is to make sure that we can use this new feature.
Remember that Hooks came with React sixteen point eight.
So let's go check to see that we have a react sixteen point eight or higher.
So I'm going to open.
Visual studio code and I know shocker, up until now, I've loved Sublime Tax, but it looks like a
lot of people like Visual Studio Code, so I have to conform to what everybody else is doing just so
that you get to see a different editor as well.
All right.
So we have our terminal here to the right and then we have our robo friends app.
If we take a look at package DOT, Jason, let's see over here what version we have.
We see that we have sixteen point thirteen, so higher than sixteen point eight.
So we should be able to use Hooke's.
Awesome.
The very last thing before we move on to the next video and finally introduce you to Hooke's, because
I've talked to a lot about them and you still have no idea what they are.
Let's just do npm start to make sure that everything still works.
We've updated our packages.
We want to make sure that things are still working.
So ampm start.
Hopefully we get no errors.
All right, looks like things are loading up on the console, there's no air and I can search my robot
friends and again, things are working awesome.
All right, time for hugs.
I know.
I keep building the suspense, but I promise.
Next video, we're going to find out what folks are seeing that one by.