Now that we see the benefits of using styled components and specifically using styled components to
compose elements that will form our user interface in a semantically pleasing way, and all those words
basically mean we're creating components that have nice names.
There's one more thing I promise to you, and that was consistency.
And in order to achieve consistency, we have to use something called a theme.
Now, if we go look at Riak native specifically style components for Riak native, when we go to the
advanced section, we can start talking about theming.
You see, styled components has full theming support by using something called a theme provider.
Now a theme provider is a wrapper component.
So think of it like something that we put around the app Shell.
And then suddenly everything inside of the app has access to the theme object.
It's kind of like a global state of sorts.
This component provides the theme to all the components underneath itself through the context API.
Now what is the context API?
Well, if we go look at react context, what context is, is it provides a way to pass data through
components without having to pass props down manually at every level.
Now if you've never written react before, this may be very new to you.
But don't worry.
Basically context is a way for us to share things globally.
We can share methods, we can share data, we can share anything globally.
And so you can read up on context here.
And basically there are a couple of ways that you can utilize context.
And the theming in styled components is one of those ways.
Now, as you can see over here, this is the normal way that you would normally write a style button
in HTML.
This is not a Riak native version, but bear with me.
And if you look at it in a themed approach, this would be the way that you would apply a theme, see,
this is how you would apply a color if you were to use the theme props that theme dot mean.
So you can obviously put together a theme that has all of the properties that we would need.
Right.
In order to achieve consistency across.
And we can theme a bunch of different things.
So let's get into setting up our theme.