All right.
So now that we have our focus history rendering out, let's go back to the app and let's go look at
what we actually need to do to fill up this array.
Well, every time the timer ends, we know we've successfully focused on something.
So the most basic use case here would be to do something along the lines of, well, we saw that in
timer when we call the on end.
Well, we're not calling the actual.
On time timer in.
So we'll grab that from over here.
We'll go back to our timer.
And what we want to do here is on time, and we want to take the subject that we were focused on the
focus subject.
And before that is cleared, we want to pass it back up, right?
We may focus on it multiple times, and that's completely fine.
We'll store the amount of times we focus on something.
That way we know.
So every time the timer ends, we know we successfully focused on something.
So all we have to do here is take in the subject that was focused on and we'll set the history to be
taught our thought history.
And we'll add in the subject, so every time we focus on anything now, it will be added to the list.
So now if I do test and then I start it and I wait for it to actually complete its cycle when it's done
vibrating.
It has now called on timer end.
Now if I say like, I'm done focusing on this test item and I clear it, we can see, Hey, I've successfully
focused on test.
Now, if I do failed.
Right?
Because this is going to be one that we fail.
And I say, I'm going to focus on this.
And hey, I'm like, Nah, nah, I'm done.
And I didn't wait for the timer to finish well.
I didn't successfully actually focus on it.
So why would I keep track of it?
It's not something I actually focused on.
It's something that I tried to focus on, but I did not complete.
So now we can add like test to.
And we can see how that works, and if I start it and I wait for it to actually complete here.
Now, once it completes and my phone starts vibrating, I know I've successfully completed a round of
concentration against test you in effect, clear here things we focus on Test two.
And so this list will continue to grow and grow and grow.
And that is amazing.
So now we basically can keep track of everything we've focused on in one go in one app.
Isn't that awesome?
Now, one final thing we should look at here is in our focus history, we defaulted to not rendering
out anything when we didn't have a length.
But what we should actually do is say.
We haven't focused on anything yet, and that will give someone the indication that, hey, we haven't
actually focused on anything yet.
We kind of still need to go through the motion so you can give them the indication of, Hey, we need
to start over.
We need to start here in some way, shape or form.
Now we can design this any given way we want, right?
We could put it in the center of the screen.
We could do all types of things with it.
But in essence, here now if I go test and I say plus and I start pausing and starting once this actually
completes, that's when we know that when the phone vibrates, I've completed and hey, things we focused
on test.
Awesome.