There are a bunch of ways to reach your desired effect when it comes to rendering out the menu inside
of the safe area of the restaurant, a detail screen.
Now, here, I'm going to show you how I achieved it.
First of all, I had a couple of you states that I was going to require in order to open and close the
accordion groups.
So I had state for the breakfast, the lunch, the dinner and the drinks.
And this is keeping track of each individual accordion's state.
On top of that, I had to import list from Riak need of paper in order to utilize what the list has
to offer us.
And next to that I eventually need a scroll view.
But first, let's go through putting together the accordion.
So what we need to do here is we need to define the accordion's one by one, and that means having the
accordion's predefined before putting the list items inside.
Here we have an accordion for breakfast, which I gave the title breakfast.
On the left side, I put a list out icon of the icon bread slice, which was available, and then I
linked the expanded.
So the tracking of whether it's expanded or not to the state of breakfast expanded.
So any time we trigger the list accordion, this will be set to true or false, depending on it's open
or closed state by triggering the on press, which returns an inner function of set breakfast expanded
of the inverse of breakfast expanded.
So if the current value is false, it'll be set to true.
If the current value is true, it'll be set to false.
OK, so now what we need to do is we need to create the same accordion groups for lunch and dinner and
drinks.
That means creating a accordion for lunch.
For dinner.
And then for drinks, so here we have dinner.
And then we have drinks as well, which is going to be linked to the state of set drinks expanded,
and so with that, we have all of our accordions ready to go to be filled in with information, but
they currently do not have any information inside of them.
And so if we look at what that renders out.
We need a closing tag for each and every one of these.
Now, when we look at this accordion, is each one of our accordions closed and here we can see the
following.
Are expected closing tag for Alstott accordion, and it seems that I said I wrote according to small
little mistake here and then.
What we can do here is we can just, oh, I made the same mistake everywhere, according according according
to one little mistake.
Now, if we open these up, what we're going to see is that we have breakfast, dinner and drinks,
and they're triggering their state to open and close the accordion, which is great.
So that means that we're tracking the state correctly in our accordion's, can open and close at will.
Now, what we can go and do is we can go put list items inside of here and those will expand and contract
with the accordion group so you can put however many items you want in every accordion group.
It doesn't really matter.
I chose a couple of list items for breakfast, lunch and dinner, and that allows us to set up our breakfast,
lunch and dinner and drinks accordingly.
Now, if I contract lunch and then we see dinner.
We can see that within dinner.
I put breakfast.
Oh, actually, I accidentally skipped one.
So what we need to do here is this is the lunch clause.
And this is the breakfast clause, the accordion, rather, that has these items, and so by saving,
we restructure.
And then I have a couple of drinks here that I wanted to put in.
I was list items in the drinks accordion, and that allows us to set up correctly dinner and drinks.
But we have one issue here, you see.
When we set this up and we unfold every single one of these, we can't really see the entire list item.
And if this and in the drinks area, we can see clearly here after Coke we have fatha but it's going
off the screen.
So what, what can we do here.
Well one option would be to use philatelist but then, but then again we don't really need flat list
here because it would separate out too much of the data.
The data would have to be each individual item in a category and then structuring that would be very
hard.
So what we need to use here basically is a scroll view.
We just want to make the area scrollable for us.
That means that we're going to import scroll view from Riak native and this will just make the area
around the accordion's scrollable and thus able for us to scale our accordion's accordingly.
And now we can see that if breakfast, dinner and drinks is all expanded at the same time, we can still
scroll down and see everything that is available to us very easily.
You see, Flat List is for when we have data coming in of a certain structure and we want to render
out one certain item here.
We have accordion groupings and items inside those accordion groupings.
It's not to say we couldn't use philatelist, but all we needed to do here was make the area scrollable
in order for our menu to become scrollable.
And we're never going to hit a case where our menu has a hundred thousand items.
So we're not at risk here of running into performance issues because menus tend to be limited.
You may have 50, 60, 70, 80, 90, maybe 90 items at max.
And at that point you have a gigantic restaurant and I don't know how that kitchen is doing it.
So a scroll view is just performant enough here for us to be able to gather all of our information and
set up and have that scrollable interface while still keeping the top level information, the important
information of the card right here for us.
OK, now that we have our detailed screen fully built, what we're able to do from here, right, is
we have our detailed screen.
We know that for every single restaurant and these work with a swipe down action.
By the way, you can also click the tab icon in order to close these.
Now that we have this set up for each individual restaurant and we have the detail screen set up for
each one of these, what we can go ahead and do is we can go ahead and set up our map for you now because
we have all of our information ready to go for us.
So why don't we go to the restaurants and now render them on a map?