All right, all right, all right, hopefully you were able to do that a little bit of a challenge.
If not, no worries.
I'll show you how we can convert things into using hooks in this video.
But again, hopefully you got a chance to check out the using the state hook and using the effect hook
in the react documentation.
Because it's not as hard as it seems.
Remember what I said, Hook is a special function that lets you hook into react features so that you
use state and they use a fact hook, allow us to hook into a react feature because it's from the react
library to.
Either work with state or with life-cycle methods.
So the first thing I want to do is to actually remove this component from here, because we're no longer
using that component class to extend app, instead, we want to change this into a function.
Right.
So I can now say function app and we remove this and turn this into a function.
Next is we no longer need this constructor super and this state because we're now creating a function
we can, let's say, comit the self for now just so we can see it.
We are also going to comment component did mount because inside of a function, there's no such thing
as component did mount.
Remember, we got Component Dedman because we were able to use the component class in here that gave
us this feature, this life-cycle hook.
So now we can't use this either.
And then because this is a function, what we need to do is turn this into a variable so the answers
change and the render is no longer needed, instead will have.
This piece of code.
That just simply returns out of the function.
So if I say this, I'll probably get a few errors.
All right, so I have you state is defined by never used use effect as defined by never used on search
is assigned but never used.
And that's because on search now is just a variable inside of this function.
And you see that we're using that this keyword here.
Remember what I said?
Because we're no longer in a class.
We don't need that this key word anymore.
So if I say this, we have one lesser.
Now, if I go back to our app.
Oh, we have some errors, can I read properly, state of undefined.
And that's because, again, we're using the this state here and we've commented about the constructor
that gave us state, right.
So this not set state that came from our component class no longer exists.
This that state no longer exists either, again, because it's no longer a class, so how do we create
state?
Now remember, Hooke's give us now the power to have state inside of our apps, and we do that using
the use state hook.
Let's find out how to do that in the next video.