It's time for an exercise, and this one is going to be a fun one, because what we're going to do is
we're going to go look at the styles that we've already written throughout the app and we're going to
clean things up like I promised.
We're going to do this as if it were a real, real project.
And for that, we need to make sure that at any given point when we write things, we write them in
a consistent way.
So right here we can see we have padding sticks and right here we have padding 20.
And if we go look at spacing, well, we don't really have 20 in here, which means we're going to have
to make a decision.
Does it become 16?
Does it become 32?
Usually I am a fan of rounding down to the closest value.
So I would personally make, for instance, the 20, a 16.
And that would make way more sense because then the padding is consistent all around.
So what I want you to do is the same thing that I did over here.
I want you to go through all of the properties.
And I want you to replace the properties that can be replaced with their proper theme equivalent, and
then in the next video we'll see what that looks like.