Next up are our Font's right here, you can see some restaurant and you can see here in our final app
that we have a way, way, way nicer font going on.
Why is it that the font isn't applying here?
What is going on?
Why isn't our font applying to our text?
What exactly do we need to do here?
Well, let's get into that.
Let's start applying our fonts, because we already went through the preparation of setting up which
fonts we're going to use here, but now we have to import them and we're going to build this super cool
component, a text component that's going to be able to hold the specific font that we are going to
set up.
OK, so let's get into that.