Welcome back.
Let's talk about the second most important hook, and that is the effect hook that comes with react.
Now, the effect of as the ability to perform side effects from a function component.
It serves the same purpose as Component did mount, component did update component will mount and react
classes again.
Remember, the whole idea of Hooke's is to be able to do the things that we were able to do inside of
a class, but this time inside of a function.
And we see here that we can use use a fact, like a function and just tell it what we need to do, so
let's give it a go.
I want to use effect now to replace this component dismount, because right now our robots aren't being
fetched.
Our friends are non-existent because we're not fetching.
So let's do this.
Let's do use effect.
We have that because remember, we've imported over here and use effect is going to.
Run like this and inside of you is the fact we have to tell it, what is the side effect that we want
this function to do?
So I'm going to just create an error function.
And inside of here, we're going to put this.
First call that we had in component did.
So let me just comment that out.
Make sure our spacing is correct.
And inside of here, we now have use effect and this use effect gets run every time the function app
gets run.
So we see over here that we're calling use effect because of the brackets and inside of here we're telling
it, hey, what's the side effect?
So this is something important to remember.
By default, react runs this use affect function after every time it renders.
So when app renders, it's going to run the use effect and whatever is inside of it.
Now, remember, we no longer have this date set state, instead we have what are we changing?
We're changing the robots.
So I can say set robots right over here.
And this set of robots is going to get the new users.
Like that, now let me say this and see if this works, I want to save.
All right, compiled successfully, no errors, but do we get our robot friends?
Let's have a look.
Hey, look at that, we have our robot friends love it.
Can I search through them?
What look at that, so simple and it works just as expected, but let's take a look at the console.
If I open up the console, I don't know if you can tell here, but look how many times this render function
is running.
It just keeps going.
It's actually running in an infinite loop right now.
Hmm, let's take a look and find out why that is.
And this is another tricky part of when people get started with hooks again, it's often commented in
the documentation, which you can read on the React website.
Now, this use effect actually has a second parameter that it receives.
Remember, the first parameter is the function, what it should do when app renders.
And the second one.
If present, which is an optional argument, if present effect will only activate, if the value in
the list changes, what does that mean?
Well, use effect receives an array as a second argument.
Now, before I just show you what this does, let's have a look at why exactly the use effect was running
continuously over and over and over.
Well, if we look at the code, when the app renders it creates the state, right.
That's the initial state and then it runs the use effect because it render so it fetches the users.
And then these users are going to update the state, it's going to update their robot state with the
new users.
So what happens?
Well, new users are being rendered right here.
So the app re renders and says, hey, I got new robots, so I need to render myself to show the robots.
So it renders but remember what I said with use hooks every time the component renders it's going to
run use effect.
So it's going to run fetch again and then it's going to set robots again.
So it has to render and then it goes use effect again.
Then said robots.
So it goes into a continuous loop.
And the trick with the use effect is that if you don't want this to constantly Remender, then you wouldn't
want to set state inside of use effect.
But if we are setting state like we have here, we can give it an optional list.
And this optional list tells us in here, hey, when should I run use effect so you can tell react to
skip applying the effect or the use effect function if certain values haven't changed between referendums.
So in here we say, hey, only one use effect if one of these have changed.
So, for example, if I put in robots here and I save, what will happen if I go back?
Well, you see that it's still running.
Look at that, it's still running, still running, still running.
Why is that?
Well, because robots changes, right?
We always run robots.
So that means, hey, run use effect because robots changed.
Hey, run use effect because robots change.
That's exactly what we're doing before without the second argument.
But in here, if we do, let's say search field only run use effect if search field changes, if I see
this and go back, there you go.
It no longer goes into that infinite loop.
But if the search field changes.
You'll see that we're fetching again, so that's not good either.
Instead, we want to give it an empty list or an empty array, because what does that mean?
It means, hey, only one use effect when this changes, but when the list or the array is empty, it's
a shortcut for doing component Inma.
Hey, just run use effect initially when the component mounts, when app is rendered.
So the component did mount shortcode is essentially this adding an array.
I know it's tricky, maybe doesn't make sense.
It's just a quirk, a thing that you just have to remember with react.
Remember, hooks aren't a JavaScript thing.
It's just a way to use react that you need to get used to, just like you had to get used to this dot
set state.
So by having an empty array here, I now replicated component demand.
So now if we just move console dialogue over here.
Use effect, so inside of use effect.
We'll ignore the warnings for now, if I go back, you'll see that it's an empty array, but as soon
as I.
Type something, no other updates are made because use effect is only run once versus before when we
didn't have anything and you see that it was going like crazy.
So this is a SHAWKI remember, component did mount, we just add the empty array and then we can give
it different options instead of this array.
Now, if you're using a react app, this actually gives you a hint here whenever you're using it incorrectly.
So react hooks, use effect, has missing dependencies, robots and search field either include them
or remove dependency array.
And what this is saying is, hey, inside of use effect, you have two pieces of state robots and search
field that you're using.
Now, in our case, we're just console logging, but it gives you a warning saying, hey, don't you
want these to run if you're using them inside of use effect and add them to the dependencies.
So it's saying this, hey, just add these and you see that it's compiled successfully.
But again, we don't want to do that because remember, robots change all the time.
So if we do that, it turns into an infinite loop.
So let's remove and remove.
There we go.
I'll see in the next one, Pabai.