Now that we have to render a mapu, we have to do our research, what exactly do we use?
And luckily, because we are in an export controlled environment, the export docks can point us in
different directions when it comes to utilizing specific functionality.
And when we look it up, what we can see is that they have a MAPU implementation, specifically with
Riak native maps, which provides a map component that uses Apple Maps or Google Maps depending on the
platform you are on and on.
Android and EXPL uses react native maps from the community, no set up required for use within the client.
Now what do we need to do in order to get this up and running?
Well, all we need to do is run expo, install react native maps.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So if we go over here to our app and we open up our terminal, what we're going to be able to do is
run that command in a new terminal X will install react native maps.
And while that's happening, let's go back to the documentation, as we can see here, in order to utilize
Riak native maps.
And you can see the full documentation app react, native community, react, native maps.
We can import a map for you from Riak native maps to say that 50 more times react native maps.
In any case, we're able to import a map you and with that map, you were able to give it a specific
style and it will just render out a map.
Now with that map, we can then give it directionality in terms of which location to render out what
specific zoom level to be at and where to put pin markers.
Now, you can try this out on an example stack, and that will bring you to an example snack that will
run react native maps.
And if we tap to play here, we can obviously run the map inside of an actual project and test it out
before we get into the nitty gritty of specifically what we're trying to accomplish ourselves.
Now we have Riak native maps installed and the next thing we need to do is we need to make sure that
our navigation is set up correctly.
So if we go into our.
Infrastructure and we go into navigation, what we can see here is at the App Navigator level, we still
have the setup that was previously done for the map, which is an inline function right here.
Well, not an inline function.
It is a component function outside of the body, but it's in line in this file.
And so what we want to do here now is, first of all, we want to go into our restaurants and we want
to build for the restaurants a new feature, what we're going to call it.
Well, we could we could either build it inside of restaurants, but we're going to create a new feature
and we are going to call it map.
And that feature map is going to have a screens folder and you folder screens and inside of that screens
folder.
We're going to create a new file and we're going to call it the map screen.
My thoughts screenshot G.S. and so inside of that map screen, what we need to do is we need to, first
of all, import react and the mapu from react native maps.
Then what we need to do is we need to ensure that we're able to utilize all of the functionality that
we require.
So what we're going to do is we're going to export CONSED map screen and that's going to render out
the map view initially.
That's what we'll do.
And then we'll take map screen, we'll go back to our app Navigator will remove this initial map implementation
and we will import the map screen from dot, dot, dot, dot slash features, map screens, slash map
screen.
OK, now that we have our map screen me, we have to ensure that it is properly being used here.
And once we do that, what we can see here in our app is that when we reload.
If we go to the map now, once everything is loaded, we go to the map, oh, nothing's being loaded
just yet.
Why is that?
Well, let's give it a style.
And let's say that the style is height, 100 percent width.
And then let's let's leave the with off for now.
And now we can see that we're rendering an entire mafune side of here.
And if we go over to Android and we run the same exact thing, what we'll be able to see over here is
that once it loads the map, screen should also render out the map, but this time with Google Maps.
So we have our map implementation working here now.
And from here we can start layering on the functionality in terms of rendering out the right zone,
putting on the map markers and all of that good stuff, as well as triggering a redirect to the restaurant
detail when we click on a marker.
Good stuff.
A couple of easy installs and we are good to go.