I hear you asking the question, Mo, why did we set up a map screen and then import that map screen
directly into Riak native navigation?
Why didn't we create a navigator called Map Navigator like we did for Restaurants Navigator?
Well, that's because right now we're just building out the map screen.
We don't know all of the other functionality that it may need if it needs to be able to go to different
screens, if it has different screens inside of the map, or if it's solely just the map view that's
linking out into Restaurant Navigator, we haven't built out all of the functionality yet.
So for now, map screen will suffice for us to enable us to be able to load what we need from maps.
Now that we have our map up and running, the next thing we need to do is we need to make sure that
it gets the information it requires in order to render out what it needs to render out.
So for us to do that, we're going to need to build out a bit more than what is already here.
So right here we see that we have a map screen.
And if we open this up, what we're going to be able to do is build out what our map screen is supposed
to look like.
Right now, the entire mafia is rendering inside of the entire shell of the app, and we don't really
mind if it's taking up the entire view rather than, for instance, rendering it in a safe area.
We don't mind the full the full screen solution here because it looks nice.
It looks nice when the when the map extends out into this area.
So we're going to leave it as is.
But what we're going to do is we're going to import styled from style components native.
And what we're going to do is we're going to say consed map equals styled and we'll give it the map
for you and then we'll say.
One hundred percent.
With 100 percent just for good measure.
And then once we have that, we don't we can utilize that as our map rather than have the inline styles
going on.
And as we can see here, it is still loading correctly when we go into our map.
That looks amazing now that we have our maps set up with a style component.
What's the next thing we need to do?
Well, I would argue that the next thing we need to do is figure out how we're going to render out the
search bar at the top.
So right now, our search is inside of this feature component restaurants.
So what we can do here is we can utilize the search that is currently inside of here or we can build
a standalone search for the map screen.
I lean towards building a standalone search for the map screen because at a certain point these search
bars may diverge in terms of functionality and view.
And we don't we want to build the right component for the right use case.
So what we can do is we can copy everything in this file because it's going to look close to what is
currently here, will create a components folder and then we'll create a search component that is.
And will paste what is in here.
And this will allow us to have a very similar component to what is already inside of restaurants, but
the reason that we're copy pasting is it's not bad to copy paste components when they differ in visualization
or they may differ in some view in functionality because we don't want complex, if else, logic inside
of the component determining, hey, you need to render this icon or you need to render this icon in
this specific use case.
And as a search bar extends across multiple features, it becomes like this very, very bulky thing.
So for that case, we build the search bar specifically for the map view.
Now we can go ahead and we can say import search from Tattaglia.
Components search component, and now we'll have a search bar for our search screen, so we'll do search
here.
And as we do that now, we'll be able to see that we have a search, but it's not really positioning
itself correctly.
And so that's where the search function already diverges from the search function we saw for restaurants
instead of it being having padding.
It's also supposed to be positioned in an absolute fashion.
And next to that, we're going to give it a Z index of nine nine nine so that it renders at the top
it already has a padding.
And we're going to say from the top, always be 20 pixels far down.
And so with that, oh, now it's rendering over here.
Well, let's also give it a width of one hundred percent so that it scales to the to the UI and maybe
let's render it a bit lower.
That looks good.
That feels good and.
Maybe we could go a bit lower, we could go a bit lower, and if we look on Android here, what we're
going to see is something very, very similar.
We're going to see it render inside of The View at a good position.
And so with that, we now have our search bar that is rendering already the same value as in the restaurant's
view, because it's already hooked up to the context.
Right.
We already hooked up the search to the context.
So it's using the same keyword that is currently set.
And this is pretty cool because let's say we searched for Antwerp inside of here, Antwerp.
Now we're going to run there, the restaurants for Antwerp.
And if we go to our map view, oh, well, this isn't updating.
Why isn't this updating?
Well, we're only setting the search keyword for the initial render.
So we need to make sure that any time the keyword updates, we update the search keyword inside of here.
So what we can do is we can set a use effect inside of our search component locally and we can say any
time the keyword changes.
Let's set the search keyword, let's set the local search keyword to the keyword.
And let's import use effect from over here.
Now we can have a sink that happens between these two screens.
So if I reload here and I search for Antwerp, we're going to see that it is going to adjust itself
inside of this screen.
But if I search for San Francisco here.
What we're going to see is that in here, it's not going to update, so we need this logic in both places.
But the reasoning behind us duplicating this logic is because we don't want to search components, we
don't want one search component for both use cases because they're going to diverge heavily in visualization
and positioning.
So the styling, the search container is going to differ as well as some of the functionality in here.
Now, we could say that we may take out the search bar and give it some conditional logic.
I honestly prefer this method because this will scale with the feature if the map screen feature needed
more intense search functionality type of head functionality from Google type ahead to test or AB testing
the map screen search versus the restaurant search.
So I like to Buckett these features.
I like the bucket, these features to be separate.
And one of the things that we're immediately going to do is we're going to show a custom icon inside
of this search component for the search map screen.
And so the way that we're going to do that is we're going to say icon is equal to map.
And by doing this now, we can see that when we're on the restaurant screen, it's going to show us
a search indicator.
But when we're on the map, screen is going to show us a map indicator.
And that map indicator is going to allow us to know, hey, visually, we're on the map screen.
So another divergence point.
OK, so now we know that if we type in Antwerp here and we were to hit search, what we would see in
the restaurant screen is also a loading of the Antwerp restaurants.
Amazing.
We're starting to link functionality together, we're starting to get the map screen in a good shape.
Now we've set up search for the map screen.
We set up the map screen in side of the navigation, and we've kind of coupled the searches together
so that when one search happens in the map screen, the other search also updates that back and forth
is very important.
In the next video, we're going to look at how we can extend the map for you to render out the information
for the restaurants.