The question becomes, how do we installed these fonts, because we know we're going to use Oswald and
LoDo, but what are these?
So let's go look them up if we go look up Oswald font.
Then we can see here in the Google fonts, the Oswald font, and the same is true for the lotto font.
Now, that said, there is this cool package from Expo called Expo Google Fonts and the X will Google
Fonts Package for Expo allows you to use any of the nine hundred ninety one fonts on fonts that Google
dot com for your expo app.
That's amazing that so many fonts.
Honestly, if you want you can pick out your own font.
I would suggest doing the installation process of the fonts we currently have so that you know how to
do it.
And you could potentially pick out your own phone of you want to make the app your own.
But for now, let's stick to what we know, which is we need Ozwald and LoDo.
So let's go figure out how do we install this.
So here's an example of how to install the Interphone family.
So XPO install at Expo, Google Fonts, Inter Expo font, huh?
What is Expo installed?
Well, just like yarn and yarn ad expo install is an expensive tool going to do the installation process
for you, but also do extra things behind the scenes for hookup and consistency and making sure that
everything works properly as it should with Expo.
So we need to do two installations.
There's the Expo, Google fonts enter and then there's the expo font itself.
So first off, let's go into our command line and let's do Expo install expo font.
That's the first thing we need.
And then we need to do Expo install.
Export Google fonts, and we're going to get LoDo and Oswald.
So, first off, it's going to install this whole font package and this is a pretty cool process.
You know, it's resolving packages, fetching everything.
So, OK, we have XPO fonts now.
So now we have to do XPO install XPO Google Fonts, Oswald.
And after we do Oswald, what do we need to loto you got it, Lardo, is it loto?
I'm saying LoDo like it's the lottery, but, you know, building this up, we are basically winning
the lottery and it's so beautiful.
I'm kidding.
In any case, the funds were installing here are going to make our app look like we won the lottery.
That's what I'm trying to get at.
So Lardo.
OK, so once we've installed these two fonts, we're basically 90 percent of the way there to get this
going.
What we need to do now is we need to import the use fonts and the well, not the interphone we're not
using in there, but the Oswaldo Dell'Orto font.
And if we go back to the Google font, we can see that we have all different types of fonts available.
We have regular four hundred medium semi.
And it looks like we particularly want to use the four hundred varieties.
So how do we go about this?
Well, first off, what we need to do is we'll copy this and we'll figure out how this works over here.
So first off, we're going to create some space here and we're going to say, well, we don't want Intr,
we want Oswald, OK, we want Oswald and we don't want particularly the Oswald.
Nine hundred.
We want the four hundred.
OK, so it said over here, it said inturn, nine hundred black.
So we want Oswald.
Four hundred.
It needs to be named regular.
And then we have the use fonts, OK, this looks good.
So what we're going to do now is we're going to go over back to France and we're going to see how do
they load this.
OK, so they do something like this.
So let's do something similar.
So they do font's loaded.
So we're going to do Oswald loaded.
And we're going to do use fonts and we're going to say, Oswald, four hundred regular, OK?
And we're going to say consed here we don't like let's and next up, we need to duplicate this, duplicate
the Seline.
We also need to make sure that this is coming from Oswald.
This would have been bad.
We're not trying to import from Intr and we're going to LoDo Lato 400.
Well we need to go look does Lettow have a four hundred regular.
How does a little work.
So let's go browse the fonts and let's look for Lardo.
And if we go over here it has a four hundred regular so we're going to go that route and we're going
to say.
Also here.
Lardo loaded, and we're going to use the front loto for regular.
Amazing.
And so now we can say, well, huh, OK, if.
Oswald is not loaded.
Or Lardo is not loaded.
Well, then we'll just return not we won't return to that.
Well, they're still loading, right?
So we don't want to return anything right now.
So let's go look at what that looks like.
So use funds has already been declared.
Oh, we have a duplicate use fonts, so we're going to call this as use lato and we're going to call
this as use Oswald.
And then we're going to say, use Oswald, use lardo.
Beautiful.
OK, but hey, wait.
Laro, it isn't being used here.
What's going on?
Well, we need to tell.
The TextField right here, which Forn family is supposed to use.
So we're going to go from family.
And we're going to say props and then we'll say, hey, OK, props start theme thought Font's is it
thought Font's, let's go look.
That body, so let's do that body.
OK, so we're over here, font's dort body, let's just close this so we can focus on it.
And as you can see, we set the font family over here on this line.
We said from family to props theme font's body, which is Oswald, four hundred regular and as we can
see here now, it has applied.
So we have a nice font going on.
And if we remove this line, boom, back to the ugly font.
So we've loaded custom fonts into Riak native and we can choose from all nine hundred ninety one fonts
that Google has to offer us as long as we rinse and repeat our recipe over here for being able to load
different fonts.
Right.
As long as we utilize this technique right here, we'll be able to load however many fonts we want.
That's absolutely amazing.
And you can load different sizes as well.
You could go over here and you could say, OK, well, I also want 700 Bould.
So you could, for instance, say, I want like this LoDo.
700 Bould.
And then once we do that, we'll just add it to the list.
Boom.
And then once we added to the list, what we can do here is we can go over here.
Up here to our phones and we can say, for instance, that body is supposed to be this.
And oh, suddenly it's a different font, amazing, so we have this ability to load any type of font
from any font family.
That we want.
That's absolutely amazing, so I'm just going to undo this real quick because I'm going to keep it to
the base that we want to use and that's going to allow us nice consistency with the design that we set
out.
But feel free to load any font you want.
Feel free to make this your own, obviously.
So with that, we have now taken a massive step forward.
This is a customization that honestly opens so many doors for you.
Awesome.