That was a bit of a tricky one, wasn't it, and it was a bit of a tricky one, because taking something
as simple as this and putting it at the end takes a lot of practice with Flex.
There's different ways of doing it, but doing it with flex box triggers that you have to kind of start
practicing certain concepts.
So what we did here is we did an equal spacing.
So on the one hand, we have our rating over here and next to the rating we have this section that kind
of pushes in all the way.
And so how did we achieve that?
Well, let's look at that.
Over here in our code, we can see that we kind of put a section wrapper around our section, so let's
just switch colors.
So we have the section over here, right.
And the section is wrapping the entirety of the rating and everything around it.
Right.
So if we just quickly see that everything is gone, so it contains rating and it contains something
we would call section end.
So section end is a special type of component.
And we'll look at what the CSFs looks like that contains a conditional.
If you are open now, it's going to show you an open.
What is an open?
What is this?
Well, let's take a look.
So if we go up here, what we can see is and this is only one way of solving it, you can solve it in
a bunch of different ways as long as you've gotten the desired effect.
What I'm trying to show you here is a potential avenue of how to solve it without breaking the layout
in specific ways.
No, you can solve this any given way, but this is the way that I chose to solve it.
So over here, we have our section.
In our section has a flex direction of Roe and Roe means that basically it's going to well put them
in a row style syntax and we align the items to the center and then we have our section end, which
also takes a flex direction of Roe, but justifies the content to flex end.
And the end outcome of this is that it's going to push out to the side.
And then we took open, which is a styled a custom styled of our SGML that also takes a flex direction
of Roe now.
Was this necessary?
Maybe not.
Maybe it was.
What happens if we remove this off of the SVG, XML while nothing.
So it goes to show you that you can try out different things.
But at the end of the day, the way that we decide to lay things out can vary heavily.
Initially, the way that I was solving this was by trying to create a custom open SVG, right.
A custom SPG, XML that was going to lay itself out.
But then I ended on having a section and a section and that kind of wrapped around the thing.
So at the end of the day, I don't really need this.
I can take this away and I can go down here and I can say that open is an example and my layout still
works perfectly.
And it goes to show you that sometimes you'll add properties that don't really make sense or aren't
really required.
And that's completely fine.
It's about testing and looking in the visual Ed..
What's going on?
So over here, you can see that we have a flex direction of rollover section.
And then inside of that, we have a.
Rating and then beside that, we have our view right here of our SGML, OK?
So what now, so we solve this?
Well, I want to add two more things.
What I want to add is I want to add the potential for the if it is closed temporarily.
So if it is closed temporarily.
What I want to add over here is this.
I want to say closed temporarily and I want to give it a color of red.
And then what I want to do beneath that is I want to add an image and that image right below this and
that image is going to be our icon over here, the icon of whether or not it's a bed and breakfast or
lodging or a restaurant or what it is.
Now, you can see that the spacing around these items is a bit all over the place.
And so a way to fix that would be, for instance, to say on the image padding left would be 16.
Right.
And that should kind of fix it.
Nor should it.
Oh, that kind of like doesn't do anything.
So what do we need to do here?
Well, we can put a view inside of here and kind of say, well, the style of this view is equal to
a padding left of 16.
And so we can take that and we can add it to our react native over here.
And does that do something, oh, yeah, that seems to do something.
So let's take that same view and let's put that over here.
And what we'll see here is that, oh, that adds a perfect amount of spacing on both sides.
Right.
So we're using an element to kind of create this fake space because the image was kind of overflowing
with the padding.
Now, we could have easily taken this and just said, well, instead of padding left, how about we
do margin left?
We could do that, too, right?
And that would work just as well.
This is now going to push off.
Now, the reason I'm showing you that I'm doing it in a view is this is a styling technique that I like
to use.
I like to use elements to push other elements aside.
I call it the concept of a spacer.
And so now that we have these two different techniques and we've basically built out the entirety of
our restaurant view because we're using all of the properties now, we've completed a feature.
First of all, I want to dig a bit deeper into the spacer concept and maybe clean up some of the code
because we still have some inline styles in here.
We still have some stuff going on that we could probably make a bit better.
So now that we've completed this full feature set over here, right.
We have this beautiful card layout that kind of showcases a restaurant.
Now, we can kind of go and do some reflection on what we've done so far.
Awesome.