The last thing we need to do is make the call outs clickable, because right now, when we click them,
nothing really happens in order to do that.
The Matthew Call-out has a on press function and this on press function has the ability to do a function
call.
Now, as you remember, any screen that is given to a navigator, if we are looking at our navigators
inside of infrastructure, any view that's given to a component here has the navigation prop.
So because we know that we have the navigation prop, let's quickly go and get it navigation.
And what we can do here is we can say, well, on press, do navigation, dot navigate and where do
we want to navigate to where we want to navigate to restaurant detail and we want to make sure that
we give it the restaurant as a value.
So restaurant.
And we'll give it the value of, well, we have restaurant here so we can give it value restaurant of
restaurant or you can shorthand this and just say restaurant past the restaurant alone.
OK, so now that we done this, if we press, we're going back to the restaurant screen and we're showing
Tommy's joints info.
That's amazing.
It was that simple.
And if we go here and we press enter the via.
Well, instantly, we're going to the restaurant detail screen, absolutely amazing, it was that simple
because we set up our navigation and our infrastructure in such a simple and rigorous way.
We now have an easy way to link everything together.
A couple of lines of code, exactly three.
And we have a fully fledged integration between the map screen and the restaurant detail screen.
It was that easy.
Absolutely amazing.