So there's two things I want to focus on over here.
One is the fact that we have these components, right, these views that are offsetting our content.
Right.
So basically what that means is that they're pushing the content aside.
Now, some would say, Mo, this is kind of redundant.
You can just use a margin and you definitely can.
It's just the style that I've learned to like.
Now, it's not for everyone.
Some people like to just give things margins and all this good stuff I like to give margins to.
It doesn't matter whether it's a margin or a padding.
What I'm particularly after is that I like it when I have these things that will push content for me
so that I know that my content is in itself stylish almost, and that its position is irrelevant to
the things around it.
And so I called these spacer components.
And so I want to go ahead and make one of these components.
So let's go ahead and make a folder in here and let's call it spacer and inside of spacer.
We're going to make a spacer dot component.
Dot James, right?
And so we're going to import react from react, we're going to import.
View from Riak native, right?
And we're going to do a very, very basic implementation, we're going to do export consed spacer,
right.
And it's going to take two parameters.
It's going to take let's say we'll call it a variant.
Right.
And based on this variant, we're going to return different views.
OK, so we could do different types of areas.
Let's do a switch on variant, right?
And with a switch case, we'll do a default of returning.
And let's see here, we'll return of view.
That has a we've got to be a bit smart about this.
All right, so let's think about this.
Let's import style from styled components.
Netiv.
Let's create like three or four variants, let's do Consed Top Small, and let's say that that's a styled
type view that has the following properties, it's going to do a margin.
Top of four pixels.
And let's do a top medium.
Right, top medium.
And that's going to do a margin, top of eight pixels, and then let's do a top large, which is 16
pixels.
Right, and so if we switch variants, we're going to see a case.
Well, let's do it if statement because it's fairly simple for now.
Let's let's say if variance is equal to top thought small, we're going to return top small, actually.
Let's return top small by default.
And let's say if it's top medium, we'll return top medium.
And if it's let's let's see here.
Got a bunch of issues.
And if it's top large, we'll return top large.
Right, and so now you can see we're building a lot of logic, right, so we could say left and we could
do the same.
We could do left small, left medium.
And left large.
And so that will be the same, it will be for eight and 16.
But it will be margin left.
So let's, first of all, go ahead and do this.
I got to fix this.
This is margin up and these will be margin dash left.
OK, so now I can also say, well, if my variant is left.
Or left that small.
So let's add a left thought small and you can see I'm quickly accumulating a lot of logic here.
The spacer component feels kind of like heavy, but let's see what we can do because we're going to
optimize it.
Don't worry about that.
But if we go back to our restaurant card, we can now replace this with a spacer.
So if we say spacer and we say variant equals left that small and we do two spacers here, actually
it was medium.
So let's do medium.
Should it be medium, let's do large, because we want a decent amount of space between each and then
we'll go here and what we'll do is we'll import spacer and we'll do that from Balthasar slash slash
components, slash spacer spacer component.
And so that'll give us the spacer component.
And what we'll see over here right now is that everything works just the same or does it right.
What's going on here?
Well, first of all, let's reload and let's see.
So right here, left that large, doesn't seem to be working.
So our very end, we set to left that large.
So what exactly is going on here?
So we did left that large.
Oh, well, of course, more.
So let's take these and let's make them left.
OK, there we go.
And now everything's moving aside.
Right.
And so the way that things are moving aside is that there's a little view in here that's basically pushing
it.
OK.
Now, love it or hate it, this is a pattern that I've learned and grown to like because now I don't
need to care about specifically, OK, how much does this need to be or how much does this need to be?
I have a consistent spacer for myself, and I can go as far as to say, well, hey, these spacing's
that I'm giving here, I can go ahead and I can use my theme that speccing.
Right, so I can use four, eight, 16.
So.
I did it a bit faster here, but actually what I should be doing is doing props.
And then doing props, dot theme, dot space, and then thought, I believe it was too.
And then we can do two.
And for.
And here we can do two.
And it's looking good, right?
This is way better.
So now we have an effective spacer that works the way that we intended to work.
I believe it's actually actually I may be one off, I maybe one off.
I may be pushing it away too far.
It's one, two and three whoopsie, so we have to go back to our spacer here and we have to make sure
that it's one, two, three and one, two, three.
We were pushing it out a bit farther.
Now we can see that our spacer is working accurately for us to space things apart, to push things apart,
whether it be from the top, from the bottom, from the left.
And for now, we have top and left.
Left small.
Actually, this one should be small.
I have another issue here so you can see how the spacer, you know.
It's great and all, but there's a lot of logic to it.
There's a lot of logic to the spacer, but it's a great component.
Brings me into this case of where, hey, if we have a ton of variance of styles, right.
So like let's say, for instance, we have text and we wanted to have text, that was a caption and
we wanted to have text that was a title.
And we wanted to have text that was a heading.
And we wanted to have text that was just body text, like a paragraph.
All of those variants.
Are we going to encapsulate those each in their own component?
That sounds like a lot of logic just for a minor styling change between them.
So I'm going to show you a technique in this next video where we're going to use something called styled
system in conjunction with styled components to achieve absolutely amazing results through a technique
called variance.