Last we left off, we wanted to optimize the spacer and in order to optimize the spacer.
Well, right now we have this entire if statement tree that's kind of telling us, well, if it's top
left, bottom right, will you only did top or left.
And we already had one, two, three, four, five if statements.
We don't really want to do that.
That's that's not something that sounds very appealing.
So what we're going to do here.
Right.
We're going to do instead of Var., we're going to do position, which is that, and then we're going
to do size.
And so based on position and size, we're going to render out the right type of view.
So here we're going to do spacer component.
And then we're going to pass it position in size, so we're going to say position is equal to position
and then we're going to say that size is equal to size.
Now, we don't even actually need to do this.
So what we could, for instance, do is we could just say, hey, styled dot view, that's going to
be our spacer component.
Let's do that.
That may be a bit easier.
And then what we'll say is, will remove all of this and I'm going to show you a technique that may
be a bit of trickery.
Now we're going to see here that we're going to read the props, right?
So we have the props.
These are our props now, what we're going to the structure off of the props is going to be positioned.
And then we're going to do size and position, we're going to default to the top, and the way that
we're going to do that is we're going to say spacer thought default props equals and we're going to
say position is equal to top and we're going to say size is equal to.
Small.
Right, and so over here, what we're going to do is we're going to say CONSED sizes is equal to an
object where we say if it's small, we're going to do index one.
If it's medium, we're going to do index two.
And if it's large, we're going to do index three.
And so these are going to be our different options.
Right.
And so now inside of here, now that we know what the size is going to link to, what we can say is
the position, right, top, bottom, left, right.
So we're going to say CONSED positions and we're going to make that an object as well.
And we're going to say if it's top, we're going to do margin top.
And if it's left, we're going to do margin left and if it's bottom, we're going to do margin bottom,
OK?
And then if it's right, we're going to do margin, right.
So these are all of our options.
These are all of the possible combinations that we can get to.
So what we're going to do here is we're going to say the following.
What we're going to return from this function is we're going to return a string from this function.
Now, this may be a bit weird because we're returning a template string inside of a string, but basically
what we want to return here is something along the lines of margin top one, two or three margin left
one, two or three.
Right.
So that's what we're trying to return here.
OK, so what we can say is get variant.
That's what we're going to do.
And we're going to give that position and we're going to give that size.
And then we're going to say over here that consed get variant is equal to position and size and what
is going to return is a string.
That is the combination of.
We're going to do positions.
Of position.
Or let's call dispositioned variant, because that would make more sense, we're going to say select
the position variant and select the size variant based on the size.
So the position variant of position is going to be if we give it top, it's going to do margin, top
if it's left, to do margin left and so forth and so forward.
And then we're going to say we need to return a string.
So we're going to do this and then we're going to say we're going to add this over here and then we're
going to say size, variant of size.
We're constructing a string here.
And basically what this says is, OK, so you're going to pass me a position of this size which can
be top left, right or bottom.
And you're going to pass me a size variant, which you're going to be small, medium or large.
So we're reading this syntax, this language for this component.
Right, these props.
And we're going to say that the defaults are these top small.
OK, so knowing that we know now that we're formulating over here.
We're going to get the position and size off of the props with the spacer component, and we're going
to say run the get variant function and get various function is going to take the position in size and
go select the position variant based off of what was given and the size variant based off of what was
given.
Right.
So with this, what we basically have over here is the ability to have a function that will generate
this.
But the one thing we have to add at the end of this is pixels, because we always have to actually,
we don't because we're referencing sorry, we don't have to add pixels because we're referencing a certain
size on the theme.
One, two and three is referring to the spacing.
So one, two, three, four, eight and 16 pixels.
So that's great.
So knowing that we're basically set up for success here now, we do have some errors in here and we
can go check those out.
What is the error?
Parsing const declarations require an initialization value, and it seems that I made a little syntactical
error here, that has to be an equal sign.
OK, and so we're ready to go, right?
And so there's one more thing that we need to do now, this spacer component, you may have noticed
that originally we had put it alone as kind of like an alarm component right here.
But since it's a view, you can actually wrap the thing that you're spacing so you can put your spacer
around something and that will allow it to space that element.
And that is a way more effective way of being able to inspect it, because if we don't do it that way,
we won't be able to see the view.
It will still space.
It'll just be very hard to target in the element, Inspector.
Right.
If we do this, for instance, on the image, what we're going to see is that in the element, Inspector,
we're going to have a very hard time targeting specifically where that thing is happening, whereas
on this element, we can kind of figure it well, it's still hard, but you can still get it if you
click on this and you go over here up one level, for example.
You can usually get it.
Right now, it isn't spacing at all, and that's because the spacing is extremely small.
What is happening here is if we go up here and we can't hold out longer position variant and let me
just put the spacer back around.
And then right here, I need to remove this part.
Boom.
And we're good.
OK, so right now it is spacing and if we cancel the log, exactly what's going on with the spacing?
What we can see here is if we hide the element of Specter and we reload quickly, what we can see is
that.
Our get variant, let me open this up a bit more.
What's going on in here?
Every element should have unique you sure?
In our spacer, it doesn't seem to be console logging.
So let's see here.
Oh, yeah, well, OK, so if we went back here to this.
What we'll see is that margin left is being set to three, so this isn't actually the correct size,
this isn't getting it from the theme.
So what we need to do here is we're getting the correct size variant, right.
So what we can do is we can optimize this a bit.
We can say const size index is equal to this and then we can say property.
Is equal to the position variant.
And so now we know that this is going to be marginal left margin top and then for the size, and that's
what we want to do.
Here is one more thing.
We also want to get the theme object and we want to pass the theme to this.
And so what we can do now is we can take the theme in here and we can say for the size index, this
is CONSED, the actual value is equal to theme that space, I believe.
And then we give it the size index and we'll console lock that console that log the value.
And we'll just put value inside of here, and that should warrant us properly to get the correct spacing.
So if we look here, it's so hard to target these inner little things, but we can see the spacing going
on here, right?
We can see that.
And so, like, let's play around with that.
The element inspector targeting small, little things, always so hard.
Now, what we can do here is we can play around with the spacer so we can say left, small, right.
And if we say left small here, that's going to make that smaller.
So we're going to see a large.
And we could say for here top.
Right.
And that's going to break that.
So.
Wrapping the spacer around the thing you want, the space is the first proper thing we should do because
look, at the end of the day, you don't need to wrap the spacer around the thing.
You want the space.
You could just as well do this and it would still space adequately, like you'd still see the spacing
occurring here.
But kind of depends on what you want to do.
I find it better to wrap it around the thing you want to space, because at least then you'll have a
better chance of targeting it for viewing in the element, Inspector.
So we've basically built and optimized the entire spacer component to be able to get the variant that
we need for the style that we need from the theme based on a couple of props that we gave it.
So basically us giving it a prop position and size is able to tell the spacer how to space adequately.
And we've built, I believe, 12 or 13 variants of this component just with a couple of lines of code.
And that's absolutely amazing.
And we've also defaulted it to be top small.
So optimizing these spacer and getting these variants is a very good pattern just because it allows
us to create so much versatility in this component versus all of those if statements.
Right.
All of those if statements were quite complex.
At the end of the day, this is building up the entirety of the statement that is going to be the property.
That we're returning inside The View and so the syntax can be a bit wonky, right, but what we're doing
is we're getting the props off of the prop values and then we're running a get variant function based
off of those properties to get the correct spacing from this menu.
Right.
The size variance index and the position variant, name margin, bottom margin, right margin left,
all that good stuff.
All right.
So optimizing that space component, no more if statements and way more functionality.