Now that we're getting started on our favorites feature, one of the important concepts that we need
to come back to is the concept of services.
So far, we've we've used services to mock API calls to external services like Google, but services
extend way beyond the fold of just that.
In essence, with our service folder, it has everything to do with our interaction of data.
Right.
Data is what flows into the application and flows back out of the application.
And services are that layer that communicate with the data.
We don't want data all across our application being muddied in terms of where we call in request data
and retrieve data.
No, we want a nice shell around how we work with data.
And so services are that show.
Now, when we get into the concept of services, obviously we have our service, our mark in our context
and the context is there to provide the glue between what is react and what is the actual data transmission.
Right.
The API call in the transform we do against the data is one layer of requesting data, but the other
layer is how do we get that into the react ecosystem?
And so we decided that context was going to be that way.
Now, when we talk about our favorites, our favorites are basically also a service.
Now, whether we decide to store them locally or store them externally on a server, on a database or
whatever, at the end of the day, it's data that we're interacting with that may eventually become
an external concern.
So when we talk about it as a service, we have our favorites service.
But our favorite service is a bit different than the other services that we've created so far in the
sense that we're used to having a mock, a service and a context, in this case, we're going to be
storing our favorites locally.
So in that case, what we're going to start by doing is we're going to start by building the context.
So we're going to have a favourite's context.
Yes.
And this is going to kind of be where we focus all of our efforts.
So as with all of our services so far and all of our context, we're going to import, react from react.
And what we're going to do here is we're going to also import the all important to create context.
Now, what we need to define here is export const favourite's context, and that's going to be equal
to create context, which is going to be the context that is going to hold the favorites.
Now, as with everything, we're going to export a const favourite's context provider, which is going
to be the one that wraps the tree or the app is in order for us to be able to supply the favorites to
the tree of react.
And inside of there, we're going to say favorite context dot provider, and then we're going to close
that off thought provider.
And inside of here, we're obviously going to render our children, which are going to come from the
props of the component.
Now that we have this, what we can do is we have our baseline.
And so when we talk about favourite's, well, our favorite context needs to keep track of our favorites
and our favorites are basically the restaurants.
So the restaurant data is what it's going to store.
So we're going to import you state and you state is going to have CONSED favorites and a set favorites
function.
This is going to be equal to you state of an empty array, because we do not have favorites when we
put the up.
And each time a user decides that they want to interact and add a favorite, we need to set up something
to add and remove favorites.
So let's say const add is equal to adding a restaurant.
So we're adding a restaurant to our favorites.
And this is going to equal the process of doing set favorites of the current favorites.
Plus, the new restaurant that is going to be the process that is followed by the add function, now,
if we go look at our remove function, the remove function is going to look a little something like
this.
It's going to take in the restaurant that we want to remove.
And what it's going to do is a bit more involved.
It's going to do CONSED New Favorites is Favourite's Filter and it's going to check the restaurant by
Placide against the other restaurants in the favorites.
So the current favorites have all of the restaurants and we're filtering seeing if the police I.D. matches
do not add.
We could do something similar to this where we said if it is equal, don't add.
Now, that logic is going to be left for the outside, now we need to provide our provider with the
value that it's going to provide externally, and that value is very important for us because it is
the shape that is going to go to the outside of the component.
So first of all, we're going to provide favourite's and then we're going to say add to favorites is
going to be equal to our add function.
Remove from favourite's is going to be our remove function, and that's basically it.
These are the three methods that are going to be part of our favorites context.
It's very simple, very straightforward.
And so now let's go look at how we hook it up.