There's an interesting issue we have with our spacer component, you see when we run on Android, we're
seeing an issue of it not being able to set the property position in the shadow of our view.
Now, what does this mean?
Well, basically, this means that Android is having difficulties rendering the styled component view
from the get go.
When the app launches, it's unable to process the get very in function on load.
So this is a bug that specifically will happen on Android, whereas iOS has no difficulties at all.
See, iOS is just able to function correctly.
And this is one of the many scenarios that you may run into where you write code for iOS, you test
it on Android and suddenly everything breaks.
OK, so now what comes the question?
Well, we still want our space component and we still want it to work properly.
But how do we optimize it?
Well, the way to go about this is basically this inline function that we're running inside of the styled
view.
Right.
We're running a dynamic function inside of the render body of style.
Do you?
Well, we need to separate that out.
So what we're going to do is instead of having the spacer component immediately return a style view,
what we're going to do is we're going to do const space view is equal to style dot view.
And when we do this, what we're going to do is we're going to say instead of running a function, we're
going to pass the variant immediately that it needs to render and we're going to say return the variant.
So it's not going to run the dynamic function anymore.
And by doing this, we optimize our ability to render out the spacer.
So the spacer is going to become a normal component.
And we know what happens when we import normal components.
We need to import react.
From React.
And by doing this, we're now able to write a normal component now that said, we need position, we
need size and we need children.
And with these three properties, what we're going to do is we're also going to import use theme, which
is a hook.
That style system extends us so that we can calculate the variant inside of the functional body of spacer.
So we'll open the body and what we'll say is const variant equals.
But before we do that, we want to get the theme.
So we'll say conse theme is equal to use theme.
And by using the theme now we can say over here const variance is equal to get variant of position,
size and theme.
So now we've calculated the variance ahead of time and what we can do now is we can return.
And what will be returning is the spacer of you will be returning the spacer view and will be giving
it variant equal to variant.
So we've calculated the variance ahead of time and the last thing we need to do is ensure that spacer
view renders out the children, if there are any.
Given to it, and so by doing this, we've now inverted the flow, the in line render function of the
spacer initially created issues for us.
So now if we go into Android and we run Miles to go, what we should be able to see is that because
we're calculating the variance ahead of time now, everything works properly and our spacers work properly.
Now these types of things can happen, and these differences between Android and iOS can creep up at
a moment's notice.
What's important to note here, though, is that in order to anticipate these issues, we need to test
on Android and iOS regularly.