All right, so now we're going to look at the same thing for the tax component, so what I've done is
I've created the typography folder in the source components folder and I've created a text component.
And in that text component is where the magic is going to happen.
So first of all, as always, we have to import styled from styled components native.
This is going to import styled components for us now at the bottom.
Let's start at the bottom.
The first thing we're going to do is we're going to export a component text that takes the styled object
and references the text component.
Right.
So it's taking the text component that's styled components has exported for us.
It's the text component that Riak native also use.
So we're doing styled text and then we're saying, hey, the styles for style text are going to be two
dynamic properties.
So we're using the dollar sign with the bracket in order for us to reference the properties of text
and the properties here, meaning that we would reference if text had, for instance, the variant equal
to something.
If we did something like props over here, we could do props start variant.
Right, and so we're getting the props of the component now, this over here with the brackets again
is a shorthand syntax.
This is a shorthand syntax to take the properties off of the props object directly.
So we're structuring here.
So we're saying, hey, get Verint.
OK, so we're getting variant and theme.
And so with these two properties, what we can do now and with this property up here, so we're doing
two different things.
So on the first line, forty five, we're getting theme off of the props and then we're saying, hey,
run this function, default textiles and give it the theme object.
And what is default textiles?
Well, you guessed it.
It's constructing the defaults that we want for our text.
Any time our text doesn't have a variant at all.
If it so happened to be that way, it would construct the following font family body font with regular
color primary text primary.
So we're getting it all off of the theme.
We're going to say flex, wrap, wrap so that it wraps itself margined bottom.
No margin on the text element.
And so by doing that, we're guaranteed that we have a default amount of styles and then on the second
line we're grabbing the variant and the theme.
And we're saying, hey, we have a variant objects up here, right?
A variance.
So on variance, there is going to be a key, whether it be body label, caption, error or hint.
These are all objects on the object itself.
Right.
So this is the same syntax as are saying, well, body is equal to a function or body is equal to one,
two, three.
We're just saying, hey, reference body from over here.
So we created functions that are named the same way as the key.
So we're using another shorthand syntax here.
So body is declared up, their label is declared up there.
Caption is clear there and they're all declared as functions.
So we're putting keys on the objects of variance.
So these are all keys.
If we did something like object keys, right of variance, we would see exactly what was on there.
And if we went to terminal, we could see that here at the bottom.
I have a couple of errors that I'm contending with right now, located at yada, yada, yada.
It may have logged them, actually, maybe.
Over here.
Where is my law coming in?
Oh, well, obviously, obviously, you need to consult log dumb anyhow.
So when we counsel log, what's going to happen here is we can see that our array, if we do object
keys, we're going to see the array of the variance.
If we just cancel log variants, we're going to see that it's an object that has a body, a caption,
an error, a hint and a label.
And there all the functions are the functions that are declared at the top.
OK, so now what we know is that hate variance can get some type of key, right?
It could be something it could be labeled text color, hint, whatever the case is.
And so what we're going to do here is we're going to say, hey, grab whatever was given to text variant
as the property variant and put it in here.
So if I put a label in here, it's going to grab the label.
So if I did this console, that log of various label, what I'm going to grab here is the function label.
It's going to get that function now that if I invoke that function with the theme, then I'll get the
styles.
So with that, we now know that, well, the variant that we're passing in here is going to go in this
object and going to get the right function.
And so we're going to give that function the theme of style components in order for us to run that function
and get the appropriate styles.
So those appropriate styles are the following right for body.
We're seeing that the font size is going to be body.
So we're adding that on for hints.
We're going to say the font sizes body as well for error.
We're going to change the color to read for caption.
We're going to change the font size in the font weight to font size caption and font.
Weed's bold and all of this code will be available in the resources.
So make sure to go into the resources and get the code from right there.
Any time we're going through code a bit quicker or showing you how these particular portions work,
it's always available in the resources.
Now, over here we have caption font size, font weight is being changed and then we're looking at label
font, family, font size, font weight is being changed.
OK, so now that we know that, hey, based on the variant we give it and we're giving it a default,
which is body.
So it's always going to run this by default.
Now that we know that we can give it any type of variant, we can very easily create variant functions
here to give a different variation of text with different styles.
We could say title, text variant title, and we could give that a specific with the height and all
that good stuff.
OK, so now that we've done this, let's go and optimize our restaurant card here to use this.
So if we go over to our restaurant card, what we can see over here is that I've gone ahead and taken
the liberty of going to import the text directly from typography text.
And from now on, any time we need text, we're going to grab it from over here because this is the
one we want to use.
OK, so over here in our restaurant card, what we're going to do, first of all, is we're going to
remove title.
We don't need that.
We have our text component now that can take variants.
There's no need.
So we're going to go over here.
We're going to say text and text, and we're going to see what it renders out and it renders out this.
So now we can give it a variant.
And if we give it a variant of, let's say, a label, let's try that.
Well, now it looks similar.
And then over here, down here, we're going to give this a variant of caption and that's going to change
the text of the close temporarily.
And we don't need the style tag anymore because the variant caption is already taking into account what
needs to happen for the text to be well, or is it is it so we have to actually call it error?
Oh, that was it.
That was the one we needed.
Exactly.
So we can create variants on variants, on variants for specific use cases.
Now we have an error key, an error variant that's going to give it a read text.
And so we could, for instance, create a variant title just as well.
If we go look at our text component, we have a label which has the font size heading, so.
Honestly, I don't feel like this should be called label, but at the same time it should be called
label because it's not really a title the font is heading, but the font sizes body and the font weight
is medium.
It isn't really a large size.
When I think of a title, I think of something that has a font size that is bigger than font size body
and font size body has a size of 16 pixels.
I'm thinking more along the lines of these ones, these big boys.
Right, so.
In that case, we've now optimized our restaurant card component as far as we can with.
Attributes that can scale across the code base, so we've taken the text component and we've scaled
that out so that we now have text that can be used anywhere.
We need text.
We have a spacer component that can space elements anywhere.
We would need spacing.
Right.
And we have consistent spacing at that because we're set up.
One more thing we may need to do here is I don't like this image component, so we're going to make
this an icon component and we're going to say over here, const icon equals styled dot image and we're
going to give that the width of 15 pixels and the height of 15 pixels.
And that's going to basically.
Fix that up.
OK, so one more thing we need to do here, basically, our entire component here is in good shape,
right?
We have this over here and this over there.
And we're looking like we're we're in good shape for this.
So one more thing we need to do here is we need to take a critical eye at our code and we basically
need to clean up anything that is.
Not necessary right here, and I'm going to give you a pattern for this, one thing we're going to do
is inside of components, inside of the feature restaurant card.
Right now, we have the restaurant info card component.
Now, one file I want us to create as well is going to be restaurant.
Card dot styles torture's.
And what I want us to do in this in this particular file is I want us to go ahead and I want us to take
each and every one of these components.
Right.
Each and every one of these components that we made specifically for the restaurant info, and I want
us to move it into that style folder and let me show you how that works.
So let's, for instance, take the icon and let's go over here.
Just copy paste it.
So one thing we need to do here is we need to import styled from styled components.
And so now we're going to export CONSED icon, so we're going to add the export to the Gonski and one
more thing we want to do in here is we want to go over here and we need to say import.
From and then DOT's Restaurant InFocus styles, so now we have our icon coming from there and if we
look at our card, everything still works.
So what I want us to do is I want us to go ahead and take each and every one of these styled components
and put them in the styles file.
And that's going to be the exercise leading into the next video.
And then we'll look at the solution.