This is amazing.
We now can see all of our favorites and we can start them and we can underwrite them in any given screen
for the restaurant detail, and that is absolutely amazing.
Now, one thing we also need to keep in mind here is that if we want to build a favorite spa, what
we're going to need to do is we're going to need to track some state here because we're going to toggle
and untangle it at given points.
First things first.
Over here in our restaurants, we have a search component.
And in the search component, we have the ability to give it an icon and that icon value, we're going
to currently set it to heart.
And what we're going to see here is that it's going to be a clickable element.
So we're going to do an on icon press and that's going to be equal currently to a known method.
And so, as you can see, it is now a clickable element.
OK, so now we need to set up our state to be able to track and the restaurant or rather the favorite
spa is going to be a feature that is going to live right underneath search.
So this component is going to need to track some state, will use state.
Now, what we'll see here at line 31 is const.
Is toggled, set is toggled.
Is equal to use state false.
And this will be the method that we will pass into our search container and we'll call it on toggle.
Policy set is toggled equal to.
The opposite of the current is toggled, so we'll invert the toggled each time it is clicked and this
will allow us to toggle it on and off.
Now that we've given it a method, what we can go do is we can go back into our search component and
we can see here, well, first of all, we also need to pass the toggled state.
We'll say is favourite's toggled and then will also do on favourite's toggle.
We'll give it a bit more of a semantic reasoning here.
On the inside, it's OK if we name it as toggled, but for search, we need to give it more of a name
and so in search we're going to take in.
The prop is favourite's toggled and on Favourite's Tovo.
And we're going to run these so on press is going to run on favourite's toggle and in the icon we're
going to say his favorites toggled to a full heart, otherwise do a heart outline.
And here we have to say full on heart outline.
And that's going to allow us to toggle off and on the heart.
So here we can see we're toggling it on and off given the state.
So we're able to toggle the favorite spa on and off.
Now, we don't have a favorite spa yet.
So what we need to set here is is toggled and and we'll set up a favorite spa.
And this favourite's bar is going to come from the same place that favourite's comes from, so we're
going to say Favourite's Bar comes from component's favorites, favorites, bar dot component.
And over here in Favourite's, we're going to set up a favourite's bar component.
Dargis that's going to import react from react and export consed favourite's bar.
Which is equal to will quickly put something in here, will import text from Riak made of quickly.
What we'll do with this text is we'll say text favourite's bar.
And so if we visualize this out in our component, what we're going to see here is Favourite's Bar no
favorite of our favorite bar, no favorites bar.
OK, so now that we have the framework set up around the favorite bar and being able to toggle and untangle
the favorites bar and we set up that infrastructure for the favorites bar, we can start building out
the visualization.
So let's get into that.