Don't you just love code clean up, so the intended outcome of this exercise was to take all of our
components that were styled components and take them out of the restaurant card component and put them
into something called restaurant info card style starches.
And so this is a pattern that is very useful when you're creating style components that are just solely
visualisations based.
Now, you may be asking yourself, well, why are these Dorte styles?
But is text a component?
Well, that's because in the text we're adding extra functionality here with kind of these variants
and these functions inside that that make it a bit smarter.
So that's why it's called it Dow component.
And the same is true for a spacer because we're using kind of like this get variant type of interaction
to make it a bit smarter.
So it functions more as a component because it's utilizing props.
It's utilizing properties that are given to it to dynamically determine styling.
Whereas over here and restaurants up InFocus styles, well, it's just using basically the theme to
colorize and position things.
So we're calling that dot styles.
So by putting everything in that styles right, one of the things you may have noticed is you have to
move the imports over here and you have to add the export keyword to every single one of these in order
for it to work.
And then over here, so much less code in this component.
And a nice, nice overview of where we're importing things from and what we're importing and specifically
calling them out to be styles right there, styling their components that are positioning things in
the right place on the screen.
So over down here, we can see now.
All right.
Pretty nice overview of very, very basic UI.
Sixty three lines of code.
And we have this absolutely, absolutely stunning card component that is going to be utilized throughout
the course to create a stunning visual of the app.
And so in the next video, now that we've done our cleanup, what we want to do is we want to look at
how to apply this card.
Multiple times we're going to use a list, great, see you in the next one.