Now that we have everything in order for the favorite spa and all of the different parts set up that
we need, what we can start doing is building out what the favorite spa is intended to look like.
So, first of all, what it needs to take in is the current favorites.
That is what it will be consuming.
And then once it has the current favorites, what it's going to return is a styled view.
So import styled from styled components made of and we're going to create a component that's called
favourite's wrapper, and that's going to be a component that is styled thought view.
And we're just going to give it a basic padding.
We're going to give it a padding of 10 pixels all around.
That's all that it needs.
And so we'll take that favourite's wrapper and will render it out.
And inside of that favors wrapper, what we're going to need to do is we're going to need to put in
a scroll view, a scroll view from Riak Netiv Scroll.
You in that scroll view is going to work basically as our horizontal navigator.
So we'll put in a scroll view and we're going to put in the following properties on it horizontal and
show horizontal scroll indicator false, both of which are necessary to make sure that our scroll view
goes in this direction, right this direction, not this direction.
So from left to right, not up to down.
Once we have our scroll view set up, what we can do is we can say favourite's map.
I'm going to copy a code snippet here, what we can say is favorite stop map.
And then each individual restaurant is going to have its name and we're going to split and join it.
That's a potential that you could do on the key.
We don't really need this, but it's an option.
And we can say that we're going to have a concert.
You know what we'll do?
We'll have a spacer here that is going to be of type left, so position left.
And size is going to be equal to large or you know what, let's do medium, so we're going to have a
spacer here because we had a view that basically had an inline style, but we don't want to do that.
So we're going to import spacer from bottega spacer spacer that component.
And that's going to allow us to space the compact restaurant in for which we also need to import from
DOT's Restaurant Compact restaurant info.
So it's going to be a very basic setup here.
And then what we're going to say is that the key is equal to key.
Right here, once we do that, if we go over here to our overview and we open it up, undefined is not
an object.
Favorite sport isn't receiving favorites, of course.
So we have to go over to the restaurant screen and we have to make sure that we in the restaurant screen
import the restaurant context.
And the low key and the favorites context, specifically, so favourite's context from favorites, slash
favorites, thought context.
So once we have our favorites context, where we can go do over here is we can use the context, favorite
context.
We can pull in the favorites, the current favorites, and we can pass them to the favorites bar like.
So now here you asking me why do it this way as opposed to having the favorites bar.
Just use the context directly.
Well, the reason for that is the favorite bar should be able to receive its favorites at any given
point from anywhere, just as a prop.
It should be something that flows in.
And so the question then becomes, well, why didn't we do that to the favorites component?
Why does that one take in a restaurant but kind of hook itself on to the context?
And that is because we consider this favorite to be more of a module.
It's kind of a self-contained feature of sorts.
It interacts without any outside help and it's just there to position itself.
If we were to take in all of these different methods from the outside, it would defeat the purpose.
We could even go so far as to put this inside of a module favorites folder.
But I decided to leave it as a favor to component.
We could even potentially rename it to favorite module.
But all of those are semantics.
It's just the reasoning behind why we're doing this.
If we look now at our favorite bar.
And we open it up.
Oh, no element type is invalid, expected a built in function, so there's something going wrong here.
So if we look at Favourite's Bar, it's importing from Oh.
Accidentally undid it, so this should be from favourite's and then it should be favourite's bar thought
component.
And this should allow us to render out.
Nothing well, that's new, and that's because we don't have any favorites, so once we start clicking
favorites, oh, there we go.
There are our favorites.
This is looking good.
So we can import all of these.
And as we import all of them, you can see them pop up here.
And once they pop up, they basically become usable right out of the get go.
And so removing them will remove them from the list in the position that they were in.
And so we can quickly see here that we will push them to the back of the stack.
If we add them back, we can hide and show our favorites bar.
But there's one crucial thing missing.
In the fevered spa, we're unable to click on the compact restaurant info, and so one thing we would
want to do here is add a touchable opacity and once we add the touchable opacity, we would add it around
the compact restaurant info and on press, we would say navigate.
So on press, we could say.
Go go to detail and go to detail, would come in as a prop or we could say on detail, let's call it
on detail, and when we say on detail, what we're going to do here in our restaurants screen is we're
going to pass it a function to go to Anta detail.
And that's going to be the same function that we basically use over here.
But we're going to pass it in here and we're going to say on detail equals and we're going to pass it.
Not the full navigation, but we'll pass it navigation, but navigate.
And that will allow us to go inside of Favourite's Bar.
Let's call it I'll navigate that feels better on navigate.
And then in the restaurant screen, we'll call it on navigate and then we'll be able to copy the same
body that we put inside of here.
And when we go inside of our favorite spa, then once we have the touchable opacity, what we can do
is we can say on navigate as a function return and there we go.
That'll work a bit better.
Now, we don't have any favorites, so once we add them, we can quickly see here that we can.
No, if they are favored it or not, and once we click them, we know where they are, we can go see
the detail of them.
That is absolutely amazing.
And so now we know all of our favorites.
Little thing we could add here to the top is potentially some texts.
So let's import text from Thugged typography text and we'll add some text with a spacer around it.
Right up here and we'll call it favourite's, and so now we know that we're looking at our favorites,
the things that we favorite it so far, and that allows us to better understand what is going on up
here and what are we looking at.
Amazing.
So we just built out our entire favorite spa, but there's a small issue.
When we reload, we lose all of our favorites.
And so nothing is rendering out.
And so we shouldn't be rendering out if we don't have any favorites.
So one thing we should add into here is a return up here and then down here.
Let's close it off.
And what we'll do is we'll say.
If favourite's the length.
Does not exist, right, is zero, then will return, no, we won't return anything.
So just to make sure that we don't render anything out in case that way we kind of know, hey, we don't
have any favorites.
And then once we select one, OK, it's pretty obvious that it will show up in the list.
Great.
But we also need to figure out how we're going to store favorites, how we're going to store favorites
between sessions.
Even so, let's take a look at that.