We've hit this proverbial wall because now we're able to add favorites and when we add favorites, they're
immediately visible when we go to our favorite screen.
And that's absolutely amazing, right?
When we trigger our favorites bar, we can see all of our favorites and we can remove the favorites
and see it happen.
But we have a problem.
When we reload, all of them disappear.
So they're not being persistent.
And that is a consequence of, first of all, our favorites being in local, state and second of all,
us not storing it anywhere.
Now, there's two options.
We can store it on a server or we can store it on the phone.
And I'm always a fan of these types of information.
It's good to store them on the phone.
Because it's local information and eventually, if we do get to a level at which we have infrastructure
backing the app, we can move it out.
But it's good as a caching mechanism, as a secondary caching mechanism as well for the first 20 favourite's
so that the user doesn't have to wait on an API call or whatnot.
There's different reasons to store locally.
For now we're going to store locally because we do not have a server environment and we do not need
one because a user has a limited cap on how many favorites they're ever going to store.
You're never going to have a user with one hundred thousand favorite restaurants.
I don't think a person can like more than four or five thousand restaurants.
And even then, how long would it take them to get there?
By then, we would already have our infrastructure.
So it's a premature optimization.
So then we have to ask ourselves the question, well, how are we going to store locally in Riak Native?
We have the concept of async storage, but I know.
Well, what is this about deprecated?
It's been deprecated.
Riak native deprecated async storage.
Oh, and this is why the docs are also important.
Riak native has a lot of moving parts.
Things move all the time.
And so it's important to keep on top because as Riak native grows as an ecosystem, so does its support
there, moving things out of Riak native and into external packages because they should not belong to
core.
And so it's saying use Riak native async storage instead.
And so when we look at Riak native async storage, it can store string data, it can store object data,
but you need to serialize it first.
So it's saying you can use JSON, String Afie and JSON pass when loading Glatz.
That's pretty good.
And so with that, well what is it.
So let's do XPO async storage and when we go look at the docs of XPO, which is also always useful when
we're looking at high level features.
It says use riak native async storage, async storage and it has an expo install command even.
This is amazing.
This means we have first class support for the package that Riak native is telling us to use.
And so with that, let's go ahead and run this command.
And if we open up our terminal over here and we open up the Terminal two and we run the Expo install
command while that's installing, let's go look at the usage.
If we look at the usage in here, it says import async storage from Riak native async storage, async
storage.
That's a whole mouthful.
Try saying that three times fast.
And if we go into our code where we want to import, this is inside of our favorites context.
So at the top, we're going to import async storage and we're going to go look quickly at how this works.
So it's saying store data is an async function.
This is a sugar for a promise.
This is kind of the same as doing a Dianabol, something that we saw earlier or promises an async.
A wait is a different way of writing it.
And so we can say store data is an async function that is awaiting async storage, that set item.
And then when we store an object value, it's JSON, that string of file.
So if we have a complex object, which is what we're going to store, we're going to JSON, string ify
it.
And then if we want to read the data or data, we can do an async function again where we're going to
await async storage, Daudt, get the item and then check if the item has a value.
Otherwise catch the error.
This is pretty good, isn't it?
And what we can do here is we can go ahead with this and we can try to directly implement these methods.
So let's go inside of here.
And we've now installed Riak native async storage and so let's quickly implement our functions.
So it said that we need to store data.
So let's call that first of all, let's call that saved favourite's.
That sounds better.
We'll call that C favourite's and it's an async function.
And what it's going to do is it's going to do a JSON value of evalu.
And in case of an error, let's console that log the error just in case.
Now, we're also going to need a load, so reading the data.
And so let's go ahead and do calls to get data like they did over here.
Let's call that load favourite's.
And so with these two functions, we're basically set up to put together our favorites, but we need
to give it a proper storage key.
So let's say at Favourite's, that's going to be our storage key.
OK, so now that we've set this up, what we need to do now is if the value is not equal to null when
we load it, well, then we need to set it to favourite's.
Right.
But we need to.
Jason Poza set favorites Jason on that pass and we need to do value.
Value is basically the equivalent of getting our favorites, and if we have an error, let's console
log the error just in case and let's say error loading as a prefix and error storing.
As a prefix, just so that we know which error is which.
And so now that we have this basically set up, what we need to do is we need to grab our use effect.
And once we have our use effect, we can start implementing how this is going to work.
So right here below the remove method, let's put a use effect and let's say that the use effect is
going to listen to any change in favourite's.
And any time favorites changes, we're going to store the favorites, so we're going to do a save favorites.
Of favourite's.
And that's going to be what we want to store.
OK, so now we have that use effect where we're going to save, but now we also need to make sure that
we load the favorites, which means we're going to load favourite's every time on the very first mount
of our context.
We're going to make sure that we load the initial favourite's.
Awesome.
So with all of this code, are we set up for success?
Well, let's go take a look, because that wasn't a lot.
And we basically know now what exactly is going on.
So let's just restart XPO.
Inside of here.
And let's make sure that everything works as intended, so if we load Miles to go here, what we can
see is that once it loads up in the very first instance, we're not going to have any favorites.
But once we start saving favorites, so we'll save the first two and then we'll showcase the first two.
If we now reload our app, we should still have them saved as favorites.
So let's take a look.
Oh, amazing.
They're still save this favorites and I can still see them here.
And if I go to Antwerp and I search for Antwerp and this starts loading and I save a favorite from Antwerp
as well and I reload, what I'm going to see here is that load favourite's on.
The very initial load of my context is going to load up my favorites from the async storage.
So from the storage on the phone.
And we have all of our favorites loading up in between sessions.
So even if we close and reopen our app and we kill the app, we're going to save what we stored so far.
That's absolutely amazing.
That's a big, big, big advance.
But there's one more thing we need to do here, and that's select some favorites because we need to
pick our favorite restaurants, don't we?
Awesome.
This is a great feature.
I love it already, don't you?
And so now we have three fully built features.
We have our restaurant screen.
We have our favorites implementation.
We have our favorites saving and loading.
We have our map for you in which we can go and we can go to specific restaurant details.
What's left?
Well, there's quite a few things left, so let's look at that in the next video.