I'm so excited we're about to build our very first list for you, and that is absolutely exciting.
So where do we start here?
Well, we need to go back to our restaurant screen because that's where we have all of the magic happening.
Right.
We have this restaurant info card right here.
And so what we want to do right now basically is we want to take this and we want to make it a list.
Right.
We want to make it that scrollable goodness.
First of all, we need to know exactly how to go about this first and foremost, let's go ahead and
let's clean this up.
We have the restaurant list container, right, that has Fleck's one and all of that good stuff.
But we will no longer need this.
We we kind of use that to kind of fix our list in a certain way.
But we're reaching a point at which we no longer need that.
What we need to do is we need to go to the riak need of docks.
Right.
React native to our Holy Grail.
And so what we need to look at here is flat list and flat list is, well, what you would think a flat
list.
It's a performant interface for rendering basic flat lists and supporting the most handy features.
It's fully cross platform.
It has optional horizontal mode.
It's configurable, it has header support as footer support as separator support.
You can do pull to refresh, you can scroll blook, you can do all the things OK.
And also if you need section support, if we need sections in our list, you could also look at section
was.
So this is why it's useful to read the docs because they guide you in all different types of directions.
So if we look over here at Flat List, this is kind of what it looks like, right?
We have our first item, our second item, our third item.
Right.
And flat list has this interface where it's going to take in data.
And it's going to render an item and it's going to potentially use a key extractor, that's if you don't
seddiqui now what is a key?
So let's look at what the key is.
If we Google react key.
Right.
Listen, keys first.
Let's take an overview of how to transform a list.
So if we take a list here in JavaScript, write numbers, one, two, three, four, five, and we map
that well when we render this out.
In this way.
It basically becomes difficult for react to reference what specifically every item is, if there are
duplicates, if the number is duplicate for reacts rendering cycle, it needs to know a little bit more
about this.
And this is a great article highlighting why you need keys, what a key is and all of that good stuff.
Right.
A key is a special attribute that you need to include when creating a list of elements, and they'll
discuss why it's important in the next section.
And they go through, hey, this is what keys are.
Keys, help react, identify which items have changed, added, removed.
It's basically like this identifier that really needs to kind of go through the motions.
And for those of you who are new to react, we will link this documentation for you to go through and
read and understand and understand the importance because it is an important concept and highlighting
what it basically does.
It allows react to kind of have knowledge of your list.
Now, when we go to flat list, when we go to the flat list implementation.
Right.
If you go to the doctor, you can try this out on all different types of devices.
But what we're trying to do with the flat list approach is we're trying to allow data to be rendered
in a specific way.
So this is our data.
If our data was an array of an idea and a title object and we have three objects, what we could say
is that in our flat list we would have down here the data as the data and the render item as a function
render item and render item would take the item and it would map it to a different component, a different
component that would then take the properties off of the item, which in this case would be identical
and put them in a text field.
OK, so knowing that what we want to know about why specifically we need to use flat list as opposed
to like something else is basically because it is a wrapper around something called a virtualize list.
So it has inherent memory optimizations.
It's going to do things out of the box that help you better relay information in.
And if you have massive lists and data is coming in dynamically and all of these things are changing
often, or it's a very, very large amount of data, a flat list is your main solution because it has
these optimization.
Now, you could go to something directly like scroll view and scroll views, a component that just provides
you a scrollable interface.
Right.
And scroll view versus flat list.
Which one should you choose?
Will scroll if you just renders all of the children at once and that has a performance down side.
So scroll view is something that you may use if you have a fixed number of items available.
But flat list comes into play when you want to render items lazily.
So like you're doing something where you want to pull data from a different website like Google or somewhere
else.
Flourless is also handy if you want to.
If you want to render separators multiple.
There's so many different variations of things that we can do here and it's honestly mind boggling.
But so what we need to know now is you have scroll view and then you have flat list and we're going
with flat list because we want to future proof our code.
We may reach a point at which we would want to extend this app and do things that made you lazy loading
or pull data from an API or do a pull to refresh or anything kind of crazy thing.
So we want to future proof our app.
And in that case, we need to make the smart decision and choose the implementation that best suits
what we're trying to accomplish.
OK, with all of that background, what we need to do now is we need to go inside of Riak native.
We're going to remove the things that we're not using anymore because we don't need them and we're going
to import philatelist.
Right.
And Flat List is one of those things that we're going to go put it over here.
All right.
And what we need to do with the flat list is we need to give it a couple of properties.
So we're going to give it data.
Well, what data?
So what?
We don't have any data.
Good point.
For now, we're going to give it the restaurant card.
OK, so the restaurant card, that's what's going to render out right now.
We're not giving it any data.
We're not stripping the item.
We don't have any data yet.
So we don't know what we're giving it just yet.
But stay with me and then we're going to give it a key extractor and the key extractor is going to say,
hey.
For the item.
Right, for the item, take the item, not name as the actual key.
We're going to take the name of the thing that we're trying to render, and that's going to be our key.
OK, good.
Now, we also need to make sure the right content container style.
What is this?
What is this content Container Store?
Well, I'll show you.
So if we look at content container style inside of what we would call scroll view.
A content container style will apply the style to the contents of the container, so for each child
it will apply these specific things.
So what we're going to do is we're going to say padding 16.
Now, this is not allowed, but we'll get there.
Don't worry about it.
All right, so now we're in a state where we have a flat list, but look, it's not rendering out anything.
Why is that?
Well, our array is empty.
So if we added things to our rate and we said name one and then we said second object name to.
What's going to happen is we're going to render out to restaurants.
Huh, that's pretty cool, isn't it, on the why is this happening and what would happen if we said
our pattern here to zero if we set our pattern here to zero?
Well, they're going to stick to the edges.
That's why we're adding the padding to every single item.
OK, good to know.
Get to know.
Why is it rendering two items, Nomo?
Well, as you can remember, inside of the component restaurant INFL card, we set all of these logical
defaults to every single property.
So it didn't really matter if we gave it a property or not, because it's going to fill in our mock
data either way.
So this is pretty good because now we can start building our UI without having to wonder about where
data is coming from just yet.
OK, so if we do this and we copy this right and we say, well, OK, paste that a couple of times,
so let's do that, let's do that, let's do that, let's do that, let's do that.
And we're doing something wrong here because basically.
We're forcing multiple objects with the same name.
So we're going to do three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12.
13 and 14 now, we won't have children with the same name, and that's pretty good.
And as you can see, we have a pretty long list here.
It's looking good.
And we just implemented a whole list feature.
OK, but there's still something wrong.
I see you asking yourself, Mo, why are these sticking to each other?
What is going on?
And that's a good question.
Why are they sticking to each other?
Didn't we just add padding, then we add padding to them?
Well, yes, we did.
Well, we also need to add a margin pop potentially of 16.
Huh, that really isn't doing anything that like they're still sticking to each other, that doesn't
look good.
So how do we go about this?
Well, I'll tell you what's going on here is that although this is applying a style to each individual
item, it it isn't really applying a speccing inside of the item itself.
Right.
So, like, if we go look at this and we show the element, Inspector and we do this, the element itself
is not being spaced correctly.
So how do we go about doing this?
Well, I'll show you.
Give me one second if we go inside our restaurant info card, right, right over here.
And I'm going to show you some magic that's going to happen, and we look here, restaurant card, OK,
so we'll go to a restaurant card.
Where is restaurant card?
We set a background color, OK.
OK, so let's add some padding.
But we don't want any padding.
We want actually let's not do padding.
Let's do margin bottom and let's set margin bottom to spacing three and then let's see what happens.
Oh suddenly they're spacing themselves apart.
So there are certain styles that still need to be applied to the card itself because content container
style won't just automatically apply it.
Right.
We want this card specifically outlaid this way.
So we still need to say to the card, hey, you need some spacing around you.
And we could, for instance, do that just by doing this.
We could do patting.
And now we're stretching the card, that's not good.
That's why padding wouldn't work here.
This is why we need margins.
So we're going to add a margin bottom of the theme Space three, and that's going to give us the kind
of ideal layout that we're looking for, because now they're ideally spaced apart in a good way, right?
In a good type of way.
It looks so slick.
It looks like a real production grade.
Nice feature packed up.
Look at this.
Wouldn't you want to eat those?
I want to eat those potatoes.
What don't you want to eat?
That looks great.
In any case, what we're trying to get at here.
Right.
Is there are certain styles that need to be applied specifically to the item that you're rendering inside
and we could have done this another way.
We could have, for instance, done this.
We could have said, hey, render the restaurant card.
And then also we could have used our spacer here, I believe.
So we could have done something like spacer and we could have said, hey, wrap this with a spacer.
And then if we go into the info card over here, we can just copy the import to our speaker and we can
put it over here at the top right there.
And this should work.
And let's see what that does.
So if we did this and then we, for instance, said over here.
Don't do this one.
What's going to happen is the spacing is going to be way smaller.
So this is a different way, for instance, doing it.
And we could have, for instance, that if we go look at the interface of the spacer, we could have
said position bottom.
Let's go back into here.
We could have said position.
Is bottom.
And then we could say size equals large.
And boom, but more spacing, so this is another perfectly fine way of doing it and at least you know
now where the spacing is happening, right?
We can see our spacer here and we could say, hey, space them from the bottom side and do it large.
So we're wrapping this and we're saying, hey, just push it down a little bit so we don't have to go
look inside of the restaurant card in the style and see that the margin bottom is being applied here.
Can you see how the spacer component is adding value here and how we can see how things are being spaced
directly in the UI?
I just find that useful.
Some people don't.
It really depends.
And so if we don't add our content container style, we're going to see a little bit of a sticking point.
And in that case, what we can do is we can, for instance, go back here and we can say, hey, add
some padding and this will add padding, but only on the inside.
OK, so that's an interesting side effect.
Right?
So we do need this content container so so we know what to do now.
Right.
What we do is we say CONSED restaurant list is styled, right styled, and then we give it the flat
list and we say, Hey.
Patting, let's take that padding, let's put it there.
Well, will that actually work?
No, it won't, because this is applying the padding to the flat list itself, not to the specific content
container style, so we can't actually use this.
That's an interesting side effect of using content, container style.
Right.
So what I would advocate is in some cases, it's perfectly fine to use content, container style and
do some inline styling.
If you don't want to do that, you can still do something like like styles.
But I personally find that completely OK to do something like padding 16 here, because at least I know
where the padding is happening and why it's happening.
Right.
You could do padding 30 to and really give it some space.
It really depends on what you want to do.
But just know it's available to you and we'll look at how to optimize this potentially in the course.
Of course, our excellent is telling us no inline styles and we're keeping that there for now.
Right.
What we could also do is we could, for instance, disable it for this line and then it wouldn't complain
over here that something that you kind of want to avoid, you always want your lending to be in line
with what you're trying to build.