Oh, we have a bug if we look at a restaurant favourite's bar here, the images are loading on iOS but
not on Android.
Now, why would that be?
Well, remember when we originally set up the restaurant compact info to work in a certain way?
Well, if we go look at compact restaurant info, if it was Android, it was going to load the Web view,
but we wanted that specifically only for the mapu.
So what we should add here is a specific trigger that we're going to check and we're going to call it.
Well, we know that naming is hard, so we'll call it is map.
And we'll check if it is Android and and it is MAP, then we'll render the compact with you and so on
the map, we're going to go inside of the screen and we're going to say that the map call-out, which
is this component over here, we're going to say is map.
And so this will allow us to render out the correct view for the favorites locally.
Right in the favorites bar.
We still want to use an image component, even if we're on Android, because we specifically only had
the bug with the image view inside of the mapu.
So we didn't want to trigger that logic when we weren't on the map for you.
And so that's important to note here.
And so what you can see here is, of course, the images don't correspond because we're randomly selecting
images.
Of course, if I deselected reselect, you'll see the image pop up.
This is because we're randomly selecting images for each restaurant.
And so this can happen.
The images may not match up, but that's completely fine.
As we can see, the feature is working as intended.
And on the map view, we are still rendering out the images in the Westview correctly as intended.
So the bug fix for the map is still there.
But we aren't breaking the favorites bar on Android anymore.