We've come so far from the blue and green screen we first started out and our next focus point is going
to be authentication and authorization.
So the ability to login and the ability to register an account so that you can login.
And logging in is the simple process of being able to fill in an email address and fill in a password,
and if you fill in the wrong password, seeing errors, filling in the right password will then give
you access to the app.
And this entire back and forth is here because we want to have different users be able to use our app.
Of course, will have the ability to log out as well as well as some personalized info from the account
showing up to know who you are.
Now, the question remains, well, how do we go about this?
What are we going to use?
How are we going to build authentication?
I've never done this before.
Well, authentication is a kind of a procedure that now more and more is being offloaded onto these
external services.
And over here you see something called Firebase.
Firebase helps you build and run successful apps.
So Firebase is one of those platforms where it's backed by Google and loved by app development teams
because you can use it and have so many services out of the box for free.
It can grow with your product and grow with your solution as your app journey begins.
Now, if you look at all of the build products, you can see that they have so many different things
going on for them.
They have a build section, they have a release and monitor section, and they have an engaged section.
So you can literally go through the process of building your app with core infrastructure to release
and monitoring your app in production and also tracking specific analytics.
They have such a wide plethora of products that they offer that it's almost ridiculous not to go with
Firebase these days when you're starting off bootstrapping a product.
Now, if we hit the go to console button up here, what we're going to see is that it's going to ask
us to sign it now in order to use Firebase, which is completely free to begin with.
And in their particular Sparke plan, you need a Google account.
So for those of you who do not have a Google account, I recommend you create a Google account.
This is in the form of a Gmail email address, for instance.
So you you need to go through that process of creating an account.
And over here you can see that you can fill in your first name, last name and pick a username for your
Google account as well as a password.
And so once you go through that process, what you're going to see here is that when you go to the Firebase
Docs outside of the console, you to fire based Google dot com.
Then what you'll see here is that the go to console button will actually take you to your console for
your particular Google account.
Once we're here, we can start exploring because the exploration is part of the fun, you can see here
all of our firebase projects and right now what we want to do is we want to create a new firebase project.
So we need to give it a name and we'll call it meals to go.
Once we do, that will hit continue.
And we're going to turn off analytics for our project right now because we do not need it.
And we'll create the project and now Firebase is going to go through the motions of setting up everything
that is necessary for us and provisioning all of the resources that we require for all of its services.
So it offers like authentication and databases and all of this good stuff.
And so it just needs to make sure that it has everything hooked up properly for us, for our project.
And now that our project is ready, we're good to go.
Amazing, so as you can see here, we start off on the Spark plan, which means it's a zero dollar plan,
we don't pay anything, we don't have to supply payment information and everything that we can use is
absolutely free.
And as we can see here, authentication is one of the main pillars of them to keep and manage your users
as well as something called the cloud firestorm.
And there are many other build features.
And so they've bucketed all of the features inside of build, release, monitor analytics and engage.
And by doing that, they give us the ability to know, hey, here's what you use for this particular
pillar.
So inside of build, we're going to be focusing on authentication because that's what we need for our
application.
So if we hit authentication, what we're going to see here is that we haven't set up authentication
yet and authentication manager users from providers without any type of code server side code particularly.
So we're going to set it up as if Firebase is our server and it's going to be our intermediary for authentication.
So we'll get started.
Once we start getting started, we can see here that it's going to take us to the authentication settings,
specifically to the sign in method, because currently all of the optional Sinon methods are disabled,
which is not what we want.
So we want to enable email and password.
And once we hit enable what we're going to see here at once we save is that it will be set to enabled
and that means that we're good to go now.
Currently, we don't have any users for this project.
And we we can we can see here that there's all types of different analytics that we can see here, how
many people signed in this month and the current billing period last seven days, yesterday, today.
So we can see some type of in-depth analytics as well as we can see all of the users that have registered,
which we do not have as of yet.
OK, but it's set up, right?
It's set up.
Yes, it is.
And so now we have to look at what the end to end integration is going to look like for Firebase.
So make sure you have an account.
You've registered a Google account.
If you didn't have one, you've created a project for meals to go.
And once you've created that project that you've set up the authentication the same way we have.
And then we'll go into the next video where we look at how we're going to feed this back into our actual
application.