I can hear you screaming from the rooftops.
You told us no inline styles, we set it up in our linta.
Why would you do this?
And.
This is not ideal.
But sometimes this is the way it has to be, not I'm kidding.
There is a way to resolve this with without components, obviously, but we just haven't seen it yet.
And I don't want to overload the previous video with more content, because this one this one is a bit
strange and I'll show you why.
So we start patting 16 over here.
Right.
And we basically did that because we wanted the padding around the item to be concrete.
So if we were to create our own component here called restaurant list.
Right.
If we did contact restaurant list.
And we said that was equal to styled and then we gave it a flat list.
That didn't do anything, and if we gave it inside here, a padding of 16.
Pixels, that is well, that's 16 pixels is being applied.
But it's being applied to the holistic list, right, so it still looks right, but it's not the same
concept, really.
It's a bit different content.
Container style applies the padding to each individual element.
And so, although this looks right, it's not the same thing that we were doing previously.
In order to do that, what we would need to do is we would need to do something that is onboard style.
So we're going to leave this intact.
But right behind here, we're going to do dot press, right.
And we're going to put an object in here.
And this is the call to the function method that attributes so that attributes gives us access to give
specific props to our default flat list.
And so what we would say is content, container style.
Right.
And then we would give that an object.
We would say padding 16.
And as you can see, it's applying the style correctly to everything.
And that is the expected outcome that we were looking for.
This is exactly what we were looking for.