Now that we're looking at the end to end integration of Firebase into our code base, I can hear you
screaming from the rooftops.
No, we need a service and yes, yes, we do.
But first, we need to do a little bit more research about how we're going to integrate it into the
app.
And so if we go over here to the documentation, they even have a guide on using Firebase and they say
things like Firebase gives you the functionality, like analytics databases, messaging, crash reporting
and authentication and Google's infrastructure skills automatically even for the largest apps.
So if we look at the firebase integration with the client, they recommend using the Firebase JS SDK,
which supports authentication, the firestorm, the database, the storage functions, et cetera, et
cetera, on react native.
Other modules like analytics aren't supported, but we can easily extend that by using something like
XPO Firebase Analytics.
OK, so XPO has gone through the motions of trying to cover every possible service that Firebase can
give us.
And so with that we can go and say, hey, well, if we need to do this, how do we go about installing
it then?
Because, you know, we know throughout the past of the course that usually there's an expo command
coupled to this and try and true, they have an expo install firebase.
So let's go through the motion of running that and then we'll continue reading.
If we go over to our terminal here and we open our second terminal and we run XPO, install Firebase
while this is installing, we'll continue reading.
So the firebase console provides us with API keys and identifiers we need for project initialization.
Oh, interesting.
OK, so we're going to need a specific configuration here.
Oh we're seeing, we're seeing a use case here.
So we're an import star as Firebase from Firebase and then we're going to put together a configuration
here with all of these different.
Huh.
What are these.
Oh, an API key and off domain.
A database.
You URL.
Great stuff.
So Firebase is going to supply us with all of this information ahead of time and then we're going to
use that to initialize our app so that it can be linked back to our meals to go application that we
set up here.
So Firebase, somewhere in Firebase, we're going to be able to find this information here.
OK, well, that's that's good.
That's good.
Now, let's look at how that would work.
Is Firebase installed yet?
Not quite yet, but we'll go ahead and trek ahead a little bit.
So we know here that we're going to have to import start as Firebase from Firebase.
And so we want to inject Firebase at the right position in our application.
And so that would be the entry point, which is abcess there.
We're going to import Firebase from Firebase and we're going to also take into account the firebase
config that we need here.
We're going to declare that just before the render function.
Just before the declaration, rather, and we're also going to copy this last line, the Initialise
app, based on the firebase config, and by doing this, we now have an initialise app or do we know
this isn't the right information?
You forgot that we need to get it from our actual app.
And that's true.
So let's go over here to meals to go now.
Where would we find all of this information?
I don't I don't see it anywhere.
And so what we need to do is we need to go back to a project overview.
And if we hit this little icon and we go to project settings, we're going to end up on the settings
panel.
And so once we're on the settings panel, we can see that we have all of these different settings that
we can touch, but the one we need to focus on the most is if we scroll down right here, we have all
of this information, project ID, project number, all of this good stuff, but we haven't configured
any apps yet.
And so the app we want to configure is the third one in this.
So you can see iOS Android.
But because we're running Riak native, we want to use what is called the Firebase Web SDK and the FIREBASE
Web SDK is nothing more than just a JavaScript software development kit that will work on Riak native
like we read on the expert documentation.
So we're going to call it meals to go react native and we're going to register the app.
And once we register the app, it's going to give us all of this beautiful information in order to set
up the SDK.
So we're going to copy this bread and butter right here and we're going to paste it right in our firebase
config.
And by doing this, we now have all the information we require for the firebase package to link itself
to our FIREBASE app.
So Initialise app is going to take this config and now Firebase is going to be able to talk to the app
that we set up here originally if we go back to the console and and now when whenever we authenticate,
it's going to say, hey, do you have a user now?
We don't have any users yet for this project and we haven't said anything up other than the linking
of our Riak native app to our FIREBASE app.
But they're not really talking just yet.
They just know of each other now.
So now we want to make our app talk to Firebase and be able to get a response from Firebase.
Let's look at how we're going to achieve that.