Funny story, did you notice right down here that there's this blank space, why is this blank space
here?
Well, it comes from an early decision that we made and we made this decision on purpose because I was
teaching you how Flex works and I was teaching you how Flex works in a very, very specific way because
I didn't want to confuse you between.
Well, Flex applies here.
Flex doesn't apply here.
Flex does this flex does that flex safe area view is one of those special components that is trying
to avoid and dodge.
Right.
The areas that you can click now in order to do that, it basically has a specific overlay schedule.
And so by giving it flex one, basically what we did is we told it, hey, you're forced to be the entire
height and that kind of messed with it.
Now, if we remove flex one, you can see gone is the white little edge, and that looks way more aesthetically
pleasing on iOS specifically, right?
That's way better, but when we put it there, well, we didn't have the issue of it dodging to the
bottom here, right.
Like it actually grew with the bottom.
And so that isn't really aesthetically pleasing, but if we remove the flex one, what we'll see is
that basically now our content is dodging at the bottom.
And so what we could do to avoid that is now we could go calculate a margin bottom over here, right?
We could say margin bottom and then we could kind of go that route and then we could say five.
And that would kind of allow it to dodge the bottom.
But that really isn't dynamic in any way, shape or form.
So you're kind of stuck here with one of two options.
Either you give your safe area of you flex one, in which case everything below it can grow properly.
Right.
And everything below it can kind of properly take the shape.
And you can see here now the area has become double because of this margin bottom.
And that will allow everything to fill properly, but you're stuck with this kind of like, ugly thing,
and if you gave this background color blue, it would become even more obnoxious because now everywhere
it's blue.
But now you can see kind of where it's dodging and what it's wrapping.
And that visual piece is important.
So this is the best way that I found to render a flat list to fill the parent height.
And you kind of have to live with this area here that's going to fill in kind of white.
But to be honest, it's better that way because at least is an indication to the user in the user experience
cycle that this area is free for them to still utilize.
Now, if you don't want that, then you're going to have to remove Fleck's one from the safe area and
you're going to have to do some dynamic calculations inside of either the styles of the restaurant list
or otherwise to determine if your list has over a certain amount of items grow or don't grow.
Because what happens here is if, for instance, we said if this had only two items and we did that,
well, now at least we know that it's filling the full height.
Whereas if we removed Fleck's one here now, it's a bit weird.
Oh, look at where it's cutting off already.
Look at what?
Oh, that's that's not good.
So it's like the better of two evils, in my opinion, to render a flat list this way.
And although this on iOS is not the greatest visual, it still adds usability concerns into account
in terms of having the clickable area and not overlapping it.
And it allows your content inside to grow dynamically, which is useful.
Now, you could go other approaches and you could find different approaches online on how to render
lists dynamically with their height to fill the parent and all this stuff.
But I opt for flex.
In this case, I opt for Flex.
In the scenario, it's just the easiest way of achieving the best possible outcome for the UI.