What's next on the docket?
Well, it's good you ask, because now that we have the majority of our UI intact right here, right?
We have our search bar, we have our main content.
We have our list rendering.
Well, what's next is we need some navigation up in here.
We need to have that navigation goodness going on, which will also avoid this bar from showing up,
because with the navigation, we're basically negating the fact that this ugliness is happening.
So navigation is the next crucial piece that we will be focusing on.
Now we'll have a restaurants tab, a map tab and a settings tab, and that's what we'll be focusing
on.
So let's go through the setup.