So we said that we were going to focus on creating a tab and navigation.
OK, this is possibly the most common style of navigation in mobile apps, a tab based navigation.
And this can be tabs at the bottom of the screen below the top bar of the heather or even inside the
header.
Now we're going to focus on creating a tab navigation that's at the bottom of the screen.
OK, now it says before continuing first install reac navigation bottom tabs.
Why is that?
Well, as we said, REAC navigation is an extensible library.
So what it's trying to achieve here is it's separating out all of its core fundamentals into separate
packages so that you can only install what you need.
And so what we need right now is the bottom tabs.
So if we take this over here and we go over to our terminal.
Right.
What we can see inside of the terminal is that.
We basically need to install the package, so we'll do yard add Riak navigation bottom, perhaps.
OK, so now we're installing the bottom top navigation and now it's giving us a basic example.
Right, a minimal example of how top navigation works.
So at the root level, we need our navigation container.
Our navigation container is going to come from react navigation netiv.
And then it says Create Bottom Tab Navigator from REAC Navigation Bottom Tabs.
Interesting.
And then it's giving us an example of how to set up a home screen, a setting screen.
And then it's showing us how to create a bottom PAB navigator, interesting, so we have to return a
navigation container and then we have to put a tab navigator inside of there from this TAB Navigator,
and then we can put screens inside of their.
And we can try this out on a snack as well.
Absolutely amazing.
OK, so here's the exercise I want us to do.
What I want us to do is I want us to take this example and apply it to our code base in a way that we're
going to have a restaurants screen, we're going to have a setting screen, and we're going to have
a map screen.
I want all three of those screens available.
And I want us to create kind of the functions that are going to render those screens except for the
restaurant screen, because for the restaurant screen, we've already built out an entire feature.
Right.
We have our restaurants that screen and where I want us to build this this initial navigation example,
let's build it straight.
An app Dot Jase's.
And I thought, yes, I want us to replace the restaurant screen.
I want us to follow this example to create the tab navigation that we will see at the bottom here.
That's going to look like this.
We're going to have restaurants, map and settings.
And so by replacing this and creating this, we don't have to focus on the icons just yet.
Don't focus on the icons at all, just get it.
Rendering the tab navigation and the ability to switch will focus on the icons later on.
I want TAB navigation in its basic form now that we have everything ready for this, and then we'll
look at optimizing it and cleaning it up.