We're in real good shape now, what we need to do is, as always, we need to decide, well, how are
we going to build out the future for this navigator and with with everything we've built so far, if
we go look at our infrastructure navigators, the navigator, the navigator, the restaurant navigator,
usually they're linked to a feature in some cases.
In this case, account is linked to a feature.
And so the feature is going to be called account.
And in the account folder is where we are going to build out the majority of the code for the account
feature.
Now, inside of the account feature, we're going to define the screens folder as we've done with so
many other folders.
Right.
And also we're going to have a components folder which is going to carry our components that may be
shared across screens for this feature.
And if we go and look at what screens we need to actually build, will the screen we need to build is
the login screen that yes, this is the screen that is going to basically be the screen that will interact
with the user to login.
But we're also going to need the account screen.
The account screen is the entry screen at which the user decides whether they want to register or they
want to actually.
Login, OK, so knowing that, let's also preemptively create our register screen Dargis, and we're
going to fill these with temporary information for now.
But in any case, what we need to do inside of here is we need a couple of imports.
So we need our.
Hmm, good question.
What does the screen look like?
Let's go look at what the screen looks like so we can determine what we need.
And if I go home and I open the KPM app of Mughals to go and I quickly log out, what we're going to
see here is, OK, we need a backdrop.
So we're going to have a background image, we're going to have a background image, and then we're
going to have a small section where we have a login button and a create account button.
And we're going to have a title over here, Miles, to go.
And then at the end, we're going to add in this amazing animation of a watermelon.
Hmm.
Where do we start?
Well, let's start with the image backdrop.
OK.
Knowing that we need the image backdrop, well, we're going to need to import a couple of things.
First, let's start with CONSED account screen.
And let's let's set the scene for us to be able to actually build out what we need and let's return.
So the question now becomes, well, how do we do an image background?
And if we go to react native, what we're going to see is we're going to have a image background component.
And this is a common feature, requests from developers that they want to use a background image like
they would on the Web.
And so the image background component provides the same props as a normal image component.
But it works in a different way.
It works in allowing us to set up an image background for our app.
Now, what we're going to do here is we're going to set this up so that we can render out the background
image that is required for our account screen login screen and our register screen.
So all three screens are going to use the same image background.
Now, what I want you to do as an exercise is I want you to go here and I want you to take all of this
into account.
And what I want is I want scalable code to be created.
So I want us to go inside components and create something that is called maybe account styles, accountant
styles docs.
And we're going to create a styled component that is an image background and we're going to use it across
all three screens.
And then we're going to utilize that in order to create consistency among all three screens.
Now that is the exercise and in the next video, we'll look at what the solution looks like.