So in the end, this is what we should be able to see when we put in place our image background now
on the previous video, you will have found the resource in the resources on the video in order to get
this particular image.
But you can load any image you want, honestly, take whatever you want and use that as long as you
find that your app looks amazing.
Now, if we took a look at the code.
What happened in our recount navigator is that we set up an extra screen, so we set up an extra screen
that basically was the register screen because initially we didn't have this.
So we had a stacked on screen for Mean, which is the main account screen.
We had a stacked on screen for login, which showed us the login and we had one for register which showed
us the register and we imported these all from the feature authentication screens.
OK, so like I said, in authentication screens, we set up an authentication, not styles, but yes,
now in that styles that yes, we can set up something called an account background.
Now, you may have done this in a different way.
This is what I personally find the most optimal way to set it up.
But as long as you've got it working well, as long as you've got it working, that's what's most important.
And great job on that.
By the way, this is not easy to achieve in the particular way that I did it over here.
Now, with that said, what we want to achieve here is and if we look at the code we import styled from
styled components, Netiv, and then we set up a component called account background style dot image
background is the react native element that we wanted to target.
And so we wanted to give its particular attributes.
And we've done this in the past.
And when we target attributes, we can basically set props on the image background hardcoded.
So the prop that I want to set on the image background hardcoded is something called source, and the
source points to the image that it's going to load as the background.
And I set it to require dot, dot, dot, dot, slash and so forth to the assets folder, the home background
component, that jpeg.
And then I set it to flex one.
I gave it a background color, which is not really necessary.
You could honestly leave this out and it would still work perfectly.
I was testing some things out when I did that.
When we do a line items, however, we're trying to make sure that anything that comes inside of it
is particularly Fleck's aligned because we want to center the information.
OK, so this is the initial way that we can do it.
And then if we look at account screen, basically account screen just became an import overcount background
where we just render it out.
And then the login screen became the exact same thing where we did the exact same thing and the register
screen does the exact same thing as well.
So all of these will render this as a background and it's that simple.
And now look at how beautiful this looks.
This this honestly looks like a real application, like a real meals to go up.
We could compete with Obreht easily.
Easily, I tell you.
OK, so now that we have this in place, what I want to do next is I want to fortify our account screen
and start building it out a bit more.
So let's go ahead and do that.