All right, so looking at this example, it seems like there's two things we need to do, right?
First of all, we need to pick our icons and second of all, we need to copy paste what's here.
So we'll copy paste this entire thing in between here.
And it's going to be the easiest way for us to figure out how this is going to work.
So if we copy paste all of that and we go to the top navigator and we open it up, we can basically
piece that in between there.
And then if we save, we're going to be set up for success here.
OK, so we can see when we copy paste, first of all, that the icons aren't really matching.
So the settings icon is already broken.
That isn't really working, but what we want to do here is we want to focus on, OK, what do we need
to do?
What's going on here is on the tab navigator, we're setting the prop screen options and screen options
is returning a function that is returning an object.
This is a shorthand notation for returning an object.
This is basically the same as saying, for instance, we did this in a function, right.
Const screen options.
We could do it like this and we could say, well, it's a function that contains the root and it opened
the body of the function.
It returns an object.
This returning of the object can be done in shorthand by doing this, by returning parentheses object,
it's a shorthand for just immediately returning an object.
So.
It has a route and it's returning an object, and that object has a Tabbaa icon, and so that Tabbaa
icon is also a function and that is eventually going to return a component, an icon component.
So that's what's going on here.
OK, so knowing that we now know whether or not its focus, the color and the size and the route available
now, first of all, we don't need to know whether it's focused or not.
We're not going to be changing the icon based on the focus information.
Now, if you did do that, that's completely fine.
But for my solution, I didn't go ahead and I didn't do that.
And so, first of all, we don't have a route named home.
We have a route named restaurants.
So if it's restaurants, what we want to do here is you can go to the Expo Vector Icon directory and
you can choose an icon.
Now, I chose MDE Dash Restaurant.
That's the one that I was focusing on, and then if the route was settings, I had something called
MDE dash settings, OK?
And so if we look at that real quick, what we can see now is that we already have two icons set up
here, one for the settings and one for the restaurants, and they're changing colors as they are selected.
Now, what was the focus then for?
Well, the focus was for whether or not we wanted to change the actual icon when it was focused.
We don't want to change the icon.
We want to keep the same icon, but we want to fill it in.
OK, but we have one more tab.
So else if route dot name is equal to and then map.
And so what did I choose for this one?
Well, what I chose for this one is I chose icon name is equal to m the dash map and that's the one
that I picked and I left the of 10 color and the inactive color the same.
But you could really go and pick any color you want here.
You could for instance do this and, and have like a blue color when it's selected.
You can really play around with that.
I liked the tomato color.
I like the way it looked.
But you can customize this honestly any way you please.
And so now what we have in that simple fashion with that little code, we have TAB icons, we have TAB
icons available for every tab.
And that's absolutely amazing.
Now, let's look at a way to optimize this code potentially.