Now that we have log-in register should be a breeze, shouldn't it?
And for the most part, it will be.
What we're going to do now is we're going to go look at our authentication service and we're going to
set some things up that need to be set up in order for unregister to work.
So we're going to say CONSED on register and in unregister, we're going to see email.
Password, repeated password, and what we're going to do is we're going to call a firebase method,
which is basically firebase start off create user with email and password.
That's the function we're going to call.
Now, there's one small issue with this.
It doesn't do any password petion, verification.
So what we need to figure out here is, well, how are we going to create an error?
OK, well, let's say if password is not equal to repeated password, then we'll do set error.
Error passwords do not match and will return and exit the function, and that will allow us to check
on what exactly is occurring now over here in the create user, what password?
What we want to do is we want to use that same dot then the catch structure that we had here, because
when we register successfully will also be locked in.
Now, with that, what we want to do over here is we want to pass this on, register into the value
context, and then we can start using it.
And so with this, we basically have everything set up roughly in order for our register screen to work.
Now, what I want to do is, first of all, I want to go remove the secure here.
I have this because I copy and secure entry twice.
Secure keyword does not exist.
Do not use that.
But the secure text entry does exist.
Now let's copy paste everything that's in here and let's just go ahead and rename this register screen
because they look fairly alike.
Now, the main difference here is that register screen is going to have the repeated passwords, so
set repeated password and we're going to call this repeated password.
And then we're going to instead of taking all along and we're going to take on register and our register
is going to be passed to the button below.
Now, this is going to take email, password and repeated password, and that's going to allow us to
get the error back in case we do not have the password done twice properly.
Now we're going to need a second off input of the type password, which is going to be repeat password
as a label.
And we're going to give it repeated password as the value now, the last thing we need to do is we need
to use set repeated password and we need to put that in place over here.
Once we do all of that, what we can actually achieve over here is a fairly easy registration process
by doing this.
While, of course, we need to use the right icon here, which is mail, and then we'll do a contained
actually what did we call it over here, an account screen.
Let's let's use the same one, its account email.
So let's do that and then we're going to call it register.
That needs to be correct.
And so once we said all of these properties, what we can do now is we can do more plus one at beneath
audio, which is a syntax just to reuse the same email to register.
And we can do tests and we can do test again.
And when we hit register, oh, password should be at least six characters.
So we really got our errors back.
It was that easy.
So if we do test one, two, three and we do test, test one, two, three.
Well now when we register, we should log in.
Right.
It was that easy.
We just built an entire registration function in that many lines of code and it wasn't hard at all.
We basically set up our service.
We knew where to set that up.
We knew where to hook it up.
We knew how to do our repeated password logic.
So if we do MO plus two beneath audio and we do test one, two, three and we do test two, three for
what we're going to see here is an error.
Passwords do not match.
So we set up all of the logic.
We set up a register button, we basically copy paste of the entire login screen and tweak that a little
bit.
And we already have everything working as intended.
And if we hit the backburn, it's going to go back.
Absolutely amazing, just like that, built to full features.
OK, it took some set up on the London screen and and, you know, we have to go through some motions
over there and make sure that everything was tight.
But once we did that, we were in a good state to just build the registration function.
No muss, no fuss.
And if we go look at Android here and we quickly go inside and we say reload, what we're going to see
is that it's going to work exactly the same way.
When we load up the app, we can see over here our login screen looks exactly the same register screen
looks exactly the same.
If we do more plus two Abney audio and we then go to password test one, two, three, test one, two,
three.
We can see when we register it's actually going to log in.
Now we don't have the instant feedback yet, like it was registering for a minute, but the button was
still there.
Now that's something we need to solve for, of course.
But you can see how instantly amazing this is and how simple it was for us to achieve all of this.
OK, so now that we have our registration set up, let's go tighten up some more loose ends.