There's one more thing we need to do on Log-in register, and that's ensure that the user is being told
when something is happening.
And for that to happen, we need to grab the imploding indicator.
And when we grab the loading indicator from the off context, what we also need to grab is some type
of activity indicator.
And so what I want us to do is I want us to grab activity indicator and colors from react native paper.
And so in order to do that, we'll grab this, we'll grab our activity indicator and the colors.
And over here at the bottom, what we're going to do is we're going to say if it is loading.
Is loading questionmark, we're going to show if it is not loading, we're going to show the off button,
otherwise we're going to show the activity indicator.
And this is going to allow us to switch between the authentication button, which is going to allow
you to register and the activity indicator, which is going to show you that something's happening.
And, of course, we need to do the same on the login screen, which means we're going to need to do
the same import we did over here in the login screen.
Over up here, and then once we do that, let's grab the activity indicator from the bottom.
Right on here.
And so now will grab is loading from the Authentications State.
And with that property, what we can do over here is say if it is not loading.
Show the off button, otherwise show the activity indicator, and that will allow us to again.
Tell the user that something is going on, and if we look at what that looks like, if we refresh here,
we reload the app, what we're going to see on login is when we do know at Beeny that I'll test one,
two, three on log and we're going to see the activity indicator interoperate.
And if we look on register, what we're going to see is if we do Moule plus three Beeny that audio test
one test one, two, three, test one, two, three.
And we register.
Something isn't happening on register.
Why is that?
Well, let's take a look at that, because that's strange.