As we can see, we have a major problem right now when we log in to Mo Adine, the audio with test one,
two, three, we're loading the exact same.
Favorites for each individual user.
So right over here, we can see we're loading these favorites and if we reload and we log into to plus
to add beneath audio, we're going to see the exact same thing pop up mode.
Plus to add, we need audio test, one, two, three.
And we log in.
We're going to see the exact same favorites load.
Now, first of all, why are the exact same favorites loading?
Well, we have an issue where we're not uniquely identifying each and every favorite, we're not uniquely
identifying the favorites, and that's a problem.
But the second problem is why do we have to authenticate every time we reload?
Why isn't the session persisting?
So there's a twofold error going on here.
Our authentication infrastructure is eight percent set up, but we have a problem with the persistence
of the session.
Right.
Our user, when we reload, is technically still logged in, but for some reason we can log in again.
And then on top of that, our favorites aren't being stored against the right user.
OK, so we have to solve this one issue at a time.
And so the first issue we need to solve is we need to solve the issue of the session persistence.
And in order to do that, what we need to go look at is the way that Firebase is set up in the often
vacation context.
And over here we can see that.
Well, if we log in, we're we're doing our login or register.
All that stuff is good, but we're not checking on app load if there is actually already a session.
And so Firebase has a hook for that.
Firebase has a hook that's going to go look for off state changes.
And it's called Firebase off on state change.
And that's going to take the user object and is going to say, well, if user then set the user to user
and that's going to ensure us that, well, Firebase is going to go look, hey, did I previously authorize
someone to log in?
And if I previously authorized someone to log in, well, let's go ahead and use that user and log them
in rather than still have authentication session going on.
But allow a different user to login because that creates conflicting state.
We don't want to we don't want to work with conflicting state.
We don't want to have issues between different users going on.
So when the app boots and we set up our authentication context, let's quickly go check if there's already
a session going on, if not completely fine.
We still go to our account screen and we can log in.
OK, so now how do we log out then?
So you kind of basically broke the entire thing and now we can't log out.
Well, good point.
The way that we need to log out is kind of through Firebase as well.
And so in order to get that going, well, we need to add right here and log out function.
And I just noticed something we're missing.
A set is loading to true for the register function right over here.
And so that may cause issues.
So let's make sure that we always start loading when we register, but we need an on log out function
where basically we'll set the user to know and we'll call Firebase off that sign out because that should
always work.
It's just going to clear state so we don't need to use the dot then the catch syntax.
It will always successfully log you out.
And so because of that, now we can take this on logout function and we can pass it over here to the
value.
And we can quickly build a very simple logout function before we have our settings ready over here in
settings, we can quickly go get a button from Riak native.
And once we have this button, what we can do is we can say button title is equal to logout.
And we'll say on press.
Is equal to a function called of on logout.
Now, we don't have on logout right here currently, but if we import the authentication context.
Thought slash, slash services, slash, navigate authentication, slash authentication context, now
we'll have it.
We also need to import use context from react so that we can use the context.
And if we quickly build it inside of our settings placeholder here, we can quickly put a button in
place just to make sure that we have a full circle authentication.
So const on logout is equal to use context of and then we grab our authentication context from here.
And we'll plug it into this part.
And once we do that, well, now we can go full circle with our logout function by doing this, we now
kind of have gone full circle.
If we go to settings, we can press the on logout function and that's going to Lagus out.
Firebase no longer has a session now and we can securely log in to another account without having any
issues of potentially having conflicting state or anything like that.
And so what we want to do is say test one, two, three.
And if we log in now, we're logged in as a different user.
But we still have the issue of the favorites being persisted, even though we have different users.
So how do we solve that when we've solved one fourth of the problem, which is our authentication session
issue?
And the second fold of the problem is the favorites issue.