Now that we've solved one part of the equation, which is the full authentication flow, finishing the
full authentification flow end to end, then making sure that Firebase has full control over our session
and can properly manage our session because you never want to fix a feature when your infrastructure
is half built.
Now that we've done that.
How exactly do we fix the issue in here and so one would argue that, well, the favorite context is
broken because the favorites aren't uniquely identified in that that would be completely correct.
So the first thing we're going to do is we're going to import authentication context and we're going
to import that from dot, dot, dot, dot, slash services, slash authentication, slash authentication
context.
And once we have that, we're going to import use context.
And when we have our context here available, what we're going to do is we're going to see CONSED and
we're going to structure the user is equal to use context of authentication context.
And by doing that, what we now have is the user object.
OK, now what we need to do here is we need to uniquely identify this in some way.
Well, how do we how do we do that?
Well, we'll we'll retype at Favourite's because that part was OK.
And now we need some type of unique identifier between here in order to identify the user.
Well, we have the user object right here, so how about we use user Eweida?
How that could work?
Well, let's just put you IDM.
We don't need to do user ID and let's make that a parameter of the function the function takes in the
user identity in order to save and load the favorites.
And that way we uniquely identify the favorites at any given stage.
Now we have to go to our use effects.
And when we look at our use effects, will we have one main problem?
Load favourite's only loads when the uploads doesn't reload, when the user changes, and the same with
the favorites, it doesn't receive the favorites when the user changes.
So we have no idea here what the ideas.
So we need to add user as a dependency and user as a dependency here.
And we need to add a check to both.
If the user has a value, then we'll load the favorites.
If the user does not have a value, let's not try because we'll run into gnarly situations in that case.
And then in that case we'll add user uid as the parameter here and user UID as a parameter here.
Huh?
Would this solve it, would it be that simple?
Well, let's go take a look.
So if we go into our log function now and we log in as more beneath audio and we do test one, two,
three, we log in and we see all of our favorites.
What's going to happen here is basically when we log in, we're going to have the favorites for McGeeney,
which are these two.
But when we log out and we, for instance, register MO plus 12 at Beeny Audio and we do test one,
two, three, test one, two, three, and hit register.
Well, something is going to go wrong here because we're still loading the favorites of MO.
Why is that?
Why isn't it on mounting?
Well, let me show you, if we look at where the favorites context is loaded, it's loaded all the way
at the top around the authentication context provider.
Now, this is a problem, right, because all of these context providers are basically at the top level
and they never, ever, ever get unmounted.
Now, are they all our favorites, location and restaurant?
Absolutely necessary.
At the top level, they aren't anymore because now we have to navigator's.
So what we want to do is any time our App Navigator mounts, that's when we want these contexts to mount.
Any time the App Navigator is mounted right over here so that around the tab navigation, that's where
we want to add these.
So we'll go ahead, we'll copy these and I'll just take these and then we'll save here and we'll go
over here and at the bottom will piece these, make sure that all the navigators are there.
And what we'll do now is we'll grab all three of these, which need to be added at a lower level.
Now, they can be at the app level anymore and we're going to put them at the App Navigator level right
over here.
And what we're going to do is we're going to make sure that they're imported from the right spot, so
that's about that and we'll make sure that that's true for all of these and this one as well.
And once we do that.
Now, all of these should be imported correctly.
And if we go over here to our load function, OK, now we see that we're loading the correct ones for
the user, but now when we log out, we should see when we register a new account.
So for instance, NMO plus one twenty one, two, three at Beeny audio test one, two, three, test
one, two, three.
If we register that account, what we should see now is that it shouldn't be rendering the favorites
of more one.
And that's because the context is getting unmounted.
It's cleaning itself up.
Previously, when the context was at the app level, we were unable to clear the app context.
We were unable to clear the favorites context because it was an app level consideration.
So navigation was rendering after all of the context.
So the context never got unmounted.
The favorite context never got cleared between sessions.
So every session the favorite context would stay the same and the favorite context would say the same.
And so what we learned here is that navigation plays a vital role in where we should load specific contexts.
So at the App Navigator level, once we're logged in, that's when we should start mouthing the favorites,
the locations and the restaurants, because that's where we need that information.
When we render our tab navigation, when we render our main app, when we log out, they should be cleared.
And when they're cleared and we go back to the account screen so we load up a different navigator.
All of these are unmounted and thus their memory is cleaned.
When they were at the app level, they stayed in memory.
So now what we can see is if I do NMO plus to be Nutrio and I do test one, two, three and I log in,
what I'm going to see over here is that when I load up Mobily two, I'm going to load up Mobily 2s favourite's.
So I'm not going to load up Mobeen ones favorites.
And when I log out here and I log in to Moab Nidderdale, that's going to enable me to load up specifically
Moaveni I favorites.
So we solve that problem.
But the bug was so nesh it had to do with code structure.
It had nothing to do with the actual implementation.
It had everything to do with the way in the place that we were structuring our contexts.
So putting all of the contexts right, all of the context at the entry level is not always a good idea.
It isn't always the best plan.
We need to put the context in the place where they're needed because we were loading the favorite context
all the time and it never got unmounted, even though we were logging out, even though we went back
to the account screen.
And even though we were loading a completely different navigator in the account, navigator, right,
because we swapped them out here, we weren't clearing the state properly and that was causing issues.
Now, the best way to solve this is, of course, to put the context inside the navigator.
There are other ways to clean this up in order to make sure that you can potentially inject it at the
level.
But in my opinion, that would just be hacking around context because context should only be used in
the spots where it's necessary and when it's not necessary anymore.
You don't need to keep it in memory anymore because why would we keep favorites, locations and restaurants
in memory?
Those are a consideration of the user being logged in.
And if they're a consideration of the user being logged in, that means that when we go look at indexed,
yes, they should only ever be loaded if we're authenticated.
So they should only ever be loaded if we're loading the App Navigator and that solves our bug.
Amazing.