All right, so here I'm going to show you how I would have built a favorite screen, I hope you all
got a version working that works for you.
However, this is the model solution.
This is how I would have done it.
That doesn't mean that there aren't different ways, but I would have said const favourite's is equal
to the use context.
Of the favors context, so we would have pulled in the favorites context and we would have done that
from import favourite's context, from.
Dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, dot, slash services.
And then the favorites context, and that would have given us access to our favorites at that point.
I would have said if favourite's dot length, we're going to return something, otherwise we're going
to return something else.
And the something else we're going to return is, first of all, let's import the safe area and let's
import text as well.
And then we're going to render out in the safe area is a text where we say if you do not have favorites
yet, we're going to render out no favorites found yet.
But if you do have a length, let's just put that to no real quick.
Right over here.
We're seeing, well, a line item center justify content center.
So we're going to need a styled component here in order to make this a bit nicer styled from styled
components, Netiv.
And we're going to call this favourite's area.
Const favourite's area is equal to styled and let's call that area.
Let's take the safe area of you, let's add onto it and let's say a line items center.
And let's say justify content center.
And by doing this, we can now put in favourite's area.
Let's remove the style over here, and by doing this, we can put favourite's area here great.
No inline styles.
What do we render, though, if it has a length?
Well, that's a good question.
Let's take our safe area then at that point, because we want to render out a safe area.
We don't need to align anything and let's say safe area.
You know what let's call favourite's area.
No favourite's area.
See, no favorite area.
Let's call out because it's only when you have no favorites.
So when you have favorites, we're going to render out a safe area.
And what we're going to do is we're actually going to import our restaurant list component.
What is that component that actually well, let's go look at restaurants and let's go look at the components.
And so what we had inside of our restaurant screen was a restaurant list that came from the restaurant
lists component.
That was a flat list.
Correct.
So we use the flat list with a content container inset.
All right.
So now we need to reuse this.
How are we going to reuse it?
Well, we can export it, but we kind of want to put it somewhere nice.
Right.
So let's go over here.
So we have restaurant info, car styles.
So let's create a new file called Restaurant List DOT Component Dargis.
And although it's a style component, we're still going to call it a component because it's going to
be reused in that way.
We could also call it that styles, maybe we should call it out styles to be consistent.
So let's do that styles and let's say Export Council restaurant list and then let's import style from
styled components native.
And then let's import philatelist.
From React native, you could also do style that flat list, and by doing this now, we can go and say
restaurant list is the import restaurant list from slash components, slash restaurant list styles.
And now inside of our favorite screen, what we can say is.
Import restaurant list from the states.
And then again, dot org slash will go to restaurants, will go to component's, will go to restaurant
lists, styles.
And with this component now, we will build our view here.
So we'll say the same thing that we did over in the restaurant screen.
So where the restaurant list is, we're going to do the exact same thing.
We're going to copy this entire implementation from line forty nine.
So we'll copy that and we'll go back to our favorite screen.
And this is basically what we need right here.
So what else do we need?
Well, we need touchable opacity, so we're going to import touchable opacity.
From Riak native.
And then once we have that now, we need a restaurant.
So what else do we need here?
Well, we need to use the context for the restaurants from the restaurants context.
So let's do that restaurants context and we're going to import the restaurants context.
From the services restaurant, so restaurants, context from services, restaurants.
Restaurants that context, such as.
And once we have that one in there now, we can grab all of our restaurants and what else are we missing?
Well, we need navigation.
So our favorite screen is going to pull in navigation.
And then what we need is our spacer.
So we're going to pull in our spacer from.
Spacer spaceboy component.
Kind of building it up correctly.
And then we can pull in our restaurant in Fourcade, so we're going to do restaurant info card and we're
going to go here.
To the end, we're going to delete this part, we're going to say restaurant info, card thought, component
thought.
Yes.
Now we've built up our favorite screen based on features that we built for the restaurant screen.
So we're utilizing code in a proper way to build out a feature quickly and safely.
Now it says favourite's has already been declared.
What exactly is going on here?
Oh, this hasn't been refreshed properly.
So let's just restart this.
And once we restart it, what we should be able to see is, first of all, if we have any imports that
are incorrect, so import safe area component.
So let's go look at that.
Is our safe area coming from the right spot?
So let's just make components a safe area and this is in the favorites screen.
So let's just reload this real quick, unable to resolve all those components.
So let's just make sure that this is the correct path.
And let's do this thought out, slash, component's, slash, utility, slash safe area, that component,
and once we do that.
Let's reload here.
And we should be good to go once we go to our settings screen and we load our favorites now we can see
all of our favorites over here or can we?
Oh, I copied a bit too much code.
Like I said, we didn't need to load the restaurant, so we actually didn't need the restaurant's context.
And this can happen when you copy code.
You have to be very aware of what your data sources.
And so now when we swap it out and we go to settings, now we're rendering out our favorites.
And if we go back here and we quickly add one, what we can see over here is it's been added to the
list.
So always make sure that your data source is correct and that you're pulling the correct information
into your list.
Because as you can see, when I'm copy pasting code between features, it's very easy to have a slight
oversight line.
Twenty four caught me in my overview here in my feature overview of Favourite's, I was loading the
entire list of restaurants, not just the favorites, but with a quick swap.
We now have the correct implementation and it goes back to the restaurant view and it shows you the
detail page.
Amazing.
So looking at this now, we have a fully featured application, we can view our favorites, we can log
out, we can log in, we can register, we can view a map view of our restaurants.
We can go into the detail view.
We have the menus.
We can see what they sell.
All of that is a great feature.
We can show our favorite bar here at the top that has a nice effect.
We have the clearing of search and the sinking of search between the two places we can search for Antwerp.
And if we search for Antwerp over here, we're going to view Antwerp.
If we log out, we have this cool watermelon that's going to pop out when we register.
We have the entire registration flow set up.
We have manuell back buttons.
Just we have all the features, every single thing you could think of.
Absolutely amazing.
Now, with that, you have built the majority of focus time and now we can go and look at ways to extend
functionality.
Great job.