Hello and welcome to the section on data preparation of the advanced course on our programming.
Super excited to have you on board.
And today we've got an interesting project brief.
It's called the Financial Review.
Let's have a look inside.
You have been hired by the Future 500 magazine.
The stakeholders have supplied a list of 500 companies and would like you to create some draft visualizations
for the upcoming online publication.
They have requested the following chart a scatterplot classified by industry show revenue expenses and
profit scatterplot that includes industry trends for the expenses to revenue relationship and baulks
Plus showing growth by industry.
Note that the data set has numerous discrepancies that need to be addressed before analysis can be performed
.
All right so just short of Future 500 is a made up magazine that takes data on companies and then they
run some statistics some analysis around it and they publish interesting articles about them.
So they are after some specific scatterplot and bar charts box plots that they would like to create
.
So they've had supplied you a data set and you'll see this dataset contains 500 companies or 500 rows
each one representing a company and some financial information on them.
Industry information and so on and you'll need to prepare this analysis for them.
But this the key line here is that bottom line that the data set has numerous discrepancies and that's
what we're going to be focusing on in this section.
We're going to learn how to deal with problems in our data how to convert different types of columns
into other types of columns how to deal with factors we'll talk about the fact a verbal trap.
We'll talk about cleaning data we'll talk about replacing missing daughter and so on and what methods
you have available to you there.
So that's our main focus.
And at the end we will indeed create these charts that they're after.
So where do we get this data set.
Well to get the data set we need a browser.
And in our browser we need to go to superdog assigns dot com slash our course advanced with a hyphen
in the middle.
And if you scroll down here you'll see Section 2 data preparation.
So go ahead and download these files.
The challenge for that we looked at just now the data set is the main data set.
And bear in mind here when you download it ill have a hyphen in the name will be future high and 500
doses in the tutorials.
Mine doesn't have a hyphen so it's up to you if you want to correct that.
And then a future of half hundred.
It's a marked up Excel file.
You will see in the tutorials I will show you when we will need that file when we're talking about different
types of missing data.
So go ahead and download those and I will see you in the next tutorial can't wait to get started on
this.
And until next time happy coding