Hello and welcome back to the boss of course in our programming.
In today's tutorial we're going to continue exploring the fact variable trap and we're going to look
at a more relevant example something that will resonate with us more.
In fact something that comes directly from our dark side.
So once again let's look at our dollar sign which is fin Right here we've got some variables so we are
going to be specifically looking at revenue expenses and profit.
And let's look at a summary or let's look at last year our first of thin sure we'll see that in these
three out of them to recognize those factors.
And so ultimately what we all need to do in this daughter progression phase we're going to need to convert
these into non-factors into actual just numbers.
However dealing with these is a bit more complex.
We're going to need to know how to remove the commas the dollar signs so we're going to need some extra
functions that we haven't learned yet so we'll cover all of those in the coming sterols what we're going
to do for now is we're going to deal of profit.
And here you can see that it's not a factor right.
So we're going to pretend that it was a factor initially and then we'll learn how to deal with it.
They're just going to make this example.
It won't overcomplicate this example make it simpler for us and the Senate will allow us focus on the
facts or side of things rather than introducing new functions right away.
So let's do exactly that.
We're going to take F-in and then we're going to take the profit verbal here and we're going to replace
it with factorisation of thin profit.
So basically we're creating this artificial example for ourselves as do that.
And now let's have a look at Esther Arfin.
So here you can see that same thing as previously like if I look at this first look at the top six rows
.
If I look at the top six rows you'll see that you can't even really tell the difference.
It's actually the same.
It's got the values here just as we had before.
So if I look scroll up here those are the values same values here.
And if I look at the structure of this data set.
Now you can see that it is being recognized as a factor.
So that is the difference.
It's not being recognized as numbers anymore.
It's been recognized as a factor and so is been assigned these different levels.
There's a total of 498 levels in this factor and they're being assigned these numbers so this is these
are the numbers that are uses to deal with the factor in his back and these are the numbers that we
are seeing.
So let's say Now we want to go ahead and convert this factor into a numeric so that because now if I
look at summary for fin I'll see that profit is being recognized as a factor I don't want that.
I want to see you know I mean like here median and stuff like that I want to be able to perform arithmetic
operations of profit and so on.
So how do I convert profit her or convert this variable over here profit into a non-factor variable
.
Well the first inclination as we discussed in the press the first inclination of a novice our programmer
or somebody hasn't dealt with this issue before would be to say okay I'm going to take thin don't assign
profit and I'm going to convert to an America as an American.
And then because I already know that this is what this function returns I'm just going to write a way
put it into $50 profit so I'm going to override my existing values and print profit which are for some
reason recognized as a factor which looks like a character.
So we're going to convert it into Gnumeric and we're going to then just put it in there so far on this
line everything seems should be OK.
So if I look at this chart then what I get I get that it's a number.
It's no longer a factor.
And so now let's look at the top pros of this dataset now.
Now what we can see is a top ROSETT are completely different.
The top row the profit is $342 foran 76 the 1:48 completely different to what we had here.
Right.
So if I scroll up it has to be 8 million 550 three thousand eight hundred twenty seven dollars.
This was 13 million eight million.
So this was in the millions of dollars.
Now profit is in just the hundreds of dollars.
What happened here and moreover can we reverted back.
Well the answer to the last question is no.
The Dudus out of frame has been rude.
What have we done here.
So what we did is because we use the as numeric function instead of dealing with these values that are
the actual values that we want our is looking at the representation of the Numeration of the category
so these identifiers that are has come up with for the categories.
That's what art is applying as numeric function to and then that is now what we see in our profit and
that is what is being displayed here.
So and the worst part is that there's no way I'm going back so we'll probably that's not the worst part
the second worst part.
There's no way of going back to the actual profit figures because they're gone.
We just.
All right.
By doing this slide we've overridden our doorframe that whole column in our doorframe.
And while the worst part is that if you don't pick this up while you're dealing with it then you're
going to report on the analysts is going to report numbers to the executives or to his manager which
are instead of being in millions are in the hundreds of dollars completely different picture completely
incorrect result.
So as you can see this puts it into perspective.
This is a major issue that needs to be recognized and needs to be avoided.
So you need to avoid this pitfall and just make sure that you perform your conversions correctly and
we will practice that in the coming to Tauriel.
So for now what I'm going to do before we end this tutorial I'm just going to comment this part out
so the FBT example or in fact I'm going to comment the part out that is actually dangerous that's overriding
things so that it doesn't bother us when we really run this whole script and I'm just going to say dangerous
and same thing here and now I'm just going to run on this whole script so we do have the correct data
set with the millions of dollars here.
So when we proceed to an exit Tauriel we have the right data that we're dealing with.
Okay.
So I really hope that that puts it into perspective and you can see that's why it's important to understand
the fact variable trap and avoid it.
And in the next trial we will proceed with our data progression and I look forward to seeing you then
.
Until next time happy.