Hello and welcome back to that month's course on our programming.
Today we're going to start dealing with the fact Marable's the revenue and expenses ones and we will
learn how to convert them into nonfactor variables.
Because as we can see they are just numeric variables they contain information on doorman's so they
should be stored as such so as numeric Darroze So as we can see here profit is stored like that.
So that's what we want to do with these variables and also with the growth bearable.
So we're going to learn how to do that.
And for that we're going to need two functions we're going to need the sub and the G subfunction.
OK.
So here I'm going to type in sub and G subs So what are these mysterious functions for this call.
The question mark.
Let's have a look here.
So let's zoom in over here and what we can see here.
So Suppe is the function and g such as other function.
So what they do is they look for a pattern.
They replace it.
And then that's X is where to look for that pattern we're not going to worry about the other parts of
this of these functions.
And the difference between salbe and A-G sub is that sub replaces just the first instance supper places
all instances.
So let's have a look here and see salbe and some perform a placement of the first and all matches respectively
pattern matching and replacement.
So let's go ahead and try these functions out.
So what you want to do.
Well we're going to be actually dealing with the GI function because in our case there's no situation
where we want to just replace one instance of something.
We will be replacing the dollar sign will be replacing the Como's all of them and then comma's here
then the word dollars space and the percentage.
And so in all cases we want to replace all instances of what we find so it is going to be dealing with
sub.
So let's see how we can work with some.
Let's say we want to start with the expenses column for instance.
So what are we going to do here.
We're going to say even dollar expenses and we want to replace that with just Bob.
All right.
Here we can specify the pattern.
What parent do on fire.
We want to find this parent so space and then dollars.
So we're spaced out here and we want to replace that with nothing.
We want to replace that with an empty empty quotation marks because we want to just basically remove
it and then we're going to say Come on where do we want to find that we want to find that in thin dollar
expenses.
So once again this is the pattern that we're looking for.
This is what we're replacing it with.
And this is what we're analyzing where we search for that Paran and replacing.
So if I run this line what that just did is it is replaced all of the expenses there.
So let's go ahead and look at that top line.
You'll see that in expenses we no longer have that word dollars nor space dollars.
We don't have that.
So now we want to replace these commers or replace the commas in the expenses column.
So let's go ahead and do that.
We're going to take just a couple of slide and here I was going to say common.
If I run this and I look at the top you can see that expenses no longer has the commerce and and the
interesting thing here is if I look at SDR fin you will see that expenses is no longer a factor.
It's a character.
So that's an important thing for us.
We're going to use that to our advantage when we're continuing with this verbal.
But let's just remember that for another it's character not a factor.
And let's deal with the revenue variable.
All right.
So revenue is going to be a little bit different.
What do we want to replace in revenue one replace the dollar sign signs so let's go in.
In dollar revenue we want replace of using Giese.
We're going to replace the dollar sign.
So if I type in just dollar sign and then I say nothing.
And then I say fin dollar revenue if I run this and I look at the top what you'll see is a dollar sign
is still there what happened why doesn't it get replaced.
Well that is because a dollar sign is a special character and are as you can see we're using it here
and here and there it has its own implications.
And if you want to find a dollar sign inside of a string.
So if you want to actually address the dollar sign in its character meaning then you need to create
an escape sequence.
And now without going into too much detail the way to create an escape sequence for a dollar sign is
to put a double backslash before the dollar sign.
Inside the quotation marks.
So if I run this now and I look at Fin you'll see that the dollar sign has disappeared.
Now there are a few sort of symbols that will need a escape sequence before them.
And so basically if you run into the way to deal with it the best ways to if you run into something
like an issue like this and you are suspecting that you're dealing with a special character like a dollar
sign is a type of special character.
Well then just look up the escape sequence or just google for escape sequence for that specific sign
in are and most likely will be something similar.
So that is how we replace the dollar sign.
And now we want to replace.
Same thing we want to do for Cummins.
Right.
So there's just some coma and then with nothing and we're going to say fin dollar revenue.
So if or not I look at the top.
There we go.
So we've got revenue very nice.
So if I look at our Finegan you'll see that both of these variables on our characters rather than factors
.
And what does that mean.
That means that we'll soon be able to very easily turn them into new markets.
All right.
So what are we going to do now.
Now you can actually pause the video and you can do the same thing from growth.
So it'll be a good practice exercise if you get rid of this percentage sign on your own for Growth Other
wise if you want to continue and see how it's hungry to do it just keep watching the video and I'm going
to do it.
Actually right now.
So I'm going to go fin dollar grove and I'm going to go Geez sob.
And I'm going to look for percentage sign comma nothing.
And in when I'm going to look for a Infin dollar growth.
Yup.
So for that and I look at the top pros.
So I go head when you will see that growth no longer has upside.
So there we go if corrected are three columns revenue expense and growth.
And now all we need to do is convert them from character into a numeric.
And as you remember this is going to be much easier than converting from a factor into a numeric because
basically what we just did remember this part where we had a factor and we had to first converted into
character and then we could only convert into an America right.
So when the factor variable trap well.
Using the Jizo function to replace things.
What we actually already did is we did that transitional step we completed this step instead of using
just as character we use g sub which perform some conversions and sub actually did that conversion.
And apart from replacing stuff it what it did is actually converted the factor into a character for
us.
So basically this step has already been done and that's why we seen characters here.
All we have to do is now apply that has numeric function.
So in this case it was like it's a bit concealed but we're still doing that same method.
We're still first converting to character.
The factors being converted to character and then is being converted into a numeric.
So now we're going to do that Spenser's right.
So if I on that that should be it.
And I'm just going to be a bit lazy and change this to revenue and this to revenue.
This is going to be Grove.
All right so far on this.
Now I can look at Fin so I can see that it's American-American numeric.
It doesn't matter that this is integer.
That's pretty much the same thing it just means that it's more specific that there's no doubles in there
or anything like that.
And here we're going to look at summary for thin.
So if you look at summer 15 you can see that is beautiful.
Now all four of these variables revenue expenses profit and growth are being recognized as actual numeric
variables which is exactly what we wanted.
We can now deal with them as they are.
So just to recap we did follow the same process which we discussed here where a factor variable has
to be first converted into character.
And then it can only be converted into numeric to avoid the factor of arable trap.
In our case because we used the subfunction to replace things.
This is already incorporating our conversion into character.
And then we are converting the same variable using as numeric function into an actual numeric.
So that's how this works and that's how we avoided the fact variable trap.
In this example and I hope you enjoyed this tutorial.
I know it was a bit of coding this time but definitely worth it.
We got an all variables as we want them and I look forward to see you next time.
Until then happy Cona