Hello and welcome back to the course in our program today we're talking about dealing with missing data
so missing data is a very common theme in data science or analytics and it happens because data set
sometimes not full or there might have been some errors while it was being supplied or somebody forgot
to put something in or just basically that data was not collected in the first place.
So dealing with missing data is important.
You need to know what options you have and what approaches you can take in order to fix the data or
maybe not fix the data and what you do.
Every different case today will quickly overview.
What exactly are those options that you have.
All right.
So option 1 is the best option when you can predict the missing data with 100 percent accuracy and we'll
see examples of this in our tutorials in this section.
For instance if the field for a state is missing but you know that the cities New York will in that
case you know for sure that the state is actually also New York.
Right.
Or if the city is San Francisco and the state is missing then the state is actually California.
So things like that or for instance another good example is where you have two variables and you can
derive the third variable based on that.
So for instance if you know revenue and expenses but the field for profit is missing well in that case
it's very easy to derive profit because profit is actually a sequel to revenue minus expenses assuming
that there's no issues in the data that was supply originally and that there were no errors or there
was no fraud then that is a calculation that you would perform.
So that is the best case scenario when you can't predict the data 100 percent accuracy and then it's
as if you never had any missing data then the next option is to leave the record as is.
So don't change anything about it just leave that cell empty.
And when we use this well this approach would work.
If for instance that specific field is not important for our analysis and we'll see an example of this
if the field is not important for analysis then doesn't really matter that it's empty.
The other option is that if the algorithm that you're going to be applying your data set and this is
a bit more advanced if the algorithm you're going to be applying it actually already incorporates some
methodology is to account for missing data and to correct that inside the algorithm.
And in that case also leaving the record is OK because the competition on method will take care of it
.
Next is remove the record entirely so sometimes you're missing some critical data.
And in that case when you cannot restore the data the only option that you might have left is to completely
remove that whole row from your analysis in order to keep your analysis.
So nerd's keep your algorithms working or keep your approach working.
You have to remove this one record.
And this has a drawback.
The drawback here is that your analysis becomes less significant or has a smaller sample and that can
have certain implications.
So if you're fine of sacrificing a few rows here and there and it's not critical for you to have information
and every single record then this could be another approach that you might apply.
Next one is a replace with the mean or median.
This is a very popular approach and we're going to also see an example of this in our data set in our
tutorials this is going to be one of the main approaches we're going to be relying on.
And so basically here you can say that if for instance you have lots and lots of browes and they all
have a certain value for revenue and that one row is missing that value then you can calculate the mean
or the median and put it in there and then proceed with your analysis.
So I mean is an ok option but usually median is preferred because median is less affected by outliers
.
All right.
So that's another approach.
And then we've got to fill in by exploring correlations and similarities so that's kind of a step up
from mean or median where you can actually create regressions or you can create different models that
will find your data set predict what the values for those empty cells could have been.
So that is an extra step up from mean or median.
And finally introduce a dummy variable for missing this.
This is a very interesting approach where we actually introduce new new bearable and where some data
is missing.
You give it a yes flag when it's not missing you know no flag and you can and you explore the correlations
of that variable with the outcome that you're looking for.
So this is also a more advanced approach and we won't be looking at it in these tutorials.
All right so now let's have a look at our actual data set and see what the data is missing in there
is going to be quite an interesting exploration.
So I'm going to move to the data set and zoom in a little bit here and here you can see the same exact
data as we see in our blood.
It's actually an Excel because here I could color it nicely and show you around.
All right so here's the data set.
And let's go from left top to bottom left to right.
So what do we have here.
We've got employees right.
So in this case what we can do this missing daughter so the red represents missing data.
What we can do here is we can replace or proxy it with the industry median.
So I'm going I'm going to do is I'm going to as we go through this I'm going to show comment.
So here we can't just proxy of the industry media we can take the median for this whole column and just
put it in there and because we have this classification by industry we can simply look at only the companies
that are in retail and that we will get an even better approximation than if we took the whole media
for the whole role and also median is better because if we took them mean then there are some outliers
here so companies that have 1500 employees and there's another company here as you can see there's also
a few more missing values as you scroll through the data said there is a company here with even more
employees.
But basically that's the point that some outliers with huge numbers of employees will skew the mean
.
But with the median.
They won't affect it that much.
OK.
So what else do we have.
Well let's proceed to industry then in this case what can we do here.
Here we can either keep it empty right or we can research the value or we can remove the line entirely
and in our case industry is an important factor for or an important variable for our analysis.
So in our case we're going to assume that we current research the value so we're going to just remove
the records with the missing industry then Inception or the year when the company was formed here which
you can do is you can either keep it empty or research it or remove lines of industry and burn my hair
you countered proxied you can just take the average or the mean value for the inception for all the
other companies because that doesn't work that it's not it's supposed to be a numeric value it's actually
more of a it's more of a category so you can just take an average of the year of Inception put it in
here.
So you either research it or you just remove the line keep it empty.
In our case it's not going to be that much of an important variable so we're going to just keep this
line as it is.
All right State what can we do if said well this is that example that we talked about that here.
This can be corrected with 100 percent certainty we can say that the state is New York here and this
is another example that here with 100 percent certainty we can calculate that the expenses is the revenue
minus profit so we know that profit is revenue mind's expenses if we solve that equation for expenses
we get expenses equals profits so we can easily calculated here.
And then we've got a line here where we've got the revenue expenses and profit.
All three are missing.
So what can we do here.
And actually Graaff is missing as well.
What can we do here we can proxy all of these with industry medians so we would proxy the revenue of
the industry median.
Expensive was with the industry median the profit would have to calculate because once we know our own
expenses profit is 100 percent certain and grow food also proxy with industry medium.
So this is how we deal with different missing elements in our data as you can see we're applying different
approaches in different situations some place we get proxy some places we can predict or find out to
100 percent certainly some places we just have to remove the rose and some places we can keep them.
So it all depends on your understanding of the data set and the methods that you're going to be applying
for analyzing it.
And then once you know all of that then you can make these judgment calls on what is going to be replaced
what is going to be kept.
All right so that's our overview of missing daughter and we're going to get started on all of this in
the next tutorial and I look forward See you then.
Until next time happy coding
.