Hello to welcome back to the advanced course in our programming.
In the previous tutorial we talked about the which operator and we learned how to filter our doorframe
four rows with non-missing daughter and I hope that you had a chance to play around with what we learned
previously.
Because ultimately this is what the Course is about.
It's about getting as much hands on experience as we possibly can in order to practice the things that
we're learning and to remember them better.
And as a quick creep cap on what we did learn last time is we talk about the which operator.
And we found that if we're filtering our doorframe for a certain column for instance here we're looking
for all companies in our data set with 45 employees and if that column has any values then in our subset
that we're creating will get these mysterious rows with names across the whole row.
So there's one and there's another one.
Now in order to avoid that what we learn to do is that if we apply the which function to our filter
as we can see there it is being applied there.
Then we will completely avoid these and a rose and we will get a very pretty subset of our data that
we are after.
So today we are continuing this two part series and we are talking about using is not a name for filtering
missing data so we're basically talking about the opposite.
How do we pick out rows from our data set.
How do we subset rows that do have an ace.
So let's have a look at what we're talking about.
Let's look at head fin and let's say we look at the top 24 rows and what do we have here.
Well here we've got an A's here we've got a NA's and a some missing values missing values.
So let's say that I would like to pick out from my whole data set from a whole doorframe.
I'd like to pick out all of the rows that have a missing value in the expenses column.
How would I do that.
Right.
Well we actually already know that we can't just compare something to in any way but let's say hypothetically
we forgot that because we skipped one of the previous tutorials or this is just our first inclination
what would we do.
Well the first inclination is to go finial assign expenses.
This is us creating a filter equals and a.
And then we would take this filter and would put it inside our doorframe common nothing.
So just like you would over here fin Dolin please equals 45 comma nothing here which is safe in Dola
expenses equals and a.
So let's have a look at this what will happen over here.
Well let's first look at the filter.
What does it feel to look like.
Aha.
So it's not just true false it's actually all all all N.A. and that is exactly what we talked about
previously that you cannot compare anything to and and a because the result will always be an A.
And essentially Naturally if you run this filter run this subset now you get a very beautiful picture
of 500 and A's or 500 rows of A's and yes so that is not what we're after.
Definitely not helping here at all.
And as we recall that is something we have already been prepared for.
Once again we cannot just compare anything to and anay has to be a different way.
What is that other way that we can finally find these rows that we're after these rows with and A's
in expenses.
Well that other way is through a function spatial function that has been created.
This code is dot and a.
And this function checks if something is and a as simple as that.
Similar to functions like is that character is not integer is not numeric and so on.
So let's have a look at how it works on a simple example.
Let's say we have a vector a vector a of the following values that say one twenty four five hundred
forty three then and they and then seventy six forty and and then again.
Right.
So there is a vector.
And now if we apply is anay to victory or do we get we get false false false true false false true.
So exactly what we were after it's telling us where these energies are sitting.
And now we can use this function to our advantage.
We can go ahead and apply it to our dataset so basically we are going to do the same thing as we did
here but we're going to use a function instead of that equals sign so we're going to get rid of this
double equals we'll say is Dawnay brackets X fin expenses.
Run that here you can see we get false hopes also false true false false also holds true and so on.
So we're singling out these days and that's exactly what we need for the filter so now we can simply
take this replaces equals sign filter with this new filter new and improved filter.
And if we run this we get the exact rows that we are after all these three rows have and NA's in the
expenses column.
So there we go.
It's as simple as that.
Picking out Rosbif.
I highly encourage you to practice this so just maybe pick a different column that we know that has
a name or maybe we don't even know it has a name and maybe try finding those names and see if you can
pick out columns that or rows that have names.
For instance let's try the state column.
Can you pick out the rows that have a missing values in the state column.
Using this method and I'll see you on the next tutorial.
And until then happy coding