Hello welcome back to the advanced course in our programming.
Now that we know how to single out rows with missing values.
Today we are slowly going to start working on our data set to either correct these values remove them
or make other decisions about them.
And specifically today we're going to be removing records with missing data.
So let's first go back to our Excel spreadsheet and see which records we agreed that we need to remove
.
So the ones that we want to remove are the ones in the industry column because let's say hypothetically
and as you'll actually see further down in the section we do need the industry column for our analysis
so we can just keep them empty or.
And in this case we can research the values for these companies because they're actually imaginary companies
so these two options don't work for us.
The only option that all is just keep those Let's just say that we're doing this option we're removing
the lines.
And that's what we're going to be working on today we're going to be removing these lines.
And just a quick note for Inception.
We don't we're not going to be relying heavily on this information in our analysis so we're just going
to keep the value empty here.
So let's go ahead and work on this industry on these rows of empty values in the industry column.
Back to our.
And first things first whenever you're working with Datto whenever you clean up a data set.
My biggest recommendation to you is always make a backup because we've done quite a lot of work so far
and as you could see here and sometimes we had to rerun all of these lines.
So let's just make a backup of our current data set as it is so that you know if anything goes wrong
we can always restore it from this point.
So we're just going to say fin back up and then we're going to say fine.
Simple as that.
And that one line can save us a lot of trouble.
There we go.
Now we've got our back up ready in here and now we're going to look at these rows that we are interested
in.
So how do we find these rows.
First of all let's look at all of the rows that have some empty values so we're really not to do that
complete cases comma nothing.
And here is going to be fin around that you can see that we've got all of the rows that have an empty
value somewhere in one of the columns.
And so we only have two rows in the industry column that have empty values and we're going to need to
work with them.
Of course we could just look at these rows based on their IDs so we know that the ID number here or
we can look at the wrong number and or the name of the company we could work with like that.
But there is a better approach because we do know this is a function we can single out these rows by
themselves.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we'll say fin is dot NA and we want to check the industry column.
Right.
So comma nothing.
So we want to see which rows have something empty in the industry column.
There we go.
So there are our two rows number 14 and 15 or IDs 14 and 15.
And now what are we going to do is we're going to simply take the same line and we're going to take
the opposite.
Right.
So we're going to say which rows are not empty in that specific column.
So are we taking the opposite way around that you can see that if we scroll up up up up up and we look
for our rows we'll see 10 11 12 13 and then 16 17 18 19.
There we go.
So those two Thoreau's have been removed in this representation.
And now all we have to do is go and sign it back into fin.
So that's how you remove Roe So you first create the subset and then you override the previous doorframe
with that subset.
And now if I look at fin you'll see that if you scroll up to the top so scrolling scrolling scrolling
.
And here we see that 12 13 14 15 or so 14 15 are missing.
And that's exactly what we wanted we have subsided our doorframe.
So there you go.
It's as simple as that to remove the rows.
And we do have that back up in case we made a mistake somewhere.
And now if we just look at our complete cases or look for our names you can see that we have dealt with
two rows already.
They're not in this industry.
Call me Concini and A's and slowly we are going to get through all of them.
OK Popinjay's Tauriel and I look forward to seeing you on the next one.
Until then happy coding.