Hello welcome back to the advanced course in our programming I hope you enjoyed the previous section
.
And today we've got another exciting challenge ahead of us.
We're talking about weather patterns.
Let's dive straight into it.
You're working on a project for a meteorology bureau.
You have been supplied with a daughter for four cities in the U.S. Chicago New York Houston and San
Francisco.
You are required to deliver the following output.
Before we jump to the outputs Let's have a look at the data set because otherwise it's going to be hard
to understand the outputs.
All right so let's quickly proceed to the data center and we'll come back here.
All right so where is the data set as usual.
It's at super data science dot com slash are of course one word HIF and advanced.
If you scroll down here you will find a section for Applied family a function the challenge and then
the weather data that's what you need to download and this time it's a zip file.
So there's a few files in there and that's why they've been zipped together.
And once you download it and open it up this is where to look like.
So it's got eight files in total four cities and two files for every city.
So let's have a look at them like this we won't even open them because on a Mac you can do this which
is quite convenient.
So for instance there's Chicago with Celsius all the European system so the metric system not the empirical
system we've got Celsius Celsius millimeters days of precipitation and hours of sunshine so we've got
five metrics that are being observed.
And then we've got every single month of the year.
So what is this actually before we describe what it is.
I'm going to show you the Fahrenheit one so this is the empirical system we've got the aincha inches
here and we've got Fahrenheit in terms of temperature.
And even though personally I'm used to Celsius in this section I'm going to switch around because all
the time in this course in my course as we talk about Celsius and we talk about millimeters and so basically
the metric system.
And I thought you know what this time I'm going to do a favor to those students who are from the US
because you know they've had to cope with all of these metric terms all the time so maybe for once we're
going to work with Fahrenheit and inches so and the tutorials I'm going to use the Fahrenheit versions
feel free to use either just stick to one which have on issues either Celsius or Fahrenheit and just
use that.
But if you want a full to follow long and tutorials exactly like I am doing it then use the Fahrenheit
ones.
And good news for those who are from Europe.
You'll be in the same boat as me where I'm not that comfortable with these terms anyway.
But still we'll be able to do that.
Alisyn.
All right so let's discuss this file for instance.
This is Chicago and it's got Fahrenheit.
The average high right.
So what does that mean.
That means that within many many years which is I think from memory it was from 1962 2010.
So three of these data sets all three of them so choose Chicago Houston and San Francisco are measured
or was 19.
No it was in 1982 2010.
So that 30 year period and New York was 1962 to 1992.
So also a 30 year period.
But basically what they did is they measured the highest temperature in January for those 30 years and
then they said OK so what's the average of the highest temperatures in January for those 30 years.
And it turned out to be 32 degrees Fahrenheit.
So be careful.
Fahrenheit here it's not that hot.
It's about zero in Celsius.
So then they did this in February March so every time in those 30 years it took July of 30 July months
and out of them they said What is the highest temperature every time in July and then they said OK what's
the average of that.
And that's how this number came to be.
Same thing for the next row.
Oh they took for instance here they took May it took 13 months of May they said what's the lowest temperature
every time in May.
And then they took the average of those.
So you kind of see how on average the temperature changes throughout the year.
So the maximum temperature per month and the minimum temperature per month then precipitation in inches
.
Same thing.
So what was the average What was the precipitation.
How much rainfall was there in every one of those that say August 30 times.
They took three months of August in a row.
How much per station was there and then they said again what's the average.
The same thing with days of precipitation how many rainy days were there.
This one is easier on how many rainy days were there in October in Chicago over 30 years.
Right.
And then they said on average how many it's about 10 rainy days and on average in October so if it's
October in Chicago right now and you're watching this then expect to have about 10 rainy days hours
of sunshine.
Same thing how many hours of sunshine was there in February.
So 30 February's in a row.
And then what's the average 36 hours.
So that's how all of these data centers are structured propitious often like this.
So there's there's Chicago there's Houston right so you can see right away where more sunshine and also
a lot more precipitation which I was not expect.
Never been to Houston but interesting new york.
While New York's got the record for precipitation out of all of them or for the rainy days something
some were there and then also you've got San Francisco with the most shiny or sunny days.
So we got 330 hours here which is probably the maximum and we'll we'll get all of these things throughout
this challenge.
All right so hopefully now you're a bit more comfortable with the data sets that we have.
And now I'm going to go back to the challenge so that now we're there we can look at what's required
of us.
All right.
So what is required.
You're required to deliver the falling outputs at table showing the annual average as of each observed
metric for every city.
So we need to average out you know how we have the monthly metrics although we have the metric split
by month we need to average them out for every city.
And so we'll say for Chicago the average days of precipitation out of the ones that we saw is this.
And then we need to create a table.
So we'll have metrics and we'll have the cities in that table so it'll be like kind of a matrix see
.
It's interesting how they say how they say how Kyrle road here table and not a frame or matrix so we're
going to have to actually decide that for ourselves a table showing by how much temperature fluctuates
each month from minimum to maximum in percentage terms take minimum temperature as the base.
This might sound a bit confusing but basically what we know the minimum so we know the average minimum
for January we know the average maximum for January.
So what's the difference between them and divide that by the minimum because we take the minimum as
the base.
Right.
So we'll we'll discuss this more in the clause.
But it should kind of make sense.
So basically what's the relative fluctuation in temperature for every city between the minimum and the
maximum throughout the year.
Next a table showing the annual maximums of each observed metric for every seat.
So it's pretty much the same as the first deliverable.
But here it's maximums there's averages and the fourth deliverable is annual minimums and you'll see
why they comes third and fourth instead of second and third because it's harder to get to them.
It's there's pre-built functions to do this.
We'll do it very quickly will be very easy.
But then this it'll take us pretty much till the end of this section to learn how to do something like
that and not that that is the goal of our section to learn how to drive these maximums and minimums
.
It's just that the techniques that we're going to be learning about apply functions only quite sophisticated
techniques will allow us to get to these values.
And finally a table showing in which months the annual maximums for each metric were observed in every
city.
So and this is going to be a very advanced tutorial you'll see that it's actually towards the end of
the section actually has a label advanced because in this specific case we're going to need to use quite
a lot of different combinations.
And if you get to that tutorial if you successfully completed then my congratulations to that means
you've mastered this section in its entirety.
But you know it's quite a long way away.
We've got a lot to learn before then.
So I'm looking forward to going through this section and it's going to be a lot of fun and definitely
we're going to learn a lot of new techniques and tools which are very powerful in our.
And on that note I look forward to seeing you on the first tutorial.
Until then happy coding
.