Hello.
Welcome back to that course in our programming in this tutorial we're going to finally start learning
how to use the Apply function in art.
So let's jump straight into it.
The first question I want to ask is What is the Apply function.
So let's bring up the Help for this function.
And if I open this one here and we zoom in a bit you can see that the function has a falling structure
.
So the word apply X margin and fun fun.
The third argument is the function that you want to apply to your matrix X and margin is specifying
where they want to apply to the columns or you want to apply it to the rows.
Or you can even apply to the rows and columns.
So here you can see that for a matrix one indicates the rows.
So if you want to apply a certain function like that say the average find the average of CRN rows of
all the rows then you'll say 1 in place of margin.
You want the average for columns you'll say two in place of margin.
And also you've got these optional arguments which if fun requires optional arguments you can pass them
on after as additional arguments for the play function.
And here you can see that also a side note that in cases of functions like plus and matrix multiplication
subtraction division all those functions that don't have a name are actually have a symbol instead.
Then they must be backordered or quoted.
But we will be delving into those kind of operations in our tutorial so we won't stop on that.
That's more of a side note for us.
OK.
So there is our apply function how do we use it.
Let's get some hands on practice.
So we're you're going to say apply and then we're going to apply this to our Chicago matrix.
So what do we want to do.
We want to apply and want to look at the average for our Chicago matrix so let's just run Chicago first
here.
Here you can see that it's got five rows and 12 columns.
We want the average for every row.
How do we do that.
Well we specify the matrix here.
Then we want to specify that we want to apply something to all the rows.
That means one.
One stands for rows and then we want to tell the Apply function what exactly it is that we apply and
we're applying the average function which is called Mean.
Now we don't need any brackets after mean in the specific case when you're just passing the name of
the function.
So if you run that there you go as simple as that.
So you got five rows that's where you are five results for every single roll you've got the average
.
So we've got the average of those temperatures the average high temperatures in Fahrenheit is fifty
nine point three.
The average of the average low Fahrenheit temperatures which I hear is 43 five and so on.
All right.
So that makes sense.
And you can always just quickly spot check this.
Let's check it.
You can say mean and then you just choose one of these rows and run it for that.
So let's say Chicago here we're going to say let's look at the Rose which is called days with precipitation
and coma nothing.
So if I run this line you'll see that the average for this row if you calculate separately is nine point
nine 1:06.
And here it was also calculated as 9.9 1 6.
So everything seems to be running smooth.
Awesome.
Now let's analyze one city in a bit more detail what other functions can reply.
That's where the word apply comes from because we're literally saying what other functions can we apply
to this matrix.
So there it is Chicago right.
What other functions can't blind.
Well obviously we can look at the max right.
So does that apply.
Chicago won max.
So that's the maximum values and you can see here that is indeed 84 is the maximum 68 was the maximum
in this call and this row four point thirteen was the maximum in this row and so on.
And then we went to apply same thing Chicago by want to apply the minimum.
So this will tell us what the minimum Nitro was great.
Now we're going to do the following thing just for practice because it doesn't really make sense in
our specific case but we're going to look for the maximum in every column.
Right.
It doesn't make sense here because this type of matrix is more kind of actually is more of a doorframe
and kind of flipped out a frame where every column or every row here is kind of a separate metric that
really can't so it's either this foreign high temperature or in precipitation in inches or days of precipitation
it should really be comparing them across each other doesn't make any sense whatsoever.
But for practice purposes we're going to do that.
We're going to just see what the maximum or minimum in each of the columns is.
So let's go ahead and do it.
How would we do that.
Well I would just say apply.
And also Chicago then will say to which is for columns two stands for columns and I'll say Max Right
.
So there we go.
Of course it has picked up this whole row as Max because it's over 100 and the rest are under 100.
And then you can do the same thing.
And just a minute.
So I'm just going to say it doesn't make much sense.
But good exercise.
So just remember that this was an exercise.
All right.
And now are we going to do is we're going to get a little bit closer to what we are.
We've been asked to deliver it right so we're going to compare some cities side by size.
So let's take this line that we have here.
Chicago with the average cop here a few times.
So here we're going to change this to New York.
And here we are going to say Houston and here in San Francisco.
All right.
So now if I were on these lines let's just run them all one by one.
One two three four.
You'll notice that we've come up with something very similar to what we are officer.
So we are officer a representation of annual averages of every metric for every city.
So we want to find.
So like let's have a look at Chicago so we need the average for this row.
The average for this show average for every single road.
So that would be for Chicago.
And when you compare them across the different cities and that's exactly what we have here.
So here in Chicago we get average for every single row.
New York we've got the average Houston average San Francisco average.
So already here visually.
Right now we can compare and we can say OK the average high Fahrenheit temperature was the highest in
Houston.
Right.
Annual average average of average is actually then low.
So the average of this column annually was the highest Where was it in.
Also in Houston and the lowest was in Chicago.
And then the precipitation the highest was in Houston as well.
Days with precipitation.
Interesting result.
It was actually higher in New York.
So more rainy days and hours of sunshine here you can compare and you can see that in San Francisco
is the most sunshine.
Now this isn't of course the final result.
We're very close.
We can already compare these.
Right now we could have used something like see bind to bind these into matrix to get our final result
.
However we will instead progress through the section of the course and you'll see that there are more
methods that are available to you in your arsenal and that can get you to that final result that we're
looking for much quicker.
So here I'm just going to say let's make a comment here step away a bit and we'll say so this is deliverable
one but there is a faster way.
Right.
So actually say nearly says not the final deliverable.
It's very close and further down in the course in the section of the course we will find that there
are other ways to get to what we are after.
All right.
So hopefully this illustrates how powerful the Apply function is and we'll actually talk more about
that in the upcoming tutorials and I'll see you next time.
Until then happy coding.