You finished this course,
congratulations,
you did an awesome job.
But the thing is, with finishing this course,
you did the first big step
but actually, there are additional steps that you could take now to become a real CSS expert. Now which
steps could these be?
Let's have a look.
Now obviously, it's always about practicing, practicing and more practicing. In this course,
we already gave you plenty of opportunities to practice the things you learned but it never ends.
You should also try to build your own web projects, maybe clone popular web pages, like the Emerson product
page,
things like that, where you try to implement the page you're seeing with the features or with the concepts
you learned in this course.
Additionally, you should also dive into more advanced CSS topics. In this course, we cover it all
but there's always more you can learn.
You should dive into the Mozilla Developer Network which we reference a lot in this course or into
blog posts which explain advanced usages, concepts, things that go beyond the scope of this course or
beyond what you learned here,
patterns you might not have seen before,
this is also something where you can grow as a developer. And last but not least, if you got CSS down
but you didn't have a look at Javascript yet, learn Javascript
because with HTML, CSS and Javascript, you got everything you need to build amazing front-ends and
front-end web applications.
Definitely and that's actually the final important thing
we wanted to add right here because in the end, if you finish all these things or dive into all these
topics Max mentioned, you will become a CSS expert and also a web development expert
in the long term and therefore as said before, it was a pleasure to have you as a student and we hope
to see you in other courses.
Yes definitely, see you there hopefully,
bye.