Welcome to this course,
it's great to have you onboard.
My name is Maximilian Schwarzmüller
and I'll be your instructor in this course. Now in this course, you will learn everything about CSS,
Cascading Style Sheets.
We'll have a closer look at what CSS is in the next video,
but you will learn it in this course from the ground up and not just in theory, we'll build an entire
course project with CSS. We'll start with the basics and gradually enhance it with more and more
CSS features.
Now I'm working as a freelance web-developer and therefore, I work with CSS day-to-day.
I can tell you that getting started with it is easy but it also offers a lot of features which can be complex,
but which also allow you to build powerful websites.
Now I'm not teaching the course alone though.
Who am I? I'm Manuel, I'm also a web developer and together with Max,
we are Academind and our goal is to teach you how to become a web developer.
For that, you will dive into the practical side of CSS
throughout this course. As Max told you, we will create a real-world project but
in addition to this, you will also have assignments, quizzes and a lot more to really understand
the theoretical concepts behind CSS; because applying it is one thing, but you also have to understand
the 'why'. With that approach, you will be able to confidently apply CSS in your own projects
after finishing this course. You don't need to be a designer,
you don't need to understand CSS or JavaScript,
the only thing you'll need is some basic HTML knowledge. With that, let's jump into the course right
now.