So welcome to another module with me again, Max.
Now that we worked a lot on the look and feel of our page, on the responsive design and that Manuel
ensured that
you learned how you can do that, how you can adjust your page to different device sizes and screen
sizes,
now that we got all of that out of the way,
let's dive back into adding some content to our demo page here
and let's add some content which is basically available on almost any webpage you see; forms and form
elements, elements where users can input data, be that an email address, a password or anything like that.
So what's inside this module?
You will learn how you can style inputs and buttons,
we'll have a look at different kinds of inputs and how you can adjust their look to fit the overall
look of your page or the look
you basically want to achieve.
We'll also have a look at validation styles,
so how you can give the user feedback about whether a value entered into a field is valid or not, how
you can give such feedback to the user by changing the way the input looks, for example by adding a red
border or something like that.
That's what we'll dive into,
so why don't we just start and have a look at all these things starting with the next video.