Welcome to this module. So we're diving deeper and deeper into CSS,
so right now is the time to have a look at a really special property, the position property which as
the name says right here, allows us to change the position of elements on our website because so far, we've
worked with the display property for example and we saw that this allows us to change the default behavior
of the way our elements are displayed,
so block level, inline and inline block for example
but with the position property, we can really change the actual position of an element on our website.
So what will you learn throughout this module?
Well, we will first of course understand the position property, how it works, what it does and why we can
use it to,
well as I said, position the elements on our website.
After that, we will learn how to create fixed navigation bars with a specific value for this position properties,
the fixed value. After we understood and apply this fixed value, we will learn another property in connection
with the position property, the so-called z-index which will allow us to position our elements along
the z-axis on our website.
Why this is important and really helpful, we will find out all that in this module. After we've worked with the
z-index, we will have a look at two more values that we can apply to our position property because
so far, we had a look at the fixed value
but then it's time to have a look at absolute and relative.
We will have a look at these values standalone and in combination because as it will turn out, there
are some nice situations where the specific characteristics of these values can be easily combined to make
positioning a lot easier. After that, we'll have a look at the last value,
the sticky positioning. Just like fixed, absolute and relative,
this is also a value that can be applied to the position property and this is a rather new value,
so we will see that there are some limitations when using it but having a look and that general understanding
of it definitely makes sense.
After that, we will wrap up this module with the so-called stacking context.
This is something that is connected to the z-index and this is a concept we might not use on a
daily basis but understanding the theoretical concept behind it is definitely important and can make
your lives a lot easier if you work with the position property.
And this is actually what you will learn throughout this module,
so why don't we just start right now and have a look at the position property,
what is that actually?