Welcome to this module.
So we added Javascript to our project,
now it's time to dive into responsive design because until now, we are working on our website,
we are adding style to it and the look improves more and more
but the problem is that we are only focusing onto the desktop version of it. Nowadays
a lot of users will visit your website from mobile devices.
Therefore it is really important to ensure that our website looks awesome on both, mobile devices and
desktop devices and to achieve this, we need to implement a responsive design. As the name already indicates,
a design which adapts to the device
our website visitors are using.
So in this module, we will have a look at the difference between hardware and software pixels because
there is an important core concept behind it which we need to understand to ensure that our website
scales correctly to a desktop or a mobile device. We'll also have a look at the viewport meta tag in HTML.
Well, this is a CSS course but this is a really important meta tag we have to add and understand to
be able to create such a responsive design,
therefore we'll have a closer look at that
and finally, we'll have a look at media queries and how we can add them to our code with @media. And
with the combination of these tools and these concepts, we should be able to turn our nice desktop web
website into a really cool responsive website.