Welcome to another module. Let's dive deeper into CSS and if we were to give this module a lot different
title, it would probably be working with boxes
and after this module, you'll also know why. Specifically we'll dive into the box model,
a core part of CSS, really easy to understand thankfully but really important to know too, so that
is what we'll start with.
We'll then have a look at how we can actually change the height and width of elements,
we'll have a look at the display property which helps us with layouting our page and positioning elements
next to each other for example and we'll also dive into properties worth to remember. I mentioned that
there is this complete reference of properties and CSS features which you can always consult if
you want to dive deeper but there is a common set of properties you work with a lot,
so I want to share some of the properties I personally find to be the most important ones.
And finally, we'll have a look at these pseudo classes and elements I already mentioned in the last
core section,
now we'll learn what they are and what you can do with them.
So with that, let's just get started and let's continue working on our webpage.