So we already had a look at quite a lot of SASS functionalities,
We worked a lot with variables and there's one thing which might have come to your head, to your
mind.
We got our size default and size tiny which we use quite a bit but we also got cases where we have 3rem,
2rem, so multiples of our sizes you would say. Of course we could define separate variables for
these and if we were to reuse these values a lot, that would make sense but if we just have some usages,
what we could do and what is supported by SASS is simple arithmetic.
We could use size default here which is 1rem and simply multiply it by 3.
If we now save this and we have a look at the created main.css file, you'll see that we still
get 3rem here because SASS is able to do simple math like this; multiplication, division, subtraction
and addition. You can do it with variables,
you can also do it with other values, details about this can be found in the official SASS documentation.
The cool thing is now this padding also depends on our default size,
even though it's not the same value but it's a multiple of it,
the same for this padding.
There we could also use size default times two, for the box shadow here for example, we could use size
tiny divided by two, since we used half of it
and so on.
This is what you can do in your code in general, here for that margin, size default times two for example,
here for border bottom, we could use size tiny divided by four,
since we used a fourth of our tiny size which is .2. With that in place, we can save
and now again in the main.css file,
you will see the same values as before and if you reload the page, you see the same as before
but if you go back to main.scss and you ever change your default size to two, you will see that
your entire page adjust now because we in general increased all these multiples too.
So that now takes it one step further to a really reusable and flexible page with the help of SASS.