So that's it for this module,
here's what you learned.
You learn that CSS works with rules which you look like this, you have a selector, a property and a value
for the property.
You learned that there are different types of selectors, element selectors like h1, class selectors
with custom created classes, attributes selectors which we haven't used yet but which we at least touched
on,
ID selectors with custom IDs and the universal star selector.
You learned that there are many properties and values, that you can find a complete list on the
Mozilla Developer Network, MDN and there are different types of values and we will explore way more
properties and values throughout the course.
We had a look at selectors and combinators, so that you can combine multiple selectors to be more precise
about which element you want to select,
you learned about these four and you learned very important about inheritance and specificity. You
learned that parents styles are generally inherited, though there are exceptions.
You learned that multiple rules can apply to one and the same element and that specificity is used to
resolve conflicts arising from this multiple rules thing.
You also learned that the inheritance defaults can be changed by using that inherit keyword, that inherit
value.
You remember when we set font family to a value of inherit? Then we overwrite the general behavior that
we would not inherit because of specificity
and we did inherit, so that is something which can be changed.
This is what we learned thus far,
now we'll dive way deeper into all of that and we'll continue working on our web page which still doesn't
look super amazing
I'll have to admit but these were very important foundations on which we can now build up to dive deeper
into the internals of CSS and see how it works and then also to continue working on our web page.
So let's continue.