So what can we now do with the viewport height and viewport width? Let's find that out in this lecture
but before we do that, let's quickly go once again to the packages.css file because I have to admit
I forgot something, I forgot to change the package badge font size because this is still at 12 pixels
and this should rather be let's say 0.8 rem,
I think that's the better unit for that.
With that change being applied, we can now focus onto the viewport units. For this purpose,
we will go to the shared.css
file right here and work on our backdrop again because the viewport height and width units will simply
be placed right here,
so the vw viewport width to the width property
and the viewport height will be placed right here at the height property.
Now just adding these letters right here won't help us a lot,
we also have to specify the viewport width and let's maybe start with 100 right here and also 100
for the height, like that.
If we now comment out our display none decoration right here because the backdrop should not be hidden
anymore
and reload the page, we can see that we have our backdrop back on our website,
it behaves as it did before,
you can see it, like this and like that,
so this generally works fine.
This is also important to understand before we continue. For the situation we have right here
when we added position fixed to our selector right here, then the difference between width 100%
or height 100% or adding the viewport units like that is not really there.
As I said in the other video, this is just a different approach to achieve the same result
in this case, in a few minutes we'll have a look at another example where we can relate the width and
the height of our element to the viewport, although the position property is not set to fixed.
So just wanted to make this clear because at the moment, there is no real difference to the previous
solution.
However let's have a closer look at that viewport units right here because what happens if I change just
now to 80, like that? Well as you might have guessed,
now we only have the backdrop covering 80% of the width of our viewport and that's actually what
these numbers basically mean,
it's basically a percentage number.
This just indicates that it always refers to the viewport and that's the important difference.
We could also apply a height of 50% for example right here
and with that, it would look like that.
So I think the general logic of this viewport unit is clear,
it simply allows us to, as I said, always refer our sizes to the actual viewport no matter which position
property we have right here
but there are two more units for this viewport that we can use.
One of these is vmin,
this one right here.
Let's see if this changes a thing,
yes we can see now our width became a bit smaller,
what's the reason for that?
Well, view min simply takes 80% of the smaller viewport
and in our case if we make this bigger, we can see it doesn't increase the width because in our case, the
smaller viewport is of course the height, so the height is smaller than our width right here.
Now what does this mean? I can increase the width as far as I want because it will always take 80%
of the smaller viewport but it's not always 80% of the height because if I reduce that, at a
certain point and that's exactly the point
where the height and the width are equal
and now the width right here, the width of the viewport becomes smaller than the height and because of
that,
now it jumps to taking 80% of the viewport width.
Let me repeat that,
now we have 80% of the viewport width because the viewport width is smaller,
so this viewport is smaller than the height.
As soon as the height becomes smaller than the width which is right now, can you see it, at this point,
the backdrop doesn't increase anymore because it now takes 80% of the smaller distance which
in that case is the height.
Now in addition to view min, we also have view max which as you can imagine simply works the other
way around,
so if I reload, we can see that the width increase because now we take 80% of the larger distance
between the width and height of the viewport.
So right here, it keeps increasing because our width is a lot bigger than the height
but as soon as the height becomes bigger then the width, as you can see, it doesn't move anymore because
the height is now a constant value,
we don't change it so it always takes 80% of the height without any adjustment of the backdrop
and that's it actually
regarding this shared.css file, I will change this back to 100 viewport width and 100 viewport height
because this is actually what we need right here.
As you can see right here, it looks fine but with viewport height, viewport width and especially with
view min and view max, you can easily create such overlaying elements basically and stick them to the viewport.
Now talking about stitching them to the viewport,
let me quickly comment this in again and reload the page
and let's now stop working on the backdrop,
let's now have a quick look at our picture right here because if we go to our main.css file now,
we can see that we defined the height of this image with 528 pixels,
so this height right here.
Now as we are not the biggest fans of such values and the image actually always can refer to the viewport,
I don't think that's a big problem,
why don't we just change the pixel value to a viewport unit?
The only question is, which one should we take?
Well I would say we use vh, so the viewport height but which number should we add?
Well as we saw, the image has 528 pixels height and our HTML elements, so every everything we see right here,
here has 1600 pixels height,
well I would say that maybe 33% of the viewport height might be a good value for that.
Let's see what this looks like.
We can see that our image is now smaller and to be honest, I prefer this look,
the problem though is that it's a little bit well far down now, so
I would like to see a bit more of the top of the image,
so let's quickly jump back and work on the background image,
let's change bottom to maybe 60%,
let's see what this looks like.
Yes
almost, not totally happy, let's say 70% maybe even because I would like to see this woman a bit
more,
yes I think this looks cool,
this has this kind of freedom-like look that we want to have,
so this definitely improved our website and actually, we could also change the width to 100vw, like
that because why shouldn't we do it the same, right here? If we do that,
nothing changes
but now both units refer to the viewport, like that
and I think this looks pretty cool now.
What we also saw is that although the position property of this background image was position relative
and as you learned, position relative, so the units of these elements do not refer to the viewport, just
by adding vw and vh, we were able to simply change this behavior
and because of that, easily adjust our image according to the viewport.
With that, we could actually conclude vh and vw
but unfortunately there is one
little downside regarding this unit.
If we go again to caniuse.com and look for example for vh, we can see that browser support
is generally pretty good
but for the Internet Explorer 11 right here, there is only a partial support. The partial support
luckily only refers to the vmax unit which is not supported,
so the vh, vw and vmin units are supported,
therefore the issue is not the biggest one but having a look at caniuse.com before using a
specific unit is definitely a good idea
and let's keep in mind that using position fixed for example in combination with percentage values for
width and height is always a good alternative.
The problem now is though that you might still be confused and you might not be sure which unit
to use in connection with which property
and I think this is something we should have a closer look at in the next lecture.