So now that you had a brief introduction to that display property and especially inline block, try taking
this to the next level. If you have a look at our navigation, in the header to be precise, we still have
a problem,
our div which holds our brand link still is on a different line than the nav because both div and nav
elements are block level elements hence they take the full available width and don't go into the same
line.
Here is your challenge,
add code that ensures that both now sit in the same line.
You again can now pause the video and thereafter we'll do it together.
Were you successful?
Let's do it together.
So the goal will be to turn this div and this nav into an inline block element.
Now for that, we can add a class to this first div.
Now we can do that and it would not be bad, even might be the best option of doing that
but I also want to practice a combinator again.
So what I'll do in main.css,
here after main header before main-nav__item, not because the priority matters but because it
makes more sense reading the HTML file from top to bottom, I'll add main header and then the direct child combinator
to directly select a div.
Now I only want to select a div that's a direct child because later in the course, we might add some
nested divs somewhere in the header, so this will now only select this div and any div siblings of that div
if there were any
and now we can give this a style of display inline block, like this.
If we do that and we go back to the page, nothing changed.
Well because the nav element also still is a block level element.
Now the nav element has a class
and of course we could also select nav with a direct child combinator,
I just wanted to throw this in here real quick,
it's generally better to use direct selectors like this class selector.
So now I will take the main nav class which sits on the nav element here and in the main.css, I'll
now also add some styling for that by selecting it with .main-nav and in there,
well display inline block is what we need.
If we add this here and we go back and reload,
now they're in the same line,
so this is looking much better now and this already is the solution to the tiny task I gave you.
Now what we also could do now is we could try to move the elements in that nav element to the right.
Now one thing we can try is since we have an unordered list with list items that are also turned to
inline block, we could use text align on the main nav element to align all our text, and inline block
elements will be treated as text, to the right, so we could add text align right to the main nav element.
If we do that and we reload,
nothing changed
I guess. If we inspect the nav, well we actually see the elements are aligned to the right and we can
confirm this by selecting the nav, here
we got a text align right
and if you argue, that doesn't matter because list items are children of unordered list.
Well, this also has it due to inheritance,
so here text align right is inherited from main nav.
So this is getting applied but it doesn't have an effect because unordered list sits inside nav which
is an inline block element and which therefore doesn't take the full available width,
it only has as much width as its content needs,
hence text align right doesn't do anything here.
So we instead need to set a width and the width should be the width of our header minus the width of this
div here at the beginning.
Now then we would still have a problem because that unordered list in there still has an additional
padding,
if you go down, you see we've got a padding to the left
and we also got margin to top and bottom even.
So we first of all should reset that before we try changing the width of the main nav navigation.
So back in code, in index.html we see this unordered list where I just said I want to reset padding
and margin, it has the main-nav__items class.
So if we copy that class name and we add that with the class selector, we can actually set margin to
zero here
and padding, to reset all these basic settings or remove them essentially.
There's one additional property which we can set and that is list style none, this removes the bullet points,
though setting the padding to zero will also remove them
but that really ensures that there are no bullet points.
With that, we can now change the width of main nav, we could set it to 100%.
If we do that and we reload, yes it's on the right but it's also in a new line if you watch closely which makes
sense,
the nav now takes the full available width minus the padding of the header and therefore, it doesn't
fit into a line with our first div here anymore.
So what we need to do is take 100% minus the width of that div and that div if we scroll down
has a width of 48.134. Now reading this from the rendered page like this is
not the best possible approach to be honest,
we'll find a cleaner approach later
once we got more powerful tools. For now what we can do is we can take that value,
so let's make it 49 and subtract that from 100% and CSS got a function, a helper
for that,
the calc function. We can assign this as a value too and calc takes a simple calculation.
Here, the calculation would be 100% minus and the whitespace between the number and the minus
does matter, whitespace
and then the value you want to subtract,
for example 49 pixels.
If you now save this and you reload, it became narrower but it's still in a new line
and that is something that is related to inline block and it's super important to be aware of this behavior
because that can cost you hours otherwise.