So we had a look at the inheritance in the last video, a very useful feature that also saves us time
when writing more complex code.
Let's now have a look at mixins, this will be the last thing I want to show you
but this is a really cool feature that also allows you to save code.
Now what are mixins? Mixins are reuseable custom functions if you want to put it like this.
You already got functions, like map-get or lighten which do utility things for you
and mixins are really your own functions you can write.
They are super useful whenever you want to
for example put some code which you commonly use into such a function
so that you just have to include your mixin function in that place and then enter that code you outsourced.
Well,
that sounds super complicated, doesn't it?
So let's see that in action, for example here, we got our display property in the container and we get
that again further down in the documentation links class.
Since I use vendor prefixes here, we get the same code four times,
so we got the four display properties here.
Now we can put this into a mixin. A mixin is created by using the @mixin directive provided by SASS,
this is not a CSS feature.
Then you define any name you want, like maybe display-flex but again, it's up to you how you rename
this. Thereafter, you add parentheses and you could accept arguments here,
I'll show an example for this in a second too,
for now we'll use this without arguments and then you simply add the code which you want to print out
whenever you use that mixin,
in our case, that display flex code. So I'll cut it from the container and put it into the mixin, just
like that, no selector, nothing like that, it's just added between the curly braces.
Now we can use that mixin in all the places where we want to enter this code.
So we go back to the container and there, you now don't just put it in like this but instead, you add
@include, another directive provided by SASS.
@include then takes the mixin you want to use
and don't forget the parentheses.
Now with this line, this code which is placed in the directive, in the mixin I should say, will be
added in this place here,
so in the container. Now I can copy that and add it in the other place where I want to use that same code,
so down here in documentation links. If we now save this and let it recompile and we reload the page,
you again see no difference because it works as before
but if you have a look at the compiled code here, you can actually see that this display code is entered
correctly,
so that mixin is used and that of course is super useful because with that now, we can put code snippets
which we use quite a lot into our own mixins.
Now another thing we could put into a mixin is our media query here. So we could add another mixin
with @mixin and name this media-min-width
and now here I actually want to put that media query, like this.
Now we got two problems with that mixin, we hardcoded the min-width and for this application, this would
even be fine because we always use 40rem but it would be nicer if we could accept this as an argument,
to have a truly reusable mixin here.
So this can be fixed by simply accepting an argument,
you name this with a dollar sign at the beginning and then any name of your choice, like width and then
you simply use that variable, which is now only available within the mixin, in all the places where you
want to use that width, like this.
So now we're creating a mixin where we can actually pass in different widths
and the only thing that is shared amongst all the mixins is the min-width condition here, which is exactly
what I want to have here.
We got one other problem though,
we got the font size hardcoded in here and not in all places where we use the media query
we want to set the font size and that's even the case for our application,
for example we also set the width. So we somehow need to tweak this a little bit, to not just accept an
argument which gives us the width, the minimum width we set but to also be able to pass in the actual content
of the media query from outside.
Now how would that work?
Inside of your mixin, you can simply add another directive, @content like this.
This now allows you to use
the mixin a bit differently and pass in dynamic content.
You would now use it by going to the place where you want to use it, using @include as before, then the
mixin name, media-min-width, then I would pass the width here but then I would add curly braces thereafter
and again add the content which should be injected into the mixin.
So this would translate to this code being added but the font size here would be placed in this
@content's place here and the width passed as an argument would be used here in the min-width condition.
If I save this
and we have a look at the compiled file,
we can see just that,
we got that media query where we set the font size.
Behind the scenes though, in our SASS code, we use our mixin.
So now I can copy that code here, @include, media-min-width with the 40rem and use it anywhere where
I want to use that mixin but I will swap out the content with the actual content I want to use in
that place, like in this case here the width
and let's see if we got another media query,
no, this seem to be all.
With that, we can save this again
and if we reload this page again,
still no changes. I guess from this part,
this is a really boring section, isn't it?
But it's really interesting to learn how you can use mixins, both in a simpler form or with arguments
and even a content hook to create a really reusable code snippets
and with that, we got much leaner code.
Now again, for mixins just as for the inheritance, you can dive in much deeper and you should simply
click this link here to learn more about mixins.