We're almost done for the module.
We worked a lot with images in this module,
do you remember? Now one popular form of images or icons is svg for scalable vector graphics.
Now svg is a topic for its own, you can dive very deep into it and there are whole courses
diving just into svg graphics. Attached to this video, you find three files for svg graphics we can
add to our key features area of our main page. If you go to the main page, I'm talking about these circles
here.
Now let's enter the first svg graphic inside of the key feature image container. Simply copy the
svg code into there
and yes it's quite a lot but you can use it inline like this, browser support for this
is very decent.
Now let's do the same for the two other svgs
you can find attached to this video here.
Let's grab the second one and enter into the second key feature image container
and let's also do that for the third and depending on your IDE, you can always simply reduce that, so
that the content still is there but doesn't occupy your entire HTML file. If you do that and you reload,
you see the icons are added but actually they're a little bit too big.
Now you can style svg too,
this is exactly what I want to do with you now.
However we will not dive into the depths of styling svg because as it turns out, you can even select
the svg elements themselves and start styling these.
So you could go in there and start styling the colors the svg lines and so on by overwriting that
fill color here,
this is something a bit more advanced and more related to svg than CSS.
Therefore what I want to do is I'll go to the main.css file and there
let's scroll down to our key feature area.
Now we got that key feature image part here
and let's simply add a padding in there of let's say 20 pixels.
Now if we do that and we reload, this looks much better. Now to still give you an idea of how you could
style svg though, let's use the developer tools and let's select an element here. As you can
see, we can select the individual parts of that svg image, for example that orange branch line here.
Now as you see, the style here is set with inline styles because I didn't create these svgs on
my own,
I got them from an external source and there, they were exported like this.
We can still overwrite this, either with the important mark or anyways here in the developer tools
and what I want to show you right now is just that we get some extra properties there, most importantly.
the fill property which defines how this element is filled but also the stroke property to add an extra
stroke, maybe black.
Now you see there's a tiny black stroke around this orange line,
you can also add a stroke width property to set it to let's say 10 pixels so that we can clearly see
it here on the left.
This is just a brief introduction to how you can styles CSS, fill and stroke are the most important properties
there,
you could translate them kind of with background color, border color and border width,
however if you want to learn more about this, at the end of this module, you'll find an article which
dives a bit deeper into this,
again a dedicated svg course is what you should be looking for if you want to dive deeper into styling
svgs. For now, this style should do
and I have to say I like the look of our page already.
This looks awesome,
we greatly enhanced it over the course of this module with all these background styles, with all these
images and now also these svgs
and with that, I'd say let's just move on and let's keep on improving this project further.