So let's start working on that plans page now.
Now the first thing I want to have is I want to have some spacing to my navigation bar.
We could add a margin top to that first section but we can actually just add one to that main element
here and here we can also use the elements selector, we could add a class of course but we will not have
a second main element on this page,
so using the main selector is fine. So in the packages.css file,
I'll select the main element here and I will add a padding top to have some spacing between the topmost section
and the header of let's say 32 pixels.
If we now save this and reload, this is pushed down a little bit more and the links are not blue anymore
because I accidentally clicked on one.
So this is the first part I wanted to add,
now the next thing is about the individual packages we have,
so a package really is just one of these sections.
So if we go to our index.html file on the packages folder, we can add a package class to each section.
Of course you can name that class whatever you want,
the idea is that we can assign some general styling.
So let's now select package here
and for example ensure that they don't take the entire width of the page,
let's maybe limit the width to 80% let's say.
Additionally, there should be some spacing between the packages,
so I'll add a margin to top and bottom of 16 pixels but 0 to left and right because I want to position them
on the edge of the page.
Additionally, maybe some border works nice there too, maybe like 4 pixels solid
and in this dark green which was #0e4f1f and if we save that then, this looks like this.
Now from the visual perspective, we can probably still improve that,
for example we could get rid of that left border.
Now for that we can target border left and set it to none, the other borders will be kept because we also
defined here
but then we overwrite the border left. So with that if we reload,
looks a little bit nicer,
looks like the plans are coming out of the left edge which is a lookalike a lot.
Now of course the text looks awful,
so we definitely need to work on that too.
For this, I'll use my package and select the anchor tag inside of it
and of course you could also assign a class to that
but here I'll just use the combinator. I'll set the text decoration to none and the color actually to inherit,
to use my page default. I'll then set display to block to ensure that the anchor tag takes the full available width
of the surrounding section and add a padding of let's say 32 pixels. If we now save that, our boxes look like
this,
so we're getting there,
style is improving and these still are links even though they don't look like them anymore but you see
we still got that hand
icon if we hover over that.
Now one thing you can also see is that I can even click that top right corner of that plan and it's
still a link because we set that anchor tag to be a display block element and hence it takes the full
available space inside of that surrounding section.
So here you see that's my anchor tag,
it really fills the entire section box.
So with that, we got the link styled,
now I want to style the content inside of that of course,
so inside of that box.
So this is what we'll work on in the next lecture.