So throughout this module, we learned a lot about SASS.
Now looking over our code, there are still some things we can improve or things that look like they could
still be improved.
For one, I forgot that here, this h1 tag,
we could nest this into this section header to be in line with our other logic where we use nesting when
possible
and the same here for the paragraph in the sass-introduction, this also can be nested in here
and if you already did this earlier in this module, for example in the assignment,
good job.
This is more investing done but what else can we do?
Let's have a look at this hover and active thing,
doesn't this look a bit strange?
We've got all these nice improvements in place and still here it looks like we still have to manually
create this group of selectors, which is the same selector as here, just with a pseudo selector added.
Well we can handle this with SASS too.
Now the first thought might be that you couldn't nest this, so that you can add hover and active like
this in your selector or in the documentation link selector.
Now if you do that and you reload your page, you'll see that hovering has no effect anymore,
let's check out the created CSS code.
There you see that actually what it did is it created this, obviously as nested selectors,
so if we had other elements which are hoverable or active inside our documentation link,
then these styles would get applied to these elements but we don't have them,
so this doesn't work here.
Instead what we want to do is we want to apply hover and active to the documentation link, not nested
to it.
Now how do we do that? For this,
SASS has
the and, the ampersand operator. We add it in front of :hover and :active and then we still keep
it nested in documentation link.
This tells SASS that these pseudo selectors here and this does not only work with pseudo selectors, you
could also have a normal class of for example, that they should be connected to the element here rather
than nested inside of it.
So if we compile this and we go back to we main.css file, you'll see that the rule changed
and now it changed the documentation link with the hover effect or with active,
so now we have this connected selector here. And now with that, if we reload the page, it works again
and now we can hover again.
So this was one final improvement
I wanted to put into place because now, we got a really optimized and nice looking SCSS file where
we take advantage of the many features SASS gives us.