So what is my problem with the navigation bar?
Before I show you that, there is another fix that we should implement because if we go back to our code
and to our main.css file, you remember that we added this media query right here with the min width
and the min height,
so this logical operator where we say that both criteria must be fulfilled.
Well the problem is that the min height was set a bit too high for our purposes.
So in case we are using a laptop for example, the image might look kind of awkward,
therefore what we could do now is we could also set the main height to 40rem and with that, we can ensure
that our image also looks good on laptops for example.
That's just a small fix, you won't see a difference right here because on my screen, it looks good.
So this was the quick fix but now I'm coming back to the navigation bar because if we look at the structure
of our navigation bar, so right here in the header and then we have our div right here and then we have
our anchor tag and inside this anchor tag, we have our image.
So we defined a height of 2.5rem for our image,
that's what we did when we worked on the responsive design
but the anchor tag actually has a font size defined, 1.5rem
and this leads to the issue that if we look at the height of our image, this is like 40 pixels but the
anchor tag is 46 pixels, as you can see it in the left upper part of the screen
and although this is not a big problem, I don't think that's a logical behavior. Therefore, wouldn't it
make more sense to simply get rid of the font size right here of our anchor tag and define a fixed height
for our anchor tag of 2.5rem,
so the height we had for our image and then the image can simply have a height of 100% of its
containing element which is the anchor tag and then the structure would be a bit better.
I think this would make sense,
so let's go back to the code
and let's now change this.
For that, we have to go to our shared.css
file, this one right here and now go to our main header brand and main header brand image selectors.
So the main header brand shouldn't have a font size,
we will delete that but it should have a height of 2.5rem, as we just said,
this is the height we had so far for our logo, for our uHost logo.
So as we now defined the height in the anchor tag which is the containing element for our image, for our
logo, we can simply set this height to 100%.
If we do that and we load our page, we can see that nothing changed.
We have this little gap right here,
we'll fix that soon
but the cool thing though is that we have a height of 40 pixels right here for our image and of 40
pixels right there for our anchor tag, so for the containing element.
And I think this is a better code structure and we want to have a good code structure,
so I think that was a nice fix.
However we now have this little gap right here between the background image and our navigation bar,
this is simply 2.5rem
we now have for our image and for the anchor tag
and in addition to that, we also have, right here in our header, we have this padding right here as you
can see it, we have a padding of 0.5rem to the top and to the bottom.
And this simply means if we select our background image right here and go down in the code and see that
we have a top margin or margin top of 3.75rem,
well then this is a bit too much.
So if we simply go back now to our
main.css
file and go to our image right here and simply change this margin top to 3.5rem, like
that and reload our page, we can see that now we fixed our navigation bar and our image still looks
nice in all versions,
so be the mobile version or the desktop version.
So this is just a fix for our navigation bar and the two little fixes for our background image.
Now there is only one final fix that we should also apply as part of this responsive design module because
the footer, we talked about that, is kind of positioned in the middle of nowhere now
and this is also something we should have a look at now.