So here is your challenge,
I want you to style these links on the right here to have a little bit more distance from each other.
Keep in mind, you are limited regarding margin top and bottom when it comes to inline block elements
but left and right should work
and I also want you to make sure that the anchor tags in these list items do actually have a green text,
the same green text we have for the brand by default and that they're not underlined.
This is using a couple of concepts taught in the previous lectures and even the last module,
good luck with that,
here's your chance to pause the video, thereafter
we'll as always do it together.
So were you successful?
Let's do it together.
So to change the styling as we want it, I'll first of all add a little bit of margin between the items here.
So on main-nav__item, I'll now add a margin and I only want margin on left and right because top and bottom
won't work anyways and I don't want it,
so I'll use that to value shorthand. The first value refers to a top and bottom, I'll set that to zero,
the second value is left and right and there I'll use 16 pixels, like that.
If we do that and we reload,
now we got more spacing and also notice that this doesn't lead that to jump into a new line again because
margin is not included in the width calculation.
So this now positions them nicely,
let's now take care about the underlining and color.
Now we can add text decoration none to our main-nav__item. If we save that and reload, the text decoration
is still there,
let's inspect that item.
The problem is it's our anchor tag
where this text decoration underline is set by default by the browser, so changing it on the list item
doesn't do anything.
It could be inherited in theory, though not even that is happening
but even then, it would be overwritten because even browser defaults do have the lowest priority
but even they directly target the element
so they would overwrite inheritance.
So setting text decoration here doesn't work.
Now we got at least two alternatives to solve this,
the first alternative is to assign a CSS class to all the anchor tags in our list items,
so we could give each anchor tag a class.
We can also use a combinator.
So here I'll use main-nav__item a to select the anchor tag.
Now what is better, using a class or using that combinator? From a performance perspective,
assigning a class should be a little bit faster, though I will say unless you're building the next Facebook
at least, you will probably not notice this
and especially for cases like this where you have one anchor tag directly, so as a direct child, nested
in an item with a class, this is a high performance selector too,
so performance isn't even that much worse here.
So that is perfectly fine to use and often it's just unnecessary to create an extra class, though you
could do that,
this is a perfectly fine way of selecting that nested element.
So with it selected, we can of course style it now.
So let's style it by removing the text decoration, setting this to none, giving it this darker green color with
that hex code we used before
and saving this.
Now if we reload, these are our links, they look better.
Now as a next step, I want to change the appearance when we hover over them. So that's something we'll cover
in the next video.