So throughout this module, we had a look at a lot of SASS features in our code here.
You learned about variables,
nesting, mixins,
partials, the different import syntax and so on.
Now I can only encourage you to dive deeper into the topics which are linked in this project, as well
as simply on the official SASS page.
There you can learn more about SASS and more about how you can use it and add it to your workflow
and that's also important,
you'll not always use the SASS command line tool as we did here. In a lot of projects where you use webpack
anyway
for example, you can implement SASS loader and that is now really beyond the scope of this module here
but you can implement tools that integrate with webpack that will do that SASS compilation as part of
your regular build workflow.
So this is also available,
you don't have to use the SASS command line tool we used here. But it's a great place to get started
and I want to encourage you to keep on practicing SASS and playing around with it
since this really is a more fun way of creating CSS, at least for a lot of people including myself.