So now we use the grid on our page,
that's very useful
but one thing can be noticed on the main page.
Now here above the image, we get this whitespace, so the image is now not positioned correctly anymore.
Now the reason for this is simple,
if we inspect the main element and the rules of it, we see that we get a margin top there,
we should remove that to ensure that the image looks good again.
So let's go back to our shared.css file,
let's remove that margin top here along with our min height calculation.
We don't need it anymore because now we use the solution of reserving the place for the header with
an extra row.
So now if we reload, this change stays in place, on the other pages we didn't have a problem with that
anyways and now it's fixed on this page and all the other pages too.
Now if you go into mobile mode, you also might notice that the footer doesn't really sit at the very
bottom of this entire thing. In the layout tab,
you can still see that
we have a grid though and the grid row doesn't go to the very bottom, so that's issue we got here.
We can also see that our footer here is basically cut off.
Now the problem is the footer increases in size on a mobile device because we use flexbox to position
the elements in the footer below each other, like terms of use which are outside of the footer box here.
So we basically need to change our setup here for the grid
to something else than these fixed 8rems.
This should be something else which allows the footer to also grow, something like auto maybe.
However if we add auto, it still isn't perfect here as you can tell
and besides that if we set this to auto, we got a different layout on the other pages too
because if we got auto twice as we now have, these two will basically distribute empty space between
each other
and this is not the layout we want to have,
so auto isn't really the solution we're looking for here.
Instead, there is a special function which I haven't shown you yet,
it's fit-content. fit-content takes an argument which is a default size
you can assign, like 8rem, which will be used in case the content is smaller or requires less place, less
space than that. If the content requires more space than that, it will get this size though
but only as much as needed by the content.
So if we set this and I now reload, now the footer is at the bottom. By the way in Firefox, you can still
scroll, as you can scroll to the right but this is actually just a bug,
it doesn't work like this if you open it on a mobile device or if you preview it in Chrome for example.
There, everything works as it should
and the same is true for all the other pages.
So now everything should look quite nice and should work the way
we expect it to work, the footer is at the bottom and takes as much space as required in case it's
not smaller than the 8rem which would be the default size of the footer otherwise.
So I hope this also helps with styling this and understanding how you can style it, fit-content is another
very useful value when it comes to having some row which should have some minimum size but
also not be bigger than its content.
This is what you're looking for.