So what is wrong with our footer?
Well as you can see, the footer is kind of positioned in the middle of nowhere,
this is also true for the customers page. For the starting page,
it's better because we have more content
but generally I think it would definitely make sense to think about the way, how to create a general
style, so a style in our shared.css file which defines that the footer is always positioned at the bottom
of our page.
Now how could we acheive that?
Well what we basically need is we need a header right here,
then we need the main part which should leave us the gap for the footer at the bottom.
Now if we think back about our units module, why don't we simply add a height of 100vh,
so
100% of the viewport to our main element and then deduct the height of our nav bar because
that's the space the nav bar needs at the beginning,
so this means our main part would now simply end right here
and if we then also deduct the space our footer needs, then we will ensure that the footer is always
positioned at the bottom of the page.
Now to achieve that, we simply need two things, we need to select our main element and then we need a
calculation formula.
We already applied such a formula right here in our shared.css file because if we scroll down a bit
to the main navigation selector, we have this formula,
this calculation, so we know how to do this basically.
Now what formula would we need to make sure that the footer is positioned according to the way I just
described?
Well basically, we could add the main selector as a starting point right here in our shared.css file.
Then we would need a minimum height,
that's important because that's always the height our main element should have
and this should be calculated based on 100% of the viewport height minus,
now what's the minus? Well the minus must be our space that the navigation bar needs,
we learned that in the last lecture,
this is 3.5rem, like that and minus the space our footer needs.
Now what is the space our footer needs?
Well basically, if we inspect the footer like that, this is 19 pixels plus 64 pixels for the top and
bottom padding,
so this means we have 83 pixels plus the 48 pixels for the top margin.
So in total, this would be 131 pixels
and if we turn that into rem, we know 1rem is 60 pixels, this would be 8rem.
So this means we need to deduct this 8rem right here, like that.
So this is the first step,
this is the calculation formula we need, if we now reload the page, we can see that we have an issue right here,
it's not perfectly positioned at the bottom.
If we go to the customers page, it's also not perfect. But let's start on the landing page right here because
here on the starting page,
it looks better but let's inspect the structure for a page and let's see if it's really correct already
here because if we go right here into our main element, we can see that one thing is missing actually,
we are missing a top margin because the main element should not be hidden below our nav element. At
the moment,
this is not the case because we added the margin right here, this margin top to our product overview ID,
this one right here,
our section element. The better approach would be to add such a 3.5rem margin top to the shared.css
file.
So let's add margin top right here of 3.5rem like that
and if we now reload the page, we cannot see a difference but that's simply due to margin collapsing because
as we can see on product overview, we have our margin top and we also have it for our main element right here.
What we can do now is we can go to our main.css file and get rid of that margin top right here because
we now defined a general rule in our shared.css file, right here.
If I now reload the page, this looks all right
and if we now have a look at the packages page, we can see it's still not working perfectly and the
same thing is true for the customers page. If we go to our packages page and inspect the main element,
we can see that we already added a margin right here of 3rem.
Now if we go into our code, into the packages.css file, we can see that this is basically applied right
here in our media query.
Now we don't need that anymore actually, so let's delete that part right here because we now have this general
rule and if we now go back and reload the page, we can see that it works now because as you can see, we
now specified the margin top directly right here in the main element based on our shared.css rule
and therefore, we don't need that rule in the media query anymore
and with that, our footer is now also positioned correctly right here on the packages page.
Important,
we still have this padding of 2rem to the top, so this one, this is simply here to ensure that we have
a distance between the nav bar and the actual packages, like that
but as you can see, this is just the padding, on top of the padding
we have our margin, if we scroll down, we can see it,
this is the 56 pixels that we defined
and these are the 3.5rem that we specified in our shared file
and with that, we also fixed the footer right here.
Now let's have a look at the final page, the customers page because here, we still have kind of a mess.
If we have a look at our code,
so in the customers.css file right here, we can first see that we have this testimonial first of type,
this margin top that we added,
so basically the margin, that one right here. We don't need that anymore because now we specified that
we need a margin to the top for the main element already in the shared.css file, this is this 3.5rem margin
we defined.
So the remaining margin we need right here to ensure that this looks the same is 2.5rem and the next
thing is, I don't think this has to be a margin,
this could also be a padding that we add to our main element right here.
Now to make things short, we can simply delete that margin top right here,
like that. If we now reload the page, we have the same behavior right here that we saw on the packages
page because right here, if we simply now remove the padding top right here, we can see that the main
element is coming directly after the navigation bar because of the margin top of 3.5rem
and that's the same behavior we have now right here.
We have the main element, we have the margin top of 3.5rem
and afterwards, the main element comes and now we can simply add another main selector right here,
this one. Now in the customers file
and this should not give us a margin now because you don't need the margin,
we can also use a padding top of 2.5rem, like that.
With that, we have 2.5rem for the padding and if we reload the page, we can see that our image is positioned
as before
but now with a different structure. Now we have a top padding of 2.5rem plus the margin top that
is applied generally for all our pages in the
shared.css file.
And with that if I click through our pages, as we can see the footer is positioned correctly right here,
it's positioned correctly right there on the packages side and on the customers
side.
Let's also have a look at the responsive design now,
this looks good, looks still good,
looks fine, yes
I think this is a nice design we have right here.
Let's also have a look at the packages page, at the mobile design right here,
this looks fine
and if we increase the size, we can see that we made a mistake because we have to add back our left and
right margin, this should be auto.
Remember we have to add the margin left auto and a margin right of auto, like that.
So if I now reload the page, we can see we got our responsive design back, right here and right there, this looks
fine.
So let's also have a final look at the customers page right here,
let's see if the responsive design works.
We have the limitation if it gets above 1500 pixels and we have a nice mobile design, the footer also works
perfectly.
Important maybe, if we go to the customers page right here and down there to our media query, I kept
the margin of 3rem and auto for the media query because right here, it makes sense that once we go
to our desktop design, that we have this little gap right here,
therefore I will leave that margin as it is. And with that, we finally finished this responsive design
module.
So in the next lecture, it's time to summarize what we learned in here.