So what have we learned throughout this module?
Well, we basically learn that we have different units available in CSS, we have pixels and percentages,
these are the ones we already used throughout this course so far but then we also saw that we have rem
and em, so these units that refer to the font size and we have viewport units, vh and vw, vmin, vmax.
In addition to that, I also showed you that using auto especially for margins can also be a really nice
helper, in case you want to align your objects to the center of your website.
We also had a look at the containing block which is basically the reference point whenever we apply
percentage units to our element.
The containing block basically depends on the position property that is applied to our element. Generally,
the containing block is either the closest ancestor or the viewport.
We had a detailed look at that,
so we also saw the different combinations we have,
for example we also saw that if we have the position fixed declaration applied to our element, then the
containing block is not the closest ancestor but the viewport.
If we have the position absolute declaration applied, then the closest ancestor which also has a position
property applied is our containing block and we saw that if we have position static or relative applied,
that the closest ancestor which is a block level element is our containing block.
In addition to that, we also had a look at the 100% height issue because we saw that if our element
itself and the ancestors both use the position static or relative value, then applying 100%
height to our element is not working.
We saw that if we add a height of 100% to the ancestors,
this issue is fixed.
Another fix for the issue that we saw was that we could simply use position fixed or absolute or simply
use viewport units, vw or vh.
Regarding this, we also had a look at browser compatibility,
we saw the small limitations the Internet Explorer had for example.
We also had a look at the min, max width property and we saw that if we combine a normal width property with one
of these properties,
by the way both are also available for the height of course,
well if we combine these, we saw that we can easily restrict the size of an element, for example setting
the max width to make sure that our image is not displayed too big on larger screens.
Same thing was true for the min width
when we said that we wanted to make sure that our image doesn't get too small.
This was our first step towards a more responsive design but we will dive into the details about that
in a separate module.
We also had a look at em and rem, these are the units which depend on the font size.
We saw that rem always depends on the font size of that root element,
so the HTML element and em depended on the size of the element itself.
This means our element used inheritance to get the font size of the ancestor and then multiplied this
value with the em value applied.
We also saw that em and rem, although these depend on the font size, are not restricted to the font size property,
we also used rem for example for our margins
and this is it actually. These are the core concepts you should understand now to make sure that you
are really familiar with the units in CSS.
Now with that, I will hand over back to Max who will now give you a short Javascript introduction because
we created our nice backdrop in this module but the backdrop at the moment is not really working because
we only have the option to comment in or comment out display none.
Not the best solution as I would say,
so let's see how we can make this a bit more dynamic.