So let's continue working on this webpage
and I want to continue with this red block.
Right now, it doesn't look super impressive,
would be nice if it were a little bit bigger, had more height, maybe some spacing inside of it and also
that whitespace around it,
I want to get rid of that too. Until we add a navigation bar,
this red block should be the very first element on our page without surrounding whitespace.
Now we can achieve this, we can add all these things, we can control how the block is designed or how
much space it takes up by working with the box model.
Now what do I mean with that? Every element in HTML is interpreted as a box by CSS and you can see
that box in the Chrome developer tools if you inspect that element and again you can really select
any element.
So here, I selected the h1 element,
now let's pick the section element
but again, any would do it
and if you then at the bottom scroll down below your styles and the inherited styles, you will see this box.
This is how CSS thinks about an element, every element has a content, that's the blue area,
that's really what's inside of it.
So for this section, the content actually is the h1 tag, for the h1 tag,
the content is its text.
So we get that content, the blue area and then we can add a padding.
Now we got none here indicated by that dash but we could add a padding which is some internal space within
that section element from the content to the next part, the border,
we can add a border to each element.
Now we don't have a border here, so we'll add all these things in just a second of course, a border surrounds
an element and directly comes after the padding which in turn comes directly after the content.
Now finally, we sometimes also want to have some spacing around an element and that would be the margin.
It's not part of the core element, that ends with the border including the border but it comes after
that,
it's the distance you have between that element and its next sibling.
For example the h1 element has a margin, by default
it's set by the browser,
you can see this if you scroll up the browser defaults, there you have that strange margin before and after
thing,
well that's just the default browser margin
and there you can see this element happens to have a margin of 19.92 pixels to the top and bottom,
that's this orange area which is also indicated on the top left corner,
so here in the loaded page. As you can see already, the margin goes outside of the surrounding section
container because it's not part of the element, which in turn is the content of the section.
Now since the margin is not part, it's not part of the content and therefore not part of the section.
This is the box model, these layers, the content, the padding, the border, the margin, every element is interpreted
as such a box in CSS.
Now there are two different types of elements then, block level and inline, something I'll cover in this
module too where some of these things will differ a bit
but I'll dive into that. For now,
let's simply keep in mind that every element has these layers.
Now let's work with that.