So now with that little dive into pseudo classes and pseudo elements, let's dive into something else.
Do you know these two rules? They're exactly equal if we leave out the selector which of course
differs.
If you got a case like this, you can group them into one rule because repeating code like this is not
good
and if you ever change the color, you have to change it in two places.
So what we can do is we can group the two rules by adding a comma after the first one and then in the
same one in the next line,
I always add in the next line because it's easier to read, we add the next selector we want to add to
the group and you can add as many as you want.
Important,
this is not a combinator, these two rules, these two selectors are not related at all,
they just share the same declaration set.
So now we can remove that active rule and still get the same effect because now it's simply grouped
into one rule, into one assignment. So if we reload the page, we still got the hover and hold effect.
So this still works,
it's now just in one group, in one rule.