So what is flex grow, how can we use it?
Well let's first again delete align self from our item three right here
and if we now look at our elements, I prepared two equal elements here,
the last one's width, the width of 350 pixels and as you might imagine, I had a good reason to do that because
I will now show you flex grow with the example of these two items.
So for that, we go back to our code and now we will add flex grow right here. Flex grow has an initial
value of zero,
so if I add flex grow zero to both our items right here, like this and like that and go back, you can
see that if I inspect the width now, we have a width of 350 pixels because we've reach the maximum
and if I decrease the size, we still have wrap applied,
let me go back quickly and change our flex wrap to no wrap because this makes it easier for me to
show you the flex grow property, like that.
So if I now decrease the size, you know already it decreases the width up to the point where the content
needs the space inside our box which is right here at 202 let's say, round about 200 pixels for both
elements. Important,
both elements behave the same way,
that's the minimum value
and if I increase the size, as I showed you, we have a maximum value of 350 pixels.
Now let's keep that in mind and let's now go back to our code right here and scroll down to item 5, because
what if I change the value now from 0 to 1 for example?
Keep in mind, the default value for flex grow is 0 for item 6
and of course also for all the other items.
Now let's go back and let me first reduce the size, like that
and now reload the page because as you can imagine, the size is still equal,
316.3, 316.3 but if now increase the width right here,
like that,
can you see what happens?
The last item,
so our item right here with flex grow zero doesn't increase the width
as soon as it hits its maximum of 350 pixels but if I now inspect the other element, we can see that
it has a width of 383 pixels now
and this is interesting, right? Because just by adding this flex grow value of one, the element used
the remaining space available because otherwise if we would increase the width of the page, we would
have space available if this would be limited to 350 pixels and simply occupies this space because we
added flex grow one right here.
Now we added flex grow one, what happens now
if I add flex grow two to our last item right here, this one? Let's do that and let's first again decrease
the size of course and reload the page
and let's now increase the size.
I think it's hard to see,
let me change it maybe to 4
even, so that's a bigger difference.
So we have flex grow one for item 5 and flex grow four for item 6.
So if I now reload and increase the width, I think now you can see it right here because the last item now
became the one with the biggest width
and if we inspect the values, we can see that this item, that's not the best value, let me increase it
a bit more
so that we're close to 400, this makes it easier,
yes.
Now we can see that this item has a width of 400,
this one has a width of 556.
Now how is this calculated?
Well basically, what happens from a mathematical perspective is the remaining space is calculated first,
so if we increase the width, we would have an empty space right here which is not occupied by elements
and this space has a certain width,
then this space will be divided by five because we have one for this element and four for this element.
So we basically have five parts,
how this remaining total space should be divided.
Well and one part of this remaining space, so one-fifth of it will be applied to our first element right
here,
so round about 50 pixels and then we have the remaining four-fifths,
so round about 200 pixels which will be added to that last item.
So what we basically see right here is by increasing the width of our page, we had a remaining space of 250
pixels that must be distributed between these two flex grow items right here. As we have flex grow
one for this item, one-fifth is applied to this item and four-fifths are applied to this last item,
so that's how it works.
If I now would add flex grow one to this element right here also, like that and if I reload the page
again,
then you can see that both elements now have a width of round about 425
pixels because this simply means again we have a free space of 250 pixels which will
then be split into two parts,
one right here and one right there and then equally distributed.
If I change it to two right here as a last example and reload the page, you can see that we have 85 right
here
and we have 170 right there,
it's not totally matching because it's not exactly 250 pixels but again, one-third is added right here
and two-thirds are added to this item right here. One last thing about flex grow though, if I would change
the flex wrap again to wrap right here, like that and go back and reload our page, then nothing happens
right here
but if I decrease the size, we can see that as soon as we hit the defined width of 350 pixels, the element
will be wrapped into the second line
and interestingly, this element then occupies the entire space of this second line.
Now why is this happening?
Well if this element would only have 350 pixels, there would be an empty space and this empty space will
again be filled but we only have one element now with a flex grow of two applied, doesn't make a difference
though, if I apply five right here for example, it will remain the same because the space can only be distributed
to one element,
therefore as soon as you apply a flex grow which is larger than zero, a single element which will
be wrapped into the second line will occupy the entire space as we can see it right here.
So this is the last thing about flex grow
and let me change flex wrap back to no wrap right here
and let's also the delete flex grow right here and right there because we don't need it at the moment, right
here like that because our page looks fine like this.
And with that, we can jump to the next property because if we have flex grow, well chances are that
we also have flex shrink.