Now that we talked a lot about the general capabilities of the grid and especially about how you can
position things in the grid,
let's talk about the automatic capabilities of the grid.
We already saw them partly in action,
now I want to dive deeper. Attached to this video,
you'll find yet another little theory starting project.
If you open and run it, it looks like this,
well like this without the grid preview,
so it's a collection of quotes. You might identify which quote is by me and which quotes are owned by
other famous people.
So this is our collection of quotes and it's basically distributed there or handled by a grid.
The grid still is on the container class here with display grid
and the only thing I did when it comes to laying the grid out and styling it is I defined columns, two columns
of equal size.
Of course I could have used
repeat to 15rem instead of manually setting this,
so this is an alternative.
This is not what it's about though,
so this only creates two columns
but as you can clearly see here on the page, we've got more than one row or no row because I didn't define
any rows but actually, you see we got four rows, you can see it really well in the preview here,
in the bottom corner.
Now the reason for the existence of these rows is that by default as I already explained at the beginning
of this module, if you add display grid to any element, it will put all its child elements, its direct
child elements into new rows,
it will create new rows dynamically.
This of course is a good behavior because it ensures that we can create dynamic grids,
so if we happen to have a page where we don't know how many rows we need, for example because the user
can create them with the help of some Javascript function that adds elements to the DOM, anything like
that,
so whenever we don't know how many rows we need, we can rely on the grid automatically creating them.
However, thus far we didn't really have a look at how we can control the size of these rows
for example. As it looks, the default size is auto because each cell here essentially is just as big as
its content requires it to be or its neighbor column here as in the case of this element here. The content
wouldn't require it to have such a big cell
but of course the neighbor element has the requirement of having such a big cell
and since it's in the same row, the row height is adjusted and the other element also gets the same
row height.
But we can of course overwrite this default,
we can add grid auto rows here as a property.
This allows us to create the style of automatically generated rows. The default here is auto which means
the size will be auto,
we can overwrite the size for example to 30rem.
If I do that and I reload,
now you see we got very very huge cells because now every newly generated row does not orientate itself
on the content it holds but it simply has a height of 30rem.
Now this is a bit too big maybe so
let's set this back to 11 or 12rem maybe, let's save this,
now we got some nicer items here.
Now obviously, auto might have not been a bad setting here but if you want to ensure that all rows are
equally sized, then being able to set a clearly defined height here is certainly a nice tool
and of course you can also use minmax here for example to define a minimum height of 8rem but auto
otherwise, now it would not be equally sized but they also wouldn't be as small as they were before.
So this might also be a look you're interested in,
the main takeaway here is that grid auto rows allows you to define the size of the newly added rows,
something we weren't able to do previously.
Now that we had a look at grid auto rows,
let's also have a look at how we can automatically add columns.
Right now the default behavior is that new content automatically is put in a new row. This is not the
worst default behavior because especially if we consider that we're most of the time designing for mobile
phones first, adding content at the bottom is typically a better idea than adding it to the right
but you can switch that behavior nonetheless.
You can tell the grid cannot add new items as a new row but to instead append new columns,
you do this by adding the grid auto flow property.
You might have guessed that grid auto columns is the right one but this actually will be required to
set the size of these automatically added columns,
grid auto flow allows you to define where new elements should be added, as a row which is the default,
which is why we didn't set it previously or as a column which is the value I'm now setting. With this
set to column if we reload,
you see now all the content is added to the right
which clearly doesn't lead to the best design we ever had
but it is a possible approach you can take in case you want to ensure that you never add new rows but
always new columns as you add more more elements.
Be aware, you can still manually create rows with grid template rows of course,
this is something that's never affected,
you can always explicitly add columns and rows,
we're just talking about the automatically added ones,
so for cases where you didn't define them yourself. So this is grid auto flow and for completeness sake, of course
you got rid auto columns then. If grid auto flow is set to column, then you obviously also want to
give these newly added columns a style and that would be the width of these columns, so maybe 5rem.
If you set it to this,
now it's really ugly but this is something you can do
and again, this will of course be overwritten for your explicitly set columns. So the widths you assign here
of course take precedence over the auto columns.
Now with all these properties set here, grid auto rows flow and columns, you now got a lot of controls
to customize the behavior of the grid
when it comes to automatically added items. Now I'll set auto flow back to row because it looks better
but it's important to keep in mind that you can change it if you need to change it.