So what have we learned about flexbox and about how to use it?
Well generally, we learned that with flexbox, we can easily change the way our elements are displayed
on a website. Specifically, flexbox includes the flex container, so this parent element and the items
inside this container.
the so-called flex items. Then we were diving deeper into that and had a look at the flex container
which was created by adding the display flex or inline flex, that's also possible, declaration to an element
and this element will then be turned into such a flex container.
Now regarding the properties we can apply to such a flex container,
we of course have the display flex or inline flex property.
We also had flex direction which basically defined the way our elements are displayed,
so remember we had row, row reverse, column and column reverse.
We also saw that we can define how the elements should wrap,
so with wrap and no wrap for the flex wrap property, we could change the behavior and the shorthand for
these two properties was flex flow,
so the first value for the flex flow is the flex direction,
the second value is the flex wrap.
We then had different properties which allowed us to change the behavior of all the flex items inside
our flex container. With align items, we could align our items in relation to the cross axis, justify
content allowed us to do the same thing along the main axis. With align content,
we were allowed to define the behavior along the cross axis again, that's important, in case our elements
are wrapped over two or more lines.
When talking about these properties, we of course also had a look at the main axis versus the cross
axis.
We learned that flex direction basically defines the main axis,
so if this is the row or the column and the properties we applied to our flex container are also dependent
on the main axis and the cross axis we had which therefore also meant that the behavior of the flex
items that is coming with the properties we used is also highly dependent on the flex direction property.
We then also had a look at the flex items because in contrast to the properties we added to the flex
container which affected all flex items, the flex item specific properties allowed us to change the
behavior of individual flex items.
Therefore, we also had a look at the different properties related to the flex items, we talked about order
which allows us to, well as the name says, changed the order of the flex items along the cross or main
axis.
We talked about align self which is kind of like align item, so which allows us to position an element
in relation to the cross axis
but this time for a specific flex item, for the individual flex item and then we talked about flex, so the
flex shorthand which combines flex grow, flex shrink and flex basis and that's actually it.
This is actually all the core knowledge that we have now to work with flexbox
and as we saw in our project, to make our project a bit more leaner and easier to use and maintain.
So this is the end of this module
and with that, I will now hand over to Max again who will show you another, maybe more advanced concept
of changing the way our elements behave and are displayed, the CSS grid.
So let's find out what that is, how it works and especially how we can apply it to our project in the next
module.