So in this module, we learned quite a bit about the grid, time to summarize it.
You learned how you can create a grid, you do that by adding the display grid property to an element,
this will automatically create a grid then and it will automatically place the direct child elements
in rows of that grid.
The rows are generated automatically and are as high as the content requires it to be.
You can overwrite that default with grid auto flow,
you can set the default of creating rows to create columns there for example and you can also style these
automatically generated rows or columns with grid auto rows or grid auto columns. With grid auto gap,
you can also add gaps between your columns and rows to the grid.
Now that's the general grid, regarding the structure of the grid,
you define columns and/or rows explicitly if you want to do this via grid template columns or grid
template rows.
Now please keep in mind what I said about the explicit and the implicit grid,
you can also stick to these automatically generated rows if that is all you need
but if you need at least two columns or you need certain layouts for your rows, then you want to add
your columns and rows manually with these two properties.
You can configure both rows and columns with repeat,
there you enter the amount of times you want to repeat a certain size
and then there will be as many columns or rows created as this function spits out,
for example repeat three 10rem would create three columns or rows which have the width or height of 10rem
.
You can also use auto-fill or auto-fit on columns only
though in the repeat function instead of entering a number in the times slot, this will then generate
as many columns as fit into one row. Auto-fit also ensures that it's nicely centered and takes the full
available width into account.
And you shouldn't forget about the minmax function which you could enter in the size slot of the repeat
function or in any other place where a size is required.
Minmax will take two arguments; the first argument defines the minimum amount of width or height the
column or row should have
and the second argument defines the maximum.
This is great for ensuring that certain columns or rows are never smaller than a certain size but
also never bigger than another option or use auto as a maximum size, then they will always take the
remaining free space. With the grid and its structure defined, it's all about placing elements.
Now you don't need to define a grid structure on your own, you can just use the automatically created
rows for that but you can then, in either of the two cases, decide where an element should be by using
grid row and/or a grid column and then you can use line numbers or line names or you use grid area together
with named areas.
You shouldn't forget about span x as well as negative values for line numbers,
this can help you to ensure that your elements span a certain amount of cells or simply span an entire
row or whatever your requirement is.
And last but not least, you cannot just position your elements in the grid,
you can also align them and alignment is done with justify items on the x-axis and align items on the
y-axis. For the entire grid where the content might not take the entire space you reserved,
you can position it with justify content on the x-axis and align content on the y-axis.
This is the brief summary, obviously it's all about practicing and diving into the different properties
and simply using them
but I hope that this module was very helpful when it comes to getting started with the grid.