The place to start is on sass-lang.com, sass-lang.com,
that's the page of the SASS language if you want to call it like this
and there you can get started with SASS. There by the way,
you can also find the documentation where you can dive in much deeper and learn way more about SASS
if you want to do so
but again, I will walk you through the core features here.
So for now, let's simply click on learn SASS here and there, you can find out more about how it works and
you also see the command you need to run to compile an SCSS file in this case to a CSS file which
again you need to do to ship it. Now in order to compile it,
you need to install it
and for that you can click on that go here link, on that learn SASS page, to learn how to set your machine
up for SASS development.
Now there, you can find that there are a couple of tools you could install but we will use the command
line and for the command line, we can install a certain tool we can execute there to compile our files.
Now for Windows, you will need to install Ruby first and you can simply follow that link to the Ruby
installer here on the SASS page to simply download and install Ruby.
Now we won't write any Ruby code, SASS just is a Ruby gem, so a tool built with Ruby you could say and therefore
it requires the Ruby runtime to work.
So make sure to download and install that Ruby installer on Windows, on Mac, this is not required because
you already start with Ruby installed,
so once that is done, we can continue with these steps here, both on Windows and Mac.
We first of all should open a terminal or a command prompt and then we can install SASS by using the gem
command which should be available once you get Ruby installed.
So let's do that real quick,
I did open my Mac terminal here,
again you would execute the same command on Windows and now you run gem and then it's install SASS,
so gem install SASS. This will install that SASS tool which we need.
Now this can take a couple of seconds, so let's wait for this to finish
and what you might get is a permission error on Mac.
In this case, you should write sudo gem install SASS and you will be prompted to enter your password
thereafter
but this will now grant the right permissions so that you can actually successfully install it.
So now let's wait for this to finish
and once it's finished, we're already ready to write our SASS code and use that tool.
Now on Mac,
you also might get another error where it says that the installation failed, failed to build gem native
extension, you then need to run xcode-select--install,
this uses Xcode, the developer tools by Apple and you will be prompted in a new window
then, simply click install there and agree to the agreements and this will now simply download a certain
toolset from the official developer tools
Apple provides which are needed behind the scenes to compile that successfully.
So once this is done, we can go back to the terminal and then you should be able to successfully install
SASS.
So let's try this command again now,
the sudo gem install SASS command and now this looks much better.
You can confirm that it was installed successfully by running sass-v here and it should give
you the latest SASS version you just installed.
Now with that, you're ready to write SASS code
and for that, I'll switch back in our project. Now to be precise,
attached to this video, you find a little starting project.
If you open this by double-clicking the index.html file, you will see this,
these links worked by the way, so definitely feel free to dive deeper into this
after this module.
So this is a normal page styled with normal CSS, split across two files,
though I will admit the second file is not that big but you will see why that is useful or why this is
interesting. So this is just the CSS code
and obviously there is nothing wrong with it but we can already notice some things that can be improved
and hopefully, SASS can help us there.
So let's quickly identify these areas of improvement and let's then dive into SASS.