So our goal is to dynamically change the display property and for that, we need to understand how we
can in general change the style of elements with Javascript, why with Javascript? Because Javascript is
the only tool we got which allows us to run code after the page has been loaded and with this code, we
can of course change the content or the styling of the page.
Now you don't need to know Javascript to continue with this module here though,
I will explain carefully what we do.
It will help working with Javascript in general if you pick up a Javascript focused course along the
way though but for this course, to complete this course, you'll definitely not need it.
So we need to add Javascript and we could add it inline in our index.html
file by adding script tags, like this.
We can add them in the head section or in the body section and also at the end of the body section which
typically is the wiser way of doing it because this way it will ensure that all the HTML code has been
parsed already and we can safely access it at the point of time our script runs.
I however won't add my script code to the HTML file,
I'll put it in a separate Javascript file as we did it for our CSS code too.
So I'll simply create a new file in the project folder and I'll name it shared.js
because actually the code I put in here will be shared across the different pages of the project.
Now that shared.js file can now be imported with the help of these script tags and you need an opening
and closing script tag, that's important
and here in the index.html file in our root project folder at the end of the body section
but before the closing body tag, I'll add stript source, src and now simply a link to the shared.js
file,
basically just as we did it with the CSS imports, the import syntax is just a bit different.
With that, we execute that shared.js file and a quick way of demonstrating this is to simply throw
an alert where we say this works,
this will create a browser default overlay alert and let's see how this looks like,
if I reload this page, here we see this works, that is how such a browser alert looks like, it's not the
best user experience,
so we're not going to use this for our normal UI interaction with the user.
So let's get rid of that alert, it was just a test to see if the file is getting imported and let's instead
now focus on accessing the styles of HTML elements.
This actually is a two-step process.
First of all, we need to get access to a so-called DOM element,
the DOM is essentially what the browser makes of our HTML code,
it parses the HTML code and then creates a virtual representation of it,
the document object model or in short the DOM and we can essentially access the elements in the DOM
via Javascript and then manipulate them.
We can manipulate their attributes, we can execute certain actions,
we can listen to events on them,
we can access their styles, we can access their CSS classes, we can access their content,
we can even add and remove elements,
these are all things you learn in a Javascript focused course though, we'll focus on selecting the elements
and working with their styles or CSS classes.
So how do we select an element?
Let's go back to the index.html file and let's try selecting that backdrop.
Now how could we do that?
You can actually select elements with Javascript in a similar way as you select them
via CSS,
you can select them by tag, by ID, by attribute or by class and the detailed ways of selecting elements
again are the topic of a Javascript focused course,
the general approach always is the same
so let me show you how it works. In the shared.js file, I'll
first of all create a so-called variable to store the selected element
you could say, so that we can later use it.
I want to select the backdrop, so I'll name the variable backdrop but the variable name is really up to you,
it doesn't have to be the same name as the class,
this is not required.
So this variable should hold a value, it should hold a reference to the HTML element, to the DOM element.
We do this by using the document object,
this is a default element
you can say, we can access in the Javascript code provided by the browser,
it gives us access to the parsed document.
Remember I was talking about the document object model,
well this gives us basically access to the document object model. On the document, we can access a lot
of properties and methods and the method we'll need to get access to an element is the query selector
method. Query selector is executed like this with parentheses and then we pass an argument within the
parentheses and this argument now actually is just a normal CSS selector,
just as you could put it into your CSS code too.
You can use a tag here, an ID, an attribute selector or a class selector and you can also use combinators
like you could do some class and then add another class to point at an element which has another
class which has some parent with some class.
Here however, I'm interested in an element with backdrop,
so this is how I can select my backdrop.
Now here's a nice way of seeing what we actually selected,
we can use console log backdrop, like this.
Let's save that code and go back to the page and now make sure to open your developer tools and open
that console tab there.
If you now reload the page, you should see the log here
coming from our Javascript files and it should log the element it selected. It logs it in element
view here,
if you change console log to console dir, you actually see it in an object notation.
Now this is basically the object
you can now work with in Javascript and you see it's an object with a lot of properties and methods you
can call. This is the DOM representation of an HTML element and it is what we can work with.
Now important, our backdrop here essentially selects elements by class,
now query selector will always just select one element,
the first element with that selector it finds. Since this is a CSS class selector,
it could find multiple occurrences.
Now query selector like I just said will always select the first one,
if you get a case where you need to get access to all of them in a so-called array, you can use query
selector all.
How this would select all elements with the backdrop class and would return an array.
If I now save this and reload, you'll see we got a node list essentially and we would have to access
the element with the index 0, which is the first element, to get access to the first element with the
backdrop
and if we had multiple elements, we would have multiple elements of that list.
However back to query selector because I just want to have the first element,
I only got one anyways,
I just wanted to show you that this alternative exists.
So this is how we access an element, if we now reload again to see it, let's inspect which properties we
got here.
We see we got a bunch of properties here with all kinds of information and a very interesting one
when it comes to styling can be found towards the end of that list, the style property.
Now if we expand this, we actually see all the style properties we can set for this element and their
respective values.
Now one thing that can be confusing, if you scroll down to set index for example, you actually see that
it has no value here,
it's empty.
Now if we inspect our CSS code for the backdrop though, in shared.css,
you'll see that we actually have a set index of 100.
So why can't we see this here? Because of all the styles here are added as inline styles to the element and
this element, as all our elements, got no inline styles.
That's important,
the style property allows you to access inline styles.
I'll also show you how to access classes later in this module,
for now let's work with this inline styles. Since inline styles overwrite all other styles,
we can simply manipulate a style with the help of that style property
to change the appearance or the look of the element. Back in our shared.js file,
what we can do instead of logging this is we can access the backdrop and then the style property we
just saw
and then there, maybe for example the display property and keep in mind, we set it to none in our class.
Now here we set inline styles and we can set a new value by simply adding an equal sign and then assigning
the new value which has to be a string and then block for example,
this will overwrite our display none style from the CSS class.
Therefore if I save this Javascript file and I reload again, we see the backdrop again,
it's again there because if we inspect it, we can see in our styles that we set display
block here as an inline style which overwrites our class display none style. This is how we can select
elements in Javascript and how we can manipulate the styles.
Now let's also add an event listener to not do this by default but to instead manipulate what needs
to be manipulated
whenever we click one of these choose plan buttons here.