So why do we have to position our elements or how does it work so far actually?
Well, to understand this, we can imagine the following
HTML and body elements
and inside this body element we have three divs for example, three block level elements in our case
and as we know, the general behavior of these block level elements is the way it is displayed right here,
occupying the entire space available in the row where they are positioned and because of that, being
displayed one after another.
This basically is due to the fact that these are block level elements and that these elements are following
the document flow which is basically the flow of a normal HTML document that we have right here.
Now the question is, is there already some property applied automatically maybe which makes sure that this
document flow is followed or will be followed by the elements?
The answer is yes it is, the position property is applied automatically or by default
in our HTML code, specifically a value for this position property of static is applied.
As I said, this is the default value,
so if you specify nothing,
this is what happens
and this will basically lead to the case that we saw so far on a website and also to the situation that
we can see on the left,
so basically everything works as intended.
Now there might be situations where you want to change this normal document flow of your elements,
what could that mean?
Well for example, it might be the case that you want to position this first div right here in the right
upper part or right
upper corner of the HTML element or you might want to position the second div in the left upper corner of
the body element.
Now that's of course just some examples,
basically you could want to position any element on more or less any position on your website.
Now this is actually possible but not with this default value,
for that you have to specify a position property with a value of absolute, relative, fixed or sticky.
Now sticky is great out right here because sticky is a rather new value for this property and therefore
the browser support is not the best,
nevertheless we'll of course have a look at it and see how it works
but the general takeaway of this slide is that we need the position property in combination with a value
different, that's really important, different from the default value which is static to be able to change
the actual position of our elements on the website.
That's not everything of course because with that, with these values, we just specify that we want to
change the position
but we of course also have to specify how we want to change the position,
so where are these elements should be displayed. For that, we must think about some additional concepts.
To understand these concepts,
we can again imagine our website like this and now focus onto this element right here because let's say
that we apply the position property for this element with a value that is not equal to static,
keep that in mind already.
Now with that, we basically told our element, hey come on move to another position
and the element probably asked ok but where should I move to and for that, we have four different options.
We have top and bottom and we have left and right. Now of course we could also use this in a combination
like top and left, bottom and right or maybe all of these depending on what you want to achieve on the
website,
the important thing is that with these properties, these are our properties so top, right, bottom, left,
with these properties,
you change the position of the elements in your document flow,
that's important.
So these properties refer to the initial position in the document flow,
that's the first thing
but there is one other important concept that we have to understand because if we apply top 20 pixels
now to our elements right here,
well what does this mean,
what do these 20 pixels top refer to?
Well there are different options.
One option will be that this declaration refers to the element itself.
What does this mean?
Well basically it says please take the current position of my element and move it up by 20 pixels,
one option that we could have and we'll have a look at that of course.
Another option could be though that the 20 pixels refer to a distance for example,
so let's say it should be 20 pixels from the top of our viewport or of our HTML element, of our
body element or of more or less any other element.
So as you can see, we have a lot of options right here
and all these options refer to the so-called positioning context.
So this basically means, what does my positioning change that I want to achieve refer to?
So that's the pure theory,
let's now get a little bit more into a practical example, not by jumping back to our website immediately
but by going to an intermediate project,
so kind of a hybrid between theory and practice and play around with the property. Specifically,
I would like to show you what the exact behavior of the static value and especially of the fixed value
is.
So let's find that out in the next video.