Pixels, percentages and more, what do I mean by that?
Well so far we worked with two units basically,
we worked with the pixels, with the unit of px and we work with percentages,
so with the percentage sign basically. Now in addition to that, we got more units available in CSS,
for example we have the root em and the root em is written with a unit of rem. Root em or rem is a unit
that refers to the font size,
we'll see how this works throughout this module. In connection with rem,
we also have em written just like that,
em from a unit perspective. Em and rem both refer to the font size but there is also one important
difference between these two units,
we'll also find out what this difference is of course. In addition to that, we also have the viewport height,
written as vh and we have the viewport width, written as vw,
also two more units we didn't use so far but we'll dive deeper into these two.
The problem now is, well you probably have this question mark in your head now because we basically understood
pixel so far but we are not even sure about the percentages
and what they actually refer to
and then I come over with new units and with rem and em and so on,
so this is maybe a bit too much. But actually, we can break down these units and the issues arising in connection
with that to three core questions,
the first question probably is this one, which properties can I use in connection with these units? Because
we have all these units
but just applying a unit alone
won't help us a lot.
So we have to find out if there are properties which are really made or basically made to apply some
of these units, maybe all of them or a specific unit, we'll find out that
but the first question really is, what can I do with these units?
We'll of course answer this question.
The second question is how is the size calculated?
I talked about that already a bit
regarding the percentages because we always need something like a reference point.
We'll have a look at the percentages and I said that rem and em are kind of connected to the font size and
for vh and vw,
well it's called viewport height, viewport width.
This might be the viewport and you're right by the way
but we have to find out how exactly this calculation works.
And then after we understood this, the last question probably is, what's the right unit to choose right
now? Because we know that we have different properties,
we know how it's calculated but which unit should I apply for which properties, are there any best practices
or can you give me some advice?
The good news is, I think I can give you some advice but this will happen at the end of this module of
course
but why don't we just dive directly into the first question,
which properties can I use or where units matter? So here, you can find the question again.
Because basically we have our box model, Max already explained that to you,
so you're probably an expert in the meanwhile. In your box model, you have the content right here
and if we think about this content and we have the background color, for the background color we don't
need units but the font size,
I think this is probably a property where a unit, for example pixels as we did it so far,
definitely makes sense but maybe there is more than pixels that we can use for the font size.
If we then come back to our box model and think about the next step, this normally is the padding
and if we think about the padding which specifies the distance between the content and the border, well
then the padding itself would be a really good property to apply a specific unit that defines the size
of this padding.
The same thing is true for the border actually,
the border is also a property
where applying a specific unit
definitely makes sense
and if we follow our box model, then this is of course also true for our margin right here.
Now with that, we see that we have already four properties where units definitely matter.
Now let's continue, what else do we have in our box model?
Well we have this right here, the width and we have this right here, height because height and width are also
properties where we have to specify a unit, this can be a pixel or a percentage as we saw it so far but
maybe there are more units we can apply also and maybe there is also a unit which makes more or less
sense,
this is also something we have to find out.
By the way, at the moment I indicated the width and height with box sizing being set to border box,
just to remind you of that
but that's also something you know already by heart hopefully. However, with height and width, there are
only well basically four more properties where units actually matter. This one right here, the top and bottom
properties,
so properties that can be used after we be applied the position property, I showed you how this works
two modules go,
so you should also know about these properties and with top and bottom,
we also have this one right here, left and right.
So definitely, also properties where applying units makes a lot of sense. With that,
we now understood two things, that we have different units that we can use and that we have different
properties where applying the units make sense. The connection between the properties and the units
is not perfect yet,
we'll change that in this module
but with that, the first question,
so which properties can I use,
I think this one is answered.
And with that, we can now move on to the second question we had on the last slide,
how is the size now actually calculated for the different units?