We had a look at CSS variables and one problem there was browser support.
Now let's stay in that world,
obviously our users are able to use different browsers and different browsers implement new features
differently and at different speed.
Once a certain feature reaches recommendation state, you saw that earlier in this module, it should be
implemented in all browsers equally
but until then, each browser might not implement it or implement some of its features or maybe implement
some features differently than other browsers do, simply to try how it works,
how the users of that browser use that feature and so on.
For this, we got vendor prefixes.
This is a mechanism which allows browser vendors to implement an upcoming feature in an early version
without breaking the feature when it finally gets released,
here's an example, flexbox. We add it by setting display to flex and nowadays, the support for this is
pretty good.
A few years ago when that standard was brand new and in very active development, browsers started to
implement flexbox step-by-step by implementing prefixed versions of the flex value,
here are some examples.
Now the interesting thing here is these are special values which only work in some browsers,
for example webkit box works in older versions of Safari,
webkit flex in newer versions, MS flexbox in Internet Explorer and Edge.
So these values are not understood by other browsers but they don't need to understand it because they
either already implement the flex value or their own prefixed version.
Why do we use these prefixes at all,
why don't they just all use flex?
Because if the standard then changes or becomes finalized and they therefore all implement the same
specification, then if they suddenly overwrite the flex value to now work different than it used to be,
a lot of websites that were early adopters of that technology would get broken.
Therefore they have their early adopter implementation,
the prefixed version which they don't change even if the standard changes or becomes final and then
they implement their final version once that is the case.
So now they got different implementations and this allows you a developer to use these features ahead
of time,
it also ensures that your webpage won't suddenly break and it also,
that's another advantage, allows you to safely implement a certain feature which will still work, at least
to some extent,
even in older browsers because let's say an older version of Safari already supported flexbox with
webkit box but didn't support it with display flex.
Well, if you also provide that vendor prefix, it will understand this, it won't understand the other values
for display but it will then just ignore them,
that's how the web works and therefore, you can still use flexbox
even in that older version, even though it doesn't support flex yet.
I hope this makes sense.
So vendor prefixes are really great as they allow us to implement new features ahead of time and even
support older browsers.
Now let's see that in action on our website,
how would we implement such prefixes?
It's actually recommended to implement prefixes for flexbox, so let's do that.
Let's search for a flex value in our shared.css file, like here
and the correct way of implementing this would be to specify the display property a couple of times and
the final standard, the default one should be at the very bottom, because your code is parsed from top to bottom,
so they will start with the older versions and that's important so that the older versions don't overwrite
the newer ones and if they understand the newer one,
it will just overwrite the older ones which they also might have understood, otherwise if they don't understand
the newer one one but an older one
they'll use that. If they don't understand any of these,
well it just won't work.
So here we could add webkit box,
we could then add display MS flexbox and we could add display webkit flex for newer versions of Safari.
This is the correct setup,
this one overwrites the legacy versions,
so if a browser understands the new one, it will use that one,
if it doesn't,
maybe one of these can kick in. With that if we save that and we go back and we reload our page,
everything should still work there as it did before because we didn't break anything,
we now just have a chance of also making this work on older browsers.