So, what is this course all about?
Let's have a look at the outline now, because the course offers you three different tracks right here:
the basic track, the advanced track and the expert track.
Now what's the reason for that? With these different tracks,
we offer different entry points depending on your CSS skills.
Now no worries.
You can start the course right here,
it builds up on the knowledge step-by-step
but in case you already have some advanced or expert knowledge, you can jump in later to really dive
into the topics of your interest.
Now with that, let's have a look at the basic track now
because at the moment, we are almost done with getting started. After that, Max will have a look at the
basics of CSS and after that, dive even deeper into these basics.
So we will talk about core concepts like selectors or the box model, for example.
After that, in the next module, we will round up this basic knowledge by answering some common questions
like, "Should I use an ID or a class selector?"
With that, it's time to practice what we applied so far, we've worked on the project up to this point,
no worries
but now we will apply all the knowledge we gained so far and make sure to give all the different pages
on our website
a nice styling. After that,
I will take over and have a look at positioning. Positioning simply means that we are able to change
the position of our elements on the website.
Now with that, the basic track is done. Now we can continue right here with the next module; backgrounds
and images
or if you are an advanced user, you can jump in right here into the course. In the backgrounds and
images module, we'll have a look at
the style of backgrounds and images;
so these two different concepts,
how we can add them, how we can style them?
After that, I will have a look at dimensions, sizes and units together with you.
Following that, Max will have a look at the way JavaScript can manipulate the CSS styles applied
to a website. Following that JavaScript part,
we are almost done with the core structure of our website.
Therefore, it's then time to dive into responsive design, because up to this point, we will have created a desktop
website and although this is awesome, we also want to make sure that users who use a smartphone for example,
to visit our website also experience a very beautiful styling.
Now with the responsive design implemented, we'll have a look at forms; so we will learn how to add a
form to a website and also how to add some cool styling to it.
Finally in the last module of the advanced track, we will have a look at text and fonts, because using the
default fonts is OK but we don't want OK, we want
awesome!
So with the advanced track being finished, we will continue with the expert track and this track will
begin with Flexbox; an awesome tool or concept that allows us to dynamically change the way our elements
are positioned and displayed on our website.
After that, we'll have a look at the CSS Grid; a rather new CSS feature and very important, not the
same thing as Flexbox but we will have a look at the way CSS Grid works and also look at the differences
between Flexbox and the Grid.
After the grid, it's time to have a look at transformations, because by adding transformations to
our website, which allow us to, for example, rotate our elements, is also a really nice
feature
we should definitely learn about. Now with the transformations,
we'll also have a look at transitions and animations in the next module, because these are the features
that increase user feedback and therefore make browsing our website an even better experience.
Now with that, we are almost done with the course,
there are only two modules left. In the next module,
we'll have a look at writing future-proof CSS code, because we learned already that CSS is constantly
evolving,
therefore we want to make sure to stay updated and to write future-proof CSS code already today.
The last thing we'll have a look at is SASS. SASS kind of enhances CSS and makes working with it a bit easier.
So, we'll have a look at that
in this last module. With that, we will have finished this complete guide and now the question is, what does
it take for you to succeed in this course?