Because if we comment that in again
and with that, have our good looking layout once again, we can see that this declaration right here, the
values follow a certain pattern
obviously because the first value right here, this one, is the font family that we want to address.
Please note the capital letter right here and the quotation marks, the quotation marks are actually not
necessary all the time right here,
you have to add them though if your font family consists of multiple separate names
and so therefore, you have whitespaces, then it's required, right here
we could also delete those, like that
and if we now reload the page, we can see that it would still work.
Nevertheless, you can add them all the time,
it's not a problem actually
and after this font family, we have this sans-serif right here and as we learned, sans-serif is a generic
family and this already shows you the general pattern how you should write this declaration.
You first start with the most specific thing you have and the most specific thing you have is basically
your font family.
This could by the way not only be one family, this could also be two or more families,
for example we could use Verdana right here,
let's also add the quotation marks, like
that and then add sans-serif at the end. What will simply happen then is your browser will look for Monserrat,
in case you can't find it, you will apply the
Monserrat font family.
If they can't find it,
he will jump to the next font family, Verdana.
If it cannot find this one, he will jump through the next one and so on and so on
and in the end, he will simply fallback to this
fallback,
the generic family and then simply apply
a font family out of the generic family
you defined. Now what I simply mean by that is if we would fallback to sans-serif, the browser would select Helvetica
in our case because we specified in the browser settings that if the generic family that should be displayed
based on their code is sans-serif, then use the Helvetica font family please.
Let's maybe try that out quickly and enter a value as like unknown, right here,
so the unknown font,
I don't think this one is existing.
So if we now try this out and maybe not use for Verdana as our second font family because this is our
standard font right here,
so let's maybe use another font,
let's see which one looks different, this one right here,
yes,
Zapfino,
this
one right here,
this is a font family we will recognize.
So let's go back to our code and add this one right here, so Zapfino, like that and if we
now go back to our website right here and reload it,
then you can see that this relatively ugly Zapfino style was applied.
Why is this happening now?
Well because the unknown font family, so our first family right here could not be found of course,
therefore the browser goes to the next one, the font family Zapfino, which was available in case of the
Chrome browser, so
in my case and therefore, this font family will be applied.
If we would change that name right here to
maybe also unknown, like that
and then reload the page, we can see that the font style changed again because now, we fell back to our
sans-serif generic family right here and the sans-serif family that we have is this one, Helvetica.
If I would change that now again to maybe Zapfino, what we just had, then you would see that the website
changed according to that because the fallback simply says Please choose the sans-serif generic family
and then select the font family that we defined in the browser right here.
This was Helvetica I think, so let's add it back, like that,
if we go back, Helvetica is back here and that's actually the core idea of the syntax of this font family
property. You would define the property of course,
then you define the first font family you would like to have,
then the second one, as many as you would prefer actually
but in the end, you'll specify a generic family because with that, you always make sure that the text
on the website can be displayed and the text that should be displayed should at least be part of
a generic family of your choice.
However, we will change back one family to our default value and this was Monserrat right here, this
one because with that, our website looks the way it did before again. And for the next lectures, we will
not use the entire website to play around with the font families but we will focus on the packages.css
file and package info class.
As I said before, this basically refers then to this part right here
and with that, we can see the difference as to our default font that we applied and to the new font we want
to apply in an easier way.
So with that, if we think back about the slide, we understood this default behavior with the standard
font that will be defined or selected by the browser
if we don't add the font family property.
We also had a look at the generic family that we defined and with that, we allowed the browser to select
the font family that was selected in the browser,
this was our fallback basically and we had a first look at the definition of a font family in CSS.
What we didn't have a look so far at until this point is the difference between having the font family
saved on the user's computer
as a web font or retrieved from a server.
So in the next lecture, we'll have a look at this and dive in the different approaches,
the advantages and disadvantages and we will start in the next lecture with the fonts that are normally
installed on every user's computer,
we will see what ever user's computer actually is, how we can use them and what the limitations are that
we have
using this approach.