So we had a look at these vendor prefixes,
the question then of course comes up is, which prefix should you use?
Now there is a page, what CSS to prefix,
this gives a nice indication, it also links to caniuse which you also should use to find out where prefixes
are needed,
so if we quickly check the flexbox page on caniuse,
you can click show all to also see all browser versions
and there for example for older Chrome versions, you'll also see that there is partial support with the
webkit prefix and
the same is true for other browsers too.
So here you can see which prefixes might be needed to support these older versions and that should I prefix
page is of course a really great source to get a quick overview.
There, you see which features do not need prefixes and which ones should be prefixed
and then you even see the syntax you should use,
so this is a really valuable resource which helps you write code that works in more browsers.
However, clearly it is very cumbersome to check this for every feature you add and for manually adding
all these prefixes, thankfully there is a tool for that, auto prefixer. You can simply google for CSS
auto prefixer
and you should find this Github page here, post CSS
auto prefixer. This is a tool which automatically fetches a list of properties you should prefix
and then adds these prefixes to your code,
so it simply runs over your code and adds the prefixes and you specify which browsers you want to support
and based on that list of browsers you want support, it does the prefixing.
So let's see this in action.
If you scroll over that, you'll see multiple ways of including it,
you can include it in your gulp or a webpack workflow for example,
this is the way it's used most often by the way
but if you don't have such a tool or workflow and we don't have one, you can also just google for CSS
auto prefixer again and you'll find auto prefixer online.
Now if you open this page, you can just paste your code into this page.
So for example, we could grab our shared code and put it into that page and it would then, on the right,
give us the prefixed version of that code.
So as you see, it automatically added a lot of prefixes, for example for grids and so on
and now we could just grab that code on the right and put it back into our code
or maybe even better than that, into a separate version,
so shared-prod.css for example. By doing this, you now have a prefixed version of your code which
you can now import into your file instead of the old code and which now should work in more and also
older browsers.