I actually gave you a brief overview over the most important feature here in all these links.
We had a look at nested rules or selectors in the last video,
now let's have a look at nested properties.
Now what are nested properties?
Let's go up a bit, here in the container class,
I'm still in the main.scss file by the way.
There you see,
we got two properties from the flex namespace; flex direction and flex wrap.
Obviously we're not dying if we have to write this manually but what we actually can do now is we can type
flex, like this and now add curly braces and now add direction column and wrap, no wrap like this. This
allow us to remove these two lines here
and behind the scenes if we save this and we have a look at the created file and we scroll up to the
container, you'll see it still generated the code we had there before.
These are nested properties.
If they're from the same namespace,
so if they start with the same part here, flex-, font- and so on,
you can just use that namespace without the dash and then nest all the nested properties in there.
So this is a quick and nice way of also keeping your properties together.