So let's work on the title and the price of these elements
and for that, I'll add more classes to my HTML code. For the title, so free, plus and premium, I'll add a
class of plan__title and for the price,
unsurprisingly I add plan__price.
Now of course, these classes have to be added to all plans,
so the title to all the titles and the price obviously to all the prices we got here and for the last
plan.
With that added, we can again jump back to the main.css file and add some styling and I will
add it above
the plan features class selector, simply because in HTML, the title and the price come prior to the
features.
So now with that, here we can add the plan__title selector and set let's say the
color of the text to a darker green, maybe the same dark green we used before on our page.
If we now save this, this looks a bit more like value
in my opinion though, so I like the look of that.
Now the price, that's all is something we can change or where we might want to change the style,
I will add a plan__price selector here and set it to maybe a grey-ish color.
So maybe let's start with color, this grey
maybe is not dark enough, so let's pick a different one,
maybe go there
and by the way, if you're using Visual Studio Code, you can click on that rgb function to also get the hex
code version of that if you want, of course doesn't really matter,
you can use either of the two.
We then reload,
that looks nice but not in the highlighted plan. In the highlighted plan,
this price especially is not looking that great,
so let's go back and let's change the style for the highlighted plan price.
So for the plan highlighted, plan price,
now I'm using a combinator to target only the planned price classes in an element which
has the plan highlighted class.
There, maybe the better color for the price
also is that dark green.
Now since this is also the same color we used for the title,
we could also change the title. So I will again use plan highlighted but now together with the title
and change the color of the title
maybe to just white. So with these two changed styles for plan title and price in highlighted plans, if we
reload,
this looks better in my opinion,
this really leads to a better style of our plan.
With these things added, I'm liking the general look,
the buttons are things we can still work on and you also maybe notice that whilst everything is aligned
in the middle, the left and the right plan don't have an equal height which makes sense because the
left plan actually has a line break for this text here whereas the right one doesn't.
Now with the current toolset, it's not that easy to achieve that they all have the same height.
We could set the height property,
the problem just is that on bigger devices where this fits into one line, we'll have a lot of empty
space in this box thereafter
since the height is set to a fixed height but the content height changes depending on how many
line breaks we need. We'll later in the course learn about flex box, a tool which makes that much easier,
which allows us to really position the elements in a way that their height is equal and still looks
good when it comes to their content, that their content is centered vertically then and that you overall
can style this in a more appealing way.
So for now, this is what we'll work with
but be aware that we will change
this throughout the course, we're not stuck with this result.
So with that, let's move on and let's work on the button in the next lecture.