So what happened here, what did we do by applying flex direction to our parent element, to our flex container
and what does this have to do with the main axis and the cross axis?
Well this is our starting point, right,
we had our flex container and we applied the flex direction property with a value of row.
Now what happened then is, basically this is the default value as I said, is that our starting point for
the main axis is the left top corner of our element basically or of our website.
Now if the main axis goes from the top left to the top right, well then the cross axis which, that's
important, always has the same starting point as the main axis goes from the top left to the bottom left
corner of course.
So that's basically the default behavior, how our flex items are displayed then. They are displayed in
a row,
so along the main axis and from left to right. Now in addition to row, we also applied another value,
we applied flex direction row
reverse and if we think about the way row behaves,
so from the top left to the top right for the main axis, then row reverse simply behaves the other way
round.
It starts in the right top corner and goes to the left top corner and the cross axis starts also in
the right top corner,
as I said, they always have the same starting point and goes to the right bottom corner.
That's actually the first thing we have to understand about these two axis,
we have a main axis and a cross axis and depending on the value we apply to the flex direction property,
the starting point and the finishing point of these two axis changes.
Now let's go back to the code and play around with that a bit to really get a better feeling for it
because right here, we have our flex direction which is still row and the flex wrap is set to wrap which
is totally fine.
Now in our code, if we increase the size and reload it,
so what we can see right here is that the first flex item, so this one right here, starts in the top
left corner.
You will see in a few seconds why this is the top left corner and the flex direction is row, so
it goes from the left to the right
right here.
So this is the main axis now
and if we now reduce the size so that the wrap takes place, it simply wraps along the cross axis,
so from the top to the bottom
but as we can see, the first flex item is still on the top and still part of the top left corner right
here.
Now let's increase the width and let's now change the flex direction from row to row reverse. With
that if we go back and reload the page, we can see that the behavior changed because the way our main
axis and cross axis are defined also changed because now the starting point for both axis is the
top right corner of our flex container
but if I now reduce the width, as you can see it right here, the first flex item stays on top because keep
in mind, the starting point is still the top right corner but all the other elements are then aligned
along the cross axis,
so from top to bottom right there.
So that's what we have to understand now basically, with this flex direction, we can have an impact onto
this main and cross axis and this is only flex direction row and row reverse
but we also had flex direction column and column reverse.
Now let's go back to the slide and have a look at the theoretical concept behind these now because what
happened now if we again take our flex container and now apply flex direction column? Well then and that's
also another important thing,
the starting point is exactly the same that we had before for flex direction row,
it's still the top left corner
but now the main axis as you can see goes from top to bottom and the cross axis goes from left to right
and that's really crucial to understand because we will need that concept throughout this module. The flex direction
basically defines if our main axis is the row,
so from left to right or right to left with row reverse or if the main axis is from top to bottom or,
that's the second thing we can see right now, if we add flex direction column reverse or from bottom
to top, starting from the left lower corner.
So that's the tricky thing right here maybe but it's actually quite easy to remember. If the flex direction
is row, then the starting point is the top left corner and the row defines the main axis. With
row reverse, the starting point is the right top corner and the main axis is of course the row. If the flex
direction is column, then the starting point is again the top left corner
but the main axis now goes as the direction indicates, along the column
and if we have column reverse, then the starting point is the bottom left corner and the main axis is
again the column.
Now let's also have a look at that in our practical example now because right here, if we go to
our flex container and now change the flex direction from row reverse to column like that and reload our
page right here, you can see exactly what we just saw on the slide.
The main axis now starts in the top left corner and the items are aligned along the main axis.
Now that's important,
the main axis now goes from top to bottom.
If I would go back now and change it to column reverse like that and reload the page again, then the starting
point is the bottom left corner right here
and as we can see, the items are again aligned along our main axis which is
now this one right here.
So with that, we saw the core concept behind flex direction,
it allows you to define the way our elements are displayed
and really important, to also specify the main and the cross axis and the main and cross axis is a really
important concept that we need to understand now because it has an impact onto other properties we
can use. If we for example go back right here and change our flex direction to row again, like that and
now go back and reload the page, we could already see that if I increase the width, that the elements, so the height
of the elements, simply adjust to the largest elements, so the one with the largest height you could say
and well so far, we simply accepted this behavior
but the thing is that we can change this behavior, so also the height and default behavior our elements
have right here.
For that, we need additional properties and we need to understand the concept of main versus cross axis.
Well the latter one is something we understood now but now it's time to have a look at these other properties
we could apply now.