In the last lecture, we added different selectors to ensure that our second section and h1 tag doesn't
look like our first one.
Now maybe there's one thing you did wonder about.
We do a set the h1 tag to have a white color and then we set the section title class to set a
green color,
now actually both selectors here match our second h1 tag.
We still have our h1 selector in place here,
so it still selects the second h1 tag too,
it doesn't stop selecting it just because we added a class and then a class seems to overwrite this.
Now you could argue, this happens because the section title class is defined after the tag selector
and as the file probably is parsed from top to bottom which it is, this simply overwrites the previous rule.
You would not be entirely wrong by this, though actually if you switch the order, just for demo purposes
here and you reload the page, you see that the styling still applies,
so the class still overwrites the h1 tags style.
On the other hand, if you quickly assign the h1 tag again and set the font family back to serif and
not to anton and now you save and reload, you'll see the h1 tags get changed,
so the fonts did change.
So the order does seem to matter but only if you use the same selector, the class still overwrites
the color,
so that's really strange
and there's one additional strange thing.
If the class somehow overwrites the styling for the h1 tag,
so if it still sets the green color, why doesn't it also clear the font family?
Now we set it back to serif manually here with the second rule
but even before we did this and it becomes clearer if we set this to sans-serif, like this, now it's changed
to sans-serif style but not back to anton,
now you can still see this section title doesn't seem to clear the font family.
It clearly overwrites the color but it doesn't reset the font family, so it still keeps that style around.
So two things are going on here,
multiple rules seem to affect the same element and additionally, the different rules here seem to have different
priorities because otherwise, how would we explain that
this section title class overwrites the color, even though it comes before we set up the other rules?
Now let's explore what's going on here and for that, we'll use the developer tools.
You can open the developer tools by pressing command option and i on Mac or F12 on Windows or you open
it from the menu of your browser,
here I'm talking about to Chrome developer tools by the way. Now in the developer tools, you get a couple
of options in case you never worked with that.
If you clicked on elements, you'll see your HTML code so to say and you can select elements by expanding
and clicking there and then at the bottom, you see which styles are getting applied to these elements.
You can also select that element from within your page
by right-clicking on it and choosing inspect,
this also works if the developer tools are closed, they will open then. If they are opened, it will just
jump to that element and select it, as you can see here and you can also pick that tool here on the
top left of the developer tools
and now click on element in your DOM to also quickly inspect it.
Now if we do that on that h1 tag in our second section and we bring this up a bit here, we can actually
see which styles are getting applied and the list here has to be red from top to bottom with the top
most style taking the highest priority.
Now there you see, a couple of styles are indeed getting applied.
If you scroll down, these are all styles that are applied to that h1 tag.
You see the topmost is actually an empty style,
that would be the inline style if you add the style attribute to the h1 tag because it turns out that
inline styles have the highest priority
or this concept is called specificity to be precise but then you see that the class selector, section
title appears. So it seems to have a higher specificity than the h1 selectors which are coming below it,
you'll see two h1 selectors because we got two in our CSS code and if you watch closely, you'll see the second
one with just the font family, sans-serif, has a higher priority or specificity than the first one simply
because it comes second in the file and the file is parsed top to bottom but again as already recognized,
the section title class overwrites them both even though it comes earlier in the file but internally
by the CSS specification, it seems to have a higher specificity and it does.
If you scroll down further, there also are some browser defaults for that element and these have the
lowest priority
they do apply though
but you can overwrite them and that is something we will also do later.
So these are the styles which are getting applied,
the fact that we have multiple rules affect the same element is the cascading part
of the feature we're using here.
CSS stands for cascading style sheets and cascading simply means multiple styles can be applied
or multiple rules can be applied to the same element.
Now these rules may lead to conflicts though,
here for example, we got our color set up in the h1 tag
and in the section title class.
Now to resolve such conflicts,
CSS knows a concept called specificity and there are clear rules included in the CSS specification
that define how such conflict should be resolved and which type of selector has a higher specificity
.
Now here is an overview,
as I said cascading means multiple rules are applied to the same element. Specificity resolve conflicts
arising from that fact and specificity then simply has the following order,
the tag selector and also pseudo elements selectors which we haven't had a look at yet but which we
will see in the course, have the lowest priority, the lowest specificity.
Well actually, the universal selector, that star has the lowest priority but you rarely use that.
So tag selectors have the lowest one then, a higher specificity is assigned to class and pseudo class
as well as attribute selectors.
So these three are on the same level and if we then have two conflicts here, simply the latter one in
the same file wins,
just as we had it for the two h1 tags in our CSS file.
Now pseudo classes are also something we'll see later in the course,
this is something like controlling hover effects on an element,
so if you mouse over it. A higher specificity is assigned to ID selectors, so if an element has a tag, a class
and an ID selector and they all set the color of that element, the ID selector would actually win
no matter where it is positioned in the CSS file.
The highest priority however is assigned to inline styles,
we saw that earlier but we shouldn't use them
but if you add them, they will actually overwrite all other styles,
they have the highest specificity.
Now there are more rules connected to specificity, some advanced things connected to things like inheritance
which we hadn't a look at yet but these rules here are important to keep in mind,
tag selectors have the lowest specificity, inline styles have the highest.
Now this doesn't mean that you should always use inline styles,
it just means you should be aware of this and you should style your page cleverly by actually using
all these types of selectors,
maybe without inline styles though and simply be aware of how they overwrite each other and it's actually
not hard to work with these correctly and we will do it throughout the entire project,
so there is a lot of space for you to practice it.
So back to code then, let's see how this actually has an impact in reality and what else is connected
to this concept.