Ok, the last one was a quick one,
nested properties can be really useful.
Super useful are variables though,
now what are variables? Now variables allow us to define a certain value and reuse it throughout our
code,
for example that color here. This color, this exact color is getting used a lot
as you can see, here
we use it quite a lot in our code.
Now if we define it like this and we ever decide we want to use a different color, we have to go to all
these places in our code and manually adjust it, which is not super comfortable.
So what we can do typically at the top of the file, we can define a so-called variable, a feature which
is also available in next gen
CSS, you learned about CSS variables already but which is also available here in SCSS and when using variables
in SCSS, you of course have the great benefit that it will be compiled to code which does not use CSS
variables,
so which will run in all browsers and not just in more recent ones.
So this is a great way of using variables without having to support cutting edge browsers only. You define
a variable by adding a dollar sign, that always has to be the first character and then the name of your
variable, maybe main color and then you simply add a colon and the value you want to store,
in my case the hex code, #521751, that is the color we're using everywhere.
Now with this saved here, we can use that variable in our file.
Now by the way, you can in general store as a value here for the variable
what you can use as a value in CSS, so you could also store center or something like 1rem, whatever
you plan to do with that variable.
Now in my case here, I want to use a color,
so I will store a color.
Now we can grab that variable name, including the dollar sign and replace all the hex code usages here
in our SCSS file with that variable name
and when this gets compiled, this will simply get replaced with the value of our variable. Again which
whichever value that would be,
of course the value stored should fit to the properties you're using the variable on.
So with that, if we save this and we reload our page, we see the same as before
and if we have a look at the compiled code, we also see that the color code is in there which is exactly
what should be the case.
It doesn't use variables in the CSS file,
it uses the real value,
it just replaces our variables with that value we stored in there.
So this can be thought of as a placeholder so to say and that of course is great because it's downward
compatible but actually on our page, we can do more with variables,
there are more things we're reusing and you can not just store single values in a variable,
you can also store lists or maps in variables.
So let's have a look at that in the next lecture.