So how can we now add a badge to our package right here?
Well I think a good starting point would be to go to the HTML file, right here and add such a badge
right there in the HTML code. For that,
we have to go to our packages class right here, this one and we need the plus package because that's the
one we want to recommend.
So let's maybe add the element right here, another h2 element and we could give it a class of course
of package-badge maybe, this makes sense again with our BEM notation right here
and let's maybe write or name it RECOMMENDED, with capital letters like that.
This looks like this now,
well not really beautiful yet but we will see how we can change that
but at least we have our recommended text already here.
The question now is, how can we change the position
because that's what this module is about. Right now, to position this badge right here,
maybe in the right upper part of our package. Of course we could maybe add a left margin or a bottom
margin but I don't think that would work and that would be a good idea
from a code perspective but maybe we can use this position fix declaration to
kind of position it right here
because it worked with the navigation bar,
so why don't we give it a try and see if we can use that knowledge.
So let's go back to our packages.css file and remember package__badge, that's
the class we want to refer to
and why don't we add that new class
maybe right here
before the package subtitle. So it was package__badge and now we learned that we can
use position fixed, like that.
Let's see what happens now, if we go back, yes the recommended badge is taken out of the document flow,
it's positioned in the middle of nowhere though,
so we learned how to change that,
we can simply add top zero and left zero, right like that.
So let's reload it again,
now it's positioned to the left of the viewport
and we also have a distance to the top. Yes, this is the margin,
I think we can keep this margin, this is fine,
we can maybe even add a margin for the entire element,
let's see how big this margin was, right here in the developer tools. We have a default margin of
almost 20 pixels,
so let's maybe add such a margin now, 20 pixels like that and with that, yes we got the badge positioned in the
left upper corner of our viewport.
Well, this is nice
and we could now play around with that
and for example increase left to, I don't know, 400 pixels to have a bigger distance right here, like that.
Yes we're getting closer and then we could add a little bit more for the top distance, maybe 50 pixels,
just guessing, like that,
so it's moving down
but as you can see, this is a lot of trial and error
and in the end, the core problem is that the recommended badge would be related to the viewport
and if we scroll down, well it would behave like that,
definitely not the behavior we want to have for such a badge.
So maybe there is another value for our position property which brings us closer to the behavior we want.
The good news is there is because we can simply change position fixed to position absolute, like that.
Now that
we changed it to absolute,
let's see if that changes our website. Apprently nothing changed
but let's scroll down
and as we can see, if we scroll down now, the element is no longer stuck to the viewport,
it is now stuck to, to what is it stuck actually? Well for absolutely positioned elements, the positioning
context is defined based on two cases.
If none of the ancestors, so of the parent elements, has a position property applied, well then the positioning
context of the element is simply the HTML element.
If we have the second case that we have any position ancestors, then the closest ancestor which has the
position property applied is the positioning context for this element.
Now let's see what is the case in our situation. If we simply change top 50 pixels to top zero once again,
like that and reload the page,
well we can see that our element apparently is stuck to the HTML element because that's actually the
element that wraps the entire website.
If we would change that and now add a position property to our package class though
right here,
so let's add position absolute right there,
as you can see in the index.html file, we are in this class right here
and the package class is an ancestor.
If we reload the page right now, well this kind of crashes our entire website because now all the packages
are displayed with an absolute value
and as we know, this takes all the elements out of the document flow and therefore, we have this mess.
But isn't there another position value that we could apply that doesn't crash our entire website?
Well yes it is
and we'll have a look at this value later but for the moment, we will simply apply it to our package
class right here and this value is relative, like that.
With that if we reload the page, we can see two interesting things already.
Apparently the relative value doesn't take our elements out of the document flow
but as I said, we'll dive deeper into that later
and the second interesting thing is that the positioning context of our recommended element right here
now changed to the closest ancestor which has a position property applied
and this is the anchor but if we unselect the inspect tool, we can see that the package class
basically is this ancestor as we also saw it right here in the HTML code,
so the badge and then we have the package class right there.
So what have we seen so far? The fixed and the absolute value are quite comparable
in general, both take the elements out of the document flow if you apply these values to these elements
but for the fixed value, the positioning context always is the viewport, for the absolute value, the positioning
context depends.
If you don't have any ancestors with a positioning property applied, then the positioning context
is the HTML element,
we saw that right here.
If you have ancestors with the position property applied, then the element, the absolutely positioned
element, will be positioned in relation to the closest ancestor which has such a position property applied.
With that, we basically made sure that our badge is at least positioned inside the right package but
we didn't position the badge itself.
Let's see how this works in the next video.