So as you probably guessed by now, developing for the web isn't trivial
because we need to support many browsers, at least in some of our pages we need to do that.
Another problem we face
besides some features not being supported in some browsers are cross-browser inconsistencies, this means
that different browsers use different defaults.
You remember this default styling some elements get? The default font size of h1 tags, the default
font family which gets used, things like that, browsers implement that differently. For some elements, we
might have different margins or paddings, different box sizing behavior, that box sizing is set to border
box in some browsers for some elements by default for example and so on.
This is not necessarily bad, different browsers offer different defaults and some users might pick
a browser because of some of the defaults it offers
but some defaults are also annoying and you want to have a consistent look of your webpage across
browsers too.
Therefore, you can implement some reset libraries like normalize.css,
which is a CSS package you add as one of the first imports or as the first import in your
HTML file, which basically overwrites some of the global browser defaults.
So for example, this could set box sizing to border box for all elements or you do that manually of
course.
For example in our code, in the shared.css file, we are doing such a reset with a universal selector
where we set box sizing to border box.
This is one of the things normalize.css or other packages like it might do for you,
you can of course do it on your own.
Now very important to keep in mind, if you use a package like normalize.css which resets a bunch of
things, that of course is additional code your users need to download and therefore, this increases
the size of your page so to say.
Still, it might be worth it but there are a lot of arguments these days that maybe it's just better to
do that box sizing reset because that really is annoying if it doesn't work like this and not reset
anything else but simply overwrite things, like font sizes, like font families or colors if you work with
that specific element which actually is affected because you could also argue that packages like normalize.css
reset
a lot of styles which might never be used in your page because you never use that element which it resets.
For example if you never use a select element, it doesn't matter to you if the styles for it are reset
globally or not.
So keeping in mind that resetting some features makes sense and that you can do it manually with the
star selector or by using packages is definitely something which is important.