Now that we worked on all these styles here, on the styles of our elements,
let's think about validation.
Now what does validation mean?
Validation means that in a real form, we typically require certain things; we want to make sure that
no field is empty for example, that the email field has a valid email address,
stuff like that.
Now there are tons of ways of implementing validation and this is not really about the implementation
logic, you normally always have to do validation on the server
as a side note,
so validate the inputs on your server side code because the client can always be tricked, here
it's only about providing nice user feedback.
Now which typical approaches do you have for validation?
Typically as I said, you use server side validation.
So you click that button, a HTTP request is sent to the server and once it reaches the server, it there
is validated and maybe if it's invalid, the form page is returned to the client and you present it to
the user again and you want to mark the inputs which are invalid as invalid.
Now one obvious approach to giving the user such feedback is that you define special CSS classes
which are attached to an input
if it is invalid and it is attached to that input on the server side when this page is re-rendered or
also on the client-side through Javascript. Now here we will hardcode it in there though
but it's easy to then just add this conditionally in a real project when the form is invalid.
So let's say the e-mail would be invalid,
then you might add a class named invalid, the name is totally up to you though
and again, this is added either on the server when you rendered the page or through Javascript.
Now here we hardcoded it,
the idea now is to simply take that invalid class and give it a special style.
So now we could in the end just go to our signup-form input selector here and say signup-form input.invalid,
this simply selects all inputs that are invalid and probably do the same for selects and then just maybe
set the border to one pixel solid and red and a background color of
maybe not red but some light red color, like this. With this if you save this and reload,
now the e-mail would be marked as read.
Now the border, here
I actually just want to set the border color to red and I need to reposition this so that this takes
priority, I'll add it of course and that is the right way
after all my other input styles because this always should overwrite all other styles because it's only
conditionally anyways
and now we have this clear invalid state and that's really all that's to it.
You would add this class to any input that is deemed invalid,
so for example, let's also add it to the checkbox and see how it looks there
and let's also add it to the select element here,
class invalid like this.
If we reload,
now these are invalid
too. So that's pretty cool,
so now we have a way of marking
these, that's the manual approach.
You simply add a class on any condition defined by you, either on a server or through Javascript and you
just simply give that class the invalid styling you want to have.
Obviously, you're not restricted to backgrounds and borders here,
you can set whatever you want. Now this is the manual approach,
HTML and CSS actually offer you a more elegant way of doing that though,
there is a special pseudo selector, the invalid pseudo selector.
So let's add another rule here,
signup-form and let's target any element inside of that form.
So there is a blank after signup-form which has the invalid pseudo selector.
You could of course also restrict this to only target inputs or selects,
here I'm targeting anything. With this if I save this and I reload,
nothing happens here
but in the e-mail, you actually see as soon as I click out of there, this now has the invalid style.
The reason for this is that HTML
so to say or the browser automatically validates this because our e-mail input is of type email and it
detects that
T here is no valid email address and hence, it marks this as invalid and adds this special invalid pseudo
selector.
The only problem we have is that our nice border is getting overwritten by that not selector here,
even though we specify our selector here with invalid after that, the reason for this simply is that
not and the selector in not takes a higher priority and hence, this goes first.
Now here, one solution would be to actually add important, here you could make an argument for it because
this is a temporary class only anyways and it should
overwrite
anything else, the other solution of course would be to incorporate this not selector here too and simply add
this rule in there too,
so add another rule here and target inputs which are not a checkbox which are invalid.
This is really long though
and from a performance perspective, this is not so good to parse,
so maybe we just go with the important solution here
in this rare case.
So now with that, if we reload and I type a T in there again, it's invalid again.
If I start typing, we get the green background because the focus state takes a higher priority but that's
fine
but I'd say this is a
nice automatic way of validating this.
Now if you want to validate the other inputs too, this is now just HTML, you can add things like the required
attribute, a HTML and browser feature which tells the browser that this is invalid if it's empty.
So we can add required to all the inputs here, like this and to the password
and now if we reload, everything is ready right from the start because it's all empty
and only if we enter something there, we get out of that invalid state.
Now it's up to you if you want that,
obviously you're greeting your user with an all red form here.
You could find some combinations,
for example you could change your selector to not select any invalid elements inside the signup-form
here
but anything inside a
signup-form which has a class needs validation or whatever you want, you are free to name this however
you want and then you add this class dynamically with the help of Javascript when the submit button
was clicked,
then you would apply these styles
after the user had a chance of doing something but you essentially need Javascript for that,
it doesn't work without that.
So I'll go with this approach for now
and now we added quick and easy validation.
One important note, there also is a valid pseudo selector
and as you might be able to guess, this just does the opposite.
So now anything that is treated is valid
and please note that even the button or the form as a whole to be precise has this valid invalid style,
now everything that's treated as valid would get these styles. So I'll turn this back to invalid
but again, these are nice things to know.
Now one other nice thing to know;
in the Mozilla Developer Network documentation for invalid,
if you scroll down, you'll not just see examples,
you also can see the browser compatibility which is quite good.
You'll also note that the overall form invalid and the same is true for valid classes which we saw in
action a second ago when the button became red, this is not supported in all browsers, to be precise
Edge and Internet Explorer, the usual suspects, they don't implement it,
so if you're relying on that, might not work. In the way we're using it on a per input level, this is supported
in all browsers though,
so that's great.
Now with that, we're almost done,
let's focus on this button now before we finish.