So what are lists and maps?
Well, let me introduce you to this. A list simply is a variable that holds more than one value,
a typical example would be something like the box shadow here,
this is a list of values,
it's not just one value, it's a list of values
and of course we could store each value individually in a variable and then construct this from multiple
variables
but it's easier if we just store this.
So here we're not actually reusing the box shadow,
maybe we find another example where we are reusing it.
An example would be the border, this border definition with 0.05rem solid and the main color, we use
that twice.
So let's grab that value here and create a new variable which I'll name border default
and now I just put the value in there.
Now as I mentioned, you can basically put anything you find on the right side of a colon into a variable
but this officially is named a list because it's more than one value.
We can now grab that border default variable and use it wherever we use that set up,
so here for that border in SASS introduction and also for that border in the SASS details here.
There is one more border at the bottom for documentation link. So now we're using that border
default variable everywhere
and as you can see, you can also use variables in variables,
we're using the main color variable in the border default variable
and if you save this and you reload your page, you again see no changes because this was replaced correctly.
As you can see, if you check out the main.css file, there you'll see the border was replaced with
the value you stored here, this however is called a list. Another list would for example be the font family,
so a list is not just something where you have whitespaces separators,
if you use a comma as seen here, this also would be a list you could store it in the variable.
Now we could do that for this set up but since we're not reusing this, it doesn't really matter if we
stored it in a variable or not
but you could do this,
this is also called a list.
Now on the link here, you actually see lists and maps though.
So what is a map then? Well a map is simply a list where each item has a name by which you can access
it.
Now what does this mean?
Let's add a new variable which I'll name colors because let's say we've got a couple of different colors
in our app, as we actually do.
We do have that purple color but if you scroll down, you also see for example that orange color which
we use and there is one additional color which I won't put into the map though.
Now I already mentioned it,
I want to create a map of colors,
obviously we could use main color, we could use secondary color and we could store all these colors and
variables and there would be nothing wrong with that
but sometimes you want to have more structure and you want to group your variables and map allows you
to do that.
A map is constructed by adding parentheses
first of all, that is how you simply start a new map. In the parentheses,
you now create key-value pairs by first of all defining a key,
so a name of your choice, like main, you could name it main color but we're already in the colors map
so it's clear that this is a color.
So main is the key,
then you add a colon and then the value of the key and you add more key-value pairs by adding a comma
and then adding secondary
and now that would be the orange color. With that, we can actually comment out the main color and by
the way, you can now see that you can use two forward slashes as comments,
this would not be possible in normal CSS but SASS allows you this commenting syntax
and now we can use our color map to set our values. The question just is, how do we get this value
or these values out of the map?
For example in all the places where we did use main color before, like here in the border default variable
definition. It's simple, SASS also is a couple of built-in functions, one of them being map-get which allows
you to get a value from a SASS map.
There, you first of all pass the name of the map, which is colors
in our case and then the name of the key you want to get, in our case main. If you now save this, you
of course get an error because we get a couple of other places in the app where we're still trying to access
main color.
So let's copy that map-get syntax and add it there,
so in all the places where we're using main color, we want to use that map-get function now to instead
extract our color from our color map.
Let's also do it for the orange color here,
there we have to reference secondary though
and now with that, if we save this again, it should successfully compile.
If we check out the compiled file here, we can also see that it
now still use our colors correctly, also the orange color down there and if we reload our page, this
also looks unchanged
but now we're organizing our code a bit more efficient by using a map for our colors,
hence we're grouping these values according to their function which makes a lot of sense I guess
and by using normal variables or actually a list variable here too.
So these were lists variables in general and maps
and as you can see, this allows you to save a lot of code because you simply can define it here
and then you use these variables
and if you ever want to change something, you change it here once and you're good to continue.