So time to have a look at the last property in connection with the flex container and this property
is called align content,
so basically, a combination of align items and justify content.
Now let's start with align content center right here.
If we do that and reload our page,
nothing changed
but if we now decrease the size, can you see the difference?
Well let me show you right here by going into the developer tools
and let's now unselect align content right here, like that.
Can you see the difference? Align content allows us to align our items along the cross axis.
As for the other properties, we have different values available for align content, you can find links
to that attached to this video.
So this is center, with that we centered our items but we can also add something like flex start once again,
like this
and if now reload the page, you can see that the items are positioned at the beginning of the cross
axis.
If I increase the size, it jumps back to this behavior
because keep in mind, we have align items and justify content center,
so this is basically what we see right here
but as soon as we have our second line available right here, the align content property will come into
play.
We also have other values for it,
for example we have space between, this one right here and if we apply this value, can you see what
happens? The space between our elements is now simply used in a way that the elements in the first row
are positioned at the beginning of our cross axis and that the second row is positioned at the end
of our cross axis,
it's also a nice way to display values like that differently.
So that was it actually, that's the last property we have for our flex container,
let's maybe change this back to center for example,
I think that's the better way to display our elements right here but still, the theory is done
and the theory is nice but I think now it's time to jump back to our project and to see where we can
add flexbox right there because as you hopefully saw, it's quite a powerful tool actually
and just by adding these lines of code right here, these ones right here, excluding the commented out
part of course,
we were able to change a lot of the behavior of our elements.
So in the next lecture, we will go back to our project and see what we can change right there.