Let's add a customers page and for that, let's first of all create a new folder in our project, I'll name
it customers and in there, I'll create an index.html file and a customers.css
file. Now into the index.html file, copy the code of the file, the HTML file you'll find attached
to this lecture,
this content here.
Now there, we already also have the import to
customers.css,
so that is added right out of the box.
Now we also need to add our header here though,
so let's go to index.html and grab our entire header code from there and go to the customers
page and add it here,
by the way let's also add the updated header with our image to our packages file.
However for that, let's first of all fix the images path
here in the customers header,
we need to go up one level to reach the images folder
and again let's do the same for our other header.
Actually, we just need to copy the image here, the header image,
so let's go to the packages folder and replace the uHost text with the image there too, make sure that
the path is correct here too.
So back into the customers file, we got the header,
we get that main content I shared with that attached file,
you see some text and you also see some image imports there and we get the footer.
Now regarding the image imports, you'll find two images attached to this video too,
customer 1 and 2,
let's insert these into our images folder
and with that, the last thing I have to do is check if our links are correct.
So on the main page, here index.html, in the navigation, we should navigate for customers to the
customers folder and the index.html file
and for packages if we go there, we should go to one level up and then into the customers folder and from
inside the customers page, in our header,
we also need to adjust the links because we copied that in from our main page. For packages,
we should go up one level and then go into the packages folder. For the brand,
we should also go up one level and then navigate to index.html,
so to our main.html file. For customers
however, we can just target index.html because that's exactly the page we are on and start hosting,
well we don't have that yet,
we'll add it later.
Just a quick check in
packages,
ok
the brand link is OK.
So with that if we save all files and we reload the page, we should be able to go to customers now and
here we get our two customer testimonials.
Awesome guys,
they really like our service and I like that
we position them in a very prominent way but maybe a little bit too prominent, maybe we can do more with
their images,
especially if we consider that I wasn't even zoomed in. So if I do zoom in as I am on the rest of the pages
to make this more readable,
yes
then we really got some styling issues here, we don't even see our customers that well.
Now over the next lectures, we'll work on this page, mostly on the images of course.