Enough off cross-browser problems, unsupported features,
let's think about our code,
how should we actually name our class names? As you saw in this course,
the class selector is probably the selector you used the most often because it allows you to create reusable
styles and even if you only apply a class to one element, you can give it a really expressive name which
makes it far easier to understand your CSS code.
Here are some dos and donts when it comes to class names. Dos;
use kebab case,
so this is class name style where you use lowercase characters and separate words with dashes.
It's important because CSS is case insensitive,
so if you use snake case for example, where you have one word and separate the words with uppercase characters,
this is not something CSS understands,
for CSS, snake case with a capital C is the same as snake case with a lowercase c.
So if you got two classes with the same name and you think they are different, they aren't and this can
lead to strange behaviors.
Additionally since you can't use this snake case version, you would have to use really long words without
any separators which are hard to read,
so use kebab case,
it's easy to read, easy to understand and the browser understands it too.
Another important hint,
name your classes by feature, for example page title.
It's very clear what this style will do,
we don't know which element your page title is,
if it's h1, h2 or a div
but this doesn't matter,
we know that this probably will refer to the page title.
Don't name your classes by the style they're going to apply,
for example title blue is a really bad name.
Yes, we can guess that this probably will color the title with a blue color but we can see that by the
properties and values you then use in that rule anyways
and if you ever change the color of your text to be red, then you probably have to rename your class.
So this is a really bad class name,
name them by feature instead.
In this course,
I actually try to follow a convention which is called Block Element Modifier styles, BEM.
This is a convention which makes sure that we name our classes in a uniform and consistent way across
our project and that we also prevent clashes because as you can imagine, the bigger your project gets,
the higher the chance of you reusing some class name unintentionally and all of a sudden, you might overwrite
the style somewhere else in your page without you noticing it at first.
Therefore BEM enforces a certain way of naming are classes which should minimize this risk.
You obviously start with a dot in the selector but then you have the block portion of the name, two underscores,
the element portion,
maybe two dashes and then an optional modifier.
Here is an example,
here we got a selector which selects the menu main item which is big or which has a big size.
The block here is our main menu, hence menu main, you could of course also name this main menu,
we select a single item in that main menu and we select an item which is very big, which should receive
some special style because it's big.
The last part, the modifier kind of goes against this rule of not naming classes by style but in the
end,
this is not the entire class name,
the whole thing here is the entire class name.
Here's another example,
we got a selector which selects a button which has no special element, so all buttons but which also
has the success modifier.
Now mastering this is something which is very hard obviously and you can probably flame me for some
of the class names used here but if you follow this pattern in general, you already gain a lot.
If we have a look at our source code here, you'll see I try to follow this,
we got a main header here,
we got the toggle button and then we got a sub-element in the toggle button, so these horizontal bars
in the hamburger button.
We got the brand in the main header and so on, so this is the idea, here we got a call to action modifier
on the main nav item.
These classes look a bit ugly but they really help you prevent clashes of class names
and once you get into the idea of these class names, they also help you understand what a certain class
selector is probably referring to.