So in the last lecture, we worked with height and width.
Well that's all nice,
we change the height and width of the box unsurprisingly
but what exactly did we change? When we set the height and the width, did we set the height and width
of the content, of the content plus the padding, of the content, the padding and the border or of the content
the padding, the border and the margin,
well let's take a look. Let's take a look
by inspecting that section where we did set width and height. There if we scroll down to our box model,
what we can see is that in there, we set the width and height of our box here
I'd say. The width is calculated dynamically as we increase and decrease the page width because it's
set to 100% and the height is the 522 pixels
we added in our code but let's now quickly add some padding back to the party.
Let's maybe add a padding of 10 pixels, a border of 5 pixels solid and black and a margin of 10 pixels.
If we now save this and we reload the page, we can already see one strange thing,
it shifted a little bit to the right,
the 100% width leads to our red element to go out of the right side of our page
and that doesn't change if we decrease and increase the page width because it's already set to 100%.
So something seems to be wrong with the width.
If we scroll down to our box model again, we now see something strange,
the height really is 528 pixels for the content, the width is 100% of our content
too but now the padding, border and margin add up to that.
So what we actually now got is a total width and height that's bigger than what we specified
and we can see the total values if we simply hover over it, we can see that the actual width of our
element is 937 and that the actual height is 558.
Now if we go back to our box model here in the developer tools, the height was 558, well if we add up,
that's 528 plus 10 plus 10,
so 548 plus 5 plus 5.
So we set the height and width of the content and padding and border is not included into our calculation
or is not part of what width and height target, it is what the browser in the end adds up to it though
which leads to our element being positioned incorrectly.
This happens because all elements by default happen to have a certain way of calculating width and height
which is called content box,
we can set this behavior by adding the box-sizing property to the element where we want to change it
and as I said, the default here is content box.
This means if we set a width and height, we set width and height of the content, not of the entire box
including padding and border. We can set it to border box though,
now width and height include padding and border, they don't include the margin and we can't make it to
include that.
With that set however if we save the file and reload, we still see that the element goes out of the page
because the margin is not included in the calculation
but if we go down, we see that actually it now only has a height of 498 because now if we add 10
times 2 for the padding and 5 times 2 for the border, now we end up with the 528 which is our height
which now again targets content plus padding plus border
and that often is the setting you want to use.
It's actually so common that you often overwrite the styling for all your elements to
always use box sizing border box because it's more convenient to think of the height and width referring
to the entire box without margin than to just the content.
Now as I said, margin is never included,
so to avoid that effect where your element is moved to the left, you simply have to remove the margin,
which I guess makes sense. If you want your element to sit right on the edge,
don't add a margin after your element,
it makes sense that this is not part of the width and height.
So box sizing border box, really really useful
and as I said, so important and useful that it's often used as a default style for all elements anyways
and this is also what I want to do here.
So we could add it to body
and if we do that and save and reload the page and go back to the box model, we see we're back
in content box world.
The reason for this is that we're now inheriting the box sizing set up
but actually, we don't see it here as a browser default style but because it's a block level element,
here by default, this is overwritten automatically.
So actually, our nice inheritance doesn't take effect because the browser sets its own box sizing because
section is a block level element.
Therefore what we have to do is, we have to use the universal selector and that is one of the rare cases
where you really use it if you want to reset all elements to have a certain behavior, like using box
sizing border box,
then you use the star, the universal selector because this is now not using inheritance,
it's not using the same mechanism as setting some body had,
it's really targeting every element on its own, hence overwriting inheritance and also overwriting browser
defaults and sets the box sizing to border box.
And I will leave this for the entire course project because I always want to target content padding
and border when setting width and height.
So with that added, if we now reload and go back, we see we're back in the world where our content is only width
and height without padding and border so that if we set width or height, we actually include padding
and border in the calculation.