Welcome back.
Today we'll be talking about joining in multiple fields to start off of this tutorial.
I will show you an example when it is necessary to join on multiple fields and I will show you what
happens when you accidentally forget about joining on multiple fields.
And finally we will look at how we can rectify this situation and actually in fact join on several fields
to get the right result.
So let's get straight into it.
Here we've got two tables table and table B Table A lists the orders that were conducted in our two
stores which are north and south.
As you can see we had two orders in the north store order number one and Order Number two.
And in the south store we had only order number one.
And also it lists the customers Mike Jack and Susan.
Table B lists the itemized description of those orders.
So we've also got the store location we've got the order number and we've got the item within that order
and the sale made on that item.
So here you can see right away that order number one in the north Norton the store had two items sold
a laptop and a month's order number two had one item which was the monitor and Order Number one in the
salad and store had only one item which was a camera.
So now we want to connect the two tables and basically what we're after is we want to see how the sales
that were made for each of the customers the total sales for each of the customers.
So visually you can see right away how that works.
But let's see how we can do it through joint.
So if we were to go ahead and do a left join.
So basically we wanted to attach the table in the right to the table the left and if we were to just
do a normal left join using one field we would try to join on order number.
So here if we want to match order number in the lift table to the right table it all looks something
like this order number one will be matched to order number one in the first draw of the right table
in the second row and in the fourth row.
And as we can see that's already incorrect because we're matching order number one from the northern
store to order number one from the south and store.
By this third match but let's let's see what happens further down.
So now if now Order Number two from the northern store will be matched toward Number two that's because
there's only one order number two in both of those tables.
And then order number one from the south and will actually be matched to three rows in the second table
which are Order Number one Ordon from the northern store.
Then the second item from Order Number one unknown store.
And finally the only item from or number one in the south and store.
So in total the resultant table will look like this.
We will have three rows for North or Number one one row for North order number two and three rows for
south.
Order number one.
And as you can see this is a mistake there's an error because this highly inflates our sales.
It looks like we've sold two laptops it looks like we're sold to mice and two cameras whereas in fact
that's not true.
So joining on a single field here can lead to incorrect results.
So let's see how we can fix that.
What we need to do and this you can see naturally from these tables is we have to include information
about the store in our joint so we know that the order numbers are unique for each store.
And so therefore if we include the store now join then we will avoid this whole problem.
So let's see how that works.
At the on the top left here in circled in red you can see that we're joining on order number from table
a Eco's order number from table beat and store from Table 8 Eco's store from table B.
Let's see how this works.
In fact here we've got the North order number one being matched to two rows in the second table.
So North order number one which is the laptop and north or to number 1 which is the mass and that's
correct next door to number two from the northern store is matched to only one row in the second table
which is the monitor for the North End order number two which is also correct.
And finally the solid number one order is matched to only one row in the second table because there's
only one row that contains both the words South and the number one for the order.
And that is the camera for that Susan.
So now if we perform that join then the final resulting table will look like this.
And as you can see here the one row in the table on the left was duplicated to match the quantity of
items which was two items bought by Mike.
And so in total you can see that this you've got the correct result we can also assess how much each
customer has bought.
And there are no mistakes because of an incorrect turn.
So that was a good example of how to use joins in multiple fields.
And more importantly why you need to do that in certain cases to avoid errors.
I hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.