Welcome back to the course and tell them today we're talking about clustering.
So as we know we have our cities here visualize and we can see the revenue whether it's high whether
it's low.
That's told by the color and the size.
We can also you highlight the new ones these 10 new ones but we can really tell from here which ones
we should invest to in terms of marketing which is the best bets so we can probably say that this one
has a low revenue but at the same time this is not really a story it was Alsation.
So let's proceed to creating a storytelling Weasel's action which create a new sheet.
And here we're going to actually visualize revenue versus marketing spend.
So revenues are going to be are Y-axis and market spend is going to be our X-axis.
And as you can see we only have one dot here so we can either disaggregate these dots or their approach
is to actually use the store ID in detail to change the level of granularity.
And we already know how all of that works in the background so that's always exciting to understand
what we're doing exactly.
And as you can see here we've got some points on our scatterplot and in total we have 150 points so
you can confirm that if you check on the bottom left in the bottom left corner and what we are seeing
here is every single CD in our data set.
We're seeing the revenue versus the marketing spend.
So maybe we'll just make these a little bit bigger.
That's a great start.
That is awesome.
And already from here we can tell that there's at least there's there's two distinct groups there's
a group of cities over here which are kind of performing quite okay.
And then there's some cities here that are not performing as okay.
And why is that.
Well here we've got marking Spens So as you move from left to right you're increasing the marketing
spend you're spending more and more.
And here we've got the revenue.
So you would expect that the more you spend on marketing the more revenue you get so for instance for
to start with you if you take two cities for example you take this city or the store in the city has
got an idea of 48 or in city this location is 48 basically So working spend is $2000 revenue 16000.
If you take this city here marking spend 3000 nearly 4000 is $56000.
That makes sense right.
So when you increase your marketing spend you expect more revenue but then this city of for example
doesn't make sense.
Right so you have a city here which the marketing spend for is $1800 and the revenues 19000 and this
city market spend is $3900.
So more than twice as much.
So this was 1800 these 3900.
But there are still $19000.
So if we talk in terms of trends then these cities they might be sharing a certain characteristic that
they all kind of like.
They're all stuck at this $20000 revenue level and regardless of how much you invest into marketing
it doesn't really change anything.
So if you invest more you're not getting more return whereas these cities here you can see that there's
an obvious trend if you invest $2500 you'll get somewhere around 40000 revenue.
If you invest $3500 you invest you get somewhere on $60000 in revenue.
So as you can see there's two distinct groups and we can actually visually see them.
So that's always a good thing.
But how do we now identify them and politically from a statistical point of view.
And this is where clustering comes into play.
If we go to the analytics tab on the left here and we scroll down you'll find this option for under
models which is cluster and that will allow you to cluster or create clusters identify clusters in your
zeal zation.
So let's go ahead and try it out.
We'll drag it onto the chart and that's it.
So right away you can see that the variables used are a sum of marketing spend which we have over here.
Some new which is also we're here so the variables that are building obviously just by using them.
Tablo is applying an algorithm called K means clustering.
And it is right away building this visualization for us now it's a very quick way to derive very powerful
insights.
So from here we can tell right away so Tablo grouped all of these into one class and grouped all of
these into one.
So it's big it's quite intuitive right.
So exactly what we spoke about.
We just didn't think that these would fall into that closer but Tablo is using information that it has
on a marking spin.
So these variables to identify which are all alike which of these stores of cities are alike that they
can be put into one group and it turns out that these are all alike.
And these are all alike so they kind of like very close to each other in that sense just by looking
at this viz. in terms of distance.
Right so we can see that these if there is if you're going to identify two groups and this is how Tablo
suggests identify it.
Now that's a great start.
And we can already derive some insights from here we can say which cities depending on which group you
fall into your city falls into.
You're either deriving a good return on marketing investment or not such a great return marketing investment.
And for instance we can check our cities that we have.
So if we go back to Dora and we look at new expansion put into detail and then we show highlighter.
So now I'm just going to bring the Hayler to the left.
Now what we can do is we can just look at the new cities and you can see them being identified there
so you can see that we've got two cities in the lower group and we've got all these other cities in
the better group.
So this is some preliminary clustering analysis that we've performed and right away we can tell from
here that probably it's better to invest into these cities rather than into these cities because their
return regimen is better.
But at the same time what we can see is that this is probably not the final step in our clustering and
that is because we can see that these cities they don't look exactly that they belong to this group
more so they look like they belong to this group and in the future to Charles in the section we'll learn
how to refine our clustering analysis even more so that it is more sophisticated and it's telling an
even better story.
Now I wanted to mention as well that don't worry if this is so it looks a bit complicated right now
or something that you haven't encountered before.
That's totally expected.
Totally normal in coming to Tauriel.
We'll get more used to this concept of clustering and identify these groups We'll talk about some trends
and you'll see exactly how we'll derive the analysis for now what is important for us is just to understand
how to perform this clustering analysis how to create these clusters using analytics pain and going
forward will be much more comfortable get much more comfortable with this whole concept.
I hope you enjoyed this tutorial and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then I'd be analyzing.