Pillowed Welcome back to the course on Tablo and into this Tauriel we will learn how to make our dashboard
interactive.
So what do we mean by that.
Well what we want to do is we want to allow the user of this dashboard to drill into certain parts of
the dashboard by just simply clicking on it.
So for instance if the user wants to drill into a certain state like IL de France for instance he can
just simply click on this bubble.
And then the customer scatterplot will automatically adjust to reflect only the customers that live
in that state.
And same thing goes for any other state because that will add a lot of value to this dashboard and the
users who are going to be using it because they'll be able to analyze difference geographical regions
individually and separately.
So let's see how we can do that in order to do that.
We need to add an action and then Tablo there are two main types of actions they're called filtering
and highlighting.
So let's go to the dashboard dropdown here and we'll click action here you can see that if you want
to add action you can choose between filter highlight.
There's also a third action call your L which will take your turn and link but we won't be looking at
that for now.
Instead of adding an action here right now what we will do is we will add an automatic action which
is much easier and that will help us slowly get into this topic of actions.
So what we're going to do is at the top of map of Europe will look click this dropdown and we will select
the menu which is called use filter.
So as soon as you click that it's all done.
So now as soon as I click on IL de France you will see that the scatterplot has been adjusted.
If I click on England it's also been adjusted.
I click on Netherlands right away you can see it's just that.
So as you can see I am able to now very easily select different states and see what is going on in each
one of these states.
So that is a very handy way channelised are.
So what exactly happened.
Let's have a look in more detail.
Now if we go to dashboard and we go to actions you will see that there is an action here ready and it's
generated action meaning it was added automatically.
Now let's click on this generated action and we'll click Edit.
So here you can see that there's a few fields.
First of all what is the source of the action dashboard one is our dashboard looking at and in Dashboard
one it is map of Europe that is the source of the action.
The action is around only when you select a certain element.
And once you've selected an element the action is applied to the target shoots the target sheets or
the customer scatterplot and the map of Europe once again.
So in this case what is going to do is it's going to filter the customer scatterplot it won't actually
take out the rest of the values from the map of Europe because Tablo smart it knows that if you take
out the rest of the values from the map of Europe then you won't be able to click on something else.
So let's have a look at that again.
I clicked OK and now once I'm selecting as you can see this is the source of the action.
And these two are the targets of the action.
So in this case the customer scatterplot being the new worksheet is being filtered.
So when I click through the states these customers are own only the customers that live in that state
are being left.
So now what we're going to do is we're going to go to dashboards.
We go back to actions and we'll adjust the sections to have a play around with it.
Now instead of a select Let's choose Hulver what that will do is the action will be applied as soon
as we have over a dot on our map.
So let's see how that works click OK.
OK.
And now this however over some of the states as you can see our dashboard.
I'm not clicking anything and the dashboard is being adjusted right away as we're just hovering over.
And that is another way that you can present your dashboard.
It might be more convenient in certain cases for you to be just required to just Hoover over these bubbles
to get the second worksheet to adjust itself.
They'll just look at the last option that we had there.
If we go to dashboard actions and we click Edit or we select menu what will happen is instead of adjusting
the decimal right away we are presenting a menu where we can toggle the dashboard ourselves manually.
But personally I don't use that often.
So now let's do some more other things so overcoached dashboard actions as it lets leave it at select
and let's explore this part of the dashboard.
So what happens when we clear the selection.
Well we can either show all values which is happening now.
So once we click somewhere else on the map all values are returned what we can do is leave the filter
so let's have a look at that.
So click OK and now if I select a state and then I click somewhere else.
As you can see all the states are shown again but the filter is stays on.
So if I click somewhere else and I click back once again the filter does not is not removed which is
probably not a good thing in this case because it is misleading.
It looks like all the sites are selected but in reality not all the customers are shown.
So let's change that.
Go to edit and you can also do exclude values so have a look at that in your own time.
It basically just will exclude all the values from your scatterplot.
So we'll just click and leave it back on show values click OK.
And since we select something and unselected we once again have all those.
So two things that I wanted to show you.
The first one is how you can create that specific filter on your own.
So let's go to dashboard actions and we'll delete this filter.
Remove it.
OK.
So once again now you can see that once I click and nothing happens the scatterplot is not adjusted
if I go to a dashboard.
I want to add the filter on my own.
I go to actions.
I want to add action filter here.
The source of our filter is a map of Europe we can call our filter selects geography because we don't
want to call select state because we might want to change our dashboard and show it at the city level
one day.
It'll be a select type of filter national values upon clearing the filter and those who are the target
shooters.
OK.
And there you go.
Now it's all working.
And we created that filter all on our own.
So that's that's great.
That's how you create actions manually.
And the next thing I want to show you is that you can actually select multiple regions so I can select
two or three I'm just coding control on my keyboard and I can select many or I can use the multiple
select feature here and Tablo.
So say a rectangular selection and here I've got the customers shown for all of those states or I can
do a circular selection say I want to select.
So here I can select these customers or grade one which I like is this free form selection.
So let's say I want to select all the people that are in France in the French States and they go I've
just selected everybody in France as easy as that.
Now I can analyze the customers that live in France.
So that is how you create action filters in Tablo dashboards and that is also how you can select many
points on your map and in the next tutorial we will talk about the action which is highlighting and
we will look at why highlighting is a bit different to filters and what the intricacies are there.
Have a play around with that and look forward to seeing your next step.
Until then happy analyzing.