Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo and I've got this feeling that by now you're probably
getting a bit tired of all of these Daughter prep tutorials.
We've had a few in a row.
And yeah definitely it is a bit tedious sometimes but it's a very important topic so I'm happy that
we carrying it off and also to spice things up.
I promise you that at the end of this tutorial We'll look at some visuals and play around with the daughter
just to have a bit of fun.
So today we're talking about the metadata grid.
What is the metadata grid.
It allows you to do is it allows you to look at all the columns separately before all this daughter
getting in your way and get some information and maybe do some work just with the column names and just
call them themselves.
And that is a very handy thing to have especially if you have like 30 20 30 40 50 columns.
It can be quite a challenge crawling around this place and finding the ones you need to do something
about.
Whereas if you use a metadata grid right in front of you.
All of them.
So how do you get to the metadata grid.
Well like everything in Tablo It's very simple you just have to click this one little button over here
and once you're there.
This is I think it's called managed metadata.
Once you there you've got the grid in front of you.
We only have four columns so it isn't that big.
But at the same time you can really see some how we can add some value to our dashboard through this
metadata grid.
So here we've got the original name of the current name of the column.
Then we've got the table where it comes from and the remote field name.
So what was the original name of the column.
So in our case we've got regions which came from our spreadsheet and it was also called the regions
countries.
It came from a spreadsheet is called.
It's called countries pivot field names.
In our case it came from the pivot and the it actually represents the years so because we pivoted on
the year you can see that pivot field names is a different years and pivot field values is the total
number of cars sold.
So how about we go ahead and make these adjustments here so instead of pivot field names we'll call
it year and pivot field value we'll call it maybe not cars that's called vehicles sold.
And I'm not specifically don't want to put vehicle sales because that might imply dollars and we don't
want to confuse the users so we'll just call it Pickle's sold maybe we'll put a space in between them
and countries we can put us like uncapitalized regions as well or just cold region.
And in this case country.
So that allowed us to clean up a bit our spreadsheet or our daughter.
Now you can see it's a much better region country year vehicle sold and that is how you work with the
meter dot grid.
Once again very small number of fields for us in this case.
But if you do ever have more fields you can come here and work refit and it will be much more convenient
and much more handy for you.
So here you can also like look at other things like alias's for change names for countries or the different
values of fields like do some splits which we've already talked about and so on.
So let's have a look at some data as promised because we want to see some colors.
All right.
So we're going to go to a sheet.
What are we going to look at vehicles sold and we'll look at it by year.
Right away we've got an interesting picture so the total number of vehicles sold globally has been growing
and it's currently sitting at 65 million vehicles sold in 2014.
What else could we add here let's add region.
And now we've got a colorful chart so orange is Asia here and bulu Europe.
So we can see that Asia Oceania Middle East 34 and a half million vehicles were sold in 2014.
What do we want to do now.
Well perhaps we want to see how much what percentage of the global sales.
Was the were the sales in Asia so we can see here right away that it is quite a high portion.
Based on the size of this bar bar we don't really see what percentage exactly it was.
So how about we compare the percentages in sort of the total values.
All right so we're creating a calculated fields table calculation and here will look for percent of
total but not across we want the percentage of total down because we want the percent of total for every
single year.
Click Apply and then we go we can see that what what percentage exactly.
Each region is constituting for every single year.
Maybe it will just take this table allocation hold down control added into label maybe format our label
I by now I hope all of this is very straightforward what exactly we're doing because this must be very
easy stuff for you guys right now.
So just click Format this whole tab and make it bold.
And now if we format our label we just want to change it from one put a percentage with no decimals.
There we go.
So that's that's what we can see maybe we you might want to change an area chart but that label doesn't
look as good so maybe keep it a bar chart.
And so here we can see that in 2014 53 percent of the world's vehicles personal vehicles were sold in
Asia Oceania and Middle East.
19 percent were sold in Europe.
So Europe is in second place but far far behind Asia and the Middle East but fair enough because that
is a very big region and US so the North American Free Trade Agreement that America us United States
Canada and Mexico 14 percent of the total vehicle sales.
Once again those are personal vehicles.
So there we go we had to play around with the daughters just to make a little bit more fun feel free
to explore further.
This is quite interesting to say maybe you look at your country see how the sales in your country have
been changing this is freely available on the net so it should be should be quite accurate.
Next what we're going to do in the next tutorial we will look at the errors that you can that can happen
when you're working with map so data errors.
When working with maps and we'll see how to fix them and that will be a very interesting or very useful
tutorial if you are planning on working with maps going forward.
OK so that's it for today.
Thank you very much for attention.
I look forward to seeing you next time.
And until then happy analyzing.