Hello and welcome back to the course on Tablo in the previous tutorial we learned how to combine cluster's
and trendlines and what powerful insights we can derive from such analysis.
And I hope that you had a chance to play around with that and really get that knowledge thinking because
indeed it is a very powerful tool that now you have in your arsenal and is just going to be very satisfying
when you find situations in your analytics when you'll be able to apply this kind of approach or something
similar.
And today we're going to talk about saving this Klosters.
So now I have these clusters How do I actually save them to perform further analytics with them on other
sheets for example so if I want to create a new sheet How do I carry those clusters onto the sheet as
well.
Well one way of course would be to recreate the clusters again and in our new resolution but creating
the classes every time is going to be quite tedious.
So there's a fast way.
All we have to do is take Klosters from here hold on control and drag them into dimensions.
And so what that creates is it creates a group.
Once again I know we haven't spoken about groups.
For now it's just a convenient tool for us to have.
You can always learn more about groups if you decide to check out that one of course but otherwise just
right click and rename this group and we'll call it clusters all is just called our clusters just so
that we remember that we created this group ourselves.
And if we go to sheet 6 Let's see how we can use this group.
Let's say I want to put it into color and then I want to put it into columns.
And now I want to look at the average population per cluster.
That'll be interesting something that we were curious about previously.
So that's right click drag population into label say average and maybe let's copy that into the rows.
So here you can see right away what the result looks like orange Schloesser indeed has the highest average
population.
Blue has a medium and red has the lowest average population.
So that's how quickly we can move our clusters to different sheets.
It's very easy and you wait to save them as groups like that.
And another example would be if we plot our cities or this plot or state on the map and then expand
it to cities and here if we want to quickly see which cities are from where we can just take our clusters
and put them into color and there we go right away we can see how these cities where they are located
and you can see lights so we can increase the size further or we can connect the size to something else.
For example we can put revenue on size and add some transparency and then you can move around the colors
so let's say we can put the red ones on top because they're there we know that they're small some revenue
and you can just maybe add a border so that they look nice.
So there we go.
Now we know how to not only create clusters but also use them in our analysis and use them across different
sheets and different visualizations that we're creating.
So hopefully this knowledge will come in a useful for you one day and you'll be able to perform closer
analytics on your daughter sets as well as you can see is a very powerful feature that is integrated
into a table and on that note we're going to complete this tutorial look for the next time.
And until then happy analyzing.