Alone Welcome back to the course on Tablo.
In today's tutorial we will create the remainder of the required of Islamization and use two tips in
solving our business challenge.
Now we need to create two new sheets.
Let's start off with the first one.
The first one we will actually call the average annual salary math because that is what we will have
on the for the counties on the map of New York State.
And to do that we quite simply drag in the Ag County into our map and yours might look different but
if you're also located outside of the United States you might end up like this having 62 unknown locations.
Now this normally happens when your regional settings on your machine or you are with regional settings
of Tablo is different to that of the United States.
When working with addenda States from the United States to fix that is fairly easy.
You literally just click on the 62 unknown and edit locations.
You can also exclude the data by using filtered data.
That doesn't make sense at all.
In this case but we actually edit locations no then Tablo allows us to change the country which tends
to focus on others if located in the Netherlands at the moment so we that's why it defaulted and it
ends but we will just go to United States and we will also change the state and the province because
we know each of these counties of all each of them are located or related to the state of New York.
And like magic everything disappears all of the problems and it draws the map properly.
We actually want pay field maps that will just click on map over there.
And these are all of our counties in the state of New York.
Now we can continue.
We know we want to use the average annual salary as our coloring.
So we can just right click and drag that onto column which will open up fuel way because we don't want
this sum of annual salary because remember we have all of the figures for every year.
We actually want to then calculate average over all ages so it will just click on average and I think
we can make a few improvements.
Firstly the dog lines seem quite daunting so let's change that to what white borders.
We can change.
Also the actual transparency or the Pasotti to 65 to make it a bit more transparent and see what goes
on in the background.
And furthermore let's also change the color to black curial always likes to do this is to change the
color green.
I also prefer it like that.
And as we've done in the previous tutorial we want to see the names of each of the counties and to display
it in a nice way.
We could obviously see it on the altar.
But is this better.
I swear we can just go again into map layers and switch on the county names.
We don't need the borders.
We already have the borders but these are the names in the back are on the map and obviously chose it
for the rest of the counties as well but doesn't really matter.
We can actually see it on our map nicely now and that's this visualization done very nice and quick.
Now we can just move that to the first as that's our most important one and we can create our last one.
So this is the one where we create the top five industries Bauch out the way we look at the average
annual salary range and you show the top five.
So it's quite an easy chart again as well.
We will take the average annual salary.
Put that into columns and the change that to average making sure we use average and then also take the
industry and put that on two rows.
We will also use the industry while holding control down.
Put that into color and I just actually want to change the color and make it something a little bit
different but more not as striking as this on the ballot.
For now we know any showing the top five so we can use that.
So there will be a few repeats now but we will take industry once again and put that into filters because
we know we are only looking for the top five and they just top five of day based on the average annual
salary.
And there we go.
So you can see the repeats are gone repeats of the number of or at least of the industries.
And we can see the top five over all for all the top five industries for all years in all different
counties in the state of New York and we can just rename this as well and just call this our top five
industries.
Right.
And then we can move on to putting it all together using the our nice intuitive functionality so Tablo
added this for us and I think it is just awesome.
So you will remember that our client specifically asked not to use a dashboard and to combine these
sheets and also not to do different sheets.
And thats why this tip comes in handy.
Now to add a to a sheet or a different sheet to your visualization in the tool tip you just click on
tool tip and obviously just go to the bottom two two added Badillo the takes we already have.
And you would just add it from this insert button over a year and normally we added fields from from
there but we see this new option called cheats.
And that way we can select the sheets that we've just bought.
So let's start with a staple line chart.
So we just click that and automatically Tablo for zero the required information.
So you can see it specifies the Schiedam the max with the max side.
So obviously the space within a tooltip is limited but the space specifies the maximum space that can
be used by default.
And then also to make sure that all filters that are applied to our visualization is also then applied
to that specific view or to that specific sheet.
So if we hit OK and start dragging a mouse or mouse pointer over the graph you'll see how each county
then updates the chart or gets the chart updated for that specific county.
Pretty helpful because now we can see specific spikes like that in Fulton County or you know even other
spots in Stephen County so which boy we're not visible at all.
When we looked at them together it's a pretty pretty nice what we can then also do is add more than
one or more than one sheet to this tooltip so we can just click again.
Just put it at the bottom over there to same Up same approach and add the top five industries.
You'll see again all the same values are put in there.
Obviously the sheet name will be different.
So if it's OK now you see we've got two over there.
So that is pretty neat.
And that's exactly what we wanted.
But this is obviously not where we'll stop.
We need to make some some fixes on here.
I think the tooltip is way too big.
It loses the overall picture and the information on there which we don't need to edit out tilter I think
what we can do is we can just change the maximum size and this is obviously we are able to edit this
so the maximum I'm not going to change the maximum.
With apologies we change the maximum height because we want to keep it small and we can also just change
these all these hating so we can make that much bigger.
So let's call that 18 and just give it a different color just to look slightly different and we'll just
call this our average annual salary like that and we hit play all week.
OK.
And look at that.
She does.
Our sheets are much smaller.
You can see the spacing used is a little bit less.
And we've got a nice Hading there as well.
So to go in edit the accessories and maybe make the font size a bit smaller also on the smaller and
individual sheets we can just go into each one.
And as we know we've done this before.
We don't need for instance the title.
It's self-explanatory.
And even for you of a year you don't really need that.
So we can just remove all of it and then next we can just also format and take this to the smallest
size possible.
And as you can see now it looks way better in terms of the use of space and the same with the top industries.
We don't need that over there.
We can edit the axes as we don't need any need it to live.
And let's just also make sure that we use the smallest size available in this case and voila.
That is our visualization.
And doesn't that look great.
And that also then concludes after Tauriel for the section and in the next the toile we will actually
be doing a recap of the most important features which we've learned during this section.
And I look forward to seeing you.
Until next on happy analyzing.