And we are back.
So welcome to this new chapter in this section, we're going to be learning how to take what we've learned
so far and get a little bit more complex, get a little bit deeper into the editing process.
So we're going to be learning how to create a height edit.
And what I mean by that is just a short 30 second edit.
It's high energy, high speed and really something that's exciting.
So what we're going to do here is use the key techniques that we've learned so far, which are workflow.
We're going to organize everything back, everything up, create a clean workspace.
We're going to then pull our selects to decide what's going to go in our content.
We're going to create our rough edit and then we're going to find the best sounding track that really
fits our edit.
And finally, we're going to learn some new techniques around stylizing time remapping, post-production
stabilization and how to take.
Looking footage and really edit it in a way that makes it look more professional and more creative.
So go ahead and get your editing software ready to go.
And you can either edit past content that you already have or you can download the same exact footage
that I'm going to be working with and whether you want to use your own or the footage that I'm supplying.
We're going to gather around five to 15 different shots from that footage and turn it into a really
exciting montage.
And of course, we're going to transfer that footage on the device that we're going to be editing on.
And we're going to build on the techniques that we've already learned and get into newer techniques.
And then you're going to export and share your video URL link, whether you uploaded to YouTube or Facebook
or wherever you want to share it.
You're going to post that link in the student Q&A section for feedback and to share with your fellow
students.