OK, so new day, new fit, new background, want to switch up the look?
We've been working together in this course for quite a while.
It's been about eight and a half hours so far, just a pure post-production and editing content.
So we're building a good relationship for getting to know each other.
And I'm really excited for these next two chapters, because these are both going to be downloadable
content that I'm going to be editing, that you'll be able to download a more lower resolution version
of and follow along and edit with me.
So let's get into what content we're going to be working with in this chapter.
So I want you to grab the downloadable footage that you can click next to this lecture or edit a pass
project that you have now.
This past project has to have a real coverage and B, roll coverage.
And what we're going to do is create around a 30 to 45 second promo video.
So in this chapter, I'm not going to be going through the back of the footage, gather the footage,
capture it or organize it, pull it into the timeline, create Selex, make it back up of that sequence
color and label everything.
We've already done that together through around four or five projects already.
So from this point on in the course, we're going to be focusing on the more advanced techniques that
come after that, just initial organizing and setting up phase.
So I'm excited to get into these new techniques.
So before we dive into this chapter, be sure that you have your initial rough edit ready to go.
And then what we're going to focus on together is these new types of techniques, like creating a multicam
sequence using quote unquote, unusable B roll.
That's going to be really cool.
We're going to get into masking and how to create cool new styles of overlays, more of the glitchy
effects.
And we're going to get into some of my favorite filters to use.
Then at the end of the chapter, once we've finished our edit together, you can export and share your
video URL in the student Q&A section for feedback from myself and from your other fellow students.
And I want to mention that these techniques you can use for any kind of promo.
So whether you're creating a promo for a product for a client, you know, it could be any kind of product,
I don't know, like product for a client or possibly you have a service that you offer, maybe you sell
something online or maybe you offer something in person.
This kind of promo video will be a high energy short thing that will make that product or service or
video series that you want to advertise or music album that you want to advertise.
That's what this specific promo that I'm going to be editing is for.
It's a promo for a music album.
But for anything for a client or personal project, this will work.
So what I want to do first before getting into the editing lesson is show you an example of what one
of these final products looks like.
Let me just.