Welcome to this brand new chapter.
And at this point in the course, we've done a lot together, we've done LouisI here, we've done our
hyp edit, we did our travel edit with our iPhone footage.
We've done our violinist's live performance video.
We've edited an entire vlog together.
We've done professional client types of edits.
And we've done personal project edits and we've done showcase video.
It was a high end real estate walkthrough video.
I think there's a few of the things that he did in there, but it's been a long, long, long journey
together.
And now moving forward at this part in the course, now that we've worked together to really build up
our skills, working on the very, very beginning all the way to the end of each and every edit.
Now, what I want to do is zoom out a little bit and start to focus on more advanced and pretty complex
edits.
And these are going to be more case study and break down type lectures where rather than dragging things
in, we're going to look at the timeline together and we're going to look at edit it's edit.
It's edits that I've created for clients.
And we're going to break down and deconstruct what was going on there, what techniques were used,
why they were being used, and then the effect that they have.
So, yeah, I'm excited about this part because we're going to kind of switch things up a little bit
and we're going to really be able to dive into more complex topics and even cooler editing tricks.
So in these remaining lectures, that's what we got.
Oh, that's what we'll be diving into.
And yeah, I will see you in the very next video lesson.