So what is up and welcome to this video editing masterclass.
My name is Julian Melanson, and I'm going to be the instructor at teacher for this journey that we're
about to go on together.
Now, I'm super excited.
I've been wanting to put this course together for a while.
I've done preproduction courses, production courses, the business of filmmaking courses.
And the editing is something I've really been excited to get to.
So let's not waste any time.
We're going to do a brief introduction on the overview of this course, how you can get the most from
the content, and then we're going to go right into the actual learning lessons.
So let's get started.
Now, I've packed this course with tons of information.
And really the goal of this entire course is for you to have a massive transformation from when you
start to when you finish the content.
Now, that transformation is going to be that you're going to be able to edit and create incredible
looking and sounding videos with any software that you're using and footage really from any kind of
phone or camera.
Basically, the information that I chose to focus on the most is going to be applicable across any kind
of footage and any kind of piece of technology that you're using.
Why?
Because you want to be able to use this information a year from now, five years from now, however
long, with whatever kind of content, with whatever kind of client, and not be restricted to the equipment
or technology that you're using.
That's not very interesting to me.
What's interesting is upgrading you as the creator that way.
Whatever you're holding, whatever you're using is automatically improved from your knowledge.
Now, the information that we are going to be diving deep into is perfect for beginner to intermediate
video creators.
So if you're just getting started, don't worry, we're going to go over the fundamentals.
If you've been editing for a while and you want to upgrade your edits to be better, more cohesive,
expansive and inspiring.
Perfect.
This is going to give you those tools that you need.
Now, even if you are a pre intermediate to advanced Ed, I guarantee there's going to be amazing tidbits
and lessons in this course that you're going to walk away from and be able to use to enhance all of
your more higher end advanced edits, because we're going to start from the beginning.
How to master the fundamentals.
And then we're going to move into more advanced techniques and processes together.
So a bit of a micro overview of some of the main steps we're going to be doing is first, starting with,
like I just mentioned, the fundamentals.
How do we capture our footage, label it, organize it, back it up, make sure all of our content is
safe and really learned how to do this the right way at the beginning, so that when you do advance
and you're still editing and creating videos years from now, you have a really solid foundation and
workflow that's going to allow for you to spend more time on the creative side and less time on the
more logistical fundamentals side.
Next, we're going to learn how to pull our selects, how to create our main edit, how to choose our
music, how to do all of the beginning processes of creating a really good looking mean video edit.
Then we're going to go into the refining steps.
So this is really important because we're going to do the fundamentals.
We're going to get really good at the main bulk of the process, all of that workflow.
And then we're going to learn all the techniques that I've gathered over the years to really refine,
polish, upgrade and just create something that is unique and special and stands out.
This happens in the refining process where we take a bit of a rough stone and we polish it into this
really beautiful looking final piece.
And lastly, there's going to be editing prototypes throughout the entire process, which are essential
bits of wisdom, knowledge techniques on top of what we're learning throughout that are just going to
give us a little bit extra fuel and skills to continue to improve beyond this course.