OK, so we have made it to the final chapter of this cause, I mean, what a huge event, a journey
this has been for both of us, for me, putting together all this content, working with you to help
you create these new videos and all these new techniques.
And this is this news, this celebration, actually.
Let's see what we got.
Hmm.
Huh, huh, huh, huh, huh, huh.
OK.
Yes.
Super excited that you made it all the way to the end through the hours of content, information that
we shared and literally hundreds of video lessons, tons of information, tons of stuff to absorb.
So pat yourself on the back.
Amazing job for making it all the way to the final chapter.
Now, I just have a few more slides of just kind of final tips and techniques that I want to give before
we conclude this journey and finish the process.
Now, like I mentioned, I just have a few final editing tips.
I kind of, you know, said this a little bit before, but you always want to take time off your edits.
You want to take all these techniques we've learned together.
And then when you are in the refining phase, you want to take time away from your edit.
Close the computer for a little bit and try to remove your personal bias when you're watching your videos,
because after you've seen it so many times, you have a very clear expectation of where the cuts are,
what the sounds are, and what to expect next.
And a side effect of that is you can also become kind of attached to certain shots for you.
They took a lot of time to pull off.
Whether that took a lot of time in the filming phase, you know, of the hours of struggle that it took
for you to get that shot or whether it took time of hours and struggle in the editing phase to create
that specific sequence.
We don't necessarily know or it doesn't necessarily carry that much weight for the person watching it.
So even though you have a very strong attachment to certain shots, we want to remove that and watch
our videos as clear and with as much clarity as possible.
And when you're doing this, ask for feedback before releasing your video, because like I mentioned,
you kind of become blind, deaf to a lot of this stuff.
So I always, you know, send out my rough edits to certain groups of friends that I know I can trust.
They have a good creative eye.
They have a certain amount of respect in their own field and that they know what a quality project should
look like.
So find those friends, find those family members that you can trust to give you honest, constructive
criticism and positive feedback on your projects.
Because once you hit the upload button and you hit the pause button, it's there.
Of course, you can delete it and take it down if there is mistakes that you find out that you see later
on in the process.
But the goal is not to do that.
You know, when someone releases a feature film, they're not like, oh, yeah, yeah, you know, I
got to take that back.
It's when it's done, it's done.
And that's how it should be, so that you can move on to the next video, which should be twice as exciting,
twice as inspiring, and twice as high of a production quality.
So what you want to do with all of this is to explore it like we did in the previous chapter, is export
and view your edit outside of your editing software, do it on your iPhone, do it on a different computer,
whatever it is.
And then we do that same exact process of taking mental notes and writing down the timestamps with changes
needed.