Welcome back to a brand new chapter now, I hope you learned a lot and had a good time doing the promo
chapter of this course, and we're continuing to get more into the refining and more of the subtleties
and more of the professional side of video editing.
So in this chapter, what we're going to be doing now is we're going to be doing more of a professional
style.
We're not going to do all the flashy swooshed transitions and that stuff, but we're going to get more
into what it takes to create a much more seamless, clean and professional video for you in the future
when you might be doing client work, you might be doing a video for a product, and you don't want
to have all of the stuff.
You want to make a much more classy and a much more grounded and well-rounded overall video that has
a much more professional feeling.
So let's get into it.
So in this chapter, you're going to follow along with me.
And you can either edit past footage that you already have or you can download the footage, which is
going to be a high end real estate walkthrough.
This is like a 10 or 20 million dollar property.
So I'm really excited to edit this along with you.
And I want you to gather either your own footage that resembles kind of something similar.
It doesn't have to be real estate.
It doesn't have to be house, doesn't have to be more of a destination, location, travel style.
It can be really good roll that you may already have of a product or an object or something.
So if you have that footage.
Awesome.
If you don't have that footage, download the assets in the folder that I provided.
And you can go ahead and start by creating your initial rough edit.
Just like in the last lecture.
I'm not going to be going through those beginning processes, processes that we've already completed
together in previous chapters, in many previous chapters.
I'm going to walk right into going from right where I already have all the selects pulled out, already
organized everything.
So if you have questions about that process, you can go to the previous chapters.
I believe chapters two through four, two, three and four, possibly even five, they'll quote me on
that.
But we already go through the organization categorizing process.
So we're going to go over in this chapter shot arrangement, editing down our music, doing some custom
transitions, working with some, working with split screens, coloring and refining our footage to
get that professional looking polish.
At the end of the chapter, you can export and share the video that you created alongside with me in
the student Q&A and get feedback from myself and other students.
And like I mentioned, these are techniques that you'll be able to use for any kind of showcase video.
It doesn't have to be real estate with a big mansion.
It can be a product video for, you know, your friends coffee brand.
You know, it can be a product video for an app if you have good bureau footage.
All these techniques will work for that.
But we're going to just dive into the professional side of how to upgrade goodlooking b roll and make
it look just that much better.
So I will see you in the next video lesson where we will dive into these new techniques.