All right, so let's get right into the edit now, what I have already done here is taken my main footage
and I've dragged into my timeline.
This is my Viorel timeline.
As you can see here, we have the B roll shots, just kind of cool environment or footage.
And I filmed it in a way, knowing that this was going to kind of be a gritty Urbani kind of more city
downtown and gritty vibe.
So the way I filmed it was kind of shaky, handheld way.
And we're going to get into the real thing, not of this lesson, but in I think the next one, which
I'm really excited because a lot of these shots would be unusable from an outside perspective or maybe
initially looking at it.
So we have that set up and ready to go.
We need to pull these Selex, which I'm going to do.
And then we have the promo song.
So that's going to be our backing track.
Our main audio for this edit, and yet if you don't have this footage downloaded yet and you want to
edit this with me, make sure you download that, because we're going to get into everything here.
The song is in the folder, the B Roll, and then the main footage is in the folder as well.
So here's our main footage performance.
One performance, one B for performance, two performance to be because I shot everything at four K.
What my camera specifically does is when it hits a certain point, a certain amount of gigs, whatever
it is, or a certain length, it'll cut up the clip into two things.
So that's not a problem, but that's just a little bit more of a complexity.
But basically to A and B is one performance, three Amys, one performance and so on.
So I basically shot this same performance six different times.
So if we take a look, we have this first one that's shot on a Steadicam and I shot wide and some close
ups if we go to the next one and a shot even wider.
And if we go to the third one, I think this is.
Yeah, some more close ups on what he's doing with the hands.
And if you go to the before, I think this one I think the next one is hand-held.
No, OK.
The last one is handheld.
Cool.
So once I got his performance perfectly or whatever perfect means, but once I got his performance done,
well, five times on the last one, I was getting more artistic shaky shots that it's going to be quick
little cutaways that we're going to really put to use.