OK, so we're going to start this process by deconstructing and diving deeply into the most important
moments of this trailer for a large client of mine that produces online courses, very similar to Masterclass,
very similar to that kind of content.
So they hired me to produce film and edit one of these trailers for their upcoming course.
So we had two camera angles to read Comodo Angles shooting at six each.
And we also had a separate dialogue track connected to our zoom handheld recorder, recording really
high quality dialogue of the teacher speaking.
And then we have music bed underneath and a lot of different layers.
So let's hop over to the screen cap and let's see what we're working with.
So we have the edit here.
As you can see, it's a pretty complex timeline.
Here are all of our video layers.
Here is our audio track.
Here is our different music.
And then the shorter ones, these shorter audio files are going to be all of our little sound effects.
So we're definitely in a dive into that in this chapter.
Now, if you go over here, we also have our project window.
So we have our talking footage.
We have our main sequences.
These are the same exact steps and processes, processes that we went through earlier in the course
of pulling our Selex, of creating backup sequences properly, bringing in possible tracks that we're
going to use for our edit color coding, labeling everything properly, and choosing the best kind of
music for our track.
We have our screen captures.
We have all different layers.
And that's why the organization that we focused on so much during this course is so key, because once
you get all these kind of different media assets going in your timeline, in your project, as you start
to grow and develop as a video editor, you're going to be really happy that you took this course and
we did this together.
So let's do this.
I'm going to go ahead and queue up this edit and we're going to hit play and watch all the way through.
It's about three minutes, and I'm going to pick out some very important moments that will then zoom
into and discover what was done, why I was done, and how you will be able to do a similar effect for
your edit.
So let's watch this edit.
The question is not how to get better at AP lit.
And the question isn't even how do we go from being high school level readers and writers to college
level readers and writers?
The question is actually, how can we see stories in a more accurate way?
Getting better at reading requires seeing the written word differently once you get the hang of that,
the writing comes naturally.
Can study in literature make you better at every subject you'll ever study?
I absolutely believe the answer is yes.
My college students would come up to me on the first day of class and they would say, you know, I'm
really worried about this class.
I'm a science person.
I'm a math person.
I'm not a literature person.
And I would say, OK, you're a science person, so you love questions.
You love identifying evidence to support an argument.
Sounds like you've everything you need.
Literary analysis is analysis.
It's about assessing, cataloging all the pieces of a text and finding a question that you're going
to answer your why questions are what's going to lead you to that college level thesis development.
You'll go from understanding the words to understanding the forces, working between the words.
So what makes a poem, a poem?
If a poem can be in paragraph form and prose can utilize the concrete space on the page.
Then what defines a poem?
You actually get to answer that question.
So oh, captain, my captain by Walt Whitman, I love this poem because I love the sound quality of
it.
So pay attention to the moments that are getting stressed.
And we can call this, you know, our poet's ear.
We're trying to build our poet's ear.
Oh, Captain, my captain are fearful.
Trip is done.
The ship has weathered every rack.
The prize we saw is one.
The port is near the bells.
I hear the people all exulting while falo eyes, the steady Neil, the vessel grim and daring.
So in those first four lines, we're getting a military drumbeat, right?
Oh, captain, my captain are fearful.
Trip is done.
It's like but a da da da da da da da da da da da da.
And then we have what's called the Volta.
This is where there's the vibe change, right?
But oh, heart, heart, heart with the sound, the difference in the sound and the difference in how
the words literally look on the page.
We are suddenly thrown into urgency, were suddenly thrown into an emergency.
And that's where the angst of this poem lives.
Each one of these quizzes, premium learning lessons and study guides is going to give you the tools
you need to totally transform the way you experience literature.
So if you're ready to get started, you can choose your membership plan and become an annual member
today.
OK, so pretty in depth, there is a lot of lot of things going on there, we had swoosh audio transitions,
we had visual transitions, all those things.
So now let's just start from the beginning.
This is going to be like a shotgun mishmash of a bunch of different types of tips.
So, yeah, let's start at the very beginning and let's just start with what we're seeing first.