Perfect, so let's hop right into this edit and get our Demario started.
So what I did already is I gathered my handful of my past video projects.
So this is just simply leave me with this real quick.
This is just the final full resolution, exports.
For some past client projects, maybe a few personal projects in here that are from the past.
And so what you want to do is gather shots or projects where, you know, there are shots that are unique
that showcase your skill set, that are visually pleasing and have something unique and special about
them that you want to share.
That's really the key to a good demo, really, is showcasing who you are in a short amount of time
so that someone doesn't have to look through your whole website or your whole Instagram feed or your
whole whatever social media platform to go and scroll through all this different kind of content boom
in one piece of content.
Just in a few seconds, they can instantly see exactly what it is that you do.
So I have all these videos right here.
Now, what we're going to do is open up our editing software.
We're going to create our demo reel sequence.
So I'm going to go to a new project.
I'm going to type in let's do a demo reel, OK?
Now, I'm going to like we did a lot together during this course.
I'm going to go to the proper place here.
From here, editing demo reel.
And I'm on tape and demo reel.
Editing folder.
Boom.
It shoots it.
OK.
And now I'm going to drag in all my Demario files and I'm going to make this bigger and I'm going to
go here and I can see the video info right here, and I'm going to choose one that is the proper frame
rate.
We want it to be twenty three point nine, seven, six.
I don't really know why some of these exports.
That's strange.
Those might have been some older exports that were export.
It added 30 frames per second and 60.
I'm not sure how that happened.
But the key here is that I want to choose one like this one.
That is 1920 by 10, 80.
So it's going to be 10 ATP, which is standard, and it's going to be the right frame rate, which is
24 frames a second.
AK twenty three point nine seven six.
I want to right click that.
I'm going to hit new sequence from clip and then I'm going to title it demo real mean Selex.
Now we have a proper sequence with the proper settings.
And I'm going to highlight the rest of these clips.
And I'm going to go ahead and De unSelect, the one that's already in the timeline and drag me in.
Now we have our main video files.
Oh, and I also have yeah.
Just a string of just drone footage.
And we're going to try to do something unique with having a mini drone like montage inside of this larger
demo reel.
So we'll see if we can do something cool there.
But let's go ahead and drag the rest of these video files.
So I'm gonna take all the drone footage and I'm going to drag it in.
And now what we have is, oh, my God, this is an hour of footage that we're going to pull Selex on.
But there's going to be something that's going to happen here that I want to fix before we get to that.
Now, we have different sized movie files, because some of these are for case.
Some of these are 10 ADP.
You can see the four key ones are really big.
What I want to do first before I start editing anything is to select everything in the timeline.
And I'm going to go right click and I'm on to set and scale everything to the frame size boom.
Now, the things that need to be scaled down are scaled down, the the files that need to be scaled
up or scaled up.
And we're good to start pulling Selex.