And I just wanted to add a few more of a little bit of a mental checklist to check off before actually
hitting the export button on the final final edit.
So be sure that all of your sequences in the edit itself and all the different clips in the edit.
Of course, everything is where it needs to be.
The visuals are clearly synched up to the audio.
You're cutting to the B, you're cutting to the dialogue.
There's no cuts that are too quick, and there's no cuts that are too slow and boring.
You want to find that middle ground and really find a rhythm and pacing that matches with the overall
vibe of that project.
Of course, you want to color.
Correct and get all the lighting exposure, color, temperature, tone, saturation, sharpness.
Correct on your image.
And then you want to go through a do the grading process.
So we spent a lot of time on which is then stylizing and adding a very unique aesthetic look to the
final footage.
And then, you know, you want to do some cool effects.
What are the transitions and overlays that you can add on to the edit that you're going to do multiple
times throughout that one video?
That's going to be the unique look and specific special effect.
You know, whether it's film burns or whether it's Ruchi type audio transitions or whether it's kind
of a glitchy style.
There's going to be a specific look.
You really want to narrow and hone in on and develop for that project.
Then you want to smooth and level out all of your audio, all of your music using these techniques that
we've done using the bezier when you keyframe to really create a smooth in and out point and really
blend your audio elements together.
And finally, you want to drop in your final media assets, whether that's a motion graphic title card
at the beginning, at the end, showing your website, showing your client's product, URL, whatever
it is.
That'll be one of the final steps that you'll do.
And when you take these and do all of these elements together in the way that we've done it throughout
this course and apply that all to one video, that is when you create a super amazing epic, interesting,
inspiring, educational, motivating and magnetic piece of art, piece of work that you do with your
own creativity.
So I hope that that little mini recap summary gives you some final tidbits on what we learned throughout
this course.