So we are now going to dive into your editing workflow.
And basically what we're going to do here is I'm going to show you how to create a clean workspace,
OK?
It's really important to have the laptop that you're working on, computer that you're working on,
phone that you're editing on, whatever it is.
We're going to have things organized so that as you build that skill level, you're going to really
build a good structure and a good routine now so that that can grow with you.
And you really have good habits.
So it's really important.
We're going to spend some time to now organize our footage so that our edit starts to flow seamlessly.
So let's do that now.
The first step is to pull the footage off our cards that we've already shot.
In this case, because we're doing something we can all edit together with is that we're going to be
grabbing the footage off our phone.
So I'm going to do that now.
All right.
So as you can see, I have my footage already in an album.
So if you haven't already kind of collected the video files that you want to use for this learning exercise,
you can go ahead and pause the course and you can go ahead and do that now.
So now that I have all of my video files selected, this is just kind of a little bonus tip on how I
transfer content.
Like I said, so much of us are shooting now in our phones, photo and video.
And the best way I found to transfer that content is to airdrop rather than having to plug in your device
and go through all that stuff.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to select all my videos here.
I'm going to hit share.
And then I'm going to go to air drop and then boom, there's my laptop.
OK, I'm going to click the device and this is going to start sending all the footage that I'm going
to edit with.
Right.
The very first step, which is capturing the content that you've shot.
It's going to transfer it from my filming device to the equipment that I'm going to be editing on perfec.
So that just finished transferring to my laptop.
Now that we did a little mini saiid course tangent on how to actually get the footage from our phone
to what we're editing on.
You can see here I have a different kind of content I shot on a recent trip to Mount Shasta.
So the very first thing we want to do is to create a folder where our whole edit is going to take place.
So I'm going to title this Mount Shasta edit, OK?
And inside this main folder, this main folder that we create is going to encapsulate all of the content
that's involved, the audio, the music, the visuals, the pictures, everything.
OK, so inside this folder, we're going to create some folders that keep everything very organized.
So inside that folder, I want you to create a footage folder and then I want you to create an editing
folder.
I'm using Premiere.
So I always personally title the folder that is holding all the editing assets because these are going
to be separate.
Your original video and audio files is one asset for your edit, and the editing files are the basic
like signpost and little connection.
Things that you're editing software is doing, you're editing software is always using the original
footage.
So you have to keep them organized and safe in their own respective place.
So going to make a premier file, you can name this something like project files, editing files, whatever
helps you instantly know that this is the folder with all your important editing assets belong in.
If I hop back over here to our slides, you can see we created our folder with our project name, our
editing folder, and there's a few other folders that because this is one of our initial edits we're
doing together.
It's much more on the simple side.
So we don't really have all these different complex sub folders to create.
We don't need to really mark the day, the scene, Ayro coverage, buro coverage.
Those are things we'll get into more as we get on to more complex edits.
So the next step that I'm going to do here is highlight all of the footage that we dragged on to the
laptop.
It's now ready to be categorized.
So throwing all of that in the footage folder.
And next up, we're actually going to create our actual editing file.
So like I said, I'm personally using premiere, but this is going to be the same exact process for
whatever editing software you're that you're using, whether that's final cut or premiere or any of
the other ones.