OK, yes, and so we got a lot to talk about for this project, and I want to say this just once at
the beginning of this chapter or the beginning of this project, so I don't repeat it through the video
lessons.
If I'm going through the edit and you see something like, wait, what?
How do you do that?
Why is he not explaining that?
I'm moving past that because I've already explained it earlier in the course.
I just want to say now I have to repeat it.
Do you see something like, wait, how the heck do you filter the audio or how do you out of reverb
or whatever it is, it's because it's already in the course.
This whole portion of these showcases and case studies and breakdowns is to focus on the more complex
stuff.
So good.
OK.
Perfect.
Now, let's get into this edit.
And I want to just show first off, we have this text layer.
So I got this from the client.
This is their logo for the track that they made.
And so what I did is a simple fade in and fade out.
But as you can see, we did the bezier on it.
So we have this nice curve.
If we don't have the Bezzina, just linear.
It's one straight line.
So when it fades out, it can be a little bit more abrupt for a project like this, where it's smooth
and it's mysterious and it's ethereal.
We want to have things right.
So that's one thing right out of the gate.
We have a nice soft curve that makes the fade a lot smoother like that versus push.
Push, right.
So that's something right out of the gate.
And let's kind of see as you can kind of look here.
I have it's hard to see.
OK, I have these markers on this clip.
OK.
Boom.
And it's showing where I want my first cuts to be.
And it's a pretty slow pacing at this beginning of the video.
We have this opening mysterious shot where the character is swimming, but we don't quite see what it
is.
This is kind of a cool reveal shot where it catches your attention.
And that's why I put it first.
And it's also acting as a little bit of a background image for this logo to sit on top of.
If I took that same logo and put it on a really clear image, it doesn't look bad.
But because the background is already kind of a little bit blurry and darker, it's perfect for our
opening shot.
Take a deep breath, and I want to mention that, yes, we are following the pacing of the track, this
not dum dum dum dum dum with the cutting, there's not a bunch of quick cuts.
It's pretty slow and steady because the beginning of the song doesn't have a beat B. It's not right.
There's no beat.
It's just a really cool kind of atmospheric ambient noise.
So you want to cut slower, but you want to find where the beat is, even if there is in a specific
instrument.
So we're cutting on the different note changes.
A.
No change.
Is no change.
And no change.
And you see how we're holding this shot, so it's got an extra cool feel of just extra epic ness overall.
Take a deep breath.
By two feet, breathing all the way out.
And there's some subtleties going on here.
Yes, we do see her feet in the shot.
It's just kind of a little bonus that this motion that she's doing and the feeling of this song or the
feeling of the shot matches up with her vocals.
And then we have kind of an abstract shot of just her dress.
And the vocals are breathe it all the way out or something like that.
We're not showing her physically breathing out, but we're showing a shot that in an abstract, creative
way, it doesn't really make sense on paper that, OK, I have to breathe it all the way out.
And then if I write down, show dress shot wouldn't really compute or make sense.
But if you see the motion of the dress, it kind of has a metaphor simile kind of effect to what she's
saying.
So hopefully understanding that kind of subtlety.
Let's take a look.
A deep breath in.
By your feet, breathe in all the way out.
Take another deep breath and bring on it.
OK, perfect.
So as you can see, we're cutting with the major parts of the track and her vocals.
And this is something I want to share called a match cut.
Oh, is it?
Yeah.
OK, yeah.
This is a match cut.
So we have her hand in roughly the top right part of the frame in the following shot.
We have her hand in a different location, a different time of day, a completely different part of
the production.
Roughly in the top right part of the frame.
Right.
So you can kind of create some cool visual moments by what's called a match cut.
Now, what that means is we're basically having two separate images with a very similar area of where
the viewer is looking.
When you look at the shot, I can guarantee your eyes looking right here.
It's not looking over here.
It's not like it over here.
It's going to be looking right here.
Now, in this next shot, your eye is already going to be resting at this part of the image.
So when the shot comes in, your eye is already looking there.
And I guarantee you, when you look at this image, your eye is going to start here.
It's going to go here, here, here, here.
So if you pay attention to where your eyes looking at the image consciously, you'll find that.
And that's a really cool way to use a matko is my looking here.
The next part of the image, I'm looking at the same place and then I can look elsewhere.
I'm looking here the next cut or the next image, boom.
I'm still looking there.
That creates seamless edits.
And that's a really cool way to change location kind of seamlessly or in a unique way is to find similarities
of where the viewer is looking.
And what the contents of that actual image is.
Now, let's move forward and find some other unique parts of this edit.