So go ahead and make your way to your editing software.
Perfect.
So now that we have our editing file open, we're going to create a brand new project.
OK, now I'm going to title this.
The name of my trip, Mount Shasta.
Edit.
OK, perfect.
And now that we put in the title of our project.
Remember that folder that we created that we sent all the editing assets?
We're going to go.
OK, that's where we're going to go to now.
So go ahead and hit browse or select or find folder or whatever that looks like for you.
Go ahead and choose the location.
Mount Shasta, edit, select and boom premiere.
This is where all the assets are going to go.
Choose perfect.
And then we're going to hit, OK.
So now we have our editing file.
And the next step here is to drag in the footage that we're going to be editing for this project.
So I'm going to go to Finder.
I'm going to go to my footage that we selected.
And I'm going to drag that into the project window.
And before we actually get into our edits, now that we have things organized, it's always, always,
always a good idea to back up your content on to to take to separate locations.
OK.
So I have all the originals that we just worked with directly on my laptop.
Now, what I'm going to do is create a backup folder on a separate hard drive in a separate location
so that we have two copies of the same information.
So that just in case, none of it ever gets lost.
No matter how big or small your project is, I always recommend taking the time to do this extra step
and even though it takes up a little bit of extra room.
Yeah, I know.
It's kind of frustrating because we can run out of space quickly on hard drives.
It's going to be worth it in the long run.
So let's do that now.
So I'm going to open up a new window and I'm going to go to my hard drive and I'm going to go to create
a new folder.
And I'm going to the tile at Mount Shasta back up.
OK.
And then once you've done that, we go to our original folder and you can either copy the entire folder
or copy the contents inside the folder.
It's really up to you.
Does the same thing.
But what I did there is I copied the information in the folder, and now I'm going to paste it into
our backup folder on a completely separate drive.
And so now that we've gotten the basic logistic side of capturing our content, what I want to first
show you is an actual final edit with the footage that I'm going to be working with.
So you can kind of get an idea of where we're going to be heading in this learning exercise for the
rest of this learning exercise.
And you can see where we're going, and then we're going to build it from square one together.
So let's check it out.
Now that is the waterfall.
Cool, so you can get a feel for what we're kind of going for here.
And I also wanted to mention it's very simple cutting, very straightforward cutting.
And majority of this edit, we want to be using the raw audio just to kind of understand how to, you
know, get used to just using raw audio.
And then later in the course, we're going to get into actually I think it's in the next learning exercise,
we're going to get into more adding in extra sound design and extra audio.