So now that we are nearing the very end of this journey together, I want to actually give you a creative
challenge.
Now, my challenge that I'm giving to you as a graduate of this course is for you to take all these
techniques.
Take the knowledge, take the techniques and actionable takeaways.
And I want you to create one video every single month, week or day.
Whatever works for your schedule, whatever kind of content you make that fits into whatever time frame
doesn't matter.
But I want you to commit to a certain time period and create regular content in that time period and
make videos that you are proud to share with the world.
So with that said, now it's your turn to go out there and create an wiki's, new awesome videos that
I know you're going to be putting together.
Make sure you tag me in your posts.
And keep in touch with me at Juliane Discovers on Instagram is honestly the easiest and best way to
keep in touch and to keep me updated on your projects.
So this is the final time I get to say, OK, and now above Oblo or so, now we're looking good, or
now this edit is looking pretty good.
This is the last time.
So let's see.
Thank you so much for joining me, for editing alongside me, for taking the time to grow, change,
evolve and improve your creativity and your skills.
So with that said, I will see you in the next online course.
Thank you.