And now we are ready to start our actual edit.
So let's first start by selecting all of the clips that we want to create a sequence from right click
the first clip and create a new sequence from this clip.
Now, first thing I want to do here is label this timeline main sequence.
And I'm going to create a sequence is, as you are getting very good at by now, main sequences folder,
drag that sequence into the folder.
And we're going to start going here and pulling Selex on our footage.
And I actually want to take a second here, because this is going to be a circumstance where, like
I mentioned, we have multiple takes of the same performance.
This would be a scenario where in other situations, if we had the same exact timing on a clip, we
would.
I don't want to see this in a different editing project.
We're going to be using the synchronized and multicam function of our editing software to sync multiple
takes together and multiple angles together automatically in an automated way.
Now, because she was doing a live performance on each one of these takes, if we look at the waveforms
here, we can see that it's different every single time, even though she's playing the same song.
Each one is a different performance.
So we won't be able to use the automated synchronize function in this specific scenario.
And with different videos that you are doing different projects, you're going to be able to do it in
the automated way, which we will do together.
But for this one specifically, we're going to find a point that we can mark on each one of her takes.
There is going to be in the same moment, and then that way we'll be able to go and manually overlay
all the different takes together to have one multilayered take, to then be able to pick and choose
what shots we want to use for which moments.
Hopefully that makes sense.
If it doesn't make sense right now, it's going to make sense as we go through this edit.
And I'm just going to continue here to label these different takes different colors.
OK.
Perfect.
Now we have all of our different takes are separate colors.
And now, like I mentioned, we're going to be manually creating a marker on each one of these takes.
So we can go in and manually line everything up.
So to do that, what I want to look for is somewhere in the waveform that has contrast.
I want to have no information and then a peek or a high amount of information.
That way I can scan these other waveforms and easily see where that repeating strong sound is happening.
So let's take a listen to.
So is towards the end of the routine.
OK, perfect, I think this is going to be a good moment to sink the rest of the clips, too, so I'm
going to take my cursor to the peak of this note that she plays towards the end of the track.
And I'm going to find that same moment on the next take.
OK, it's coming up right here.
Perfect.
Go to that peak, select the clip, go to the peak.
Hit em to leave a marker.
And now I'm going to add it to the rest of the sequence.
Boom.
Perfect.
Now we have our marker here on each of our takes.
Now what we're going to do is manually move our takes and layer them on top of each other.
So I'm going to drag the video for this one up,
match up these markers
and do the same thing for the rest of these clips.
It's.
OK, perfect.
And now we have all of our different takes stacked on top of each other.
So you as well by now should have all of your takes linked up together.
If you're using this footage to work with or if you're using your own footage to work with, you should
have all your takes ready to go and select.