And the last thing that I want to do before I actually go into the editing process of putting this whole
multicam thing, which is going to be pretty dang fun to do, but we don't want to use any of this audio.
This audio is very echoey if we listen.
It was just the, you know, the on board mike of the camera, I think I shot this with the one, the
X mark, two of the five, D mark four.
So what we want to do is take the good actual produced song and bring it in here and synchronize it.
So we have the song here
and you can see how much better that sound.
So I'm going to copy that.
I'm going to go to our multicam sequence.
I'm going to double click it to open it up.
We have all of our layers.
I'm going to paste in the good track.
I'm going to drag it down here to the bottom.
And I'm going to go to the final beat of the track, because that's the most definitive part of the
video.
And I'm going to listen on a solo or good track that we want to use.
And I'm going to find that final beat and make a marker.
OK, I know it's right there at that last hit.
OK, now I'm going to line it up.
And I'm an unmuted OK.
And now I know that synched up in what I can do is mute the rest of the tracks and what we'll have now
is all of our tracks.
Synched up.
With the good sounding audio.
OK, now we're starting to get cooking here.
Now, if we go back to our main sequence, and I'm just going to delete this tail off here, because
we kind of scooted everything a little bit forward in our multicam sequence.
And now we have our main sequence and it just looks like one layer, right?
We have one layer of audio and one layer of video.
But this is where the good stuff happens.
This is where the magic happens.
I'm going to hit shift zero.
Now, I have all six of my angles that I can view at once.
So if I let this play.
So we have everything that we need.
Now, here's the cool part of the multicam.
So I'm going to show you how to do it, and then I'm going to go through and edit this 30 second cut.
So if we look at our waveform, we can see kind of where big striking moments are.
I can already tell that right here is a striking moment.
I can tell that just the beat is at the beginning of this video.
So it's just a touch before the actual musical instruments come in.
The big B is right there.
There's a pause right here.
And then the ending is here.
So that's going to kind of dictate where some of my cutting is going to be and the way we can do the
cutting is either by using the blade tool like this, I create a cut and then I minimize this and I
can click where I want this cut I just made, which angle I want to use for it, basically.
So I go.
And then a cut to the next angle, if I didn't want to use this angle, I could simply click.
And now it changes this whole clip to be that angle.
The other thing you can do if you don't want to click is you can use the numeral what's it called,
the number pad.
So I'm hitting one to go to angle one.
I'm hitting two on the keyboard to go to two, I'm hitting three and the keyboard to go to three, four
and so on.
Those are the two main ways to cut stationary without you playing.
But honestly, my favorite one to do is to actually let the clip play through or let the timeline play
through and cut live.
This is the kind of like breakthrough aha moment that I had with using a multicam sequence the first
time that I used it.
So if I let this play and I start clicking with the shots I want to use, it's going to cut live.
So let's let's see what that looks like.
Gas.
OK, so I hit pause and now it just saved all those cuts that I just made.
So let's see in that little 20 second window what kind of we just magician didn't put together.
Gas.
So just like that, we weren't pausing bring out the blade to a cutting, scooting everything over,
removing, cutting, changing angles, pulling back layers to see was below it.
We just played it through and simply clicked or use a numerical pad to cut live, almost like cutting
a live event or a live TV show.
They use switching boards, kind of similar to this multicam sequence where when you're watching like
the Olympics or a sporting event like the Super Bowl or something, there's guys sitting in a room with
a live cutting board where they see all the angles that are happening on the field.
They're cutting it live.
And that's what you're seeing on your television.
That's really the same process that we're doing here, is using that really cool sound, good same technique
to make our editing process quicker when we're using multiple angles.
So now I'm going to go through using this multicam sequence and create the first draft edit, and then
we're going to hop into how to then add B roll into our sequence.
So I will see you in the next learning lesson.