And as we go through this, now that we finished our Selex, we're going to start making our rough edit.
Now, we're not going to use any music yet because we want to first get this sequence down from right
now.
It's at six minutes and five seconds.
We want to get it a lot closer to kind of that 30 second window that the actual edit is going to be
before we drop in the music track.
OK.
So let's now scrub through our Selex and see which shots are going to be the best.
OK, so if we look at the beginning of the sequence is going to be our opening shot.
OK, so I'd imagine that by the time we get to here, we have plenty of other coverage, simply meaning
by coverage, I mean other angles that are covering what we're shooting.
So more coverage means more shot options, less coverage means less shot options, since it's going
to be a really quick paced, high rhythmic pacing.
We're probably going to have a cut by the time we get to here.
We have plenty of other shots to choose from, so I'm going to delete.
Right there and I know we have better coverage from the Selex we polled.
This is kind of a wide, boring shot.
It doesn't look too dramatic.
The batteries kind of, you know, sadly falling to the ground.
He's reloading, but I know we have better reload shots from the process we just did.
So I'm going to delete that.
And now I'm going to see if this intro shot is better or if this one is better.
So let's go ahead and delete the access from both of these and let's play these back to back.
OK.
I like his posture there and the way he kind of pulls around the camera.
It looks like the camera's got some weight to it.
This one is not as interesting the way his body's angled.
This one seems to be a little bit more appealing with the camera movement.
Versus this one.
OK, so let's go ahead and make the decision to delete the second one, because it's likely that we're
not going to use it, and we always do have it as a backup in our SELEX backup sequence.
OK, that's a little bit out of order, we're not going to use that one yet, so we're going to the
opening the camera.
Which means that.
We can actually put these at the very end.
And this set of orange clips is going to be the next four hour sequence.
So let's see which of these three is the best take.
OK, looks like the battery gets caught up on that tape.
I don't think we're going to be using that.
That's OK.
That one is really cool.
Let's delete this middle shot that we don't need, so then we have opening the battery thing, pushing
the button and then throwing it whenever you're skipping forward ahead in time and kind of breaking
continuity by speeding up a process.
You're automatically making that process kind of jump forward and feel a bit more exciting.
So that's really the goal on this style of it, is if we were doing something that is more smooth,
storytelling with a voiceover would be a completely different style of editing, which we are going
to be doing in the next exercise.
So let's leave this as a rough edit the way it is.
Boom, love that shot and notes.
Now, as this is falling out of frame, that's the perfect cutting moment when you're looking at when
to cut to transition to this now coming into frame.
Oh, so you always want to, as an editor, go for a seamless style of editing.
So here we can see that he's bringing in the battery.
And just before we cut, there's a little bump you see right there.
There is an extra few frames where his motion pauses and it creates a little bit of a like a little
bit of a jerkiness into the next shot.
So there's extra space there.
So we're going to take this shot and we're going to scoot it over.
I'm going to hold command and do the left arrow a few frames to scoot over this shot closer to this
one.
Boom.
So there's still oh, that little pause right there.
So we're going to take even a few more frames by moving this clip over to the left.
OK, that's a lot better.
OK.
And now there's a little bit of an extra pause on this shot.
You see how where we start the clip.
It's waiting, boom.
So what we want to do to create an even more seamless, smooth cut is cut on the action versus cutting
on when there's pausing.
We want to transition the action here of the movement into the action here of that movement.
So there's a few extra frames here.
So let's go ahead and scoot to where the action starts and we'll create a cut.
And now look at the edit.
Boom, that's a lot better.
I would even move over this clip even further to the left, so let's one to three.
Oh, so this is really the key and one of the main benefits of using multiple different shots and having
those different shots in your SELEX sequence is that we can really easily navigate the scrub through
and find the best shot like this one is so much more smooth and kind of interesting, even though it's
such a simple little thing of just closing this little camera hatch, it's going to make a big difference.
So boom, boom, boom, that one we don't want.
And we just found that the very last take that we did has the best real close.
So let's go ahead and trim that or hit save and we'll see our three options here for the ending shot.
So that's looks a little bit blurry.
Is that intro?
Yeah, I'd like to see one with the camera and the lens in focus.
So it seems that one's looking a lot better.
Oh, I think this one is the one.
So can you see the difference in these three options?
That was, OK, this one's a little bit better, and I think we nailed it on this one.
Right.
The performance is great, even though he's just lifting the camera.
But it's in focus.
Good framing.
And the motion is great.
So let's delete these extra ones.
Get rid of this empty space.
And cut in.
And we'll probably probably do some time remapping, which I'm really excited to show you how to do
that.
Perfect.
And now that we have our super rough edit ready to go.
Next up is to find the perfect song to match our edit.