So we just talked about audio cues just in this first 20 seconds of our edit and we're going to talk
more about audio, but I now want to dive into some of the visual stuff that's going on towards the
beginning of this edit.
So let's look over here at a screen cap.
And by the way, I know we spent a lot of time upgrading our motion graphics or upgrading our text to
look more professional.
But, you know, you can still do a lot with just really clean font with a black screen that has the
right size, you know, and the right with and the right amount of information on each line with a nice
little fade in and just a little bit of movement can go a long way and still create that professional
look.
So don't think you have to always have these crazy motion graphics with glitchy eage transitions in
and move in and different colors and all that stuff that we worked on to create together.
You can do really great looking stuff with very clean looking font.
Now let's go ahead and skip forward to getting better at reading requires seeing the written word differently
once you get the hang of that.
The writing comes naturally to study in literature make you better at every subject you'll ever study
I.
Okay, perfect.
So we have our music synched up to the cool moments in our visuals.
We have the music synched up to the right moments to when she's speaking.
And that's really the goal that we focused on throughout the course.
Now, I just want to explain what's going on here and why these shots work so well together.
You can kind of see, OK.
And by the way, these shots are right here, one, two, three, four, five shots.
And if I go ahead and reveal this in the project, OK, sorry about that.
My computer or my editing program actually just crashed.
And that's one of the dangers when you have a lot of stacked footage with a lot of filters on it.
This can happen.
So you have to save your process regularly.
OK.
Now back to this.
I'm going to right click the first shot in a viral sequence.
I'm going to open it up and I'm going to show you what the original shot look like.
So we have the teacher, I'm giving her some direction on what to do.
So we have her walking up here, OK?
Of course, we're not using any of these things before, and right there is the shot, as you can see.
Then she walks up and she honestly doesn't really do anything.
We do it again.
She walks up.
She starts writing.
I'm giving her notes or feedback on what to do.
She's kind of doing a mock teaching session here, like pretending like she's teaching a class.
She's writing out OK.
And altogether, this is a seven minute sequence.
So what we did is we took the most interesting parts of that sequence.
Of course, we color corrected it, as you can see between this shot and this shot.
So we have her walking in.
We cut to her writing.
And as she's still doing that movement, boom, it goes to this movement.
And as she's moving her hand, still, boom, it goes to this movement.
And as that slides, then that goes into this same type of movement.
That's what creates that to do really smooth transition between these five shots.
That was really seven minutes of raw footage that we went through in the select process that you should
be an expert at by now.
And we took that and we cut together this little let's see.
Twenty eight seconds to 33 seconds.
So this is a little four to five seconds in literature, four or five second piece.
And you can see the other reason why it feels right is because each cut is on beat with this track.
Here's our track.
These mountains or peaks are going to be our beat.
OK.
And actually, let me solo this track.
Boom, boom, boom, boom, boom, boom.
So boom, boom, right.
It goes right with the song itself.
So it feels natural to the viewer.
And it also goes to the moments of her speaking.
So as you develop your skills, at first you're going to be able to create a montage just to a song,
and then you're going to be able to create, you know, a montage and an edit to just vocals maybe,
and mash up the visuals and show the visuals that explain more about what's being shared audibly.
And then you're going to be able to develop the skill where you're sinking the visuals to what's being
said.
You're matching the beat with your cuts on the music track, and then you're adding in all these extra
layers.