Now, I want to mention one more thing before we go into our next video lesson, so we have this shot
boom, and then we have these birds that are moving to the upper right part of the frame.
So it's like there's a line, a curve being drawn like this if you watch this image.
There's a curve in your tummy.
And in the following image, see this curve, your eyes are going to be along this line.
I guarantee you're not looking over here on the top left.
I guarantee you're not really looking over here in the top middle.
Your eye is going to be drawn to do this.
Push your house.
In the next image, we have a curvy line made by our subject's body.
This is another great example of a matko.
So these shots really blend together with the Filburn with the match cut.
The motion of the subject is also going to the top, right?
So we're going to the right, to the right, to the right, basically.
And then.
And the other thing that we're doing here, like what we mentioned before, is she's doing a movement
but doesn't complete the movement, which leads into the movement of the next shot, which leads into
the movement of the next shot.
If you want to make it clunky, you can skew things over, skew things over, skew things over.
Let it play.
Allow your tummy to relax in your breath, to flow naturally.
Which so that was not terrible, but it just didn't have a very good flow.
This movement looked OK, but didn't lead into the next movement, and that movement didn't really lead
into this movement.
So let's undo that and check it out again.
You're telling me to relax.
In your back to flow naturally.
What's showing up to you today?
Perfect, so you don't always have to do that, it doesn't mean that your edit, it needs every single
shot flowing into the next shot, but it's cool to do it in moments where there's a sudden smoothness.
And then like, for example, this shot is kind of abruptly not matching these other bright fluffy shots,
which I mean, actually.
But it works because in this part of the video, her vocals are asking a specific question that's very
separate from what we just saw.
So she's telling you to relax, flow, see what comes naturally.
And then she's asking a very direct question, what's showing up for you today?
And we see this much more bluish tone.
She's not moving.
She's more in a meditative posture.
That's pretty deep right there.
But I'm hoping that you can grab some.
I'm really.
Yeah.
Wow, OK.
Hopefully you can grab some insights from the subtleties that you can really get into with this kind
of edit.
And I will see you in the next video lesson.