Now that we have all of our footage into our editing software and the peek files have been generated
or good to go and start this edit, and this is a perfect opportunity to learn about how to work with
different frame rates.
Now, if we take a look here, we can see our frame rates.
All of these clips are shot at twenty three point nine seven six, which is going to be most of the
time the frame rate that you're working with for normal speed footage, a.k.a. twenty four frames a
second.
Why cameras in the US shoot at twenty three point nine, seven, six frames per second instead of 24
frames a second.
I don't know if, you know, maybe leave it in the Q&A, but that doesn't matter so much.
What does matter is that this footage is always going to playback in real time.
OK, there's not going to be any speed changes unless we add that in post-production.
But what I want to focus on is utilizing clips that you may have and that we have in this edit that
are shot at double the standard frame rate, which is 60 frames per second, or because I don't know
why camera companies do this, fifty nine point nine four frames per second.
They just kind of add that little point zero six frames per second.
I don't know.
It doesn't make sense to me.
But what we're going to learn here is how to slow down this footage so that when we drag it into our
timeline, it's automatically playing back as smooth battery B roll, slow motion footage.
Now, the first step is to highlight all of the footage that we want to adjust the frame rate playback
from.
And then the next step, which you'll see why we do this in a moment, is to label it and change the
color.
Now, the reason we're going to do this is because now we know that all this is going to be our slow
motion footage.
Generally for YouTube videos, you're going to have your AROL coverage or your main interview.
You talking to the camera, like what's going on right now?
And then you're going to have your cutaway shots.
So if it's a travel log, you have you speaking to the camera, doing your travel log thing, pointing,
doing whatever.
And then there's going to be footage that you shoot where you're getting slow motion footage of cars,
of scenery, of really cool places that you're shooting.
And that's going to be your B roll or secondary shots or cutaway shots.
Now, I never and you should never shoot your normal interview talking footage at slo mo 60 frames per
second.
You should always shoot it at the normal frame it twenty three point nine, seven six.
So seeing this frame rate tells me that this is all my Bairo cutaway shots from my YouTube video.
Now I labeled it and changed the color so that I know that it's going to be my cutaway shots.
And the next step to change the frame rate so that when we play it back in the timeline, it's the cool,
slow, mo look that we want for our cutaway shots.
We're going to right click.
We're going to go to modify.
And we're going to interpret our footage.
Now, you can see at this frame rate tab, what it's doing is it's playing the footage at its normal
frame rate that it was shot at.
But what we want to do is click, assume the frame rate of this clip.
Now we're going to type in twenty three point nine seven six, which is going to tell the computer and
the editing software.
I want you to play this back as if it was normal speed footage, but it's it was shot at double the
speed of that normal speed footage, meaning when the clip is played back, it's going to play back
at half the speed of real life, which is going to give us the cool, slow mo that I've been talking
about.
So we put in twenty nine, twenty three point nine, seven, six, and we hit OK.
Now, if I were to double click this clip.
And hit play.
Let's find a let's find a better example.
You can see this is not the best example because there's not a lot of movement going on this clip.
But you can see it's playing back in slow motion automatically without us having to select the clips.
Go to the speed duration.
Slow it down a half speed.
This will give us a smooth, slow motion playback.
So now that we understand that the next step is to go to the remaining folders of footage that we have
and do that same process to all of the slow motion viral shots that we have.
So that when we drag everything into the timeline, it's all playing back at our desired speed.
So I'm going to close the folder that we just made, the update and navigate to the next folder.
Scroll.
And I'm looking at this frame rate column.
OK.
We have some slama footage here.
I'm actually the double click this first one so that we can see what it looks like.
OK, so normal speed, right?
You can see I'm getting some close ups.
And what we're going to do now is select these clips.
We're going to color them.
Let's just say Teale, and then we're going to right click, go to modify, interpret footage.
Assume the frame rate is 29 excuse me, twenty three point nine seven six instead of 60 frames a second
and hit, OK.
And now if we watch that same clip we were just looking at.
You can see it's got that nice slow motion aesthetic.
Now we've got one more folder in here.
This has got a lot of footage.
Oh, my gosh.
And it looks like this last folder is probably all talking footage because I don't see any slow motion
shots.