So you've taken the fire footage that I've supplied and you've edited it together, you have a music
track.
Don't worry if it's not a masterpiece yet.
Don't worry, we'll get to creating a masterpiece as we go through this course.
But now I want to have you see the edit that you created.
And I want to show you edits from other students that have used the same exact footage as you.
And let's see what kind of conclusion we come up with after viewing some of these other examples.
Get ready.
OK.
Super high energy edit this one is kind of the exact opposite.
Very slow, very thoughtful.
Super Bowl track on that one, I love the laidback style.
Now let's get into another edit name for me.
Remember the name?
Nancy?
No.
The.
OK, so we just saw a few of those submissions, and you should probably be seeing a trend here.
Same exact footage.
Different editor.
Completely different final product.
So there's two reasons that I wanted to put this at the very beginning of the course.
One, to give you something fun, easy and quick to do to get, you know, a little bit of serotonin,
a little bit of dopamine hit, a little bit of excitement, you know, on the psychology side, so that
you are incentivized to continue to go to the cause and then to it's a long roundabout way of explaining
and giving you the realization that every person has their own unique taste, aesthetic and sense of
what they feel.
Looks good, sounds good and feels good.
So the whole goal of this first exercise is for you to really embody and lock in that realization and
find out that your specific unique look style and feel the more that you hone in on that, the more
that's going to become your trademark, your your ability and your persona as a video editor.
Regardless, if you do like blogs or tutorials or documentaries, you're going to find a specific look
in all great artists have a specific look, and that's what made them rise to fame.
It's not about being famous, but you you develop a certain characteristic that when someone sees that,
they see, oh, yeah, that's so and so's painting.
And then people really start to resonate and like that specific look that they get regularly from that
person.
Your favorite directors, your favorite films have a specific look that that director or producer usually
has across all their videos.
And you come back to them and you view their art because you love that feeling.
So the feeling that you love, naturally, the more you can hone in on that throughout this course,
the more other people see that they'll resonate with it.
And then there's a lot of benefit from that.
You get to create art that inspires you.
You don't have to go and follow other trends and the other things that people are doing because it's
popular at the moment.
No, you want to create your own personal trend in style that other people will see and be inspired
by.
That's the first part.
The second part is that you develop that look style and feel clients will see that and they'll say,
hey, I loved what you did with this video, in this video, in this video.
I want to pay you to do that style for my product or service or website or any kind of thing that that
client has and that they're willing to pay you for to create content and a video for.
So I really hope that this beginning exercise really opens you up to the type of expansion and exciting
stuff that we're going to learn together in this course.
So that wraps it up for this first chapter.
And in the next chapter, we're going to dive into some beginner level exciting editing fundamentals.