All right, so now I went through and I pulled all my Selex, so we went from an hour of footage to
now just about four and a half minutes of footage.
So I have all the best shots.
And next is to well, first of all, we're going to go ahead and drag in our possible music tracks.
But what I also want to mention is it's a little bit tricky to organize or at least order a demo reel.
You know, when you shoot a project, you have an overall rhyme and reason for the ordering of shots.
You have a beginning, a middle and an end in a demo reel.
It's just this huge collage of different shots.
But you want to keep in mind that you want to try and find some kind of intro opening shots, some maybe
middle, exciting high energy shots and somehow find some kind of good conclusion ending the video type
of footage.
So right off the bat, I know that I do have kind of a handful of these eye shots.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to copy that shot.
I'm going to scroll to the front.
I'm going to create some room here.
And I'm going to put this shot at the beginning and this one as well.
And we're going to try to do some kind of cool multiple eyes opening to open the beginning in the video.
So I'm going to just scroll through here real quick.
We're this shot.
So you can do this similar process for your footage, if you have multiple styles or multiple of the
same type of shot, like if you were doing some kind of sports demo reel and you had a bunch of maybe
dunks, you know what I mean?
Or you're doing some kind of clothing video and you had a bunch of shots where you're tying the laces
on your shoes on multiple like 10 different pairs of shoes.
You could put that at the beginning, like boom, boom, boom.
And that could be the opening.
If that was the type of Demario you were doing.
So let me just finish going through here.
I feel like there's one more.
Oh, yeah.
There we go.
Boom, baby.
All right.
So, yes, we got.
Yes.
OK.
Now, in a place this at the beginning.
So we kind of have a rough maybe set of opening shots.
Of course, the pacing and the the timing is like not set yet, but we have some kind of similarity
between this grouping of shots.