So now that we have all of our clips synched up, the next step is to drag our audio that we're actually
going to be using for the edit.
So let's go to the same point of the audio track and mark the same point that we marked for all of other
video files.
So as towards the end.
So it's that point right there, it m for marker.
And now that we don't need any of these audio files, we can go ahead and select all the audio files
hit delete.
We still have the markers here as a reference, and we can drag our audio in line up the marker.
And if we did everything right, this should be synched up.
That's looking, seems to me so we've done a good job so far.
Now what I want to do is trim some of the excess clips that we don't need.
So we're going to go to the beginning of our actual audio file.
And I'm going to hit see to bring up the blade tool.
And I'm going to hold shift before I do the normal cut that we've been doing throughout the course.
What that's going to do is rather than making a cut on one single layer at a time when I hold shift
and click, that's going to make a scene cut across all the layers, which is really handy in this kind
of scenario, because we've got quite a few layers that we're working with here now that I've made the
cut on all of those layers.
I'm going to highlight them in a tweet.
Then we can simply right click repl delete to fill that empty space.
Now we can do the same thing at the end.
OK, go to the end.
I'm going to proceed for the blade to hold, shift and click.
There we go.
We have all the clips and we're going to get to the end.
And this will be a good time to create a backup sequence.
OK, so that way we have all of our Selex pulled in together and then it'd be nice and safe.
So let's go to our sequence.
Let's hit Comanche and hit Command V to duplicate it.
Let's go ahead and name this backup.
OK.
Drag it back into the sequences folder.
And now we're ready to start cutting together our rough edit.