And I'm going to grab our possible music tracks now.
What I did here to gather these tracks and let me go ahead and put them all into one sequence so we
could talk about what it did here was I knew what I wanted in mind for my specific kind of demo reel.
I know I don't really want vocals because that can kind of have too much emotion behind it or the words
of the song can be a little bit too dissonant to what you're showing.
So if the song is singing about a breakup, it's not going to work for a demo reel.
You want to be careful about how much emotion your song is going to have.
So you want it to be right amount of energy without being too high.
OK.
So we definitely talked about this early in the chorus, but let's see what our options are.
OK, yeah, that's pretty cool.
It's a little bit on the not so bright side, more on the dark kind of trap music side, but we're going
to save it.
I'm going to do blue.
OK,
that was kind of cool.
It's got a little bit of a quirkiness to it.
I don't know how much I'm feeling the Corke, but I'm going to do the maybes orange, so.
And what I'm doing here is we're going to go through because when you pull possible tracks, you know,
you want to have at least three to choose from for a video like this where I really want to nail the
track perfectly.
I'm going to do more than three options, like maybe six.
And we're going to just go ahead and try to get rid of what we definitely feel like.
It's not going to work that way.
We can kind of narrow it down a little bit easier.
Oh, man, I'm feeling like all of these are just maybes.
So I haven't found one yet.
That's like a Helius.
Now, there's one more track that I actually also have that.
Let's see what this sounds like.
OK, let's try this one out.
So in the next video lesson, we're going to drop in our track.