Now, next step, which might be applicable to your footage if you shot your project in four K.
This was not.
But if you did, the next step would be to create your proxies.
That way, it wouldn't employ your computer.
Create a black hole and suck everything in where you're working in.
Do I know I'm going with that.
But so let's go ahead and create the proxies, even though I haven't shot in four k.
I still want to show you the process again so that you really lock it in.
So let's select the clips.
You want to create proxies of right click those clips, go to proxy, create proxies and you can choose.
I recommend either medium or low, depending on your computer's speed and editing capacity.
And before we hit, OK, we want to choose where we want to save these proxies, too.
So we're going to navigate to our original folder.
Create a new folder title at Proxy's, select the folder, and then hit, OK.
Now, what that's going to do is automatically pop up Adobe Media Encoder and it will automatically
add all those files to queue and start generating the low resolution proxy files once those are done.
You can get back into premier.
And if it doesn't show the proxy column already in your project panel, you can right click the top
click metter display type and proxy highlight the proxy function.
Hit OK.
And now it'll show you which proxies have been created and attached.
Once those are done in that footage is in the timeline, you can then engage and disengage the proxies
by toggling on and off the proxy function in the program panel.