So we have already looking pretty good, as usual.
And what I want to go into now is effectively using title cards.
So this is a great opportunity in any kind of showcase video you're doing to have text on screen that
explains something further.
So what I basically want to do is a title card at the intro.
And then there's a few moments where we can explain further what's on screen.
But the information's not there, like about how many bedrooms this property has or about how many square
footage or how many square feet the property is.
So if you're doing the same kind of video, it's a product you can say things like it's a hard drive
and it's five terabytes and the data speed is this much and it's built to withstand a five foot drop
and so on.
So this can be used for any kind of video.
But let's go to the beginning and let's kind of create an intro title.
So I'm going to hit T for the text tool and I'm going to say welcome to the.
And just going to make of a name here, Hillcrest.
Residents.
No, OK, Hillcrest property.
Sounds nice.
OK, Hillcrest property.
I'm going to go over here.
I'm going to center it.
And then I'm going to scale it up a bit.
Actually, it was scaled back a bit and a good way to create.
Let me actually turn down the opacity of this, OK, to make the text kind of stand out a little bit.
A good way to create a more of a professional text when you have things on two lines is to vary the
amount of thickness.
You want to use the same font family.
You don't want to have multiple font families, at least in a professional type video.
If it's more like a kid's video or something that's supposed to be kind of the young, playful feeling.
You can have multiple font families, but for a professional video for a client, you want to have one
font family for basically the whole video and to get it to look cool if it's on multiple lines.
You can vary the width of that font.
So personally, this is a little bit too light.
All I have is the light sembled and extra bold for the specific font.
But what we can do is increase the stroke of the font, and the stroke is simply going to be the amount
of thickness that you're adding.
To the text.
So if we go to maybe add to of the stroke, then we could start to see how this is starting to look
a bit more professional and pop versus just looking like that.
So we got the font looking good.
We can even probably scale this down a little bit.
And that's the other thing that you can do is you can vary the size of the fonts.
So the welcome to is kind of secondary.
And then the primary focus of this specific title is the title or the name of the property.
So we scaled down the top row and we bring down the thickness of the font.
That way, we're creating a little bit more of a unique looking title card.
So let's go ahead and drag this out all over the front clip.
And what I've found, too, and we're going to create a little bit of space between these two.
So there's these different parameters.
This is the space between the letters.
But vertically.
And then this is the space, but with both of the lines changing.
So we can create a little bit more space vertically and.
I've definitely found that adding kind of a very minimal small line with the same color as our phone
when it dropped this on, this is just a full solid, but I found a little bit of a hack a few years
ago.
If we take off the uniform scale and we scaled down the heighth.
We can then create this.
Really, if we put this like point five, this tiny line where it can either go across the whole screen.
But, you know, ideally we're creating something like that.
And we can put it between both of our lines or on the bottom of both lines is really a lot you can play
with.
But this is kind of a unique thing where that's starting to look a lot more produced.
And a cool thing about this kind of uniform scale or taking off the uniform scale is that we can actually
keyframe our width.
So I'm going to go to the end of an add of keyframe.
I'm going to go to the beginning and I want to make it go down.
I'm going to take the width and shrink the width.
And so if we play forward now, we have this nice growing of this line.
So we're adding a little bit of motion there to this graphic.
And next, what we would definitely want to do is add a fade in that's going to also help with making
it just look a little bit more professional.
OK.
And if we want, we can also vary the fade in so that the property comes in first and then the line
comes in.
Or we could do it the opposite way.
But for now, let's just have the line come in a little bit after.
And another thing that we can do, just add a little bit more, is to scale up our text.
OK, so I'm going to go to the end of this text.
I'm going to go to.
Scale, I'm going to hit keyframe.
Go to the beginning, scale it down a few points, I'd say ninety.
Hit play.
So we can see it's moving forward.
It's a little bit slow so you can actually scale it up a little bit more, let's go to 105.
And now we have our text moving forward.
It's moving with the cool line that we created that we just kind of whipped up there.
And now we can also add a fadeout, because this just cutting to straight, just disappearing, it's
not very elegant.
So let's extend our texts and let's extend our keyframes, because right now the keyframes is just going
to stop.
So if we extend the key frames, the animations that we created are going to continue and then we can
create fade out.
I'm hitting the P for pen tool.
There we go.
OK.
So just like that, we just whipped up a nice little intro, Grafik.
If I wanted to add a little bit more, let's say that this wasn't doing it for me and I wanted a little
bit more of the uniqueness, I can go in and add filters to the text.
So let's say I want to go in here and add a fast blur.
Now, what this is going to do is it's just going to act like as if you had your camera out of focus.
It's going to take the fight and blur it so we can animate this property as well.
So I'm going to hit the stopwatch to create a keyframe.
I mean, go to the beginning of the clip and I'm going to bring this up to, let's say, 90.
That way, when it fades in, it also blurs in.
Let's do that same exact process.
Let's do that same exact process as we fade out.
And let's see what we got.
OK.
Looking pretty good.
Let's copy this blurring effect that we just did and let's add it to our line that we created.
OK.
Looking pretty good, so I'm pretty happy with that.
That's a quick way to make a much more professional looking title card.
What we started with was this.
Pretty average, you see that in some videos.
But, you know, the key is really to just create some animations, to create some variance in the text
size and the text with or the stroke of the text, and to have, you know, a fade in, a fade out,
a blur, a little bit of motion and a little bit of animation that just takes that plain text on screen
and has a little bit more character and personality.