Now we are at a party in the edit where we're about a minute in, so we've been working on everything
up to a minute now.
And yeah, we're at a part in the song actually, where the energy gets picked way up.
There was like the mysterious intro, and then the bee kind of came in and we started to pick up the
pacing.
We did a few things with film burns, and now we're at a song which I actually marked here Yellow.
So here's the track, this yellow part you're going to hear.
So I want you to listen and hear the audible change.
So actually, let's listen to it before we actually see what happens.
So pay attention to what happens here as you sift and sort through them like clouds passing in your
sky.
See the sun setting and twinkle lights near?
Another sky full of lights, TerraMar.
OK, so it just dropped in to a completely different, you know, different kind of dreamy, mystical
ness that wasn't this kind of low thing.
This is how I feel things as an editor.
Like when I hear a sound, it either goes up or goes down or it's spiky or it's soft and it's round.
Write it down.
So, yes, you want to be sensitive to these kind of vibe changes.
And let's see what we chose to add as our visual.
To further tell the story of the change that happens right here in this part of the video as you sift
and sort through them like clouds passing in your sky.
See the sun setting?
And twinkle lights, mirrors.
Another sky full of lights, Jeremih remained where she and North Star.
OK, so there's like some symbology stuff going on here.
We have these exciting sparkler shots.
And if you look at these and I don't know why it's having this weird glitch that's not in the final
edit, that weird graininess, not supposed to be that.
So for me, it is doing something weird.
But anyways, this you know, this looks like what this sound in the audio sounds like and twinkle like
two mirrors.
Plus she is saying and twinkle lights here.
And these are twinkle lights.
So, yeah, there's a metaphor thing going on and then there's a literal thing going on.
But this is a subtle vibe change that we are paying attention to at this level of being a video editor
to create that special moment.
So we have boom, this electric excitement in the track and twinkle.
Others and then a more introspective curiosity line that she delivers right here.
Either sky full of lights.
Germany made very similar style, and then we have this crazy looking dear mermaid shot, so we're not
showing this at Mermaid Dear Mermaid, we're not showing this a dear mermaid.
We're showing the frickin mermaid like amazing shot at that point.
Right.
And then she's talking about where is your North Star?
We have this very star esque looking reflection of light coming in through the water as she's touching
it.
So that's the kind of metaphoric thing that I was talking about.
By doing this, you make people feel what the audio is wanting them to feel.
Right.
So and if we go here, we also have a little bit of subtle overlays.
Now, these are different than film birds.
These are much more of like filming something through a glass type of prism.
There's no burned red orange tones like a traditional overlay.
But they have this really cool crystal type of appearance and they are overlaid on top of these shots.
So if I remove them.
To Mary.
And twinkle like to Mary.
Either, Scott, you can see this whole sequence loses its energy and twinkle nightmarishly.
Scott?
Full of lights.
So like I mentioned, you don't put film burns and overlay it just on every shot.
You do it consciously to further make the specific shots look better.
Whether they need it for a transition into a different kind of sequence or the shots just feel a little
bit dull.
So let's keep moving here and we'll get more into some overlays.