So we went through and we added this really nice looking intro card graphic.
Now the next step and probably something you're definitely going to come across in a video like this,
is there's going to be other parts of your video where you want to label something or you want to give
some type of descriptive text to certain parts of the video.
So I just added four of these kind of reminders for myself as I was going through this edit that these
are points in the video where I want to add a little some type of information about this property.
So what I did is I just typed out a few descriptor things like, you know, the location, the square
footage, indoor outdoor living room, what the bedroom and bathroom situation is for this property
specifically.
So I'm going to highlight the first title card that I want to add in to the edit.
And I'm going to go to this title card that I just kind of put as a temporary placeholder or we're going
to switch it around.
But I'm going to go ahead and paste this information.
And let's go ahead and move this up now for information that you're putting in displaying on screen.
That's not a center.
Very important.
You know, intro graphic, when it's during the edit, you don't really want to have things on the bottom
middle.
Generally, it's best for this kind of information, like people's names, locations in the video times
of day, all those cool little pop up graphics that you see generally there on the bottom right of the
bottom left.
There are a few situations where it makes sense in the edit, you know, but you'll kind of see that
it just looks better and it fits better on the bottom.
Off to one side.
Now, if we let's say we chose to go to the bottom left, it looks better if we also justify, I believe
it's called.
Yeah.
Or alignment to the side that we want to choose.
So if I want to go to the left and let me actually scale is down.
So it starts looking a little bit better.
Yeah.
That's a lot better.
Generally, your text is going to look a lot better if you align it.
So this is a left aligned.
And if I let's say I wanted to go to the right side, I would hit the right aligned side and I would
go ahead and scoot it over.
And that's going to look a lot better and a lot cleaner.
But personally, kind of like the same way we read a book from left to right.
I personally think that this kind of information does the best on the bottom left part of the screen.
And you want to leave some padding.
You don't want to put this kind of information like that back in the day when things used to go on television.
Imagine that.
You know, if you were an editor, it would pretty much be only going most of the time.
You'd be editing stuff for television or for movie.
And those had different kind of display ratios.
So there was this thing called a title Safe Margin.
And you would never want to place your text or any part of the video outside of the borders that this
type of overlay shows you.
So these days, when things go on YouTube and Instagram, we don't really have to worry about the way
it's displayed on different types of displays.
But it is kind of nice if you do put on one kind of these kind of overlays, there's a safe margins,
transparency.
Good.
That's a bit different.
There's even this ruler, one which I don't use, but the safe margins, a good way to have equal spacing
to the left and to the bottom, and just kind of use it as a guide frame of where it might look good
for your text to fit in the best.
And just a good rule of thumb is try to keep equal spacing below the text and to the left of the text.
If I have it kind of like this, it just looks a little bit funky.
But if the spacing is similar below and above, that's when it looks good.
If it's got a lot of space below, but not a lot of space to the left, it looks a little bit strange.
Right.
So this is a good rule of thumb to go for when you're adding this kind of graphic.
And there's no specific hard rule that you really need to follow unless your client is asking you specifically.
But the more you're centered, the more that this is the focus and what's behind it is secondary.
So if this is in the center, you're telling the audience that, hey, this is this, this is like the
center of a target.
You're always aiming for the center.
Right.
So if it's in the center, it's the main focus.
The more you bring it off to the side, the more it's secondary.
They're seeing what's happening in the image and then they get to see the details that you're providing
them.
So it's a fine balance.
You don't want to have it too far out towards the center.
You don't want to have it too far down.
So it looks like it's about to fall out of the image.
There's a middle ground so you can find that middle ground.
Some of it is just personal preference and then find that middle ground and just find something that
feels right and looks aesthetically pleasing.