Where is your star?
Do you see?
Take a deep breath in.
Bringing in all the juicy Murphy yumminess and stickiness that life offers.
And experience here sounds revitalized.
Now, purposefully intent.
OK, I love this sequence here.
This is such a fun was such a fun sequence to shoot, and it was a really fun sequence to edit together.
So we have a lot of different pacing changes here.
We really follow the flow of her voice.
So pay attention to the intonation and the energy and the kind of speed and rhythm of her vocals, and
then watch the speed and rhythm of the visuals as well.
So we have one long shot here for quick shots, one shot, another shot, one medium shot, and then
we go to even longer shots back here.
So let's watch those two items.
So pay attention to what's going on here.
Take a deep breath in.
Bringing in all the juicy, messy yumminess and stickiness that life offers.
And experience yourselves revitalized.
Now purposefully, intentionally carried out.
You OK, perfect.
So we are really riding the beat of her vocals.
Now, what I mentioned about having a different type of overlay.
I did something here to really spice up these shots.
There is not as many sparks as you would imagine in the actual content, in the actual footage.
So I have these.
What we did is I had my cinematographer the day of the shoot film, a bunch of footage with just the
black sky in the background and sparks and embers coming up from the actual fire that we had on set.
But without the talent, without the character, without anything like that, he just filmed just the
sparks.
Now, I used those raw video files that we have overlaid right here.
This is the overlays of the sparks.
This is the footage below.
I use these as a basically almost like a film burn, but more of an overlay.
So I use the same process of setting it to screen.
And if we take these out, boom, you're going to see the sparks disappear that weren't actually there.
So we have all these sparks take away.
It's just that.
So if I let that play for us.
So again, the computer is kind of lagging because these Forres files are so dense.
But I can't fully play this through.
But we have it without the sparks, with the sparks, without, with.
And as we go through, these sparks end up making a huge difference.
See, we have all this coming through, this part of the frame.
These guys, these vertical ones, if I were to remove that, then we don't have this whole area is
kind of empty.
And even in this sequence where I kind of overlay, you can see these sparks starting to come in here.
So if you go frame by frame, it looks kind of like something's odd.
But what I did was blend in this layer of sparks onto the image a little bit before just to spice things
up a little bit, because what she's saying and the vibe of that part of the track really needed something
in the yumminess and sticky that life offers.
And there's also, as you can see, a slight time remapping right here.
You can see we speed up the footage was zoom just a little bit, stickiness, that light boom and experience
your sounds revitalized.
So, yeah, all this stuff in the foreground, all these really cool blurred out sparks.
Yeah, those are all added later on in the edit.
Now, there are a lot of other situations where you can do these kind of unique overlays.
You can film your own film, burns in your own overlays just like this.
Anything that has a dark background that you can film with a light foreground of what you want to retain
in that type of custom overlay that you're filming just like this.
I knew ahead of time I wanted this to look like a crazy bonfire scene.
That was something I knew going into the filming process that would be awesome to use in the editing
process.
So hopefully that gives you some cool insights and tips for getting the gears turning on some unique
stuff.
You can do with future edits.