OK, so I'm going to take my first choice track.
I'm going to copy it and I'm going to go ahead and paste it into our sequence.
Now, before we start editing, we want to first make sure that this potential track is going to be,
you know, the ideal track to use.
So with nothing edited, we're just going to hit play and we're going to sit back and see how the edit
is flowing and feels.
OK, not bad.
I'm actually really liking that, so I say it's a go.
I think that this is a good track to use for the edit.
Now, sometimes, you know, you let's say let's take one of our second options and let's go ahead and
paste it in over the one that we're going to use.
And you think, OK, this track is going to be great and you hit play.
And the potential track that might have been it just doesn't match, so sometimes the first track you
try and paste in, boom, it's perfect.
You're good to go.
Sometimes you have to try a few different tracks.
In this case, we got lucky.
The pacing, the energy is perfect for this track, and it matches the vibe of a lot of these shots,
which are a lot of them are slow motion shots.
So next, I you know, when we were listening that first time, I definitely heard that this intro is
really slow and very kind of like, how do I say this?
Yeah, it's like turning on an old television or an old vinyl record.
So these quick shots that we originally wanted to put at the beginning, this is not going to work.
So what we want to do is to lock our soundtrack because we don't want the soundtrack to move, what
we want to do is move the other stuff around our soundtrack.
So because we want to kind of build this out chronologically, it'll be easiest from beginning, middle
to end.
Let's scrub through our demo reel and find those more potential elegant, slower types of shots.
I'm thinking that some of this underwater footage would be perfect for that.
So let me grab.
The more slow ones I know I have the underwater footage, that's more high energy.
So we'll leave that.
But let's grab.
Yeah.
The slower ones.
So I'm going to grab them.
Ominous.
Scooch everything over.
And boom, I'm going to paste them in.
And let's see how this is looking.
OK, that's feeling way better.
OK, cool.
So we just need to kind of increase the pacing here a little bit.
And what I'm going to do is just quickly cut to the beat.
So as we play through, I'm going to make quick cuts as I feel where the next cut should be.
While listening to the track.
OK, so let's see what we did.
OK.
And now I doesn't want to have something special for this moment.
And let's see if we scooch everything over, how these will cut together.
OK, this shot's OK, it's it's kind of boring compared to all this great other stuff.
This one's a lot more high energy, so we don't need this eyeshot so much.
Let's go ahead and delete that one.
OK, and let's try and a lot of this is trial and error, so I'm just going to try to reorganise things,
change the orientation in the pacing a little bit until I get something that feels good for now with
this cool, big moment.
Oh, OK, now we're talking.
Oh, perfect, OK.
It's just the timing is a little bit off.
OK.
That is really cool.
So all this is actually synching up pretty nicely.