So you can continue to be cutting your secrets together.
And choosing the best shots that line up with the best moments.
And I want to kind of go even more into detail on shot choice, shot length and shot ordering.
So when we have multiple takes in multiple angles like we've been working with.
You want to always ask yourself which shot best conveys the purpose of this specific scene.
In other words, which shot has the best performance or wording from the subject?
Or, like in our previous edits, tells the best story through camera movement and through framing.
You want to keep in mind what is supposed to be seen, what is important, and even what is supposed
to be hidden.
Just like in our opening sequence, we didn't want any questions to be there for the viewer and just
show a close up with the violin.
We purposefully showed a wide shot so that the viewer was comfortable knowing where the subject was
so that there wasn't any ambiguity for the viewer, wondering where the violin was hanging in space
randomly on a close up.
And they could instantly dive into and immerse themselves in the really cool backdrop we had for this
specific video.
So if it's important, make sure it's seen.
And on the other hand, if you want the viewer to have questions or curiosity, you can actually hide
things by not showing wide shots until there's a purposeful way of showing it.
Later in the edit, also with going through and choosing these different shots, you're looking for
that feeling that you get when you see the shot lined up with your audio.
That's that.
Yes, this is a type of feeling you'll know when you land on that shot.
So really pay attention to what your body and experience is in the moment while you're creating your
edits.
And there's a few important insights I want to share about deciding your shot ordering.
Generally, you want to start off with your mastership the way we did in this edit and work your way
in.
This puts the setting into perspective.
Then we move closer to our subject.
But like I mentioned, we can purposefully create wonder or mystery or curiosity by starting on the
close up and working our way to the wide shot versus the normal way, which is to start with the wide
shot and work our way into close ups.
The reason this is important is because it's all about ordering things in a way that makes your story
flow most naturally, which is all depended on your type of footage.
And we're going to get more into this in the montage section.
But I just wanted to kind of bring it up now while we're going through this edit.
The next principle I want to talk about is choosing your shot length.
The longer we hold a shot, the more information we give to the viewer.
So if I was just a flash, an image to you very quickly, you want to be able to really pick up a whole
lot on what's going on.
But if I showed you that same image for, let's say, 10 seconds, there's a lot more information you'll
be able to pick up.
So if there isn't a whole lot to be absorbed in your shot, you'll need to hold it for that long.
You'll know by feeling into it.
And if more information needs to be given or if the shot is ready to change.
So if it's a complex moment, there's going to be extra time needed.
And so, like I mentioned, if I had a long paragraph of information, I want to just flash it to you
in one second.
You would want to let the audience.
This is a metaphor, by the way.
I don't literally mean a paragraph of information.
I mean a metaphor for that of how much information is in your actual shot.
But you would let it be read for a longer period of time by your audience before moving on.
That's why it's so important to watch your own footage as if you've never seen it before.
You're listening to what's going on audibly.
You're feeling what's going on visually, and you're trying to have a neutral first time experience
when you're watching back the edit, because your viewer is only going to be seeing it probably once.
And when that happens, it's going to be their first time seeing it.
When you're editing, you've seen a shot 10, 20, maybe 100 times.
So you kind of have to consciously erase that memory of what you're used to because the viewer is never
going to have that same memory.
So here's a perfect example of explaining shot length.
I was playing football at first, but once I first started playing basketball Jacomo game, you know,
being in the best in world when you use the best players.
But that's up the line of long, so it's definitely expansion of official for.
So what we have here is the summarizing thoughts by our main character in this previous project.
He's really going deep in saying how appreciative and how much he loves playing in the NBA.
And we give a little extra beat, a little extra moment for the viewer to absorb his statement and his
thoughtfulness behind what he said.
This is a lot of information and subtlety to take in as the viewer.
If we see the second example, we don't have quite as much breathing room and space for the magnitude
of what's being said and shown to really absorb.
Let's see what that looks like.
Send us up to date on the law.
And so if there is one huge national treasure for.
So, as you can see, it doesn't nearly have as much impact because we didn't create that space.
There's nothing really analytical or logical about the decision of holding the shot longer.
It's purely an emotional and storytelling decision to extend that moment and leave that moment with
some time to breathe so that each moment on screen is purposefully there and being seen.
I think that rhymed.
I like that.