So now that we have the area where we know we want this title to go, next up would be to do the similar
process that we did with this first graphic.
And let's go ahead and see which font we use.
OK, I never know how to pronounce this one.
Mont Serat.
No.
Yes.
OK.
I called it monster at for the first few years.
I was using it Monsoor.
OK, I still don't even know how to say it.
But Emmo and I know it starts with emulating a T..
Let's see it and and let's go ahead and do a similar thing that we did before we can make this light
and add a little bit of a stroke so that it's not too wiry.
It's got a little bit more weight to it and we can shrink this down a little bit.
Yep.
And because there's a lot going on in the background, it's really helpful for these kind of title cards
to add what's called a drop shadow.
Now, I know we've talked about this already, so I'm not going to go into a lot of detail, but you're
basically creating a shadow behind the font.
So that is going to help it stand out a lot more if I were to move it away.
You can see what that job shadow is looking like.
If I were to turn up the thickness of the drop shadow, you can start to see.
And there's really a fine line.
Like I personally don't like seeing a drop shadow.
I like to really have it there subtly in the background.
So you don't notice it, but it just barely helps to keep the text separated from the backdrop so that
you can clearly read the words that are on screen.
Because if you can't if it's not legible, then there's no point of it even being there.
It'll be more of a distraction than anything else.
So we have a little bit of a drop shadow, and I'm going to go ahead and do something similar with adding
a line just like what we did with our previous edit.
Now, there's just something about having a line.
I don't know what it is, but with text and when you add basically some type of line, it kind of helps
to frame up the text and helps it to sit in your image a little bit better.
It feels a little bit more that it's placed properly so we can kind of experiment here and we can like
try the line at the bottom.
That's not that great.
We can try to at the top.
That's OK.
It's not looking too good.
We can even try rotating it 90 degrees and putting it up.
And put it up, cheese cut and put it kind of vertically, which I definitely like doing some time,
so let's get it the proper length.
Let's move it over.
And I like that.
So this is without kind of you know, it's there, it's OK.
But as soon as we add that, it just adds a little bit more purpose and a little bit more structure
for what we're seeing.
So let's go ahead and see what we have.
I want to put this to zero so that the line expands.
Yep.
Perfect.
OK.
And we can see that expansion up just a little bit.
Now, let's add a fade in, just like what we did before.
In a FETO, we can make that fade even longer.
OK.
And you know what?
Because we have this cool vertical line now that's happening.
And we want to add a little bit more of an animation.
You know, just like what we did with this first one, just to kind of create a little bit more of a
professional feel.
We can totally do that Mersch motion blur thing again.
You know, that's definitely a go to that I use a lot is adding that motion blur.
It always looks elegant and it always looks clean.
But for this one specifically, I want to, you know, try something different so we can go in to our
effect's tab and type in white.
And this is going to be a transition, kind of an intro transition effect.
So what it's going to do is it's going to have the clip just like that scroll sideways.
So you see how it's coming in from left to right versus before, where it's just fading in all at once.
So in this way, it kind of goes out of this vertical line that we added.
So there we go.
That's looking pretty good.
Now, if we wanted to have a little bit more control, I don't like how this isn't feathered.
It's just a solid line.
You can see there's no feathering.
It's just like one really harsh line that goes across.
Now, if you want to take it a step further, have a little bit more control instead of using a preset
wipe transition.
We can go in and type in Krog.
And this is going to allow for us to have a little bit more control over this transition.
So if I go to the middle of the clip, we have left top, right bottom.
Now, if I scale up the left one, you can see, OK, we're scrolling from the left.
And if I scale up the right one, you can see that we can do this wave, but manually.
And the thing is about doing it manually is in we can add this edge feathering.
So now that is looking a lot better.
We have more of a gradual effect that this transition is going to have versus the kind of harsh, hard
line.
So let's go to the beginning of the edit or the beginning of the title.
Third.
Turn our stopwatch on with the effect fully engaged.
And let's go to where we want the text to be seen fully right there.
And let's see what we got.
OK.
That's looking a lot better.
So it really just kind of gradually comes out and gradually displays.
And now we can do that same exact thing to the outro.
So where are opacity starts to go down and we have the natural fade out?
Let's do another keyframe.
Go to the end and put our crop all the way back up to 100 so that it comes back in gradually.
So.
And then it'll go.
There we go.
And we can even add, you know, how the line expands and comes in.
Now we can add the line going back.
So let's go to our heighth of our line, just like what we did earlier with the uniform scale kind of
hack that I've discovered.
Go back and hit a key frame.
Go to where we want it to disappear fully and put this at zero.
Now put this at zero.
So let's see what that looks like.
OK, so that looks really clean, right?
We're getting the information, it's legible, it looks professional.
And there's even an intro and outro animation so that it doesn't look just like so that it doesn't look
just like a really simple, plain looking title card.