What I'm going to do is because I want this to get sooner to this, OK, so if I can lock this track.
I wanted to transition on this sound boom right there, so I'm going to hit a marker so we have a marker
right there, and I want the transition to be here, which is this marker.
So we're going to bring up our time remapping tool and we're going to do a little ninja work here.
I'm going to speed.
Actually, I want to create two key frames.
Boom, boom.
I'm going to speed up this center area.
Just like that.
And kind of smooth this out.
Oh, who?
OK, it's a little bit late.
Not bad.
OK, so you see how we have slow pacing at the intro.
Any song that you choose is going to have an intro, an exciting part, a mellow part.
Well, OK, any any song that you choose is going to have an intro, a build, exciting part, a mellow
part, another build, and then another exciting part, then an outro.
So what we're doing here is we're following that kind of template of our intro here.
And as the excitement builds, we go into the higher paced shots with more movement.
OK, so this one's a little bit late, Ionescu, this over.
Shh, shh.
OK, we're going to do the same thing here now because we're working with content that's already been
exported.
If we had the raw video files we were working with, which you can do it that way, you can drag in
the files directly from, you know, the other project.
But it's more time consuming.
We don't really do we really need to be that specific and that precise for this edit.
So that's why I'm using the time remapping tool so that we can speed up where the cuts are, where we
need.
Now, I don't want to have too many of these style shots from one video back to back in the demo.
Really, you kind of want to have multiple shots sprinkled in with each other, you know, because you're
showing a variance of your different skills.
Right.
So let's move on to a different set of footage.
I'm going to pull over the rest of our shots.
And we're only 20 seconds in and we're starting to look pretty good.
So let's just take a second to look back at what we've done so far.
OK, cool.
So there is a few little things in there I would change, I'm going to move that over.
OK.
And there's a noise here.
It's like the doom, doom, doom.
And I want to have something cool for that.
So I'm going to just scroll through and see.
What would match up with that noise?
Boom, boom, boom.
Let's see if this if we can get this to match up.
I don't know if that's going to work, but let's give it a try.
And let's bring it over.
And let's face it in.
OK, so actually, yeah, let's grab this shot and put it in front.
I'm going to hold all I actually command and drag it in.
OK.
Let's see.
And let's move this over as well.
So all I did there was held command and pushed these back.
So.
Let's move this over slightly.
And.
OK, so I think we're going to get something here.
Let's watch your back.
OK, that's pretty cool.
Now I'm cool with that.
We're about 30 seconds into the edit in the next edit, we're going to continue to refine our first
rough edit.