So we're going to continue to go through this, edit and uncover some more secrets and techniques.
Now, I wanted to mention that, you know, we're doing a lot of lessons, video lessons here on like
overlays and film burns and that kind of stuff is because you'll find each edit is going to have a lot
of its own specific look in some of the projects we edited together previously.
Some of the edits were had a lot of glitching in some of the edits, had a lot of audio swoosh, kind
of sound design, some of the edits, had a lot of motion graphics and text to some of the edits, had
a lot of other specific elements that are kind of repeated throughout the video.
So you want to find what it is at.
That specific project needs to upgrade it to the higher level of production quality.
And then you're going to hone in on that and then you're going to kind of repeat it throughout the video,
but in a way that doesn't feel boring.
I don't overdo the sparks overlay.
I do it just enough in the scenes that need it where you almost don't notice it.
But it looks really inspiring.
We have the different kind of crystal overlay things and crystal overlays at the right moments.
And then we have the more Filburn style at the right moments as well.
So keep that in mind.
You know, you're going to find a specific look for a specific project, hone in on that look and then
put it throughout the video.
Now, let's go ahead and continue to go through and see what we can find across the room, watching
it hit the ball across and all the way around the world, all the way back into your next deep breath
and see the world record with your contribution.
OK, so there was a few things there.
We had this subtle time remapping right here.
Boom, boom, boom.
So let me hear it play.
Let me let it play.
You can see the time.
Remapping starts right there, ends right there across the room, shouting at it, which just gives
it a little extra something.
If I were to take away this and let it cut into the other video or the other clip room.
Watching it.
It didn't work.
There was just something wrong.
I want I thought it would work initially because it's like there's these that almost look like embers
out of focus.
You know, there's actually a lot of similarity in these two shots as far as the bouka and doing.
But it didn't it didn't work.
Watching it, I don't know.
There was something about it that wasn't working.
So I added this little time remap that sped things up on this clip right before we cut the moon.
And for some reason, that worked perfectly in this situation.
Hit the wall across and all the way around the world, all the way back.
Now we have a theme that's happening between these shots.
We have our hand going into frame, going sideways, actually.
We have our hand going sideways and down.
We have our hand going out.
And then, boom, we have this matko of her hand at a different location.
So let's watch that back across the room.
Watching it hit the wall across and all the way around the world, all the way back into your next deep
breath and see the world record with your contribution as your north perfec.
So a cool little unique 10 second sequence there.
We we used a similar move made between our shots with a similar repeating in this case body part her
and to create a pretty unique sequence.
So we also have some filmar an action going on.
So this one was used right here, see the world to link these two together in a way they just felt better
if I were to take that away and let this play see the world of this year.
It's cool.
It's fine.
It just doesn't have that final payoff, you know, is a big exposure difference between these two images
and a big color difference.
But a similar movement with our character.
But perfect situation to link these boom with our Filmon, with your contribution as your North Star.
Whether it's behind clouds or not.
Dipsy.
I should confess.
What is your why?
Open your eyes, see your star.
OK, perfect.
So we have this camera movement going up to the sky when she says and fly, I'm arriving in this lesson
and I love it, OK, and then we go to a fade.
Actually, across is all of this shot.
Now, of course, for this project, our trusty Filburn is really helping out with getting these two
shots linked together.
If we were to scroll through it without its cool.
You know, that's fine, it's cool.
But this is one of those projects where filmmakers are really the money on this one, so get comfortable
with using film burns because it's going to come in handy.
They're really easy to add.
They're really easy to use.
And the professional look, you can get by dropping the perfect one in at the perfect moment of the
video.
Is the game changer trust?