Let's look at a few more tracks and see if we find anything interesting.
OK, perfect.
I love the style of that track.
So let's go ahead and take the other one that we got from Epidemic or put this into the music folder
that we created at the beginning of this edit inside of our project files.
And now let's bring this music folder into our actual editing project.
And now what we are going to do is double click either one of these tracks.
I'm going to do this little squiggly.
I don't know what the heck this key is called, but it's going to enlarge the top left window.
And we're going to skip forward here.
And I'm going to make an end point right there.
So what I did is I created an endpoint by hitting I write on this drop, OK?
And it's going to create another outpoint there.
And I'm going to drag it down so that before we start refining or before we really start diving deeper
into this edit, I want to first put our two possible soundtrack's below our footage to see which one
matches up the best.
So let's do the same thing for the second track here.
If I'm going to put an endpoint right there and I just put a marker by hitting M on the drop, that's
another way to kind of mark things can go here in an outpoint.
Hit the squiggly to get rid of the big screen, drag over the sound icon to drag the clip into our timeline.
And now what we can do is we have both of our tracks really rough, not synched up yet to our footage,
but we can mute one of our tracks so that we can now play our rough edit and see what it looks like.
OK, cool.
Sounds good, that's a cool song.
I think it sounds pretty good with the footage, if not super in love with it.
Of course, we're going to sync everything up to the striking points in the beat of the track.
But let's now listen to our other option.
OK.
I can already tell I got the feeling in the body, so that's something that you want to be looking out
for when you're going through your content, is what is that thing that's creating a resonance in you
as you're absorbing the information from your edit?
So the audio and the video is speaking to you.
And as soon as there's that resinate match between the two things, you're going to feel it in the body.
There's going to be some excitement in this scenario.
There's excitement because that's the type of music and footage in more of a maybe heartfelt video that
you might be working on in the future or something that's a little bit more on the creative side or
artistic side.
Whatever the emotion that you're trying to draw from your audience, you're going to feel that sink
in.
So it's not just happening here.
You really want to feel your edits in the body as a response of something that is lighting something
up inside of you.
So we definitely want to move forward with this second option here.
The next step would be to go ahead and get rid of this extra track that we don't need.
And now we're going to lock down our musical track to keep it in place.
That way we can cut and move around all of our video footage without accidentally cutting or changing
the musical track, which doesn't need to be changed or edited in any way.
So now we're going to get into some more a little bit more slightly complex video editing techniques
where we're going to be doing time remapping, we're going to be speeding up clips, and we're going
to be doing faster cutting style and using different shot choices.
And then once we do that, we're going to stylize our footage, stabilize the shots that need to be
stabilize and get a really cool looking edit.
So you should now have your footage selected and organized.
You should have your music picked out and cued up, and you should be ready to start synching up the
cuts and the pacing of your footage to your track.