OK.
And this brings us to editing pace now a good way to kind of think of this is if we look at a timeline
here that we've been working to create for this first edit, each one of these blocks of footage is
creating a beat every single time we have a cut.
It kind of actually looks like musical notes when you see it like this.
And the reason that's interesting is because each one of these cuts is creating a beat.
Each time there's a change right there, boom.
That's a B.
Whom there's another be so visually, we're creating almost a visual song, and the visuals are cued
up to how I explain this.
Oh, darn.
OK, so the editing piece that we're deciding to create by the frequency or tempo of cutting.
Right.
This is a low amount of frequency of cuts.
This would be a high frequency of cuts, a high tempo of cutting.
When we're doing that, we're dialing up and dialing down the overall energy of our edit.
The higher the frequency and tempo, the higher the energy, the lower and lower energy doesn't necessarily
mean a bad thing.
It's all about the overall experience of your viewer that they're having from the vibe of your edit.
And if we go ahead and hit play here, if this is a slow intro.
With a low number of cutting.
And it feels good to watch because the frequency and tempo of cutting is matching the tempo of the actual
song.
If it if so, if we were to take our backup sequence here with all of our shots and we're just going
to call this high tempo and it's going to be a little bit of an experiment.
Now, even though we have all these amazing shots to work with and you have a great shot for that moment,
it doesn't necessarily mean that you need to have shot, shot, shot, shot, shot.
If the emotion and tone of that part of your scene needs that, perfect.
But I want to show you an example of even though the shots are good, we don't need to use all of them.
We need to show the one that gives the right amount of information and creates the right response.
So it's kind of randomly make some cuts here with a really high tempo of shot choices.
And let's see what happens.
OK, we're going to use the same track.
We have the same footage, but we're just going to change what the viewer is seeing and.
And so that was a much more rapid pacing and tempo of cutting, there was still doing a good job of
showing all the great shots we were using.
So nothing bad about it.
It's just different.
Now, let's take a look at the edit we made together and see how the rhythm and editing pace compares
in and.
And.
In a.
So as you can see, same shots, but the frequency of cutting the tempo has increased.
So I'm saying this because there's no right or wrong.
It's all a creative decision.
But I want you to be aware of your options for all your projects moving forward so that you can really
consciously choose what to do and have all the tools in your arsenal as possible to make the best edits.