So now what I want to focus on is using multiple angles in an interview kind of scenario just like this,
and how cutting multiple times while someone is speaking is going to bring up and excite what they're
saying.
We did this with our montages where the faster pace of cutting that we did, the more interesting and
exciting the footage felt.
So let's hop over to the screen cap and check out this portion.
My college students would come up to me on the first day of class and they would say, you know, I'm
really worried about this class.
I'm a science person.
And that person is not a literature person.
And I would say, OK, you're saying first, so you love questions, you love identifying evidence to
support an argument.
It's not to give everything you need.
Great.
So at this part, we have no bureau that we're working with because she's saying and I labeled this
all this kind of purple magenta color.
She's kind of seeing a definitive final statement before we transition from our music track here.
We have a smooth transition, which, you know, as by now, you know, that's our favorite.
And then we go to this new track and OK, but let's not worry about that.
I want to focus on the visuals here.
So we have the purple is her speaking footage.
So if a double click this, we have this layer.
And if I double click this, we have this side layer.
So we had one main camera facing right in front of her.
And then our B camera off to one side.
So you can see we're here how she's speaking.
We cut to this one and she's speaking.
We cut to here.
We cut back and then we zoom in slightly, zoom in again and zoom in one more time.
Now, now that you know what's going on, let's watch it one more time and then we're going to break
it down.
My college students would come up to me on the first day of class and they would say, you know, I'm
really worried about this class.
I'm a science person, math person.
I'm not a literature person.
And I would say, OK, you're science person, so you love questions, you love identifying evidence
to support an argument.
Sounds like you've everything you need.
OK, so we're using the cutting between these angles to create kind of a suspense and to kind of zoom
in chronologically or one after the other to create a moment that is matched up with the words that
she's saying.
So if we were to take out this side layer and let's say put back this layer here, take out this one
and only use one camera angle, my college students would come up to me on the first day of class and
they would say, you know, I'm really worried about this class and the science person and that person.
I'm not a literature person.
And I would say, OK, you're a science person.
So, you know, it seems like it takes a long time just for us to get to this part of the edit.
So when we put these two angles back in these side angles, college students would come up to me on
the first day of class and they'd say, you know, I'm really worried about this class.
I'm a science person.
And that person is not a literature person.
And I would say, OK, if it helps us to further keep listening to what she's saying, when we're looking
at one static shot, it's like, OK.
Uh huh.
Every time we cut anything in our edit and we change angles, we're creating a new brand new start of
thinking for our viewer.
So we're doing that here.
Consciously.
With the words she's saying, and then we let this front angle stay.
Once she really goes into the important part that we really want the viewer to listen to, and the way
that we intensify that moment is by holding this same exact angle and we take out our music later.
So I have the music layer with multiple tracks in the bass.
We have the beat and then we have kind of these additional sounds.
OK.
So as we're listening, you're going to hear the base is going to drop and then the beat is going to
go away as well.
Let's say, OK, your science person, so you love questions.
You love identifying evidence to support an argument.
So like give everything you need.
So she's listing off something.
OK, you love questions, OK?
You love identifying, yada, yada, yada.
That's why we're cutting to these close ups now.
So we go wide shot, close up closer and then boom.
Now, what we could have done is maybe brought back this side angle.
And let's see what that looks like to person.
And I would say, OK, your science person, so you love questions.
You love identifying evidence to support an argument.
Want to give everything you need.
It's not bad.
It doesn't look bad, but when we're holding this same shot that we have but pushing in, we're creating
a huh?
OK, boom.
OK, and then that creates the moment where we can transition into our next track.
So that's a creative way to use scaling up your image in a proper moment consciously to create that
kind of effect and having some fun playing between different camera angles to find out that, OK, the
beacom works for the beginning.
The ACAM is perfect right here.
The beacom is great again here.
And then when she changes what she's saying, she's going to do something definitive.
Let's hold this shot for longer.
Let's drop out the music.
Let's push in on each important point that she makes and then push in all the way on the very last moment
to create the most dramatic moment in that part before we use our all time favorite swooshed transition
into our next track.
Everything you need.
Literary analysis now that should give you some cool insights on some subtleties and hopefully some
ideas for you to further maximize the different camera angles that you're working with in your future
edits.