Now, what I want to kind of share here is how to go ahead and read your waveforms so we can tell just
by looking at the waveform that this is not going to be used.
None of this stuff is going to be used.
Here you can see talking, talking, talking, talking, OK.
No talking.
Right.
So what we want to do in this first initial step is to go ahead and delete what we're not going to use.
So what is up, guys?
I wanted to actually add this lecture or series of lectures.
OK.
And we can go to the end of this tape.
So let's get into it and we can delete what we don't need.
And now we go to the next cut.
So, first of all, I want to kind of show you and we can go ahead and remove this excess shot.
Right.
And you can see it's really clean and mundane.
There's not a lot of going on in the background.
It's really just a very clean shot and I'm doing that.
And in this first process here, I'm just removing these extra amount of space that we don't need shot.
And we're not worrying about what's going to make it in the final edit right here.
We're not worrying about what our viewers are going to see in the final video.
We just want to start trimming out what's not needed so that we can start to see our edit take shape,
start to take shape.
OK, now it looks like I did it take here.
And the footage is actually blurry now until I figure out if I redid this take.
I'm assuming that I definitely did.
But until I figure that out, I'm going to wait and leave it in just in case.
That's the only usable take that I have.
And what we're going to be effectively doing here is building our SELEX sequence that's going to start
to look like this versus the original raw sequence, which looks like this with a lot of extra space
and a lot of mistakes and areas that just aren't going to make it in the final edit.
So I'm going to continue to read my waveforms, which is going to save a lot of time in the long run,
because you can go ahead and scrub through the video hit play to see if that's a good part, scrub through,
hit play, scrub through, hit play.
Or you can look at your waveform.
You know, nothing's there, nothing's there.
Nothing's there.
So I can really ninja my way, scrub right to where it ends up to right where it begins, scrubbing
right to where it ends.
Do the same thing.
Scrub here, scrub to here, and continuously let the audio of my clips dictate where my initial cuts
are going to be for the selection process.
So now I'm going to go ahead and finish pulling the Selex on this initial intro footage, and we'll
see what we get next.