Moving forward here, we're now at the 54 second mark of our edit.
We've already broke down a lot.
We haven't even made it a minute into this edit yet.
So we have at this portion, we have more of that really clean, simple version of a motion graphic
or not even emotion.
This is just text with a simple fade and it looks clean.
Now, what I did add is this background layer.
I felt that it looked a little bit too bland without something in the background, because all of these
shots are really colored nicely.
A lot of character.
There's a lot of like brick and, you know, color in the background that we have.
But when it just cut to this black screen here at the one minute mark, it didn't really work.
Earlier in the edit, when we showed our overall video title card, it worked here.
But at this portion of the video, I just felt that it needed a little something.
So what I do have is this clip that we shot.
And I brought down the opacity to 19 percent.
So originally it was like this, which is clearly too much.
You can't see what's going on.
It's too distracting.
But when I brought it down to 90 percent.
It's a perfect balance.
You get a feel for what's going on in the background, your subconscious brain picks up, there's a
book page churning, OK, that's nice.
It's pretty, but it's not distracting you too much from the text that's on screen.
That's actually more important to read.
Just like with the audio that we were talking about, you always have primary audio, audio and secondary
audio when they're speaking in your video.
Talking is primary and music is secondary.
So speaking should be the loudest and most clear.
Audio should be a little bit quieter and a little bit less frontal.
More background.
This is a similar kind of scenario, but we're taking that same principle and applying it for our visuals.
So we have the primary focus of this two second clip is for the viewer to read or at least absorb some
of these lines, because it's explaining the contents of the course that this video is a trailer for.
So we have the primary stuff and then we have the background secondary items item, actually, which
is this background image.
And rather than turning down the sound like on a music track and vocals, we turn down the opacity.
So something to really think about.
It's kind of a cool way of looking at that.
Now, as we move forward, we have now we have a cool looking motion graphic.
So we have our background layer of normal footage, and then we have this motion graphic on top.
So let's take a look at what that looks like.
Literary analysis is analysis.
It's about, OK, so we got a few things going on here, we have this motion graphic that pops in.
There's actually two motion graphics.
That's why it's in a nested sequence.
So if I were to double click this, we have our top sequence and then we have our bottom sequence.
That's this like definition of literally literary analysis.
The top sequence is, you know, the words literary analysis.
And then we actually have a third aspect to this kind of custom moment here.
We have this red line that comes into the frame.
So this was simply this kind of emoji file.
And what I did to take it, from what it looks like over here to what it looks like in the final edit
is I'm going to select it.
I'm going to go up to our effects controls.
And you can see I change the uniform scale.
I put the width of this item all the way down to 15 and put that heighth of this item up to 245.
So if I were to undo the uniform scale and it would keep the scale of the width and height the exact
same.
This is what it would look like.
It's not ideal.
Originally, the line was too wide, but I really wanted to use it because it had the right amount of
movement and it was perfect for the edit.
So that was the very first thing I did was I changed.
That was the original right there.
Actually, when we change this, this is the original.
So I change the motion by using uniform scale that change the kind of aspect and made it more of a squished
longer line.
And then I also added a mask layer to this.
I felt like it was a little bit too wide like this.
So just slightly I added this mask that basically just cuts off wherever I want it to.
We talked about that earlier in the chorus, but I just added a little bit just because, like I mentioned,
this was just a little bit too wide for my taste.
The next thing I did was I went to my effects and then I added what's called a ramp.
Now, this really just allowed for me to change the color of this overlay from white to literally any
color that I want to.
So it's a totally different vibe.
So, you know, you can go in and with something like a ramp, you can really move where the color is
affecting your overlay pretty easily by just switching a few parameters around.
But let's go ahead and undo that.
The reason I chose the white and red, because I felt that that matched the vibe of this edit the most,
is kind of a cool teacher on a white board or on a chalkboard kind of feeling.
So we have the red line, we have the main letters, and then we have the definition of the letters
as well.