So let's go to Fusion.
Think.
Thank God.
So we have the biggest striking point of the entire video.
This big booming chorus of our track.
Now, we built up to that by doing some time remapping, speeding up these cool, sparkly shots, which,
you know, technically this shot could be considered kind of unusable.
It's out of focus.
It's really messy, you know, and it's really not all that useful on its own.
But if we listen to the track and we see how that visual lines up with the track, it actually did a
pretty good job.
So we use that kind of, you know, fast camera movement to throw the viewer into this time remapped,
underwater shot.
So if I were to just kind of drag over this shot that's in focus and fine and no issues and very usable.
Let's see what that would have look like.
Right.
There's no camera movement, there's no like fast pace in this to it, so it doesn't really do anything
for the viewer to.
So these moments are key.
You don't want to throw away shots that, you know, would be quote unquote unusable in your edit because
you can do ninja type things of man.
I just remembered we're not doing perative slightly, OK?
This is a pirated throw it up.
Yes.
You don't want to throw away shots that initially you would think are unusable, because a lot of the
times, like I just said, you can do ninja things and ninja ways to speed up the shot, have it as
a really quick, quick cut away or use it with an added overlay like we're doing right here, which
is going to make it seem like it's the right shot at the right place.
Now, our trusty overlays are doing a really good job here of making the most exciting part of the video
feel exciting.
So if I take these away, let it play itself.
Looks good.
But with the overlays, here we go to.
And looks good, so as you can see, relinking our movement together to create a seamless flow between
all these shots.
So movement, VOON, movement VOON, movement foom.
And then we go into her singing.
So what I did here was I blended her singing Selex that we looked at we that we looked at at the very
beginning of this process.
Where is it?
Yet we have this.
So I blended this sequence together with.
The awesome underwater footage that we have.
And the fire footage.