This is a slow motion shot.
I don't feel like that's going to fit in the edit that we're doing here.
That's something to keep in mind when you're doing your edit.
Is it a bunch of normal real time footage that's not slow motion?
And then all of a sudden we have this, you know, footage is shot at 240 frames a second when the rest
of our footage is thought, it shot at 30 frames a second.
If you do something once randomly in an edit, then it's just random out of the blue if you do something
twice.
Then there is like a theme going on that makes it very likely to happen a third time.
So that's something to think about, is that things generally do better in pairs or triplets.
If you're going to do some type of stylistic choice or slow motion footage, don't have one slow motion
clip in your footage.
It'll be like a random blip, OK, if you're going to do that.
Have two, three slow motion shots or the whole thing is slow motion.
So this is a really cool shot, but the audio is not going to be usable.
So that's something that we're going to get into here in a minute.
And we kind of have our last shot here, which is all these little yogis here meditating in front of
the waterfall, which is kind of cool.
So if I scrub through here, there's really no change in this clip.
So even though this clip is about 30 seconds, because we're sitting still and there's no information
that's changing in the actual footage, what's being shown on screen.
Doesn't matter too much where we create our in and out point.
But I will kind of look and see if there's anything cool.
The waterfall kind of does a cool splash here of kind of mist.
So I'm going to create the endpoint there, actually.
Yeah, it happens there.
This starts to be some of that mist that comes in.
So let's go ahead and make this blue and let's put this with the waterfalls.
And to recap, what we've done is we've captured all of our footage.
We've organized it on our computer laptop.
We've created a backup to keep everything safe, keep two copies of things.
And we've pulled our Selex, organize everything and labeled our clips in our timeline.
This is the step where now?
We want to create a backup sequence.
All the work we just did.
And there's a reason that we're going to be doing this.
And that reason is when we're going in this edit and we start moving things around and we start, you
know, trimming things down and deleting clips we think we're not going to use.
Sometimes we don't make the right decision, which we think is the right decision at the time.
But then later on, we're like, oh, where's that one shot?
I know who's in there, and it's gone.
So over the years, I've really learned that creating a backup of your Selex is going to save you a
lot of time down the road.
So this is kind of a little extra protip here.
We're going to click our main sequence in our project window, and we're going to hit command C or we
can go and right click it and copy.
And then we're going to paste, which is command V or right click and hit paste.
So now I have this backup sequence of the selects we pulled.
What I'm now going to do is label it what it is, which is main sequence backup.
OK.
And drag it and put it in the sequences folder.
So now I can always come back to this backup if needed.