As I've been going through and pulling Selex on our sequence here for this YouTube video, I got to
a point in the shoot where I do the kind of intro hook statement that starts the whole YouTube video.
And I want to show you in real time how you can go through and really decide on which states to use
and kind of chop up those takes, because on something like a YouTube video or any video where you're
talking to the camera, it's very likely that when you're trying to deliver a line to camera, that
you mess up, try again, mess up, try again.
Sometimes there's a good part from the first take and the second half.
You want to use parts in the second take.
So we're going to dive into that right now and see what we can do.
So here we have the beginning shot, which is a wide shot where I take the pelican case in the center
of the room and I set it down.
OK.
And then I move in and shoot a close up of that same exact movement.
Oh, I know this doesn't look like much now, but in a few days, this is going to be my brand new film
recording space.
So that's one take.
So let's go ahead and label these a specific color so that they stand out from the rest of our sequence.
So I'm going to go with Rose and then let's go and skip forward.
Not going to be using any of this.
I'm reading the waveforms, a.k.a. looking down at my audio here to find out where to bring the player
head next, which is right here before I deliver another option of that same exact take.
So in this video, I'm going to walk you.
So in this video, this is exactly what I'm talking about.
Now we can see I restart my line here.
I restart again here and I restart again here.
Now, what I'm going to do is go to where there's no space so we can get a clean cut right here.
We don't need those first mess ups.
So I'm going to create a cut in play.
So in this video, I'm going to walk you through this step by step steps that I went through to take
this studio space from this to this.
OK, that might not make sense.
Now what I'm saying.
But in the final edit, you understand why I'm saying this line anyways.
What I also heard in that tape was there's a little beginning noise that we don't need.
That's something you always want to keep in mind, especially when you're cutting dialogue together.
The exit.
Mm hmm.
All that stuff.
You can take it out because you just it adds no value to the viewer.
So in this video.
So I find this so in the moment.
So in this right there.
So in this week and sometimes.
Let's see if I even cut one later.
So we missed this problem you run into sometimes we have a noise that the subject makes before the actual
line that we want to cut into now.
So there's a little kiss before the first word that I speak as I'm clearing my throat or whatever I
was doing.
And if I want to do a frame later to cut into, I'm then cutting into.
So when this the first kind of syllable or hit of that first word, the way around that is to bring
down by creating a key frame.
I hit P to bring up the pen tool, and then I create a little bit of a fade in.
So in this, that creates a lot more of a clean beginning of my sentence, because when we speak, most
of the time, we're blending words together in our sentence.
Like when I say this, it goes into that.
It goes into that.
And if I try to create a clean cut, sometimes the end of that word is at the beginning of this word.
And so you'll be able to really clean up those kind of things by creating fade ins and fade outs like
we've done previously, but that we haven't done yet to vocals.
But it's an excellent, excellent tool to create those clean cut.
So we know that these were my two mistakes.
I read the audio waveform to get to the tape that we wanted.
Now we're going to delete this excess and let's scrub through right here.
Well, let's get into it.
OK.
This is the beginning of a second take for the whole sequence.
May it be OK?
You can see I tried to say the line, but I lost my train of thought, didn't know what I was going
to say.
So let's go ahead and skip ahead right to where before the sound is telling us where the take is going
to begin.
And I'm going to delete this mess up.
We're not going to use that.
Man, I know this doesn't look like much.
I know it doesn't sound like much, but in a few days I'm going to show you how I went from taking this
studio space like this.
And made it look like this.
OK, so when I snap in the footage and the actual edit happens, I'm going to show cutaways of the before
studio that to the after studio boom, which we have footage of that we haven't gone through yet.
And if I read this waveform here and if I look at this waveform here, it looks like all of these are
me delivering this ending phrase and made it look like this.
So it looks like we're going to have a lot of options to work with.
I'm going to go ahead and delete these empty spaces.
This is going to allow for us to be able to play back to back these multiple takes in, easily choose
the best one who.
Oh, perfect.
And so what we just did is we pulled the Selex on our very first shot.
We have two different takes to choose from.
Oh, I know this doesn't look like much now, but in a few days, this is going to be my brand new film
recording space.
Man, I know this doesn't look like much.
I know it doesn't sound like much, but in a few days I'm going to show you how I went from taking this
studio space like this and made it look like this.
OK, so I see something that you may run into when you're doing videos similar to this.
There's a line here that I see that it straight up doesn't make sense.
I say in the next few days sound like much, but in a few days, in a few days, I'm going to show you.
And that's not what I was trying to say.
So I have another take that I do say the proper line, and I want to use this as an example to see how
we can splice two different takes together seamlessly so that we get the right information that we're
trying to convey to our viewer.
So in this video, I'm going to walk you.
So I want to start at this.
So in this video, I want to start that clip there and I want to end this video before I say in the
next few days, I.
I know it doesn't sound like much, but in a few days, I'm going to show you how I went from tape.
But so I'm going to try to cut it after I say.
But we'll see how that works.
So I make a cut there and I'm going to drag this in bold command.
OK, budg but so in this video, I'm sound like much, but I know it doesn't sound like much.
So in this video, I'm going to walk you through.
OK, so let's say we were happy with that, right?
That we were happy with the splicing that we made.
If you wanted to get rid of this jumpcut, much so in this video, let's say we were really happy with
the audio.
We didn't have to fine tune it.
I would find to it a little bit more, maybe add a little bit of a fade to this clip much.
So in this video, and we can even drop this on a lower layer and push them together so that we don't
have any empty space and see if that helps the line to flow a little bit more cleanly like much.
So in this video, I much I know it doesn't sound like much.
So in this video.
OK, so that's clean enough audibly for now.
But let's see.
We want to do something like I was saying about this jumpcut an easy way to get around that if you don't
have two angles that you're working with.
See, this would be a perfect time to switch to a different angle for this situation.
I don't have that.
But what we can do is select our clip that we're cutting into.
Go up to the effects tab.
And we can increase the scale of our clip.
Let's say we increase it 20 points now because I increase the scale.
It's cutting off the top of my head.
We don't want that.
So we're going to push it down a little bit and we can center.
Now, we have more of the frame to move around because we scaled it up beyond the borders of our actual
frame size.
And now let's see what that looks like.
Man, I know this doesn't look like much.
I know it doesn't sound like much.
So in this video I'm going to walk you use.
So that cuts together a lot better.
I know that the like the cutting between these words in this sentence isn't the cleanest example, but
it's more about how to splice two different takes together.
And if you don't have multiple cameras to work with, how do you fix something that would be a distracting
jumpcut?
An easy fix for that is to scale up the image like much.
So in this video, without that scale up, if we go and remove what we just did, here's what it looks
like and don't like much.
So in this video, I'm not very good.
And then with our scale down like much.
So in this video, I'm going to weigh cleaner.