All right, so let's start by first speeding up some of the extra space that we have here in our first
shot, because I like this first part where we can see the light changing on the camera.
We can see it pulling out the actual camera.
And then we kind of want to skip forward to get to this transition between this shot and then cutting
to the next shot.
So what I'm going to do here is show you two ways to time, remap your content or your footage for any
of your projects to really kind of.
Yeah, do a cool effect where you speed things up.
So the first option, which is kind of the more basic style, is to choose where you want your cuts
to be.
So I'm going to play and then right here on B, I'm going to create a cut and then I'm going to scrub
forward.
And right as he's opening the whatever that thing is called, I'm going to make another cut.
OK.
So we have one clip is now cut into three clips on this center clip.
The part I want to speed up.
What I'm going to do is right click that center clip.
And I'm going to choose the speed and duration function.
OK?
This is going to allow for me to take the clip that's playing at 100 percent, 100 percent speed, which
is normal speed.
If I do 90, that's 10 percent slower.
If I do 110.
That's 10 percent faster.
OK, we're going to speed this way up because we want this to be a really cool quick motion.
So let's try three thousand percent.
And now we have this empty space that got created.
So what we need to do is select our clips and drag everything over or right click our empty space and
hit REPL delete.
Let's see what that looks like, for example.
OK, perfect.
So what I'm going to do is move the rest of these clips to this first big hit, because we know we want
the edit to start there.
We're following what the music is telling us to do in this situation.
So this space here, we want to fill with this intro shot.
OK.
So what we're going to do is kind of scoot things around a little bit so we know that we want this clip
to end.
OK, that's perfect.
So.
I want to scoot this over, skip this over and add a little bit more of an intro time into this clip
and let's see what that does look for, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
OK, so that actually is flowing pretty dang nicely right out of the gate.
What we're doing is making sure we have some continuity.
We're breaking a lot of continuity here by skipping forward ahead in time, different shot times facing
different ways.
So we're not too worried about continuity, but what we do want to create is cutting on action, which
is a form of continuity.
So the action of him opening, whatever this thing is called, the battery door, we're cutting into
that smooth movement of him doing that same movement motion in the next shot.
OK, so let's see that again.
Florida, far more detail.
OK, looking pretty good.
That is option number one.
Now I want to show you option number two.
So what I'm going to do is duplicate this intro shot and I'm going to go to where we want to cut it.
As if we were starting from scratch with this original shot, and I'm going to highlight that clip,
right click it and go to show clip keyframes, then instead of it showing the opacity, which is what
it's currently doing.
So right now.
This selector is changing the opacity level, zero opacity is how much you can see it, opacity is another
word for transparency or opaqueness.
It's the same thing.
So zero transparency.
It's not.
There are 100 percent.
You know what I'm trying to say here?
OK, well, we're in this situation.
We're not going to be messing with the opacity.
We want it to show the key frames for time, remember, which is really similar to this process of cutting
it into three individual clips.
But we're going to be able to do the time speed changes in a more gradual way, similar to when we made
those audio crossfade of it went smoothly from 100 down to zero.
We're going to now go from 100 speed up to three thousand back down to 100 with Slope's.
So it'll be slightly different.
But if you can imagine a clip being 100 percent going into a cut of a thousand and going to cut up a
hundred, it's boom, boom, boom, boom.
What we're going to create is boom.
Sure, sure.
I love my sound effects.
So let's skip forward here and let's create a keyframe.
I'm going to hit piece for the pen tool.
OK, that just created a key frame for the speed and duration of our clip.
I'm then going to go to where I want this speed change to stop, right as he's opening that camera latch
on to create another key frame.
And now, instead of cutting our clip into three, we have one clip with the speed function changed.
What I'm going to do is take the area of the clip between our two key frames that we just created.
And I'm going to scooted up.
And as you can see, the percentage of speed is increasing from a hundred.
It's at two hundred and four percent.
Three hundred percent.
Up and up and up.
And I'm going to keep going until we hit.
Let's let's see how it looks at two thousand.
And what that just did was it shortened our clip because what was that?
One hundred percent playing for a long time.
Now I was playing at two thousand percent, very short, only on this middle portion of the clip.
So what that looks like
is basically what we had done here.
So no big difference yet.
But the extra step is when we zoom in and we change
our slope of increase between one hundred percent speed to two thousand percent.
So it's going to slowly climb and be more of a gradual change in speed.
So it's not a too quick of a stutter.
So I'm going to gradually increase it and gradually decrease it for.
You can see it's more of a gradual time change.
This is far more detail compared to this far more detail.
You can see there's a little extra cash, so I'll play that again.
The original first way we did it, more choppy.
And then the newer way with more of a smooth transition from Florida is far more so really subtle,
but you can see there's more of a gradual change which can create more smooth looking edits.
So do you want more of a punchy style?
It looks a little bit more fake in some ways, or edited in some ways.
Or do you want more of a smooth style that can look a little bit more organic?
Both are doing the same thing.
We're speeding up our content to get more information in a short amount of time.
But one has maybe a bit of it, more hip, a bit.
But I personally prefer the aesthetic of the second option, which takes a little bit more time.
But I think it's worth it.
So let's keep moving here in our edit.