And so you should be by now becoming a level 10.
Maybe not Lyttleton yet, but maybe a little eight little nine editing ninja.
So next up, now that we've gotten a really cool understanding, pacing, editing shots, we shot links,
all these little intricacies and subtleties as an editor.
We have these new things in our arsenal.
What I want to do now for the rest of this learning lesson is to now hone in on some of the final refining
steps that's really going to take this video and elevate it to a higher level of production.
And so if we take a look here, I'm going to actually turn this down.
This was all shot on a gimbal, but there's definitely a lot of noticeable shakiness and jerky motions
and movements that I'm not super happy with and doesn't match the flowing tone of her performance.
So a really excellent and effective final polishing layer.
Once you get to the second draft edit like we're at now is to apply post-production stabilization.
Now, what this is going to do is it's going to tell your software to analyze all the movements and
shakes and wiggles and jostles, all those kind of verbs.
It's going to analyze those and it's going to decide where movement is happening.
And it's going to scale up your image and make a steadiness and really undo those motions.
So if the camera moves this way, it's going to actually do the exact opposite movement, which cancels
out the unwanted shakiness that we have in our footage.
So let's go ahead and go to our first clip here.
And I'm going to grab our warp stabilizer effect.
This is what it's called in premiere in other editing software, as it might be slightly different wording.
But you want to grab your postproduction, stabilizing effect and drag it on to the first clip they
were editing with here.
Now, what this is going to do is it's going to analyze the footage frame by frame.
And when it's done analyzing, then it's going to scale up that image depending on how much movement
is in the actual clip.
The more movement, the more it needs to scale it up to come back that extra movement.
And as you can see, our warp stabilizer has finished analyzing the clip.
It's scaled up our clip from one hundred percent to one hundred and two percent.
So just a little bit.
And let's see what that looks like.
So a lot smoother if I undo the clip.
You can see it goes back to 100 percent scale and there's like that jitteriness.
See the difference?
The downside to this, when there's a lot of movement in the foreground, in the background, the computer
can't tell depth in your flat image, you can't tell that you were shooting in a three dimensional area
where if I'm moving the camera here, this is in the foreground.
That's how you in the background.
And it has a hard time knowing that there is a separation here.
So for this clip in particular, we have this wobble and this kind of underwater look.
So this is the effect and filter that you really want to find, too.
You really want to turn it down to the point where it's still stabilizing your footage.
But on some shots, it has a really hard time knowing that this is in the foreground and this is in
the background.
So it's warping the whole clip as one big thing.
So we're going to find a way to get around that once we get away from this tree.
It looks pretty dang smooth compared to without the stabilization.
There's all that extra shaking going on.
So let's see what we can do to fine tune this clip.
So we're not getting this under the sea.
Look here.
OK.
What you can do to minimize that warp is change the smoothness function every time you apply this filter
to your clip.
The automatic value is going to be 50 percent smoothness.
This means how much you're applying the filter to the clip itself.
Now, let's turn this down to, let's say, 20 percent.
Now it's going to reanalyze quickly and it's going to restabilize the clip.
So now we're only scaling it up one hundred and one point nine percent.
And let's hit play to see.
OK.
That's looking better.
There still is some definite unwanted war penis.
So we're going to have to bring it down even less, let's say, 10 percent.
And the other thing that we can do is change the method at which this effect is analyzing our clip.
OK.
If we go from subspace warp, which is the default main method, it usually does a great job.
But what I've noticed when there's foreground in the clip, in the background subspace work, you get
a little bit Werbe.
So we have perspective position, scale rotation in position.
Let's see what these other options do for us.
So if we go to position and hit play, it's only going to be analyzing and moving your footage on an
axis and X and Y axis, the position left, right, up and down.
OK.
That we don't really want.
I never used just the position method because it doesn't really do a whole lot to your clip.
If we try the position, scale and rotation method, it's now applying changes on the position up,
down, left, right, the scale and the rotation.
So it's adding more axis of change to better smooth in the image.
So that's actually looking a lot better.
And the last option, which is my favorite for this kind of scenario, when we're not getting a very
good stabilization on some tricky shots, I click perspective instead of subspace work.
Let's check that out.
So that's starting to look pretty good.
There's still a little bit of war up there just at this beginning.
But we could fine tune it more.
But I really want to move forward onto the other clips so we can continue this refining process.
So let's check out the set of the next three shots.
So there we've got a lot of shaking going on.
This one is decent.
There's not a whole lot of excess shaking, and that one is not too bad either.
And this one's definitely got some extra movements.
So let's start with this first one.
I'm going to apply.
This warp stabilizer to all of these cliffs.
Now we're going to play through and see how good these clips work with the default settings of the stabilization.
It's likely that we're going to have to do some fine tuning, which is very normal with this type of
filter, because every shot is different.
There's different foreground background, camera movement.
Contrast where everything is is different per shot.
So it's not a one size fits all when it comes to this type of filter.
Ooh, that's looking good.
OK, a little too much warping right there.
So that looks so good.
It's just right in here when we get a little bit too much.
So let's see what it did for default.
Of course, smooth.
This is smoothness is always default set to 50 percent.
And it only scaled up our image to one or four, which is not bad.
So but let's bring this down to, let's say, 30 percent.
And let's see if that gets rid of this excess.
OK, that looks great.
OK, there was still little it's subtle, but we don't want it to be obvious that there's stabilization,
we want it to be seamless.
And there's just these artifacts that show up of that underwater worthiness that makes it really obvious
that everyone knows who knows knows that you were using a warp stabilizer.
We don't want that.
We want everything to look smooth and invisible in a way not obvious that we apply to filter.
So let's bring it down to 20 and let's hit play.
OK.
I like that next shot.
Looks pretty good.
There's some extra bumping going on here.
OK, so let's bring this down to, let's say, 10 percent, because there is a lot of movement in this
one.
The more movement, the more you have to bring down the smoothness, because otherwise the stabilization
that it does cancels out how good it looks, because you go from shakiness to underwater and you don't
want that.
It looks pretty good at 10 percent.
But as you can see, it kind of does a bounce with her movements and we don't really want that.
So let's try perspective on this one.
And.
OK, we're still getting those movements.
So let's drop it down even more to, let's say, five percent.
Even more, two percent sometimes even do two or one percent, and honestly, it's good enough.
You don't need to take out all of the movement.
You just want to take up the distracting little shakiness, OK?
We don't need to really take away all of this movement with the camera, but it's just these actions
that kills the professional.
Look for your video.
Perfect.
So I've gone through and I fine tune the rest of these warp stabilizer filters now on a lot of these
clips.
As you can see, it's down to one percent on a lot of them, because for this specifically, there is
a lot of movement going on.
There is a lot of changing in the frame, closeups, trees in the foreground, other things in the foreground.
So it's really going to depend on the type of footage that you're working with.
But now, before we wrap up this lesson, I want to see a side by side with the footage where we took
the extra step and time in our second edit to add this fine tuned stabilization and see that next to
our edit, which looked good.
But until we see it side by side with one that's even more refined, you're going to see a big difference.
Let's check that out so you can see a lot of extra bouncing, a lot of extra shaking.
So that extra 10 to 20 minutes that we spend on that step can literally add an extra 10 to 20 percent
of production quality to our final edit.
And that's what footage that was shot already on a gimbal.
So you can really do even more with hand-held footage and with other shots that need just a little bit
of extra oomph to get to that level of professionalism that you're looking for.
So in the next lecture, we're going to finish this project by adding our final step for this process,
which is our final color correction layer.