So once I had those, I pre composed it or nested that sequence or those clips, rather.
And that's what became this.
Then I could independently or actually then I could move all of the clips as one.
Because if I try to do that without testing the clips, as soon as I try to move this one, then I got
to move the rest of them.
So once I had the alignment properly, I had this exactly where I wanted.
I had this exactly where I wanted.
And I had the definition thing exactly where I wanted.
I nested that.
And then that's what we got right here.
And that's what allowed for me to.
Originally it was this big, so I scaled it down 80 and I could put it literally wherever I wanted and
or wherever I want.
And group them all together.
Now, that's what's going on.
On the visual side.
On the audible side, you can see our music comes down here because her speaking comes in right here.
So we want the music to go from the primary thing to the secondary thing as the primary.
Her audio, a.k.a. her audio, comes in.
And then we have this sound effect in the background, which is simply a little sound effect.
I got line of a chalkboard of a person writing on a chalkboard sound effect.
So if we look at all those elements together.
Literary analysis is analysis, this little sound effect helps to provoke or just, you know, make
this moment a little bit more realistic with what's happening on screen.
So if I were to remove that.
Literary analysis.
OK, I'm going to put it back.
It just has a cool little shop.
Right.
And that's really the key with these little subtle sound effects.
We have vocals, music.
Sound effect layer.
Sound effects, layer.
And you want to only use a sound effects layer in proper moments where stuff needs to be.
You know, if I do this and you hear it, that's very normal.
But if I did this.
And I took out the sound or it didn't add the sound in, when someone sees that, they're just like
that doesn't really make sense.
That's a really good way to explain when you should add sound effects and why it's actually helping.
So if we move forward a little bit more, it's about assessing, cataloging all the pieces of a text.
And we have a lot going on.
But all this is is the same exact process that I just explained.
We have the audio sound effect right here.
We have our music right here.
We have her speaking right here, and then we have our nested sequence that is all of these overlays
very similar to what we just worked on.
So we have a color mat that's just blocking out a part of the image that we don't want to show up.
We have our screen capture that is of the website.
And then we have if I double click that we have all of the elements that we dragged in on top.
So this is basically just a really complex version because there's so many layers to have all this stuff
coming in.
But it's the same exact process.
I use a ramp to change the color.
OK.
Right there, I change the scaling height and with to get the right ratio and proportion on all these
different elements.
I move them all into place exactly where I wanted them to go, just like that.
And then I stacked them on top of each other and had them all come in at their own moment to really
make a complex looking piece.
Once I had that, then I nested that sequence just like this.
So now I have all of what's inside here.
I selected everything right click went boom nest.
That's what created this sequence.
And now they're all right there, boom.
And then I overlaid that crazy complex sequence on top of a screen cap of their website that look like
this, which is the background.
Right.
And nested that again.
And that is what created this one single clip with all of that motion.
And the reason I did that final nesting was so as you can see this zooming effect originally, if I
go to the effects and let's say I cancel these and we just hit play, it's about the Stassi cataloging
all the pieces of the text.
It's very stagnant.
It's very still.
There's no movement.
So if I put that back, then you'll see as we play through, there's this nice zoom in.
So nesting and having multiple media assets.
Yeah.
It really will allow for you to create a lot of cool stuff because then you can take 13 layers that
you created for this two second sequence, nested and then changed the function of the parameters of
all those clips at once.
So another cool, really advanced technique to take a lot of content boom, upgraded as much as possible,
use audio in this kind of moment and create a really cool looking overlay, high end asset for your
video.