OK, so as I've been pulling the SELEX, I've been removing parts that were mess ups on takes, choosing
the best takes, making the proper cuts and refining and taking out what's not needed.
I've been labeling the clips that signal and show me as the editor when the topic is changed or when
the scene may change or any other kind of thing that I should know when I go back to the edit now,
because we're working more with dialogue and getting more into these intermediate level steps where
we want to have more refined audio and videos.
I want to kind of show more of this process of refining audio.
It's going to be very applicable to all your future projects, because a lot of being an editor is making
smooth dialogue and a lot of recordings to the dialogue doesn't happen all the time front to back where
you just do one take all the way through and it's clean.
So we kind of got a ninja our way in here.
So I wanted to take a second and continue to kind of show what this process looks like and how we get
a seamless cut in our edit.
And I'm shooting at two point eight.
OK, we're going to make a cut there with the ISO at four.
When eight with the eye and when you're making these kind of cuts to take out the empty spaces.
You want to be able to play it back, close your eyes and listen to hear if you can hear a cut being
made.
Now, if I'm visually looking at this while I'm watching it eat with the I see a cut being made and
it makes it OK that there's an audio change.
The trick is, if we play this back and we don't look at our edit at two point eight with the eyes,
I hear a little bit of an extra gap.
OK, what I'm going to do to fix the gap right here, 8:00 with the OK is to select our clips and scoot
them over a few frames.
And I'm going to close my eyes and playback.
I'm shooting at two point eight with the eyes.
So there's still a little extra gap.
I want it to be a seamless sentence that doesn't have any weirdness.
OK, so let's take out a few more frames here.
And I'm shooting at two point eight with the IESO and I'm shooting at two point eight with the eyes
so perfect, so that to me doesn't send any red flags in my brain.
It doesn't say there sounds like there's a cut there.
There needs to be more space or less space.
That's perfect.
Now, let's continue, because this is actually a really well lit, brightly lit circumstance, the
invo.
Here's another scenario where there can be something kind of refined here.
I repeat myself a little bit, and there's an extra earth that we don't need brightly lit.
So let's make a cut after the Earth.
This is actually a really well lit, brightly lit circumstance.
OK, so I say well lit, brightly lit, so we could try to cut in the well.
But I already say brightly lit.
So what I'm going to do instead of making the cut here brightly lit, is make the cut here circumstance
after circumstance and just completely skip these two attempts to fix my audio.
I'm just going to skip those.
So you're really well lit circumstance.
OK, perfect.
And there's a little too much space, really well lit circumstance, the really well lit circumstance,
really well lit circumstance, the cool.
So that's a pretty seamless edit.
In one cut, we took out an extra hour and we took out an extra repetitious, repetitive phrase.
And the reason we're doing that is, A, making this seamless edit the people's attention span is like
that.
Right.
So we want to really take out any extra information that doesn't need to be there.