OK.
And so before we move on from this specific video project, I want to also share one more aspect here.
The client asked me or actually was part of our contract for me to put together for 15 second cut downs
and one 30 second cut down.
So a cut down is basically exactly what it sounds like, a shorter version of the final product.
So these are used for Instagram.
They're going to be used for Tick-Tock.
They're going to be used for all social media platforms as shorter posts.
The full music video is going to be the main video on the client's website, on their YouTube channel.
All that good stuff.
So I just want to kind of walk you through the process here and let's hop right into it.
So if we just kind of take a listen to this first track here, you can see we have our 15 second edit
cut down.
What is your purpose?
What you buy?
And it goes right into the main course of the song.
So knowing that there is like this for second of intro, I'm going to have some really nice intro shots.
And going into the more exciting part, I know I want to have some exciting footage that matches up.
So the process which we've touched on before, but it's basically going through and taking your main
edit just like this, what we have here, you want to duplicate it.
So let's call this music video shutdown's.
And now you can edit this, change things around, move things around without affecting your master
final sequence.
So that's the process that I started with.
I duplicated it.
I started moving things around.
And I kept in mind, OK, I'm going to have this as I'm going to keep these as intro shots.
And basically, the client specifically for this project wanted to have one cut down with beach footage,
as you can see here, our beach footage and it ending title card for the artists album.
So I just dropped that and added a little bit of a fade so we can actually play this real quick and
see what it looks like.
What is your purpose?
But issued you buy.
Perfect.
So even though we didn't get to use the exciting underwater footage, we used quicker pacing with these
really sunny, bright high energy shots that when they're edited correctly with the right amount of
rhythm, they actually match up quite nicely with the main course.
So that was a perfect execution.
The client loved it.
They got all their beach footage in one mini video.
Now let's move on to the next 15 second cut down trees.
OK, so there we go, we got another 15 second cut down, but they just wanted the and I mean, this
glitch is really bothering me.
I think it has to do.
Yeah, there we go.
It has to do with the overlay that I have for some.
We for some reason, when it renders, it does a weird glitch.
So anyways, yeah, a client wanted another version, which is the nighttime footage and locations.
So I used, you know, the normal shots in the original edit.
I accentuated a few things.
There was a time remapping here, which you could see it'll speed up.
You saw that?
I just enhanced that or increased it from the original edit so that it matched up with the audio better
here and went forward with, again, adjusting the pacing.
Paying attention to what the beat in the song was, doing the rhythm and cutting these shots to the
new parts of the song.
So here we have more of the underwater style, similar type of editing process, their clients outro
card.
Take a deep breath.
And close your eyes, breathe it all the way out.
See the world of report with your contribution as your North Star.
Whether it's behind clouds or not guides to you, what is your purpose?
What is your why?
Open your eyes, see your North Star and fly.
OK, perfect.
So this one's a lot more calm laid back, and this is the 30 second version now that we went through
the process of how I put that together by duplicating our main sequence, moving things around, selecting
the right shots for the right moments in the new cut down audio.
Now I want to show you how I go ahead and repurpose it for specific platforms.