Now I have after effects open, I downloaded the template and double clicked it, and now this is the
main screen for the after effects editing process.
Now, when you buy one of these templates, the cool thing, this is our timeline down here.
And the cool thing is you'll see that they'll come with multiple logo styles.
So we kind of have this more dark, you know, black background.
It's a little bit more, you know, techi, I would say a little bit more of a technological type of
product rather than a real estate kind of vibe.
So we're not going to go with that one.
This one looks nice.
It's got kind of a 3D look to it.
And then this one looks nice as well.
It looks more there's a shadow down here.
There's a lens flare.
So when you do purchase one of these premade templates, always look through the multiple types of logos
that they give you in that template and choose the one with the color scheme that matches up the most
with the style of video you're creating.
Now, we have are different types of logo styles that we look through up here.
They're always going to have multiple folders that have the different kind of elements of the edit.
So we don't need to worry too much about the elements, the footage and textures.
These are basically all of these things like the blur, the noise, the optical flair, different shapes
that it's adding in there.
That's all what they did for you.
So you don't need to worry about that stuff too much.
The only thing you really want to worry about is there's always going to be a sequence that you can
open.
It's going to allow for you to replace the logo and text.
So let's go ahead and let's double click that sequence.
I'm going to load it up here.
Perfect.
Now, what we have is the sequence where we can replace the standard logo, this Envato logo, because
that's like the name of the main website.
We don't want that in our motion graphics.
So if you have a logo, your client's logo, your personal logo, your brand logo, your product logo,
whatever it is, now would be the time to go on your computer.
I just downloaded a lion page because why I feel like lions.
It just really matches up with this kind of kind of royal vibe of this expensive property.
So let's follow the guides that these vertical lines and horizontal lines that this template is showing.
And I'm going to, of course, turn off the example logo that the edit came with.
And I already know that I want to go with logo number three.
So I'm going to go ahead and close out these other sequences with the other logos you don't need.
And let's load this up and see how that's looking.
And that looks super clean.
Now, of course, we don't want to have the Envato dot com.
That's just a placeholder that these kind of templates will leave for you so that you can add your own
website or address whatever it is.
So because what was the name that we put here?
OK.
Hills Hillcrest property.
So let's just to Hill Crest property dot com.
OK.
Let me load that.
So that's looking pretty good.
Just, you know, from a design point of view, I'd say the logo is looking too big compared to our
font.
Now, we can fix this a few ways.
We can scale up the font or scale down the logo.
I think we can do both, because if font looks honestly pretty tiny.
So on a scale this up from 50 to 60, OK, that's looking better.
And it's a little bit thin.
So what I'm going to do is add right here, we have the similar stroke function, just like in from
here.
This is how we can set our stroke with.
So I'm going to take it from zero to two.
Now, next thing would be would be to scale down our logo.
So I'm going to double click our logo.
So I'm going to open up the logo sequence.
I'm going to hit s to open up the scale function.
And I'm going to scale it down from one hundred to 80.
Now, in AfterEffects, you can see you can change all of the parameters of the clip that you've selected
right underneath it.
It's different than in premiere.
All that stuff is up here in the top left.
And after effects, boom, it's right with the clip.
So after effects is good for a high amount of.
Refinement and editing on, let's say, a five second piece of a video when something like Premier is
perfect for putting together the entire three to five minute video.
And then you go in after effects to really create a very specialized look for just a very short amount
of that video.
Now, I know that there's alternative templates inside this one with different color schemes, and there's
this other one that also looks really good.
So honestly, both would match.
Both have that same kind of elegant, professional, high end kind of feeling.
Any kind of Lione logo automatically makes it feel high end.
And these are very clean, modern, minimal graphics styles.
So honestly, both would work, I think, for this example.
I'm just going to go with this version.
It's super clean and it's perfect for this style.
So now what we can do is once we've gotten our logo in there and we've gotten whatever kind of title
or text that we want on screen, we can kind of go and edit the, you know, overall other stuff that's
going on in the image.
This is going to be our optical flair.
So you can see this blue light.
There it is.
And then without.
I'm going to personally take it out because we don't need any kind of Star Trek over the top.
You know, we don't want it to feel over edited.
We want it to be clean and simple.
If it was a more high energy video with a more futuristic theme and feeling, boom, leave the lens
flare in there, that would be perfect.
But we're really wanting to go for subtlety.
Now we can do other stuff like take out the drop shadow
just like that, or put it back in by using this icon.
For each one of these layers, we can selectively turn the visibility on and off for the different layers.
So what we can do is kind of preview the intro of what this edit or motion graphic is starting to look
like.
So I'm going to go ahead and select the first two seconds and I'm going to start to load a preview so
we can check it out.
And boom, this is the first few seconds of the animation.
Now, it looks freaking amazing.
Like I said, this would have taken me days or an entire day to put together.
So I'm super happy to pay 15 bucks to then have this kind of template for all my future projects.
You know, and of course, we can go in and there's tweaking we can do.
There's all these different layers.
We can mess with the blurriness, the intro, you know, all the different stuff, the shadow, the
reflections, all the animations.
I'm going to leave this as is for now.
And what I'm going to do is I'm going to export it, and then I'm going to drop it in to our premiere
sequence and see what it looks like as the ending title card.