And so depending on the type of travel video you've been editing during, this whole portion is really
going to dictate what your opening shot is going to be.
And something I want to mention is the same way that every single shot has a beginning and end, every
single video that you create has a beginning and end.
I know this sounds obvious, but the reason I'm saying is because we just went through on how the beginning
cut and the ending cut is so important because you're showing the person where is important, what is
important to start looking at, and then what is important to end looking at or end hearing.
It can be an audio thing.
A dialogue thing can be a visual thing.
Our whole video is like a zoomed out view of what happens in one edit.
I don't want to get too abstract here, but we want to start with the shot that really like sets things
into gear, sets things in motion.
The opening shot of your video, regardless of if it's a music video, commercial comedy documentary,
YouTube video, Instagram video.
Take that video.
Does it matter?
The opening frame, the opening shot dictates the tone and the vibe and the feeling that the viewer
is going to have for the rest of the video.
The ending shot is kind of the conclusion.
It's what they walk away with.
So something a little bit deeper to really ponder and think about that.
But let's get more back into the practical side.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to scrub through and I'm going to find the shot that really
grabs me, because if it grabs me, yeah, OK.
If it's grabbing me and my attention, it's a good sign that hopefully can grab someone else's attention
and get them interested in your video, because that's the whole point.
Right.
So this is definitely a contender.
I like this.
I think it's a unique type of shot.
I mean, the scenery is like just ridiculous.
We don't want to get too much down into like, uh, too low here.
So maybe we'll start the shot.
Let's say there so that we get the vibe, the kind of point of view feeling.
That's an example of continuing to refine when we did this first pass, like, OK, in and out, in
and out, in and out.
Now, on the second time when I'm looking at that shot, it was starting with a little bit too much
leg, a little bit too much leg action going on.
So what I'm going to do is because this one catches my eye the most, I'm going to slide this over to
the very beginning of our edit.
That way, we open up on this shot and it really sets the tone and the feeling for what the rest of
the video is going to look like, and if it's obvious the clip is too loud, we can bring that down
a little bit by clicking and holding that white bar.
But I don't want you to worry too much about getting the audio levels perfect, because that's one of
the final stages of creating the edit.