I want to show you how to take a screen cap and add footage into that screen cap to create something
that wasn't originally there.
So let's hop over the screen cap, OK?
Is it a screen Gaffigan?
Inception, right.
Let's hop over to the screen cap I'm doing right now.
And then we'll talk about editing a different screen cap.
So what makes a poem?
A poem is supposed to be in paragraphs and prose can utilize the concrete space on the page.
Then what defines a poem?
You actually get to answer that question.
OK, cool.
So we have this first screen capture.
Now, all I did was I use quick time on my laptop.
I went to the client's website and I clicked on one of the videos on their course dashboard.
So that's this clip right here.
If we zoom into this clip we have.
The page loading, scrolling down, and then my mouse goes over and clicks.
Now I added a color mat on top of this one, just like for the other one, because when you're logged
in to the Web site, it shows an icon of your profile picture.
We don't want that for this kind of video.
So a color mat is a really great way to get around that.
And so basically, I just scaled down and moved it over to just cover that part of the image.
If I wanted to change the color of this karamat, I'd double click it and I could put it to anything.
But what I did was I double clicked it.
I hit the eyedropper tool and I went to the color that I wanted to cover and I hit boom and then hit,
OK.
Now what we have is this moment.
And you can kind of see actually skip forward here.
So we have the original screen cap.
I think this is the clicking boom.
I think it took me a minute to like click.
I don't know what what was going on, but I just scooted over a bit of a screen cap to make the clicking
sooner.
Now, let's back up a little bit.
And we have this.
Now, what I did here was a nested this sequence.
Again, we're starting to really love nesting because of the cool things we can do with it.
And I used it to, again, create a little bit more camera movement.
You can see up in the top these key frames that are going on.
We're scaling up our image and we're also going to the left part of the frame, which is where the mouse
goes, because that just creates a little bit more movement and it makes it feel less stagnant.
We have all these moving shots and interesting shots.
And then if you come to a very bland still screenshot, it can get a little boring.
So I really recommend you always add some kind of zoom pan motion to your screen grabs or screen captures.
Now we go to this next shot and it shows, you know, going from clicking on the video to then going
to an example video.
And we have a zoom in like we've already been talking about these key frames at the top.
We're zooming in here.
But if I don't click this, let's break this down.
We have our top layer fixing the top part that we don't need.
And then we have this middle layer right here.
And then we have our background layer, which is our main screen capture.
So as you can see, we have all these different shots.
They weren't really there.
This is what was actually there.
So what I did was I took raw footage that I had.
I scaled it down properly so that it covered the actual screen where video should be playing.
And I added these bero shots that made it look like these footage, these shots were actually on the
client's Web site.
So I grab the screen cap shots.
I ordered them where I wanted them to go.
And then I nested them by going like this hitting nest.
And that's what created this nested sequence.
Then I could scale all of them down globally and move them into the proper placement.
So instead of having this, let's go back to our edit and utilize the page.
Then it turned into this and utilize the concrete space on the page.
Then what defines a whole huge difference, right?
Huge difference.
So one last thing I want to mention as well is just this little subtle mouse click you can utilize.
I don't know if you can hear it with this audio.
I can hear really clearly just a little sound.
I went and I downloaded the apple mouse keyboard click.
Just that little sound to further sell that this is really happening and this is what the experience
would be like for a student or a customer actually using the website.
So with all those things together, the movement that we added to this kind of footage, the sound design
that we added on the bottom, the zooming and then the adding of B roll on top of a screen cap.
That's what made this quick sequence just that much more professional and that much more entertaining
to watch.