So we've made it to the final stage of our edit, and now that you're becoming an expert, Ed, can
you guess what we're going to be doing in this stage?
Hmm.
Yes, we're going to be doing the color correction and color grading process, because what we already
have here looks pretty darn good.
I mean, you can't really go wrong with shooting with a location like this and having a subject that's
performing with a violin.
I mean, that's pretty -- cool.
But just like with the stabilization process, there's a little extra time that we're going to spend
on this.
Refinement is going to make the colors pop.
It's going to make the imagery stand out a little bit more.
And it's going to bring up the production value of our final product.
So let's hop into the color correction and color grading process.
All right.
And so your timeline should be looking relatively similar to what we have here.
If you've been working on the violin footage, if you've been working on your own project with your
own past footage, be sure to have had your first edit done.
And your second refinement edit done, ideally with some post-production stabilization.
And now your edit is ready to be stylized with some coloring.
So to save time and really do this the right way.
What we want to start by doing is first, scrubbing through our footage and seeing any shots that stand
out and don't match other shots instantly.
I can see there is a pretty decent exposure difference in this transition from these two shots.
So what I'm going to do is select the second shot, go to Effect's, type in lume tricolour or type
in whatever color filter title that you're editing software uses for it.
Drop it on.
And we're going to hit up and we're going to hit up.
We're going to open up the basic color correction panel.
And what we're going to do here is we could drop the exposure, but you're going to see what that's
going to do.
It's almost going to drop the opacity, which here's the thing.
This exposure is nice and this one is a little bit over.
So rather than dropping the exposure, something you can do to drop down the overall intensity of light
but create an even better looking image is to really bring the shadows down instead, because that's
going to create more depth.
There's going to be more I don't know what other word to use besides depth in the shadows, but there's
going to be more of a contrasty, stylized look by dropping the shadows, because you're just pushing
down the dark parts of the frame.
You're leaving the middle and you're leaving the bright parts of the same to stand out rather than bringing
down the exposure, which is bringing down the darks, the maids and the lights.
Right.
The blacks, the midtown and the white tone.
I don't know if tone is the right word, but you know what I'm trying to say here.
So we're just going to bring down the shadows, just a touch so that these shots now are starting to
match up a lot better.
There's also a little bit of a color difference here.
You can see is a lot more Tannen's going on in this image.
And this one is feeling a bit more blue and cold, but it's not too bad.
It's nice.
We get the tans here once the shot pans around, but.
We could, if we wanted to add a little bit of an increase in color temperature to bring up some more
warmth in this shot.
So that's the original that's what the color temperature increase we could do a little bit more.
Let's do 10.
OK, perfect.
So without with subtle, but you can see that that's a little bit more bluish and that's got some more
Tanzimat, which is perfect when we want to match our shots.
So that shot looks fine.
Let's continue to scrub forward here.
Now, this is a scenario when the exposure in the overall image is pretty good, but the way our subject
is positioned and the way she's kind of backlit and we don't have an external light over here.
Out of frame.
We don't have a Phil card over here bouncing light on her face.
We didn't have that during the shooting process.
Now, what we can do is, like I said, the overall exposure is great, but her exposure on her face
is a little bit dark.
So there's two ways we can do this.
One way is to push up the shadows, because you can see this is all going to be affected by shadow parameters.
OK, because these are all dark's.
These are all lights, OK?
So if I boost the highlights, that's really going to start bringing up the exposure on all the bright
parts of the frame.
We don't want to do that because the bright parts of the frame are already bright.
What the problem is, is that the dark part of the frame, which happens to be her face in this shot,
is a little on the dark side.
So we can push that up and bring some more exposure to her face.
Of course, it is going to affect the shadows in the rest of the shot.
But it's perfect for focusing on her face for this shot, particularly so without and with this out
inwith.
So that's a little bit better.
That's one option, one way to do it.
Now, the other option, I'm going to go ahead and turn this off and I'm going to put on a new color
correction layer so that we can see the difference between option one and option two.
Now, option two is to create a mask that is only affecting an area of our frame that we want it to
affect.
Now, there's two or three actual ways to do this.
We have our Elipse mask, a square mask and our pen tool.
If we click the Ellipse mask, what this is going to do is it's going to add a circular mask to our
image that's affecting where our color correction is going to affect our image.
So if I turn this up instantly, we can see where we're affecting the exposure only on this part of
the frame, which is pretty cool.
That's a really handy tool to have.
Now to blend our mask so there's not an hard edge.
And it's obvious that there's a mask there.
We can feather the edges of our mask by changing the intensity of the mask feather.
And we can change the opacity of that mask as well, which is going to also change the intensity of
the masks effect.
And then we can change the expansion of how wide or narrow the mask is.
And lastly, we can invert our mask so we can actually affect the opposite of where the mask is.
So let's go ahead and delete this.
I'm going to click the mask it delete.
And we can also do this square icon here to create a square mask.
If there was something that we knew in the frame was had right angles to it.
We can do the square mask to kind of save time.
We will be able to move the points of the frame of the mask around to match up our image.
Of course, that's not the style of mass we're going to be doing in this situation.
And lastly, if we really wanted to affect a very particular part of the frame that wasn't a square
was in a circle.
And we wanted to take the time to really draw in our mask, to make a very unique shape.
We can use the pen tool and literally outline our subject by hand.
Now you can get as complex or as detailed with this as you want.
I'm going to change the zoom so that we zoom out a little bit and I have some room to select around
the frame outside of the actual image to finish off the mask.
And you can really fine tune this.
You can move this around.
You can also hold ALT to create curves instead of right angles, which is really great in a lot of situations,
so that your mask looks a lot more organic with curves.
And you can actually use these little lassos to even more fine tune where the mask is in your frame.
So squeeze out, OK, we don't need this to curve here.
OK.
I'm going to zoom back out here, fit it to the window and turn the effect back on.
And now we can see we're just affecting our subject now, monitoring the exposure down, because this
is definitely not the look we're going for.
So I'm just going to turn it up a little bit and boost the shadows just a little bit, 10 percent.
And now I want to further out the edges so that it's not so obvious as a mask.
There you can see that's without the mask.
That's with the mask.
We're just adding a subtle little fill layer of light on our subject.
And if we're happy with that.
Perfect.
But to take it one step even further, we can actually keyframe the path and positioning of our mask
frame by frame.