Let's continue to move forward in this edit and see what else we can focus on and learn from this project.
Now we have this part of the video where we can clearly see our music track is going to fade away.
The reason I decided to do that at this moment for this whole sequence is because this is the part of
the video where it's an actual teaching moment.
It's not fun, flashy, inspiring lines that the character is delivering, but it's an actual minute
and a half sequence where we wanted to demonstrate what an actual video lesson would be like in this
project or for an online course specifically.
So let's go in and play for a little bit.
We'll have our music fading out.
As you can see right here, we have the key framing to bring our track audio down.
So oh, captain, my captain by Walt Whitman, I love this poem because I love the sound quality of
it.
So pay attention to the moments that are getting stressed and you can call us, you know, our poets.
We're trying to build our Pulitzer.
Oh, Captain, my captain are fearful.
Trip is.
So you can see that sinking going on where we did what we did before, creating the same exact kind
of motion graphic, the same way we are to explain.
We have a nice sound effect that's going and our music drops out right here as she's going into this
brand new style of speaking.
Oh, Captain, my captain are fearful.
Trip is done.
The ship has weathered every rock.
That size we saw is one.
The port is near the bells.
I hear the people all exulting while falo eyes, the steady meal, the vessel grim and daring.
So we have again, this Viorel sequence.
Now, if I save this real quick.
Right click and reveal this in our project.
We have a one minute raw clip of me directing her through the secrets.
So we took this.
You know, there's a lot of pauses.
There's a lot of waiting to get the framing right, telling her, OK, do the marking.
And we took that raw sequence and we cut it down.
Boom, boom, boom, boom.
Only two the great moments we needed that were synched up to her audio.
One.
And then after that, we went to the beacom side angle.
I personally do this because I felt like this captured a lot more the cool snapping motion that she
was doing.
And if I didn't do that, here's what it would have look like.
People all exulting while falo eyes the steady Neil, the vessel grim and daring so vs. the bells I
hear the people all exulting while falo eyes the steady Neil the vessel grim and daring.
So in those first four.
So that's another great use of when to use which camera angle you always want to use, the one that's
telling your story the best.
Sometimes it's going to be the angle from the side.
Sometimes it's going to be a straight on angle.
It really depends in each moment.