Perfect.
So we've learned so far together how to really create a first draft edit using the much more foundational
and straightforward techniques and tools as an editor.
Now, we could technically call the edit done at this point.
A lot of people do, but it is the final fine tuning and little extra aesthetical aesthetical, I hope.
I don't know if that's a word, but stylistic choices and changes that.
Is that less 10 percent.
That creates a final edit that really looks different.
So what we're now going to be moving towards in this next learning lesson is how to add that final glossy
layer to an edit like this.
For each edit, that final glossy layer is different.
For some projects, it could be more adding motion graphics for other projects.
It could be adding a specific transition throughout the piece that makes it look more cohesive and stylized
for this particular project.
We're going to color correct all of our clips individually to get the levels right and the exposure
correct.
And then we're going to do a pass across the whole timeline where we're going to actually colored grade
our footage.
Now, people kind of mix up the words color corrected color, great color.
Correct.
Is you're correcting the color, the levels, the highlights, the darks, the blacks, the whites and
the tint and the tone of your content.
Sometimes you have a random green shot in there.
And when all the other shots are pretty neutral color temperature, or there's a very blue shot or an
overly orange shot in the color correcting process, we're balancing all the shots of the whole timeline
is equalized.
And then in the color grading process, where then stylizing a layer of a specific look on top of the
footage.
So we're going to do that.
And then we're also going to add some more key framing and motion changes to some of our clips in our
timeline so that it matches up a little bit more with the beat and adds a little extra character and
stylizing.
So let's get into it.