So we have this opening shot, and I'm going to cut it right about there.
It's interesting when we're looking at the waterfall, but then we start going over here too much.
So it's cut it there.
And let's just see, because I think this next shot that was kind of already placed there is pretty
interesting, too.
It's pretty unique to see that, especially because it's really contrasting this first shot.
So you want to keep in mind what you're editing.
If you're editing something that you want to be like a travel video, that's really punchy.
It's cool to have contrast, like an image with a lot of reds in it and then an image with a lot of
blues in it.
OK, that's going to create more of a punch, Yoenis, an impact for the audience.
So let's see how these two flow together.
OK, so I think I want to start this a little bit later.
And that is feeling like a pretty harsh cut because the audio is so drastic, but what we can do is
continue to bring down the audio on the really loud waterfall.
Let's let's keep that for now and let's keep moving forward.
Well, really fine tune this audio, but let's try and get the right ordering and the right pacing for
our visuals here.
So this first shot is about four seconds, as you could see.
And I want this to feel kind of like a story, kind of like turning pages in.
You're going through the traveling trip that's going to kind of dictate the pacing.
Now, the pacing is the amount of frequency of cuts.
OK.
So if it's like boom, boom, boom, that's a pretty slow pace.
If it was like this.
OK.
Boom, boom, boom.
So I don't mind the audio, but that's a much faster pace, which makes things feel a little bit more
moving forward, a little bit more acceleration, a little bit more energy, a little bit more of a
quickness.
OK, so let's continue to move forward here.
Let's go ahead and cut that clip there.
Looking back at this one, it doesn't really do a whole lot.
So I'm going to delete that.
This boomerang is cool, but it's a I want this to feel like a flow.
I want someone to be able to watch this video and flow through it like they went on the trip himself.
And this boomerang where it's going back and forth is not flowing for me.
So we're going to go and delete that.
And I want you to be making those same decisions as you're going through right now with your Roughan.
What is the purpose and the primary sensation feeling take away that you want the viewer to have?
And is the visual or audio that they're experiencing right now in your edit, giving them more of that
thing that you want them to receive, just like a chef is choosing certain food ingredients to bring
together little bit of salt, a little bit of pepper, a little bit of paprika, a little bit of cayenne,
you know, to spice things up.
If that's the kind of dish you want to make, make sure that all of your ingredients, which are your
edits, are creating that final dish that you want to create.
It's a nice analogy there.
So let's keep it moving here.
That is far too loud.
I'm not super feeling this one.
So let's go ahead and do eat that.
And of course, we have our back up.
So if we do want to go back and put that shot back in, once we have our rough edit, we will have that
there.
So.
OK, so we have two yellow shots here.
Oh, yeah, OK.
I really like this clip here.
It's got people in it.
It shows the environment.
I think there was already really good audio from it as well.
Yeah, you see, like it's not even going to take that much work to get it sounding good because the
audio is already really good.
OK.
I don't feel like we need this waterfall shot because we already have a shot in our edit that tells
that story.
So if you have some type of duplicate that's not really pushing your footage in your story or video
along further, it's going to take it out.
I do like these two shots.
I'm going to go ahead and hold on to them by pushing them to the back.
So what I just did right there is I highlighted the clips that I feel like I may use in this edit,
but they're not going to be happening at this place chronologically.
And I highlighted them and did command X, which is simply instead of copying, you're cutting it,
which is going to remove from the timeline.
And then I'm going to take the player head to the back of the timeline and paste it.
OK.
Now I'm going to triple delete and remove that extra space there.
And let's see what we have here.
I want to see what this shot will be like directly after this.
I like that there's kind of something to link them together, which is the trickling water sound.
That's something to kind of keep in mind when you're doing an edit this like this is you can blend things
together by having certain similarities.
Whether that's something similar that's in the frame, let's say you have two shots of a sunset and
you cut them together and the sun is in the same place on both shots or the camera movement is similar
on this shot.
When it's ending, the camera is going this way.
And on the next shot, the camera is doing the same thing.
So let's see what these two look like.
OK.
So I'm going to kind of scooch this over.
So I like how those two are cutting together because it's a similar camera movement and the audio in
the background is going to be similar when we do level that out.
And I like this linking together of these kind of different water shots.
So let's skip forward here.
And let's see how dragging this one in after this.
OK, that's OK.
It doesn't need to be perfect just now on this rough edit.
But I think those will cut together and we can even add, because this is a tripod shot for this meditating
Yoji shot.
But we can't even add a little bit of movement when we get to our next stage.
And I'll show you how to do that.
As we can see, you can kind of tell I'm kind of cutting these shots even in half the duration that
they originally were when we pulled our original Selex.
So that's something that I kind of mentioned, where you don't want to get too nitpicky too early on
in your edit.
It's way faster in the long run to do something that's a basic layer, a basic pass through the edit,
another basic pass.
It's a little bit more refined.
Another basic pass.
It's a little bit more refined, rather than finding the exact shot in the exact location of the exact
timing.
So hopefully that's making sense.