And I also want to mention the reason for scaling or no excuse me, the reason for nesting this sequence.
Now, if I go back to, let's say, this sequence where we didn't nest it, but we have a new sequence
setting, everything is going to change independently.
So we have our adjustment layer.
We have our overlays.
So everything gets scooted over.
And because we were originally this big rectangle and we went to the square.
We're missing the size of our image.
And now everything is scooted over.
So if we wanted to, let's say, move her, but then the overlays didn't move, so then we would have
to go in and move the overlays to.
And there can be a lot of different issues, and it just saves time to nest the sequence before adjusting
the overall sequence ratio.
Now, the same exact process is going to be for when you do, let's say, even a nine by 16, which
would be a post for tick tock or Instagram stories.
So let's do 10, 80 by 1920, about a boom.
And now we have that vertical phone aspect ratio.
And of course, we can go in and with our nested sequence, scooch things around.
And also scale it down so that it's filling the frame properly if it's scaled up.
That means we're missing a lot of information on the sides and the top and bottom because we went from
horizontal to now vertical.
So you always want to make sure you scale it down so that the video is just barely filling the frame.
So at one hundred percent, we were actually losing a lot of information or a lot of X external side
parts of the video on the side and top and bottom.
Now, we are having a lot more video in the frame.
And if we wanted to do that same thing over here, you know, we would have to scale this down.
OK, now it's fitting perfectly.
And then the overlay is, OK, you got to scale these down, OK?
And this other overlay right here, boom.
So I wanted to share this, really create protip really great protip on a final process, especially
when you have a client asking for multiple exports with multiple different ratios.
So we have the versions that are ending with her main logo, ending with the now available logo at the
end, ending with all these different kind of edits.
And then we have the nine, but our 16 nine by 16 edits as well.
So this is a great way to do that as efficiently and easily as possible.
I will see you now in the next video lesson.