Now, there are two main types of montage, a musical montage and a sound driven montage.
Now a sound driven montage is going to be an edit.
It's driven by the actual audio from the scenario you were shooting in.
And a musical montage is going to be a compilation of visuals that are edited to a musical track.
So we've done a bit of both of those.
But we're going to do one for this specific video.
But this is really a great technique of creating mini montages in your videos, especially for YouTube
and social media content, because it really separates the video into different kind of chunks and makes
multiple videos into one video in a kind of way.
It's great for people with a short attention span.
It's great to really spice things up.
And the way we're going to be learning how to do it in this edit is to cut down about five minutes of
this footage that we have here with audio from our scene of this whole opening the boxes.
So I'm going to go ahead and undo the audio track for these shots that we have here, because we're
actually, like I mentioned, you're going to be using the audio.
Hopefully it's good.
So let's go ahead and skip forward to the first important moment.
Basically, I'm going to be opening up this knife and then opening up all the boxes.
So let's go to this moment.
We can read our waveform and see this is our moment right here.
OK.
And what we're going to be doing here is really cutting a.
We're not going to be wasting any time.
We're not going to be doing things in real time.
We're going to do short, quick cuts.
And I want to just grab for the first draft of this montage.
Every moment that has a sound to it.
So the throwing down, the opening.
And as you can hear, we have sadly, the lens of the camera was pulling focus.
So there are these these moments we're obviously going to do our best to cut around, ideally if we're
recording something like this in production.
We are using an external microphone.
Apparently, I wasn't using one for this situation.
So that's on me.
Now, we got to fix it in post, as some might say.
But let's continue to pull the cool moments from this sequence.
So I'm going to go right in front of the moment.
We want make a cut.
Before.
OK.
And now.
What we have is all the cool shots that have a cool sound to it.
Back to back in a quick succession succession, a succession of edits.
OK, we're going to leave that for now, but we can adjust the pacing, speed things up on the next
pass of this edit, but let's continue to go through and pull the rest of all this footage in the Tann
sequence.