So we've created our title cards, we've created our main sequence, we made our really cool custom
outro motion graphic, and now we're at the time in the edit where we want to do our color correction
layer.
Now, what I'm going to do is a similar process to what we've done before, where I want to raise up
the titles that we treated that way.
When we turn up the exposure or the highlights or drop the shadows on our footage below.
We don't affect our title cards.
That's a big no no.
So I'm going to go to our project window.
I'm going to right click.
I'm going to hit adjustment layer.
I'm going to create that adjustment layer.
Drag it in.
Extend it out.
And I know this ahead of time that I have quite a few different overall exposures.
We have this outdoor sequence.
We have these indoor to outdoor stuff.
We have this living room stuff with outdoor.
So there's a lot of different exposures.
So we're going to have to kind of go through and fine tune.
And then once we get over here, then we're outdoor again.
So that's just something to keep in mind that we're going to have to do a little bit more work to get
everything leveled and looking the same, or at least getting the exposures correct on these different
types of clips.
So I'm going to go in I'm going to hit lume tricolour.
I'm going to grab that main color correction filter.
And what I'm going to do is now that I have the effect laid over the entire timeline with no parameters
adjusted yet.
Now I can go and cut where the major changes in scenery and exposure are going to be.
And we already kind of did that marking earlier by changing the colors of what's in our timeline.
So I know that all of this is going to be a very similar exposure.
It's shot in the same location.
If I make a cut here, I know that all of this, again, is going to be a very similar exposure because
this is a grouping of the same parts of the house.
Now, I'm going to go here and we'll take it to OK.
So here's where we go, outdoor.
So right here, all these should be bedroom bathroom yet, OK.
And then we go to here, we're outdoor and then we go to this nighttime transition.
So we're going to create.
Oh, I forgot about that.
OK, we got to do our nighttime transition.
We'll do that after this process.
So we have our adjustment layers ready to go.
And now it's time to go ahead and start fine tuning these clips.
Now, this is a pretty good look and exposure.
We have enough definition in the dark parts of the frame where it's not too dark, but it's not too
bright where it looks, not to where it looks kind of boring, you know, but we don't want to go for
a light.
We're not going to do a lot for this type of project, because if we take a beautiful house and we start
dropping on, you know, these kind of preset custom lights, it's going to start.
You don't want to do that too much on this kind of project because you want things as they are.
Like that looks really cool.
If it was more of a music video.
Right.
So always keeping in mind what type of project it is.
You may have a certain, you know, love that you love that works for all your projects.
But if you hired by a client and you needed to create a clean, bright looking space, it's not going
to work.
And so we've talked about it before, but the coloring is what gives your footage the feeling.
So this is a very like called Iron Man kind of vibe if I go to just pick a random different one.
This is very black and white looks, old school.
It's the same exact house.
We're not changing the location.
This is more of a western kind of feel, you know.
So that's like more of a nighttime.
Now, this looks like almost nighttime footage.
So we don't want to create that type of personality for this kind of project.
We want to let our footage speak for itself.
We want it to look nice and be realistic, not overly stylized.
OK, good.
So we got that out of the way.
Now, a good thing to do, though, is to definitely start with bring up the saturation for a project
like this.
We want everything to look vibrant and inviting and almost, you know, healthy in a certain way.
We don't want to have a black and White House with no color, no sky, no green plants.
People aren't going to be interested in purchasing that first showcase video.
So instantly, just by boosting up the saturation, 75 points, that's looking pretty good.
This one doesn't not need a whole lot of work.
I can bring up the exposure just one point, you know, maybe two points and a little bit more saturations.
Go to 185.
OK.
And that's looking great, OK?
These are really easy, these other shots, I think they're going to need a little bit more help.
So we go into the house.
Okay.
OK, so I see a big exposure difference.
So we'll deal with that separately.
But let's focus here and let's bring up the exposure.
Let's say point five.
OK.
And let's bring up the shadows because we can see all these dark parts of the image here.
Right.
That's not a good look.
When you really want to show something off and you want it to look pretty nice and clean.
Right.
So let's go ahead and see what that looks like.
And let's bring up the s the excuse me, the saturation.
OK.
OK, so without with without, with.