Awesome, so now we're towards the end of our edit, and I want to spend this last video lesson for
this project, specifically on deconstructing the outro, the final sequence of this edit.
So let's hop into it.
You were suddenly thrown into a Virgin Sea, and that's where the angst of this poem lives.
Each one of these quizzes, premium learning lessons in study diets is going to give you the tools you
need to totally transform the way you experience literature.
So if you're ready to get started, you can choose your membership plan and become an email member today.
OK, cool, so let's start at the beginning here.
We have the final words, the final line of this sequence, and we just went over this whole brown sequence.
She delivers her final words right here.
We have our favorite swoosh transition going.
You can see it's negative.
One hundred.
So originally, you know what we're using it for.
Sounds like this.
But in all honesty, the original was this.
So I reversed it because I wanted the intro of the sound to be longer, I want it to be short versus.
Right now that in a sense, you can reverse your sound effects to either bring, you know, this part
to the beginning of or to the end.
It's a really cool way to do it.
So I wanted a little bit more lead in the use of this sound specifically to go into our new song, which
is right here.
Each one of these twists and we're using the same technique of bringing our sound to the forefront right
here, dropping down the audio just as the vocals are coming in.
And, you know, you can see this gradual.
We're not doing this where it's just like.
Each one of these.
That's too abrupt.
We want to gradually always be working gradually with sound and music.
Rarely are you going to do any key framing.
It's like sometimes, but very rarely you want it to be as smooth as possible.
Now, we're going to have some sound effects right here and we're going to have more screen caps.
Each one of these.
Oh, and by the way, yeah, we did the same style where we had our audio.
I mean, excuse me, we have our title card right here.
OK.
And then we have a little bit of a B shot behind with very low opacity secondary in the background so
that it doesn't look too plain like that.
But we're adding a little bit of character.
We cut to our screen cap.
You can see there's a pretty consistent zoom in throughout all of these shots.
So if I let it play, each one of these quizzes, premium learning lessons and study guides is going
to give you the tools you need to.
So, yes, we have this subtle kind of zooming in.
That's really nice for each one of these clips just to create a little bit more movement, especially
on this last one right here.
You see, we have like we scroll down that's moving.
I didn't have to add in.
That was actually from being on a website and physically scrolling.
But you see, we have this nice give you the tools you need, kind of pan or tilt down.
So these things are key.
Like the reason I keep repeating is sharing these, because when I do that now, I take it away.
Look at that.
It has not nearly as much of a good vibe.
This is with it, Boonchu.
Right, so these little techniques you use multiple times in one video that build up to a much cooler,
better looking final product and final edit.
Totally transform the way you experience literature.
So if you're ready to get started, you can choose your membership plan and become an annual member
today.
And again, we have this zoom out with her.
I chose to zoom out at the end because we're leaving.
We're ending our sequence.
We're not zooming in like in the beginning of the video where it's like a fun, exciting, exhilarating
kind of intro.
All these beautiful shots, we're ending our video or ending our project.
So what did I do here?
I did a scale out, boom, we're moving away.
And then we have our very simple titles come in and we have the client's logo.
That's right here.
You can see that's originally what it looked like.
What I did was I created a color matte down here at the bottom, and I made it the same exact color
of the logo.
So if I take away the logo, here's the color matte.
If I just have the logo itself.
That's what it looks like.
OK, so caller, Matt, same color as the background of the logo that you can see right here.
And then we have our title.
Now, the logo kind of has a nice little slight blurriness that helps it come in a little bit more elegantly.
So if we take away this blur, you see it's a lot more sharp, but we don't want that for this kind
of scenario.
So at the beginning, I put a fast blur.
We talked about this earlier in the course.
I keyframe it up to 50 percent and then down right here to zero percent, just as it's fading in.
And then let everything else on the fade out.
There's no fast when everything else fades out the same way.
But just to yeah.
Create a little something else, this just kind of does a nice blur fade in Denver today?
And I also did a fade in on our color minute.
So what it does is it kind of comes in from a black screen to the branding color of the client.
Now, if I take that fade in a way and let it play, you'll remember today.
It's just too abrupt to just go to this big purple bluish Barney, whatever kind of color scheme it,
it didn't feel right.
So I added just this little right here you can see it, opacity is at zero percent and it fades in right
there.
It hits 100 percent.
It's become an annual number today.