All right, so before we move forward, I want to just take a moment to watch back the edit that we
have so far, so let's check it out.
Awesome, so there's a few things that stick out to me so far that I want to fix before we move forward.
I think it'd be pretty cool now that we're adding some sound design already.
We have this background audio going on.
We have a filter that we added to this song, which was a high pass filter.
I want to actually take this low pass filter that we didn't use.
I'm going to copy it and I'm going to paste it on to the beginning, because remember, we were going
to use a low pass and it didn't work well because we were underwater.
Well, that's perfect for this intro.
So here's our.
I'm going to paste it here and I want to.
Start everything.
And I'm going to turn it on and I'm going to start it so that it sounds like it's underwater and actually
it would be kind of cool if it slowly came back to normal sounding audio.
Right.
As we made this transition, we have this match cut with the hand touching the water from below the
surface and then the hand touching the water from above the surface.
Perfect opportunity to try and pull off a little bit of a cool audio transition in this moment.
So let's just test this out.
OK, so we got to tweak this a little bit here.
OK.
And I'm going to turn down the intensity by raising up the frequency, I know it's a little confusing
with a low pass filter, but basically the higher this value, the less effect and the less the the
filter is cutting out of the audio.
OK, so still going to need to tweak it a little bit.
Now I'm noticing, because we're cutting so much of the audio, everything to the left of this key frame.
It's kind of quiet.
So I want to create a audio keyframe.
I can do it up here by doing this or I can do it down here by clicking with the pen tool.
Same thing.
But we're going to turn it up and turn it down as this audio filter is getting disengaged.
OK, cool.
Perfect.
So we ended up actually using that filter, that's perfect.
Now that we have that taken care of.
Now, I want to add a little bit of a sound design element to this transition right here to help us
get from track one to track two.