OK.
And so now it is time for us to go back and actually watch our full rough edit for the first time.
So by now you should have your Selex pull your shot, ordering me your overall pacing, no blank black
screens in your edit, and a decently cohesive video that's ready for you to watch with a neutral perspective
as if you were a viewer seeing it for the first time.
OK, so go ahead now.
Pull up your edit, start at the beginning and we're going to play it all the way through.
And we're going to take mental notes here on what sticks out that is working and what sticks out.
That's a little bit more important on what isn't working.
Anything that's distracting, that's a little bit.
Ooh.
OK, now I need to change that or that's really not working or this really isn't going to make it into
the final edit.
You want to sit there and really keep an eye of some squeaky.
You want to sit there and really keep a little mental note, keep track of that.
So in some stuff, that's a little bit more complex.
I personally will start a notes tab on my phone and on my laptop, so I'll go in and let's say Mount
Shasta.
Edit and I'll start a bullet point list of, let's say, for example, 14 seconds, remove shot, and
then, for example, 30 seconds.
You know, writing.
So you can kind of either go through pause and put the notes down or watch it all the way through.
But that's just a little bit of a side protip there that depending on how complex your edit is at this
beginning stage, we're not getting too complex yet.
So with that said, let's really keep track here mainly of the visual elements that need to be changed.
We're going to do another pass together and work more on the audio.
Fine tuning.
But anything that comes to mind, feel free to take a mental note or jotted down in your notes with
the timestamp.
So let's go.
Now that there's a waterfall.
Yeah.
Whenever he has a ready.
OK, cool, so not too bad for a rough edit.
I feel like it gets the point across and hopefully for your edit as well, you're getting the general
gist of what you want to share across your audience.
I think this does for the audience.
You get a few of what Mount Shasta is like, what it's like to get out and immerse yourself in nature
out in this location.
Experience the amazing like waterfalls that they have, all that good stuff.
So there were a few things that really stuck out to me.
The first main one besides the audio was this definitely needs some motion.
This tripod shot at 25 seconds, need some motion.
So I'm going to say add motion.
Twenty five seconds.
Definitely at four seconds.
I want to replace the audio with something a little bit more Chave like and a little bit more, I don't
know, Mystikal versus people just talking in the background.
That's good.
And then as an overall note, that doesn't really need a timestamp, but that I can tell is needed.
Is adding a crossfade of the audio between the different cuts.
So I'm going to add a note in here.
Add audio.
Cross fades.
OK.