So I want you to kind of play your footage while I'm playing mine and we're going to play it through
and we're going to just kind of neutrally watch the edit and we're going to see what catches our eye
or catches our ear that we have a feeling and gives us a feeling that there needs to be something changed
or updated for you.
OK, so what really caught my eye first is we've got a lot of great movement.
We've got a lot of great action in all of these shots.
And when we get to this shot, it's the energy stops.
It's it's two still.
There's really no action going on.
So because we don't want that shot to stand out in that kind of way.
You can have contrast and shots where every shot has a certain look, a certain feeling, and then,
boom, we hit a different shot where we want to really emphasize or make that shot stand out on purpose.
This is not one of those scenarios where we want to break that kind of rule on purpose.
We want to do is make this shot match up with the other ones.
So this will take some experimenting.
So let's first start by highlighting the clip and we're going to go to the effects panel and we're going
to do a scale keyframe here.
We're going to hit the stopwatch to start our keyframe.
And we're going to go to the end of the clip and we're going to try scaling it up.
So I'm going to go from a hundred to, let's say, one O five.
And let's see what that looks like.
So that's a lot better.
I'm liking that.
Zoom in.
Any time you're zooming into something coming closer, you're creating more of a.
I don't put that into words.
You're creating more.
And if someone hands you a photograph and you really like what you're seeing, you're going to like,
oh, yeah.
And you going to pull because you're not going to go like, oh, yeah, put it away for you.
This is really great.
I'm loving this.
So it's just two different feelings that it creates by going into something versus leaving something.
So when we do it scale up, we're creating more action going into the motion.
When we do a scale out or zoom out, we're doing the opposite.
So if we have the zoom in here,
let's go ahead and flip it.
So I'm going to take that final key frame and I'm going to put out the beginning and put the beginning
keyframe at the end.
So now we're going to be moving from one hundred and five for the scale to 100.
Let's see what that looks like.
OK.
I want to undo so we get back to the original.
So as an editor, it's good to remind yourself that if you want more interest, more energy, more intensity
of what's happening in your frame, you can zoom into it.
If you want to feel like that shot is ending or that scene is ending or that part of the video is over.
You can zoom out and create that effect.
Now, if I wanted to create even more intensity or let's say that for some reason this battery was really
important for the storyline or for the video you're working on.
We can scale it up even more.
So instead of one or five, let's hit 115.
So you can see even more of a quicker zoom in.
So as a final kind of thing we can do here, because for this shot specifically and for other shots
that you'll be working with, there's always going to be a point of interest, an object of interest.
It's where the viewer's eye is naturally going to be drawn towards, because this image specifically
has no interest here in the background, not much interest in the foreground for the viewer to be looking
at their eye is going to be drawn to where the movement motion and objects are in the frame, which
is the battery, because we're zooming into the battery, we're creating more of an interesting shot.
But if we want to take things a bit of a step further, we can add a position key frame along with our
scaling zoom key frames that we're doing.
We can change the up and down, up and down side to side movement of our actual video clip.
So I'm going to slide over at the end of our clip, our video to the right, and I'm going to move it
up slightly so that we're kind of actually going to move it down so that we are gradually going into
where the battery is versus just scaling up the center of the image.
We're actually going to where the battery is in the frame.
Let's see that.
So what that does is it makes the focal point of where the viewer is looking even more laser focused
on the part where the camera is zooming into if the camera is zooming into the center of the image.
Yeah, it's going to be some like perspective change or there's going to be some more scaling up of
what's going on in the frame.
But if it's zooming directly into that object that they are probably looking at, it creates even more
of a dramatic effect.