So this first shot catches my eye and this one's a little bit tough.
There's a massive exposure difference with the sun coming in through the window.
What I'm going to do is travel.
What I want to do is go ahead and make a cut here.
And rather than dragging on a new loom, the tree color and bringing down the highlights, what that
would be doing is that would work.
But we're going to be combating the exposure increase that this one's giving and then reversing it by
trying to push it up.
So in this kind of scenario, for this specific type of problem, let's go ahead and cut our adjustment
layer so that we're only affecting this image.
Let's bring down that exposure a few points and let's bring down our highlights.
Let's say negative 30, and we don't need to boost our shadows a whole lot more.
So let's bring that down to 10 and say play is much better.
OK, great.
This one didn't need a big this one did not need that much of a boost.
It already had radio.
Oh, man, I can't talk.
So this one really didn't need that much of a boost.
It already had a lot of light going on.
So let's continue.
This is looking nice.
OK, so let's create a cut here, and this one needs a lot of help.
So I'm going to bring up the exposure.
I'm going to bring up the highlights.
Okay.
That's looking way better, we can't even bring up these highlights.
Let's go to 100.
Now you can see something that's starting to happen here when I'm when I'm increasing the exposure on
this image.
It's very subtle, but there is a 10 light purple that we have in the whites.
So the white balance was pretty different.
And the coloring in these two rooms is the same colored walls.
But these lights are a different color temperature.
The daylight and these warm lights mixing into this room is creating very tan walls.
This is creating very almost a purple light, light, light, light, light purple because of the lighting
is different in here with this green almost yellowish.
This is more of a green light that we have coming up here.
So that's a bit of an issue.
It's not the end of the world.
But what we want to do is to kind of try to blend these colors a little bit better so that we have more
of a cohesive work.
So quick way to do that is I'm going to bring up the temperature.
It's bringing up the four points.
OK.
A little bit better if that's not doing the trick.
What we can do is go down to our creative tab and we can selectively change the color of the highlights.
So the bright parts of the frame are now getting pushed to the blue.
And we can selectively change our shadow, which is changing the color of the dark parts of the frames,
the frames selectively.
So it takes what you have up here a step further and allows for you to only change specific parts of
the frame, depending on their quality of light, depending on their amount of exposure.
So because we want to get this a little bit more tan, let's see how it looks if we bring up the tan.
I'm pushing this more to the yellow.
On the highlights, so the highlights would be walls, these would be bright.
These would be dark.
So if I were to change the shadow on this image, I would be changing the color of the dark part so
that plant would start to go blue and all the other dark parts.
So that's looking better.
Let's bring in even a little bit more tan.
OK.
And a little bit more highlight, because this is still looking a little bit dull for my eyes, so let's
go to 120.
Even boost this up to one point nine.
OK, that's good enough for now.
Let's keep moving.
OK.
We have these.
So this looks good, but we have this one.
It's a little bit too tan.
So I'm going to bring the temperature down negative five and I'm going to boost these a little bit more
light.
So I'm going to go one point two, OK?
And what I'm also seeing here is, is a lot of saturation in this one compared to this.
So I like the colors and the amount of saturation of this one.
This is looking to saturated.
So sometimes you actually want to bring your saturation down to match some of your other images.
OK, let's try that.
Ooh, much better.
OK, so before we had it like this to that, it was very yellow to a nice white.
Now we have it nice white across both of these images.
OK, this all looks great.
OK, and we need some help here, so let's go and let's bring up the exposure one point.
Bring up the highlights.
Let's say 30 points and boost the shadows.
Let's say 30 points as well.
Before?
After.
Hmm.
OK.
So what I'm seeing is I like the exposure of these two bathroom shots, these two.
But it gets a little bit dark and a little bit dull with these bedroom shots.
So I'm going to create two cuts.
I mean, go here and I'm going to continue to boost.
Let's go to the highlights, the 70.
OK.
And let's go here and let's do the same.
Great.
Now we're to the outdoor pool area.
Let's bring up the exposure point five and the highlights 60.
And the way I'm deciding, you know, how much to bring these up is I've been doing this for a while,
so I know soon as I look at the image, I got a feeling for the amount of increase or decrease in whatever
parameter it's going to need, and you will start to develop that same exact sensitivity.
So now these are starting to pop.
Now I'm going to increase our saturation.
Bring that up.
OK.
Looking good.
OK, cool.
Yeah, that's our transition scene that we're going to get to.
Okay.
Now we have all this nighttime stuff and this is dark.
Oh, geez.
So we're going to bring up the exposure one point five.
And let's bring it to highlights.
Let's say 70.
And now this last shot, it has an overlay under it or a graphic under it, so we're not going to be
able to pop over this adjustment layer because it's going to affect this.
So, for example, if I drag this adjustment layer on top, you see what we're doing.
We don't we love and we really enjoy.
Right.
We have a perfect exposure, everything on here.
So what I'm going to do is on a copy, the filter on this adjustment layer, go directly to this clip
and hit paste so that we're not going to be affecting what's underneath it, which is our title card.
Now, this can use some more exposure and it's a little bit purple.
So I'm going to counteract that by bringing down the tent, which boosts the greens.
The more I bring down the tent, the more it's going to take out the purple.
We just want to do a little bit negative for.
Great, so now we have the exposure's everything is equalized, we've done our color correction across
our entire editing timeline, and in the next video lesson, I'm going to show you how to do a really
cool custom transition between these two similar shots from day to night.