And one thing I actually wanted to add before wrapping up this lesson is to kind of summarize this idea
of continuity and compressing time.
So let's take a look at continuity.
This idea of continuity ensures that your video has matching position of objects in your frame space,
a.k.a. where you're shooting and time, a.k.a. the flow of normal time.
So in most videos, the goal is to create a smooth flow of space or location, even when parts of your
film are not necessarily even shot in order or at the same time.
So what we're going to talk about is can be a little bit tricky.
Now, if we break continuity or compress time on a dialogue scene and characters in your video start
skipping forward, in the words that they're saying, instead of saying the whole sentence from front
to back, they say the first word and you edit to the last word.
That's not going to make sense.
That's not a proper break in continuity, and that's not a proper way to compress time in your edit.
In that scenario, this exact principle would actually be distracting and bring down the quality of
your video.
But in other scenarios, we can use this technique to skip forward in time and purposefully break continuity
to create an effect.
So if we just look at the first few shots of the montage we just created.
This is the perfect example of a scenario where it makes sense to break continuity.
There's information that simply doesn't need to be shown here.
That's why we skip ahead.
So one of the beauties of film is that twenty four hours in the film or video world doesn't have to
equal.
Twenty four hours in real life.
So if we take the same exact shot without any breaks and continuity, without any compressing in time
and just play it as it was in real life, let's see what the clip looks like.
OK.
Not a whole lot to talk about there.
Right, but I think it's pretty clear your goal is to find those moments where you can bend the rules
and use your blade tool, use your edits to enhance your footage and create something that wasn't there
originally.
Now, the techniques aren't going to be one size fits all for every single video.
It's about your discernment that you're starting to really cultivate from this course, and that's how
you're going to be able to make the right decisions in all of your future edits.