Now we can just have it like this with the sound.
But I really feel like it's missing something.
This whole area is really full of Saland.
And when we cut to this at the end, it's just kind of feeling boring.
So we need some kind of sound effect here.
So I'm going to go and grab a kind of swoosh sound effect.
This is going to make the ending a lot more definitive.
So it's just a standard high hat.
But if I reverse this highet, it's going to be like.
OK, so that's going to make this ending way more definitive.
And I already kind of know this is going to be too slow.
Just by hearing it when we just played it, someone to speed up 160 percent.
And let's see.
OK.
Cool.
Looks pretty good.
So without.
Kind of boring.
And with.
Perfect.
So just in a few minutes, we put together an ending title card for our promo video that gives information
about our client or our personal project about where the viewer should go, and that is the purpose
of the promo video.
So now I'm going to export this video.
We'll watch it back together and we will see our masterpiece.