Let's go ahead and duplicate our top clip and let's take off our cross dissolve and let's zoom out here
and let's create a.
Mask, so I'm going to hit the square and the mask under opacity to create a new masking layer.
And now we can actually scale this up.
So if you can see here what this is doing is now we can do something interesting.
So I'm going to turn off our crossfade and I'm going to only focus on what we're doing with the mask.
Now, if I turn up this feathering and what we have now is this overlay shot of where we're going to
transition to only appearing at this really cool part of the image, that actually makes a lot of sense
for this kind of thing.
So masks are really great for selectively adding certain elements in parts of your frame that you can
like frame things inside of doorways, inside of windows, inside of a coffee mug, whatever creates
a frame around it.
That's a good time to mask and use that natural part of the image that's already framed and create something
cool editing wise.
So let's go ahead and start to keyframe our expansion.
This is going to tell the editing software how much to spread out the mask that we already have.
So I'm going to hit it at zero at the very beginning and go here and go to, let's say, 100 percent.
And then what that does is that kind of style of transition.
Now that's looking a little bit cheesy.
So let's go ahead and feather this out as much as we can.
OK.
And let me adjust some of where our mask starts.
This way, the feather is just going to equally fill the entire frame and it doesn't have to be perfect,
but let's go ahead and fix that.
Turn this down.
And let's go ahead and add a fadin.
Now, because, like, for example, the sky disappears and it kind of creates a really big shift,
I think what we can do here is duplicate this mask layer.
Let's go ahead and delete this mask.
Let's turn off this layer below it real quick and let's try something.
So let's create a new mask and let's drag it to the top of our image now.
I'm going to scale this down so I can, you know, move this mask around properly.
And let's go ahead and take off this cross dissolve.
So now what you can see is we have just the top of our nighttime image.
I'm going to feather this out just a bit.
Bring this mask down.
And now that doesn't look so good, but there's something we're going to do here.
Let's go ahead and create some keyframes with our mask layer.
So I'm going to go to mask path.
I'm going to go to the beginning.
I'm going to hit a key frame.
And I'm going to drag this all the way over here.
And let's create this a little bit bigger.
And let's go to where we want our edit to start coming into frame.
And let's go to about here.
And we know we're going to feather this, so we got to create a little bit of a bigger mask.
And so now what we have, is it all so it doesn't look so good right now, but this is going to create
a lot more depth by having two different parts of the frame transition into our image at slightly separate
times.
OK.
Yeah, trust me, edge feathering is everything.
It makes such a big difference.
So, OK, let's just fix this and now drag this to the end.
And we need to fix this.
OK, so it's not perfect.
We don't want to obsess over the little bit of frames, but we just want the overall transition to look
cool.
OK.
And now we can even feed this one in and turn on the layer below it.
So it could use a little bit of fine tuning, but it's still a lot more unique than just a simple crossfade.
Now, that's a great way to use masks in different parts of your image to overlay and bring in a shot
slowly and in a much more stylized way.