Yes.
So let's go ahead and find out how we can end this track, we want this view and around this one and
a half minute mark.
Because if we don't end it here, we're not going to get a chance to end it for a while.
As you could see, the track is going to go for another, you know, two and a half minutes.
So let's find our mark where we want to have this ending.
Boom, right there, right where I put the marker.
OK.
Now what we can do is go to the end of the track and grab the ending, and we're going to kind of splice
these two things together.
The.
OK, so right about here.
Boom.
It's honestly a little bit of a weird ending.
So we're going to have to get creative.
There's like this weird bup bup bup, bup, bup, bup, bup.
We don't want that because that's not in the previous part of the track we're actually using.
So it's getting a real feel real funky if that comes out of nowhere.
And then there's just kind of a weirdness.
Yeah, it kind of sounds distorted, but not in a bad way, just in a stylized way that the artist that's
just how they created the track.
So it's going to be a little bit harder for us to do this, but we're going to make it work.
Now, let's sync these two up so that the endpoint here is synched up with this beat that we can see
right here.
OK, now let's go ahead and cut, and we don't want to have an abrupt ending, actually, let's go ahead
and feed this down so that we still get that final beat.
OK.
And we can kind of fade this one into.
We might actually want to try to bring it in right there.
So let's bring that in.
It's OK.
It's going to take a little bit of massaging, so let's go ahead and just bring the volume down a little
bit.
There's this high had to go slow and the abrupt stopping of that high hit high hat is what's making
this transition a little abrupt.
So let's kind of see if we can repurpose this high hat that we.
OK, we might be able to do something here, so the pitch is different.
That's lower and this is a higher pitch.
That the short.
OK.
So since the picture's different, I'm going to go ahead and speed this one up, just a touch.
And I think this kind of reverb is going to smooth out the transition between because this one, this
ending the end of the song is really kind of hard to work with.
OK, so not so bad for what we're working with, that's really not too bad.
I'm just going to scoot over this, Phil, or sweep that we have.
Oh, there we go.
Let's hear it again.
Perfect.
OK, now we can end our video just in that minute and a half mark.
So now let's find what footage we want to go right here for this last bit.
We got plenty of this kind of footage.
Let's go ahead and get this out of the way.
Let's see what else we have.
Oh, yeah.
I want to get some filmmaking stuff in here for sure.
So let's drag that in.
Hopefully this is going to line up.
Oh, yeah, I like it.
OK, we don't really need this final one, I'm thinking for this ending.
We can have a title card that has my website because.
Yeah, with a demo reel, you want to end it with some kind of call to action, because the purpose
of it is for someone to see it and for them to do something afterwards, whether that's higher, you
buy your product, follow your account, share the video, whatever it is.
So we're going to end this demo reel with a call to action.