So I hope you've been enjoying this process, putting your own edit together, and I hope that it's
been something that's been on like your hard drive of your phone space has been needing to get edited
into something interesting.
So the next step that we're going to focus on here is really to start to refine our audience.
Now, this is going to start to really bring everything together, and it's going to make the blending
in between our shots a lot more linked in and linked together.
So there's a few different ways, two main ways that we can kind of lend our audio together.
And let's take a look at the first way here.
So if we select our audio in our timeline and we go to the effects tab here just by scrolling over to
effects and we type in Crossfade, it's going to give us these audio transitions.
OK.
It's going to give us the ability to do a constant game, constant power, which are basically the same
thing.
It's the amount of curve that it's transitioning or cross fading in between two clips.
And then an exponential fade is going to have a very steep drop off exponentially.
So I wouldn't worry too much about the type of curve you're dropping on this.
The basis is the same.
So let's go ahead and do the constant power here.
Drop it in and let's see what that sounds like right out the gate.
So that's one way to do it.
For me personally, this is the quick, easy way to do things when it comes to audio transitions.
I personally don't like doing it that way.
So I'm going to show you another way to do it.
OK.
What I like to do is layer things, because this you don't have too much manual control over how long
the feed is over here.
And it can be a short fade over here between two clips.
I'm crazy.
And I like to have that type of control.
So what I'm going to do here is I'm going to start pulling together these tracks on different layers
of the timeline.
OK.
So all I'm doing here is highlighting the audio portion of one of my clips, and I'm dragging it down
to the layer below.
OK.
And you can see I'm alternating these layers between the two.
That way I can create more of a slope from one to the other by basically doing the same thing that a
filter will do.
But I'm doing that process manually.
Now, the next step to really get this done is to highlight all of your clips.
And you want to separate the audio from the video, because if I try to drag this over, it's attached
to the video layer, as you can see, whatever I do with the audio.
The video follows.
That's fine and well until you want to start refining just the video and just the audio.
So what we have to do is unlink those two things so that we can have a little bit more control manually.
And the best way to do that is to select a video clip where you want to separate the audio and video
so you can control them separately and hit command l.
OK.
That's the shortcut in premier.
And that is going to d link our selection.
The other way to do that is to click the linked selection icon right here in the timeline.
This is going to do the same exact thing.
Both of these are linked.
If I tap that now, I can control them separately, which is what we want to do in this situation.
OK.
So I'm going to do that for all my clips in the timeline.
So there's two ways to do that as well.
I can highlight all the clips and hit command.
Well, now they're separated or I can hit command, eh?
Which, eh, for all highlights, all the clips in the timeline.
So it would be command a boom.
Everything is highlighted.
Command L, boom.
The audio and the video files are now separate.
So now we move on to manually overlapping these.
And I'm going to kind of drag this around a little bit so we can see things better here.
I'm going to pull this up.
I'm a shrink that down.
So now we can kind of see our audio files a little bit more.
Now, when you're working on the video, you want to be able to see the video clearly so you can move
your layout of your editing software in a more appropriate way.
That's best for you to see it clearly when you're working on the audio.
You know, you don't really need to see the video as much.
So you can maximize the view of your audio.
OK.
But what I'm going to do is drag these to overlap.
I'm going to hit P, which is the pen tool, which is going to allow for me to create key frames for
the audio layer.
OK.
Like I said, this is the man we're doing manually what a crossfade is doing automatically.
But we want to be good editors that have control over on editing software, and this is how we do it.
So I hit P.
This brings up the pen tool.
And wherever I click on the volume line of our audio files, that is where it's going to create a key
frame.
And I can now create a fade.
So take a listen.
OK.
And the reason I do this is because I can manually drag.
And create a short fade or a longer fade.
OK.
And have more control over how quickly the two audio clips are blending together, which is really important.
OK, so let's take a listen.
That's not too bad.
OK.
So I feel there's a little extra space there that we don't need.
So I just scooted everything over.
And.
I'm going to drag this clip over it, pee for the pen to create a key frame.
And then create another keyframe at the beginning to create this.
Fade in.
OK, let's take a listen.
OK, and we're going to fade this out.
And the more we drag, the audio fade out under the next clip, the more they're going to kind of blend
together and the more they're going to kind of blur where the cutting physically or visually happens.
When you bring in the audio of the next clip, it leads in to the cut to show you what the next clip
is.
So sometimes the clip comes into abruptly.
That might mean that you need to fade the audio of that clip that's coming in sooner so that you're
giving the audience more of a heads up of what's happening next.
OK, we're going to do the same process here, dragging over the audio, creating a crossfade.
Dragging over the audio, creating a crossfade.
Way better.
So you see how that happens there.
Those really seamlessly blend together.
Now, if we go to our backup and we have that same exact cut.
It looks like the map, the cut just doesn't match visually.
Why?
Because the audio is telling the viewer what to prepare for, what to feel, what to think.
And really, it gives a layer of, you know, how they interpret what they're seeing visually.
So let's look at it.
Looks abrupt and out of place.
And let's go back to what we're working on here.
Perfect.
OK.