So we have this transition that we've been working on.
Now, what I'm going to do is highlight both of these clips and I'm going to show you how to bring these
into after effects to create a little bit more of a stylized look and have a little bit more control.
So I'm going to right click those clips hit open with an after effects composition that's going to automatically
transfer these to video files into an after effects comp.
And I'm going to title this showcase video transition.
OK, great.
Now we have both of our shots.
So what we're going to do is kind of a similar process of dragging over our shots so that there's more
of an overlap.
Now, I'm going to go to this top layer and go to effects and presets, which is over here.
And I'm going to type in Luma Key.
I'm going to drag this on to our top layer, and what it is going to do is just like in a premiere,
it's going to remove our top layer.
But the great thing about after effects is that it allows for you to feather, which, you know, the
feathering is key, as you know, by now, feather this effect.
So let's start first by creating a key frame of the threshold.
That's how much the effect is applied to our clip.
And then I'm going to go to where I want the transition to end, roughly about right here.
And I'm going to turn the threshold all the way up.
Now, you can see there's some part of the image that's not getting removed.
Now, we're going to fix this with a similar masking overlay kind of technique that we were doing in
premiere.
But let's start by also adding an edge.
Feather feathering is our best friend.
This is going to create a lot more of a clean look.
Oh, look at that.
It's already looking pretty cool.
So let's go ahead and create an endpoint by hitting the letter B, create an outpoint by hitting the
letter.
And I'm going to hit command zero to start at the preview.
And let's check it out.
Oshkosh, OK.
That's looking so good.
OK, perfect.
So just in a few seconds, there is saved a lot of time.
Now, I like the speed of the transition.
You know, it can even go a little bit slower.
Actually, I won't mind that for something like this.
That looks so cool.
You don't want to speed it up too much.
So I'm just going to drag this key frame to start a little bit sooner and end a little bit later.
OK.
Now we have a little bit more time to enjoy this transition.
And what I want to do is duplicate our bottom layer, which is the nighttime, nighttime shot.
And I want to fix this blip, this glitch that happens in the top, because the exposure difference
on this specific image.
The sky is blown out.
So there's no information there.
And the filter, the Lumia key filter doesn't know how to.
It doesn't have any information.
So it doesn't it can't create the effect they were wanting in this part of the frame.
So we're going to have to kind of do that manually.
So I'm going to take our bottom layer to duplicate it, drag it to the top.
Right.
But as you can see now is taking away our effect.
So what we're going to do is turn this off for now by hitting the little icon right there on the left.
And I want to create a mask layer.
So I'm going to zoom out a little bit.
And I want it to come across the screen from here and go, whoosh, similar to what we did in from here.
So what I'm going to do is cue for the mask tool.
I'm going to create a square shaped mask.
I'm going to add a path keyframe at the beginning.
I'm going to go to the end of the clip.
Right.
Is that transitions coming in?
And where I want this to be finished, I'm going to select both of these nodes, these points, and
I'm going to drag it across our clip.
Now, if I turn this layer back on, you're going to see that we've replaced the sky.
So as that comes in, wash.
OK, great.
So now we fix that problem where now our sky comes in gradually before the sky started to come in and
hajjis all of a sudden, Nosik.
So we don't want that.
So, OK, we have this guy coming in gradually.
We duplicated that layer.
Now we're going to use our best friend, which is, of course, the feathering tool.
We're going to feather this up.
I'm going to expand this a little bit.
And now let's see how that looks.
Wash.
OK, cool, so that looks good, there's no glitching, it's it's starting to look really nice, but
honestly, like the sky kind of comes in way too fast.
We want this to feel more elegant.
So let's extend the speed and slow down the quickness of this Skyy transition.
OK, and we can even fade in this guy transition so that this guy doesn't just wipe from white to black,
from white to black, but more comes in gradually.
So let's go to let's say about here.
Let's hit the opacity icon, the stopwatch more hit 100 hundred right there.
And then we'll go to the beginning of our clip.
Go to zero.
Perfect.
So that's a super cool looking transition.
It's gradual, it's elegant, it's clean, it doesn't look over edited.
It allows for us to transition from this daytime shot to this nighttime shot in a way that just looks
cool.
So that's how you do it in After Effects.
This is a great way to transition between shots, using masking to mask out specific parts of your image
and using something like the Luma key filter with our best friend, the edge feathering function to
really blend these two shots together.
And that's the best way to do it.