Now we have this outro right here.
And let's go ahead and drag in.
You know, you can do any kind of title card.
You can go ahead and do it.
You know, the good old fashioned way WW W and your website do with plain text.
We've done that earlier in the course.
You can do it anyway.
For this example, I'm going to use just grab one of my kind of go to motion graphic templates.
Again, you can buy these really easily online or even find them for free by just searching the name
of your editing software and free motion graphic or motion graphic template.
OK.
Now, let's see what we can do to kind of customize this.
I'm going to take this top line and let's say demo reel.
And it looks so much cooler as one word.
Yeah.
And let's face this.
W w w Julian discovers dot com.
So we have my website.
And let's take away the gradient.
We want it to be all white and we can scale it down.
And instead of Demerol, actually, let's make this say.
Port folio, OK.
Boom.
And let's center this.
Scale it up a little bit more and let's see.
OK, perfect.
So I already know ahead of time that I'm going to want to have this cool intro that this template has.
And you can do this same thing about to do with any kind of template or you just redo, do what I'm
about to do with what you created.
Does even have to be a template.
But we're going to duplicate this layer.
And now I'm going to reverse the speed of the copy that we just made.
I'm going to go to the end, which was the beginning.
And it's now the end.
I'm going to cut and I'm going to remove the part we don't need.
I'm going to take our original.
Remove the ending that we don't need.
So now what we have is intro, animation, our text, and then a reverse of the intro, which now becomes
our outro animation.
Perfect.
OK.
I'm loving that.
Now, we can kind of spice up this outro graphic a little bit before we kind of review our edit.
So I know I could kind of use an overlay.
It looks kind of plain.
So let's go ahead and grab some film burns and just get this motion graphic looking a little bit more
unique.
So let's start with this and we'll try to do a little cool, kind of glitchy something here.
So I'm going to drag in this film Burn.
And I'm going to put it in our timeline.
I'm going to change the track mat or the blending mode to screen, which is just going to leave the
light parts of the image and take away the dark parts of the image.
Let's go ahead and delete the beginning.
OK.
Hmm.
We don't need the whole thing.
I don't think we need the whole thing like on Frayne the entire time, so let's just have it at the
beginning.
Yeah.
OK, so let's start it right here and let's make the film burn at its max.
Let's make it right here when it's at its max before it goes back out of the frame.
Let's put this point at the transition between shot one and shot two.
So I'm going to shoot it over.
So it's going to go in more, more boom, less, less, less.
And then we can cut the rest.
Actually, we can cut it right there because we don't need this weird bounciness, it's not looking
too good.
And let's cut in right there and let's use this part for the ending.
So I'm going to take you here.
Boom.
OK, we don't need quite as much.
Let's speed it up, because that doesn't really feel right.
So a go two hundred percent.
OK, let's scoot it forward.
Yeah.
Why don't we put this one over here?
OK.
And then let's put this one over here and yeah, we're going to switch these.
Perfect.
OK.
And it could even used.
I don't know if we can do anything with that.
Let's kind of experiment here.
So I'm going to drop this in and I won't change the Bleaney mode of this to difference.
Now, that looks kind of crazy, but we're only going to have it for like a split second.
Yeah, OK, now we're talking.
OK, I like that.
OK, we don't need it quite so much.
We will take it.
And let's look back at that.
Perfect.
OK.
Loving that.
So just feel a little bit of a, you know, a proper amount of a film burn with the right amount of
blending mode with this animation of our text created a really cool and unique, more dynamic feel.
Let's see what else we can get done in our next lesson.