And if we want to fine tune this even more, we can take these key frames that we created and we can
right click on these key frames.
Right now, they're set to linear.
Linear means right angles.
Right.
It's something that's OK if we do Bezier, I think, as you say, I don't know.
I think it's French, but we can actually smooth those curves.
So rather than say it goes.
So I hope you like that interpretation of it.
But let's right click the key frame, click bezier.
You can see how it instantly makes it more curved.
See that?
OK.
And then we're going to do that same thing on the second keyframe.
Now, what this is going to allow me to do is to drag the little ball and line icon.
So I can really adjust the amount of curve that the keyframe itself is going to have.
So that's really interesting and something to play around with.
And a little bit of a protip just to get your audio design to a further level of really fine tuning
something.
So it's not too much of a drop off, but it of goes I don't know, I keep doing the score, but I think
you understand what I'm trying to say here.
So let's take a listen.
Perfect.
There is.
OK, so let's take a listen to what we got.
Now that is a waterfall.
Yeah.
Okay.
Whenever you guys are ready.
OK, perfect.
So that looks pretty good.
And it's sounding pretty darn good.