So what we're going to do is start by creating an adjustment layer in our project panel hit adjustment
layer.
I'm going to hit OK, because we don't need to change any of these parameters.
We want it to be the same settings as I sequence.
And now I'm going to drag this adjustment layer on top of all of our footage.
I'm going to drag it out, so it's covering the footage and nothing is happening yet until we add another
color correction layer to this adjustment layer.
So now what we can do is globally change the look of all of our shots with one single layer.
OK.
And this is a perfect time to now hop into adding luts or preset looks to your footage.
What we do here is scroll down to our creative tab.
We're going to go ahead and open that up.
And we have our looks function.
OK.
This has a handful more than Annville, actually a Kwanten Ethereum or a veritable plethora and quite
a few preset looks that we can scroll through.
Now, what creates the deciding factor of the look that you go for is the tone of your video.
Now we have kind of a cool, bad -- filmmaker, James Bond ASQ tone here.
So we want something that's punchy and we want something that's maybe a little bit more on the gritty
side with a pretty punchy edit and a really in-your-face song.
So we're not going to want some like emotional blue nighttime feel.
We're going to probably want pretty contrasty.
More of the comic book saturation punching is for this look.
So let's see what does work and let's see what doesn't work.
So here we scroll to the Blue Day tonight preset.
Let's go out and play that.
OK.
It's a cool look, but we're not really looking for this blues and purples because this is not like
a vampire movie like Twilight fans.
So let's find a different look here.
Let's keep scrolling down.
So these have some greenish tones.
Kind of that matrix vibe that we mentioned before.
I'm really looking for a coloring that matches with the tone that we're working with and our musical
track.
That's OK.
Too much greens, I think we're wanting more of a punchy golden here for this kind of edit.
OK, so I like the tone of this, of course, is way too contrasted, and this is God, just way too
much crushing of the blacks, the dark's are too dark.
And it just looks too fake.
So what we can do is change the intensity of our actual preassigned lutt.
So if you go to zero, that's our original footage.
If we start increasing this, then we can see our transformation happening here.
So that's looking pretty dang cool.
Let's put this at 40.
We don't want it to be too saturated and too colored.
So let's see.
Without with, without, with.
And this is a little bit red in a little too orange for my eye.
So what we can do is adjust the temperature.
This is going to change the blue to orange and yellow shift of our image.
So if we have it at zero, we can scoot it down to maybe negative 10.
And this is going to kind of neutralize the overall orange and overall redness that we are having now
if it's still looking a little too red.
We can also change the tint.
Now, the tint, instead of blue to orange or a little bit of yellow, the tint is the greenish to purple.
Now, purple is similar and close to the red in the color spectrum.
But if we go to the opposite side and start increasing the green, that's going to actually balance
out the excess redness in our image.
So this is now having more of a golden feel if we go back to zero.
There's more red if we go to negative 10.
It has more of a slight green.
OK, we don't want to go too far in the green.
But let's say we put that in negative four.
OK.
And everything is starting to look pretty darn good.
If I want to bring a little bit more detail back up from the dark parts of the frame like here, you
can't see any detail in these parts here.
You can see detail in the camera, which is what we want.
That is a little bit dark, I would say.
That could be a little bit brighter.
And this is well, so what we can do is bring up the shadows.
And you can see as I'm bringing out the shadows, we're getting more detail.
Back in the dark parts of the frame, of course, we don't want to put it at 117 here because this is
not the look they were going for.
But if I put this back in zero and I push it up just slightly, let's say 15 points.
You see that shift of where we're getting detail back in these parts of the frame.
We can maybe even go a little bit more.
Let's go 20.
That's going to give us a better overall exposure.
We want our blacks to feel punchy, but we don't want to lose too much detail in our image.
So there's a fine tuned balance as an editor where you want to color correct it.
So look stylized and even better than real life, but you don't want to go too far where when someone
sees it, it's like it's like almost one.
A dish is too salty or too seasoned.
There's a fine balance there.
And that's kind of a final last change here.
We can add a little bit of sharpening.
Now, what this is going to do is going to chris up our image a little bit, because a lot of these
shots, they're a little bit soft.
So they don't have that super clear, crisp clarity that, you know, you really want your videos.
So I'm going to increase this.
Let's try 20.
We want it to be subtle, but it's just basically going to make our footage look a little bit more high
def, a little bit more of a higher resolution.
And I'm really liking that.
So let's see what it's looking like with our music.
And ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba, ba,
ba, ba.
Awesome, so that wraps it up for this part of the learning lesson, where we delve into color correction
and color grading.
I'm like really excited to see your edits and what you put together.
So you'll be able to share that in the student Q&A section.
And I will see you in the next lecture.