Now, there are two things that really stuck out to me.
There's two clips here that the audio from the environment is not working, OK.
It's this first cave clip where it's talking in the background and a lot of footsteps.
And then this final clip when my group is, you know, talking about I don't know where we're going
to have for lunch or whatever we're doing here.
So you'd be surprised at how much of the television movies, videos that you see actually don't have
audio coming from that actual moment of what was being filmed.
A lot of the time the voices are replaced.
A lot of the time, the environment or a sound of the characters making in frame inside what's going
on.
The action is being replaced in post-production.
And a lot of the times.
Yeah, audio is taken out from the actual footage and replaced with post-production sound design.
So what comes out to mind here is I'm going to highlight these two clips so we know what we're working
with here.
And I'm going to make these I want to make these brown so that they kind of stand out against the other
ones.
And it's something that we want to replace.
We can take either the audio from the same clip and try to get a different part of that clip.
Sometimes this happens, let's say you're recording at a I don't know, a church now.
Let's say you're recording at the beach, OK?
And you have your clip and the section of that clip you decide to use for your visual happens to have
not so good audio for that section.
But at other portions of that same exact overall clip, there's really good sound of the waves crashing
the birds or whatever it is that you're looking for, for that specific clip.
Then you can grab that part and put it, even though it's not from that same exact moment in time.
But you can still put it there and no one will know it'll be your little ed secret.
That's option one.
Option two.
Option two is to completely replace the audio from that section completely.
And there's a few different ways you could do that will walk through.
But let's first start with option one to see if for either one of these two clips that we marked that
needed to be updated.
Let's see if we can find a good section for any of those clips.
So let's go to this first one here.
Now, what I'm going to do is I'm going to create a duplicate of what we already have here for this
audio section of this clip.
I'm going to hold alt click, drag it out.
Now we have it over here.
What this is going to allow me to do is to like open it up, take out the edit that we made on it without
messing with anything in our timeline.
Next thing I'm going to do is click on our little key frames here so that the cross fades are taken
out.
And this is going to allow for us to listen to the clip in its entirety in the woliver till we have
to leave, whichever one comes first.
OK, it's sounding like there's really not any good moments in that clip that we can use.
Let's look at our second clip where we want to replace the audio here.
Let's do the same thing.
I can also highlighted, do you command C to copy it?
Move the player head over here and you command V to paste it and then drag out the ends of the clip
and delete the keyframe so that we have the clip in its entirety.
So it's full.
There you have it ready.
That's not going to work either.
So because that's not going to work either.
Let's go ahead and take a listen back to our edit as a whole and see if maybe there's some other clips
we can pull from, for example, this one.
I know has really good sound, so I'm going to grab that and bring it over here.
OK.
I'll pull it out and I'm going to delete the key frames, and actually we know we use this part.
So what I'm going to do is see if maybe later in the clip, which we haven't used, we'll be able to
use for an entirely different clip.
That's pretty good, so I'm going to move that keyframe over here.
Delete the part that we've used previously.
And I'm going to try and see what that sounds like.
Instead of the current audio for our final shot.
I'm going to select this.
Actually, I'm going to mute this entire layer, so that's going to mute the audio that's currently
there and it's going to leave the new audio underneath that we just dropped in playing without the other
audio.
OK.
So I'm going to create a similar crossfade so that these kind of line up a little bit.
And let's see how it fits.
Not bad.
That's not bad.
That's a lot better than.
Yeah.
Okay.
Whenever you guys are ready.
Yeah.
Not bad.
That's sounding pretty darn good.