So there actually is one final edition that I wanted to do before we export this and watch our masterpiece
now.
I've already explained it in previous chapters, but I did go through and add a warp stabilizer filter
to the shots that needed it.
All this footage is pretty dang smooth because it was shot on a gimbal.
So there's just a few little bumps and shakes here and there.
But if you want to know more about the warp stabilizer, how to use it, how to refine it.
Check the lectures in the previous chapters.
But for this lesson, what I wanted to focus on is we did a great job creating our transition.
But if I let it play and I watch it back, you know, there's something missing when there's something
that is kind of a drastic train change or a unique part of the video.
We've learned this before.
And what it is, is that it helps to have an audio cue, an audio sound effects, something that goes
along with the effect or the visual that someone is seeing.
So if we hit play.
Right, so it matches up with a point in the song where the rhythm or the pacing changes, which is
perfect, but it's needing a little something because it's kind of out of the blue.
There's no real there's no special effects in the rest of the video or transitions.
So what we're going to do is we're going to go ahead and find a swoosh audio transition that's going
to help tell the story of this cool transition that we created.
So I'm going to just kind of scroll through and whichever when I do end up using, I'll drop in the
student downloads so that you can also drop it in to your showcase edit.
And I'm just looking for a slow, elegant, like aush kind of transition.
OK, these are all a little bit too fast.
I mean.
Let's try this one.
Let's go ahead and drag this in, so I'm going to take this one.
It's going to need some work.
It's definitely not perfect.
But let's go ahead and drag this in and let's just see.
OK, so we're definitely going to slow this down.
So I'm going to slow it down and say 60 percent.
And let's turn down our music track just a little bit.
And I'm going to slow down even more to 30 percent.
OK, let's turn off our transition.
That's too much.
OK, that's looking and sounding a lot better.
Let's check that out one more time.
OK, and if we want to add even more of a reverb to it, to really kind of fill in and sustain the effect
a little bit more and create a little bit more personality, we can add a studio reverb.
I love the Great Hall preset.
I generally turn the room size like all the way up, turn the decay higher, which makes it last longer.
It's the tail end of the effect.
Turn up the dry, which is the sound effect itself.
And the wet is the effect and reverb layered on top of the sound effect.
We can turn down the dampening, turn down the diffusion.
That means the effect is going to be more sustained as well.
And when you dampen something or you diffuse something, you kind of spread it out, split it up and
make it less.
So we don't want to do that.
Let's now take a listen.
OK, that's pretty cool.
So if you could hear that what happened was a hit play.
That's a little bit too long so we can turn our dampening and diffusion up a little bit, bring our
room size down, bring our DeKay down, so it's going to shorten the amount of the effect.
OK, now.
Let's see that we want to sustain this effect and we don't want it to end abruptly at the end of this
clip.
We can duplicate the clip, turn the volume all the way down, select our studio reverb.
Copy it and remove it from this effect right now, it's going to make sense in a second.
I'm going to highlight both of these clips.
I'm going to right click.
I'm going to nest these clips.
Now we have the same exact sound effect, but extended the clip.
And if I paste back the studio, reverb back on.
Now, let's listen.
It gets to extend without dropping away, because the clip did not end what we did, there was a little
bit of protip, oh my God, the pro tips was a little bit of a pro tip to extend the clips so that all
of a sudden the reverb
doesn't just end abruptly.
So now let's hear it with our soundtrack.
Perfect.
Now, what I'm going to do is export our final edit and we're going to get a chance to look back at
what we did.