Now, as I move forward through this edit as well, we're pulling Selex on all of these parts, gathering
all these great clips.
And I got to a part in the footage where we have this really cool camera movement, where I'm going
from the handheld recorder, and we pull back.
Go to the microphone.
That's perfect.
But I will say there are scenarios when you might want to reverse the direction or orientation of the
cliff.
And so we haven't dropped in my voice over yet.
But let's say in my voiceover, I'm talking about the microphone and how the microphone is attached
to the zoom.
That's great.
But this shot shows the zoom and then it shows the microphone, which isn't really that bad.
But I want to show you a little trick that we can do in that kind of situation where I'm going to duplicate
these clips.
So we have our old version here.
And I'm going to highlight both of these clips that normally play from the zoom handheld recorder.
And then we're going back and then the microphone comes in focus.
So we're going to highlight these clips.
We're going to right click and we're going to choose speed and duration.
And here's the trick.
In this setting and in this panel, we can actually reverse the speed of the clip.
So we're not going to slow things down.
We're not going to speed things up.
But we're going to make the ending, the beginning and the beginning.
The end.
So I'm going to click that function.
Hit, OK.
And now what we have is this same great shot.
But we're moving from the microphone, being in focus and doing a push in.
To the handheld recorder.
And let's see the second version of that.
Where we go past the microphone again and do a really nice push and shot to the zoom.
So that is just a really handy trick that you can use to better make your visuals cue up to what's going
on in your audio.
So I'm really excited to see you implement that little ninja trick into your future at its.