So it's time for this little kind of extra hack that I wanted to share with you, which is perfect for
being able to have the thumbnail that you want for your video.
For example, when you upload to Facebook or Instagram, you can't go and export another thumbnail like
you can on YouTube where you have your video that's there.
And then you say, I want to choose my thumbnail, upload the thumbnail, and then boom.
No, no, no.
Some platforms don't allow you to do that.
They only allow for you to choose a specific part of the video itself to grab a thumbnail from.
So there's two ways to create a thumbnail and place it that will go over the fix that fixes this annoying
problem, but then also allows for you to agree.
I cannot do this right now, man.
OK.
That also allows you to create really great looking thumbnails, which is very important for your Instagram
grid and feed.
So let's first start with option number one, and I'm going to scrub through our video and I'm going
to look for a really cool moment that sums up the whole video.
OK.
That is kind of cool.
There's some action going on.
You can see he's loading a battery into a camera.
I'm not like in love with it, but it is a potential.
So I'm going to add a marker right here by hitting M.
Now you can see our marker is right there.
And let's keep scrubbing forward.
That's OK.
That's kind of cool.
That gets my attention, so I'm going to hit him right there as well.
So we have two options.
So what I'm going to do is go to where our marker is.
I'm going to right click our clip and I'm going to click Add Frame Hold.
Now we have a still image of this really cool shot.
OK, I'm going to enlarge our timeline here so we can see a little bit more.
And I'm going to drag that still image to the very beginning of our sequence.
Now, before we move to the beginning of the sequence, we need to fix this right here, because we
just created the frame hold moved it, and it's leaving a blank empty space.
All we have to do is simply drag our original clip to replace what we just did with the normal video.
And we can scroll to the beginning of our video now and look what we have, a really cool still image
at the beginning of our clip.
Now, what we want to do is make this still image only one single frame.
That way, Instagram and Facebook.
We can select this part of the video as the main cover photo, still image, thumbnail, whatever you
want to call it, of the entire post.
So we're at the beginning.
I'm going to hit the right arrow just to go one frame over, grab my blade tool, click and remove the
excess so that this is only here for that one split second.
That's option number one.
Option number two.
If you have other shots and photos from your shoot that wasn't in camera from the video that we've been
working with, you can grab that from your, you know, camera or from your phone, which is what we're
going to do in this circumstance.
So I'm going to open up my phone.
I'm going to go to my photo album from this shoot.
OK, I'm going to take this photo.
This behind the scenes shot that kind of also tells the story of what the video is about.
And I'm going to share.
And I want to airdrop it to my laptop.
You can text it to yourself, email it to yourself, send it anywhere you like.
But personally, airdrop is the easiest.
And now we're going to go to our downloads folder on our laptop, and we're going to drag in that still
image.
And we're going to kind of do the same thing here.
We're going to drag it and we're going to go to the very beginning of our sequence.
Drag it in.
We're at the very beginning.
Go over one frame.
Delete what we don't need.
And now what we can do is scale up our image to match our frame size.
So I'm going to click the photo.
Go to the effects control scale of the image.
So you can see an issue that we're running into here.
We can't fit all of what we want while filling the entire frame.
We can't fit me and the subject into our shot.
So if you're familiar with the way platforms like Instagram use thumbnails only in a square one by one
aspect ratio.
Let's bring it up so we can see what we're talking about.
You can see that it only shows a thumbnail in that square ratio.
But if I actually go to one of the posts, it's not a square.
It's actually vertical or it can be horizontal.
Same with this clip.
The thumbnail itself is square.
But the post is a different aspect ratio.
So we have a very similar thing going on here with our post.
So the way to get around that and kind of ninja your way through this problem, we want to fit everything
in our frame.
And we also want it to be framed nicely when a platform like Instagram cuts off the top and bottom of
our frame.
And the way around that is to select our beginning thumbnail.
Scale it down.
OK.
Frame it up the way that we want.
And then we're going to duplicate this image.
OK.
So I'm going to hold alt drag it up.
Now we have two copies, one on top of the other of our beginning photo.
And I'm going to click the bottom layer.
And now I'm going to scale up this bottom layer and to blend these two images together.
I'm going to go to the effects tab type in fast blur.
What this is going to do is blur out the pixels of the background image, which creates a lot more of
a smooth overall photo because the colors are the same in these two photos, because they're the same
photo.
One is just scaled up differently.
So, of course, things don't line up perfectly.
But the coloring, the contrast and the exposure of the image is the same.
All we did was blur the back.
Background so that we're filling the entire frame with the same image, but we're keeping the framing
and the aspect ratio that we want for the final product when it's living on a social media platform
to be what we want.
So now we have two options.
We have this first one as our thumbnail image, or we have an actual still screen grab from our video
itself as the other alternative thumbnail.
Now, you can also to take things one step further, stylize this beginning thumbnail the same way we
colored all of our footage in our edit.
I'm going to drop on and luminary color effect and we can even drop on the same.
Lutt reset as the actual edit turned down the intensity.
So that it matches a little bit more the vibe of the actual video, so that's without the color correction
and with.