And we are just about done pulling our Selex here, and I wanted to just share a little bit of an insight
when it comes to choosing where to begin your shot.
Now, on this example, you can actually see here that we're physically starting our shot where it's
out of focus.
And what's in focus is technically behind the main focal point of what we're showing, which is this
piece of equipment.
You can clearly see the logo.
You can clearly see the title and the name of the equipment.
And we're actually starting the shot just before we're pulling it into focus.
Now, on paper, this would make no sense.
But visually, as you can see, it's actually a bit of a nice introduction into this shot.
It has a little bit more depth, this shot.
There's no intro focus.
There's no there's nothing at the beginning of it that kind of introduces what the viewer's looking
at.
Now, if we come back to this shot, we have a nice little introduction.
So you can do this in a few different ways of a different shot types.
You can do a rack focus, just like what we're seeing here.
You can also do what's called a reveal shot, where something in the frame is covering and slowly moves
out of the way of where the viewer is going to be looking.
So let's see what that looks like.
As you can see, we have some foreground and it smoothly moves out of the way as our camera moves to
the main focus point of this, the main focus point of this image.
So on paper, like I said, again, this is another scenario where it doesn't make a whole lot of sense
to start the shot here from everything that we've learned up to this point.
This would kind of be breaking the rule of finding the endpoint, finding the outpoint, not having
any extra space or information that doesn't need to be there if it's not offering value.
So technically, this is a little bit of a rule breaker, but as you can see, offers depth and a little
bit more of a dynamic image.
So let's keep looking at some of the examples here.
So on this next shot, as we're setting up, we have the foreground camera in focus.
And we do a rack focus, go to the rest of the setup that's in the room.
So this is a perfect other example.
I can actually there's a bit of an extra wobble in here.
That right there is when we start.
So let's actually scoot that over.
Yep.
A lot more depth versus if I just started the shot from here.
Of course, everything in frame looks great.
But adding that extra few bit of frames consciously is what's giving these shots, that little extra
oomph.
Now, I think I cued up a few more examples here as well.
So as I was pulling these Selex.
I decided to keep those few extra introductory frames of these clips where I'm actually moving, what
I'm showing to the audience into frame, or they're coming into focus just as the clip comes on.
So as you can see, a little bit of movement there with my hand and the item that I'm holding coming
into focus, adding a little bit of that depth versus just starting right here.
We get a little extra moments.
Not too much, though.
Not too little.
Just a little bit.
Same with here.
I move the item into frame.
Same with that.
There's a little bit of a rack focus and with this as well.
That is just a little extra insight as you're building your skills, getting to these more intermediate
level techniques and ideas.
That's just something I want to add in there.
Now we're almost done pulling all the Selex.
And I'm excited because this is where things are really going to start to get interesting.