OK, so I'm super hyped because we just finalized and finished this entire chapter and we finished our
entire showcase edit, so we got into a lot more of the refinement, tips, techniques, strategies
for creating a more cohesive but, you know, elegant video.
It doesn't have to always be crazy suche transitions and montages.
It can be cleaned.
Video that simple is sometimes more effective.
So what I want to do now is sit back, relax and watch the final final.
I was getting the same video and edit and said Aido final edit that we created together.
So let's check it out.
Who they they look good, right, super clean.
And I really liked how the final product turned out.
So I'm really excited to also see the edit that you were creating during this whole process when we
were learning these kind of new, more refined techniques.
Now, here's just a mini recap of some of the stuff that we learned in this chapter.
We learned how to use shot arrangement to tell a story where no story was originally there.
Wow.
The footage was shot.
So we show the story of the exterior of the house walking up, walking through the doorway, the experience
that the person would have if they were actually there.
Then we got into editing down our music.
We took a three and a half minute track, I believe, and edit it down to a minute and a half while
still retaining the main beats, the main introduction, the bridge in the more laid back part and the
more excited parts of the video or of the track and, you know, tailored it custom to fit the video
that we were working on.
Then we made some intro title cards for that very beginning introductory screen, and then we made some
lower thirds title cards for other important information that we wanted to convey to our audience.
And then we went into creating an ending motion graphic is where we use after effects to create a much
more stylized and high production value motion graphic with a title, with text and with animation.
We did a few more things.
And then we also added a custom transition, a really cool day to night transition with a more beginner
to intermediate version inside of Premiere or your main editing software, and then a slightly more
advanced version where there's more ability to change the parameters inside of after effects.
We also added a little bit of a mini sound design part where we added that swooshed transition and then
we finalized our edit, did our color correction, and exported our final video.
So like I said, export share your edit, you edit.
OK, that's supposed to say your edit.
So yeah, go ahead and export and share your edit in the studio Q&A so you can get feedback from myself
and from the other students that does it for the end of this entire chapter.
I was super excited to see you in the next chapter where we're going to be diving more into even more
advanced editing techniques and principles.