Let's say we're super happy with that.
We're ready to export it.
We're going to save our project.
We're going to make sure our endpoint is set at the very beginning and we're going to make sure our
outpoint is at the end.
We're going to hit.
Oh, it's perfect.
I'm going to go up to file.
Go down to export media, make sure short two, six, four is clicked, go to presets.
Now this is going to a mobile device and we want the resolution to be the same as the sequence itself,
which is 10 ATP.
So we're going to click that and we're going to go down to our audio tab.
Make sure our bit rate is set to the highest setting.
We're going to make sure our basic video settings are matching to get rid of these black bars.
We're going to match our actual sequence by hitting match source.
We're going to render at maximum video depth.
Use the maximum render quality.
And finally, we're going to choose our destination that our at is going to go to.
And the name of the export itself.
So in our original hyp edit folder that we created at the very beginning, many, many moons and days
ago, we're going to create a new folder there called this the exports folder, where all of our different
exported versions will reside.
And we're going to go hyp edit, let's say insta stran post version one save.
And we're going to hit export.
Now we have our final video here.
We have our thumbnail at the very beginning.
And we have the final product.
And if we wanted to send this to something like Instagram, we can queued up, go to the cover and it
always default chooses the very first frame, which is perfect.
And we have a really cool edit with a nice looking thumbnail ready to be shared online with the world.
That does it for this extra little bonus lesson that I want to throw in here with a little extra ninja
technique hack for all your future projects.
I will see you in the next video lesson.