Whoo!
OK, so I wanted to take a second to just recap what we just did because we went pretty deep there.
This is a pretty in-depth YouTube video, and probably most of your YouTube videos aren't going to have
this.
Many cutaway shots are not going to have this much B roll.
But it's good to dive into a project like this so you could see how complex things can get.
So that way when you're doing a three minute video with a few cutaway shots and maybe one location with
one music track.
It's really easy to do compared to what we've been putting together.
With that said, let's take a look at the screen cap here to see where we are now in our edit.
We've whittled everything down from, you know, four hours, I think it was three or four hours of
footage to now having just a little bit around 30 minutes of footage.
And what I did is organize the main parts in their own category and a really good way to do this.
Like I was mentioning, this is a pretty complex edit.
So I know going into this that there's going to be multiple chapters where I'm walking someone through
step by step process on how to create their own filming space.
I mapped out ahead of time that that's like 10 steps or 11 steps.
So in here, I translated what I had written down to text form, as you could see right here, which
I'll show you how to do in a second.
But that way, all my footage that goes in the right step is in chronological order, and it has the
title of the step that the footage belongs to.
So to do this, let's say we want to start from scratch here.
I'm going to move this out of the way and I'm just going to delete this.
So I'm going to hit T.
Which brings up the text tool.
And I'm going to type in chapter and actually three.
So I'm going to type in four.
Create your purchase.
It's want to center it.
And then I'm on.
Drag it down.
OK.
And then we can stretch it out so that it's filling all the footage and then we simply label it.
And I'm definitely a color person.
I learned with color.
I get organized with color, which is easy, easier for me.
So when I see this timeline, this is like hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of shots, but they're
more easily labeled.
You can navigate to OK.
Step 11, here's where we are.
So now that we've got that situated, we are caught up.
We undo this real quick.
Yes.
Now we've got that situated.
We're caught up with where we are in the edit.
Now, what I'm going to do in the next lecture is drop in the voiceover.
And now we're actually really, really going to start getting into the nitty gritty of the editing process
for this YouTube video.
So I will see you in the next lecture.