So for the final portion of really enhancing the video side of this section, I want to go over one
more thing that we're going to go even more detail in throughout this course, which is color correction
and color grading.
Now, because you've been working with more footage that's been shot from your phone from a past event,
the phones these days do a pretty darn good job of optimizing the images that's coming through the camera.
So they color, correct?
Automatically, they brighten up in contrast and sharpen things and bring more clarity automatically
whenever you shoot anything.
So for this scenario, we're not going to really go through and upgrade clips one by one.
I want to show you how you can quickly after you've done an edit like the one that we've worked on,
how you can do a layer across the whole thing that brightens up the whole thing, saturates the whole
thing, and can create a kind of cool or interesting tone that you're looking for across the whole video
itself.
Later in the course, we're going to go through and individually learn how to color great color.
Correct.
And really stylized and create a very unique look for each individual clip in our videos.
So let's first start here with creating a new adjustment layer, and I'll explain why we're going to
do it this way in a moment.
So we're going to create a new adjustment layer.
You're going to have a window that pops up that just asks you if you want to keep the settings of the
adjustment layer the same as the settings from your sequence.
Of course, we want to do that.
So we're going to hit OK.
And we're going to drag that adjustment layer into our timeline.
Now, right now, this is not doing anything, OK?
This is just a layer that sits on top of your footage and it basically says whatever is on this layer,
I'm going to give or put onto the footage below.
OK, so it's a really easy way to kind of paint your whole timeline, regardless of how many video clips
are in the timeline.
You can easily paint that whole timeline with the same effects.
So now I'm going to drag this adjustment layer so that it's covering our entire timeline here.
And I'm going to go to the effects tab and I'm going to type in new Metry color.
Now, regardless of whatever you're editing software is, you're going to have a color correction effect.
That's the main color correction way to really adjust the colors and exposure and contrast.
And all those different details of your image might be called color corrector and might be called something
else.
But in premiere, it's called luminary color.
Now, I just dragged on to the adjustment layer, and I'm going to go to the effects control tab and
I'm going to open up these toggles here.
See, we have basic color correction.
This is going to allow for us to change the color temperature, the tint exposure, contrast and so
on.
And the only other thing we're going to kind of focus on here is the creative tab.
This allows for us to do some interesting things with coloring and the shadow tint and highlight.
OK.
So now I'm going to scroll over to kind of our opening image here automatically.
I can see just through the whole video itself, it could use a little bit more contrast and definitely
some saturation throughout.
So I'm going to take the saturation function here.
Right now, it's set to hundred, which is basically means nothing is being added and nothing is being
taken away.
So I bring it down below a hundred.
You can start to see this image turn the black and white if I bring it above a hundred.
You can start to really see the effect that it's doing it.
OK.
We definitely don't want to be adding too much saturation because that will make the viewer have a oh,
this is a cheesy video opinion.
Right.
Of the edit.
So we want to undo that.
And we want to find a happy middle ground here.
So I just bumped it up to 116.
Now we can kind of play through the video and see how that's looking.
So I'm really liking that.
But I'm actually going to boost this year a little bit more.
So let's say one thirty.
OK, that's going to bring just some more colors back into our edit.
And now I'm going to add just a little bit of contrast.
This is going to create a more dynamic looking image.
So if I decrease the contrast, you can see the image is going to start to turn really gray.
That's because you're getting rid of the contrast or the difference between the darkest part of the
image and the brightest part of the image.
So you can.
That's super gray.
Right.
But let's bring this back to 10 just to have a little bit more contrast.
OK, that's all looking pretty good.
And I think we can over all here add a little bit more sharpening.
Now, what sharpening is going to do is going to really make the image appear to be a lot more crisp
and clear.
So, for example, if I reduce the sharpening all the way down and play through, you can see it feels
kind of blurry and a little bit hazy.
OK.
Now, if we go.
Here.
And we set that back to zero.
Now our image is looking good, but we can actually increase and just bump this up a little bit, 10
to 15 points.
That's going to give all of our images, especially when we're shooting on a smartphone that has decent
sharpness but doesn't have that razor razor sharp look when you're not shooting at four K.
If you take a 10 A.P. image, which is what this is, it's 19, 20 by 10, 80, technically 10, 80,
19, 1920.
But basically, that's the same amount of pixels in the image for kids, about four times that.
But we can take a 10 AP image like this that comes right off your phone.
And if we increase the sharpness just a little bit, it's something that you won't necessarily see right
away.
But after looking at everything, it's just going to give it a little bit of an extra pop.
So you can see like the images looking really clear and really crisp.
And that's what the goal of color correction is for.
So there you have it.
Super easy way to kind of do a final layer on top of your footage just to give it that little extra
special sauce.
Later in the course, we're going to go really into detail on color theory, on doing a little bit more
or actually a lot more of intricate ways of using color correction.
And in the next lecture, we're going to see how much we can change our edit by now adding a soundtrack
to the project that we've been working on.