And I'm going to do one final version of this, which is going to be for more of the tick tock or Instagram
stories style.
So I'm going to take this sequence that we have.
I'm going to duplicate it one more time.
And the reason we're doing it is so that we have a version of each one.
Here's our 16 by nine.
Here's our four by five.
And then now we're going to do a story slash tick tock.
I'm going to open it up.
I'm going to right click or see Quid's.
I'm going to secret settings and I want to type in the proper pixels, which is 80 by 1920.
Boom, nine by 16.
They're really vertical video aspect ratio.
So now we have that same problem that we need to fix.
Boom.
There we go.
Now, I will say that when you're going from 16 by nine to nine by 16, you're going to have to manually
kind of go in and scooch a few things around.
For example, a lot of these are looking good, but let's say let's say let's say this shot.
We don't want to just see our characters laig.
I'm going to go to the beginning of this clip.
Create a cut
scroll to the end.
And just independently scoot over this clip to let's just say they're OK.
And for this one as well, we could scoot this over.
Boom.
So it's going to be a trade off.
Like it'll be a perfect ratio with no black bars on the top or bottom like some people do on their posts.
It's going to fit perfectly.
But the tradeoff is that you're going to lose a lot of what's on the side, because we're changing the
aspect ratio so drastically.
So let's say that we went through and manually did this process of updating the individual shots that
needed to be moved.
And we're ready to explore it.
We can do the same process.
So we're going to go to Mobile 10 ATP.
We're going to make sure that the audio is set too high and the bit rate is at 320.
We're going to match our source sequence settings when you use maximum random depth and quality.
We're going to go up and we're going to take this into story story.
Oh, my God.
Story in Tic-Tac.
And the year is three thousand thirty, which is perfect.
Add it to the Q.
Hit play, so that goes.
And now what we're going to have is our costume demo reel that we created together in three different
formats, ready to be shared on three different platforms.
So if I go to my exports folder, you can see we have our main Vimeo version.
Ready to go?
And we have our normal Instagram post version.
And then we have our tick tock Instagram story version as well.
Perfect, so that wraps it up for our demo reel lessons.
I really hope you enjoyed it and I really hope you have some new tips and techniques and that you're
able to land higher paying clients and make, you know, overall a more impressive demo reel that shares
your work in the absolute best light possible.