Great, so let's dive right back in here, so I'm going to go and grab my voiceover for this video.
Now we have all of our Selex and we have the voiceover.
It's going to go in.
So what I'm going to do is drag this in and you can instantly see our voiceover is around 10 minutes
when all the footage that we have is around 30 or 40 minutes.
So we definitely have some work to do.
Even though we've cut all these Selex, we still have way more than we need.
Now, I kind of feel like I'm repeating myself, so I'm just going to stop doing that.
So the next thing we want to do is we have a voiceover in.
We want to lock off this voice layer.
And the reason we want to do that in this step of our YouTube video is if I were to let me actually
take it off and if I were to make a cut here and I want to move that and then I want to cut here and
move this year.
You can see what it just did to our voiceover.
So I'm gonna undo what we just did.
OK.
We don't want to cut any of this because our voiceover is done and it's ready for footage to be synched
up to it on top of the voiceover.
So we're going to lock it off.
Then we're going to make sure that any of the audio that we have from our cutaway shots, all this viral
is muted in this situation.
Some of your videos, you will use the audio from your cutaway shots in this one.
I know there's no audio from this empty space there are going to be using.
I know that there is no audio from any of this.
I know that there's no audio from this stuff that we're going to be using.
So it's muted.
Now, the process starts from the very beginning.
We're going to save this, actually.
But now the process starts to now cut these Selex that we've pulled together in a way that syncs up
and is married, basically synchronized to the voiceover that we have.
The voiceover is going to be the driving force that dictates what shots were showing.
And then there's going to be music in the background, which we'll get to that in probably a few learning
lessons.
That's going to be a secondary kind of adding emotional, energetic kind of addition.
So what I'm going to do is listen to my voice and I'm gonna let that dictate where I'm cutting filming
space.
I'm choosing.
So right there is the first point where I kind of change.
What I'm talking about, I'm choosing this extra room at my house because I can renovated.
I can move things around.
It's a clean slate to work with.
I mean, look at it.
It's a pretty dang clean slate.
Empty walls, empty floor, empty ceiling, everything super echoey here.
But we're going to fix that in the later steps.
So when you're going and you're choosing your filming space, make sure it's somewhere at your house
that's not going to get a lot of extra noise from outside and that you're going to be able to move things
around and really make it unique to you.
Then we want to get so that actually synched up pretty good.
There wasn't really a need for a whole lot of cutting in this portion.
So let's now move to what will be step two of this process.
And when we get later in this edit as well, we're going to add cool title cards to these different
step main steps that we get to.
So that'll be a cool moment that we'll get to as well.
Then we want to gather inspiration.
So I went through I pulled three creative spaces that I really liked.
You got this lightsaber guy.
We have this creator that has a really nice, minimal, modern, clean space, but it's a little bit
cold.
And then we got this guy, I believe.
OK, so I notice there's an extra gap in this voiceover, so let's go ahead and scoot over.
It's a little bit cold, and then we got the.
Well, they called and then we got this guy.
I believe his name is Armando.
Really cool space, very unique background, excellent lighting.
So those are the three that I wanted to use and refit.
It's into my own space.
Next up is our.
So this shot came in a little bit too early.
OK.
Base next up is our brainstorming in concept creation phase.
This is where we're taking the inspiration that we gathered from online.
What people are doing, what they're not doing, and we're going to mix that with this space that we
chose.
So I'm doing a test shot here.
I got my camera with rough framing of what they want the shot to look like, and I'm getting some work
done.
OK, in a move this around, and we're going to mix that with this space that we chose.
So I'm doing a test shot here.
I got my camera out with rough framing of what I want the shot to look like.
And I'm getting some work done, moving the hands around, you know, busy day here.
But the goal of this is to see if the ideas that we came up with are going to work in our space.
Next up, we create our brainstorming in concept creation phase.
This is where we're taking the inspiration and we gathered from online.
OK, so I feel like this shot is getting held for too long.
And then there's a moment here that I want to scoot over to here.
So let's go ahead and grab.
This is this is where we're taking the inspiration and we gathered from online.
We're taking the inspiration that we gathered from online, what people are doing, what they're not
doing, and we're going to mix that with this space that we chose.
So I'm doing a test shot here.
I got my camera out with rough framing of what I want the shot to look like.
And I'm getting some work done, moving the hands around, you know, busy day here.
But the goal of this is to see if the ideas that we came up with are going to work in our space like
air space.
OK.
Take out this extra room, scoot this over.
Next up, we create our purchase list and we really want to max out our credit cards here because that's
going to give us some more motivation to really take our video creating creativity and career a lot
more seriously.
Why?
Because there is no choice.
We got to pay off our debt.
No.
And I'm serious here.
What we want to do is create a purchase list of all the items we're going to.
I have simply cut away some excuses over, you know, in all seriousness here, what we want to do is
create a purchase list of all the items we're going to need for our space.
I found that the best way to do that.
Yes.
So right here in this part of the video, I'm talking about making a purchase list for the items that
you want to purchase.
So I remember that I have a screen gap on my phone and I already transferred it to the laptop.
So I'm going to go grab that shot now and then we'll drop it in together.
So as you can see, we have our shot up here and we definitely don't need that part.
So we're going to scroll to where I'm typing in purchase lists.
We're going to create an endpoint.
Don't you love those little snappy sound effects that Apple has?
OK, we'll probably end up time lapsing.
This, I'm guessing, because.
Yeah, we don't need to see this in real time, but let's drag it in.
And I'm going to hit scale to frame so that it scales it to the same dimension of our sequence.
And yeah, I'm going to timelapse this, so I'm going to right click.
Speed.
Duration.
And instead of this clip being four minutes and 35 seconds, I'm going to put it to 15 seconds.
I found the best way to do this is to create two columns.
One column has all of your equipment list purchases, and then one column has all of your aesthetic
list purchases of what's going to go in your space to really give it more style and more character.
And that leads us to the Christmas phase.
This is OK.
So that's the first four steps of pulling together a rough edit.
What I'm going to do now is a little bit of a time lapse and go through pulling a rough edit together
for the rest of these steps so that we can get on to more advanced techniques in this video.