Now, if we were to put this edit that we just worked on together in a theme, I would say nature travel
outdoors.
OK, it's not a crazy action sports video.
It's not an artistic moody music video.
OK, so yours is probably in the family friends outdoors memory type of genre.
So that's the kind of feeling that we want to cultivate even more through the music that we're going
to choose.
OK, so there's a few ways of getting your music for your edits.
Like I mentioned with, you know, getting sound effects in the past through just kind of ripping and
ripping them off YouTube.
You don't really want to do that unless you have permission.
OK, you can get in trouble.
You get flagged copyright.
You don't want to get any strikes on any of your channels.
So the two main ways are to reach out to the artists directly.
And you can ask for permission to use the video that you're not selling it, you're not repurposing
it, and you're not using it to really for any monetary gains.
Generally, if you ask people for that, that it's a passion project or something that's not of a professional
nature, kind of, you know, people are pretty nice about it.
If the artist is nice.
That's one way to do it.
The other way to do it is to use content pools, for example.
Of course, I use epidemic's sound because of their library of stuff, you know.
But in the past, I have definitely gone through SoundCloud soundtracks and I like reached out to the
person directly.
There's plenty of other sound libraries as well that you can try.
So have an idea of how you want to get a hold of your music for whatever works best for you.
And I'm just going to personally go through some past downloads that I have and find maybe four or five
tracks you really want to know that you're working with and pick four or five ones that might five and
might make your edit even better.
And then we're going to go to the next step of pulling that in and testing them out.
So if you haven't already gathered four to five tracks that you think might work for you, edit, you'll
either instantly know right away or you have the perfect song or you'll go through this process that
we're about to go through, flipping through, skipping ahead and seeing which one catches your ear,
remembering what the visuals are of your video and keeping that in mind.
So let's just kind of scroll through here.
So I would put this in like a Christmas category.
That's not what we're looking for.
OK, this one's got like an inspirational kind of vibe.
But a little bit, too, on the inspirational side for my taste.
And vocals aren't going to work for this type of video.
And this is a little too like late night drive in the car.
And you know, this is not going to work.
Uh huh.
And kind of cool.
I'm going to market just in case.
OK, I right click it.
And then I went and just tagged it with the color.
Two dramatics.
We're looking for something with the right amount of energy.
Maybe possibly a moment that just in case.
That's kind of cool.
Let's mark that one that my work.
OK, I once got it kind of an adventurous vibe, I would put the video that I've been working on in
the adventures category.
So keep that in mind of what category you'd put your video in.
Too much energy.
OK, so we have four tracks here, so I'm going to highlight these four tracks and I'm going to create
a new window and I'm going to go to our original folder that we worked so hard to organize and put together.
And I'm going to create a new folder called Music.
You see how this is all coming together.
We've got everything in one place.
Don't need to worry about where things went.
And I'm going to copy these tracks and I'm going to paste them into our wonderfully place music folder.
And now I'm going to go over to my editing software and I'm going to drop it in there.
OK.
So now we have footage, music sequences, sound effects.
And here's a little side tip here.
Any kind of layers or things that you create in your edit are going to start stacking up in your project
window.
So what I actually like to do is make an assets folder, because you're going to have different things
that you start dragging in that don't go under music or footage or go under other categories.
Maybe you drag in a few photos or still images.
You can drag those kind of miscellaneous things into an assets folder.