Now we're going to move on to the other filters that I add to my voice overs, which is going to be
a hard limiter.
I'm going to double click to add it on.
Now, what this hard limiter is going to do.
You can see an input boost and a maximum amplitude, maximum amplitude.
So the input boost is going to boost the input of the sound, a.k.a. bring up the decibels, bring up
the volume, and the maximum amplitude is going to create a ceiling that's not going to let you go above.
The reason I like to do this is if I set this to minus three and then I boost this up, let's say four
points, four decibels.
It's going to boost.
You can see with any audio, you have a waveform and there's peaks.
This stops the peak from going to high where it gets distorted.
And then the boost is going to boost all these lower regions that aren't quite as high as these higher
regions to make parts where you speak a little bit quieter.
It's going to boost those up so that all of your voiceover has a very much more unified actual volume.
But then it also, I've noticed, adds a more presence of voice, because everything that you're saying
is kind of not at max volume, but at a very boosted volume.
So it can be good for people who speak quieter.
It can be good for really anything.
But I've just noticed with voice overs, it does a lot more depth of field, more narrow of a frame,
but a little bit more of a documentary field.
So as you can see, it's bringing up the sound of all my different parts of my words.
Parts when I go quieter, parts when I'm louder are not going to loud.
And the difference between doing something like a hard limiter, which is also called a compressor,
it might be called a compressor in your editing software, is that if I bring up the volume, that's
going to bring up the volume of everything and things will start clipping and boom here.
But if I use the hard limiter, it's going to boost everything but put a ceiling so it doesn't go too
high, which keeps the high parts not too high and then boost the low parts.
Makes sense.
OK.
So it looks at 50 ml next.
What I do is add a mastering filter.
It could be called different things in your editing software, but what this is going to do is do a
final pass on boosting and widening and what's called adding an exciter, which kind of boosts the highs
as well to your voice.
So my favorite filter to use is this bright hype filter.
What I'm going to do is take off the reverb.
We never want to add reverb to a voiceover.
You really always want to remove it.
So there are some situations where if you do a lot of sound processing on your audio and you removing
sounds and you're moving hums in the background and removing buzzes in the background, it can make
your audio sound a little bit too polished and kind of computer.
And when you add reverb back, it kind of makes it more spacey.
It adds more like space between the words.
But we don't need to worry about that.
That's very specific.
So we're not going to be adding any reverb to our audio today, but we're going to take away that.
We're going to take away the loudness maximizer.
We're already doing that with the hard limiter.
And let's take a listen to what this sounds like.
Oh, this is a great focal length for documentaries and short films, but we really need so you can
see it as even more of that kind of interesting.
There's more of a electricity to my voice.
So let's take a listen.
Is the feeling of the background and it doesn't feel as much that we're now let's remove these filters
focal length for documentaries and short films, but we really lose the feeling of the background.
And it doesn't feel as much that we're sitting with the person on camera.
That's a huge difference.
Let's hear that one more time.
Is the feeling of the background and it doesn't feel as much that we're sitting with the person on camera
who.
OK.
That's why I had to stop in the middle of my phase of pulling these selects for the rough edit and fix
the audio.
So you could also see, as I was playing this and that it is red lining.
Just slightly.
It is red lining just slightly over here.
So the way to combat that, because we had everything at a pretty good level, but when we put on this
mastering final layer of our filter that brought up the highs even more, what that did was increase
the overall decibels.
So we need to go to a hard limiter and bring down the maximum amplitude.
Let's say two decibels to negative five.
Is in short films, but we really lose the feeling of the background and now our audio is coming in
right above negative six, which is perfect.
That's going to leave room for music in the background, sound effects in the background.
And that's really the benchmark that I go for with all videos that I've done.
So that should give you a really good understanding of how you can use your filters.
There might have different names in your editing software, so take the time to Google it, do a little
bit of research on how you can find how to do a compressor to boost your footage footage, to boost
your audio and also add a ceiling so it doesn't clip.
And then also a mastering filter so that you can increase the highs.
And something similar to a parametric equalizer filter like this so that you can see what's going on
in your audio.