So now that we finished these important first steps for this section, I want to now go through the
exporting process and some of the really just key fundamentals with that.
Now, we've been working and it's likely you've been working as well in the vertical video format category.
So we'll walk through what it is like exporting for vertical video, horizontal video, and really also
keeping in mind that you want to export with the proper settings of where that video is going to live.
If that Liddie video is going to live on YouTube, you're going to export with certain settings.
If it's going to live on Instagram, it's different settings and so on.
So let's hop in here and see our final edit here.
And I want you to pull up your footage as well so you can follow along.
And we're going to go up to file.
We're going to go to export.
And we're going to click on media.
And actually, before we do that, we want to make sure that the in and out points in our timeline are
in the proper place.
You can see up here on the top bar of our timeline.
We want to have it so that it's the endpoint is at the beginning, and of course, the outpoint is at
the end.
What'll happen if the outpoint I'm hitting I for endpoint over outpoint.
By the way, if the output is here, it's going to export everything up to here and not include the
rest of the video.
So we always want to make sure that are in and our points are set properly for exactly when we want
to export.
Yeah.
And one thing that I'll say that's kind of a little bit handy is if you want to kind of test something
or share one part of your video with someone or.
Yeah, like what I'll do sometimes when I don't know if a certain scene is working, but I don't want
to export the whole video.
You can set an endpoint and an outpoint for just, you know, a little 10 second clip and just export
that part.
Right.
So there's some cool uses for doing it.
But for this circumstance, we're going to set the endpoint at the beginning.
Yeah.
Point at the very end in good file.
Can you go to export and go to media?
Or we can hit command.
And and that's going to do the same exact thing.
This is going to bring up our export settings panel.
And what we want to do here is make sure that our format is aged out to six four.
This is really the best format for online video.
Anything that you're sharing online where you want to retain as much quality as possible, but have
it in a more manageable and optimized codec or format for online use, which is pretty much going to
be almost every single one of your exports.
Rarely do I ever use anything else in here if I'm exporting just audio.
I'll go and I'll use waveform audio and then I'll set my sample rate a bit rate to 32 bit.
That's going to give it the max quality as possible and choose the destination.
But that's separate.
So right now, what we're focusing on is exporting our video.
So we're going to go out to 64 and then we're going to go to the preset tab and we're going to click
that, OK?
Because this is going to be for this video specifically viewed as an Instagram story format.
What I want to do is choose the mobile device HD function.
OK.
If this was going to be a YouTube video, per se, then I would go to YouTube video to NAACP or Fourcade,
depending on what it was shot ads and a little bit of a pro tip here.
When you are exporting a 10 ATP high def video file, which most almost all cameras are shooting, and
it's very likely that that's the format you'll be editing in, whether it's going to Vimeo, Facebook
or YouTube, a little bit of a hack is to click the four K function so you can do four K for YouTube
here for K for Vimeo right here, and you can do four K for Facebook.
What that's going to do is it's going to compress the information less and it's going to give more space
for all of the pixels, all of the data and all for the all of the information, even if it's a 10 step
file.
So you'll see that if you export a 10 ATP video for YouTube and that same exact 10 A.P. video at four
K for YouTube, and you look at them side by side, you're going to see the four K file is going to
look a little bit more crisp.
There's going to be little bit more detail and a little bit more color and overall data that's in your
footage and in your video, because YouTube is compressing it less in these platforms are compressing
it less because you're telling it it's a much larger file.
So let's hop back into what we're currently exporting.
This is going to be playing on a mobile device for Instagram.
So for doing that, I always go to mobile device and ATP and we can see our audio video effects, multiplexer
captions publish.
OK.
For audio, what I always do as well is it's going to depending on your export preset, it's going to
change your bit rate, depending on the quality that you're expending, as when you do do mobile device
and ATP, it puts your bit rate at 128.
OK, we want to have our audio at the highest settings as possible.
We're going to make sure audio quality is set to high as well.
We're going to go to the video tab and we can also scrub through our export to get a preview of what
it's going to be looking like.
Now, you can see there are these really big black bars on the side.
That's because our aspect ratio is 10, 80 by 1920 instead of 1920 by 10, 80.
So to get around this issue and not export of video with these big black bars, we're going to match
the source of our sequence settings and make that match the settings for our export.
So I'm going to click match source and we can also click render at maximum depth and use maximum render
quality.
This is going to allow your editing software to work more frame by frame on each different characteristic
in detail that's in each frame.
And then we have the multiplexer tab.
I've really never go into here.
These are really not parameters that you ever need to be changing for.
Ninety nine percent of your edits.
We have the caption tab as well that you really likely ninety nine point nine percent of the time you
will not be using.
And then we have the publish tab, which this can be handy if you want to link Premier directly with
your Behance profile, Adobe Profile, Facebook, Twitter, Vimeo and YouTube.
I personally don't ever export directly out of premier directly to another platform to me that I've
spent so many years not having that function.
It's just weird to me.
Maybe I'm too set in my ways here, but I always like to have the individual file that I'm then dragging
into where I want it to go.
Maybe I'm old fashioned, but I don't ever use the publish function.
But of course, take the time.
If it's applicable to you and would speed up your workflow, take the time to set it up.
And now that we've got all these parameters set up, the final step is to click our output name to determine
the name of our video file and the location, which is where the video file is going to be exported
to.
And I'm sure you can guess we're going to be keeping everything very organized and exporting it to the
proper video folder.
So I'm going to go to Shasta edit and I'm going to create an export folder.
OK.
And I'm going to title it Mount Shasta.
And this is a good time to kind of talk about labeling your exports.
Now a lot of the time you export something and you think that's possibly going to be the final one.
And then you realize, nope, there's some major changes that need to be made or something's not working,
whatever it is.
The best way that I found, of course, you can label it by the date Mount Shasta edit.
So and so date.
But what I've learned over the years is best to do version one, version two, version three.
So most of the time, almost all the time, I'll do the name of the project for the export name.
And then the one if it's vtu, it would be v2 v three.
V three.
OK.
So the one and I also add where it's going to live.
So in this case, this is going to be an Instagram story.
OK.
So if it was going to be a normal post to just be Instagram post, if it was going to be YouTube video,
B, Instagram R, it would be excuse me, Mount Shasta V1 YouTube.
OK, Mount Shasta, V1, Facebook.
So Mount Shasta, the one Instagram story we're going to hit save.
And later we're going to go down to hit the export button.