So now let's find our next moment to transition into our third track, where you're at your peak of
overwhelm during this process, because you're going to end up with a bunch of packages at your house
when you don't even really remember what you ordered, but there's just a bunch of boxes.
So I use this in room to create a cool little montage with a really pointy object.
So we're going to need to drop out our track here so we can do one of two things.
We can either just drop the track out, kind of like what we did before.
But I don't like doing those back to back either, like doing a fade out or an echo.
Because if you do the just straight dropping the track out, it's kind of a dramatic moment.
And if you do it a bunch in the video back to back.
Kind of loses its power.
And to me personally, it feels a little bit repetitive.
Some people might not even notice it, but let's see what else we can do for this one.
As with the pointy object.
So that would work if I wanted to do that.
But let's see what a fade sounds like.
So I'm happy for the pen tool and I'm going to do a little bit of fade.
Let it play.
Remember what you ordered?
But there's just a bunch of boxes.
So I use this in room to create a cool little montage with a really pointy object.
OK, the fade works, too.
So I want to show another option, which is kind of another use of the echo or reverb.
So there's this beat.
And what I'm going to do is isolate it.
So I'm going to make a blade cut in front of it and I'm going to turn down the track before that comes
in.
So I just want to really isolate this part.
Yeah.
So I'm going to make that and then I'm going to fade it out.
Mm hmm.
So now we have that just kind of one hit.
But the problem is, it fades out so away around that like we did before.
We're going to nest this and we're going to add another reverb layer.
And actually, I'm just going to grab for times sake, the one that we did earlier in the edit.
I want to paste it on.
And let's hear it.
So that is a more of a gradual it's not really a fade out.
It's not really a straight drop off like we just did.
It's kind of in the tween.
And it sounds professional because you're making that part of the track kind of sound like that.
That's the end of the track, which is when we want it to stop.
So it kind of is a little bit more cohesive.
Let's hear it with the rest of the audio.
That's when you don't even really remember what you ordered, but it's just a bunch of boxes.
So I use this all along to create a cool little montage with the really pointy object.
OK, cool.
So we got to use the echo.
As another kind of creative tool to make the transition between tracks, so we're only like two ish
minutes in the video and we've already got two tracks going, which is great because that's going to
keep the overall pacing and tempo moving forward.
Now, let's go to the end of this montage, because this is a sound driven montage.
We don't want music under it.
But when we do come back into this moment, when there's talking again, this is when we're going to
want to start our next track.
So let's take a listen without our track.
And after putting any mandates.
Now let's get our track.
And let's put it right here where we're changing.
Our scene.
Turn it down to about negative 12, because that's really working well for this audio.
And after putting any band aids on for minor takes and scratches from that last montage, now it is
time for our initial test shots instead of AIDS.
So what you want to do is grab your most important equipment.
Mine's going to be my light and I need lighting source the camera at my desk in my chair, and I'm going
to kind of move things around in my studio to find out what's going to be the best location in the backdrop
so you can continue to move things around, wave your hands and do a little bit of a dance.
And after all the testing, just move things back to where you figure they were going to be in the first
place.
But now that we've done that, we have that lined up pretty dang well.
This part where the beat really came in matched up perfectly with a point where my audio kind of picked
up energy as well.
So so you can continue to move things around.
So I kind of picked up my tempo and you can kind of even see the increase in the volume that I went
up because I was saying something I was more excited about at this moment.
You can see him kind of lower and more quiet here.
I speak up louder here because I'm more excited.
And that matched up perfectly with this beat that came in.
So I'm super happy with that.
Now I'm going to go in and add the remainder of the tracks to this edit, and then we're going to get
into some more intermediate refining steps in the next lesson.