Now that we have that exported, what I want to do is take that second version of the edit that we made.
And I want to change the aspect ratio so that it can be used for a slightly different post.
So if we bring this up here and check out for Instagram, for example, the aspect ratio that we were
just working in is this 10, 80 by 1920.
That's the vertical format that we just did.
And that's the verdel vertical format of our second version with the music track.
And what I want to do is walk you through how you can very easily change the same video to fit different
types of posting or sharing mediums.
So we're going to take this 10 by.
So we're going to take this nine by 16 aspect ratio, the average.
So we're going to take this nine by 16 aspect ratio that we were originally working in.
And we're going to change it to make it a four by five aspect ratio so that you can very easily take
a vertical video and turn it into a normal Instagram post.
So as you can see, we need to change our sequence setting to 10, 180 by 13, 15.
This is going to give us the proper ratio so that our video fits perfectly in a normal Instagram post.
So let's go into our editing software.
You're going to find your sequence that you created.
If you don't have a secondary sequence that you've already duplicated to try and add a musical track
to what you can do now is take the sequence you have been working on and duplicate it right now.
So I'm going to do copy paste.
I'm going to take this sequence and title it four by five insta grand post.
OK, I'm going to double click to open it, and then I'm going to right click the sequence and I'm going
to go to sequence settings.
Here it brings up a panel where I can see all of the actual settings that my sequence is using.
And if we go back to our different Instagram ratios, we can see we need to switch this to 10, 80 by
13, 50 instead of 19, 20.
So I'm going to type that in and I'm going to add, OK.
Yeah.
This is going to ask you, do you really want to make this change to your sequence settings?
It's going to change some previews and it's going to just simply remove any of the previews that you
had already possibly had rendered.
No big deal.
We're going to hit, OK.
And there we go.
Now we have our edit with the proper aspect ratio.
But if you scroll through here, you can see that there are some changes that need to be made.
We're also cutting off the top in the bottom of our video because we went to a very vertical format,
to a much more shortened format.
So the way to really kind of get around that and fix that is to go to these clips.
I'm going to select this first one and I'm going to go to the Effects Controls panel on the top left.
And I'm going to click the motion function and I'm going to take the position and I'm going to drag
and skewed the video itself.
So that's what it's looking like now.
What it was before was there.
So you're simply just kind of reframing the shots to match this new formatting.
It's a little extra step that you're going to have to do.
But the cool thing is, is that you can take one piece of content and repurpose it to multiple platforms.
So we'll kind of play through the rest of this video and see what other shots need to be reframed.
And that actually brings me to another tip for this kind of scenario.
If at the beginning of your clip, now that we've changed the aspect ratio, it's well framed at the
beginning, but you don't like it at the end.
For example, I'm framed OK in here, but then we get to the end and we don't really end of that clip
and we don't really get to see the full waterfall.
We can set a key frame at the beginning of the clip where we like the framing, go to the end and move
the framing to where we want it to be.
And what's going to happen is, as that clip plays through, because we created these two key frames,
it's going to progressively get to that point at the end of the clip.
So let's play that through.
So you see it tilt it up so that we could see the waterfall because these key frames that we created
by using this little stopwatch function.
Let's see these next shots now.
OK.
Looks pretty good.
So for this final shot, if we wanted to add a little bit more motion, we can go to the beginning,
select the clip, go to the effects control panel.
Go to the motion tab.
Hit that stopwatch.
Move the beginning of the shot all the way to the bottom.
Go to the end of the shot.
Scooch the end of the shot all the way to the top.
And now if we play through it.
We have that natural handheld movement, but then we added this movement along with it, just to add
a little extra dynamic layer.
And now that we have that, let's go ahead and export this version, we have the endpoint set at the
beginning, the outpoint set at the end.
I'm going to do command end to bring up our export settings aged up to 64.
We're set with that.
And because it's going to be going to a mobile device, we're going to do mobile device 10 ATP.
And just like the other edit you can scrub through here to preview what it'll be looking like.
And again, we have these black bars on the side here because we have not yet worked in the 16 by nine
aspect ratio.
So we're going to click match source boom.
That gives us the exact four by five aspect ratio we're wanting for Instagram post.
We're going to do render at maximum depth.
We're going to hit maximum render quality.
We're going to scroll down on the audio tab.
We're going to make sure our bit rate is set to 320.
That's the highest audio settings we can have.
And finally, we're going to go to our output name, click that, and we're going to set our name and
our destination for export.
Now, what I do, if I'm exporting something that's similar to a previous export, I'm just going to
click on that previous export, because that's going to pop up a similar name.
It's going to save me a little bit of time.
And I type quite as much Mount Shasta V1.
And this is going to be Instagram post.
OK.
If we had made changes in our edit and updated or changed shots or music, this would be a version,
too.
But because no physical changes have been made except for that aspect ratio change, it's technically
still the same version.
So we're going to keep that V1.
We're going to hit save and hit export.