Next up is to talk about title cards.
Now, as you saw, we kind of use these temporary title cards as placeholders to keep track of the main
chapters of our YouTube video.
Now, I'd love to have some type of title card for the audience and the viewer that explains where we're
at in the process.
But these little guys down here at the bottom, it's just not cutting it for me.
So I want to explain how to really update and make these look better.
Now, the easy way would be to kind of go in here and, you know, center it, maybe scale things up
and just make it feel a little bit more professional with maybe changing up the font.
I know a good font is lotto.
I use this one a lot and that looks a little bit better, but I'm really not happy with it.
But something that will help when you're using kind of big, big title card like this is to kind of
turn the exposure down of the background so that the font stands out more.
Now, that's still not cut that for me.
We could spend a little bit more time on this.
The typography of this, you know, really making it look good and making the spacing look good.
But, you know, I'd really recommend putting some time into going online and finding some motion graphic
templates.
And there's so many out online that are free that you can buy for a few dollars.
I've collected some that I really like over the years, and it's just something that takes time to kind
of build up the stuff that you like to use.
So there is this essential graphics window that I mentioned earlier in the course that there are some
templates that you're editing software will come with.
But I do have some favorites that I have saved that I use for a lot of my projects.
So I'm going to grab one of those that I use a lot, and I'm going to show you how to put together and
really whip up a really quick, good looking motion graphic or title card for your video.
So out of the ones that I really like, I'm just going to kind of grab a random one here and I'm going
to drag it down into the timeline and I'm going to turn off the footage below it so that we can really
just clearly see what we're looking at here.
So if I select this at the graphic, we can see text online one traditions, traditions.
Is there text online, too?
This is just automatically what it comes.
I don't know why it's talking about Japanese tea ceremonies, but OK, now I'm going to look back here.
OK, so step seven, start the build.
Let's see how we can put that into the template that we're using.
And this is going to work for any template that you use.
You want to find a cool way to display the information that you want to have on screen.
So I'm going to type in step seven.
And, you know, you can use a number, maybe that looks cooler, but honestly, in this kind of scenario,
I'm going to spell out the number and I'm going to say start the build, because that's the name of
the step in this one and yours as well, that you use whatever it is, it's going to have like different
parameters.
This one has a good gradient parameter.
But, you know, I want all of the text in here to be white with no gradient.
So you could see what the gradients there is, those different shades of white without the gradients,
no different shades.
And I don't need all these kind of like geometry thingamajigs.
But I do like when it comes in and that type of animation.
So I'm going to cut out the beginning kind of overly geometry kind of things.
And I skewed it to where we want it to start.
I'm going to cut it where we want it to and I'm going to get rid of the old one.
Actually, I'm gonna keep you on the on so we can see it before and after.
And I'm going to turn back on our bottom layer.
Now I'm going to turn on the safe margins, kind of overlay.
It just pops up basically this wireframe, just so I can really get our graphic centered, because sometimes
that's hard.
So I'm looking at these horizontal dashes and then these vertical ones, and I'm just going to kind
of eyeball it.
Put that in the ocean.
Put that in the center and then that in the center.
I feel like the step seven thing is a little bit high.
So we could scale this up.
And then I want to bring down.
Yeah, OK.
Bring that down.
Scooch it over.
And we're starting to look pretty good.
Now we can take this off, see how it looks.
And now that we've done that, it's time to second guess all the decisions we made up to this point.
But we don't have a whole lot of time for that, because now it is a building process.
This is where we get to lift.
OK, cool.
So I like that.
That's a lot better than that.
OK.
We're making progress.
What I do want to add, though, is I really like this intro animation, The Mute, that I really like
this intro animation now, because it just disappears.
It doesn't look as cool.
Right.
So what I want to do is grab this clip, hold alz.
I guess I'm a really fan of holding alt and dragging Clevis, because it's just such an easy way to
duplicate a clip without clicking it.
Command C click somewhere else.
Command V.
You can click and drag it wherever you want, and it's just great.
So we're going to click this duplicate.
And what I did, I just duplicated the friend.
So but there's a problem.
It's like, no, that's not what we want.
So what we do want is to right click the clip.
We're going to reverse the direction.
So at the beginning, animation is now the ending animation of it going away.
OK.
And sometimes to smooth things out a little bit.
This is kind of a weird cut.
It's a little bit of a jump cut.
So we'll fix that.
But it's kind of cool if you overlap whatever animation you do, put on the screen a little bit over
the next cut.
So I'm actually going to fix this jumpcut because it makes it hard.
It's distracting.
So we're just going to scale this up.
That'll kind of take away our jumpcut.
OK.
And now,
boom, the animation comes in and then, boom, the animation goes away.
But you see how it overlaid on the next one.
That kind of just meshes everything together.
This is a clean cut without the overlay or, you know, the lag, actually.
And then this is with it going over, which is funny that you would think that that would make it that.
But it actually works really well.
I do that a lot with animation so we can even even do it to the beginning.
Boom.
So it comes in on the last shot and overlays versus the clean cut.
So it's kind of an aesthetic decision.
There's no right or wrong.
They both look good.
But I kind of like that look instead.
Now, the other thing is, because these two shots are so similar, but there's an exposure change between
here, the opacity that 70 percent.
Here's a 100.
Let's kind of do a ramp up so that it's more gradual zoom.
OK.
I like that.
OK, now let's do the same process to our next.
Oh, God.
Our next overlay.
You see how this looks so rinky dink down here in the bottom.
We're going to fix that.
So I'm going to highlight what we just created, Holdall, which, you know, is my favorite thing to
do by now.
I'm going to put it in place and I'm going to turn down the opacity of the clips below it so that our
motion graphics stands out a little bit more.
And I'm going to change this to step eight and I'm going to change this to paint and style now, because
this next clip is a separate cut that we did.
We're going to have to change the writing as well.
So my copy that Cahier, paste it here and let's check it out.
And voila, step eight, paint in style.
Let's actually see what's like with the audio sound in the background to see how things are starting
to come together.
Which leads us to our painting and styling phase.
It's where we get to use a green Tabe saying to tape up all the bits of the wall that we don't want
to get.
OK.
So that's starting to really come together.
Now, I'm going to do the same process for the other chapter titles of this video, and then we're going
to continue to upgrade our YouTube video.