Righto, so we have, like I mentioned, this, you know, big shot, that's the one of the most important
shots of the video and this going to be shot.
So I want to do like a zoom effect.
Kind of a sushi kind of zoom in.
I don't know how to explain it, a zoom effect.
So a cool way to do this and really to integrate into after effects.
Now, this is not an after effects course.
It's an entirely other editing software on its own.
But it's basically the Photoshop of video final cut premiere I movie.
These are like main editing softwares that are designed to create cuts like what we've done in this
chapter.
But something like After Effects is really an in-depth editing software that's designed to create very
intense.
Oh, God, I'm repeating myself.
OK, let's just get into it.
So what I would do is duplicate the two clips that we're going to do this effect with.
And I'm going to right click these clips and I'm going to do replace with after effects composition.
This is going to open up after effects and create a sequence with these clips that we have.
And the benefits of doing it this way is that we don't have to highlight our clips, export them, import
them in the after effects, do the editing that we want, export them out of after effects, and then
import them into our editing software.
So it's asking me where I want to save this brand new after effects project.
So I'm going to put it in the proper folder.
I'm going to title this folder after effects transition.
And what I want to do to get this swoosh effect is to create a justment layer.
And this is exactly like the adjustment layers that we've been using in our normal editing software.
It's going to create a global effect on whatever's below it.
Sorry, I just kind of changed the layout of the windows here.
But I'm going to go to the Presets and Effects tab and I'm going to take one of my favorite transitions
that does kind of that cool sushi style.
And I'm going to drop that on to our adjustment layer.
Now, what this is going to do and by the way, you don't have to use this same exact transition.
You can do this, you know, for color correction if you want in after effects.
You can do this for thousands of different things that the after effects filters can do, specifically
that premier final cut can't do.
So I'm going to take this filter that I dropped on and I'm going to really just line up the key frames
to the transition between the two clips.
And I'm going to preview what that looks like.
So that has the more right effect that we're looking for.
Of course, I can go in and I can fine tune the zoom strength, the blur, all that stuff.
But this is really not about after effects.
This is just more about the simplicity and the benefit of being able to edit an after effects sequence
that automatically goes to your premiere timeline without having to import and export it.
So I hope that you can use that in your future videos and in your YouTube video that you're editing
to do some creative stuff and save a little bit of time.