And just like that, we made it to the end of our YouTube video edit.
So in this learning lesson, I simply just kind of want to sit back and view the work that we put together
together.
So this is not going to be really me doing any kind of lecturing or talking too much.
I'm going to sit back and watch this with you.
We're going to hit play and we're going to see the edit.
And I also cued up the actual timeline.
So we'll be able to see what's happening in the final edit on the screen, on the top, and then we'll
see how that edit was done in the timeline below.
So without further ado, let's check out the YouTube video that we created together.
Man, I know this doesn't look like much.
I know it doesn't sound like much, but I'm going to show you how I went from taking this studio space
like this and made it look like this.
Yep, I got a lot of work to do.
So let's get right into it.
First, if you want to do, is choose your filming space.
I'm choosing this extra room at my house because I can renovate it.
I can move things around.
It's a clean slate to work with.
I mean, look at it.
It's a pretty dang clean slate.
Empty walls, empty floor, empty ceiling, everything super echoing here.
But we're going to fix that in the later steps.
So when you're going and you're choosing your filming space, make sure it's somewhere at your house
that's not going to get a lot of extra noise from outside and that you're going to be able to move things
around and really make it unique to you.
Then we want to gather inspiration.
So I went through I pulled three creative spaces that I really liked.
We got this light saber guy.
We have this creator that has a really nice, minimal, modern, clean space, but it's a little bit
cold.
And then we got this guy, I believe his name is Armando.
Really cool space, very unique background, excellent lighting.
So those were the three that I wanted to use and remix into my own space.
Next up is our brainstorming in concept creation phase.
This is where we're taking the inspiration that we gathered from online.
What people are doing, what they're not doing.
And we're going to mix that with the space that we chose.
So I'm doing a test out here.
I got my camera out with rough framing of what I want the shot to look like.
And I'm getting some work done, moving the hands around, you know, busy day here.
But the goal of this is to see if the ideas that we came up with are going to work in our space.
Next up, we create our purchase list and we really want to max out our credit cards here, because
that's going to give us more motivation to really take our video, creativity and career a lot more
seriously.
Why?
Because there is no choice.
We got to pay off our debt.
No.
And all serious here.
What we want to do is create a purchase list of all the items we're going to need for our space.
I found that the best way to do this is to create two columns.
One column has all of your equipment list purchases, and then one column has all of your aesthetic
list purchases of what's going to go in your space to really give it more style and more character.
And that leads us to the Christmas phase.
This is going to be where you're at your peak of overwhelmed during this process, because you're going
to end up with a bunch of packages at your house when you don't even really remember what you ordered,
but there's just a bunch of boxes.
So I use this overwhelm to create a cool little montage with a really pointy object.
And after putting any band aids on for minor cuts and scratches from that last montage, now it is time
for our initial test shots and set up phase.
So what you want to do is grab your most important equipment.
Mine's going to be my key light, my main lighting source, my camera, my desk in my chair.
And I'm going to kind of move things around in my studio to find out what's going to be the best location
in the backdrop so you can continue to move things around, wave your hands around, do a little bit
of a dance.
And after all that testing, just move things back to where you figure they were going to be in the
first place.
But now that we've done that, we have our set up ready to go.
And all we have to worry about in the future is sitting down and hitting record because we know we're
maximizing our space because we did these test shots.
And now that we've done that, it's time to second guess all the decisions we made up to this point.
But we don't have a whole lot of time for that, because now it is our building process.
This is where we get to lift things, marks and things drill's some things use a cool laser thing.
And ideally, by the end of this process, we've hung these things on the wall and they are staying
on the wall and voila, there we go.
Now we have our shelves in the background, and I'm going to put some lights on in the background to
see how things are starting to come together.
Which leads us to our painting and styling phase.
This is where we get to use a green tape thing to tape up all the bits of the wall that we don't want
to get paint on.
And now that my room has got a cool kind of Tron vibe, it's time to start the painting process.
I went with a matte black because it matches the professional and minimal feeling that I'm going for.
And I know with this stuff that I'm going to have on the shelves and the warm lighting that I'm going
to have, it's going to really want the space and balance out the kind of cold minimalist that just
a plain black wall has.
But I really feel like these two styling choices are really going to balance out the perfect amount
of minimal with warm and inviting.
And once you finish painting, you want to pull off your green tape things and put things back on your
wall that you had to take off for the painting process.
So I put my shelving back on.
I'm hanging some new curtains that are blackout curtains.
And then we want to put things in the background that match up with our personality, the theme of our
videos and the overall style we want to go for.
So I'm adding these cool lights to match it with my personality and of course, some vintage cameras
and some lenses in the background that also match up with the theme and direction of all my video content.
And now that our room is looking pretty -- good, it's time to upgrade it for better sound dynamics.
So I'm going to start with taking off this big ceiling fan.
And, yep, you can see I'm doing a bang up job there.
And now what I'm going to do is add sound paneling to the main walls that's going to be reflecting the
most amount of noise.
So to get that done, I'm going to tape off all the important things in my room so I know where they
go.
Move them out of the way.
Get out my sound panels that we ordered back in the Christmas phase.
Contemplate how the heck I'm going to get this done.
And just start slapping some super glue on some cardboard panels and see what happens.
Okay, cool.
That actually worked pretty well.
Now I'm going to measure the walls, find the center, start nailing things in.
But yeah, these nails bend.
So I'm going to get some different nails.
And voila, these nails are keeping my sound panels on to the wall, which is really ideal.
And I got super McGyver with these magnets because a part of my wall had this big metal door on it.
And we did a great job.
These are a thing of beauty.
So now it is time to get your audio and microphone dialed in.
So the main thing is to get whatever microphone you're using as close to you as possible while you're
speaking.
Once you've gotten that situated, then we want to move to our settings.
Now, you always, always want to have your recorder set to manual.
And of course, set your recording format to the highest quality possible.
I use WAV files because it doesn't compress your audio at all.
And you want to have your audio levels peaking somewhere between negative 12 and negative six.
And a good protip is to speak louder than you would normally would on your recording and speak quieter
than you normally would when you're setting your levels that way, you have a good range of what the
levels are going to be like, so you don't mess up your recording and you get the cleanest audio possible.
We're doing a pretty darn good job here.
And now it is time to dial in our lighting, our camera settings and our framing.
So we're going to start with cutting out our ambient light that way.
Our main lighting source, which is our key light, is going to start really illuminating our scene.
That is what it looks like with the key light, without any practicals on in the background.
And boom, those practical lights in the background really warm up the space.
And to get that more cinematic kind of dramatic lighting, you want to have your key light at least
45 degrees off to one side of your camera.
This is going to create a good amount of shadow.
On the side of your face, opposite of the light, the more shadows, the more dramatic your lighting
and the less shadows, the more of a beauty blogger type of vibe.
Your video is going to have.
Next, we want to set our picture profile into our camera to a log profile or a neutral profile.
That way, all of our contrast, saturation, sharpness is all the way down, and we can turn it up
selectively in post-production.
Then we want to set our white balance to the same exact color temperature as our key light and set your
frame rate to 24 frames per second and have your shutter speed double that at a fiftieth of a second.
And as a little added bonus, we can add a splash of color in the background.
This is going to create a little bit more character and a little bit more personality for our footage.
And so to recap, here's how this space looks without any lighting added.
Here's how it looks with the practicals in the background.
Again, that add that character and personality and really warm up the space and boom, this is how
it looks at our key light.
And with a little bit of background light, that's going to help separate me, the subject from the
background.
It's looking really good.
But lastly, I wanted to talk about focal length.
So here's our shot at.
Twenty eight millimeters.
I really feel that this is the best for YouTube, Instagram, any kind of online content.
And here's what it looks like at 24 millimeters, it's OK.
I always feel like it's a little bit too wide.
The shallower you go with the focal length, the more professional it's going to look.
And here's how it looks at 35 millimeters more depth.
The field more narrow of a frame, but a little bit more of a documentary feel.
And boom, here's how it looks at 50 mil.
This is a great focal length for documentaries and short films, but we really lose the feeling of the
background and it doesn't feel as much that we're sitting with the person on camera.
And that is why I always go with 28 millimeters for this kind of videos, because it's the perfect balance
of a professional look while still having a wide enough perspective of the other things that's going
on inside the frame.
And as a little bit of a bonus, final touch, I added some PVC pipes to hide the cables.
Get that off here.
Oh, yeah, OK, OK.
And I added some artwork on the walls, replaced my more bulky professional tripod with a much slimmer
small footprint tripod, hid all of these extra cables.
God knows we needed to do that and added these super cool led strips.
That allows for me to change the feeling and the vibe of the room at one click of a button.
So there you have it.
All of our hard work has paid off.
This is what we started with.
And let's see that beautiful before and after shot.
Wow.
Whoo!
Baby!
That is a work of art right there.
I completely love how this space came together.
All the little details were perfect.
I really enjoy working here.
I really enjoy editing in here.
And I really enjoy just chillin in this space.
So I hope this video really gave you some insights and inspired you to go out and create your own space
that's uniquely yours.
If you like this video, be sure to check out the rest of my content where I share my other tips and
techniques on how to become a better video creator.
And I will see you in the next video.
Food, yes, so I hope that gives you a cool insight into how when you're the viewer watching the final
edit, it's like one continuous stream of imagery.
But when you actually see the timeline right along with what's actually going on, you see how many
cuts in microseconds and little moments and things were created in the post-production process to create
that steady stream of content that every video has or every good video has.
So it's been a long journey just for this chapter of this course, but that wraps it up for the YouTube
video chapter.
And I will see you in the next chapter where we're going to dive into even more intermediate to now
expert level editing techniques and topics.
I will see you in the next chapter.