Hello, and welcome to this new tutorial,
about adding the extra LSTM layers,
and of course, to each of them,
some dropout regularization.
So as you can see,
I already prepared what we're going to add,
a second LSTM layer,
with some Dropout regularization.
A third LSTM layer,
with some Dropout regularization again,
and a fourth LSTM layer,
with some Dropout regularization.
So we're going to have a total of four LSTM layers
in our robust structure,
of our LSTM recurrent neural network.
So let's start with the second LSTM layer,
and the good news is that it's gonna be
very, very easy,
because we simply need to copy
these two lines of code,
because of course we're gonna use again
.add method from the Sequential class,
to add a new LSTM layer,
and some dropout regularization
to our regressor,
but be careful, we only need to do one change
which is about the input_shape.
We had to specify the input_shape argument here,
because this was our first LSTM layer,
and we had to specify the shape of the input,
with the last two dimensions here,
first pointing to the timesteps and the predictors,
the indicators, but now things are slightly different.
We're just adding a second LSTM layer,
and therefor we don't need to specify
the input layer anymore,
and that's why I am just removing this,
and there we go,
these two lines of code,
will add your second LSTM layer,
with some dropout regularization,
and for those of you who are wondering,
why we don't have to still specify
the input shape of the previous LSTM layer,
well that's because it's recognized automatically,
thanks to this units argument here,
which tells exactly that we have 50 neurons
in the previous layer.
So no need to specify any input shape here,
when you're adding your next LSTM layers,
after the first one,
and so, we're gonna keep this same
number of neurons in this second LSTM layer,
50 neurons, and that's the same.
That's to have some high dimensional NT
in our model, to be able to handle
the complexity of the problem.
Augmenting the dimensionality of our model,
will augment at the same time the complexity,
and therefor will respond better
to the complexity of the problem
and that will eventually lead us to better results.
So 50 neurons again,
and same, we're keeping a 20% dropout
for the regularization,
that should do it,
since that's a relevant choice.
Alright, and now,
I have some even better news.
It is that, in order to add,
the third LSTM layer here,
well the only thing that we have to do,
is just copy-paste these two lines of code here,
that's out of the second LSTM layer,
because adding the third LSTM layer,
is exactly the same as adding the second LSTM layer.
We simply need to specify the number of neurons
in the LSTM layer,
and we're keeping 50 neurons
to have the same same goal
of having a high dimensionality.
We still need to keep return_sequence is equal true,
because we're going to add
another LSTM layer after that,
and we're keeping the 20% dropout regularization.
So that's done, just by copy-pasting
these two lines of code,
we now have our third LSTM layer,
however, now for the fourth LSTM layer,
things are going to change,
but very slightly.
We will only have one change to make,
try to guess before I do it,
what exactly is this change gonna be?
Well, let's see.
I'm going to paste what I copied before,
and now, according to you,
what do I need to change here?
Well, let's see.
The number of units equal to 50 here,
do we need to change this?
Well, no, we're going to keep 50 neurons
in this fourth LSTM layer,
because be careful, this is not the final layer
of our recurrent neural network,
this is the fourth LSTM layer,
but after that, comes the output layer,
with the output dimension,
which will be one of course,
because we're predicting just one value,
the value of the stock price at time T+1,
but here, we're adding the fourth LSTM layer,
and since this is the last LSTM layer
that we're adding,
well, this is the change that we need to make,
we need to set it equal to false,
because we're not going to return
anymore sequences,
and therefor, since the default value
of the return sequence's parameter is false,
I am just removing this parameter,
and there we go,
that's what we had to do for
the fourth LSTM layer,
just add in the LSTM class
with 50 units, and saying
we're keeping 20% dropout regularization.
Perfect, so now let's add our different LSTM layers,
by executing the codes.
So let's start with the second LSTM layer
of our RNN, execute.
There we go, second LSTM layer added.
Now let's take care of the third one,
so I'm selecting these two lines and executing,
there we go,
and finally the fourth and final LSTM layer,
there we go, fourth and final LSTM well added.
So perfect, now congratulations,
you are done with the LSTM part
of the recurrent neural network.
Now we just need to add
one final layer, which is of course the output layer,
and that's exactly what we'll do in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.