Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So we just completed part one, building the CNN,
that is we designed the architecture
of our Convolutional Neural Network,
and now we're beginning part two,
in which we will fit our CNN to our images.
So we will actually do it in one step
because we're gonna use a shortcut,
which is going to be very practical.
It is the Keras Documentation,
and what we will use it for, well,
it's for a process called image augmentation,
that basically consists of preprocessing
your images to prevent overfitting,
because what will happen then,
we will get the results in this tutorial,
but if we don't do this image augmentation,
well what we might get is a great accuracy result
on the training set,
but a much lower accuracy on the test set,
so that is exactly overfitting that corresponds
to this particular situation where you get great results
on your training set and poor results
on your test set due to an overfit on the training set.
So before fitting our CNN to our images,
let's precede to this image augmentation process.
So right now, we're gonna take a browser,
because as I just told you,
we're gonna use this Keras Documentation shortcut.
And so in your browser, you can type Keras Documentation,
all right, you can press enter, here it is.
You just take the first link, Keras Documentation.
Here we go, and that's the page we want.
So basically on this page
you get a lot of informations
about Keras and ready-to-use codes
that you can take for your deep learning project.
So right now what we need is some info, or code,
for image augmentation, image preprocessing.
So in these windows on the left,
we're gonna look for Preprocessing, here it is.
That's the section we're interested in,
and inside this section as you can see,
there are some info about sequence preprocessing,
text preprocessing, yes indeed, deep learning
can also be applied to text in a very powerful way.
And, of course, image preprocessing,
and that's what we are interested in right now.
So let's click on it, and let's see what we get.
All right, and the first thing interesting
to see is this ImageDataGenerator.
That's the first function that we're gonna use
to generate this image augmentation.
So what is image augmentation,
and how will it prevent overfitting?
Well, we know that one of the situations that lead
to overfitting is when we have few data to train our model.
In that situation, our model finds some correlations
in the few observations of the training set,
but fails to generalize this correlations
on some new observations.
And when it comes to images, we actually need
a lot of images to find and generalize some correlations,
because in computer vision,
our machine learning model doesn't seem to need
to find some correlations
between some independent variable
and some dependent variables.
It needs to find some patterns in the pixels,
and to do this it requires a lot of images.
Right now, we are working with 10,000 images,
8,000 images on the training set,
and that is actually not much
to get some great performance results.
We either need some more images,
or we can use a trick,
and that is where data augmentation comes into play.
That is the trick, because what it will do,
is it will create many batches of our images,
and in each batch it will apply some random transformations
on a random selection of our images,
like rotating them, flipping them, shifting them,
or even shearing them, and eventually what we'll get during
the training is many more diverse images
inside these batches, and therefore
a lot more material to train.
And now we understand why it is called image augmentation.
That's because the amount
of our training images is augmented.
Besides, because the transformations
are random transformations,
well our model will never find
the same picture across the batches.
So all this image augmentation trick
can only reduce overfitting.
So in summary, image augmentation is a technique
that allows us to enrich our data set, our data set,
without adding more images and therefore that allows
us to get good performance results with little
or not overfitting, even with a small amount of images.
So now, let's apply this image augmentation on our images.
And to do this, we are gonna use this shortcut
I was tell you about, which is to take ready-to-use code
that we can find on this page,
and that corresponds very well
to how we structured our data set,
because as you can see there's two ways
to preprocess our images
by applying image augmentation on them.
It's either by using this code that is based
on the flow method, or this code that is based
on the flow from directory method.
And as you might've guessed,
we are gonna use this code section here
because we are gonna take out data from this dataset
that we built, and that we structured
this specific way so that our classes
can be well identified in the separate folders,
cat or dogs, and since this dataset
is now working directory, well that's why we used
this function here, flow_from_directory.
So inside this function here, instead of having directory,
we'll put our dataset.
And so why did I call it a shortcut?
Well, that's because with this code section here,
we have everything we need to preprocess our images,
augment them, and even fitting
our Convolutional Neural Network
that we just built on our images.
So basically, that's the end of the code,
because this fit generator method
will not only fit our CNN to the training set,
but it will also test at the same time
its performance on some new operations,
which are gonna be the observations
of our test set, that is the images
of our test set folder.
So that's perfect, we have everything we need.
So this part is the image augmentation part,
where we apply several transformations like the rescale.
Well, the rescale is always compulsory
and it corresponds to the feature scanning part
of the data preprocessing phase that we know.
And then we have other transformations like shear range,
so that corresponds to shearing.
You know, sharing is a geometrical transformation
that is also called transvection.
And where the pixels are moved to a fixed direction
over a proportional distance from a line
that is parallel to the direction they're moving to.
So basically that is just a geometrical transformation
for that same purpose of augmenting our images.
And then we also have some other kinds
of transformations, like zoom range,
so this is some sort of random zoom
that we apply on our images.
Ad we also also this horizontal flip
that flips horizontally the images.
And we also have vertical flip, but that is not used here.
We can have fun and apply all the image transformations
that there are in this Keras Documentation,
but for now we will just use what we have in this example.
That will be way enough
and you'll see that we get good results.
All right, so that is the image augmentation part.
Now this image augmentation part is applied
on the training set, and then we use again
this ImageDataGenerator function
to this time only rescale the images of our test set.
And then we have these two sections,
trans_generator and validation_generator.
Well, these two sections actually create
the training set and the test set,
so what we'll do then when we are back to Spyder,
well we will call it training set and this test set,
so that we clearly see what's happening.
And basically this is in this section
that we will create this training set composed
of all these augmented images extracted
from our ImageDataGenerator,
and same, this section will create our test set
that will be used to evaluate the model performance
in this part of the code.
And same, the images of the test set are extracted
from our ImageDataGenerator
that was applied on our test set.
And then we have this code section here that will fit
our Convolutional Neural Network model on the training set,
as well as testing its performance on the test set.
So let's do it, let's take all this section here.
We are gonna make a few changes, but very few.
And now let's go back to Spyder
to paste this whole code section into our editor.
All right, and now we need to change a few things.
The first thing that we need to do first,
is to import the class that will allow
us to use this ImageDataGenerator function.
And this class is called ImageDataGenerator,
and we import this class from Keras.preprocessing.image,
and import and eventually, ImageDataGenerator.
All right, so now we have our class.
Now, next section.
All right, so in this section we won't change anything.
We will rescale all our pixel values
between zero and ones, because you know,
pixel's state value between zero and 255
and by rescaling them using this rescale = 1 / 255,
then all our pixel values will be between zero and one.
Then shear_range, that's to apply random transvections,
and we will keep this open two value.
Zoom_range, that's to apply some random zooms,
So this open two values here are just some parameters
of how much you wanna apply these random transformations,
and here we will take what Keras suggests.
And then, horizontal_flip, that means that our images
will be flipped horizontally, so that's fine.
That will generate enough transformations
so that we don't find the same image
in the different batches.
So basically we don't have anything to change here
in this code section here, and we can move
on to the next one.
Test_datagen, well same, here we only need to rescale
the pixels of the images of the test set,
so that they have values between zero and one,
so that's all fine here as well.
We don't need to change anything.
But then we have this code section here
that created the training set,
and here we have a few things to change.
So first, let's give another name
for train_generator, and call it training_set,
and let's press Alt + Shift to align everything well.
And so here, what do we need to change?
Well first, the first parameter
is where we extract the images from.
From which directory?
So it's not from the data/training directory.
Let's see where it is from.
Well, remember we have here our dataset
that is composed of two set folders, the training_set
and the test_set, and so since here
the section corresponds to the creation of the training set,
well we need to specify what this training set is,
and therefore we need to specify the paths,
that is, dataset/training_set.
And we don't have to specify the whole path
that leads to this dataset because this dataset
is already in the working directory folder.
Perfect, then, target_size.
So target_size is the size of your images
that is expected in your CNN model.
So as you can see here we chose a 64 by 64 dimension
for our images, and therefore here
we cannot keep this 150 and 150.
We need to put the dimensions expected by our CNN.
That is, 64 and 64.
Great, then the batch_size.
So that is the size of the batches
in which some random samples of our images will be included,
and that contains the number of images
that will go through the CNN,
after which the weight will be updated.
So we will keep 32 here.
This actually looks fine to train our CNN.
And finally, class_mode,
well that's the parameter indicating
if your class, your dependent variable,
is binary or has more than two categories,
and therefore since we have two classes here,
cats and dogs, well the class_mode is binary.
So great, this section is now ready.
Now let's move on to the next section.
Validation_generator, so let's actually call
it test_set, because this code section
will create the test set, and now let's align everything.
I'm going to press Alt + Shift,
and now let's see what we need to change.
So first, we need to input here the path
that lead to the test set, and that's exactly
the same as for the training set.
We need to input here dataset first,
and then test_set instead of validation.
Test_set, here we go.
Then, target_size, well that's the same.
The images of our test set will be expected
to have the 64 by 64 dimensions by our CNN,
and therefore here we also need to replace
a 150 by 64, and same here, 64.
All right, then we will also keep this batch_size of 32,
and same class mode binary,
because we have our binary outcome.
Great, and now finally last code section,
the model fit generator, where we fit our CNN
to the training set, while also testing
its performance on the test set, and therefore,
well first let's align everything again.
Here we go, and now let's change the last things.
Well the first argument that we need
to input here is out training set,
so we will replace train_generator by training_set.
Then the second arguments is the samples_per_epoch.
Well that's simply the number of images we have
in our training set, because remember
all the observations of the training set pass
through the Convolutional Neural Network during each epoch,
and since we have 8,000 images in our training set,
well here we need to replace 2,000 by 8,000, all right?
The number of epoch, well that's the number
of epochs we wanna choose to train our CNN.
And here, 50 might be a little too much,
so we will take 25 so that we don't have
to wait for too long to get our results.
Then, validation data.
So that corresponds to the test set
on which we want to evaluate the performance of our CNN,
and that is of course the test set.
So we will replace validation generator by test_set.
Almost good, the last parameter is nb_val_samples,
and that corresponds to the number of images
in our test set, and that is 2,000.
Perfect, and now we just need to change one last thing.
Can you guess what it is?
Well, we are using this fit generator method
to fit our CNN to our training set
and test its performance on the test set
at the same time, and this fit generator method
is applied onto our CNN model.
But our CNN model is not called model,
it is called classifier.
So we just need to replace model here by classifier.
And let's align this again, Alt + Shift,
so that now we apply this fit generator method
onto our classifier to fit it to the training set
and test it on the test set.
So great, now everything is ready,
we are ready to execute each of these last sections one
by one, and eventually we will get to our final results.
So let's execute them one by one.
We're gonna start by importing
the ImageDataGenerator class, here we go, well imported.
And now let's proceed to this next section to,
well actually, prepare the image augmentation
with this train_data_gen, which is an object
of the ImageDataGenerator class.
So in this section we are creating this object,
so I'm gonna press Command + Enter to execute,
and now our object
of the ImageDataGenerator class is created.
And this object is the object
that we're gonna use to augment
the images of the training set.
And now we're gonna do the same for our test set.
We are gonna create another object
of the ImageDataGenerator class,
and this object will be used to preprocess
the images of the test set.
And then, next code section.
In this code section we apply the image augmentation
itself on the images of our training set
by at the same time resizing all our images
of the training set into this 64 times 64 dimensions,
and by creating some batches of 32 images,
and then our CNN will be trained
on these images in all the different batches.
Okay, so let's execute this section.
And as you can see, that's actually very interesting to see.
Well, Keras found 8,000 images belonging to two classes,
and that is specifically thanks to the way
we organized our images into our dataset folder,
you know, splitting this dataset folder
into a test_set folder, composed of 2,000 test images,
and the training_set folder,
composed of 8,000 training images.
So that's why I was telling you
this is a great and simple way
to preprocess our dataset when we work with images.
And then, next section is the same but for the test set.
In this section we are creating the test set
and we are resizing all the images of the test set
into this 64 by 64 dimensions,
and at the same time creating some batches of 32 images.
So now let's execute this section,
and we can guess what we're gonna get now.
We should have found 2,000 images belonging
to two classes, let's check it out.
And we're going to execute, and here we go.
Found 2,000 images belonging to two classes,
so of course that's the 2,000 images of our test set.
And now finally, last section,
but I have to warn you,
now this is going to take some time.
So a good idea right now would be to run this code
just before you have some lunch or dinner,
or even take a nap.
I'm going to take a nap right now, but what I mean
is that it's not gonna take 10 seconds to execute.
It'll be rather 10 or 20 minutes,
but anyway now we are ready to execute
and find out about the final results.
So let's check it out.
I'm going to execute right now.
Are you ready?
And, go.
Here we go, first epoch, one of 25.
So as you can see, it's going to take a while
because right now it's training on the 8,000 images
of the training set, and it will do this over 25 epochs.
So let's take a break, let's get a coffee,
and lets this run on its own.
I'm gonna take a quick nap,
and I'll see you in a couple of minutes.
And here we go, the training is over.
We obtained an accuracy of 84% for the training set,
and 75% for the test set.
So what do you think of these results?
Well, not too bad, but not too good either.
Okay so first we obtained
this 84.5% accuracy on the training set.
That is not bad,
but that is not what we are mostly interested in.
What we are mostly interested in is the accuracy
of the test set, which is equal to 75%,
and the difference between the accuracy
of the training set and the accuracy
of the test set to access
whether there's overfitting or not.
So 75% accuracy on the test set is not bad.
That means that we get three correct predictions
out of four, so that's actually not too bad,
but then we get quite a large difference
between the accuracy on the training set
and the accuracy on test set.
So it's not like there is important overfitting,
but still there is a lot of room for improvement.
Not only can we improve the accuracy of the test set,
and you know a good goal that we can set ourselves
would be to make this accuracy reach an accuracy over 80%.
And besides, which we would like to get,
is a smaller difference between the accuracy
of the training set and the one of the set test.
So that's our challenge.
Let's try to increase this accuracy
of the test set over 80%, and decrease
this difference between the training set accuracy
and the test set accuracy.
This is what we'll do in the next tutorial,
but because you get to this next tutorial,
try to figure out some ideas
to improve that and reach these goals.
And I'll give you a hint.
The answer to this improvement
is in the title of this course.
So good luck, and I'll see you in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy Deep Learning.