Hello and welcome
to the final step of part two, building the RNN,
about fitting the RNN to the training set, of course.
Now, so far we have a highly robust wrecker renewal network,
but we have not made the connection yet
with our training set.
So that's exactly the last thing we have to do.
And besides, it is in this tutorial
that the training will happen.
Because once we execute this last line of code of part two,
of course, well, the training will take place and in the end
we will not only have a robust neural network,
but mostly, we will have a smart one.
That is an intelligent, trained, neural network,
to be able to predict in some way, the upward trends,
and downward trends of the Google set price.
So it will be specifically intelligent.
But there we go, it's the last step of this part two.
And let's tackle this.
So, you actually know how to do it,
if you followed ANN and CNN,
we need to take, of course this time,
our regressor,
and not our test fire.
And then dot and then use of course
the fit method, which will, not only
connect our neural network to the training set
and will also execute the training over
a certain number of epochs
that we will chose in the same fit method.
So fit and now, we need to input
four arguments, which are going to be
first the input of the training set
that features, or if you want the independent variables
of the training set.
Which will be the input of the neural network
and will be forward propagated
to the output, which will be the prediction
and that will compare to the ground truth that is contained
in Y train.
And speaking of the ground truth,
that is exactly the next argument we need to input
after X train.
That is Y train.
So lets start inputting these first two arguments.
First one is X train, then input.
And the second one is Y train, the ground truth.
Alright, and then we need to add two more arguments.
Which are going to be the number of epochs.
That is on how many iterations do you want your
wrecker renewal network to be trained.
Or if you want how many times do you want the whole
data, the whole training data to be forward propagated
inside the neural network,
and then back propagated to update the wait.
Well that number you choose it in the epochs parameter.
Spelled this way epcohs.
And the number were going to choose is going to be
100. And again
you can choose several numbers, but I experimented before
and you know I tried with first 25 epochs
I noticed that there wasn't a convergence of the loss.
So I tried with more epochs, 50
still not some convergence.
Then I tried 100, and there I observed some convergence.
So I think 100 is the right number of epochs.
For this kind of problem, besides
we don't have that much data.
We only have the Google stock prize for 5 years
and by the way if you want you can train
this wrecker renewal network on even more than 5 years.
The data is available online, it's the real
Google stock prize that you can take from
many financial sources.
One of them can be for example,
Yahoo finance.
So feel free to play with it
and experiment even more to create some
maybe even more robust wrecker renewal networks.
But anyway with 5 years of training data
well 100 epochs turned out to be
a good choice, with some convergence.
So 100 epochs, and now we have
one final argument to input.
And actually this will be the final element we will add
for this part two, building the RNN.
And that is, the batch size.
So our network is going to be trained.
Not on single observations
going into the neural network.
It's going to be trained on batches of observations
that is batches of stock prices
going into the neural network.
So instead of updating the wait,
every stock price being forward propagated into
the neural network, and then generating an error
that is back propagated into the neural network.
We will do that, every 32 stock prices
because as you might just guess
we're going to choose a batch size of 32.
There we go, that's our last argument.
Batch
underscore size
equals 32
perfect, and now, you made it.
Not only you build a super robust wrecker renewal network
but also you're ready to train it on 5 years
of the Google stock price.
So let's do this, I'm going to
select this line, and let's make our wrecker renewal network
the smartest stock price predictor.
There we go, the training is launched.
It is on it's way, so
and there we go.
Starting with the first epoch.
Epoch of 1 out of 100
and what we can see there are the different batches
going into the neural network.
Generating some errors and then the errors
back propagated into the neural network.
And that's every 32 stock prices.
And we know because we choose a batch size of 32.
So that's why you see in the epoch,
these numbers of the batches out of 1198.
That's exactly what you see
and on the right you can observe the loss.
That is going to be reduced at each iteration.
Hopefully, well that is what I observed.
And in the end you should be able to
observe some convergence.
That is in the last 20 or 10 epochs
the loss shouldn't be decreasing much.
So there we go,
the training is happening.
And now as you can see it's going to take
a while it's actually going to take around 20 minutes
on my computer.
So what I'm going to do is have a little
break here, I'm going to accelerate the video.
And I'll see you at the end of the training.
[Piano Music]
Alright we have just reached the final epoch
out of the 100 epochs in total.
I just had time to make a quick nap.
It's perfect, and now the training is about to end.
There we go,
the training is over.
So let's have a look at the final loses and see
if I was right about the convergence.
So we started with a loss of 5%,
0.0531.
Then of course after the first update of the wait
to improve the predictive power
well the loss immediately reduced.
So that's normal.
And then, epoch by epoch
it was reduced more and more.
So here we go, from 47 to 43
from 43 to 41
then it went back up to 46.
Then went back down to 41, then 38.
46 again, then 37, 36.
And progressively, like every 10 epoch,
we clearly see the loss decreasing.
And lets see when we were halfway there
at epoch 50 out of 100
we reached 0.0022
and then it decreased even more 0.0021
0.0019,
0.0018,
0.0017
18 again, 15
16, 17, 15.
And as you can see, in the end
in the last 20 epochs,
well it's staying around the same level
that is around 0.0015.
So if you want you could try to
do it with more epochs, I didn't try it.
I didn't try with 200 epochs,
but I'm sure you wouldn't get a loss
that with the drop out regularization were added.
Well we have prevented over fitting enough
to not decrease this loss even more.
You know if you obtain a loss too small in the end
well you might get some over fitting.
You're predictions will be close
to the real Google stock price.
But in the training set
in the training data, which I remind
is the data of the past.
So not the data we're interested in
to make predictions.
So you might get some great loss
on the training data.
But then some really bad loss
on the test data.
And that's exactly what over fitting is about.
So that's why when you do the training
on the training set, well you must be careful
not to obtain over fitting
and therefore not to try to decrease
the loss as much as possible.
And that's why here it seems that we get
really good results.
But anyway we're going to observe
the predictions then in part 3.
Making the Predictions and Visualizing the Results.
So we'll clearly see, in the end
we will clearly have a chart,
Showing the graph of the prediction.
That is, the predicted Google stock price.
And on the same chart, the real Google stock price.
So we will see how it manages to follow the trends
of the Google stock price.
We will see that in the end,
it will be very exciting to visualize.
And now, congratulations
you are now done with part 2.
And you have just reached
part 3, Making the Predictions and Visualizing the Results.
So we are just a few tutorials left from visualizing
these final results, and conclude
on the power of RRNN.
So I can't wait to start this part 3 with you.
And of course I can't wait to reach
the very exciting moment
of visualizing the results.
We will get to is very fast, and until then.
Enjoy deep learning.