Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
Alright I'm super excited because we are about to get
the final results on new observations with
the tested results.
And so we will see if the results are close
to the training set results.
That is if even on new observations, we can predict
three correct ratings out of four.
These are binary ratings, but still,
this would be excellent results
and we would definitely succeed at making
a recommended system.
So let's do it, let's find out about these results.
So, good news, it's actually going to be pretty easy
because we are gonna do it the efficient way,
we are going to take this code,
because getting the tested results is going to be quite
similar as getting the trend set results.
The only difference is that there is
not gonna be a training.
So we will remove at least one full loop.
It will be the full loop over the epochs.
But, that might not be the only full loop
that we remove and that will lead us
to the essential, the crucial point to understand.
And this crucial point is linked to MCMC,
Markov chain Monte Carlo techniques.
So we will get there very quickly
but first let's prepare the code.
Alright, so the first thing we're gonna do is,
just copy this code and we will make the required change.
So, pasting that here and now let's see what we have
to change to get the test set results.
Alright, so first there is no training right now,
so we don't need to loop over the epoch,
and therefore I'm going go remove nb epoch equals 10
and I'm going to remove this first full loop.
Alright, then we need to align everything.
So, let's do it, and there we go.
Alright, so now what change do we need to make.
Well first, we will change the name of this variable
to compute the loss.
It is now not the train loss but the test loss,
that we are trying to measure.
Then we will keep the counter that we initialize at zero,
and we will increment it by one at each step.
Alright, so all good for the first two lines.
Then we have this loop over all the users
of our, this time, test set.
In here, do we need a batch size?
Well, no, of course.
Because the batch size is just a technique
specific to the training.
You know the batch size is a parameter
that you tune to get more or less better performance results
on the training set, and therefore, on the test set.
But gathering the observations in the batch size
is only for the training phase.
And therefore, we will remove everything
that is related to the batch size.
So we remove the step and we take our users,
up to the last user, because basically we will
make some predictions for each of the users one by one.
And therefore, we can also remove the zero here
because that's the default start.
Here we go, for id user in range nb users,
so basically now we are looping over all the users,
one by one.
Okay.
So for each user and now we go into the loop.
Now, same, we have to remove the batch sizes here,
we don't need them.
And there is more, since we are gonna make some predictions
for each of the users one by one,
we will replace this batch size by actually one.
And batch size one.
Okay, now just to make things very clear
we are going to replace vk by actually v and v0,
which remember was the target by vt.
So that now it's very clear that vt is the target.
But now v is the input on which we will make the prediction.
So now the question is, we are dealing with the test set
so we are trying to predict the ratings in the test set.
So it would make sense to replace both
the training sets here by test sets,
but do we actually need to replace both training sets here?
Well let's see, let's start with the target vt.
So vt contains the original ratings of the test set,
so that is what we will compare to our predictions
in the end.
And, of course, we need to replace training set here
by test set because we want to compare the real ratings
of the test set to our predictions.
But here for v, the input, do you think we need
to replace the training set by test set?
If your answer to that question is correct,
then that means you really understand what's going on.
So the answer to that question is,
no, we must not replace training set here by test set.
We actually need to keep the training set.
And why is that?
It's because actually the training set is the input
that will be used to activate the hidden neurons
to get the output.
Right now the training set contains the ratings
of the training set and it doesn't contain the answers
of the test set.
But, by using the inputs of the training set
we will activate the neurons of our RBM
to predict the ratings of the movies
that were not rated yet, and that is the ratings
of the test set.
So we need this as input to get the predicted ratings
Because we are getting these predicted ratings
from the inputs of the training set
that are used to activate the neurons of our RBM.
And that's the first very important point to understand,
that we are using the inputs of the training set
to activate the neurons of the RBM
to get the predicted ratings of the test set.
Alright so now that you understand this first
crucial point we can move on to what's next.
But then you will see that there is another very crucial
point to understand, that is more related to mathematics
but that is fascinating because it is related
to MCMC techniques, Markov chains Monte Carlo techniques
and that is of course is related to the random walk.
Or more precisely you'll see the blind walk.
Alright so let's move onto what's next.
So what's next is this line of code that computes
the probabilities that the hidden nodes equal one
given the values of divisible nodes in the original
input vector that is given the original ratings.
And this ph0 was just something we needed to train the model
with cdk, remember that that's actually what is needed
to start this loop to make this Gibbs chain give something.
So that is just for the training and therefore,
we don't need it for the test set.
So let's remove it and let's move on to the next step.
So the next step is, again,
about this contrastive divergence
and here we are getting very close
to the second crucial point to understand.
Actually we're getting to it right now,
so let me explain.
The question that I'm asking you now
to get to this second crucial point to understand
is that to get our predictions of the test set ratings
then according to you, do we need to apply again
the CASE step contrastive divergence?
Or more precisely the question is,
do we need to make CASE steps of the random walk,
that is 10 steps of the random walk,
or do we need to make one step of the random walk?
That's the one million dollar question.
Do we need to make 10 steps or one step
to get our final prediction?
And the answer to that question is,
we need to make one step.
We need to make one step because the principal
of the random walk, and actually this is not exactly
the random walk because in the random walk
the probabilities are the same.
Here, even if it's a Markov chain
the probabilities are not the same
so it's not a random walk, so it's rather a blind walk
and the principle of the blind walk is that,
imagine you were blindfolded and you had
to make 100 steps on a straight line
without getting out of the straight line.
Well, you will be trained with Gibbs sampling
to make 100 steps by staying on the straight line
but you're blindfolded so you know it's not
easy to make some steps and always stay
on the straight line, so, you know sometimes you go a little
bit on the left, on the right and 100 steps after it's
hard for you to be on the straight line.
But you were trained to make these 100 steps,
staying on the straight line being blindfolded.
And that is by doing some random steps.
So that's why it is close to the random walk technique
and the MCMC but the difference is that in the random walk
the probabilities are the same and here that's not the case.
Because, of course, all of the probabilities are different.
But that's the thing you are trained to make 100 steps
by staying on a straight line,
and so the principle of all this
is that you are trained to do this for 100 steps
so that when you make one step, when you have to take
the challenge to make only one step and still be on
that straight line, well you will have high chance
of doing it because you were trained to do it for 100 steps.
You were trained to stay on the straight line
for 100 steps being blindfolded so when you have to do the
same exercise it's much easier because you have to make it
for one step, well you will have high chance to succeed.
And so in that example, the correct prediction
would be to manage to stay on the straight line
after one step and the incorrect prediction
would be to get out of the straight line after one step.
So that's the whole principle of the blind walk technique
from MCMC, Markov chain Monte Carlo.
That's close to the random walk
but keep in mind that the probabilities are not the same.
And so now, you might have the correct answer
to the question I just asked you.
Here we were trained to make 10 steps blindfolded
so that at the end of the 10 steps we stay
on the straight line.
So for one step we will be much better at it.
We will be much better at staying on the straight line
on one step.
That's the whole principle behind it,
and therefore the correct answer to the question,
do we need to make one step or 10 steps?
Is of course, we need to make one step.
So our prediction will be directly the result
of one round trip of Gibbs sampling.
One iteration, one step of the blind walk.
Alright, so let's make the step
and then we'll get all our predictions of the test set
in one shot.
So things are gonna be very easy.
And so now, the first thing we have to do, of course,
is to remove this full loop because we don't have
to make 10 steps.
We only have to make one step.
So, to make this step we're gonna start with an if condition
because you know that's always the same idea we want to test
the predictions to the ratings of the test set
that actually exist.
You know, in the test set we still have some ratings
that are existent in the test set
but we also still have some minus one ratings.
So the minus one are ratings that just never happened.
Whether it was in the training set or in the test set.
And we don't want to consider these ratings in the test set,
of course, that's always the same id.
And so we are making this if condition
to filter these non-existent ratings of the test set.
And so to do this, we're gonna take the len function
and parenthesis.
And so now we're gonna get the ratings that are existent
and we are gonna get them from the target,
because we don't want to get them from the predictions,
that wouldn't make sense.
We wanna get them from the target
because that's the target that contains
the original ratings of the test set.
And so here we take vt, and then again, some brackets
and inside the brackets we take all the ratings
that are existent.
And the ratings that are existent are the ratings
zero one, that is the ratings larger than zero.
Alright, and so, if len, the length that is the number
of divisible nodes containing set ratings
must be larger than zero, and in that condition we can make
some predictions.
You know that's just a condition to allow ourselves
to make some predictions.
So no worries this will most of the time be verified.
Alright, now time to make the predictions.
And according to what I've just explained
with the blind walk, well, we only have to make one step
of the blind walk that is Gibbs sampling.
Okay, so we don't have a k anymore
because we don't have a loop over 10 steps,
we only have one step so we're gonna remove
the k here and remove the k here as well
for the visible nodes.
And here that's the same, remove the k
for the input visible nodes that we'll use to get
the first hidden node, well actually the only hidden node
because there is one step only.
And here we remove the k because we only have one vector
of hidden nodes to get our final predictions,
the vector of predicted ratings.
And that's all, that's the only step of the blind walk.
Then here we will get rid of this line
because this was just for the training,
you know, we used this line to only consider
the existent ratings for the training
but then we are not doing any training now
so let's remove it.
And then here that's the same, that was just to get one
of the argument of the train function, the phk argument.
And again, since we're not doing any training anymore
well, we will get rid of these two lines that were just
to update the weights in the training phase.
So goodbye, and here we go.
We are getting close to the final result.
Now we have to update, not the train loss
but the test loss.
And again, we take the mean function from the torch library
and here be careful, we are still taking the absolute
distance between the prediction and the target.
So, the target is, this time not v0
but we called it vt, then here that's the same.
We take all the ratings that are existent
in the test set.
And the prediction is not vk,
because there is one step this time so we called it v.
And here that's the same, we take the existent ratings
so we take vt larger than zero.
Remember with this vt larger than zero
we are getting the indexes of the cells
that have the existent ratings.
Alright, so perfect and then we need to update the counter.
That's to normalize the test loss.
And finally, we are getting to the last line of code
of this whole RBM model, which is
to print the final test loss.
So again, there is no epoch here so we will get rid
of all this.
Here we go, then in the first string here we will replace
loss by test loss, you know to specify
that is a test loss.
And, of course, it would be a shame to make a mistake
in the end.
In the very end we need to replace train loss here
by test loss, that we divide by s
to normalize.
Alright, so now, as usual, one last check
before we execute because even if we get no warning
it's quite easy to make a mistake
besides when we copy paste something.
So let's see, we start with a test loss of zero
then the counter to zero.
We loop over all our users.
Then for all the ratings that are existent
in the test set, we sample the hidden nodes first
then we use these hidden nodes as input
to sample divisible nodes.
And we do this for only one round trip
according to the MCMC theory.
Then, actually, this needs to be in the if
because we are still computing the test loss
only for the existent ratings.
And here that's the same, we increment s,
still when that is verified.
So there we go, now it's better.
So with this test loss line of code
we are computing the mean of the absolute distances
between the predicted ratings and the real ratings.
Then we increment s by one, and finally we print the final
normalized test loss.
Okay, perfect, so I think everything is all good now
let's get the final result and let's hope we get
a normalized test loss around the 0.25
training loss that we obtained for the training set.
So let's do this, fingers crossed.
And let's press Command or Control plus, Enter to execute
and we get a test loss of 0.24.
Which is definitely excellent,
because that's for new observations, so for new observations
for new movies we managed to predict some correct ratings
three times out of four and even better than that.
Because we are slightly below 25%.
So that's excellent results and we definitely managed
to make a robust recommended system,
but, remember this was the easy one.
Predicting binary ratings zero one and in the next part
we'll take it to the next level because we will be
predicting some ratings from one to five.
So that will increase the complexity of the problem,
of course, working with binary values is easier
and less complex than working with some continuous values
but at least you'll know how to make
two different recommended systems by applying
two different deep learning models.
But, the good news is that, even if the problem
is more complex, while the model that we're gonna make
in the next part, that is the outer encoders,
is actually a much more simple model than this
Boltzmann machine.
You'll see that very quickly with the intuition lectures
that it is actually more simple.
But, never the less, despite the simplicity
there is this amazing contrast with what it is able
to make.
You're gonna see that we will get some amazing predictions
even for ratings between one to five.
So I can't wait to make these powerful outer encoders
with you, have fun with the intuition lectures
and I'll see you after that for the practical tutorials
and until then enjoy deep learning.