Hello and welcome back
to the course on deep Learning.
Today we're starting a brand new deep Learning
model; the Boltzmann Machine.
And it's going to be a very exciting section.
For one reason at least.
The fact that a lot of this information
is not that easily available online.
You can't just find lots and lots of tutorials.
This is very advanced stuff,
and simplified intuitive tutorials
are just not that readily available.
So we're very excited to bring you these
and help you get ahead in the space
of deep Learning and advancing your skills.
So let's get started.
So here we've got a list of items
that we will discuss.
List of models, deep Learning models
which we've already looked into
in this course.
We've talked about artificial neural networks,
convolutional neural networks
and recurrent neural networks
and that's summarized this supervised side
of deep Learning.
Then we also spoke about self organizing maps,
which was our first step into unsupervised
deep Learning.
And today we're talking about Boltzmann machines.
So let's have a look at all of these
in a diagrammatical representation.
So here we've got an artificial neural network.
With the input layer,
possibly multiple hidden layers and an output layer.
And then we've got a convolutional neural network
with the convolution layer,
the pooling layer,
the flattening layer
and then an ANN sitting on the end.
Then we've got the recurrent neural network where
the hidden layer feeds back into itself,
and therefore facilitates analysis of temporal data
and finally we've got the self organizing map,
which helps you reduce your dimensionality
and represents something,
it represents your data in a more understandable way.
So, even though the self organizing map is a
unsupervised type of deep learning model,
there is something that unites all of these four together,
and that is that all these four are actually directed models
so there is a direction in which the model operates.
As you can see these arrows are in the case of a sum.
You've got the data and then the data connects,
the information from the data goes to the nodes
on your map, on your output map.
So there's always a direction in them,
and that is where Boltzmann machines really stand out.
Boltzmann machines are undirected models.
They don't have a direction,
so you can see that there are connections here
but there are actually no arrows in these connections,
all these connections go both ways.
So that is a very very fundamental and fascinating
thing about Boltzmann machines
and that is going to radically change
how we're going to be talking about them
compared to other models.
So, I hope you're excited about this.
Lets have a look a bit closer at a Boltzmann machine
and understand what's going on.
So heres a Boltzmann machine,
and right away you can see that we've got hidden nodes
in red and we've got visible nodes here in blue,
and by the way we specifically used other colors here
simply because we wanted to help you
visually remember that these models,
the Boltzmann machines,
are different to other models so.
Hence a bit different colors
than what you're used to probably.
So here, we've got the visible nodes at the bottom, three,
and we've got seven hidden nodes
just for simplicity's sake and
the thing here you'll notice,
probably the first thing that stands out
in comparison to other neural networks,
which we already talked about,
this model doesn't have an output layer right?
So there's an input layer,
there's a hidden layer,
and there's no output layer.
That's number one, probably the biggest thing right.
Why would you even have a neural network
if there's no output layer.
The second thing is that of course everything
is connected to everything,
there's no specific layering per say.
Everything is just hyper connected to everything,
and number three, as we said,
there is no direction in these connections.
They're all bi-directional so they,
the connection happens both ways.
So those three things really make Boltzmann machines
look different and a bit weird compared to
everything else we've discussed before,
and so how do we go about understanding Boltzmann machines.
I just wanted also to point out that
in a lot of the tutorials that you'll find online,
they often jump straight to restricted Boltzmann machines,
so RBM's because they're simpler,
they're more practical,
they're actually used in practice
rather than Boltzmann machines which are more with
theoretical things,
but personally for me understanding Boltzmann machines
was the key to understanding everything else
that we're going to be discussing in this section.
As soon as you understand Boltzmann machines
and you're getting your head around them,
everything else just falls into place
and it's kind of a shame that usually people
miss out on this, but we wanted to make sure that
we're going to cover this off and
my goal to that by the end of this tutorial
you're going to walk away understanding
the intuition behind Boltzmann machines
and exactly what's going on.
So, let's dive straight into it.
How do we understand these Boltzmann machines?
So where do we start,
do we start with the lack of the output layer,
do we start with the hyper connectivity,
or do we start with the bi-direction?
Well actually none of those.
We're going to start by looking at one little tip
that I'm going to give you,
that really helped me understand everything
and made it click for me
and that little tip is, look at the visible nodes.
Right, look at these visible nodes
and you can see that they are all connected
between each other,
and when I saw that
I was trying to understand from myself
why are they connected?
What's the point of connecting visible nodes?
Once you input data,
it's fixed, right?
You have a row of data and you just input it and
there's no point in these connections
between these visible nodes,
you're not going to be adjusting the weights or training,
because that data is fixed. It's a given.
Well, that is where the flaw lies.
That's where the assumption isn't correct.
Boltzmann machines are different,
are fundamentally different to all other algorithms
and for them they don't just expect input data.
What they do is they generate data.
They generate information in all of these nodes,
regardless of whether there's and input node
or a hidden node.
For a Boltzmann machine all of these nodes are the same.
It doesn't distinguish or doesn't discriminate
between these nodes, and these nodes.
That's just for us.
For a Boltzmann machine this whole thing
is working with it's a system,
it's generating states of this system,
and the best way to think about it is
through an example that Geoffrey Hinton once gave
of a nuclear power plant.
So here we've got a diagram of a nuclear power plant,
and as you can see it's quite a simplified diagram
and normally there's lots and lots more
moving parts to this facility
but at the same time,
we can already see that there's a lot going on.
Let's say that there are certain things that we can measure
and we do measure about the nuclear power plant,
about the status of the nuclear power plant.
So for instance, and important parameter that
we should be measuring is the
temperature inside the containment unit.
Then, for example,
we could be measuring how quickly this turbine is spinning.
Another thing we could be measuring, for instance,
not as important but still crucial to the operation of the
power plant is, for instance, the pressure inside this pump.
Because, if it's too high or it's too low
that could mean a problem.
Then we could be measuring how much
electricity it is outputting.
So lot's of different things that we're measuring about
the power plant,
but at the same time there could be a lot of
odd things that we're not measuring.
For example, the speed of the wind.
Or even if we are measuring the speed of the wind,
we might not be measuring the moisture of the soil
in this specific location, or this specific location.
Or we might not be measuring the
thickness of the cooling tower wall
at a height 20 meters at this specific
radial location.
So there can be lots of different parameters
of the nuclear power plant that we're not measuring,
but at the same time all these parameters all together,
they all form one system and they all work together,
and that is what the Boltzmann machine represents.
The Boltzmann machine is a representation
of a certain system.
In our case, a nuclear power plant,
and the visible nodes are just merely things
that we can and do measure,
and the hidden nodes are things
that we can't or don't measure.
The way this whole model works is that,
instead of just waiting for us to input values
for it to model the states,
what it does is the Boltzmann machine is capable
of generating all of the values.
All of the nodes, on it's own.
It doesn't need any inputs it just generates
parameters on its own and for,
in our case what does that mean?
It just generates different states of our system
It looks at a state where temperature is
a certain temperature,
the speed of the wind is a certain speed of the wind,
and the moisture or the pressure in the pump
is a certain pressure in the pump.
So basically it looks at one state,
and then it looks at another state
and then it says, okay what if the temperatures higher,
the wind is faster,
the pressure in the pump is lower,
the moisture of the earth is lower or higher
it doesn't matter.
So it just keeps generating all these different states,
it's capable of doing that.
That is how the Boltzmann machine works
and that is the essence of why it's not a
deterministic deep learning model,
it's a stochastic deep learning model or also,
a better way to call it is
a generative deep learning model
because it generates these states.
So how does it learn?
How does it learn on an intuitive level for us?
How do we understand it on an intuitive level?
Well, the way a Boltzmann machine works is
we've got this system or this machine that
describes our different states of our system.
What we want, is we want to use our training data.
The hundred, or thousand, or tens of thousands
of rows that we have.
We want to feed it into this Boltzmann machine as the inputs
to help it adjust the weights of this system accordingly,
so that it actually resembles our system.
So it doesn't resemble any
nuclear power plant in the world,
any possible or impossible nuclear power plant,
it actually learns from what we feed it in.
It learns how, what are the possible connections
between all of these parameters.
How do they influence each other and therefore,
it becomes a system, a machine that represents our system.
It is specific to our nuclear power plant.
So what's the benefit of that?
Well the benefit of that is,
once we've done the learning,
once all of these weights are adjusted
and the Boltzmann machine understands
how all of these parameters interact with each other
and how they, what kind of constraints should exist
between them in order for this system to be
the system that we're modeling.
Once that's all done we can use the Boltzmann machine to,
for example, in the case of a nuclear plant,
to monitor our nuclear power plant.
Because we've modeled it using good behavior,
we've modeled it, behavior that hasn't led to any
meltdown or any explosions,
we know what is normal for the nuclear power plant.
Then the Boltzmann machine will help us understand
what is abnormal behavior.
This is a great example of when unsupervised learning
is the way to go.
You cannot really model a nuclear meltdown
through supervised learning
because you'd have to have an example
of a nuclear meltdown on that power plant,
or multiple nuclear meltdowns across the world
and you don't really have that luxury of
having all of this training data
with actual nuclear meltdowns.
You have to model it in an unsupervised manor,
and that's exactly what a Boltzmann machine does.
Learning through good examples,
it understands how the system works in it's normal state,
in acceptable state and through that it helps us
model what the system would look like,
or what looks like,
or what is an abnormal state and model those scenarios
and recognize those scenarios,
and therefore monitor the nuclear power plant.
So that's just an example of a nuclear power plant.
You can probably think of lots more examples
when unsupervised learning would come in handy,
as opposed to supervised learning.
Hopefully that now explains the
design of these Boltzmann machines that why,
first of all, we don't have an output layer
because we're not outputting any value.
We are creating a model that describes our system.
At the same time, why all of these nodes are interconnected
because as we kind of could sense from the diagram,
all of these parameters are possibly
interconnected with each other.
We cannot deprive the system of being able to
connect the speed of the turbine with,
for instance, the moisture in the air on that day.
So, it will decide for itself if there's a connection
and how strong that connection is.
We have to give it the opportunity to connect everything
and also, the directionality that the
important thing to understand there is that
for us, these are visible nodes and these are hidden nodes.
For a Boltzmann machine, all of the nodes are equal.
It does not discriminate between
these nodes or these nodes.
For a Boltzmann machine doesn't see these colors,
all of these parameters are interconnected
and therefore it had to be undirected.
It cannot have just direction going one way because
Boltzmann and machine does not understand what's invisible
it's a hidden parameter.
These are all parameters of the system
for the Boltzmann machine
and it has to be able to have
all the connections going both ways.
So there we go.
That explains those three things about the Boltzmann machine
that are so different to the standard neural networks
that we've, we're used to working with now
and hopefully this gives you an intuitive understanding
of how Boltzmann machines work and
what exactly they do.
In the further tutorials in this section,
we will dive deeper into Boltzmann machines.
Can't wait to see you next time
and until then, enjoy deep learning.