Hello, and welcome back
to the course on deep learning.
Alright, today we're talking about the activation function.
Let's get straight into it.
So, this is where we left off previously.
We talked about the structure of one neuron.
So, there it is in the middle.
We know that it has some inputs values coming in.
It's got some weights.
Then it calculates the weighted sum of those inputs
and then applies the activation function
and step three, it passes on the signal to the next neuron.
And that's what we're talking about today.
We're talking about the value
that is going to be passed over.
So, we're talking about the activation
function that's being applied.
So, what options do we have for the activation function?
Well, we're gonna look at four different types
of activation functions that you can choose from.
Of course, there are more different types
of activation functions.
But these are the predominant ones
that you'll be hearing about
and that we'll be using in this course.
So, here is the threshold function.
This is what it looks like.
So, on the x-axis, you have the weighted sum of inputs.
On the y-axis you have just the values from zero to one.
And basically, the threshold function
is a very simple type of function
where if the value is less than zero,
then the threshold function passes on zero.
If the value is more than zero or equal to zero
then threshold function passes on a one.
So, it's basically kind of like a yes no type of function.
Very, very straightforward.
Very kind of like rigid type of function.
Either yes or no, no other options.
So, there you go.
That's how it works, very simple function.
Let's move on to something a bit more complex now.
The sigmoid function.
A very interesting formula
that we have here you'll see just now.
There is one divided by one plus e to the power of minus x.
Whereas in this case of course,
x is the value of the weighted sums.
So, this is what the sigmoid looks like.
It's a function which is used in the logistic regression
if you recall from the machine learning course.
So, what is good about this function is that it is smooth.
Unlike the threshold function this one
doesn't have those kinks in its curve
and therefore it's just nice and smooth gradual progression.
So, anything below zero, it just like drops off.
Above zero, it approximates towards one.
And this sigmoid function is very useful
in the final layer, in the output layer.
Especially when you're trying to predict probabilities.
And we'll see that throughout this course.
And then we've got the rectifier function.
Rectifier function, even though it has a kink
is one of the most popular functions
for artificial neural networks.
So, it goes all the way to zero.
It is zero, and then from there
it gradually progresses as the input value
increases as well.
And we'll see that throughout the course.
We'll see that in other intuition tutorials
and we'll also see that how we use this function
in the practical side of the course.
And I will comment on this a bit more
in a few slides from now.
So, just remember that a rectifier function
is one of the most used functions
in artificial neural networks.
And finally, we've got one more function
that you will probably hear about.
It's the hyperbolic tangent function.
It's very similar to the sigmoid function
but here the hyperbolic tangent function
goes below zero.
So, the values go from zero to one, or approximately to one.
And go from zero to minus one on the other side.
And that can be useful in some applications.
So, we're not going to go into too much depth
on each one of these functions.
I just wanted to acquaint you with them
so that you know what they look like
and what they're called.
And if you like to get some additional reading,
then check out this paper by Xavier Glorot,
called deep sparse rectifier neural networks, 2011 paper.
And there you will find out
exactly why the rectifier function
is such a valuable function.
Why it's so popularly used.
But nevertheless, for now, you don't really
need to know all of those things.
For now, we're just going to start applying them.
We're going to start using them more, more and more.
And so, when you feel comfortable with the practical
side of things, then you can go
and refer to this paper, and then you'll
be able to soak in that knowledge much quicker
and it'll make much more sense.
So, but just keep this in mind
that when you're ready, when you feel that you're ready
then you can go and refer to this paper
and get some valuable knowledge from there.
So, just to quickly recap.
We have the threshold activation function
which looks like this.
The sigmoid activation function
We have the rectifier function,
and we have the hyperbolic tangent function.
And now to finish off this tutorial
let's quickly do a few exercises.
So, we'll just do two quick exercises
to help that knowledge sink in.
So, first one is we've got an example here
of a neural network with just one neuron
and then right away, the output layer.
And the question is, assuming that
your dependent variable is binary,
so it's either zero or one,
which threshold function would you use?
So, out of the one's that we discussed.
We have the threshold function, the sigmoid function,
the rectifier function, and we've got
the hyperbolic tangent function.
In their raw forms, which ones would you be able to use
for a binary variable?
Okay, so, the answers here are,
there's two options that we can approach this with.
So, number one is the threshold activation function.
Because we know that it's between zero and one
and it gives you a zero under certain values
and then otherwise it gives you ones,
so it only can give you two values.
It fits perfectly, fits this requirement perfectly
and therefore, you can just say y equals
the threshold function of your weighted sum,
and that's it.
And in the second case, which you could use
is the sigmoid activation function.
It is actually also between zero and one.
Just what we need.
But at the same time, you want just zero or one right.
So, it's not exactly what we need
but in this case what you could use it as
is the probability of y being yes or no.
So, we want y to be zero or one.
But instead we'll say that the sigmoid activation function
tells us the probability of y being equal to one.
So, basically, the closer you get to the top,
the more likely it is that this is indeed
a one or a yes rather than a no.
And so, that's very similar
to the logistic regression approach.
And those are just two examples
if you have a binary variable.
And now, let's have a look at another practical application.
Let's have a look at how all this will play out
if we had a neural network like this.
So, in the first input layer we have some inputs.
They are sent off to our first hidden layer,
and then an activation function is applied.
And usually what you would apply here,
and what you will see throughout this course is
we're gonna apply a rectifier activation function.
So, it would look something like that.
We apply the rectifier activation function
and then from there, the signals
would be passed on to the output layer
where the sigmoid activation function
would be applied and that would be our final output,
and that could predict a probability for instance.
So, this combination is gonna be quite common
where in the hidden layers we apply the rectifier function
and then in the output layer we apply the sigmoid function.
So, there we go, hope you enjoyed today's tutorial.
Now, you are quite well versed
in the four different types of activation functions
and you will get some hands on practical experience
with them throughout this course.
We'll be using them all over place.
So, you'll get to know them quite intimately
and you should be quite comfortable with them.
But for now, this is the knowledge
that you need to progress and understand
what is going to be happening further down in this course.
And on that note, I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then, enjoy deep learning.