Hello and welcome back to the course on deep learning.
Today we're going to have some fun,
here we've got the Boltzmaan distribution article
on Wikipedia and we're going to modify it.
So I haven't modified a Wikipedia article
in ages but here I thought it would make sense
to add a little bit to this article
and I would like to see if it's going to stand
the test of time, so let's go ahead and do this.
So here is an article, there's the formula
which we talked about, the probability
and now if we scroll down you'll see here,
it says...
There we go, in mathematics, in more general mathematical
settings the Boltzmann distribution is also known
as the Gibbs measure, in statistics and machine learning
it is called a log-linear model.
So how about we add some information
about deep learning here, it's got statistics,
it's got machine learning, but not deep learning.
I think it's fair to say it should say something
about deep learning, and specifically the Boltzmann machine,
so if you search here for machine you'll see that
it doesn't mention the Boltzmann machine whatsoever.
So how about we change that, so I've logged in,
we're here, lets go to edit source and then we'll go to
switch to editor, to visual editing
and now if we scroll down here, alright,
so let's copy in some text I've prepared.
In deep learning the Boltzmann distribution is used
in the sampling distribution of stochastic neural networks
such as the Boltzmann machine.
And to be consistent, let's add some links,
so there's the Boltzmann machine,
there we go that's the Boltzmann machine over there,
let's add the link, yep done,
then in deep learning,
there we go deep learning we're going to link that,
Is it going to link it for us?
Oh okay, deep learning, yep that's the one
and we want stochastic neural networks,
that's the one as well, let's link that one,
let's just make sure we have the right one here,
stochastic neural network, done.
Alright, save changes,
and it says describe what you changed,
added use case in deep learning,
added, yeah added use case, this is a minor edit,
and how about yeah, I would like to watch this page,
save changes, okay let's have a look,
so if I'm gonna open an incognito tab now,
let's see if I can see the change still.
Haha!
That's so cool, in deep learning the Boltzmann distribution
is used in the sampling distribution
of stochastic neural networks such as the Boltzmann machine.
That is so cool, so when you're watching this video,
just do me a favor please, can you go to this page
Boltzmann distribution on Wikipedia
and see if it's still there, and post in the comments
if it's not or if it is, I'm just curious
of how long it will stay, this is so cool.
Okay, alright, well there we go,
congratulations we did this together,
this is our little contribution to the world.
Hopefully we'll make more, of course with all the knowledge
on deep learning that we're gathering and recreating
and things we'll create, but you know there it is,
a little change and maybe somebody will read this article
and be interested in oh what is deep learning?
Oh what's the Boltzmann machine?
And they'll learn more about it.
Alright congratulations on that,
it was a great breakthrough today,
and I look forward to seeing you next time,
until then, enjoy deep learning.