Hello and welcome back
to the course on machine learning.
In this section we're talking about
the K-Means clustering algorithm.
In this tutorial we're going to talk about
the intuition behind K-Means.
K-Means is a algorithm that allows you to cluster your data
and as we'll see it's a very convenient tool
for discovering categories or groups in your data set
that you wouldn't have otherwise thought of yourself.
In this section, or in this specific tutorial,
we'll learn how to understand K-Means on an intuitive level,
and we'll see an example of how it works.
So, lets dive straight into it, lets make this topic,
this complex topic, simple.
All right, so here we've got a scatterplot
and how does this scatterplot come to be?
Well, lets imagine that we've got two variables
in our data set and we decided to plot those two variables
on the X and Y axis.
So, here we go, that's one variable,
and that's the other one, and this is how
our observations are configured
according to these two variables.
So, the question here is can we identify
certain groups among our variables,
and how would we go about doing it.
Can we maybe identify this as one, this is one group,
and this is a second group, or maybe this is one group,
the second, or maybe there's four groups,
or five groups, maybe there's three groups.
How do we identify the number of groups?
How do we identify the groups themselves?
So, what the K-Means does for you
is it takes out the complexity
from this decision making process
and allows you to very easily identify
those clusters are actually called
clusters of data points in your data set.
So, there we go, in this case we have three clusters.
And, of course, this a very simplified example.
We only have two dimensions here, so two variables.
K-Means can work with a multi dimensional object,
so it can work with three, four, five, 10 dimensions.
This example is just for illustrational purposes
so that we can visually see what's going on,
but in reality there can be as many as 10,
a hundred, any number of variables,
and K-Means will do that complex calculation for you.
So, its an algorithm designed to find
these clusters for you.
And, today we're going to find out a bit more
on how the K-Means algorithm works.
So, what is the step-by-step process?
This is my favorite part.
We're going to break it down to such a simple
step-by-step process that it will be
extremely intuitive and simple to understand.
All right, so step one for the K-Means algorithm
is to choose the number of clusters, K.
And, we'll talk more about how to select
the optimal number of clusters
further down in this section of the course,
but for now lets imagine that we've agreed
on a number of clusters for a certain challenge,
and lets say we've agreed that there's three clusters,
or there's five clusters, or two clusters.
And once you've done that then you proceed to step two,
which is to select at random K points
which will be the centroids of your clusters.
And, not necessarily these points have to
be from your dataset.
So, as you saw we had a scatterplot.
You could select any points on that scatterplot.
They don't have part of the observations
that are plotted on the scatterplot,
they can be any random X and Y values on your scatterplot.
As long as you just select a certain number of centroids
that are going to equate to the number of clusters
that you have decided upon.
Again, we'll see this in practice just now.
Then, you move on to step three,
where you assign each data point to the closest centroid.
And, that'll form K clusters right away immediately.
So, that's your starting clusters,
and then there's gonna be an iterative process
to refine those clusters.
We'll see this in action,
but basically so you just check for every point
in your dataset which, out of the centroids
that you've identified in step two,
which of them is the closest to your specific data point,
then that's where that data point will be assigned to.
And, closest is a kind of vague term here
because what kind of distance you're measuring it by.
Is it Euclidean distance, is it some other sort of distance?
That can be better defined in your business challenge,
but for the purposes of these tutorials
we are going to talk about Euclidean distances,
and so that's basically geometrical distances
in simple terms.
All right, step four where you proceed to us.
Step three is to compute and place the new centroid
of each cluster, and we'll see how that's done just now.
So, once you've found your clusters
you recalculate the centroids.
Again, it's gonna be much easier to understand this
when we look at an example.
Then, in step five you reassign each data point
to the new closest centroid,
so basically you perform step three again
but we will just call it step five here,
and then if any reassignment took place
you repeat step four.
So, it becomes an iterative process of step four, step five,
and if no reassignment took place
you go to finish and your model is ready.
I know this might seem a bit complex,
but lets go through a visual example now
so that we understand this on a very intuitive level.
Then, you can always reference this slide
or this step-by-step rule further down
when you're actually performing K-Means clustering,
or when you want to understand how its happening,
or what's happening in the background of K-Means clustering.
So, this slide will be a great reference point
after we discuss this visual exercise
that we're going to have just now.
So, lets move on.
All right, so there is our scatterplot,
and here we've got the observations in our dataset.
They're plotted against two variables.
And, right away, the first question is
can you visually just quickly identify the final clusters
that you think that we'll end up with?
It's pretty tough isn't it?
And, that is, even when we just have two variables,
imagine how complex this situation or this challenge
would be if we had three variables, or five variables.
We wouldn't even be able to plot
a five dimensional scatterplot like that.
So, that's where K-Means clustering comes in to play,
and that's where this algorithm will help us
simplify the process.
So, lets see how it will perform in action.
In this case, we're actually going to manually perform
the K-Means clustering algorithm.
So, something that would normally be done
by tools of your choice, such as R or Python,
or any other tool, but, in this case
just so that we can get very comfortable
with this algorithm, we're going to do it manually
and see exactly how it works.
All right, so lets go through the steps.
Step one, choose the number of clusters, K,
and lets say we somehow identified
that the optimal number of clusters is equal to two.
Again, we'll discuss how to find
the optimal number of clusters further down in the section,
but for now lets agree that for this challenge
it's just two clusters.
All right, and then step two, select at random
K points which will be the centroids of your clusters,
and not necessarily from your dataset.
So, what that means is that they can be
actual points in your dataset,
or they can just be random points on your scatterplot.
It doesn't matter where you select them.
So, lets say we selected these two centroids,
the blue centroid, and the red centroid.
Next step is step three, assign each data point
to the closest centroid and that'll form K clusters.
So, basically for every data point in our data set
what we need to do is identify which of the two centroids,
blue or red, is the closest.
So, lets say for this data point,
obviously, blue is closer than red
so it would be assigned to the blue cluster.
For this data point, blue is again closer than red.
For this data point, red is closer than blue.
So, we could keep going like that for every data point
and assign it to one of the two centroids,
but we're going to use a quick hack here.
We're going to use something that we learned from geometry.
So, what we're going to do is we're going to just
connect these two centroids with a line, like that,
and then we'll find the center of the line,
which is over here, and we'll put a perpendicular line
exactly through that central like that.
And, so from geometry we know, from high school geometry,
or maybe at university, or even if you didn't have geometry,
it's a very straightforward concept
that any point on this green line
is equidistant from the blue and the red.
So, if I take this point, it'll be the same distance
to the blue centroid and to the red centroid.
If I take this point, it'll be same distance
to blue and the red.
So, this whole line is equidistant to the blue and the red,
and that's how we constructed it.
And so, based on that, it now is obvious
that any of our points on this scatterplot
above the green line is closer to the blue,
and any of the points below the green line
is closer to the red.
And, that's how we're going to just color our points.
It's a very quick way of coloring them.
Again, you could totally go through every point
and individually identify which centroid is closest,
but, just for our sake while we're doing this exercise,
it's gonna be faster if we apply this quick hack method.
So, there we go, we've colored our centroids,
or our points on our scatterplot.
Before we continue, I do want to mention something here,
that closest is a very, even though it seems
straightforward, it's quite an ambiguous term,
because closest, when you're visualizing things
on a scatter plot, yes it's pretty straightforward
that it's the distance, right, but at the same time
in mathematics and in data science,
there's lots of different type of distances,
like the one we're using is Euclidean,
and the question is, should you be using
Euclidean distances, or should you be using
some other type of distances defined for your challenge.
And, that is something up to you to decide,
and that's something for you to specify for the algorithm,
what type of distance you're going to be using.
But, for our sake, we're just going to be using
Euclidean distances for the illustration purposes,
and basically that's just a very straightforward,
simple geometrical distances between two different points.
So, that's just a caveat there and if you'd like
to research more about distances and what other
kind of distances you can use,
just make sure to look into that
because for some challenges sometimes you might want to use
non-Euclidean distances that are defined
in other specific ways.
All right, so with that in mind, lets proceed to step four.
Step four, compute and place the new centroid
of each cluster.
So basically, right now we've got the new points,
all the blue ones, excluding the centroid itself,
and all the red ones, excluding the centroid itself.
We need to find out where the actual centroid,
the new centroid for the blue points is,
and the new centroid for the red points is.
And the way to think about it is
imagine that centroids themselves, they are weightless,
but these other points, they have a certain weight,
so lets say one kilo each.
Then, you need to find the center of mass
or the center of gravity of these centroids,
and you need to pinpoint it on your scatterplot.
So, for the blue cluster, it'll be somewhere here.
For the red cluster, it will be somewhere over here.
The way to think about it, on a two dimensional scatterplot,
you kind of like can just visually see where it is,
or you can just look at the X, let's say the Y coordinates
for all of the blue points and find the center of gravity
for the Y coordinates, which will be somewhere here,
and then do the same thing for the X coordinates,
find the center of gravity,
or like the average of the X coordinates,
which will be over here.
So, that's how you get your new centroid
for the red and blue clusters,
and so we just move our centroids into them.
Next, you perform step five.
So, reassign each data point to the new closest centroid.
And, if any reassignment took place,
then go back to step four, otherwise,
you may finish your algorithm,
meaning that it has converged.
So, let's do that.
Let's see how now the data points will reassign
to the new centroids.
So, if we put our line through the scatterplot,
you'll see that there is one point,
or no, there's actually three points,
this point is closer to the blue than to the red,
and these two points are actually closer to the red
than the blue.
So, now we will recolor them, there we go.
So, now we've got a new clustering
and some reassignment did take place,
so we're going to proceed back to step four.
So, we're going back to step four,
compute and place the new centroids for each cluster.
Same thing, find the center of mass for this centroid,
find the center of mass for this centroid.
Place the centroids in those locations
and now repeat step five.
Reassign each data point to the new closest centroid.
So, we're gonna to put the line through the charts,
so the equidistant line between the two centroids.
As you can see, this point is actually
now in the blue cluster rather then being in the red,
reassign that point, and what happens next
is, again, we turn to step four.
So, if I go back here you'll see that
a reassignment did take place,
so we're going back to step four.
And, that's where our new clusters are going to be located,
our new centroids, move them there.
Repeat step five.
As you can see, it's an iterative process.
We're just going to keep going like this
until the algorithm converges.
So, there's our equidistant line.
As you can see, one point needs to be reassigned.
It gets reassigned, so now we go back to step four.
Compute and place the new centroids for each cluster.
Move our centroids, and now reassign each data point.
So, repeat step five.
And, as you can see, this time the equidistant line
does not make any points reassign.
So, as you can see, all the points
are already in their correct clusters.
That means no reassignment took place during this step
so we can proceed to completing our algorithm.
This means that the algorithm has converged.
So, there we go, those are our clusters
and the model is ready.
Now, we can just remove the centroids
and the equidistant line, and there we go,
that's our final result.
So, as you can see, that's how the K-Means algorithm works.
It's a very very intuitive and straightforward,
just an iterative process, and if we compare it to
what we had at the start, this is what we had.
As you can see, it's not that obvious
how the clusters would have been arranged.
For instance, you might have thought
that maybe this could be a cluster on its own,
and this could be a cluster,
or maybe this bottom part would be a cluster,
and this top part would be a cluster.
But, based on the K-Means algorithm,
what we got as a result is these two clusters.
So, the points in each cluster
are not exactly very similar to each other,
but this is what the K-Means algorithm is suggesting.
Hopefully you enjoyed this tutorial,
and hopefully now we've demystified the K-Means algorithm,
and we've broken it down into simple terms.
I look forward to seeing you in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy machine learning.