Hello and welcome back,
to the course on Deep Learning. Today we're talking
about Contrastive Divergence. This is the algorithm
that actually allows Restricted Boltzmann Machines to learn.
So let's have a look at this.
Here we've got a diagrammatic representation of our
Restricted Boltzmann Machines. Here we've got the input
nodes, and we've got the hidden nodes in red.
And what are we going to be covering off today,
is a specific part of the learning process.
So we've already talked about the learning process
for Restricted Boltzmann Machines in the previous tutorial,
where we discussed exactly how we feed in different values,
different roles into our Restricted Boltzmann Machines
and how it looks at them and looks for features
and then assign certain nodes to those features
to further understand our system and better represent
our system. But the question that we still have is,
how does the Restricted Boltzmann Machines adjust
its weights. Because previously in the other neural networks
that we've looked at, we had the gradient descent process,
which allowed us to back propagate the error through
the network, and therefore adjust the weights accordingly
to minimize that error.
But in this time, we don't have a directed network.
We have an undirected network. And the question is,
how do the weights get adjusted here.
And this is where the Contrastive Divergence comes in.
So let's have a look at this process what's going on.
We're going to look at it in two ways.
We're going to look at a diagrammatically like this
and then we're going to look at it through a chart,
through an energy chart, which will help us understand,
we're going to tackle this problem from two ways.
So let's go. So here we've got our input nodes.
Once you put them into the network, using some randomly
assigned weights, at the very start,
the system or the Restricted Boltzmann Machine calculates
the hidden nodes. Then what's going to happen is
those hidden nodes are going to use the exact same weights
to calculate the input nodes, or to reconstruct,
the correct term is to reconstruct the input nodes here.
The key point here is that they weigh exactly the same
they don't change. What is also important to understand
is that the reconstructed inputs are not going to equal
the original inputs even though the weight is the same.
Let's have a look at our network as our
Restricted Boltzmann Machine in a bit more depth
or in a bit more detail to understand this specific thing.
Why that is.
So here we've got our Restricted Boltzmann Machine,
we've got visible nodes, our hidden nodes.
The question is, once we've reconstructed are visible modes,
how come they're not identical to the original visible nodes
even though we're using the same weights.
Well, the reason for that is because these nodes
are not initially interconnected.
There's no specific connection, not necessarily
is there a specific connection between them,
and there's no formula or equation that's connecting.
Let's listen to stand this on an example.
Let's look at this node, node number two over here.
How does it get reconstructed?
Well, it gets it gets reconstructed based on the values
that all of these hidden nodes, all of these five
hidden nodes have in them. So once we first run this RBM,
these initial values will assign or will initiate
some values in your hidden nodes.
Then once we run it backwards, these hidden nodes
will reconstruct, all of these nodes including this node.
But the thing is, each one of these nodes wasn't constructed
just based on this node. If that was the case,
if this node was on its own, and it constructed this node
constructed this node, the value from this node was used
to create the value in this node. It was then used to create
this node and then it was used to create this node,
it was used to create this node, was used to create
this node, and then we ran everything backwards,
then yes, this node would be identical to what it was
initially. But the way the RBM works is that this node
during the forward pause, this node was constructed
from this node, from this node, from this node,
from this node, from this node.
Then this node was constructed from this node,
from this node, from this node, from this node,
from this node and from this node.
So every single node here, was constructed
from all six of these. And so therefore, all of these nodes
have values that didn't initially come from here.
They came from the other nodes, and therefore
when you reconstruct this node even though using the same
weights, the values in here came from other nodes
as well as this node and therefore the reconstructed
value in this node is not going to be equal
to what you had in here initially.
That's very important to understand, that's why this whole
Contrastive Divergence process exists, that's why from here
we're going to keep going and these two don't equal
to each other. So there's a first forward pause
backward pause, now we're going to do another one.
We're going to again feed these values
the reconstructed node values of our inputs into the RBM
and we're going to get some outputs or some hidden values.
Then based on these hidden values, we're going to
reconstruct the inputs again, and again,
they're not going to equal.
Then we're going to construct the hidden values and so on.
And this whole process is called Gibbs sampling.
And towards the end, finally, at some point,
we're going to get some reconstructed input values
which are such that when we feed them into the RBM,
and then we try to reconstruct them again,
we will get those same values.
So from here we don't keep going forward from here,
this once it goes into the RBM and then it get
reconstruction we get exactly that.
So in this final scenario, what happens is yes, our network
is modeling exactly our inputs. So basically,
we can input in and we will always get the output.
So in essence, this process has finally converged
and our network is finally a great
model to model our inputs. To model that specific input.
And in terms of the curve, what does this look like?
So we've discussed this process step by step
in terms of diagrammatically.
Now let's have a look what this looks like
in terms of curve, and also what it means for us.
In terms of the curve, this is what it looks like.
So we've got two parts here, we'll start with the formula.
We've got a formula, and this is a gradient formula.
So you can see the gradient on the left here.
And we've got the gradient of the log probability
of a certain state of our system, based on the weights
in the system.
And remember, through this whole process, through
this whole process, the weights we're constant.
They we're not changing the weights, we're just using
weights whichever weights twe have.
And for now, we're also the weight is constant is very
important to remember.
But here, what it's telling us is how the weights affect
the log probability. How changing the weights will change
the log probability, and the way it'll change
is this value minus value. And so what are these values?
Well, this is your initial state of the system visible,
hidden, visible vector, hidden vector,
visible layer, hidden layer, visible layer, hidden layer.
Without going into too much detail on this formula,
we're going to look at it on the curve, because we'll supply
some additional reading, which you can look at in your free
time. But this let's go through the intuitive understanding.
It will help us understand what's going on here.
So we've got initial state, that's this one,
visible hidden layer. That's our data space
and this is our energy.
But actually, before we put these on, let's talk
about the energy. Where does the energy come from?
We've talked about energy based systems
and we said that in the Restricted Boltzmann Machines
the way we define energy is through weights.
So the weights are fixed as we saw through the whole
previous process the way to fixed, and we're going to define
this energy curve is based on the weight.
So weights dictate the shape of this energy curve,
and now we place our initial inputs
visible and hidden layer. So our first pause through the RBM
and that's where we happen to be, just because the weights
are initialized randomly. For example, we end up some where
here. Then after, so that's over there, after that pause,
now we have this pause, visible, hidden.
after the second pause, what happens is we end up somewhere
here. So as we've discussed before, a system
which is governed by its energy will always try to end up in
the lowest energy state possible.
So as you can see, this ball is rolling towards the bottom
over here. And that's exactly what's happening through
that divergent process, through that process which
we discussed through our diagrams as we go through
the Contrastive Divergence process basically.
What's happening is, we're going closer and closer
to our lowest energy state.
And a good way to think about it is like if you're feeling
a bit lost right now, just think of it as, remember
that example of the gas.
You have a room and then you let out some gas in one corner.
For instance, if you got a big room, and then you let out
some gas in the top right corner,
just based on the architecture of the room based
on the conditions that the gas has been put into,
hence the weights. So the the architecture of the room
or the design of the room, that is not the lowest energy
state for that gas at that point in time.
So the gas could be in a much lower energy state than that.
And so what the gas starts doing is it starts expanding
into the whole room, this is what's happening here.
Through the Contrastive Divergence process, we're finding
what's the values in our system, the inputs and the hidden
layers, what they should be for the system
to be in the lowest energy state possible. So here it is.
So basically, at the very end, we get certain values.
Again, the weights are not changed, the weights haven't
changed, but we get certain values, certain reconstructed
input values and certain hidden values, that bring
the system to the minimal energy state at the end
of this Contrastive Divergence process, and in terms
of the diagram, this means that this bowl ends up over here.
And from there, what this formula is telling us is,
once you have that state, once you are ball is over here
at the very end, if you subtract this value,
and again, just check the additional reading for more
information is, but basically if you subtract this value
from this value, it will tell you how adjusting your weights
will affect the log probability
of the system being in this state.
So basically, this is a recipe, this formula
is a recipe for adjusting your curve for shifting
or for modifying your energy curve, so that you can make
sure that this state is inside an energy minimum,
so that you can get any desired effect.
Right now it's like getting towards a certain
minimal energy state but the inputs are completely different
to our inputs, we want to change that.
We want to use this formula to adjust our curve, so this,
the energy minimum is actually next to our inputs
rather than some random reconstructed inputs which
are defined by the randomly initialized weights.
That's what we're doing here.
So this is a long process, as you can imagine
it takes very long.
But in 1998, Jeffrey Hinton discovered a shortcut
which I like to call, I'm probably going to call
on this tutorial Hinton's shortcut.
What happens is he says that, "Even if you take just the
first two pauses", you don't wait until it convergences to
the end, "This is sufficient to understand how to adjust
your curve as far as is the initial stage."
So this is a CD one, Contrastive Divergence one pause.
You might hear that term CD one, CD three, CD five, CD nine
and so on.
So if you do a CD one, Contrastive Divergence one pause,
what happens is, so you know from here, you've got this as
your green ball. This is your red ball,
your green ball is over here, your red ball is over here
and you know that and that's enough for you
to know which way is rolling.
So like similar to what we had in gradient descent
that's why it's downhill. But you now want to adjust
your curve. In gradient decent we just had a curve
and we were like finding the minimum.
Here we have control over the curve, we are adjusting
the weights because it's an energy based process
we're adjusting the weights so that minimum is actually
going to be here rather than here. So let's look at that.
So we know that the balls are going rolling downhill.
So what we actually want is want to pull this curve down
here and we want to push it up over here.
That way you'll see what happens viola.
So you can see your ball is already inside the minimum,
and that way you don't even have to go through the long
process of sampling to get to that recipe of how to adjust
the curve, but you can just adjust the weights.
Basically what I'd like to you to take away from here.
We have an energy curve and the shape of this energy curve,
is governed by the weights in the system, that's just
how we design it.
We also know that the way we've designed the system,
is that the Restricted Boltzmann Machine,
will aim to always get to the minimal energy state,
the state with the minimal energy possible
and what do we mean by get to that state?
What's the process of getting to that state?
Well, that process we just looked at that sampling
that Gibbs sampling process, where we input the inputs
then we get the hidden values and where we construct
the inputs then we get the hidden values,
reconstruct inputs and so on.
Through that process, the system will always aim to get
to values and its nodes which represent the lowest energy
state possible. Now, what we want is we want to redesign
the system hence, redesign the energy curve,
so that the energy curve reflects also that the system
is such that when we input our values, our training values,
the system is already going to be in the lowest
energy possible. And for that we use this formula.
So we start with some randomly initialize weights,
we input a value like one of our rows into the RBM,
we go through this process of Gibbs sampling, we calculate
this value, we find out how to adjust our curve.
Plus on top of all of that, there's a shortcut.
There's a shortcut that we don't actually have to go through
to the very end of the sampling process,
we can just do two pauses, we go first pause, second pause
and so we do a CD one, Contrastive Divergence one,
and that will tell us how to adjust the curve.
That's the essence of it all,
I can appreciate it's a very complex process,
Contrastive Divergence, there's math behind it,
there's steps involved and there's lots of understanding.
But in an intuitive way, that is what's happening.
We're trying to adjust the energy curve by modifying
the weights, in order to facilitate a system,
or create a system which
in the best way possible resembles
our input values, our training values and we do that,
using this recipe formula over here.
And if you'd like to get into more depth on this topic,
on Contrastive Divergence, it's very interesting,
there's a couple of papers that you can look at.
The first paper is a great paper by Jeffrey Hinton
and others 2006, it's called a fast learning algorithm
for deep belief nets. And you can see exactly the diagram
here which we discussed.
It's a good paper to get you started into the process.
Another paper if you'd like to get a bit more mathematical
on the Contrastive Divergence and really understand the math
behind it, and what's exactly going on with the gradients
and so on, a good paper to look at is called
Notes on Contrastive Divergence, it's not actually a paper
it's just some notes is a three pager by Oliver Woodford
I'm not sure I think it's 2012 but I couldn't find out
exactly the date, but it looks like it's 2012.
So Notes on Contrastive Divergence by Oliver Woodford date
might be 2012 or not and of course the link is over there
and I'll include this in the additional resources.
So have a look at those if you'd like to dig
into Contrastive Divergence a bit more.
Hope you enjoyed today's tutorial and I look forward
to see you next time, until then enjoy Deep Learning.