Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
So, today, we're going to convert our training set
and our test set into an array with users
and lines and movies and columns.
So first, why do we need to do that?
Well, the reason is that, we need to make
a specific structure of data that will fit
to the structure of the other encoders
and the other encoders are like neural networks,
where you have some some input notes
that are the features and you have some observations
going one by one into the network
starting with the input notes.
And so what we have to do is create
a structure that will contain these observations
that will go into the network and their different
features that are going to be in the input notes.
And that's exactly what we're about to do
by creating this array with the users and
lines in the movies and columns,
because we will have the observations and lines
and the features and columns.
And so basically we're just making the
usual structure of data for neural networks
or even for machinery in general.
That is, with the observations in lines
and the features and columns.
That was exactly the same for the dataset
of our churn modeling problem.
Remember we had the observations in lines
which were the customers and the features in columns
which were the informations of these customers.
And that's exactly the structure of data
expected by neural network, and that's why
we are now converting our data into such a structure.
Okay so now that we understand,
let's convert our data into such a structure.
So, since we're gonna do this for both
the training set and the test set,
we're gonna create a function that will apply then
on the training set and the test set separately.
So, let's create this function.
To create a function in Python,
we need to start with def for definition.
And then we need to give a name to the function.
And we're gonna call this function convert.
Okay, then we need to give some arguments to the function
and actually we only need one argument
because you know we will apply this function to only a set,
which will be the training set first, and then the test set.
And so here we only need one argument
that we're gonna call data.
So that's our argument and then when we apply
the convert function to our training set and our test set,
we will just need to replace data by training set
and then test set.
Alright then, colon, that's just by syntax,
and then enter to go into the function
to give it's definition that is
tell the function what we want it to do.
Okay, so as you understood, we are about to create
an array where the lines are going to be the users
and the columns are going to be the movies.
So I guess what you're thinking about right now
is a two dimensional numpy array.
We could do that, however, and that's just
because we're gonna use torch afterwards,
we won't create a two dimensional numpy array,
we will create a list of lists.
So, list of lists, what does that mean?
That means that we're gonna have several lists.
One list for each line, that is one list for each user.
And therefore since we have 943 users,
that means that we'll have 943 lists.
And these will be horizontal lists,
so these will correspond to our observations and lines
in this special structure that we've just described.
So it will go like this.
The first list will correspond to the first user,
the second list will correspond to the second user, and etc.
And then what will we get in each list?
Well of course we will get the ratings of the 1,682 movies
by the user corresponding to the list.
And so we'll get the rating for each of the movie
and remember if the user didn't rate the movie,
then we'll get a zero for that cell.
And that's why the new converted training set and test set
will have the same size, because basically
for both the training set and the test set,
we're considering older users and older movies
and we just put a zero when the user didn't rate the movie.
Okay so to recap.
This whole list of lists will be a list of 943 lists
because we have 943 users and each of these 943 lists
will be a list of 1,682 elements
because we have 1,682 movies.
Alright so now, let's create this list of lists.
So, we're gonna start by giving a name to this list of lists
and we're gonna call it new_data
and that will be our final output
that the function will return.
That is, it's going to be our final array
with the users and lines and the movies and columns.
And so since new_data is list of lists,
we need to initialize it as a list.
And how do we do that in Python?
Well that's very simple.
We need to initialize it this way, with an equal
and then brackets.
That initializes the list.
Okay, next step.
Next step is to make a full loop
because we want to create a list for each user.
The list of all the ratings of the movies by this user,
and therefore we need a full loop
that will get the ratings for each user.
And so here we start with for
and now we need to introduce a local variable
that will loop over all the users
of the data that is the training set or the test set.
And so we're gonna call this variable id_users
and this will take the values of all the ID's
of the users in our database.
And then we need to specify a range for these user ID's
and that will simply going to be older user ID's
from one to the max that is the total number of users,
which we got in this variable here
and so now you understand
why we got to create this variable.
So, for id_users going from one up to nb_users,
but now be careful, there is a trick.
The upper bound in a range is excluded
and therefore nb_users will not be included here.
This will go from one to the number of users minus one.
That is 942 and we want it to go up to 943
because we want to consider all the users
and therefore what we seem to need to do
is to add here plus one so that it goes up to 944
but 944 will be excluded and therefore,
we will go up to 943, which is what we want.
Okay, and now, we need to introduce a colon still
because of Python syntax, and we press enter
to go into the loop.
And so now what are we going to do in this loop?
Well right now what we want to do
is to create the first list of this new data lists.
And what is this first list going to be?
Well as you understood, that's going to be the ratings
of the first user because id_users here starts at one
and so we are starting with the first user
and so we are starting to add
the list of ratings of the first user.
And we're gonna add it in this list here,
which is the whole list.
Okay so now the question is,
how can we create the list of all the ratings
of the movies by this first user?
Well first, what we'll do is get all the movies' ID's
of all the movies that were rated by this first user.
And so we're gonna put all these movies' ID's
into a variable which we're gonna call id_movies.
Alright, and this will contain the movies' ID's
that were rated by the first user.
So how can we get that now?
Well, we need to take our data
and you can imagine the data to be the training set
because then we will apply convert to the training set
and so let's say that data is the training set.
From the training set, we want to take
first the column that contains all the movie ID's
and that's the second column, that is of index one.
And so that's the first thing we'll do.
We'll get the first index of the training set which is one.
And then we'll take all the observations
and to do this, we use this colon here
and we separate the colon and the one by a comma.
So here so far we're just taking the whole column
of the movies' ID's in the training set.
So, so far, we're taking the whole column here.
The whole one with all the users.
Okay, but now we just want the movies' ID's
of this first user.
The first user because we are at the beginning of the loop.
So how can we only get the ratings of this first user?
While I'm explaining, try to pause on the video
and try to guess the next thing I'm going to code.
So basically what we want is the movies' ID's
going from this one up to this one.
That is basically we want all the movies' ID's
when the first column equals one.
So, what we need to do is make some kind of a syntax
that will tell we want the first column of the data
that is a training set,
such that the first column equals one.
And the trick to do this in Python is to add
a new condition and we add it in a new pair of brackets
and inside this new pair of brackets,
we are gonna put the condition.
And as we said, the condition is that data
that is a training set, well actually,
the first column of data that has index zero
and we take all the lines again, equals equals
and so now as we understood we want one,
what's one is id_users because id_users starts as one.
And so we put id_users.
And so this will take all the movies' ID's
of the first user.
Okay, perfect.
We get our movies' ID's and now we're gonna get
the same for the ratings, that is,
we're gonna get all the ratings of that same first user.
And so this is going to be very simple.
Now that we get how it works,
we're just gonna take this line here, copy it,
then past it below and here instead of id_movies
we'll create id_ratings and so here that's the same.
We want to take all the ratings of the training set
and the ratings in the training set
are in the third column, that is index two,
so here we need to replace one by two
so we are taking all the ratings from the training set
such that the first column is equal to one.
And so this will get us all the ratings
given by this first user.
Okay and now we have what we need
to create this first list
that is a list of the ratings of the first user.
But be careful, this is not this one
because the one we would like to get
is not only the ratings of the movies that the user rated,
but also the zeroes when the user didn't rate the movie.
So what we exactly want to create right now
is this list of 1,682 elements
where the elements of this list
corresponds to 1,682 movies,
and for each of the movie, we get the rating of the movie
if the user rated the movie
and a zero if the user didn't rate the movie.
So that's what we want to create right now,
and so far with id_ratings, we only have the ratings
of the movies that the user rated.
So what do we have to do right now?
Well we have to create this new list of 1,682 elements.
And we're going to initialize it as a list of zeroes.
You know we will initialize it as a list of 1,682 zeroes.
And then what we're gonna do is that for the movies
that the user rated, we will replace
the zero by the rating for that movie.
The rating of that movie by the user.
So let's do this, let's initialize this list of 1,682 movies
and so we're gonna call this list ratings equals
and to initialize such a list of 1,682 zeroes,
we're gonna use numpy which has a shortcut, np,
then dot, and then we're gonna use
this very practical function that is called zeroes
and parenthesis, and inside this parenthesis,
we just need to put the number of zeroes
we want to have in that list.
And so what is it?
That is 1,682 and that is nb_movies.
So here we input nb_movies.
Here we go, that's taking shape.
And so now, what we have to do is replace
the zeroes by the ratings for the movies
that the user rated.
So, how do we do that?
Well, there is a trick here.
Try to guess what I'm going to code next.
Well, first of course we need to take our ratings
and now what do we do?
So we just need to replace the zeroes by the real ratings.
When rating there was.
So we're gonna try to access the indexes
of the ratings that exist.
So, I'm gonna add here some brackets,
and inside these brackets, we will get the indexes
of the movies that were rated.
And so what are these indexes?
Well, the good news is that we already have them.
Because that's exactly id_movies that we created here.
That's why we have to create id_movies here.
So this id_movies contains all the indexes of the movies
that were rated and so that's exactly what we want.
So, I'm going to copy these indexes here
and paste them in our ratings.
Okay but now there is another trick.
What is the trick?
The trick is that indexes in Python start at zero,
and our movies' ID's start at one.
And so how do we fix this?
Try to guess what I'm about to add.
Well we basically need the movies' ID's
to start at the same base as the indexes of the ratings.
That is zero, and therefore we need to add here a minus one.
That way, for example, let's say,
that the first user rated the first movie.
The first movie has it's id_movies equal to one.
But the first movie will be the first element
of this ratings list.
And the first element of this ratings list has index zero.
And therefore, the first movie that has movie_id one,
well to put it in the first position of this ratings list,
well we need to subtract one so that we get
one minus one, that is zero, and therefore,
this first movie will have
the index zero in this ratings list
and therefore will go in first position
and not in second position.
If we didn't have id_movies minus one,
well, id_movies would be equal to one
and therefore, it will go in the second position.
And that wouldn't make sense.
So, that's a thing we must be very careful in Python,
but be relieved, that's just practice,
if it is your first steps in Python,
this will get very obvious soon.
So, id_movies minus one, and then what do we need to do?
Well, now that we managed to get
the indexes of the movies that were rated
in this ratings list of all the movies,
well, for these movies, we need to give the real ratings.
That is, we need to put the real rating of these movies
in this ratings list.
And so what we need to do is add an equal
and since this corresponds to the ratings
of the movies that were rated,
then this will be equal to the real ratings,
and what are the real ratings?
Well, double good news, we also already have them.
Because they are in id_ratings here.
So here we go, we just need to add
the real ratings of the movies that were rated,
and that is id_ratings.
Alright, perfect, we are almost done.
Now we managed to create for each user,
the list of all the ratings,
including the zeroes for the movies that were not rated.
Perfect!
And so now we have only one thing to do left.
That is to add this list of ratings here,
corresponding to one user,
to this huge list that will contain all the different lists
for all the different users.
And therefore what we need to do
is to take this whole list new_data, underscore data,
and now what we're going to do is take
another very practical function that is the append function,
and that will append this list of ratings here
for one user, for the user of the loop, id_users,
to this whole new data list.
So, how do we do that?
Well, we add a dot here, and then we use
the append function and inside the parenthesis,
we're gonna put this whole list of ratings
for this one particular user.
And to make sure this is a list,
we need to put ratings into the list function,
just to make sure it's a list.
Alright, because we really need a list of lists
because that's exactly what torch expects.
Alright, perfect!
And now we're done.
This function is over.
I hope this was not too hard.
We had a lot of mechanism to understand,
especially with the indexes,
but now it's done, congratulations.
Our function is ready and now we're going to apply it
to our training set and our test set.
But before, of course, we're going to add here
the final line to return what we want.
But that's very simple.
We just need to add return
and then you know, what we want to return
is the list of all the different lists of ratings,
and that is new_data of course.
So perfect, now the function is really ready.
And so now, we are going to apply this function
to the training set and the test set
and to do this, there is nothing more simple,
we just need to take our training set
and then we are going to use the convert function on it,
and what do we need to input?
Well that's of course the training set.
The old version of the training set,
that is this version right here.
And this version right here,
is going to become this new version
that is an array with the users and lines
and the movies and columns.
So here we paste training set
and now we're gonna do the same for the test set
so I'm copying this line and pasting that here
and we're gonna replace training set by test set
and training set again by test set.
Alright, here we go, let's do this.
Let's convert our training set and our test set.
So first what I'm gonna do is select the whole function,
just to define the function,
and so I'm going to execute, here we go.
And now let's convert to training set
and the test set one by one.
So we're gonna start with the training set
and just to check what we expect
because we're gonna lose the old version
of the training set.
Well let's check if we will get the right values
for the first list.
That is, for the first user.
Well, as you understood,
the first list will contain the list of ratings
of the first user, that is this user one here,
including the zeroes for the movies
that this user didn't rate.
So here we can see that since the movies ID's started two,
well, that means that the user didn't rate the first movie
of movie ID one.
And therefore the first element of the first list
should be a zero and then the second element
will be the rating of the second movie
and the rating of the second movie is three.
So the second element of the first list should be three.
And then the third element of this first list
will be the rating of movie number three.
Because the user rated the movie number three.
And the rating of the movie number three is four.
So the third element of this first list should be four.
So let's just check that in the first list,
the three first elements will be zero, three, and four.
And then we'll just trust what happens for the rest.
So I'm gonna press okay here and I'm going to select
this line and here we go,
let's hope that it's going to work.
Here we go, okay, so first we don't get an error.
That's great.
Then as you can see, training set is a list of 943 lists.
You're gonna see that these 943 elements
are going to be lists, so that's another good sign.
And so now let's open this training set.
Here it is, and as you can see, this huge list
contains 943 horizontal lists.
So each of these 943 lists corresponds
to each user of our database.
So this first list corresponds
to the ratings of the first user.
And so we check that for the first movie,
the second movie, and the third movie,
the ratings are as expected, zero, three, and four.
Perfect!
We did it.
Alright, and then that's the same for the other users.
For each user, we get the ratings of all the movies
of the database, and we get a zero if the movie wasn't rated
and the real rating, when the user rated the movie.
Okay, great, so that works, and now we're going
to do the same for the test set.
And so we're gonna trust this.
We are going to select this line as well, and execute.
And here we go, we have our new version of the test set
and it still lists of 943 elements
and we get the same thing that is a list of lists
with all the ratings inside including the zeroes
for the movies that the users of the test set didn't rate.
Excellent, so I'm going to close this
and that's it for this tutorial.
Now the next tutorial is going to be much more simple
because basically what we'll do is convert
these lists of lists into torch tensors
because that's exactly now,
that we're starting with torch.
So, I'm super excited to start.
We will create very soon the architecture of our network
and until then, enjoy the learning.