Hello and welcome to this Python tutorial.
In the previous tutorial we took care of the first step,
the convolution step.
So that's one step done and now three more to go.
And in today's tutorial we'll take care of the second step,
the pooling step.
So, quick reminder, this pooling step is very easy,
it just consists of reducing the size of your feature maps.
And how do we do that?
Well again we take this two-by-two sub table,
this blue square table that you can see here
and that we slide all over the feature map
and each time we take the maximum of the four cells
inside this blue square.
So, taking the max is called Max Pooling,
and we slide the squared table with a stride of two
not with a stride of one as we did previously
with the feature detector that slided over the input image
with a stride of one.
Here, it's with a stride of two and therefore
since each time we take the max of a two-by-two table,
well what happens in the end
is that we get a new feature map, with a reduced size.
And more precisely, the size of the original feature map
is divided by two when we apply max pooling.
Well here we can see that the dimensions are five-by-five
because we have five rows and five columns
and when we apply max pooling, we get a reduced feature map
of three-by-three so that's actually half
of the original size plus one
but then if the size of the feature map was an even number,
then it's size would be divided by two.
So then we apply max pooling on each of our feature maps.
And then we obtain our next layer
composed of all these reduced feature maps
and that is called the pooling layer.
Alright, and why do we do this?
Why do we apply this max pooling step?
It's because we want to reduce the number of nodes
we'll get in the next step, that is the Flattening step
and then the Full Connection step
because in these next steps basically what we'll get
is all the cells of our feature maps,
flattened in one huge one-dimensional vector.
So, if we don't reduce the size of these feature maps,
well we'll get to too large vector and then we'll get
too many nodes in the fully connected layers
and therefore our model will be highly compute-intensive
and we want to avoid this so we're applying
this max pooling step to reduce the size of our feature maps
and therefore reduce the number of nodes
in the feature fully connected layers.
And that way this will reduce the complexity
and the time execution but without the losing
the performance because, by ticking the maximum
of these two-by-two sub tables of the feature map,
we are in some way keeping the information
because we are keeping track of the part of the image,
that contained the high numbers
corresponding to where the feature detectors,
detected some specific features in the input image.
So we don't lose the spacial structure information,
and therefore we don't lose the performance of the model
but at the same time, we managed to reduce
the time complexity and we make it less compute-intensive.
So that's a very important step
and lets implement it right now on Spider.
So here it is, all prepared, we're gonna start by taking
our classifier as usual because again,
what we're gonna do now is, use a method
which is still going to be the same
add method so dot here and then add.
Alright, and now parenthesis, and then we're gonna use
a function that will complete this max pooling step.
So according to you what is going to be
the name of this function?
Well very easy, you have it right here it's MaxPooling2D.
So let's input that into our add method, MaxPooling2D.
Alright and then new parenthesis to input the size
of you know this sub table that we slide all over
the feature map to take the maximum in each sub table.
So, the size parameter is called pool size.
Here we go, and then equals and then parenthesis,
and that's where we input the size.
So in the example given in the slide, as you can see
we take a size of two-by-two and this is actually
what we take in general when we apply max pooling
on our feature maps created after the first step.
Well most of the time we take a two-by two
because we don't wanna lose the information,
by taking two-by-two, we keep the information
and we're still being precise on where we have
the high numbers in the feature maps,
that the text and specific features of the input image.
So two-by-two is fine and I recommend
using that most of the time.
So to input this two-by-two dimensions,
it's very simple we just add two comma and two.
Alright and that's done, the max pooling step is done.
We don't have anymore parameters to input,
basically adding this line will reduce the size
of your feature maps, and it will divide it by two.
So I'm going to select this line and execute, here we go,
now the size of our feature maps is divided by two,
so we just reduced the complexity of our model
without reducing its performance.
Perfect.
So second step done, two more to go
and we'll do the third step in the next tutorial.
Until then, enjoy deep learning!