When you need fine-grained control over transactions,
and you have a small number of transactional operations,
use programmatic transaction management.
Let's talk about another method of programmatic
transaction management that Spring provides,
the PlatformTransactionManager.
This declarative code is very simple as it handles
transaction management for developers.
This makes the code very easy to maintain and evolve.
This is why the Spring team recommends this approach over
programmatic transaction management.
Now there are times when programmatic transaction management and the
flexibility that comes along with it is needed.
We've seen using the transaction template.
Now let's look at another method using the PlatformTransactionManager directly.
With PlatformTransactionManager,
you see that we have even more control over transactions than when using
the other programmatic method transactionTemplate.
We decide when to start a transaction, commit, or roll back.
We ask transactionManager to start a new transaction with that
definition by calling the getTransaction method.
The return value is a transactionStatus object to
keep track of the transactionStatus.
If the transaction is successful,
we will ask the transactionManager to commit this
transaction by passing in the transactionStatus.
If there is an error during the process,
the schedule release method will throw a RuntimeException,
in which case we will catch the exception and roll back the transaction. Let's see this in action.