First, let's understand what a transaction actually is.
A series of actions that are treated as a single unit
of work is considered a transaction.
Although there are multiple actions in a single transaction,
all should either fail as a group or complete entirely as a group.
When a single action in the group fails, all actions should be rolled back.
If all actions complete, then the transaction should be permanently committed.
There are four key properties to transactions that can be
easily remembered using the ACID acronym.
A for atomicity, a transaction consists of a series of actions,
and the approach is an all-or-nothing approach.
The transaction must either fully happen or not happen at all.
It cannot partially complete.
Consistency.
A transaction is committed once all of its actions have completed.
This keeps your data in a consistent state.
Isolation.
Each transaction is isolated from other transactions to
ensure that data is not corrupted.
Isolation ensures that one transaction cannot read
data from another transaction.
Durability.
A durable transaction is one that cannot be undone by system failure typically because it is written to persistent storage.