I've opened the project in IntelliJ and navigated to the ReleaseService.
java file.
Let's see the PlatformTransactionManager in action to
see the level of control it provides.
Notice the @Transactional annotation is not used.
Let's scroll down to line 32.
I'm autowiring the transactionManager.
And let's look at the scheduleRelease method here on line 45.
I'm setting up the TransactionDefinition on line 47 and
getting a transactionStatus object.
And now notice I'm calling the getTransaction method to start the transaction.
I'm creating the tickets on line 51,
and I'm assigning them to a release on line 52.
Notice I explicitly call commit on line 53.
And in the event of a RuntimeException, I'm catching it,
and I'm calling rollback.
So notice as the developer, I explicitly commit the transaction,
and I explicitly roll back the transaction.
This is a prime example of programmatic transaction management,
the level of control it provides.
So let's navigate to Postman and test this out.
So let's test the error case where we are assigning
tickets to a release that doesn't exist.
We have that Internal Server Error as expected.
Let's navigate to our H2 console.
Click Connect.
Let's see what's in our ticket table.
Nothing.
So that is what we expect because we are rolling back the data.
Now let's navigate back to Postman.
And let's test the case that does work.
So this is the case where we are assigning tickets to
the release ID of 1 that does exist.
Let's click Send.
We see a status of 200 OK.
Let's navigate back to our H2 console,
and let's see what exists in our ticket table.
And as we expected, four tickets with a status of Completed.
And let's see them assigned to releases. Perfect!