The TransactionTemplate class simplifies programmatic transaction execution
by wrapping the transaction manager API and providing a template method
around which a transactional boundary is started.
After the callback method concludes, the transaction is committed.
A transaction template exposes its functionality via a callback method.
One implementation does not have a return type.
That's doInTransactionWithoutResult, and the other has a return type,
doInTransactionWithResult.
Let's look at a TrackZilla example.
TransactionTemplate is implemented by implementing an anonymous inner
class of type TransactionCallbackWithoutResult.
This is an abstract class with one method, doInTransactionWithoutResult. With this code, we've explicitly specified our transaction boundaries.