Also in your research of Springs transaction management,
I'm sure you've come across the @Transactional annotation.
This annotation is an example of declarative transaction management and
allows us to easily work with database transactions.
The @Transactional annotation is convenient because
developers don't need to think about direct transaction
management and exception handling.
All of this is done automatically in a proxy class that Spring
creates to hold the transaction management code.
The @Transactional annotation can either be used at the class,
interface, or method level.
When placed on the class or interface,
all methods within it become transactional.
By using @Transactional,
many important aspects such as transaction
propagation are handled automatically.
There are specific attributes that you can set that will determine propagation behavior.