The Spring Framework allows transactions to be managed
seamlessly by offering a consistent programming model
across global and local transactions.
Essentially code is written once benefitting from different transaction
management strategies within different environments.
Spring provides support for programmatic transaction management.
Now this is where the developer writes custom code to
manage the transaction and set boundaries.
Spring also provides support for declarative transaction management,
which allows developers to separate transaction
management from the business code.
Spring supports isolation levels that help developers avoid problems
that may arise when multiple transactions in the application are operating concurrently on the same data.