We will enhance the TrackZilla system to implement programmatic
transaction management using the transaction template.
The system will also be updated to effectively roll back transactions.
I've opened the project in IntelliJ and navigated to the ReleaseService.
java file.
Let's enhance the TrackZilla application to implement programmatic
transaction management using the TransactionTemplate.
You will see now on the ReleaseService that the
@Transactional annotation is no longer used.
On line 29, I'm defining a TransactionTemplate,
and on lines 31 through 33, the constructor for the release service,
I'm initializing the TransactionTemplate using the transactionManager.
Let's scroll down and look at the updated scheduleRelease method on line 46.
Notice on line 52,
I'm calling the execute method on the TransactionTemplate and
I've implemented the doInTransactionWithoutResult method
because I don't need to return a result.
Notice on line 57,
I'm catching the NoSuchElementException and printing the stack trace.
So let's execute this.
So the app is up and running.
Let's navigate to Postman to exercise our schedule release.
So I'm posting to the schedule API.
Let's click Send.
Status of 200 OK.
Let's navigate to the H2 console.
We see our four tickets with a status of Completed.
We see our tickets assigned to a release.
Let's navigate back to the application and stop it.
So let's see what happens when we attempt to assign
tickets to a release that doesn't exist.
In this case,
there should be no automatic rollback because I'm
catching the exception here on line 57,
but I'm not programmatically rolling back.
The system will no longer automatically do a rollback for us because
we are using programmatic transaction management.
So let's test this out.
So let's navigate to Postman.
In this case, we are assigning tickets to a release that doesn't exist.
Click Send.
We see a status of OK.
Let's navigate back to the H2 console.
Let's see what exists in our tickets.
So, yes, we have four tickets.
Notice the status does not say Completed because that
step of the process did not complete.
Now we did not roll back in the event of an error.
So with programmatic transaction management,
the developer is responsible for doing that.
So let's go back to the code and update it to roll back.
So all we need to do here when we catch this
exception on the transaction status, let's use the setRollbackOnly method.
And that's all we need to do.
So let's navigate back to Postman.
Let's click Send.
We see status of 200 OK.
So now let's navigate back to the H2 console.
Let's look in our ticket table.
And we see no records, and that's what we expect because we initiated a rollback.
Now let's look at setting the transaction advice.
Navigate back to IntelliJ,
and we're actually going to do this in the constructor here.
So let's add a new line, line 33.
Let's use the transactionTemplate to set the PropagationBehaviorName.
In this case, it's going to be PROPAGATION_REQUIRES_NEW.
And we can also use the transactionTemplate to set readOnly to true.
This is the same example that forces a new transaction
each time and also sets it to readOnly.
Let's navigate to Postman and exercise our API.
Let's click Send.
See a status of 200 OK.
Let's navigate to our H2 console.
Let's see what's in our tickets table. Nothing as we expect because we set it to readOnly.