The @EnableTransactionManagement annotation enables Spring's
annotation-driven transaction management capability.
However, when using Spring Boot,
transaction management is automatically configured for us.
When looking at the sample code,
you will see that the @Transactional annotation works without having to
include the @EnableTransactionManagement annotation,
and declarative transaction management works,
although we haven't defined or configured a platform transaction manager.
The case study for this project uses Spring Boot,
and we have added Spring Data JPA in our class path via our pom.
xml file.
Due to this dependency, Spring Boot does a lot for us behind the scenes.
Spring registers a transaction manager for us,
in this case a JPA transaction manager.
It also takes care of the Datasource, entity manager, repositories, etc.
And calls on Spring Data repositories are by default surrounded by transaction.
If Spring Data finds an existing transaction,
the existing transaction will be reused.
Otherwise, a new transaction is created.
Just remember when you're not using Spring Boot,
the @Transactional annotation within your code will only be evaluated when
you use the @EnableTransactionManagement annotation.
You can easily trace transaction behavior by adding the
following property to your application.
properties file.
This is where we set the logging level to TRACE. You can easily get access to the transaction manager by autowiring it.