Up to this point in the course,
you've learned about images and containers and even seeing how you can
orchestra multiple containers using Docker Compose.
And that works great while you're on your development machine, but what do
you do when you're ready to move to another environment?
Well, that's we're going to look at in this module.
So we're going to look at movie from Docker Compose
to something called Kubernetes.
Specifically, we're going to cover the following topics.
We're going to talk about how Docker Compose is great for
some things, but not so great for others, and we'll talk
about what's missing there.
I'll introduce you to Kubernetes and give you some
fundamentals on the basics of what it is.
We'll then talk about how we can convert from a Docker Compose file to some
files that Kubernetes can use to run your containers.
We'll then look at commands you can use in Kubernetes to
actually get your containers up and running and also how you
can stop and remove those containers. So let's go ahead and get started.