Up to this point,
we've learned about the layered file system and how it
works with images and containers,
how containers are a little bit unique and have their own
thin read/write type of layered file system,
and we call that the container layer typically.
Now I mentioned though that any changes made while a container is
running that are written to the writable layer,
they kind of go away if a container is removed.
So if you delete that container,
you're also going to delete the file layer that is the read/write layer.
Now obviously in scenarios when you have database
files and logs and source code, we might want to keep that around potentially,
especially while we're doing development and just trying to
use Docker as a development environment.
So fortunately,
Docker and containers have another feature we can use called volumes. And what
I'm going to do in this section is just introduce volumes,
and then later we're going to learn about how we can use those volumes.
So what is a volume?
Well,
a volume is nothing more than a special type of directory
that's associated with a container,
and typically you'll hear it referred to as a data volume, and
that's because we can store all types of data.
It could be code, could be log files, could be data files, and more.
Now we can share and reuse these among containers,
so it is possible for multiple containers to write to this
volume, or you could just have a single container that has one
or more volumes that it writes to.
And what's nice about this is any updates to an image
aren't going to affect a data volume.
It stays separate.
Also, data volumes are persistent.
So even if a container is deleted and it's
completely blown away from the machine,
the data volume can do still stick around, and you have control over that.
Now, from a high level, you can think of volumes this way.
If we have a container,
then we can come in and define a volume within that container.
So in this example, /var/www, where do we want that to write?
Well, you kind of have two options.
You can let Docker figure it out, or you can give it your own.
And I'm going to show you how to do your own custom
volume coming up in the next section.
But for now,
let's just know that when you write to a volume, so let's say
that your code in the Docker container actually does a write
operation to this /var/www path, well,
that is really just going to be an alias for a mounted
folder that is in your Docker host.
Now remember that the Docker host is actually hosting the container.
So if you're running on a Linux system or a Windows Server 2016 or
higher type of system, then the host would be that OS. It's the thing
that the container is actually running on top of.
And so in this example,
if we had a volume that we wrote to, instead of writing into that thin
read/write type of layer that is associated with the container that we
talked about with the layered file system,
it can actually write it up into this mounted folder area that's part
of the Docker host. Now if you delete the container,
the folder that's on your Docker host, it can actually stick around,
and you can preserve all of that code if you'd like.
So that's a quick introduction to what a data volume is and what a
volume in general is in the world of Docker containers.
So now what we're going to look at is how can we actually get our source
code into our containers using volumes? And we'll see how we can set that up using things like the Docker client.