Now let's switch over to the Windows side.
Recall earlier that I mentioned that there's a few options for Windows
depending on what version of the operating system you have.
If you're on Windows 7 or 8 or even Windows 10 Home,
then you're going to have to go with Docker Toolbox
because you won't have access to Hyper‑V.
If you're on Windows 10 Pro or higher, then you will have Hyper‑V accessibility,
and therefore you could install the preferred version,
which would be Docker Desktop.
Now I'm going to walk you through how to get started with both,
but we're going to focus on Docker Desktop in the install
and throughout this course overall.
So the first thing to talk about is Docker Toolbox.
And as you can see on the web page here,
this is the legacy desktop solution if you don't have Hyper‑V available.
This will run VirtualBox instead.
And the good news is you can still run images and containers and
do all these commands we're going to learn.
It's just a older way to do it, but it definitely works.
Now you can go to docker.com/docker‑toolbox. And from here
down at the bottom, you can install it for Windows, and then
they have some instructions.
Now I'm not going to be running that one here,
but I'll let you if you need that. Go to this link,
get it installed.
If you need any help with that,
refer to the install instructions that they provide.
Now for Docker Desktop, it's going to look identical to what you saw on Mac.
We can scroll on down. We can click Download for Windows.
Once this executable comes down, we can simply run through the install routine.
All right, so now that's done.
Let's go ahead and open the file.
I'll go ahead and approve doing that.
And now this is going to start a download routine that will
get everything we need. Now in my case,
I already have this installed on this machine.
So it's going to be really fast,
as you see here. It says existing installation is up
to date, and I'll just close that.
But for you, you're going to have to run through it.
It'll take a little bit of time to get it going, of course.
Now from there, we can then go run Docker.
So if we come on down to the Start menu, we can type docker, and
there's Docker Desktop. Now what'll happen is this will go down in our
tray in kind of the right‑hand corner here.
So let me go ahead and go to that.
And you can see that our whale is currently starting up, and we now have a
message that says Docker is starting. Let me click that again, and then
we'll just wait a little bit for this to get going.
All right, so now that's done.
We can do much like we did on Mac I can right‑click.
Instead of Preferences,
I can come up to Settings. And the settings are going to look
pretty identical to what you see on the Mac side.
There's a few differences here and there,
but it's very,
very similar now. So we can start once we log in, automatically check for
updates. We can even expose some TCP ports here and do even more if you
have Windows subsystem for Linux going. We can come down to resources, set
our CPUs, our memory, our swap, and image size. Turn on volume sharing.
Notice that I have C drive exposed here. And again, we'll talk more about
what a volume is and why you'd use it with containers a little bit later in
the course.
If you deal with proxies, you can configure that.
And then just some general networking here.
Now Docker Engine, this again is something we normally don't have to touch.
Same with command line, more experimental in this case.
And then I've already talked about there's this other tool called Kubernetes,
which you can also enable here if you'd like to.
Now if we cancel out of this, we'll get to the dashboard again.
And this time,
notice I have quite a bit going. They're all stopped, but I have quite a
lot going here you'll see. So I could actually start to just clean these
up if I wanted. We could start deleting these,
but I'll go ahead and leave these.
But it's very much like what you saw with Mac.
I can actually come on in and start my containers,
stop them, delete them, and do more, get to the logs and other things we saw.
So as an example,
we could click on maybe this ASP.NET PostgreSQL Docker one, and
notice it's exited. But I could start that back up.
Then we could get to the logs and do all kinds of fun stuff there.
So there's a lot of great stuff you can do with this dashboard.
And although we're going to focus on the core Docker commands,
knowing about this is nice.
I don't use it every day,
but every now and then it's just easier to come into here to do certain things.
So that's how easy it is to get either Docker Toolbox or Docker Desktop going on Windows.