Once you have your Dockerfile completed and all the instructions are in place,
you're going to need to run that through the build process using Docker client,
and that's what we're going to look at here.
So how do we take that Dockerfile for Node.js and
actually make it into an image?
Well, it's actually a very simple process.
Docker, the client, has a build command you can run,
and then what you can do is tag that build,
and you'll want to tag each build.
Now you can do ‑‑tag, or the shortcut that you see here, which is just tag.
I prefer the ‑t, it saves you a couple keystrokes.
Now from there,
you're going to go in and give your image that you're going to make a tag name.
Now, if you go up online and look at all the node images,
there's a whole bunch out there,
lots of different versions because they're all tagged with the version.
Now in this case, I'm just going to say whatever my username is /node,
we're just going to say it's good enough for our team,
but we could put more details there with version info if we wanted.
And then finally, I'm going to give it to build context,
which is going to be the folder where it's actually going to
run this from that will help find the Dockerfile and do some
other things along the way.
So let's go ahead and do this with the image that we have.
Now,
the first thing I'm going to do is I want to get rid of my node_modules here.
So I'm going to come in and use a little npm tool I use a lot called rimraf.
So the first thing, I'm just going to right‑click and open in Terminal,
and I'm going to use this rimraf, which is a delete module.
And I want to show you that if I get rid of the modules here,
that as we build the image, that it will take care of that for us.
From here,
we can go ahead and build our Dockerfile into an
image using the docker build command.
Now, I mentioned that you can do ‑t for the tag,
but before we do that, notice that our name,
again, is Dockerfile.
And that's the default name that the docker build process looks for.
But if you do have a different name for the file,
it could be dockerfile.dev or node.dockerfile or something like that,
then ‑f will be for the file name, and then I can put the name.
Now in this case it's redundant because that's what it looks for anyway,
but that's a nice one to know as you might have
different file names for your Dockerfiles.
Now I can do my tag, we'll give my Docker Hub ID,
and we'll give it the name and then the context,
the folder in which we're going to run this is dot.
So let's go ahead and run it.
Now I already have the node image, just as a heads up,
already installed locally as a Docker image,
so I did that on purpose to speed this process up.
So aside from the npm install, which it's doing right now,
this should go really, really fast.
But once this is done,
I'm going to show a couple things here that relate to
something called intermediate containers.
All right, so we're all done.
And if we do docker images, you'll see my danwahlin node,
and then there's my node base image that it's based upon.
But notice that every single instruction generated
what's called an intermediate container.
And if I go way up to the top, and let me just slide quickly back up,
even the environment instructions each generated their
own separate intermediate container.
Now, what happens is these containers,
they won't show up in your Docker images when you run that,
but they will be cached behind the scenes so that the next time I do a build,
if this instruction, such as the environment one,
doesn't change, then the build process can just say,
hey, I've already seen that before.
Let me just go load the layered file system layer and
just include that in the build.
So it's very much like source control.
Every time you check in a small little thing in source control,
it tracks it incrementally.
That's exactly what happens with Docker instructions.
Now in the case of our environments, I could have put,
because I used the equals, if we go back to here,
I could have put the port equals 3000 right next to this one up on top,
and I mentioned that earlier,
and that would have just done one intermediate container,
but because I ran them as a separate instruction,
it has to do two lookups, and so those are very quick lookups,
not a big deal,
but it's important to know that every instruction leads to
an intermediate container being created that's ultimately
cached behind the scenes.
All right, now that we have that done,
let's go ahead and try to do the run process.
I'm going to do a docker run,
I'm going to run this in something we haven't seen much up to this point,
in a daemon mode,
that way the output of running the container won't
actually show up in the console.
It will run behind the scenes,
and then I can do other things with the console if I want.
So we're going to do the port, we'll do 8080:3000, and then we'll put the
name of the image, and let's run off to the location.
And this will be 99.100:8080.
You see it right there. All right, and it looks good.
This is showing that the source code we copied in that we did previously
in the course is actually being used in the container.
That's an example of how we can work with our Docker files,
use some of the different instructions, and then use the Docker client commands like build and run.