Let's take a look at how we can create a custom ASP.NET Core Dockerfile,
some of the different options for doing that and some of the different
images that are available that we're going to use as the base of that
cake that we kind of build on top of.
So the first thing I'm going to do is run off to hub.docker.com,
and I've already searched for Microsoft .NET Core,
and if I scroll down just a little bit, you'll see .NET Core shows up.
Now there's a few options here, but we're going to click on this first one,
.NET Core, and you'll notice these are the official images for .NET core 2.1,
3.1, and of course this will just increase over time to different versions,
so make sure you always check for the latest version as you do this.
Scrolling on down though,
you'll notice there's some different featured .NET Core images.
We have .NET Core SDK; .NET Core ASP.NET,
notice that's for production runtime; and then we have some other ones as
well that you could use if you're not doing like ASP.NET,
for example.
They even have some .NET 5.0 images.
So, if we move on down, they'll give you some info about this.
They'll talk about how to build,
and they'll even have a little example of how to run it,
but,
what we're going to do is use the SDK image first and
I'll show you the basics of that.
Then we're going to go ahead and look at the runtime image,
and I'll show you the basics of that as well.
So let's jump into VS Code here.
The project that I have loaded is just a standard ASP.NET Core MVC type project.
You'll see a Controllers folder, and Models,
and Views; and inside of it I already have two Docker
files that we're going to look at, but,
I'm going to show you how we can actually generate
one of these kind of automagically, if you will.
Now let's go to our dev.dockerfile here,
and this will look pretty familiar based on what
we've covered earlier in the course.
We have our from, there's our base image,
so, mcr.microsoft.com would be the registry,
and then we have the .NET Core SDK,
and that's the one we want in this case because you'll see we're
going to do a dotnet restore and a dotnet watch run,
but notice there's no code in this one.
So we'd have to set up a volume and you can see an
example of that down here in the comments,
and we've already looked at that.
But walking through it, we have the base,
which is our from; we have our label; three environment variables here,
notice that we're going to target Port 5000 on this one; our
working directory is going to be /app, that again can be whatever you'd like,
and then we're going to do a bash command that would run the dotnet restore,
followed by the dotnet watch run.
Now a little trick I'm going to show you though is we could come
down and build the image like we've already seen,
but we could also use a VS Code plugin. So you'll notice on the left here, I
have a little whale icon for Docker, and you can notice that I have my
images, any running containers would be listed here.
I can connect to registries, so if I had a personal registry or a
company registry, and then networks, volumes, and you'll notice all
this kind of really cool information down here.
Now I have quite a few images you'll notice,
and if we move on down,
here's an mcr.microsoft.com one, there's the SDK one actually.
So how do you get this? Well in VS Code, if you go down to the extensions,
which is this icon here, you could just type docker,
and then you can install the Docker extension from Microsoft.
It's a really, really nice extension,
totally worth installing, I use it for a fair amount of
things. And so once you have it installed,
you now will have this little whale icon on the left
that would get to your local images,
local containers, and then I could even connect to a registry here,
such as ACR, Azure Container Registry; Docker Hub; some
other one that's maybe local that stores these; GitLab,
and you'll notice a few options.
Alright,
so that's a really nice plugin and I'm going to show you how
we can use that to do some cool stuff here.
Now, this first image would be more if we're going to do a volume,
but let's say we're not going to do that,
we would actually like to build a production version of our image.
Well,
prod.dockerfile in this case would be for that, and this is
what we call a multistage build Docker file.
This has multiple steps that we can go through to not
only build our code in a container, publish it,
but then copy that published code to the final image that we want to generate.
So literally from starting the build to actually generating
the final image that's going to go up to,
say, Docker Hub or some other registry, we can do all that right here with this.
So let's walk through this.
So in the first part,
we're just going to find a base which is based on the aspnet runtime.
That's a production version and I'm going to alias it as base.
That's something you can do in Docker files just to give an alias.
Now we're going to in stage two, come down and go to the SDK image,
and we're going to alias that as build.
Now all this does is it goes and copies in this local project here,
the csproj, does a dotnet restore, copies in everything else,
sets the working directory, and then does a build. You'll notice we're
going to build a release mode, we're going to output to a folder called
app, in this case. So we're literally building the code using
containers, ultimately, behind the scenes.
Now from there,
we're then going to create this from build as publish, okay, and remember,
build is our alias up here that's going to have our build code.
Now we're going to run the dotnet publish command, and we're
going to output that to the app folder.
So, what'll end up happening is ultimately the app folder will get our
distribution code that we'd want, our DLLs and things like that.
Now the final stage of this is we're going to create this from base.
Now remember, base is ASP.NET, that's our runtime production image.
We're going to generate that, and we're going to put the
environment variable for the port we want to listen on,
you'll probably be changing that,
but that's what I have, and then notice that we have our expose, our
working directory, and then here is the magic right here.
Notice this from=publish, now remember,
publish was the one up here that was based on build, and that actually ran the
dotnet publish command and updated the app folder with it.
From that publish image, we actually want to copy from
the app folder to the local folder.
Well what's the local folder?
It's the working directory.
It's also named /app.
Now,
I could've come in and done this, it would have been the same
thing, but since we set the working directory,
that would just be duplication, we don't really need that. Now from here,
we take the name of the DLL that would be generated, and that
is what will actually be run in this case.
Now, if you're looking at that going, gosh,
there's no way I could memorize that and do all that by hand.
Well, I don't really either,
to be honest, and I'm going to show you a really cool trick here.
So remember I installed the Docker extension that I talked
about that gets me to all these things.
Well, it can do more than that.
If you hit Shift+Command+P or Shift+Ctrl+P ‑ Shift+Command would be on Mac,
Shift+Ctrl would be on Windows ‑ and type docker, you're going to notice
all kinds of stuff that shows up. Now, the one I want is docker add, and
notice this Docker Files to Workspace.
What this will do is actually generate Docker files
based on your target framework.
So I'm going to click on that, now it's going to say okay,
well, what are you targeting?
Well, I'm going to say ASP.NET Core, and now notice I get an error down here.
Now, if we expand this error, it says please generate a build task.
So we need to do the same thing.
We need to get back to the command palette and type this .NET Generate.
So let's do that.
I'll go back to the command palette,
.NET Generate Assets for Build, I'm going to click on that, and there we go.
Now what that just did is updated a launch and a task JSON file,
which basically can handle the build tasks.
So now that's there, let's go back to the command pallet, we'll type docker
again, and I'm going to do this Add Docker Files to Workspace.
We'll pick ASP.NET Core, and now from here, we can pick either Linux or Windows.
Now I'm going to pick Linux.
Do you want to include a Docker Compose?
I'm going to say no in this case,
we'll talk about Docker Compose later, and then what are your ports?
Well, for us it's 5000, and then we hit Enter.
Now what this just did is generated something very,
very similar to what you saw earlier in kind of my custom one.
This is a multistage build where we have a base; we have our build image,
which does our build; we have our publish and then we have our final
down here, and then base this name based on what's in my csproj,
you'll see that name matches up right there.
Now, what's really cool about this is number one, I didn't have to write it.
This is only for production though,
so it's important to note that any time you see ASP.NET,
that's going to be for production.
Now we have pulled in the latest version of the image at this time.
That will obviously change over time,
but that gives you a nice starting point, again depending on what
version you're working with. Now it's pretty much identical to what
you're going to see here, it's really close,
and then I even have some steps on how you can build this, but with the
extension, we could actually come on in like this, and you'll notice right
here at the bottom, Build Image, and if I click that,
it'll actually try to build that image right now on my machine and I don't even
have to really know what I'm doing. Now, it's pulling down some layers that
were missing, it's now doing the multistage build,
the publish, all that fun stuff.
We're going to look at this a little bit more manually in the next section,
but, that's how easy it would be to get started with this.
Now I'm going to Ctrl+C to stop this, we're not going to really use it
anymore, but that would be an example of generating a Docker file that you
don't even have to write the code, really all I did again is either
Shift+Command+P to get to the command palette or Shift+Ctrl+P, and if the
Docker extension's installed,
just type docker and you'll see there's all kinds of Docker commands.
But, that's an example of a more production Docker file, and then I
showed you a more development Docker file, where you might want to
create a volume to link back to your code.
So now you kind of have both ways of doing it.
So from here, let's see how we can take this and build it, and then we'll start looking at this.