Let's take a look at Docker Compose in action,
and we're going to work with a custom YAML file,
as well as use some of the different Docker Compose
commands that we talked about earlier.
All right, so I've already opened up a Node.js, MongoDB type of project.
This is the same exact one that we saw earlier where we had to
manually run some of the different commands to build our images
and then run our different containers.
So while that works, it's a little bit inefficient,
I would argue,
and definitely not something I want to have to copy and paste those
commands in every time I want to run a container,
rebuild an image, or whatever it may be.
So I've already created a docker‑compose.yml YAML file,
and the first thing we're going to do to make it easier to
bring up our Node and our Mongo services,
which is again, really our containers,
is add them and define them into this particular YAML file.
So the first thing I'm going to do is we're going to come in and mark
the current version that I have to do as of today.
Next thing we're going to do is we're going to add the services that we want.
And because we're going to have two services here that sort of link up,
if you will, we're going to do that through the bridge network.
So I'm going to come in and I'm going to name it nodeapp‑network.
And then we're going to have to say that the driver for this network,
since there are different options here,
is the bridge one that we've already talked about earlier in the course.
All right,
so that will take care of having a network that's named nodeapp‑network.
So that part represents the name.
And then the only property I had to put in this case for
that was that it was a bridge network.
So the next thing we're going to do is come in and
define I'm going to call it node, and we're going to do a node service.
And I want to build this from the custom Node Dockerfile that I already have.
And so I'm going to come in and add a build property,
and then it has some subproperties.
I'm going to name the first one context.
I want to run from the context of where this YAML file is here.
So if there's any subfolders I had to get to in the Dockerfile,
it would set the context of where that runs from.
So that's actually a really important concept.
Then the next one is what's the Dockerfile?
Well, I'm not using the standard just Dockerfile name.
I'm doing node.dockerfile.
All right, and that'll take care of that.
Now this particular one is going to run on some ports.
We're going to do the mapping of the external to the internal.
I'm going to do 3000 to 3000.
Very similar to what we've done, 3000 on the external, 3000 on the internal.
And then we're also going to need to hook this into our nodeapp‑network.
So I can say networks and then simply put in‑‑‑ Every time you see the dash,
it's because I could add multiple items here in the YAML file format.
We're going to call this nodeapp‑network,
and that just matches that name right there.
All right, so we're kind of off and running with that particular service.
So one more time, we're going to call it node.
We set the build context to basically the folder where the YAML file is,
and then we give it our Dockerfile.
We're going to expose the ports that we want to set up and hook it into
the network that you see here in this particular case.
All right, now the next thing we're going to do is hook in our MongoDB,
and this one is not going to be built from a custom image
or a custom Dockerfile that I have.
It's going to be based on the one that's up in Docker Hub.
So I'm just going to list the name of the image there,
and let me change that because it's actually just mongo.
And then we also need to hook it into the network.
So I can just kind of copy and paste this part right here.
And were off and running.
So that would be an example of creating a custom Docker Compose YAML file.
It's not that hard.
Really it's just a matter of going to the documentation on docker.com,
looking up the Docker Compose YAML file documentation,
it's pretty well documented, and then just taking the time to do it.
And the nice thing is, once you've done this a few times,
you can just start to copy and paste and tweak things
between your different YAML files there.
All right, so now we have our services defined.
We have a node.
We have a mongo.
They're both in the same nodeapp‑network here.
And that way, when we run these services and run the up command,
then it's going to put both of them in the network
so they can talk to each other, and we've seen that earlier again in the course.
All right,
so let me run off now to the terminal that I already have up for this
particular folder and because we have a Docker Compose file,
imagine that you just checked this source code,
maybe out of your version control, and brought it down to your local machine,
and now all I'd have to do to get an environment up and
running is say docker‑compose build.
So I first need to get the images in place.
Now this will take just a little bit of time.
I have some of this cached, but it should be pretty quick.
And you can see it's now done.
And then mongo was already there locally if I did docker images.
So it didn't have to do anything there.
So if we do docker images,
you'll notice I have this
nodeexpressmongodbdockerapp_node. It kind of named that
part.
And we could even name it, by the way. That's possible to do too.
And in here is my mongo image.
And so those are all ready to go.
So now the next thing to try to get this going would be to do docker‑compose up.
Now this is going to go ahead and start both of these up.
They just did.
And you'll notice though that when I brought it up,
it's kind of in log mode right now.
And so I'd have to open up a new terminal to really do anything here.
Probably not what I want.
So let's go ahead and go into here now. I'm going to say docker‑compose down,
and that's going to go ahead and stop both of those.
And it's going to go ahead and remove the containers as well,
which is really nice.
So we'll let this stop.
All right,
so that's all stopped now, and you'll notice it also removed,
so stopped and removed all in one shot.
Now what I didn't like about that is when I did docker‑compose up,
it kind of blocked us from using the terminal. So let's go ahead
and do it, but we want to run in daemon mode.
I want to run it behind the scenes.
Let's go ahead and try that.
All right, now notice they should be up.
We'll prove that in a moment.
But I can get back to the command prompt.
So you've seen that before when we did docker run.
So let's go in and do another command, docker‑compose, and
let's do ps and see what we have running here.
And you can see we have two containers.
So there's our mongodb. There's our node. It shows the status of the ports
and the IPs and all that stuff we've already seen before.
All right, so since those are both up,
let's run off to the browser. And I already have the
IP for the virtual machine here.
We're going to do the port of 3000, and this should now hit it, and there we do.
Now I'm not going to run the db seeder that we saw earlier.
I'm not seeing any data because this was a fresh container,
and so there's no data in the MongoDB database. But we certainly
could also run commands against that if we wanted, and that way we
could seed it with some data. But you can see it is up and running,
and we didn't get any errors there.
Now if you wanted to see that hey, there are no errors, then we could also,
while we're here,
do docker‑compose, and we can do logs. And what this will do is give
us the logs for all the containers that are associated with this
docker‑compose that we ran. All right, and there we go.
So notice that now I have the entire kind of log infrastructure here,
if you will.
I'm going to go ahead and exit that out. And you'll notice I can
get to all the details about, in this case,
the MongoDB setup.
Here's my npm it looks like. Here's the calls that went in as we hit the
web page. And it looks like, other than me aborting down here, everything
is looking pretty good. Now to bring these down,
which you've already seen, we can do docker‑compose down. And this will
go ahead and bring these down, and now we'll be kind of off and running,
and we can rebuild the images or do what we want. And I can even remove
all the images if we wanted to.
When you do the down,
there's a ‑‑rmi all that I showed a little bit
earlier, and we could do that as well.
So now let's do docker‑compose ps.
You'll notice nothing is running there. And we could even do the normal
docker client ps ‑a if we wanted, and there's nothing there.
But if we go to docker images, you'll see that I still have my two images here.
There's my mongo and there's my node image.
So that's an example of how we can use Docker Compose to very
easily, not only build, but also run our services and then
take those down when we're done.
And then if I wanted to set up volumes and all that kind of stuff,
we certainly could. We'll see that coming up in the later demo in this module.
Now before we wrap up this section,
let me show you one more Docker Compose YAML file.
Now this is for ASP.NET Core and PostgreSQL.
Now again,
I could come into our Dockerfile, and we could manually run the
different commands that we looked at earlier in the course.
But now I have my version, my services,
and I have a web and a postgres. And you'll notice that for the
web, it's very similar to what I just showed for node. We have a
custom Dockerfile, we set the context,
we give the ports, and we hook it into a bridge network. And for postgres,
it's really close to the same thing.
But you'll notice right here, I'm actually adding on environment variable value.
Now this is something that the PostgreSQL image knows about.
And so we did this manually earlier when we ran docker‑client run,
we had to put this on the command line, And you could do that, but again,
I don't really want to type that over and over and over or
copy and paste over and over and over. So we just simply
use this environment property.
Now I can put in the different environment variables that I'd like to set,
and you can certainly put more than one if you'd like.
And then we link that into the same network, and we can
call this from the ASP.NET Core container that'll be
running based on this name right here.
All right, so we can do the same exact thing now. If I just had grabbed this,
which,
actually I don't have this going as an image yet,
then we can come into the folder, which I'm already in.
We can say docker‑compose build.
Now this will have to build the ASP.NET image, which will take a moment.
And you can see there's a postgres image as well, which I already have locally.
So now we're kind of ready to go.
And if we do docker images,
we should now see that we have the web one here for
the aspnetcorepostgresqldockerapp.
All right, so that's kind of the first step.
Now we know we can do docker compose up. This should now start those up.
Didn't do ‑d, But that's okay, in this case. There's all our logs for that.
Now we can come back and hit port 5000.
So let's go ahead and try that.
Change that up. And we'll be off and running here, and this now hits it.
And this one already seeded the database.
So this one you can see is definitely working because it
shows us the seed data that ASP.NET put in.
And if I scroll up,
you'll be able to see some of the SQL statements and things. Even
the inserts for the seeding are shown here.
So now we can break out of here, and I can say docker‑compose ps. There we go.
They're both up.
And then, of course,
docker‑compose stop if I wanted. That would just stop them,
but we're going to do down, and that'll actually stop them and
remove them as we talked about.
So that's an example of how you can get started with Docker Compose, with Node and Mongo and a YAML file and then ASP.NET Core and Postgres.