Before we officially convert between Docker Compose to Kubernetes files,
let's talk about a few key concepts that you need to know in Kubernetes.
Now, as I mentioned at the very beginning of this module,
Kubernetes is actually a very big topic,
and that's why there's full courses just on Kubernetes.
The goal here is really just to break you in gently,
if you will,
to some of the different concepts that you need to know
so you can get up and running quickly.
But know that there's definitely going to be more research involved on your
part if you want to use this in a real‑life scenario.
So the first thing I want to talk about that we're going to see
coming up is something called a deployment.
This plays a central role in Kubernetes because it allows us to describe the
desired state we're after in one of two types of files.
We can use a YAML file, which is the normal one, or even a JSON file.
So what we'll be doing as we convert from Docker Compose to Kubernetes is
one option would be to basically translate the services in our Docker
Compose file that define the images and the containers that should run
into a Kubernetes deployment file.
I'm going to show you an easy way to do that to get started.
But really, what a deployment is all about,
in a nutshell anyway, is saying, hey,
I need these five containers up and running,
and I need them to be able to communicate somehow.
Now in addition to describing the desired state in a deployment,
you can also use it to replicate pods,
and this allows you to scale out if you'd like,
add more pods onto a node, for example.
And it even supports rolling updates and rollbacks,
which can be very important as you version your app into the future.
Now in addition to deployments,
we're also going to see something called a service.
Up to this point, we've seen that containers run in pods,
but pods can live and die.
If a container goes down,
that pod may be completely removed and a new pod might be brought up.
So they could have a very short or long lifespan.
It really depends.
So from a consumer standpoint,
we can't always count on the IP address of a pod and
ultimately the container being there.
Services allow us to abstract those pod IP addresses from the consumers,
and I'll show you a visual of this in just a moment.
In a nutshell, though, that's a good thing because now,
if a pod dies and a new one's brought up,
the consumer doesn't even know anything happened.
Everything is good to go because the service kind of acts as the middleman,
if you will.
In cases where you have multiple pods that a service knows about
it can also load balance between those pods.
And that could be good, as we talked about, when it comes to
scaling out and those types of scenarios.
So here's a visual of how this all works.
A service is going to have an IP address,
but a pod is also going to have an IP address.
Now ultimately, a consumer of this pod wants to get to the container,
but if we gave them the 10.0.0.43 address,
well, that might go away in the next few seconds,
potentially if something happened to the pod.
So, what we'll do is instead give the consumer the reference to the 10.0.0.1 IP,
which is the service.
That way, if the pod changes,
or maybe even a new pod gets added with different containers,
the consumer just has to remember that one IP and know about it to
talk to the different pods. Now behind the scenes,
the service is going to be in charge of knowing about the different pods.
If one goes down and a new one comes up and the IP address changes,
then the service will automatically take care of that.
So it's a level of abstraction to allow consumers just to
have one endpoint they need to know about.
Now are there more files and concepts aside from just deployments and services?
Yes,
there are, actually. There's a whole bunch of things we could get into. But
these are two of the key ones you're going to see in just a moment as we talk more about converting from Docker Compose to Kubernetes.