Apps set up with an even layout separate out Java
source files from other types of files.
This means that the application property files for your
Spring Boot app are located in src, main,
resources.
So I'm going to go ahead and open up that folder,
and you'll notice there's a file called application.properties.
We'll reopen that because we've already made some changes to this file.
When we set up the app,
we added the data source in jpa.properties to this file
so that our app would work correctly.
One thing that you should know is these properties are actually
overrides of Spring Boot default properties.
I've jumped over to a browser,
and I've opened up this URL to this Spring Boot Common application properties.
If this URL goes out of date in the future,
simply go to a Google search and look for Spring
Boot Common application properties, and you'll be able to find this Appendix A.
Spring Boot and Spring Boot starters provide a setup of default properties,
and these properties provide sensible defaults,
as well as provides an application developer the ability to customize
the application with having to write or change code.
If I take one of the properties we configured,
like the spring.datasource .url, and search for it,
you can see the default, which is null,
and see what starter or system the property comes from.
In this case, it's handled by the DataSourceProperties.
As I scroll up, you can see it's coming from DataSourceProperties,
as well as the DataSourceAutoConfiguration class that Spring
Boot provides in the Spring Data JPA starter.
Let's try taking another default property and changing it in our application.
The app, by default,
runs on port 8080 as you've seen when you ran it after we built the app.
So let's go ahead and change that.
We want to find a property called server.port.
You can see that the default value is set to 8080.
So how do you think that we could change this to say port 5000?
Well, all we need to do is simply put this in our property file and override it.
So I'll go ahead and copy this value and jump back to IntelliJ.
Back in the application.properties,
we can simply add that new property to the end of the file
and override the value to port 5000.
If I save that file and restart the application,
come down to the Run tab to do that, and start up the application,
you can see now that Tomcat is started on port 5000,
and that's all it takes to override the Spring default common
application properties to simply put it in your application and
provide the value that suits your needs. Next, let's take a look at overriding app properties with external configuration.