I'm back in the application.properties file,
and I want to adjust the database connection info.
Maybe I'm getting ready to deploy to production,
or maybe my database got moved, or something has changed,
and I need to deal with it.
The first thing that you should take note of is that the database URL
and credentials are currently hard coded into the app.
This info is your production database info,
and you check your code into a public Git repository,
all of the sudden,
everyone has credentials and access to your production database.
So the best way to solve this is to simply not hard code your
database info in the application.properties file.
Let's go ahead and move it to an external environment variable.
Spring Boot handles property placeholders in the application property file.
First, I'm going to copy the URL and remove it from the app properties file.
Next, I'm going to replace the value with this.
This tells Spring to look for a property called DB_URL and
set its value on the datasource.url.
In order to do this,
we need to set up an environment variable to handle that URL.
Once that's done, none of the info is actually _____ into the source code,
but I can still run my application.
To add an environment variable to the IntelliJ,
you need to click on the Run menu and go to Edit Configurations,
find the ConferenceDemoApplication configuration and jump
down to the Environment Variables box.
In here, we can add the name of the environment variable,
which is DB_URL,
and we can paste the value that we pulled out of the
application.properties file into here, click OK to save that,
we'll go ahead and apply this, and click OK to exit.
So at this point,
my app is now configured to read an external
property value for the database URL.
You'd most likely want to do the same for the username and password
properties so that sensitive data isn't hard coded into the file.
To test this out, we can go ahead and restart or run our application,
and at this point, IntelliJ is saying Tomcat has started on port 5000,
but you can jump over to Postman really quick just to test
out we can get data from our database.
Back in Postman, I can test my sessions out again.
But if you remember, we changed the port of our application to 5000,
so I'll need to update that as well.
Once I'm on the correct port, I'll go ahead and send the request to the server,
and you'll notice that we still got all of our data,
even though we pulled the database URL out of the
applications file and into an environment variable.
At this point, if you happen to deploy your application in production,
you can simply provide the production credentials as an environment variable,
and your app is now pointing to an appropriate data source for that environment.
This is one way that you can handle environment-specific configuration.
Spring Boot also provides another way to handle environment configuration, which we'll take a look at next.