Spring Boot makes configuration very easy to use and work with.
There are, however, a lot of options on how you can customize your application.
Here's what you should have learned in this section of the course.
First,
you should know that Spring Boot looks for
configuration files on the class path.
Your project will typically utilize the src, main, resources folder for this.
Spring Boot can read and work with property files and YAML files.
There is also an order of precedence of when and their values are
configured from external to internal configuration sources.
Next,
you need to be aware of all the common Spring Boot properties that are provided
out of the box by Spring and the various Spring starters.
These are your first area of customization when you need to
modify something in your application.
When it comes to your application,
Spring Boot can load in specific files based off of Spring profiles that
will override and customize your app per environment.
This is the right, or correct, way to handle moving your app from development,
to test, to staging, to prod, and so on.
Simply provide appropriate environment files
configured for each environment profile.
Finally, you can start to get fancy with configuration and handle it all in Java.
You can even create your own auto-configuration classes
and starter JAR files for your apps.
And that's it for configuration.
The only thing that we have left to do is to figure out the right
way to deploy our Spring Boot applications, which we'll be covering in the next section of the course.