Spring has made creating a new Spring Boot project easier than ever.
I'll be covering a couple of different ways of generating
or creating a project from scratch.
We'll begin first by using the site Spring Initializr,
which you can go to at a URL, start.spring .io,
in your browser.
Get that open and follow along.
We're going to be building a conference scheduling app in this course,
and this app will hold difference sessions and allow speakers to
be assigned as the presenter of a session.
The speaker can present more than one session.
If you been to any conference,
think of this as the planning and organization app that builds out the
conference topics and sessions for the organizers.
So to begin, any app that you create will need a few customizations,
and this app will be no exception.
First off,
we're going to be using the Maven Project type for
the project rather than Gradle, next,
we're going to use the preselected Java language,
and we'll go ahead and select the latest Spring Boot version,
which at the time of this recording is 2.1 .9.
For the Group name, I'm going to go ahead and change that to say com.pluralsight,
and I'm going to change the Artifact name to be conference-demo.
Finally,
we need to tell the project generator which pieces of Spring we'd
like to include in our Spring Boot application.
To keep this simple, I'm just going to select the Spring web dependency.
You can do that by switching tabs from the magnifying glass to the table layout.
And in here,
you can see all of the different frameworks that are
available for your application.
All I want to do is begin by using the Spring Web, so I'm going to select that.
Now if I go back to the magnifying glass,
you'll see that the Selected dependencies is simply Spring Web.
If you want, you could also type them in here on this text box,
and you could find different project or libraries that way as well.
Spring Web is going to pull in Spring MVC and some REST API information,
which we'll need in our application.
At this point, we're now able to generate the project.
So down at the bottom, we could go ahead and click on the Generate button.
That will download your project as a ZIP file to your computer, and that's it!
We have a new Spring Boot project.
If you want to know how to import it into your IntelliJ IDE so you can start coding with it, that's what's coming up next.