As I mentioned previously,
I'll be using IntelliJ for my main IDE for this course.
If you're familiar with something else, like Eclipse or a Spring Tool suite,
feel free to use that, but all the demos I'll be doing will be with IntelliJ.
In the previous clip, we generated a new Spring Boot application,
and that downloaded a ZIP file to our hard drive.
So you need to locate where that ZIP file was and go ahead and extract it.
Next, go ahead and open up IntelliJ,
and the IDE will present you with a few options to get a project up and running.
Since we already have our project,
I'm simply going to click the Import Project button
and find the file we just extracted.
Go ahead and select the extracted folder and Click OK.
Next, IntelliJ asks what type of project that I'm working with.
I chose Maven on the project creation on the Spring initializer site,
so I'm simply going to select Maven and click Next.
This screen allows for some customization,
but I'm going to go ahead and just leave the default
recommended settings and click Next again.
At this point, IntelliJ has found my project.
I can leave the default selected conference-demo checked and click Next.
In this dialog,
you can choose or set up your JDK that you want to use for the project.
Assuming you have a JDK installed, it should find one,
and I'm going to go ahead and use the JDK 12 and click Next.
Finally, if you want to adjust the project name,
you can, but I'm going to go ahead and leave the recommended default here,
and finally, click Finish.
After a few seconds, IntelliJ should successfully import your conference app,
and you should be ready to start working with it.
Next up,
I'm going to take a moment and go over the layout of the
Spring Boot application and the different pieces that were
set up from the initializer, as well as set up a few of my own best practice pieces in the application.