I'm going to show you how easy it can be to deploy a Spring Boot app on Heroku.
I know there is a lot of cloud options out there,
and I chose Heroku for simplicity sake.
You could easily spend some time and do the same deployment on AWS,
or Digital Ocean, or whatever cloud that you're familiar with.
Even if you haven't used Heroku before,
many of the steps will be the same elsewhere.
The takeaway should be focused on how easy the built
Spring Boot JAR files are to work with.
This is the main Heroku dashboard after you've created an account.
I'm going to go ahead and create a new app by clicking on the New button in the
upper-right-hand corner and then clicking Create new app.
I'm going to go ahead and give the app a name on Heroku,
and we'll call it conference-demo-dan.
I'll go ahead and use the United States region and
simply click the Create app button.
At this point,
Heroku is asking to connect to a Git repo so that it can find the app to deploy.
I've checked my app into a Git repository,
so I'm simply going to click on GitHub,
and I can search for my repository by clicking on the Search
button and then finding the appropriate repository.
I can then click Connect, which will tie it to my cloud Heroku.
Heroku has a couple of ways of deploying apps.
You can auto deploy on a commit or a check-in.
I'm going to go ahead and use the manual way,
and select the master branch, and click Deploy Branch button.
Heroku then auto detects that it's working with a Java application.
And once it's done building, it will say that your app was successfully deployed.
You can click the View here,
or you can go up into the upper-right-hand corner and click on Open app.
Go ahead and try that.
And if all went well,
you should get the status page that we built that shows the app version number.
But check out what happens if we go to our api/v1/sessions endpoint.
We get an error rather than a payload,
and it says that it's unable to acquire the JDBC connection.
If you think about it,
this is expected because we haven't set up the Postgres database on
Heroku so the app has no database to talk to or work with.
If I go back to the Heroku dashboard, I can click on the Resources tab.
This is where you can add additional services,
and you'll notice that Heroku was smart enough that it
already attached a Postgres database.
Heroku sets up the database settings in the Settings section of the application.
You can look at them here with the Reveal Config Vars.
Set up the database URL to an environment variable
called DATABASE_URL with the data.
If you remember in our application though,
we have the DATABASE_URL set to DB_URL as the environment variable.
Before we can set up this URL in Heroku,
you'll actually have to remember back when we created a
custom configuration class on the Java side.
If we go into the config folder and open up the PersistenceConfiguration,
you'll remember that we built out a DataSource bean,
and in here, we actually hard coded the URL.
So hard coding things into your app is not the greatest thing.
And in this case,
it's going to break our deployment on Heroku because localhost with
the 5432 port for Postgres is not going to exist.
So I'm actually going to go ahead and just comment out this bean and save it,
and I'm going to check this back into the Git
repository and have Heroku re-pull it.
Before I have Heroku re-pull that,
you'll notice that we need to modify this to match what we
have in our application properties URL,
so I'm going to simply add a variable here called DB_URL,
and I'm going to copy the database URL into it.
Now that the DB_URL is set and the Git repo has been updated to comment
out our persistence bean in the Java configuration,
I can come back to Deploy and simply deploy the master branch again.
Once that's redeployed, I can jump back over to Chrome and test it out.
This time, when we hit the sessions URL endpoint,
we get another 500 error, but it's about the result set.
I can check to see what the error is in my log files on
Heroku by coming up to the View logs.
Here, our app is telling us that the table sessions does not exist,
and again,
this makes sense because we have not loaded the data
into our production database on Heroku.
So I'm going to go ahead and pause the video and load that,
and I'll be right back, and we can test it out again with some live data.
Okay, I've loaded up the production database using the scripts,
like we did when we created our own local database with
the create tables and the create data.
Let's go ahead and try to access our sessions endpoint again on Heroku,
and you'll notice that we now have all of our payloads.
Okay, so here's to summarize what's happened.
Heroku auto detected our Java Spring Boot app,
it ran the Maven package, it installed the Postgres database for us,
and it deployed it all to a URL that was accessible.
All that we had to do was to load the database and make sure
that the app could connect to it properly.
If you've ever fussed with getting a Tomcat container
set up and then accessible publicly, deployed your app,
and get your database set up,
you can appreciate how easy some of this cloud stuff is making app development.
Now that I just put down the old way of deploying apps, let's take a look at what needs to happen to build a good old WAR file.