If you've ever used a command-line tool like Heroku's CLI or
used Ruby on Rails with its command-line tools,
the Spring Boot CLI is very similar.
If you aren't a power user and don't use the command line much, don't worry.
You don't have to give the CLI a try.
You will, however,
be surprised what you can do without ever leaving your shell or terminal.
There are a couple ways of installing Spring Boot CLI,
and you can check out the installation options here at
the Spring Boot documentation URL.
You can do a manual installation, or an SDKMAN,
or a Homebrew if you're on the macOS to get stuff installed.
At this time, I prefer the SDKMAN way, and you can install SDKMAN at sdkman.io,
and this tool is like RVM for Ruby or NVM for Node.
And once you have the SDK installed,
you simply need to open a new terminal or shell.
Once you have SDKMAN installed,
you can easily install Spring Boot by typing sdk install springboot.
SDKMAN will install the latest version of Spring Boot.
And once that is completed,
you can then type spring at the command line to start using Spring
Boot in a more interactive mode type of way.
If you type spring without providing any particular subcommand,
it'll just show some help.
You can also type spring help to give you additional
options to run with this tool.
One of the commands that you might be interested in is spring init,
and this is yet another way that you can create a Spring Boot project.
You can also run groovy-based Spring Boot application
from the command line using spring run.
Since this course is focused on Java and Spring Boot,
I'm not going to go too in depth with the groovy,
but there are some pretty cool things that you can do in this space.
If you like the terminal and you're comfortable with it,
you'll probably like the Spring Boot command-line install tools, and you should go back to the documentation to find out more information.