The future designer's work comes in a teacher's ABCD.
So today I'm going to take it to Lucy.
Okay.
Just some simple animations they can add to your projects.
So we're doing something on Lucy.
So this is Lucy.
And then Lucy when you visit the link.
Lucy for you to see what you can do.
So lots of animation that you can add into your figma projects.
So that's it.
Just go to this.
What I'm just trying to show you today is going to be a brief one.
Okay, so I'm just going to add my frame to frame.
Okay then.
First of all, you need to right click and go to plugins.
Okay.
So I already have the plugin installed.
So if you don't have it, you just have to go to browse plug ins and community and then you would have
to come to plug ins.
Okay.
And then the search for Lucy.
So when?
Except for Lucy come to plug in, see again.
Then you'd install Lucy.
I already have it installed.
When?
After installing.
Okay.
You got your project.
Are you right?
Click.
You should have it's listed.
So I'm going to select Lucy.
And then I can just.
You'd have to log in.
You have to create an account before you're able to use it.
So click here then, or search for space.
It is a space image of wounds.
Then I'm going to click on Convert to give the converted or click to Sigma.
So once they are that, you just use a skill to to scale it so that it's resizes so to the desired screen
the size of the screen once.
And then when you click on the play button, you should have this.
That should be it for beautiful speech.
Thank you.