Hello, feature designers.
Welcome to today's lesson on the UI UX training.
Doing this interface.
Okay, so this interface.
So today will be starting with this and then with time would move to this frame or this screen.
So that's it.
Firstly, what I would want to do is to get the icons down and then some.
Takes.
Okay, let's do that of the icon's face and then we can just start the project.
So if you log into Sigma, you would have to you see this interface and then you have to click on new
design, okay?
New design file.
So you click on this and then it's going to open the working environment or the working space for you.
So that said, let's go and then select the frame.
So I'm going to select this and then click on frame.
So I'm going to choose the iPhone Pro Max.
So let's frame and then let's see.
So let's use this.
Let me check here.
This should be what's so contact information.
So I'm going to rename here to contacts them just to contacts info, contact info.
And then what I would do next is to get the icons down.
So we need a Chevron and then this MO dialysis.
So I would do it.
So just right click and then go to plug ins.
Okay.
So from our previous lessons, we learned how to install plug ins.
So if you've not installed plug ins, you would have to go to manage not manage plug ins or browse plug
ins.
Okay.
So you browse plug ins where you would have to you learn to install the plug ins.
But we already have done that.
So we have I have for me, I have the design icon and I qualify.
It was taught in the previous lessons.
The Lucifer wouldn't be using that.
But it's an interesting project or.
Plug in that you might want to use.
So that said.
Or use material icons or let's start with icon ify.
So with the icon ify on our contact page, you can see we have the WhatsApp icon and then the telegram
icon.
So I'm going to search.
Okay.
So WhatsApp or so WhatsApp so we can just type here WhatsApp and I'm going to click this.
So.
Let me see.
Just click on Imports Icon.
So I should be the I contribute my screen.
So this icon and then I'll do same for that telegram.
So I qualify the search for telegram.
Press enter now click on this then imports icon so it's imported.
Okay.
So I'm going to put this.
Sorry, this.
So highlights all in the move them.
Okay.
Let's see.
And then I need the ellipses.
So we need the Chevron and then this ellipses.
Okay, so we use dots of the you can get dots in material icons and then iconic, but let's use dots
of material icon.
So that's way it's allowed.
Okay.
So it's taken a while to lose to all it lose.
Let's just try some.
If you look here, you can see the icons we selected.
You can see this seems to be separated.
So to make them one objects, you can just highlight all.
And then just use control g to group.
Or you can right click and then use look for group as group.
Okay, so why group them?
Okay, so I'm in group.
So.
The group.
So now they become one object and then I can resize them evenly.
Okay.
So they're going to do same for lots of what's up.
So you can see what is happening here.
So highlight and then group them.
So group selection and then I can move them as one objects or components.
Okay.
So our design icon is installed loading.
Let's try that for the.
There's no loading.
I qualify in search for something.
Okay, so it's back.
So I'm going to type here.
Chevron.
Think so.
We want this.
So just let me change the size face.
So engage in this size to this size them later.
And then you can also change the color.
Let's give it this color value and I will just drag it here.
Okay.
And then once that's for the more so more which is going to give us a three ellipses.
So we want this one to.
Okay.
So I'm going to drop it here.
And then we won that.
So.
Let's see the message phone and then the this one.
Email and then also the floating action button and then the search.
Okay, so I'm going to do that quick.
So search.
So we have such.
And then I'll take that off the email.
So email.
Then let's look for.
Phone.
So such a phone.
So phone.
Let me take this.
Okay.
Let me just move the C then I'm going to search for message.
Message.
Okay, so we have the message.
And then let's search for the odd button.
So out.
He's going to give us our floating action button.
So just here.
Okay.
So I can close you now.
And our interface looks.
So.
Can.
Would just leave them.
That's.
Let's leave them that way or better, so we can just highlight or resize them.
So I'm just going to hold on shift and then resize them.
Space airplane in transit.
Just recites them individually.
If something changes.
So let's do it this way.
So now if you look here, you would see we have the Chevron and then we have the text.
That's how the more icon.
So this actually is just the background colour of the frame.
So what we do is and then let's do this.
So this is just a line.
So as you see, it's a line.
So I'm going to have to pick a line.
So just let line and then let's draw from somewhere, this place.
Okay.
So to get the perfect or to make sure your line is straight, he's on shift.
So you can see when I leave shift, it's not straightened.
So when I hit, shift it straight in.
Okay.
And then I'm going to give it a height of one.
What's this opening?
Yeah.
Okay.
So it's already sets one.
And then so here it's really sets one and then I'll give it a color.
So it says true cookie the color value of this.
So we already have this call, so I'll just pick this one.
Okay.
Let's see.
It's a.