Hi there.
My name is Jacqueline Sadat and I am a UI UX designer.
Today we will learn how to design concepts, icons and figma.
These are the icons we will be designing.
We have the mobile phone icon, the email icon, the location icon, the color icon and the telephone
icon.
Google's material design has an icon template that guides with the icon design.
Using it ensures consistency, uniformity and scalability of the icons you design.
The dimension of the template is 24 by 24 pixels.
This part is the life area and this part is the padding.
So the light area is where your icons should be designed and the pattern is the space around the icon.
Now, icon may extend into the pattern if additional space is needed, but make sure the icon you are
designing does not extend outside of the grid or outside the borders of the templates.
These are the key line shapes that guides you to design the basic shapes such as circle, square and
rectangle.
So this guides you to draw a square and this guide you to draw a circle.
This guide you to draw a vertical rectangle.
And this a horizontal rectangle.
To learn more about icon design using material design guidelines, you can visit the link on the screen.
Okay, so onto a face icon, the mobile phone icon.
We will start by selecting the rectangle tool from the toolbar and then join a rectangular shape of
12 by 20 pixels on the frame of the guidelines.
Then round the corners by two pixels.
Okay.
So we'll then change the color to black using the color to add the field section on the design tab.
Once we are done with that, we select the rectangle again and draw a bar at the top and then round
the corner to one pixel full.
Then select a circle from the shapes two and draw a circle at the bottom of the main rectangular shape
with the size of two by two pixels.
Great.
Now we select the circle for the bar and the main rectangular shape, and then we go to the Boolean
menu up there to select Subtract, which subtracts the circle shape and the bar shape from our main
rectangular shape.
And voila, we have our phone icon.
Okay, the next icon is the new icon.
Once again, we select the Rectangle two from the Shape menu and then draw the horizontal rectangle
size 20 pixel by 16 pixel using the guideline provided there around the corners by two pixels.
We then changed the colour to black.
We want to be able to see that guideline with the still active so that the stroke instead.
Yeah.
We said that said.
And then select the PIN two and draw a V line from this end of the shape to the center, then to the
other end of the sheet.
Selected and set the size to one pixel, then change the color to white so that it will be visible when
we fill the rectangular sheet with black.
Now fill the rectangular shape with black and remove the stroke around it.
Once you're done with that, adjust the line with a little.
Then select both the line and the shape.
Go to the Boolean menu once again and select Subtract.
This will subtract the line from the rectangle.
Then we flatten it to convert it to a vector.
And there we have it, our very own image icon or male icon.
Moving on, our next icon to design is the location icon or the pin icon.
With this, we will select the triangle from the shapes to then draw it from the top to the bottom.
Flatten it so it's easy to work with.
Now stretch it a bit to the end of the life region.
Remember early on I told you the life region is where the design goes.
So once you're done with that, right click the shape and select flip vertical from the menu that appears.
You can either double click on the shape or press enter your keyboard to enter the vector mode of the
shape.
Before we continue, go back to the normal mode and duplicate the shape by pressing control command
on your keyboard.
Now change the color of the copy to help you differentiate it from the original.
Press and hold both the shift and optional also on your keyboard to reduce the size of the copy.
So option or the old key anchors are shaped in the middle, so the shape stays in the middle regardless
of the changes it undergoes.
Now select the original sheet.
Press enter on your keyboard, enter the vector mode.
Once again, select the two points at the top of the shape and then round those corners by changing
the values here.
These select the top corners and select the bottom corner and then round it a bit.
Now, when you're done with that, select the copy and press enter on your keyboard.
Enter the vector mode.
Then select all the three corners or points, change the corner radius of all the planes by changing
the value here to form a circle.
The legs, both the seco and the pin shape, then select subtract from the volume and to complete the
icon.
Once you're done with that, flatten it and then change the color to black.
Then we are done with the location icon or the pin i.