Everyone will come to this UI UX crash course with anybody can develop in me or Twitter for today.
Jacqueline I solidarity.
So a bit about me.
I am sorry that, as I mentioned earlier, I'm a lead user interface designer, Garner Tech Lab and
user experience designer tech so limited I completed my bachelor's in computer engineering.
I love to learn and also teach what I learned.
So on behind you can find me using the names below here.
So today what we'll be doing is introducing you to UI, UX and then.
Who explained the difference between UI and UX design, and then there will be some examples.
You've introduced the design fundamental and then you introduce prototyping by framing basics.
And finally, high fidelity mockup basics protocols.
And with that, we are going to design that.
So UI UX, what is UI?
User UI is basically user interface and what is user interface is the medium used by the individual
or the user to interact with the product or service.
So user interface is basically what the user interacts with to get a specific job done or a type of
job done right.
So.
What is UX?
UX, which is simply user experience, is how the user feels when interacting with a product.
How does it feel?
Interacting with the experiences for products can either be good or be bad for your users to have a
good experience.
The design should be equitable, usable and durable and useful.
Now, when we say equitable, what do we mean?
We mean that the design should be able to be used by a wide range of people.
A variety of people should be able to use it.
It shouldn't be only limited to a specific type of people.
Disabled people should be able to use abled people should be able to use people from different diverse
backgrounds, should be able to use that as well.
What do we mean by usable?
Usable?
Should it be too complicated for the users to understand?
They should be able to see and immediately know how to use or be able to see and be able to learn how
to use it.
If it's too complicated and not usable, it delivers bad experiences to your users.
Now enjoyable.
What keeps your users coming back is when your experience is enjoyable.
If they don't enjoy the experience from the first time or the first try, they are not going to come
back again.
So you have to make sure that your experiences are in job.
An example is social media.
Social media we know Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and so on.
People keep visiting or keep going back to these apps because they are enjoyable to them.
They enjoy the experience, they enjoy everything them and finally useful.
Now when we say user, we want the same sorry, we mean the experience should do what it says it will
do.
It should be able to perform its intended activity.
So if I say I'm designing a messaging app and the app I present to my users is not able to send messages,
then my design is not useful.
It becomes useless to my users.
Okay, so let's add the differences between UI design and UX design.
UI design involves using colours, shapes, and other design principles.
Creates a visual product of visually pleasing products, and you as design basically informs involved.
So the creation of a product that provides meaningful and relevant experiences to its user.
So UI basically involves the interface how it looks.
The colors, the typography and all that and us encompasses everything day.
It goes from the beginning to the end, the experience that is being created for the user.
That is what UX design is now.
That's some examples of.
You would say UI design.
What we see here is an example of a user interface.
Right.
We see the colors, we see the typography.
We see the size of the text and the buttons and a whole lot more.
You X here in this case involves the way the contents have been placed.
So the structuring of everything here.
There's a reason why login was not a button and get started was made.
A button is a user experience that was considered and there's a reason why the logo is up there and
not down there.
That is the user experience being considered here.
She gets it.
Thank you very much.