Hello, everyone.
Today I'll be taking you through.
Basic Introduction to user experience.
User Interface Design.
Okay.
Before we come to what we are seeing here, I'll give you a basic introduction on what that interfaces.
So sorry, your user interface is your like your app.
It's easy for you and all these things.
Do you understand what a design.
Exactly says now.
Hello, guys.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think.
And then user experience is how I think I send something to the group.
Yes, you are.
User interface is user experience.
So user experience is how you feel when you are interacting with a product.
You feel good.
When you are interacting with the product is an experience.
You feel bad when interacting with a product, you feel confused.
We are interacting with the product.
You feel angry, annoyed.
You get that this user experience.
How you feeling at interacting with.
Yes, with a product.
So just Google Sigma or type sigma dotcom, it takes you to the website.
You don't necessarily have to install it.
It's also a web based software, so you can use it in your browser.
Okay.
You just have to sign up.
As you can see here.
At a top here.
There's a bar.
I think it's similar for windows to.
The top.
Here is a bar that has already created some projects.
So.
You can see the various types, the types of the various projects.
Can you see that?
Yeah, I see that.
So it is craigslist redesign UX UI presentation.
Simple again.
Can you see that is up here?
Those are my project that I've created.
And beside the final project tab there is a plus icon.
Can you see it?
For those for those who just signed up for Figma, I'm sure you you just see that you see just the plus
icon on the the the tab update since you don't have any projects created.
So you can just click on the plus icon.
When you click the plus icon, you see.
Does see it.
You have the design file and then the fig jam file.
Now fig jam file is in.
Is a file that allows you to create.
Like your plan.
You plan with your team on your workflow or your project flow, but they are going to do on your project
to.
Is that how to help you plan?
Yes.
And a design file is a file to is where you design your projects.
So for this session, we are going to use the design file.
So we just click on that design file and then it takes us to our design workspace.
Can you see it?
Yes.
Okay.
All right.
So are we all here?
Have you been able to get to this interface?
And your various accounts.
It would just take you to.
Okay.
So I think you do the interface, right.
So yes, this is Figma workspace where you create your designs.
In adults mostly desire.
So up here we have the menu bar.
It has the jazzy toolbar.
I'll call it a toolbar slash menu.
Yes.
So it has the various tools that you need for your design work.
We have the move to here.
Move to move to wait, click on the rectangular thing and a dropdown appears and then you see move inside
and then skill inside and beside the move to is a mesh icon.
The mesh icon is a frame too.
So when you are like you see frame the frame labels showing it also has a triangular thing at the side,
showing that you can drop down to a click on the one you see frame inside.
And then there's a slice, a slice to inside.
Okay.
So moving on, the next one is the shape to the shape tools.
Who has the dropdown icon beside it?
To show the world that you can find inside.
So can click on it.
You have the rectangle to the rectangle ship.
Sorry, the line, the arrow ellipse, polygon star and then image.
Right?
So the next one is the pen to join to.
Right click on the.
The rectangular thing beside it.
It drops down to show the pen to and then the pencil to the next.
Text to then be cited to the hunt to and then we have the comments to.
So moving on and then you have the on the same bar, you have the.
Name of the file here.
You can rename your file.
Currently we've not named it so is untitled, so we can choose to give it a title by double clicking
it.
And then when I double click, well, we'll be designing a simple log in.
So our name is logging in class.
This come from.
Okay, so now I renamed my file and what you see beside it, there's this small icon here.
It shows you the current account.
Your file is in, your design file is in.
So when I click on it, I'm thinking back to my draft site.
I don't need to go here.
I know.
And then the draft shows like the folder or the group that your project is currently in, you can choose
to create a team project.
Did you get it or just leave it in draft?
Currently I don't.
We don't need to create a team project, so I'm going to leave it in draft.
Okay.
And on I think you go here you have your you can view your profile.
You have this icon.
This time it's colored.
With the anime showing that since I'm called Jacqueline, my initials G.
If you are David, your initial D and so on, you have the share button on the bar as well.
You can use this button to share your file that you are working on with other designers or other collaborators.
It helps you collaborate through life with other people when working in Sigma.
So when I tap on the shared right, I get this dialog box that's like containing the options or what
I have to do to share.
So in this input, input the email of the person that you want or people that you want to share your
file or collaborate with on your work, whatever work they are doing in the figma.
Okay.
So that's that.
And then you have this play icon here, like the play icon enables you to preview what you are working
on.
So that's it.
And then the Zoom view option scaling.
So moving on, we have the Layers panel.
The Layers panel contains or shows the elements you've used in your design work so far.
And then you have the assets.
Your assets, the assets you used in your design.
So you a component, right?
And let me give you an example.
So if I'm in your design work, you are adding a customized color palette.
You can add it to the assets so that a user due out when you make a change to want one thing, it runs
two.
Or if they are going to use a particular button, right, say a logging button, they are going to use
it throughout.
You have a number of things you don't want to be changing.
If you make a change to one button, you don't want to go to make a change to all.
They say, I want ten different buttons.
You don't want to go to make a change to all those buttons, so you can just create the first button.
You will convert it to a component, and then you create an instance of the components.
That's it for the Layers and assets panel.
And then you have the page here.
You can create a number of pages here during your design file.
So moving on, moving on, moving on.
On my right hand side, you see the design panel, the prototype panel and the inspect panel.
The inspects allows you to see the code of the access code or whatever it is you designed.
So okay, so you have the case as the under the Android I iOS.
And then so the design panel shows the properties of your design elements.
So currently I have a rectangle here and on the design panel you can see the various options or properties
of the rectangle.
You see the rectangle position, the size.
The angle, the visibility, the color, and so on and so forth.
Very good.
The prototype.
The prototype allows you to transition from one frame to another frame.
It allows you to do your animations, like your design.
As I said earlier today, with designing a simple login.
Okay.
So moving on Behance and Drupal sites where as a designer, you can go to get inspiration.
It has a lot of.
You can get inspiration from other designer schools and you yourself can go to post your design work.
Let me share my web browser so that yeah, so this is dribble.
So if I design what type of designer that you are.
Motion designer, graphic designer.
User interface designer.
You can come here.
You an illustrator, you can come here to get ideas because it's this website curates a lot of work
from other designers and you yourself can post your design work.
So for what we will be designing today, we'll look for it here.
Right.
So I said I mentioned we be designing a simple again.
So I'm sketching log in here so that we choose one and work on.
We'll be doing mobile app design today.
So,
so yeah, we all decided to do this design.
Let me copy the image and paste it and figure.
Okay.
Are we ready to replicate this design login design screen?
So the next thing we'll do is we'll create a frame.
Right.
We see that this is designed as a mobile app design.
So our frame, too should be a mobile frame.
It shouldn't be a web frame you get.
So we go to the mesh icon here, the top.
Put your present stream, tap on it, and then on the right hand side, you'll notice that the frame
options appears there.
Okay, so for that class, we'll be using iPhone 11 pro.
As a friend.
So yes, I tap on this and then is created here.
Moving on, I double tap in my layers panel.
With the first stream of dead selected I double tap the name here you can see that it's showing here
iPhone 11 pro max.
Hyphen one showing here.
I double tap on the name and then I rename name it into that screen.
Who's that string?
Okay.
I see that.
All right.
So now on this touch screen, we can see that some shapes.
In Texas, right?
So there's this there's this two large rectangle shapes here.
And then you have at the top is you have the pure shapes, pink filled shape.
And they have all these different, different, different, different shapes.
So first, what we are going to do is we are going to click.
This ship.
The shape of the mind.
The mind image are going to pictures on our screen.
Are we following?
You guys?
Yes.
Following your.
Okay.
So to create this, what I'll do is I'll go to the sheet to it's currently on rectangles I just click
it's.
And then I come here to my.
Dream.
And then I draw a shape, rectangular shape by dragging personhood, put in the mouse or trackpad,
and then dragging it to form.
She sighs.
You won't see my kids.
I guess I'll just leave it here.
Okay.
So I have my rectangle, the length of this thing, but I'm going to assume so.
I'll keep the height, adjust the height a bit and keep it up to 20 pixels.
And in the width I keep it at 115.
Okay.
So in the property here on the right hand side, you see there's x, the x position value, the Y position
value, the width of the the shape, the height of the shape, the angle, the angle of the shape that
is tilted, the Charleston angle, the ship.
And then we have the corner radius of the shape.
So what I'm going to do now is I'm going to change the radius of the rectangle I created to achieve
this shape that we see here.
I'm going to try to achieve it by changing the radius of my rectangle.
We are getting.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
With that changing of the.
Can I reduce of your ship?
You could either.
Use the camera and see the rounded things at the corner of the ship here.
Yeah.
So you could, you could choose to drag this click and hold and then just drag to create the desired
effect you want.
Or you could just go to the corner video's input box and then enter the value you want depending on
whichever method you want.
So in my case, I guess this is easier for me.
So I'll just drag the corner the corners of the rectangle to create my own reduce so you see what's
happening.
But don't worry if you can't see the circular things, you just go to the input box and then type in
a value.
Okay.
So you get that.
These are sheep.
The image sheep.
The.
The ship similar to what you are seeing here.
Okay.
So now the next step is to.
The next step is to convert the ship into an image or put an image inside the ship.
The number of ways you can.
Bring an image into Figma, right.
You can decide to drag and drop the image and then max the shape that's currently here to the image
or you can directly convert the the shape we created into an image.
In our case, you are going to convert it into an image.
So I'm going to find a random image on Unsplash so we can all go to Unsplash.com and then find an image
and message.
Okay.
So I've chosen this.
I'm going to download it.
So now you don't have to image.
What you are going to do is we are going to convert the shape we created into an image.
You have to pay attention here.
So with a rectangle selected.
That fills the section of the design panel.
I click on the color here beside.
The code you see here.
But my ship selected.
Right?
The properties of the ship appears on the design panel, which is on your right, your far right.
And under the design panel, you have a cross section.
So it's your section, right?
And then another section you have.
This thing where you see a rectangle with a color and then you have the color code and then the intensity
of the color which is in percentage, right?
So what I did or I'm going to do is click on this rectangle beside the code.
When I click on it, something appears.
So with this thing and up here, there's solid.
When you go right, you see that there's a dropdown icon.
So I click on that and then there are options available in that menu appears, right?
In this case, I want to convert the image so the shape into an image.
So.
I select the image option.
Okay.
So.
I click on the Choose Image button here.
Then I go to the folder I downloaded my picture into.
So it isn't my picture I downloaded.
All right.
So now I'm showing you on notice that there's another rounded rectangle shape behind the first image.
Yeah.
So I'm not going to create the image from scratch.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to duplicate what I already created.
So in this case, I'm selecting the shape that I have.
And then for me, it's command D for windows.
You press and you press control.
Now you see that is duplicated.
Okay.
After you've done that, the thing won't duplicate, but instead I duplicate that less until you move
one of the duplicated things off.
Okay, so moving on, moving on, moving on.
Now, if you will notice, you see that the duplicate layer is on top of the original one, right?
Like it's in front of it.
So when I move it around, when it gets to the original one, it covers or overlaps the original one.
Right.
Now, what I want to do is I want to send it to the back and to send it behind the original layer.
So but that duplicate it enough to duplicate it with the copy selected.
I'm going to right click and then go to move to back.
So I move it to the back.
If you notice now the copy is behind the original.
I don't see it.
To achieve this effect they have here.
I think this thing is slightly.
Yeah.
Yeah, I did.
And we put a slight value on the picture so that that can sort of positioned my.
My copy in a way that's going to that's similar to, if anything, what you're trying to replicate here.
So before that, let me copy pick the color.
From what you're doing.
So.
Okay, so let me teach her to pick a color to see you want to pick a color from something, right?
Like what we did.
Like the process we went to was trying to convince them that shaped an image.
You click on the film.
The rectangular, the colored rectangular box.
When you open here, you have the solid at the top, the huge color box here, then the things down
here.
You see, there's a drop icon here.
Can you see that?
Three tap on the drop icon and then you send it to the color that you want to pick.
So I'm trying to pick the red color in the guys t shirt.
When I tap on it, you notice that I've picked a color.
I created a shape here to fill it with that guy's color.
Thank you very much.