Okay.
So welcome to the continuation of the US project that we started previously.
So here I'm going to have to take this up.
Okay.
To this.
So that is quite okay.
And then you might want to preview what you've done so far.
But this remember this the line to the line shape or component.
So I'm going to increase this to two.
So one interest in our interest thing about visit, you can actually type two here.
Let's see, I'm going to do eight divided by so eight divided by four.
So two.
Okay.
So maybe you can also do some simple calculations here.
So now I'm going to pick the rectangle two and then at this point just right below the line.
So I'm going to draw.
Okay.
And then leave this here.
Let me take it down.
Okay.
So we just control plus plus two, zoom in.
So they're able to snap this a bit.
So let me snap it to it's okay.
And then I'm going to have to change this color.
So let me go here and then this color.
So this color, this is the color value or the color code has to do and then I'm going to paste it in
the fill pops.
So control v press enter.
Okay, so it has picked us for us.
Okay.
Don't it up?
Then let me control Manus.
Let's see what we have here.
Okay.
There's some percentage here, so let me see here.
Finbarr, when you go here, you can see we have a percentage like 20%.
So I have to go and change to 20%.
So just you can see 100.
So we change it to 20.
So now we have the actual color that we want.
Okay.
So what we can do now is to check this.
So we need to do the mobile, the phone number and then these icons.
So first of all, we would have to do this, the background components, okay?
So to do that, we would have to use the Ellipse tool.
So the Ellipse too, and then I'm just going to draw here.
So our denote shifts as usual cycle and then I'm going to change this color to white.
Okay.
And then now you can see if you zoom in carefully, you see that it has some drop shadows.
So control plus you can see how.
So I'm going to do that.
So I'll go to my effects and then the dropdown is already selected.
So I'll click on the effects settings and then I'm going to change my spread or let me change my Y to
zero and then I'll change the spread to, let's say two.
Then my play, I can put my play at play.
Use eight or five.
Okay.
So now I can see we have some shadows here.
See, we have the shadow.
Okay.
Which makes its appear as if is projecting out of the screen.
As you can see here, we do have this shadow.
So now we would have to pick the icon.
So let's use that.
So the message face.
So I'm going to pick this with.
And I'm going to resize it.
So while holding on auto shifts, I'll just resize it inwards to move it inwards so that it to my tattooed
and let me paste it out.
How to write click because it was picked earlier.
So I have to right click arrange and then bring to France.
So let me look for a range and then how to bring it to France.
So bring two fronts.
So it's not in France, I don't think it's well aligned.
So I can just highlight all and then try to align it's okay.
So align it vertically and then align it here to.
Okay.
So now it's aligned.
I can.
So I can just copy this control c, control v and then move it.
And then I'm going to do that for the phone.
Okay.
For the phone.
Also how to right click and then bring two fronts.
Okay.
So let me resize it first.
When we take it to buy to tell you to buy, set two right click arrange and then bring two fronts.
So bring two fronts.
Okay.
See, this is also tested by.
And it changes info.
Okay.
Let me do it.
32 by 32.
And I can highlight all and then arrange let me highlight so and then align physical here to try and
delete this from.
So we'll just take this and it'sit's.
Okay, so control minus.
So remember to group dance to highlight this and then group control g to group so it becomes one objects.
I'm going to highlight this two and then control G to group this and then now let's see the other.
So you have to do that for the IMU.
Okay, so since we've already we already control C and copy this, I can still use control V to paste
it.
So it's already stored in memory.
So I just use control v to paste it and then I'm going for the meal.
So the email I can just do the text two by 32 here and then change it to 32.
Okay then I'm just going to move it then right click arrange and then bring two fronts.
Okay.
It looks stretched, not stretched.
So let me just do it this way.
So I think I like it this way.
I like it this way.
So it's well centered.
Okay, so I'm just going to group control G.
So now we have the icons for the IMU default and then the message.
Okay.
So let's see what we can do now.
Then I.
Okay.