Next thing we are going to build is the interactive component.
Our main theme for the video, we're going to build an interactive component for the backend.
So the first thing we're going to do is select a frame, greater frame on which we get our interactive
components and then create a grid.
The grid is not necessary.
It's just to guide me.
It's just to create that margin for me so that I don't design out of that.
Another method you can use to align your design as to draw the guidelines from the ruler if you don't
have it turned on, can turn it on by using the shift, our shortcuts or your keyboard, and then you
just drag the guideline from the ruler, press our on your keyboard to select the Rectangle two and
then draw it on your artboard or frame and make changes to the properties.
We said the color to Lena in this case.
He changed the face colour to the darker shade of blue and the second colour to the lighter shade of
blue.
He then said the colonel reduced to five and then pressed C on the keyboard to select the text to and
we type work with us on a rectangular shape.
Make sure I text a center aligned.
And we change the properties of the text
after searching the properties of the text.
The next thing we do is select both the text and the rectangle and group it to group our selection.
We press command open to D on the keyboard.
Once again, we have to make sure as well aligned is aligned in the center of the rectangle.
After making those adjustments, rename our group to Action Button.
When we are done, we convert a button to a component by clicking on the component icon at the top of
the window.
Once you've created a component, you notice that component symbol is now changed to add variance and
add that.
Add another variance.
We click on that button and then it creates another variance for us, which we can edit to show another
state of our components.
For this variant, we are going to create a shadow, so we just duplicate the rectangle and then we
set the properties.
We drag it down a bit, change the size.
And add a layer blur to it.
We make some adjustments afterwards and adding the layer by layer, we then rename the shadow layer
we just created.
The next thing we're going to do after we're done creating a Hoover variant is we're going to connect
them together so that it becomes interactive.
So we select the prototype top and then drag the point from the default to the Hoover and select mount
into.
And sets the animation type to smart animate.
You then connect the whole event to the default and then you select monthly for that.
Our previous website is already set, so you don't really make much changes there.
Okay, now we're done with our interactive component.
The next thing we are going to do is to utilize it.
So we'll create a copy of our main component, drag it onto our main screen and make sure it's well
aligned to our logo.
I'm not done with that.
We preview it to see what we've done so far.
As you can see, our interactive component is working.
The next thing we're going to do is create the menu item, interactive component.
So with that, you press t on your keyboard and type whatever it is you want to type.
And then you change the properties.
You set the properties.
And you are done with that to get a rectangle, to enjoy a rectangle over our menu item.
And then we bring the menu item text to the front and make sure it's center aligned to a rectangle.
We are just a rectangle a bit.
Just use our preference.
We then draw another smaller rectangle at the edge, bottom edge of the rectangle you first created
and adjust it a bit.
It has to be small.
Then we rename it to Bar and then we change the color.
To the deeper shade of blue.
We then change the color of the larger rectangle to the lighter shade of blue and reduce the intensity
to 5%.
When we are done with setting the rectangle properties, we select them at the same time and then group
them.
We draw another rectangle over who we are going to use this new shape as a mask.
We rename its mask.
Once we are done with that, we bring our menu item text to the front.
And then the mucks are behind the group, select Buddha Group and the monks.
Leah and create a mask.
Once we're done with that, we select both the monks group and the menu item text and group them.
Then we rename our new group to menu item.
We then create a component of our new menu item group.
We expand the contents of the component by pressing the rectangular icon, and then we go into Mark's
group and select Max from that, and we adjust our max to hide our shape.
Once we finish with that, we create a variance of our new components.
We rename it to Hoover, and then in this new variant we find our max layer and adjusted to make our
shape visible.
The next thing we do after that is to connect our components to make it interactive.
So we select prototype, and then we make our component interactive by connecting the dots to each other
and setting the properties.
We are done making our components interactive.
The next thing we are going to do is use it.
So we create a copy of our components and then send it to our main stream and we edit.
When we finish, we'll preview it to see what we've done so far.
As you can see, the components we created are working very well.