Okay.
So moving on, our next icon is a color icon.
Select a circle or sorry, the ellipse tool from the shapes to enjoy it in your frame.
Remove the fill and set the stroke to 0.5 pixels.
Now duplicate the circle using command or control dx on your keyboard.
Then reduce the size of the copy.
Once you're done reducing the size, duplicate the copy using command or control.
Again, select one of the small circles and the main circle.
Then click the top align button to position the small circle at the top of the bigger circle.
Select the other small circle and the bigger circles and click on the right align button at the top
here to position the small circle at the right side of the big circle.
So when all is said and done, select all three circles and rotate it by 45 degrees to the left side
or to the left.
Now select the triangle from the shapes to and draw a triangle in the center.
Move the mouse here and increase the value of the number of sides of the triangle to five.
So now it becomes a Pentagon.
Okay.
Now select the big circle and fill it.
Once you're done with that, change the color, then move the stroke around.
Click this point or dots and drag it in the clockwise direction.
So you get what I have here.
Select the circle and fill it.
Once again, remove the stroke around it.
Repeat the same action to the other small circle.
Once you're done with that, click on the shape created with a bigger circle and select the dot here,
then drag it backwards, flatten the Pentagon, then adjust it a bit.
Make sure that everything is going around.
Select the brown shape and the two small circles and click the union selection in the volume menu.
Select the polygon and the shape that was just created and select subtract from the Boolean menu once
again.
Flatten the shape to convert it into a vector, double click or press enter on your keyboard to enter
the vector mode of the shape.
Once you're done with that, select the dots in the center and carve the corners a bit.
Then select that.
Then select the dots at the edges.
The four dots.
Yeah.
And then curve that a bit to now change the color to let's say curve.
I meant round them.
So now change the color to black.
Once you're done, you created and then we're done with our color icon.
So we're almost at the end of our video.
I lost them.
Find out.
Icon as the telephone.
Okay, so first we'll duplicate the collar and bring it here.
Because, you know, we need that.
Grab a rectangle and draw a rectangle in the frame.
Enter the vector mode.
By either pressing and telling your keyboard or double clicking on the shape and then create the point
at the side like I'm doing now.
Select the points at the top corner and move it here.
Okay.
Good job.
Do the same thing for the other side.
Select these two points and round their corners.
The leg.
The point we created as a side and round the point as well.
I'll make some slight changes to the shape we have here before we move on.
I sat down with that.
The legs, a rectangle from the sheet and draw this box around the corners of the bar as well and then
duplicated.
Change the color.
Select the Ellipse to enjoy a circle in the center of the phone.
Now create a stroke around the circle and change the color of the stroke to whites.
I just the size of the circle a bit.
I remove the peel.
The leg, both the seco and the telephone shape, and click on the subtract and the boolean menu to
create a hole in the center of the shape.
Finally, select both the collar and the body to flatten it.
Once you have that down, we are good to go.
I hope you enjoyed this video and it was informative enough.
Thank you for watching and see you next time.