Hello, everyone.
Welcome to this UI UX crash course with anybody can develop is to continue from where we left off yesterday.
So.
We are going to do now is you are going to create.
The.
Input box down here.
So you get your to and then as usual, you're in good shape.
So for me, around the corner, it's a bit.
Maybe the key to that is not to obvious and change
the color.
You can't do the modification to your creativity as usual.
Feel free to explore.
Great finish.
You duplicate your shape to get another increase.
All right, so now we have two input boxes created.
Next, we are going to write the text you see here inside.
You see John Stevens, that's email dot, right?
Right.
Yes.
You see this that thing?
We are going to agree that we all know how to put a tax lien on.
Okay.
So you don't necessarily need to type what I'm typing.
Anything you want to.
This.
I wasn't being hard to get a password.
Text is.
Yes.
That's that's that's that's that.
That's the
bad stuff that's done away from is you can't modify it or do it big enough for you to see.
Right.
Okay.
So now as we can see, there's an eye and I always see eye to eye.
Yes.
So we are going to be going back again to pick a similar icon and put it in a password box.
Okay, good.
Okay.
Good to go.
Yes.
Okay.
I just Google the symbol.
See if I'll find something similar.
Yes, I did.
Using the old method, I'll drag the icon to the input box.
So.
Okay, so next I forget password downtime.
So I already have a text with a similar callout.
These kids are particular artists and change.
That's the date for going past with.
Let's listen.
Reduce it.
Really?
The next thing is to modify the budget so we can get something similar to what we have here.
Now, looking back, I start by reducing my text points.
Yes.
If you putting your buttons from the past, will you select the select
on the text for this one selected?
If you look your text in the I'm if you put your button in that material as I was saying earlier, for
you to be able to click or select a single item out of the group, you need to double click on whichever
item it is that you want to select.
So for right now, it's the text that you want to select.
You either press and hold command or control based on the platform you are using and click on whatever
you want to select in your group.
Or you can just double click or whatever I want to select.
And then it becomes individually selected, modified to use your preference.
So now I'm changing.
Log in.
Yes.
The next is to select and modify my rectangle.
Make it a bit longer.
Okay.
So.
So our final thing is to change the text below the button instead of already having an account.
We just have to change it already having accounts.
Again, we just have to change it to don't have an account register.
So do that.
Let's.
We want.
Okay.
Firms having accounts.
So if you've done this, congratulations.
You finish getting the login screen.
So.
All right.
So now what I'm going to do right, is to.
Connect us.
Now, what are going to do is we are going to connect frames for ads so that when we click on a button
or because that you got some way we get a response words or we are able to move from the first screen
to the second screen by the trigger.
The trigger could be a button or time.
Okay.
So, I mean, let's let's do the prototype.
Nice, nice.
You can let's continue.
Okay.
So now what I'm going to do is I'm going to go to type our design.
So we click on prototype
with the type on your left.
I'm sorry.
Right.
You're right here, extreme right where the design is.
So we have design, prototype, inspect.
So you just tap on prototype and then it moves you to the prototype section.
Okay.
So now what we want to prototype here is our button, our get started button.
So what I'm going to do is hopefully everyone your buttons, everyone Google buttons, move your button.
The typing becomes a little bit challenging.
So we tap on the I tap on button.
There are two ways you can prototype your this one.
The shot method moved out along with the launch method.
After I've selected my button, I click on Welcome to Prototype.
You see Interactions and Interactions is a plus icon.
When I click on the plus icon, I create an interaction.
I tap on the action to modify the options, suits, my needs or my preference or my goal.
That's I want to achieve that particular instance.
So with this, I want to achieve a tap trigger.
And when I tap on to, to navigate to another page, to isolate, navigate to from the options here,
and then I choose the page I want to navigate to which the login screen.
This is one method you can use to prototype your screens.
Now another method is I just when I select the elements, I want to add an additional design prototype
to you see around this one here at the end the selection thing.
So you just when you write your like this becomes a plus so you can just click and drag to your destination
page.
This time when I click on it, I want you to go to my log in so I just drag that thing to my login site
or page.
You realize that once you drag the interactions and preference options or the two options open up opens
up.
So yeah, you already done the basic thing, what you have to do.
You can choose to add this one.
An animation to its not.
This time, what am I going to do?
Let me do a sliding animation.
Let me start with a short animated.
So they shot one, right?
You select your targets that you want to.
The prototype in this case.
I want to I want my page to move to log in when I click on Get Start.
So I select the stated button.
You can see that when you select that, there's a round thing at the edge of the selection thing.
So you just drag.
Tough on the wrong thing in your destination where you want the page to transition to when you click
on to get started.
So I just go.
So in this case, you want to.
Prototype our vaccine.
So what you are going to do is select the button.
But next, you're going to bust and I want you to move to my login page.
And you love it?
Yes.
I want you to smile.
So what I will do is.
Okay.
So they selected you click on this one.
The second thing was you selected a button.
Drag it to your destination page right where you want the.
Where you want to move to when you click on the button.
In this case is my login page.
So I go to the login page and then you see the interaction details.
You can do some small modification here.
You want an animation, you can choose them.
So let's move and move out, push sliding side out.
That is all this much animates instance, instance, basically adding any sort of animation to it.
So it just moves in an instance without it necessarily animating.
So in my case, I select this sliding.
So that's, you see, it's when it's transitioning.
That's it for our animation here.
Okay, so now that we are done, I'll go back to the design tab.
Tap on the first frame we created, which is the start screen, and then hit the play icon.
Now it brings me to my previous site.
The Pew site is where you see your animation in action or your people taking action.
So I am here now because I connected my buttons to the next page.
When I click on Get Started, you realize that it moves to the next page or the next slide.
So.
I deleted my original work now.
So with the prototype in, you can't do that.
Two methods you can use to create your prototype.
The first one is you select your targets, the trigger objects.
In this case, trigger objects is a button.
Right.
So as you can see, my button is selected.
And then under the prototype layer you get, you see interactions beside interactions.
The plus icon.
When you click on the the plus icon, it adds an interaction.
But then you have to do the configuration yourself.
You tap on the other interaction and then you open the interaction details, dialog box or let you see
your trigger options the kind you want.
I think to me, too.
And we talk to we maintain our own top.
And then.
The next one is what you wanted to do once you tap your button.
I want you to navigate to another page.
So what I do is I select from my menu or my options navigate to okay.
So now selected I wanted to navigate to where do I want it to navigate to or what's what's free or as
both do I want it to navigate through.
Since we have one extra adverb here, we only have one.
If you had a number of outputs, you would have seen those here as well.
So in this case, you select the login screen.
This is one way you can use to create your prototype just so you get this.
Hello, Joseph.
I've done this, though.
You've done this.
Okay, so that's one method to prototype.
The next one is very simple.
When you select your target.
Sugar.
You see around something, they click and drag you to your next stream.
So you want to go back to your this one, your set, your start screen.
You can actually decide to tap on, get started.
It moves to the login screen.
You can use your arrow keys or your keyboard to go back to your previous screen.
Or if you want to animate or do that to go back, you can choose to put a back.
That's an icon here doing that.
When you press it, you can't go back, then you animate it or you add a transition to it.
So for example, let me add this.
I'm just drawing a line to show what I mean.
Make it bigger.
Oh, so you mean the line is my arrow icon?
I go to the type, then I move it here.
Right.
You see what I just did?
Yeah.
Yes.
So now when I come here, I click on to get started and I want to go back.
I just click on this.
Okay.
Let me make it bigger.
So.
Excuse me.
I know.
Still.
Okay.
So when I click on this, you see that it takes me back to the start screen.
So that's what we can do is if you just want to navigate through your pages on there, design can use
the arrow keys or your keyboard.
Thank you very much.