The next thing we are going to do is to create the hero text and create the dynamic hero text attached
to it, which is the group.
You find a text too.
And then type our hero copy and make the necessary changes to the texts settings.
We then duplicate a text layer and then type glue.
And once you're done with that, we duplicate it and then type.
So then we change the colors.
Using the earlier method, we create a mask for our text layers to match them.
Once we are done creating our component to move it to the top, to start creating our interactive components
so we create a variance of the first group.
And then what we do is we select the bar to select just the by how to press command on your keyboard
and then use the mouse to select what you want to select.
After you select the bar, you move it to your left.
And then we go through we select our mask from the Layers panel, and then we adjust the marks to hide
the groove.
Once we're done with that, we create another variant.
In this new variant.
What we are going to do is we are going to make the growth text disappear and the saw text visible,
even though they are both still going to be hidden within the max.
To do that, we'll press on the AI icon to make the good heading and then the icon also to make it appear
so that when we slide back, what we see will be the saw instead of the growth.
Now we we're done with that.
We create another variant.
In this variant, we are going to make the saw up here.
We select the by using the command slash control key and then the mounts to isolate that.
And then we drag it to the right.
Then we select the max layer from our layers panel and drag it to our right as well.
And as you can see, the saw text is what appears now.
It's not the growth text.
We then create another variant of our components and this variant we are going to hide that.
So again, so we drag, we select the bar, drag it to our left side, select the component once again
and drag it to our left side so that I saw disappear that we create another component.
And as we did earlier, we switch, we make sure the growth is visible in this component and the saw
is hidden in this, even though they are both hidden in the max layer we're going to be creating in
this component is the row, which is what you created.
Initially, we select the bar slider to its original position, the right, and then select the mask
slider to its original position and now it shows go instead of.
So once you're done with that, we go to the prototype section to connect a variant to make the component
interactive.