Okay.
So I have my illustration file opened here.
Right.
So what I did was I selected the.
The illustration I wanted to use and then copied it and paste edits into figma as an SVG file.
So yeah.
Good.
I have my first one.
Move it to a position.
Well.
Here.
All right.
As you can see, the lady.
And then I'll go back to I'll go back to Illustrator to select the next file.
So the next one is the mine.
With the camera in his hunt.
When I select this, when I do this, you realize that it selects the background as well.
But I don't need the background, so I have to deselect the background so that I can copy the illustration
by itself.
I can copy just the illustration.
So to do that, I just press and hold shift and then click on the background.
You notice that it selects the background and only selects the illustration I want.
So then I copy it by pressing command C or control C on whatever keyboard or C are using.
Then I go to Figma and I use control.
It's just paste.
So yeah, I have it.
Hmm.
Well, I have to do a bit of resizing here.
Yeah.
Mm hmm.
Uh huh.
Uh, I have to make sure that they are.
You have similar sizes.
So.
1i5, I think.
And they change the shape here manually.
Okay.
So.
I have my illustration.
Yeah.
Okay.
So if you notice.
The background here in this design is different from what I have here, right?
The ladies background is.
A lighter shade of purple.
So I do that to do that app, to double click, to select the background, and then under the fill section,
I click on the color and then using the.
Selection color selection method I taught you.
You can select the color from sorry color picking method so you can pick the color from the design.
I think you probably know half that you'll be given the image as well.
So you pick the color from the image and then in this case I'll change.
I have the color here in my documents color.
So I just click and change the background color.
Right.
Okay.
So.
So that I have it.
I'm done.
It's left with the log.
Sorry.
The welcome update, right?
The welcome update.