Well, everyone, so welcome to the continuation of our frequent projects.
Okay, so you'll notice that our icon here is too close to the edge, so I'm going to click on it.
Let me move it.
Just that somewhere here.
Okay.
It's okay.
Let me zoom in.
So I wanted to start on the edge of this.
So here.
Okay.
So the center is at the edge of it.
Oh, this.
Okay, so let's see something and how you can rectify it.
Okay, so let me zoom out.
Now, if we should.
Pay close attention to this.
When I stretch, you can see when I'm trying to stretch the canvas or the frame, you would notice that
it's stretching the icons too.
So to avoid that error, you can hold control.
That's for windows.
I don't know.
The shortcut key for Mac is you control on your keyboard and then stretch your canvas so that you can
be able to scroll.
Okay, so we want you to achieve the scrollable.
Like I'll just be able to scroll.
Okay.
So remember to use control when you are transferred to such effects.
So what I'm going to do now is just to highlight this control C, control V, or we can just use control
DX.
Okay, I'm going to bring it down.
So stay with us.
That's nine.
And then I'll do controls D again.
Bring it down.
So it was four.
It's in the.
With that in mind, King.
Now when I do control the.
You should have it.
Okay, so I've already done some control.
D So do this.
You control D Then I'll bring it down.
That's nice.
So let me just bring this up.
Hey.
So remember, I'm going to hold the control, and then I'm going to take it up.
So what next to do is just to change the colors.
So I'm just zooming in to change the colors and then the icons.
We already have gone done.
We've already done something and let's see how to do that.
So when I click this, I can go to.
Let's see.
Sorry.
Right click plugins and then choose lossy files.
Let's wait for it to load.
Once once has downloaded.
Let me just choose Amy.
So I just click this and then convert to give.
Okay.
Then I'm going to add it to Figma.
So in other, you see it took the shape it took the shape of this icon, this loosey, when it was here.
Okay.
So we don't need to worry ourselves trying to resize and everything.
So.
That should be it for this.
And then the rest we are just going to duplicate.
Okay, so I can just take this out.
Delete.
Just control C, control it.
And then bring it here in case.
They will do same for the others.
So control C, control v.
No.
Bring it.
Delete this.
Don't drink it here.
Okay.
So that should be it for the last before we have to just align them.
Well here with the help of the guidelines or rules or guidelines.
Yeah.
So we can change the text here to exercise or yoga or whatever.
Exercise here to shopping.
Whatever you want to studies or coding remember type in code code CiCi's open countries it's.
Quotes.
Essays, recording essays.
Okay.
This one amended this donations.
It isn't work or pets.
Let's do patchwork.
Okay.
So we are going to so we have that for our progress.
For progress.
So all we have to do is just change this and it's color.
So this is going to be let's do overdue.
No change will change its color.
Okay.
So I'm going to give you this colour value, this colour value, and then we'll do same for this.
Okay?
So we just want some consistency so that our user, when the user sees this color, he knows that it's
an overdue activity.
Okay.
So just as this represents in progress, okay, this represents overdue.
And then the remaining two will give it a green color.
Okay.
So this color value.
And I'm going to green will be called completed.
Completed.
It will change here, too, to.
GREENE So this just a quick projects.
A quick project.
So.
We need to align them.
So let me select this and then this multi selects, then I'm going to align them with the help of this.
Okay, so they are well aligned.
So we'll do that for all the other ones.
So more select then align them with the help of the alignment.
So so align physical centers.
Okay.
So I'm done aligning the icons and then the text here, and then I can change here now to change this
and then select the two.
And then by holding shift and then selecting them and I'm going to give them a green color.
So a quick way to do that and I'm going to change it to complete it.
Okay.
So let's see what we have this.
Okay, so this icon, the switch icon was cut and I gave it a shadow drop shadow of an enabler of six.
Then it's a C icon.
Sorry, it's an iconic icon that I pick from icon ified.
It seems like I'm right.
Okay, so I'll click on this and then I'm going to preview it with a play button, open a window and
then load the interface was okay.
So when I tried previewing it, our main lesson isn't showing.
I don't see why it's not showing.
So let's preview this instead and see what happens.
Oh, now this works.
Okay, so when I screw, you can see Scrollable.
Okay?
And then that should be it for our projects.
So thank you.
And I'll see you in the next lesson.
Thank you.