So skill is the relative dimensions of an element measured by some percentage or numerical value.
Now there are some advantages of skill, so skill helps bring some form of consistency in your UI.
So let's see how your device or your UI would look on a on desktop and then how it will look on mobile
devices and then on tablets.
So you'd have to skill your UI elements, and that defeats all this, the various pixels of the screen
sizes.
The screen sizes of these devices.
It could be iOS or Android.
So how your UI will look on on a tablet should be different from how it would look on on a mobile device.
Okay.
So let's take a look at this.
So this is an example of scaling.
So let's say this is 100%.
And then there's a different percentage.
A different percentage.
So in the receding order.
So here you could see this looks bigger than this, done this and then done this.
So let's say this is a text.
So the how this would appear on a desktop would be different from how it appear on a mobile device.
Okay.
So we have this responsive design.
If you use responsive design, you would notice that the way websites would look on desktop will be
different from the way it would look on a mobile device.
The elements might change.
Positions of the elements might change depending on the screen size of the device that a person is using
or your use as you.
They use this use.
And so this is example of skill, then it helps in some form of a visual hierarchy.
So some kind of importance is given to objects that are scaled or UI elements, UI elements that are
being skilled.
So this is a perfect example of skill.