The next thing I'm going to do.
It's great.
My text, the number we have 8663124370.
Oh.
What is the number again?
8663124370.
Cool.
So the next thing I'm going to do is I'm going to increase the capacity since this is 50.
So I'll increase it to 80 and then change the font, which is semi blue so that it becomes more visible,
like what we have in the original design.
Then I'll give it a 15 pixel space.
Silver looks good.
It looks good.
We are almost there.
So the next thing are going to do in this design is we are going to create the icons at the far.
So next thing we are going to do in this design is going to create the icons at the far right.
So we have Facebook, LinkedIn, Twitter, and I don't know what this is.
So we just create three of the icons since only two of the icons are recognizable to me.
Once again back to I quantify yeah I know utilized I quantify a lot in this session so our search for
Facebook.
Good.
So Facebook pops up.
I select the options.
That is okay for me.
Okay.
So this time I wanted to find all my icons.
Before I close.
I qualify it.
I don't have to keep coming back here.
Yeah.
So I found Facebook.
The next thing is LinkedIn.
So I'll type LinkedIn here, see how it looks.
Okay.
This looked good enough for me, so I would like to see a.
Modify it a bit.
Make it small enough and place it.
And the.
Okay.
So what's the next icon?
We have Twitter.
So.
So pick one of the iPhones.
That seems good enough for me.
Drag it to my.
The ones again.
So I'm going to make the final.
I want a random one by just clicking, just searching social media and choosing whichever one is not
on our list here.
So.
Social media.
Okay.
Nothing should.
I guess I'll actually have to look for something.
We have Instagram here, Facebook.
We have to tell us social media.
Okay.
So we look for Snapchat.
Snapchat.
Let's just look for Snapchat.
A gay.
This should be good enough.
All right.
So now that I have all my icons, I'm now coming to the size role.
So I resize it.
By either using the options here or just using the inputs, size, inputs of the change, the sizes.
It seems a bit too small, so.
So this was the size.
And make this.
55.
You seem a bit too small, so I have to make it smaller.
Let me see how it looks here.
Okay.
I have to make it smaller.
So I think it should be.
You know, it's usual.
1817 should be okay.
Small.
Should you be?
20.
And you see the size of this.
And we sent them using the center button.
I left Facebook out and then distribute the space between them evenly.
And moving closer to my.
My grade age.
Let's see how it looks here.
It looks good enough.
So from this design, the only thing I have to do is reduce the color opacity.
I changed it to 40.
Let's see how it looks now.
Design, but looks good enough.
We are going to do is I'm going to shift this a bit closer to our icons here.
This weekend, 50.
Great.
So 50 looks good enough.
Okay.
So we are left with some few things I almost forgot.
So we have these buttons here and then we have this go button.
So to create this once again, I'll just duplicate this here.
On this.
You need the iPhone already available.
Change the color from white to black.
And make it a black.
Can I just make your block lock?
Okay.
Good.
I qualify once again.
Special headphones.
Okay.
So I just select the first icon I'm okay with.
SC One closer to yeah, this one looks close towards us there, so I'll use this.
So I drag this to my board and then I resize it.
Change the color.
Resize it.
Make a small enough to fit.
The small Seiko I have down there.
Yeah.
This small alembic give.
And then sent it to my ship.
And then finally it.
Let's see how it looks.
Okay.
Looks good enough.
So now we have our final thing, which is these two shapes.
Once again.
I'll just duplicate this instead of doing it from scratch.
I'll group bids and delete.
The phone icon.
Make the circle a bit smaller.
It make it that 60 by 50.
Yeah.
60 by 50 looks good enough.
Let's see.
And this seems to be to be.
Okay.
50 looks okay and make it for 20.
35 looks good too.
So let's maintain 45.
Okay.
So once again, back to iconic by our favorite plugin for the session and then search forward once again
forward for it.
Forward, forward.
I see.
What's.
Have something close.
Okay.
So this is close to what is there?
I drag this.
And they use it in that design.
Let me see.
Inside the circle.
Yeah.
It's okay.
I don't.
I don't think.
Okay, let me make it slightly.
Move it to 25 and then send it.
Then, Rupert.
Good.
So I have my face buttoned down.
Then I just duplicate this to create the next one.
To create the next one, I just have to double click to select the the forward icon and then right click
on the icon and then flip horizontal.
I'm done.
I'm good to go.
Are we going to design realize a similar.
We are done and does it.
I told you it was going to be a very simple design.
There you have it.
I hope you enjoy the session.
If you have any concerns or any questions, you can send it my way and I'll try my best to answer everything
as clearly as possible.
Thank you very much and do have a lovely day or evening, depending on whichever time you're watching
this course.
So next time, bye bye.