Welcome to this fake McCoys.
So let's move along.
Let's move along.
Okay.
So the next thing we are going to do is add the welcome text above the illustrations here.
So to do that, I either select the text two on the menu bar or just type T on my keyboard and then
I click anywhere in my.
In my free.
I stopped typing.
So welcome.
Okay.
So I sent out.
It has all the properties I need.
If it's not enough, it's not good enough for you.
You can change the text properties here.
Okay, so I have everything sent.
I have everything done for now.
Let's see how it looks when I preview it.
Okay.
So it looks good.
Good enough.
I could try.
Bring in the wall.
Come down a bit.
So that it could be more in view.
Bring the illustration down a bit and.
Bring down the wall.
Come a bit.
Okay.
I look at this and it looks good.
It looks good.
Now, when we look at the design here, we realize that there's some shapes here are the corner is not
true such that some designs here to do this designs to do this designs, I'm going to select the ellipse
to form the shapes to choose.
So yeah, I select the ellipse and to draw a perfect circle I press and hold, I press down shift I
press and hold shift.
And then I start drawing my ellipse to whatever shape I want it to be.
Okay, so this is good enough for me.
I just push it to the corner.
Yeah.
Okay.
So I put my shape, I push it to the corner.
It looks good.
The next thing I'm going to do is change this color to this.
So to do that, I go to the floor once again and I change the option here from solid to linear.
I'm giving it a linear gradient.
So I tap, I select the first color option.
I said again using the eyedropper to I pick my color.
Okay.
So it looks like.
This is hitting.
So I'll just drag it down and beat the opposition as well so that I can see my cut up.
Bring this down.
It looks good enough.
Then on top on the next one, X color option increase the intensity from 0 to 100 and pick the eyedropper
again, then tap on it.
Yeah.
It looks good.
See how it looks when I preview it.
And those good.
Close enough.
And we bring this down a bit, maybe reduce the size a bit.