So here.
So with the useful links, here are some links that you can get free or page resources like images,
icons, colors, illustrations, fonts, animation, and then where to get inspiration.
BLOCK okay.
So a community like so we can visit from Google dot com and then you have good number of fonts that
you can use in your design UI.
Okay.
So these are the properties you can go through them and then we have its icon.
So fonts click here or better.
So I'm just going so fonts dot google dot com and then slash icons.
So here you can see we have icons that you can use when you click on them to give you the properties,
then you can download them as PNG or SVG.
You can also click here to change the white.
We have the Android, iOS, flutter and the likes.
They can download them either SVG or PNG.
So SVG scalable vector graphics.
So you can change the colors, you can scale it to any size, resize it.
And then if you come to illustration, look here we have fun.
Sekiro so far scrolls is a good place if you want fonts for certain projects.
Then we have the illustrations we have on Draw.
So this on draw, you click on it and then you can download it as SVG or PNG.
So if you come here, I think you can even change the color.
So, so, so let's say we want this color case.
We can see how in effects you can search for.
So let's say running or run.
So you can see what we have here.
So you can download them and then use them your projects when it comes to colors.
You have coolest, coolest school, so it is a good place, a good community where you can generate
colours.
So let's see me explore trending palettes.
I'm going to explore trending palettes.
So these are pilots that are trained in and then you can use them, a combination of them.
So let's click here, copy it, and you can use it in your project.
Let's click here, can click view pallets and it is the pallets for this particular one or this.
This is so you have the hex HSP which these are like hex you saturation and it goes into B and then
so these are things that you can copy through and click to copy.
You can use it.
Just go to your projects and figma or any designing software and then paste it inside.
So when I go back and I go to the generator, so I'm going to generate some colors.
So these are the colors so you can work on these properties to change the colors.
So let's see if we can work on this you and see what is happening.
Then copy it.
You can see the color.
Okay.
So there are lots of things that you can do here.
So you can export.
See?
So you have to go through it and then whatever suits you, we use it.
And then we have the material palette dotcom.
Okay.
So here if you click if I click on icons, it should give me icons that I can use.
So you can see icons that can use when I click on this it gives me the option to see was PNG, Fiji,
iOS, Android and maybe if you are a programmer you can use this code.
Okay then we have colours.
Okay.
So you can come here and click on the colours you want and then copy them.
Then we have the palettes.
So the palettes, let's see.
So this one of Android.
So I'm going to select two colours, so pink and then let's see, light blue.
So you can see it's giving me the material, material view or material palette for this Android device.
So if I come here, you can see the colour codes here and then you can download them.
I then give you the options, CSS and the likes PNG, SVG, you click on download, then you can use
it in your projects so you can see it's giving me the pink and then the blue selected.
So you can do that for any of these lists.
So let's move to cool.
So my current sorry colour space, my colour space.
So here too is a good place to generate gradient colours.
So let me see.
I want to make a combination of gradient.
So when I click on Generate, it's going to generate ingredients for me.
So you can see I have some ingredients that I can use my.
Rejects Sue.
A combination of these should give you some credence.
We use them in your projects just as you see two colors.
This so these two colors.
So the formula of green and violets.
So gradients two colors.
Trying to fuse together.
Then we have this icon eight.
So Icon eight is a good place to get illustrations, photos, icons and the likes.
You can click on it.
You might want to read the terms and conditions.
Also, how to use the files that you download here.
I really like the 3D option.
It's taking longer for my internet to load, but this is what you should get and several other 3D files
that you can use in your projects.
And I'm going to go to here so if icons dot com so it gives you the option to preview.
So when I click on preview, you can download it.
So let me preview and then we'll see this added tons of color illustrations that we have or.
As in icons that we can use in our projects.
You can download them for free, then use them in your projects.
Okay.
So I've done with.
Okay, I'm done with this.
So Unsplash is also a good community website where you can download images and then use them in your
projects too.
You might want to check these places.
As usual, you should always remember to check the terms and conditions and import policies before using
this service.
So pixabay pixabay.
I use pixabay and it's like freelance.
You can use it for free, both commercial and then for personal use.
No attribution is required, so you can see the Pixabay license free for commercial use.
No attribution required.
You can download them and then use them in your projects by just clicking here.
We also have pixels.
So pixels is a good place to also download your things images for projects.
Stock those too.
I also want to check here.
Then.
Lucy.
So Lucy.
Or demonstrates something later.
Somewhere in the course.
Or maybe after some presentation.
A guide to UI UX to this.
You want a community so you can visit the visit IO blog where you can learn more about UI and UX and
they also have UX Spin Dotcom Blog.
You can also learn more about UI UX.
And then we have dribble.
So dribble.
So you can get images, inspirations from where you can learn.
Remember told you to copy and then improve.
So there's a good place to copy what people are doing for inspiration or methods here.
They can work on their projects, improve or just try to learn something and then improve yourself where
you copy.
And then we have templates free vs dotcom template free vs dotcom.
So here we can visit here.
And as usual, remember to read the terms and conditions as usual.