Everyone, welcome to the continuation of our previous lesson.
So our previous lesson we learned to create a contact information screen as you see here.
So today we'll be doing will be learning to create my contacts home.
So this screen is what we'll be doing today.
Okay.
So that said, we would have to go to our Figma projects.
Okay?
So remember we did this and then we have to just add a new screen so I can just go here to the frame,
click on frame.
And then since we use this, I'm just going to select this.
This is what we used.
Okay, so position it was just bring it down.
Okay?
So, okay, so now would have to, let's see what else to do now.
So how have to.
Those are the texts and then this profile or avatar.
Okay, so let's start with this.
So that's it.
I'm just going to have to copy this.
Control C, control V, and then I'll move it here.
And see if is the same.
Okay.
So I'm going to have to reduce this question to my home.
In my home.
So sorry.
My contacts.
So my contacts change it to my contacts.
Contacts.
Okay.
Then I'm going to give it to size of, let's say 24.
So 24, 64 is okay.
This was 36,
this was 24, 34.
Okay, so let's just do it 36.
So just do it just 36.
So.
So let me see the distance.
2438 So.
Hold on, hold on.
Let me see.
So there's 26, so I'm going to make it with the arrow key left arrow.
I'm going to shift it to 24 and then it's already 38 at the top.
Okay.
And now we'd have to do that.
So the proof.
So the profile is, I think 40 by 40 or 40 by 40.
So I can just control see this courtesy control V and bring it here can change the size to 40, 40 by
40.
Then just try to align it here.
There's a distance.
So here's 35.
Okay.
Sow oats, sow 40.
Ready change to sow as 40.
So we do, right?
Okay.
I'm going to move it to a discourse.
And then we'll do that off the switch.
Okay.
Research by how to use the rectangle tool.
Then I'm going to draw here.
And then I'll give it a radius of let me see what radius was used.
So the radius should be 12 pixels.
Okay.
So 12.
So I'll go.
So sorry for that.
I'll have to change the radius to 12.
It's for, so it's not.
Okay, so let's see.
Let's check the heights first.
So the height is 40, which is 43 to 7.
So 44.
The heights.
And then here 3 to 3 to this.
327.
Okay.
So that's right.
Just try to center it and then the color is white.
So I'm going to give it a white color background.
Let's see.
And then if you look closely, you see that it has a drop shadow.
Okay, so a drop shadow.
So would go to.
Let's just see how.
So a trough shadow.
So when our if effects panel or effects section, I'm going to click here.
The Drop Shadow is already selected, so I'll click on this then.
OSU up is.
And to play.
It means it's five.
Leno sets my way to zero.
Okay.
So I'm going to increase the play or let's increase the spread a bit, so let's do it.
So what I did was I changed my way to.
To so that we have this shadow most beneath.
Okay.
And then my blade was set to 12.
Now, if you study carefully, you'll notice that the distance here is 23.
So I can so stretch it.
Woman and.
So let me just just hold and then I'm going to use the left key to move it.
So I get 23.
Okay.
And then the distance.
So I'm going to have to stretch this.
Then let me hold outs and then check to 26.
Okay.
Jesus is okay because here.
I simply.
Thank you, sir, for that.
So here k click here and check is 25.
So we just leave it to my s 26 and is 23.
So leave it this way.
Now what we can do is take this.
So now we'd have to do that on the search icon.
So the search icon, I'm just going to have to select this.
Remember, we pick this on the previous lesson and then I'm going to give it a shot, a color value
of click on the fill property and I'll give it this grey color.
See this size 81 by 21.
So I can just change it here 21 by 21.
Okay.
Then I'm going to move it inside.
Yeah.
So it's.
Okay.
So the distance is.
It's easy for so.
It's a movie that gets 24.
Okay.
And then we'll have to type the hints.
So the hint is search by name or number, search by name or number.
We just have to select this.
They control C and then paste it inside control V, we will happen.
Okay.
Now I'm going to change it to search by name or contacts.
Search by name or phone number or number.
Search by number.
I'm going to move it here.
And then it seems to be centered.
And then let me check.
Okay.
So 15.
So the distance is 15.
So let's do that.
Okay.
So it helps you.
I'm going to say 215.
15.
Okay, so we are done with this.
Then let's preview it and see.
So now we change here to contacts, as in my.
My contacts home.
So let's just do it at home.
So.
Then you can preview it now.
Okay.
So there's the preview for the first screen and then the preview for the second screen.
So thank you.
See in the next lesson.