Welcome to This Week, Marcos.
So let's move along.
Let's move along.
Yeah.
So I'll just search the other icons here so I don't have to go back to the plug in.
So I'll switch user to for the user name.
Okay.
I think this looks good.
So I'll just select this.
Yeah.
This looks good.
And then our such key padlock showed padlock.
Yeah.
For the password.
I'll just pick this.
This looks good for me.
Okay, so I'm done with the I qualified plugins.
I have all the icons I need for my design, so I will just have to resize them.
Right.
So this is 24 hour.
Reduce the size a bit.
20.
Then I change the colour from black to violet.
Because that was the color of the icons.
Violet.
It looks too small on my design, so I guess I have to make it a bit bigger.
Let's see.
It's 24.
Okay.
Oh.
Yeah.
So 24 is okay.
24 is good enough.
I mean, sets the distance between them to 20.
Okay.
So to how am I doing this?
I'm checking this by pressing down option on my keyboard.
I think it's all on Windows Keyboard, so I have the elements selected and then I press and hold option.
And then just who were my moms around it to check the distance between the elements?
Right.
I want to set that distance to 30, so I guess I'll have to move it back a bit.
Okay.
As I said, you now.
So let's see how it looks.
It seems that this stands between the icon and the text is a bit too much, so I reduce the distance
to 15.
Let's see how it looks.
It looks a bit.
Okay.
So, yeah, we'll move on to the next one.
Let's see.
Okay.
No, it looks like I have to increase the distance, so.
And move it to 30 and see.
Hmm.
No, let me set it to 25.
Okay.
So you said whatever distance you are okay with.
This looks good enough for me, so I guess I just move on.
Okay, so I'm done with that email input box.
Now the next thing I'm going to do is create the username input box.
So.
I'll get a duplicate once again and then move it below.
And position my icon correctly.
Change the colour as usual.
And then also I changed this from email to username.
Right.
Okay.
So I'm done.
I just grouped them.
See how it looks.
Hmm.
It looks good, but I feel like we have to reduce the intensity a bit.
So.
Every movie from 15 to 10.
Yeah.
No, I like what I see.
Okay.
So since this is.
Let me move the logging button from here.
Sorry.
This is supposed to be the log in but ended up designing the register, so I guess I'll just have to
rename.
The frame from logging to register and then rename the title to to register.
Okay.
Good enough.
So our next page you are going to design will be the login screen to do that.
We've basically done the everything we need.
Basically.
So to do that, I'm going to create a duplicate once again of the register screen this time of the register
screen.
So I just rename my register screen.
To log in and I change my title from register to log in and make sure that my title is censored.
Okay.
So we are almost done here.
We realize that the only thing that's different here, right?
Is that illustration.
And our button.
So.
We are going to.
Delete the email from here.
Okay, so I just noticed the mistake.
This page, guys, is supposed to be the register page and this is supposed to be the login page, not
the other way around.
Right?
So I guess we are correcting it in the design here.
So we just move along and work with that.
So I select this and I drag this up here.
Good.
So now we have our username and password.
I just have to change the text here from register to log in.
Mm hmm.
This looks good.
If you notice.
Yeah.
So the next thing I have to do is change the illustration I have here.
To do that, I have to go back to my illustrator file and then pick.
The illustration I want to use.
So to do that, I'll select the one I want to use by realize that it selects my targeted illustration
in the background.
As I told you earlier, to just select the illustration after D select the background.
So I press and hold shift and click on the background.
It selects the background for me.
Then I can now copy my illustration into Figma.
To do that I just press command C and I go into Figma and then Press Command to paste.
So I just drag it into my frame, delete this and then move it to the position is supposed to be let
me see the size of this.
This is 190.
So I guess.
190.
Good enough.
And we see this position.
I'm 90.
And we make it smaller.
Mm hmm.
That's good enough.
So we are almost done here if you look at the log in screen.
You realize that there's this icon here, right?
That is icon.
So to get that, we go back to our iconic I Plug plugin.
We go back to I quantify it and then such.
For the I.
All right.
So once we find it, we drag it.
You select what you want, the one you want, and then you drag it here into your frame.
So I have this now.
The only thing I have to do.
Sorry.
The only thing I have to do is now change the colour.
So I change it and then modify the opacity a bit.
Okay.
This looks good.
This is good enough.
Good enough.
What's happening here?
That's right.
Let's see how it looks.
It looks good.
So now we are done designing our three screens.
I promise you we are going to design at the end of the course.
So we have a welcome screen now.
We have our register screen and we have our login screens.
If you are able to follow along and complete this.
Well done, guys.
Once again, my name is Jacqueline Solidarity and this course has been in collaboration with anybody
can develop A, B, C, D for short.
Thank you very much.
Adios.