So hello everyone.
So welcome to the continuation of our previous lesson thus for our my home screen.
So this was able to do in our previous lesson.
So now today we will be doing this.
So try and finish up with this.
So let's get started.
So first we'll do the results and then we just have to do some images.
Okay?
But what I would have to do is what I did was to go to Pixabay.
Okay.
In our previous lesson, I'll show you how to copy.
Okay?
So just good pixabay and then just copy the image.
So use copy right click and then copy image of the copy.
You just have to come to your working environment and then control the right click and then paste it
here.
Okay, so this was our pasted.
Okay, so let's do that.
So the avatar or the proof of this, okay.
So to do that, we've already learned that.
So the left too.
So I'm just going to do as one example and all the rest will be on assignment for you.
Okay.
So the ellipse and then I'm going to hit on shift.
Draw.
Then let's pick this animal, this image.
Let me send this to boxer.
Right click.
And then if I do it this way, it won't work.
Okay, so right click and then use us mask.
So it didn't work.
So Control Z, we won't do.
So I have to send this behind.
So right click.
Then sent back the then highlights.
Also, you can see I've highlighted a circle and then this image and the right click.
And then they'll use us.
Musk.
So now we have it.
Okay.
So even with the right position, it's where you want in the image.
So you can do that for the others.
Okay, so I'm done with mine and then I'm going to resize it.
So I'm going to use 39 by 39.
That's nine.
By Tatiana.
Okay.
Then I'll do.
Same for this.
Okay.
And then do for the last one here.
So we can just move it here.
Move them here.
So now let's see what we have to do.
We have to do that.
All the text for reasons and then this.
Okay.
So an in the distance.
So 34.
So that's it.
Four.
So let them bring you here.
Then our hood out.
And then the distance.
So the distance is 65.
I'm going to change to 34.
So with the arrow key, Kayla, stick it up.
So you get 34.
Okay.
So that's what I should be for the reason.
Schroder So the reason not the image.
So.
So I'll do is just to copy this.
Okay.
I'll copy this and.
See or.
Let me see.
It's normal.
This is normal.
You need to normal.
Okay.
And then this size, it's 14 pixels.
Soon, you need to know more.
So let me just use this control C, control V and then I'm going to move it here.
So we'll just do a regular.
I don't think I have normal here so I'll a regular and then I'm going to type recent.
Who the spelling is.
Coke resents.
Resents.
So there is no s the E.
So really sense here.
So I would have to change this to.
Semi boat or better.
So let's give it this value.
Okay.
So the mobile is semi boat and then is 20.
So then we do this also 20.
Semi boat and I'll give you 20.
So I'm just going to enter to zero.
Okay.
I'm going to use this vertical ruler.
Once our distance to align at this point.
Okay, so let's okay.
And then what we can do is just to copy this control, see less shifts and then copy that to control
C, control V, they are going to move it here.
Okay.
So then in name.
So let's see what we have for our.
So since you have the name and any contacts and then we have some ellipse and then a divider.
Okay.
So we'll have to do that.
So give any name here.
So I'm going to use Bright.
So bright.
And then we just move this image here.
So let's check the distance.
So there's some ten.
So it's actually in a box in this ship.
So what you can do, you can use the rectangle to then just draw here.
From here to hear.
Okay.
Then its size is 375.
Height is 60.
It's 60.
So the height is 60.
So height.
375.
Okay.
What is happening?
So let me just stretch it here and then I can just highlight all of this.
So highlights this, these let's bring it here.
Then I'm going to right click and then bring two fronts.
We'll just take it book.
So it escalates.
So just change it to whites.
Now we would need a divider.
Or let's start with this.
Let's do this.
But first, okay, so let me see here, then I'll bring right here.
An another ruler here.
So I want to start chestnuts where the contest starts.
And I also bring you here.
Okay.
So I'm going to have to use both and see the distance here.
See the distance from the recent races to the shape is 12 so 12 pixels.
So let me see recent.
Photos and and check that.
So it's nine here, so we should take it down.
So I guess.
Well, okay, so 912.
Okay.
And then hold.
So I think this is okay.
We want.
Okay.
So if we look here, you'll see we have the three ellipses or the more icon.
So I'm going to have to just select this icon control C, control V, then bring it here.
Okay.
We can just give it some degrees here.
So I used 90.
And then this position itself to be a horizontal, not physical.
Now I would have to change its color to this gray color.
Okay.
Then let's see.
Try and center it.
Yes, I think it's been here.
Okay.
I'll check the distance.
So let's see the distance.
It seems to be at the edge of this.
So let's see here.
Well, let me use the ruler.
Okay.
So I think it's perfect.
So that should be it for this part.
So the only thing we are left with is let me just group or let's just leave it this way.
Okay?
We'll continue populating the list as you have here.
So this a list list view, so populate it and then we'll do that of the floating action button and then
we are done.
So thank you.
And then see the next lesson.