ASO.
Hello everyone.
So welcome to today's session.
So we'll continue with where we left off when we left off.
So you can see here, I really don't like the distance between the reasons and then this whole section
or UI.
So I'm going to the project then let me just highlight these.
So one, so multi select with the help of the ships key, then select, select and do that for the ship
here.
I'm going to take it down.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight.
Okay, so let's see that gap so holds and then so I used 20, now things should be 22, so 22.
So I'm going to take down.
Okay.
So 20.
Okay, so let's preview it.
Okay.
So I think it's quite okay now.
And then let me see.
See these phones.
So this phone is no more.
You need to scroll.
So here is so changes to 12.
So you need to know more.
So let's use regular.
Okay.
So that's okay.
So this.
Okay.
And let me see the name here.
The most selected.
I'm going to bring them down.
Okay.
So we are.
So now what I'll do is I'm just going to select this again, okay?
And then we are just going to control the with the help of the shift key or bring it down.
But let me group.
Okay, so right click and then group selection.
So now they become one objects and then they move together.
Okay, so why we just have to do it?
So I'm going to take this out.
So let me replace it with this guy.
So I'm just going to take you out.
Beaten in all places with this guy.
So it seems to be position.
Well, here, let me give it some 1 to 2 heads and then give some.
One, two.
Now.
So this group look excluding this, so I would have to group it again or with astronomy group and group.
So I regroup.
Let me change the name here to Bright Data.
Okay.
Then I'm going just to group control G and then let's see the we need to have a divider.
So if you look here, we have a divider here.
So a divider.
So I think is just one point.
Let me just do that.
So a divider, we are going to use the line two.
Okay.
So the line that I'm going to select draw from here, okay.
Then while holding on shift, I'm just going to drag to here.
Let's see if that's what we have.
Okay.
It's great.
So how does it change?
It's from black to grey.
So that's okay.
So the stroke is one.
Okay.
So that's okay.
But let's see.
It's supposed to be here.
So also, let's hear.
So I'm going to move it up.
Okay.
So this.
Sorry.
So now we can just control or we just control C, control v, and then bring it down to the base of
this.
So let me see the base.
Okay, so we take this up.
Let's see.
Okay.
So specifics.
Now, let's just group this.
Group this.
How to group it.
Then I'm going to group that to.
So control G.
So now we have them as one objects.
So let's check here and see the distance.
So the distance from here.
So.
So from this.
So this.
Thin.
So ten.
So let's do that.
So I'm just going to select and then hold out.
Okay.
So ten tickets up.
So there's no intent.
So this is okay.
Let's preview it here.
Okay.
So you can decide to change the values so the name and then they can decide to change it.
So just one last one.
So I'm just going to control C, control V to open.
The.
C control fee.
This is all.
It's so supposed to be ten.
So I'm going take it up.
And then we just have to change this image.
Okay.
So bring this image here.
It's like I just bring it here.
Okay.
So now we have this.
So what we are going to do?
Change this moment.
Okay.
So.
Now we have this contacts.
So as usual, we are just going to select the reasons here.
So control C, control V with the help of the shift key, I'm just going to move it down.
Rookie.
Okay, so let's shift key while holding on shift and then that rookie shift key will help it move faster.
If I should use the rookie, you just move shifts.
It's faster.
So let me see the distance used here or the.
So it's well, so confused.
Used.
So let's do same.
Better still.
Okay.
So it's all old.
So I'm going take it down.
So I'm going to change it to contacts.
I think he used contacts.
So contacts.
It's a contacts.
So you can use control.
Plus, to zoom in, control minus twos, zoom out with the key keyboard, plus the combination of keys,
control plus and control minus.
So now what we have to do is just do this.
Okay.
So a.
Okay, so now let's see me.
See the distance from here.
So here is.
Here to 34, 34.
So I'm just going to copy this control C, control V and then bring it down.
Okay.
So I did include this.
So let me just control C, this control v, so bring it down.
And if I how to next is it change the names.
Okay.
And then we would change here would add on a so alphabet.
So that's actually another ship here.