It's 18.
So control minus that I'm going to draw a rectangle.
So the rectangle.
So its distance from the contacts is nine or nine pixels.
So I'm just going to let me face move this once.
So old.
It's mine.
I'm going to move it down.
So I get nine.
Nine.
Then the color is white.
So change to white.
Thing this a show on AMC the size 14 pixels you need to a normal case of 14 pixels need to normal so
this use disorder controls quattro v inside so right click arrange it and bring two fronts and then
send this to back right click on the shape here then send to back.
So Central Bank is going to take a lot.
So I'll just send this.
I rather you send back.
What?
So let's just send it back.
Okay.
So now it's in front of it.
So a so.
An A yes.
20.
This is what's.
It's 14 normal.
So let's change it to 14.
14.
No.
So normal use regular.
Let's make it both.
Okay.
I am going to make it both.
Semi both.
So semi boat is okay.
So a distance should be nine.
Let's center it first.
So we just move this.
Okay.
So in order to center our alphabet here, I'm going to have to just highlight it's to click this and
then click on the shape.
So select it.
Then we are going to use the aligned physical centers.
So you can see now it's centered.
Then I'm going to move it to the edge.
We'll see.
Six or so pixels.
So this is our alphabet.
And then let me see.
Okay.
So this creates.
Let me check.
Okay.
So, yeah, it's at the edge.
Then let's see the distance.
No.
So now the distance for this alphabet to this box or this shape.
Okay, so let's do that as five pixels.
So let me just highlight this, then hold out and then check.
So we use 53, so let's take it up with the help of the arrow key and getting picked up.
So rich five.
So that was it.
Okay.
Then let's preview it and see.
So interesting.
So now we'll check.
So we have to do.
So I'm just going to duplicate it.
So let me just duplicate this.
Jesse Control V is going to bring it down.
I see them.
Check the distance.
Let's see here.
So Tim so I'm going to do that here to show ten so old.
So strange since it's ten.
Then from there we have
the B, b, so as usual, we are just going to select this or even group it.
So let me just group this to this, the highlighted group, then control C, control V and I'm going
to bring it down.
Then I will change here to B.
Should be.
Then I'll check that.
So let's check the distance here.
So there seems to be no gap.
They just closed.
Okay, so let's just stick it up.
Okay.
And then just control you.
Control this.
Then bring it down.
Open.
This is.
So this seems to be close.
Okay.
So we are just going to be joining them together.
Then we'll do that for this guy to catch your second trophy.
Take it down.
See the distance.
If you notice, you will see that we actually haven't picked the shape.
The interaction is not an issue.
We can just to use our eyes to gauge.
So I'm just going to select this fantasy trophy.
Then let me check here.
We don't have the divider.
So we'll just do that of the divider with a divider just to control this.
Then I'm going to bring it down.
It should be just some distance.
Okay, so this should be okay.
If I should check, let me take it up slow.
Let's see.
And I do control C, control v, take it down.
So this.
Okay, let's check from here and see if they suggest so then.
So A, B, C, so just A and B, two, one, two, three, two, B, one, two, three.
So now what we have to do is the floating action button and the way we are done.
So the floating action button.
So I think the C here to see we can just control C, control V and bring them down.
It's not that they just delete it.
We just do that over the floating action button.
So I'm going to bring it here and I'll weigh.
If we preview it.
Okay, so that should be it.
We are not going to add this color.
We are not going to do the same like the coloring.
Just leave it this way.
And then that should be it for our final projects.
Okay, so thank you for watching.
And remember to change the names accordingly.
So thank you.