[Autogenerated] there's a principle in software development that is
continuous integration and continuous deployment.
Again, there are multiple platforms that support this C I.
C D.
Pipeline idea.
Some of the most commonly known ones are Jenkins, AWS, code Pipeline and Bamboo.
You've probably heard of at least one of those continuous integration.
The C I component of this is usually performed when code is checked in,
and it's basically a process by which the code is checked against a series
of tests to make sure that it's good and ready to go.
And it could also be integrated into the existing code base.
Continuous delivery is the process of building and executable or something
similar a package based off of the code that was checked in.
Now that obviously doesn't map directly to terra form.
But we'll see how well use the continuous delivery side of things in a moment.
As part of the continuous integration and delivery process,
there is going to be a significant amount of automated testing and
validation of the code and the builds that come out of that code to make
sure that they're valid and working as expected.
CLI see the pipelines also tend to deploy to multiple environments in stages.
What you'll see is that the initial deployment might be against a Q environment,
and then it has to be validated.
And then once it moves past that stage,
it could be deployed to a user acceptance testing environment and tested
there and then moved to staging and then moved to production.
So the pipeline is a series of stages,
some of which are deployments to different environments and some
of which are automated testing and validation.
Now, how does Terra form DLL with these software development concepts,
and especially the concept of multiple environments?
It does that through workspaces.
Terra form workspaces are a feature in terra form meant
to support multiple environments.
It all starts with a common configuration.
So all of the different environments are workspaces in terra
form are using the same configuration.
The key difference here is that the state data for each workspace is separate.
So if you created multiple workspaces and looked at the state storage,
you would see a different state file for each workspace.
That allows terra form to use the same configuration for
all of these different work spaces.
But keep the state data separate.
That leads to the support of multiple environments.
Within the configuration of terra form,
you can references what works based you're currently using,
and that's really useful if you want to make configuration decisions
based off of which environment you've deployed to.
For instance, if you deployed to development,
you might use one size E C two instance,
whereas production might get a different one,
you can also use the value stored in terra form that works space.
So you know what environment your resource was deployed to.
Now let's tie it all together by looking at how we can
use the code family of tools in A.
W S to achieve source control management and the automated deployment of our infrastructure.