[Autogenerated] When you're building out these configurations,
you may want to reference other configurations like
we did in the layering model.
Or you may want to reference resources that exist in AWS,
and we've already seen this a little bit.
What types of resources might you want to reference?
Well, a really important one is your account.
What account are you currently using?
Because the account IDE is not necessarily obvious,
you can retrieve it through a data source.
Another common data source is availability zones.
If you're building out VP CSS.
If you're building out a load bouncer or anything
that deals with availability zones,
you need to get a list of availability zones in the current
region so that you could take advantage of them.
Another example is AM access or Amazon machine images.
Those are necessary if you're going to spend up in SC to instance,
and those images could either be the ones from the marketplace
or custom images that you've built yourself.
You need a way to reference those,
and the way to do that is through a data source.
Another common data source is networking,
and you can get all sorts of information about objects that exist in your vpc s.
For instance, you could get a list of security groups,
or you could get a list of sub nets.
And if you're trying to create a resource that needs that information,
say a load balancer,
it's going to want security groups as well as substance to connect to.
That's something you can get from the networking data sources.
And then finally, e c two.
You might want to reference existing E C two instances for something
like a load bouncer or creating a new security group,
or if they're necessary for another application to
talk to those SEC two instances.
There's a bunch of reasons you might want to do that.
So e.
C two makes a lot of sense as a potential data source.
Now, how do you reference these data sources?
Let's take a look at a few examples.
One of the data sources that we've already seen in
configurations is this a W s collar identity data source,
and this is the way to get your account IDE based off of
the current provider that you're using.
Now you'll notice.
In this particular example,
I don't references a specific instance of the a W s provider.
So if you don't supply that,
it's gonna go with the default instance of the provider.
But you can also specify a provider alias as an argument,
and then it will give you the account IDE and information
that's specific instance of the provider.
Like I said, another common one is AWS availability zones,
and this will give you the fullest of availability zones that
are in the region you're currently working in.
However,
you could specify the state argument and said it SQL to
available so well only give you the availability zones that
are currently available in that region.
That's an important distinction, huh?
Another one is sub net IDs, and we'll see this in a future configuration.
If you need to get a list of sub net IDs to use for
something like a load bouncer, you'll do that through a data source,
and it does take a few arguments.
One is the VPC IDE.
Where am I getting these sub nets From now,
if you don't specify, anything else is gonna give you every sub net IDE,
which might not be particularly useful.
But if you've tagged your sub nets,
you can specify tags of the sub nets you want to retrieve in this case,
where a tag tear is equal to application and it will
only return those sub net IDs.
That's pretty useful. Let's see how Globomantics is going to make use of these data sources and more.