[Autogenerated] within a ws.
There are a bunch of different tools that all start with the code moniker,
and we're going to be using three of those tools.
In our example.
I want to explain what those code tools were before
we got to the actual deployment.
The first is code commit and, as I mentioned a little bit earlier.
Code commit is their source control management solution.
So we're going to be checking some code into code commit.
What are we going to do with that code?
Well, we want to deploy infrastructure,
and we're going to use the A W s product CodeBuild to do exactly that.
CodeBuild would typically be used to create an executable or a package
based off of what you have stored in code commit.
But in our case, we're going to use it to deploy infrastructure instead.
And we're also going to use the product code pipeline to deploy our
infrastructure in stages across multiple environments.
Those are the three tools.
Now,
let's take a look at how we're going to use those
at Globomantics at Globomantics.
The initial goal is to deploy a development environment
through a pipeline and the way that we're going to do that
is to start with a code pipeline.
Now, like I mentioned,
code pipelines are broken up into stages for the first stage of our pipeline.
We need to get the source from code commit that we're
going to use as part of our deployment.
So there is an action in this stage.
Each step inside a stage is called in action,
and that action is to go out to code, commit and get that source material.
So that's gonna be the first stage of our pipeline.
These second stage of our pipeline is called development.
And within that portion of the pipeline,
we are going to plan out our deployment.
So we're going to invoke CodeBuild and have it run
Terra form with the plan argument.
So we can plan out our deployment of a development VPC and then
we'll have a second action in that stage,
which is our apply.
So we do our plan and our apply,
just like we would normally except that we're having
CodeBuild automate that process for us.
From the CodeBuild perspective and the code pipeline perspective,
they are gonna be generating logs and artifacts,
so we need somewhere to put that stuff,
So we're going to create an S3 bucket to dump our logs and artifacts into Now.
What is CodeBuild actually doing what it's doing behind the
scenes is spinning up a Linux container.
That's what we're telling it we want to use as part of our built environment.
And then it's looking at a file that's inside the source code
called Build Spec .NET XAML and build spec dot um,
well, basically gives it the steps that are part of this build action.
In our case, we are going to initialize,
are terra form configuration based off of the source
and then run either plan or apply,
and we'll control that through environment variables.
Lastly,
we are going to need somewhere to store our remote
state from this plan and apply.
And we're going to use our existing S3 bucket and dynamodb
table from the previous module for the storage of remote
state in this build process.
So that's our initial deployment.
Let's go over to V s code and we're going to use tear form
to actually deploy all of this into A. W s