[Autogenerated] Let's go back to our commands and we
are going to run terra form in it.
And initializer are configuration helps to be in the right directory now,
doesn't it?
Okay, let's go into the proper directory first.
There we go.
And now run Terra form in it.
It's downloading Are plug ins now.
We're gonna go ahead and run.
Terra form plan dash out ST dot t f plan that will generate our
execution plan for the bucket table and the I am groups.
All right, now that that is ready we can, go ahead and run, apply.
And that will create the actual bucket the Dynamo db table
and the groups with the proper policy.
And it shouldn't take too long.
Usually buckets and dynamo DB tables don't take very long.
There we do.
That was pretty quick.
All right, now we do need to make note of these two output,
so I'm going ahead and copy this and paste it into a Notepad file.
I have off screen and go ahead and grab this S3
bucket name and do the same for that.
There we go.
Now.
I have those two saved for use later and we've
successfully deployed our bucket dynamodb table,
the groups and the policies that we outlined in the diagram.
Now, this is a fairly simple set up for a single account.
But how might you set this up?
If you have multiple accounts and environments, let's dip into that for a moment.