[Autogenerated] When you think of CloudFormation,
you think infrastructure is code and wait,
isn't that what we're doing with terra form?
So why would we use CloudFormation when we already have terra form?
That's an interesting point.
And the reason is you're not working in a green field environment.
Most of the time,
you may have existing templates and existing deployments
out there that used CloudFormation,
and those templates might not be ready to be converted
over to terra form configurations.
And those deployments might not be ready to be
replaced by terra form configurations.
You're gonna have to deal with that as an engineer now.
Another reason is the AWS provider gets updated pretty quickly,
but new services come out of a W s all the time.
And those services might be available in CloudFormation,
but not yet available in the terra form provider.
To get around that,
you could use a CloudFormation template in the ______ form
configuration and referenced the service there instead.
Now, the good news is,
you can both create CloudFormation stacks using a terra form configuration
as well as read from existing stacks as a data source.
So you have both options available to you and that makes you pretty
flexible when you're dealing with an existing deployment.
Now let's take a look at the stack Deployment resource.
In an example.
In order to deploy a CloudFormation stack,
we're going to use the resource AWS CloudFormation stack.
We have to give the stack a name, so we'll call it app Stack in this case,
and then we have to provide it the template information.
There's two ways to do that.
In this example, we're doing template Body,
and we're pulling the template information in from a file.
So we're using the file function.
To get that information, you can also define it in line.
The other option is to reference a template URL where
you have the template already stored.
So you've got two good options there.
Now we know a template takes parameters as input,
so you can specify those parameters using the parameter argument
and then giving it a map of the parameter name in the template and
then the value you want to submit,
so that allows you to pretty seamlessly interact with the template.
There's also some additional arguments, like on failure.
What should the CloudFormation stack do?
Should it roll back.
Should it do something else?
There's some other arguments, and we will see those as we get into our example.
So what is going on? A Globomantics where they need to use a CloudFormation template.