[Autogenerated] you've been storing your state data locally,
and now you're ready to migrate it to remote state.
That seems kind of complicated, though I'm I'm a little concerned.
This is important information.
How do I even go about this?
The first step in the process is to update your back end configuration.
If you're starting out with a default configuration,
you probably didn't specify a back end.
It also terra form.
Just assumed you're going to use the local back end now.
You actually have to add a back end configuration and
we'll take a look at that in a moment.
Once you have that configuration defined, you're gonna run terra form in it.
And remember,
one of the things that terra form and it does is initializer the back end.
Once it sees there's a new back end, it's going to initialize that one.
And it's also going to ask you Hey, I see you have state data already.
Would you like to migrate that data from where it is to where
you have now defined the back end to be,
and if you say yes, it'll seamlessly move that state data over.
I will say, as a precautionary measure.
I highly recommend backing up the state before you do the
migration in case anything goes wrong.
You don't wanna lose any of that data.
Now, what does that back end configuration look like?
Let's take a look.
The back end configuration is defined within the ______ form block.
You're going to create a nested block in there that's called back end.
And the label on that will be the type of back end
you're going to use in our case S3.
And you can actually just leave it at that and define the rest
of your configuration information in line.
When you run terra form in it,
you can also choose to include some information in the
back end configuration directly, for instance,
you might hard code the bucket name.
You could also hard code the key name,
and this is gonna be the name of the object and the path to the
object that gets written to the S3 bucket.
And you can also hard code the region in there.
Now note that I'm saying hard coating, which sometimes is not a great thing,
especially if you want your configuration to be dynamic,
so you might choose not to set some of these things.
The other thing.
You'll notice that I'm not using variables here,
and that's because the initialization process happens before
terra form blows the variables so you can't use any variables
in your back end configuration.
If you want to define some of the values when you're
running your terra form in command,
all you have to do is specify dash back end dash config and then
give the key value pair that you want to define.
So if we were using our infrastructure profile for authentication,
we could do profile equals infra,
and it will know to use that for our back end in figuration.
Let's go over to V s code and we're gonna go through the
process of migrating the local state for our Dev vpc to the S3 bucket that we just created