[Autogenerated] alright in maine dot t f, we have two variables.
Very simple.
We're setting up our region,
which is us East one and we also have a list of peering users.
So these are the users that will be members of that peering group we're giving
the permissions to If we open up our terra form TF bars,
file we can see that we have a list for those peering users and
the only user in that list is Elsie Vasquez.
So we're all set on our variables.
Let's go back to that main dot T f file.
We'll scroll down to providers and now we again are
creating two instances of the AWS provider.
This time they're both using the same region.
So that is the same.
But the aliases different.
We've got one called infra and one called SEC because I'm super creative
and the profile that we're using for infra is the in for a profile we
just created with the AWS Configure command.
The profile for the SEC Alias is the SEC profile that we just created as well.
So now we have two separate providers using two different sets of
credentials that reference to different AWS accounts,
man, that's all set up that's ready to do.
And that's awesome.
Let's scroll down a little bit.
In our data sources, we are using a data source called A W s collar identity,
and this basically retrieves information about the
identity that's being used for a provider.
One of the things you can get is the account IDE for that identity,
and we're going to need that account.
IDE,
when we're configuring the policies and rolls within
the context of each data source, I have a provider set here.
So I'm getting the color identity information for the infra
profile and the color identity information for the SEC profile
scrolling down a little bit more.
We are going to get into our resource creation first
by creating a I am role policy.
This is that peering policy that we're going to assign to the peering role.
So we're giving it the name VPC peering policy.
Very creative, I know.
And then for the role we're referencing a role that we're going to
create a little further down in the configuration.
The provider is a w s dot ___.
So we know we're creating this policy within the security account.
If we look at the policy verb ege,
the important thing to note here is that we have to
actions that are being allowed.
One is except VPC peering connection.
So if there's a pending connection,
we can accept it and also describe the PC peering connection.
Because if we can't describe the connections, we can't accept them.
So you kind of need both actions in there.
That's everything that goes into the peering policy.
Just those two actions.
Now we need to assign that peering policy to a role.
Let's scroll down a little bit more and we get into the configuration of that.
I am role.
We're going to call that the pier role once again.
The provider is a W s dot sec because we're creating this role in the
security account within the body of the I am role.
We're creating an assume role policy.
And this basically says that another AWS account can assume this role.
So the action is STS assume role and the principle that can
assume this role is that other A W s account.
And that's why we needed the A W s color identity for the infra profile.
Because we needed the account IDE to fill out that principle line.
Now that we have that all set up we can go over to the infra
account and create the things we need there,
so we'll scroll down a little bit and now we're creating that I am group.
In the infra account, the name will be vpc peering,
so it's pretty obvious what it's for.
And the provider we're referencing is a W s dot infra.
So we know this is using the infrastructure account.
Then we want to add some members to that group.
And remember, we only have one member defined.
And that's Elsie Vasquez.
So we're creating a resource called I Am group membership and the whole
point of this resources just to add members to a group,
we have to tell it, What's the name of this resources?
The provider, which is a w s dot infra,
because we're still working with the infra account,
the users we want to AD DS members and we're going to hand it
the variable that has our list of users.
And then finally what group are we adding?
Those users to?
So now we've got Elsie Vasquez assigned to this group Now we
have to give this group a policy that allows it to assume the
peering role in the security account.
Let's scroll down a little bit and we do that by creating a resources.
I am group policy.
We're gonna call it peering policy.
We're assigning to the group we just created and
we're using the provider A W s infra.
So we know this is all happening in the infra account.
The policy is a very simple STS assume action and the resources going to
be the role that we created in the security account.
So we're just referencing the ARN for that role that
we created in the security account.
So if you have this policy, you can assume that role in the other account.
Now, with that, we have all that set up down in the outputs were out.
Putting that peer role aren't because we're going to need
that when we create that peering connection.
So that's everything in the configuration.
Let's go ahead over to the commands and we're going to
run the terra form initialization.
So I go ahead and open up my command window,
go into the proper folder and run Terra form in it.
There we do terra form in it.
And, as usual, that's going to download our plug ins and the provider.
All right, that's all set.
So now let's run terra form plan dash out roles dot t f plan and that
will create that execution plan that we need now.
I always run,
dash out and create a T F plan instead of going directly to the apply.
And that's just generally a best practice.
And I'd recommend doing that regardless of what environment you're using.
Terra form in the.
All right, so that successfully generated a good plan.
Let's go ahead and run terra form apply to create all those
configurations across the two accounts.
And clearly that ran very quickly.
The reason being we're just creating settings in I am We're
not actually spinning up new resources, so it usually goes by pretty fast.
Now we want to make a note of this arm for later.
So I'm gonna head and copy this,
and I'm just gonna pace that over in a Notepad I have on another screen.
So that I can reference it later.
Okay, so we have our roles set up.
We have our policy set up.
We are all set to go.
What's the next thing we need?
A.
We need that security. VPC Let's look at the slide again for a moment.