[Autogenerated] Hi, everyone.
My name is Ned Bellavance and welcome to my course,
implementing Terra Form with Amazon Web Services.
I am a Hash Corp ambassador Terra Form certified associate
and founder of NED in the Cloud LLC.
Has she corpse?
Terra form is a powerful tool to automate the deployment of
your infrastructure across multiple clouds,
both public and private.
In this course,
we are going to learn about the nuances of deploying infrastructure
as code on AWS with terra form and leveraging the services in a W s
to improve your terra form automation.
Some of the major topics that we will include cover using the AWS provider,
including authentication and modules using multiple
providers in a single configuration,
leveraging AWS S3 storage for remote state and automating
deployments with code commit CodeBuild and code pipelines.
By the end of this course,
you will be ready to deploy and manage infrastructure in AWS
with terra form before beginning this course.
You should be familiar with a W s,
especially the infrastructure as a service components and have an
intermediate level of skill with terra form.
I hope you'll join me on this journey to learn more about using terra form
to deploy infrastructure is code on Amazon web services with the implementing terra form on AWS course at Pluralsight