[Autogenerated] CloudFormation is the native tool within AWS to
work with infrastructure as code CloudFormation supports JSON and
UI XAML as its to language formats.
The comparison is the Terra form uses Hash E Corp configuration language,
which is actually a bit of an abstraction from JSON.
You could technically, right, you're Tara Farm in raw JSON,
but I wouldn't recommend it.
So you will be writing things in HCL in CloudFormation when you want
to give a CloudFormation template values to use.
Those are called parameters.
In the world of ______ form.
Those very same things are called variables, which could be a little confusing.
But just remember,
variables are those things that are inputs into a ______ for module.
Within that module.
Terra Form has a concept of local variables when these are just
local values that are computed by terra form is part of the
configuration something that might be reusable throughout the
code like a common set of tags.
For all your resources, CloudFormation has a similar construct called mapping.
If you want to process some kind of logic within your
configuration with CloudFormation,
you would do that with conditions in terra form.
They simply have logical operators and comparison operators
that you can use within your configuration.
Now both CloudFormation and Terra form have resources as their core
construct because you're creating resources in A W S.
And fortunately, they call it the same thing.
Also, within CloudFormation,
there are some intrinsic functions you can use to either manipulate
values or refer to other values within the configuration.
Terra Form also has some built in functions,
and to a certain degree there are actually more robust.
Then what's available within CloudFormation.
It's something that attracted me to terra form in the first place.
If you want to use an existing stacked to augment the stack you're creating,
you can use nested stacks so you might have a VPC stack that
calls another stack to create some resources.
In a similar vein, Terra Form has the concept of modules.
You can invoke a module within a configuration to create
a set of resources in CloudFormation.
It has a concept of implicit dependency between resources.
So if one resources refers to another one,
CloudFormation understands I have to create that other resource first,
before I can create this resource that is referring to it.
Terra Form has the same concept.
It creates a dependency craft when you're running a plan,
and if it sees a dependency between resources,
it will create the resource that the other one is dependent on.
First makes sense, right?
That's a comparison of CloudFormation and terra form. Now let's talk about our real world scenario with Globomantics.