[Autogenerated] the first thing you're going to want to do is run the A W s
CLI a W s configure command to set your access and secret keys for the
account you'll be using for this demonstration.
Now, I've already set that up.
Let's go ahead and open up a command terminal.
All right,
We're in the command terminal and let's just go to the proper directory.
There we do.
If I run a W s configure with no arguments, it's gonna let me know.
I've already set my access key and my secret access key,
And I've set a default region of US East one and default output of none.
And then all that information gets stored in my home directory in the dot A.
W s subdirectory.
Now that we have that set up, if I don't specify credentials for an AWS provider,
it will use the default credentials that I just
configured with the A W s configure command.
All right, so now that we have our credentials ready to go,
the next step is the standard terra form workflow.
First, we'll run terra form in it.
And just to refresh your memory,
the terra form initialization processes what actually downloads
the provider and any modules that you're using.
And it initializer is the back end that is used to store state data.
If we look over to the directory structure in the left we can expand
the dot terra form folder and see it created a modules folder and a
plug INS folder in the modules folder.
We have the VPC module that we just downloaded.
And if we expand plug ins we can see,
there's the terra form provider A W s plug in.
So it downloaded the executable that is used for the provider.
All right, so we're all set on that page.
Now it's time to plan our deployment using terra form plan,
so we'll run terra form plan dash out vpc dot t f plan,
and it will output an execution plan to vpc dot t f plan.
Go ahead and copy that and paste it down here.
All right,
so now it's actually checking the state and going out to
AWS and seeing what resources it needs to create to make
our configuration a reality.
And it had to create a few things,
so it's gonna add 15 new resources based off of the execution plan.
If that sounds good to us, we can,
go ahead and run that execution plan by running terra form.
Apply vpc dot t F plan.
Let's go ahead and copy that and well,
paced it down here and now it's going to go ahead and create
exactly what it just showed us in the plan.
Unfortunately,
I'm not creating any Nat gateways or anything that takes a while to create.
So this VPC creation process happens pretty quickly,
and now you can see we have our outputs here.
We've got our d be subject group, our public sub nets and our VPC IDE.
Let's go over to the AWS console and see what's generated there.
All right,
here we are in the VPC management console and let's
go ahead and click on Rvp CSS.
And as you can see, there is now a VPC named Dev VPC,
and it has the correct cider block.
Let's scroll this up a little bit so we can get a
better look at what's going on here.
So if we look at cider blocks, looks good, 10 000 slash 16.
And if we look at tags,
we have our environment is Dev Name is Dev Dash Vpc and team is infra.
So this was all successfully created.
Big thumbs up for us.
We have accomplished our goal of deploying a dead VPC for our developers to mess around in.