Hi, my name is Nertil,
and in this module I'm going to teach you how to
extend the capabilities of AppSync, customize and create faster APIs,
and a better user experience.
Throughout this module,
we'll start by learning how to make use of AppSync subscriptions so we can get
notified in real time about data changes on our back end and show the changes
on our task manager application in real time.
Next, we are going to implement server side caching on our AppSync back end.
This way we are going to cache user requests so we can return,
cache the results, and reduce API call latency to improve our user experience.
After implementing server‑side caching,
we are going to look at implementing client‑side caching, which is
powered by our AppSync client and the amplify.store.
This way, while the data from the server is still loading,
we are going to show the user cached results, which will make
our task manager application more responsive.
You will learn how to implement offline capabilities to your
applications by allowing users to continue working while offline and
then sync the data back when an internet connection becomes available so
our users can continue working uninterrupted.
And finally you'll learn how to use Pipeline Resolvers to
customize application data at multiple levels,
using Lambda functions to support different application scenarios. Let's get started.