In this demo,
we are going to create the back end for our task manager application.
From the AWS management console, first,
we need to navigate to the AppSync service.
We can quickly find it by searching for it.
Let's start by creating a new API using the Create API button.
We have a couple of options for creating our API.
We can create it using the wizard.
Also, we can import an API definition from existing DynamoDB tables,
which will create the appropriate API definition for managing data in the table.
Or we can build it from scratch.
Building from scratch is useful when we have our schema definition,
and we want to use that. For this demo, we are going
to create an API using the wizard.
So let's start the API creation using the Start button. For our API,
we need to create a model.
The model will determine what types of queries the wizard should create for us.
Let's start by giving it a name. For this demo, let's name it GlobomanticsTasks.
We already have two fields predefined for us, an ID and a title.
We are going to need the ID field as this is going to be our primary key.
The type of the primary key is ID,
which is what AppSync uses to define our primary keys.
We need to make this field required as we can't have our primary key
being empty. Here, we also have an option for list. The list checkbox
determines if the property holds the list.
Types that are marked as lists can hold multiple values.
For example, if our task table had a field for categories,
then we would mark this as list, and then here we could add multiple values.
Next, we have the title field, which is of type string.
Our tasks will have a field for title, and the type will be string.
We also need to mark it as required since the title for
a task has to be always supplied.
Now let's add another field for the task description. Let's name it
description, and we'll leave the type as string. And then, we will not
mark this as required as the task description will not be required
from our application. And finally, we'll add another field for date.
This will contain the date when the task was created. Let's name it
date. And from the list of types, let's choose Date.
This field is also going to be required, so we need to check the required field.
And this is all the fields that we are going to
need for test manager application.
We also have a section for configuring model table,
which is optional. Here, we can define the table name. By default, it will
create it as the model name and append the value table after it.
And as our primary key,
it will choose the ID field. Fields that are marked as
list cannot be used as primary keys.
We can also add additional indexes.
These will heavily depend on the requirement of your application and how
the data will be queried. Our table is a simple one,
and we will not need additional indexes.
Now let's create our back‑end API using the Create button.
And finally, we need to give it a name.
Let's name it GlobomanticsTaskManager and create our API using the Create button. We'll explore the newly created API in the next clip.