To improve the performance of our GraphQL API we can implement caching.
To view the caching settings for API,
we need to navigate to the Caching tab on our API properties.
Here we get to choose how we want to do server‑side caching.
We can cache pull requests,
which means all requests that come from the same user will be cached.
And for subsequent requests, cached data will be returned.
If we choose this option, we don't have to change anything,
and all requests will be cached automatically.
We can also do per‑resolver caching,
which will return cached data for only specific operations.
If we choose this option,
then each resolver has to opt in to cache because by default
nothing will be cached unless we tell it so.
For this demo, let's choose per‑resolver caching,
as this is more complicated to set up.
And we will opt into cache list.GlobomanticsTask query later on.
For either caching options, we need to choose some caching settings.
First, we need to choose on instance type.
This will heavily depend on your application size.
If you have a small application, then you might choose a small instance type.
Each instance has the amount of cache that can be stored in it.
For this demo let's use the smallest cache,
which is cache.small so we can incur the least amount of charges.
We also need to specify a time to live for cached entries.
The default is 60 seconds, or 1 minute.
Typically, 1 minute is a good option.
But if we need data to be cached for longer or less,
then we will need to set this here.
Depending on the frequency at which our data changes and how
important it is that we have the information right away,
we need to provide an appropriate value here.
For this demo I'm going to leave it as 60 seconds.
And finally, we can decide if and how we want to encrypt the data.
We have both options for in transit,
which will encrypt the data over the network and at rest,
which will encrypt the data that is in the cache as well.
For this demo,
I'm going to leave these options and unchecked since I
don't want my data to be encrypted.
Also, it's important to know that caching is priced separately,
which means we need to take into consideration the
cost as well when we set this up.
To view the list of prices for each instance,
we can use the pricing link at the top.
Here we can see a list of all instance types,
the CPUs, memory, network performance, and price.
The price is hourly.
Since this is a dedicated instance, we are going to be charged constantly,
not for the amount that we use, but we can delete it at any time.
Now let's navigate back to our API settings and create our caching.
As soon as we hit the Create button, our cache instance will start provisioning.
Now, if we scroll up, at the very top we can see the cache status.
Right now, the cache status is still creating.
Here we get the option to delete the cache.
Optionally we can flush the cache as well if for some
reason our records become stale.
Now that our cache has been created,
we need to go into our resolver and specify the caching settings.
First,
we need to navigate to the schema and find our list.GlobomanticsTask query.
Here let's open up the resolver details.
And now if we navigate to the very bottom we have a new
setting tab called Cache settings.
Here we can decide to enable or disable caching for this resolver.
This option was not there before until we enabled caching for our API.
Now let's enable caching and set the time to live to 60 seconds.
And also we need to save our changes using the Save Resolver button.
Now that our changes are saved,
let's head back to our client application and make a few
requests so we can generate some metrics.
We can quickly generate some requests using the Refresh button which will
call the loadTasks function and load all the tasks.
After we have called the back end a couple of times now,
let's navigate back to our API definition.
Here we need to navigate to the Monitoring tab so we
can view the cache statistics.
Here on the Monitoring tab now we have some caching
information since we enabled caching on our API.
We can see that our cache is being hit.
Instead of calling the DynamoDB, now our API is getting data from the cache.
Also, on the right side, we can see the cached amount of data in megabytes.
And also If we look at the latency graph,
we can see that the latency for the latest requests has dropped because now
it's getting data from the cache and not from the DynamoDB.
If we have a big application that users continuously
request data that could be cached, then enabling caching will improve our API drastically.