The AppSync client has caching capabilities powered by the Amplify store.
Whenever we make changes to the data, that data is stored in a local cache,
which we can utilize using fetch policies.
When we queried our data, we specified the cache policy to network only.
This always queries the backend to get new data and then stores that
data into the local cache that is provided by Amplify.
But, we also have other fetch policies that we could utilize with our client.
Another option that we have is cache first, which is a default policy.
This will not query the backend if there is data in the local cache.
Whenever we mutate data,
the cache is updated automatically with the latest data from the server.
This option is good for preserving network calls,
but we always risk displaying all data on our application.
Another fetch policy that we can specify is no cache.
This is the same as network only,
which will skip the cache and make a network call.
But, the main difference here is that no data will be stored on the local cache.
This option is very useful when we don't want to store any data locally.
That can be for security reason or for any other reasons
that you might have for your application.
If we want to only display cached information,
then we can use the cache only Policy.
This will avoid making any network calls whatsoever,
even if there is no data in the cache.
Most likely, you won't ever need to use this option,
but it's there if any use cases demand it.
For example, if you want to load all the cache data on a client machine,
then you could use this option, as this will make sure that only
data from the cache is returned; and finally,
we have cache and network policy.
This option is a hybrid between cache only and network only.
It's very useful for displaying data that changes frequently.
It will return the data that is in the cache and also make a
network call to get the latest information.
This policy cannot be used with the query function, because the query function
returns one result, but this policy is meant to return multiple results. Once
it returns the result from local cache, and then it makes the network calls,
and then returns those results as well.
To be able to use this policy, we need to use a watchQuery function. In
our loadTasks function where we query all the data, we need to change
it, so, we use the watchQuery function.
The watchQuery function takes in the same biometers as our query
function, but, it outputs an observable to which we can subscribe for
changes. To subscribe for changes, we use the subscribe function, and
then on the next function inside the subscribe, we implement our
logic. Just like we did for querying data, we load the data that was
returned in the UI.
The difference here is that the watchQuery will call
our observable multiple times.
First, it will check the cache and return the data from the cache,
after which it will return the data from the network call, here, while
logging the result in the console so we can see the results.
Let's run our application and see what happens.
We can see in the console that we receive two results.
The first one has no data because our cache was empty,
and has a property called loading, which is set to true.
That's because it's still retrieving data from a server, and then the
second time our observable was called, now it has data, and has a
property load into false, as it's not retrieving any data anymore. Let's
clear the console and make another call. We can quickly make another
call using the refresh button, which will call the load task function, and,
as we can see in the console, our observable was called two
times. The first time, it got data from cache, and this time
around there was data in the cache,
so it displayed it right away, and also the second
time, it got data from the server.
The data that we got from the server is used to update the cache.
So the next time we get data from a cache is the latest.
Using this feature enables us to provide our users right away with the data
that is stored in the cache, and when the network call has finished, we
display the latest information from the server, so our application will be very responsive.