In this demo, we are going to add, delete,
and edit tasks from our AppSync back end.
In our GraphQL schema,
we have three mutations, createTask, update, and deleteTask. We need to
define those same mutations in our application so we can use them. In
our application, in the GraphQL folder,
we are going to define the mutations in the Mutations.ts file.
Just like we did with our queries, we are going to use the
graphql‑tag library to convert the query definition into a GraphQL
query object for AppSync client.
Here, we are exporting three mutations, the createGlobomanticsTasks,
updateGlobomanticsTasks, and deleteGlobomanticsTasks.
The mutation definition is the same as defined in the GraphQL
schema in our AppSync API. If we have made any mistakes, the
GraphQL client will let us know.
Now let's navigate back to the index.ts file and import these three mutations.
We are going to import the CreateTaskMutation, UpdateMutation, and
DeleteTaskMutation from the GraphQL Mutations.ts file.
Now let's start implementing the task creation.
We are going to implement the task creation
functionality in the createTask function,
which is wired up to the UI. And we get a title and the description.
Let's start by making an instance of a createTask mutation GraphQL object.
Next, we are going to define the task object.
The task object will have a title,
which is going to be the input title that is specified in the UI, a date,
which is going to be the current date, and the
description that is specified in the UI.
Using the AppSync client, we can call the mutate function.
The mutate function requires a mutation,
which is going to be the createTask mutation. And then,
we need to specify the variables.
The variable name required from a createTask mutation is
called createglobomanticstasksinput,
and we need to specify it as
createglobomanticstasksinput. Otherwise it will not work,
and it will assume that the variable is empty. And as a
value, we are going to specify our task.
Once the request is done,
we are going to reload the tasks and then close the
pop‑up model that shows in the UI.
Next, for updating tasks, we are going to follow the same logic.
First, we create an instance of the UpdateTaskMutation query object.
Then, we specify the task details.
This time around, we need to specify the ID, title, and description.
The ID is required to make an update,
and we do not need to specify date since we don't want to change
it. And then using the client.mutate function, we specify the
mutation. And then this time around,
the variable is going to be
updateglobomanticstasksinput, and then we load the tasks.
And finally,
let's implement the DeleteTaskMutation. In the
deleteTask function, we only get the ID.
We are going to use the same logic as we did for updating and creating tasks.
First, we create an instance of the DeleteTaskMutation object,
and then we specify the task object.
This time around, we only need the ID of the task to delete it.
And then we do the same logic, client.mutate. We specify the mutation. And
then for variables, we specify the deleteglobomanticstaskinput to the task
object that we created, and we load all the tasks.
And now, let's save the changes and try this in action.
Let's try creating a new task using the Create new task button. Let's
specify a title. Let's name it Test Event. And here, we can specify the
description and create it using the Create button.
As soon as we do, a new task is created,
and then all the tasks are reloaded. Now let's try editing the task
that we just created. We can do that using the Open button. And
here, we can edit it. Let's change the title to Edited and save the
changes using the Save button.
This will trigger the updateTask function that we just
implemented earlier. And as soon as we do,
the task is updated. And finally, the delete functionality.
As soon as we click the Delete button,
the delete function that we implemented earlier is
triggered. And our task should be deleted.
Let's navigate back to the code and try to misspell one of the variables
to see how we can debug this. Here, on the mutations, let's change the
createglobomanticstasksinput and make it createtasksinput2. Now let's
save the changes and navigate back to our UI. Let's open the console and
navigate to the Network tab.
Here, we can see the requests going in and out.
Now let's try to create a new task.
Let's name it Debugging. And as soon as we try to create it,
we can see that nothing happens.
And if we inspect the request,
we can see that the data object is null, and then we have a list of errors.
In the errors, we can quickly see that the variable
createglobomanticstasksinput has a null value for a NotNull
property CreateGlobomanticsTasksInput.
So this time around, it's expecting a createglobomanticstasksinput2 variable,
but we did not specify it. The AppSync API has very insightful error code and
error messages. So whenever we have an error, it's easy to debug.