So now that we covered a lot about slots,
let's finish up this modal by tweaking some of its styling again
but most importantly and first of all, by making these buttons work. Right now, I can click cancel and okay
and nothing will happen.
Now I want to close the modal in both cases but I want to dispatch my own events to which I can listen
from outside my component,
so from inside my main application, my main Javascript logic which runs in my main document, so that I
know whether the user has confirmed this modal or cancel it because right now, what I want to be
able to do in the end is that I add an event listener here to my modal object and keep in mind, my modal
object is really just my own custom component
and there it would be nice if we had like a confirm listener and confirm is not a built-in event,
so right now this will never trigger where I can do something.
So most of the time in my application, I would probably want to do something like create a payment request
which I sent to some backend once the user confirmed or where I also can do something if the
user declines this,
so if the user cancels this, then maybe I want to reset some state in my application.
Of course here, I'll not focus on the application logic,
I want to focus on the component and how we add our own events there
but I just want to give you some ideas of what you could do there in a real application.
So outside of your web component, we'll focus on making these custom events work here now,
so confirm and cancel is the go.
For that, let's dive into our modal again and then we have these buttons, since these buttons are part of the shadow
DOM,
we have to create listeners to these buttons inside of our shadow DOM.
So for that, I'll add another constant here in the constructor below my slots listeners
I added in the last lectures and there, I'll have the cancel button
and for this, I'll give this button an ID of cancel button, maybe like this confirm button
and now I can select by that ID, so I'll access my shadow root, use the query selector,
you could also use get element by ID of course and then select a cancel button ID here and then I'll duplicate this
to also select my confirm button here with the confirm button ID.
So now that I have access to these two buttons, I can register listeners here in my component.
So let's maybe start with the cancel button here and on the cancel button, I want to hide the modal
and I want to dispatch this custom cancel event to which I'm listening from outside. Therefore, I'll
first of all add a new method here and I'll name it hide,
I could turn this into a private method by adding a leading underscore and always keep in mind, it's
not really private,
you can still call it from outside because Javascript knows no private and public properties and methods,
I just add this to show, hey this should only be used from inside, if you then don't follow that rule,
well you can do that
but here I want to keep it as a public method because even though we're not doing it in our app, you
could of course definitely imagine an application where you want to hide a modal from outside,
so from your main application instead from inside of the component.
Now how do we hide it?
Well in the end, it's all about setting our open attributes to none or to remove it
and we do that not with set attribute but with remove attribute and there,
I want to remove my opened attribute. We can add an extra check here to see if this has the attribute
opened before we then try to remove it of course.
Besides that, I want to set this is open to false of course to update this property as well
and with that, the modal will already be closed because of that opened attribute which we use in our
CSS styles here.
So therefore we have that functionality, the custom event is missing but I'll come back to that later,
so for now let's continue with the event listener on the cancel button in the constructor,
there we want to listen to an ordinary click
which of course is a built-in event built into core Javascript and the browser and upon a click, I want
to trigger this hide, so this hide method. And of course I'll bind this keyword here to ensure that
this inside of hide refers to the class and not to the button which is the event trigger. Now I'll duplicate this
to also hook up my confirm button and there,
I also want to hide this modal.
Now we already see a problem here,
I definitely don't want to run the same logic two times.
So what I will do instead is I'll add a private method here which I'll name cancel and I'll add one
which I'll name confirm. Now
in both, I will call this open and here, we don't need to bind this because if we're calling it like this
from inside the class, the class itself is calling a method and therefore this in the called method
will refer to the class too.
So I'll also call hide here,
sorry
here it should be hide of course, not open.
So it should be hide in both
but now we can dispatch different custom events here.
So let's tweak that and go up and for the cancel button,
I will now actually call my private cancel method and for confirm, my private confirm method
and right now, they will both just call hide but that will change soon.
So now with that, we should already have a working modal such that when I click cancel,
it gets hidden and if I open it again, I can also hide it and close it with ok.
And you can see I can reopen it even though I have extra check here in my main app, in my index.html
file where I check for whether it is not open yet with the isOpen property and I can still reopen
it after closing it because I do update
this isOpen property in my modal as well.
So this is the first important step
but the more important and more interesting step of course now is to emit our own custom event.
Let's do that next.