So now that we talked a lot about styling, let me make the style we have in place here a bit more pretty
now. Now for that,
I'll first of all, I'm going to my light DOM, add a star selector and set the global box sizing for all my border,
for all my elements to border box
and now I'm just really working on the visuals,
this is nothing else.
I'll set a font family of sans-serif
so that all my fonts have the sans-serif look,
looks a bit nicer already in my opinion.
I will also in my lights DOM, get rid of this ugly blue border around my tooltip, it was just for demonstration
purposes,
also get rid of the highlight class which we are not setting anything.
Let me also get rid of that div with the orange border and get rid of that orange border style up there,
I really just want to make this a bit more pretty
before we continue.
Now this looks much better already
and now let me dive into my web components styles and there for example, for this overlay when I hover
over this,
I want to add some padding here and make this look a bit nicer, maybe a little drop shadow.
So for this hovering content which of course is this div here
and we could of course also use this CSS class or ID here if we wanted to,
there I'll give this a padding of 0.15rem, border radius maybe of 3px and a box shadow
of 1px 1px 6px and then this styling which is a transparent gray-ish look, if I now reload
and I hover over this, box shadow is missing.
Yes because I forgot my colon here,
so let's fix this.
Yes
and this looks much nicer.
Let me also tweak the positioning, it has position absolute
but I want to move it down a little bit by setting top to
let's say 1rem and left also to 0.75rem maybe,
let's see how that looks like,
let's move it down by 2rem,
yes, maybe 1.5,
right.
I like this way more, looks better in my opinion.
Now I also don't want this text in there to be bold just because the overall component text is bold because
of host context,
so I will give my div here a font weight of normal.
So I don't use that bold font weight
I set for my other text, so now I don't have that bold styling in there anymore.
And now last but not least, there's one other thing. When I set this background color if I have the important
tag, then I also want to add a little bit of padding around my component let's say,
so that the color does not sit directly on the edges
and now this looks OK.
This is how I want it to be,
this is a style I can live with.
Now with that, let's move on and let's see which other cool functionalities we can add to our custom web components.