It's all nice that we have some functionality on our web component but it would now be nice to work
on the styling,
for example that this tooltip does not kind of split our line here but it should be like an overlay being
positioned next door near to our question mark here.
So how can we achieve this?
Well since we are creating our tooltipContainer here, we can of course also style that and there are
a couple of ways of styling that, since it's a div, we could set up some general styling for divs of course.
Alternatively, we access the style attribute and we add styles step by step,
for example on the tooltipContainer here, we can access the style property which every DOM Node has
in Javascript and we could give this a background color of black and then we duplicate this to set a text
color of white maybe. Now with that if we save that and we reload,
we have this style, a bit better but of course the positioning is still off.
Now we might want to make sure that this has an absolute position, so that our tooltipContainer style,
the position is absolute. That means that when it should be positioned relative to our entire custom
element, we should give our custom element a style of relative.
So in the connected callback where our custom element has been rendered to the DOM, there we can
access our style,
so the style of the custom element itself, the style of the uc-tooltip and there, we set the position
equal to relative.
If we now save that and we reload,
now this looks a bit better, doesn't split our line anymore.
Now maybe we also should set a set index here so that it is above all other elements, set index and set
this to a value of 10 maybe.
Now if you reload this, this looks better,
it now really is an overlay near to our question mark,
I'm liking this. So this already is a nice way but we also have a problem here.
If I for some reason have a general style in my page with style tags or a CSS file
which I import where I let's say style all my divs to have the border of 2px solid and orange. Now obviously
this is a bit of a made up example but you could certainly have some global styles affecting all divs
or all h1 tags and maybe in your custom web component, you are using a h1 tag
or as we are doing it, you are using a div
and now what you will see is that if I save that and I reload this page, I have that orange border
on that div in my web component too.
And you typically don't want that,
you typically don't want to have global styles affecting your web components and you also don't want
to have styles you define inside of your web components affect outside elements.
In addition, it would be nice if we don't have to create everything programmatically like this, with one
line of code after the other
and if we could define some HTML template, instead of well adding or creating HTML elements with
create element all the time and for that, we have a solution,
the shadow DOM and templates. Both these techniques will help us with ensuring that we write a nice, reusable
and encapsulated custom web component.