So with the styling cleaned up a little bit,
let's come back to some key functionalities we can add inside of our web components and there's one
thing which we haven't done at all thus far.
Thus far, the text for our tooltip always was set statically, which means we assigned it through this attribute
here but there was no way of changing that at runtime.
Now I do want to change it
and for that I of course need some logic that allows me to change it,
I'll simply do it in the developer tools for now because there, you have to keep in mind that I can of
course click into that text here, double click on it and I can set this to some new text but if I do
so and I hover over this, we still see the old text because changes to attributes are not picked up
inside of the web component.
And I want to highlight here that when I change this manually in the developer tools, this is no different
to this being changed through some Javascript code for example and that of course would be the more realistic
use case for your application where you for example listen to some user input and the text entered by
the user should end up here in the attribute
and I'm just not doing that because it requires some extra boilerplate code that has nothing to do with
web components,
so we'll just do that through manual editing here in the developer tools.
The problem is that right now, our changes don't get picked up
and that is what I want to change. For changing this,
I'll have to go back to my tooltip.js file
and there, I can add a new lifecycle hook which I did mention earlier in this course.
Do you remember which one that was that was? It was the attributeChangeCallback,
this executes when an observed attribute is updated and that observed part is going to become important
by the way.
So let's add it here, let's add the attributeChangedCallback method here and this method actually
receives three arguments, the name of the attribute which changed, the old value of that attribute and
now, the new value. Now in there, for now to keep it simple, let's simply output this. So I'll console log
the name, the old value and the new value
and if I do that, the expectation would be that when I reload this page and I come in here and change
that text to something new, if we then go to our console, we see an output there but this is actually empty
and the reason for that is that on the slide, I deliberately wrote observed attributes trigger this.
Now we're not observing any attributes right now,
this is simply a performance optimization
Javascript forces us to implement.
It does not by default watch all the attributes of this element because there might be a lot of elements
which can change which you don't care about in your component.
Let's say you are changing a class which you only use in the light DOM,
you're not interested in that class inside of the component then,
so why would you watch for changes?
Or maybe you are interested in the class inside of the component but only because you use it in the
styles here.
Well that will be picked up automatically then
but if you don't want to run any logic in Javascript, there is no need to trigger this.
So to get something into this callback or to trigger this callback for a specific attribute,
you have to tell Javascript that you're watching it and you do inform Javascript that you do care about
a certain attribute by adding a special property to your class here.
You do this by adding the static keyword, static simply means that it is a property or in this case, it
will be a getter function that can be called from outside without creating this class or an object
based on that class first, you don't have to care about that though because you will not be creating
it,
then you add the get keyword which simply means this is now a function that will return you a value
but you can't reassign a value to the property of this class which is hidden behind that getter
and then the name has to be observedAttributes and this is now written as a normal function or a method
here.
Now again, it might look a bit strange if you never heard about getters and setters and if you're
brand new to object oriented programming in general, the idea here is that this is like a property of
this class,
so like something we initialized with this in here but it's not, it is accessible from outside
and more importantly, it's not settable from outside,
you can only get the value here,
so this is like a locked down property. And in there, you return an array with all the attribute names
you want to listen to changes.
So here, I simply add text and I add text here as a string because I have my text attribute here.
I could of course also add class if I wanted to listen to changes to the class attribute or which ever
other attributes you might have
but you should only add here what you really care about.
And now with this added, I can save this and go back to my application and if I reload now and edit this text
again to something new and I go to the console, now we see output here, we actually see two because when
I first clicked into it and deleted the content, it registered this as a change too. This is the change we
just applied and there, we see the name of the attribute because remember, I am simply logging the name
and then the old value and then the new value,
so here we see the name of the attribute that changed, that was the text attribute. We see the old value,
that was this text and we see the new value which I entered, this one.
And now with that, we finally have a way of adjusting the code or the text we see here when we hover over
this and we'll do that in the next lecture.