So we ensured that the side drawer can be opened,
right now only through the dev tools, we'll  add a button soon and we're doing this only with the help
of attributes and CSS. This works and in many cases, this might be all you need.
There are also reasons why you might want to use it as or what might want to add it as a prop with the
prop decorator too though.
Now stencil will automatically check if an open attribute is valid and it'll synchronize this open property
to any value you might set to the open attribute.
This can be helpful if you want to be able to check the current status,
is it open or not?
You can now do this through this property, both from inside this component as well as from outside
and this can be useful when we add a button for opening the side drawer.
I will add this button here,
a normal button where I say open side menu and I will add some logic in my application script here so
to say, to the script in the index.html file to watch for clicks on this button. So I'll name this side
drawer button and I will use a query selector here and I will query for an ID which I assigned
to this button, sideDrawerButton,
you can of course use any ID you want,
I'll just query for that down there
and with that queried, I will add a click listener here, side drawer button,
add event listener
click and when I click this, I want to open my side drawer but I only want to do so when it's not
currently open. And for that, I will access the side drawer,
remember this gives me access to my web component because I select it by its tags here and there,
I can now check the open property, so I can check if side drawer open and do something if that is the
case or in my case, I check for the opposite by adding an exclamation mark and I check whether this is
not open and only if it is not open,
I'll try to open it and now I can open it in a couple of different ways.
For example I can now of course set open to true,
I could have also used set attribute or we add a method which we can call from outside
but more on that later, we haven't learned that yet,
so let's instead do it like this
and in my side drawer, I actually want to reflect changes to this prop back to my attributes, so I
will add the reflect to attribute configuration to this prop as well.
Now if I go back, we have this button and I get an error when I click it, that is an error I have in
my index.html file,
of course it's not this side drawer, side drawer is a normal constant here, so no need for this,
I'm not in a class here. So let's quit this and now this works. Now let me also show to you that is only
opens it once by for one
adding a console log here right before I call or before I set open to true, opening side drawer and I
also want to be able to click that button all the time. So I will make sure it is elevated above my side drawer
by setting its style, giving it a set index of 1000 and a background of black and a color of
white so that we can always see it and for the set index to have an effect,
I'll also give it a position of absolute and now if we reload, here it is.
Now it's always on top,
we'll change this soon
but now if I click this again, you'll see opening side drawer is not getting printed more than once
so it does indeed not open it again.
Now I'll remove all that styling here,
that was just for demo purposes.
So now we can indeed see that having this as a prop can be useful too,
also because now we can open the side drawer programatically here if we want to.