Now of course it's nice to be able to open the side drawer,
what about closing? In order to be able to close it,
I'll add something in the header of my side drawer,
I want to have like a close button there, so I will actually add a button, simply with the x on it
and now if we have a look at this,
can't even see it because it will be placed below the main menu
but it has a black text by default,
so we'll need to do some styling there,
let's quickly do that.
Go into my side drawer style file and here, for the header, I'll
add a special rule for my button header
and first of all, I want to position this in an absolute way,
so I'll set the position of my header to relative, so that absolute positions inside of it refer to
the header and then for the button, the position will be absolute and I'll put it in the top right corner.
So from the top we have no distance and from the right, we have no distance
and then here in the button now, I'll have a padding of let's say 1rem.
I'll have a text color of white,
I'll have a background which should be transparent and I'll add a fun size of let's say 2rem and now
let's have a look at that.
This is now how it looks like,
better not perfect,
let's remove the border by setting border to none and it's a little bit too big,
so I'll actually set the font size to 1.5rem and now we have this x button here which will do
for now.
Now when I click this button, I want to close my modal.
I also don't want to have that outline around it, so I'll set the focus state and this is all normal CSS
by the way in case you want to learn more about that,
have a look at my Complete CSS Guide,
I want to set that focus state and I want to set the outline of the button to none here so that this
orange outline goes away.
But now we have this button added, now with it being added,
I want to close my side drawer when we click it, right? Now for that and I will get rid of this comment here
because it takes up so much space, for that we can add a method, we can name it onCloseDrawer.
Now you can name these methods however you want but I like to name them in such a way if I trigger them
as a result or if I call them as a result of an event getting triggered from somewhere,
so then I like to have this on something naming convention here.
However ultimately, that naming is up to you and it's not like there is a single right or wrong way of
naming this.
So here onCloseDrawer is the name and in onCloseDrawer,
I want to, guess what? Close the drawer,
so I want to set this open equal to false, right because open is what controls the mode of this drawer.
Now we just need to hook this up to the button and there are various ways of doing that,
one of the simplest ways is to add onClick
here, written like this as an attribute to this button,
this is again supported by JSX,
then you have curly braces and then you point at the method of your class you want to use here,
so this and then onCloseDrawer
and you don't execute it so no parentheses are added.
You just point at it,
you just point at the reference or you pass the reference of your method to onClick and then it will
be executed for you when the button is clicked.
Now one important gotcha here,
we use this in onCloseDrawer and due to the way the this keyword works in Javascript, this would not refer
to the class when being called but to the button,
so we have to bind this here to make sure it always refers to class.
Now if we try that and we reload here, we open and we click this button,
we get a warning that the side drawer or this open property there can't be modified
and indeed, it did not close.
The reason for that is one important reason or thing you have to keep in mind. Props by default
are immutable, which means you can't change them from inside.
You can change them from outside,
we can set a new value here from the index.html file or manually in the dev tools but from inside
the component, you can't change the value because stencil has something which is called a uni-directional
dataflow which means data always only flows in one direction,
in this case from outside the component to inside the component. If we want to change it this inside,
we can do so by adding another configuration where we set mutable to true
and now we are allowed to change this and together with reflect to attribute, this change will even be
reflected back to our tag
in the DOM. So now if I save this and I reload and I open this, if I click this, it indeed closes and we get no warning
and if I inspect this in the dev tools,
so my overall element, you see open, the attribute is present.
If I click this button,
it is removed, so this reflect to attribute thing works there as well.
So this is how we can close it with the help of a click listener and our own method and the mutable
configuration which is a fine way of doing that
in this scenario but there is another way of changing data inside the component too.