So now that we learned more about attributes and how we can listen to changes,
let me come back to our general logic here in the web component.
For one, I noticed we still have a little redundant code in there,
here where I append this tooltipIcon,
to my shadow root,
this is simply not required anymore,
we have it here in the template.
So it is rendered by default,
so I can remove that and well, still have it there
but this was not the main part I wanted to focus on. Instead what we also can do,
we can clean up our event listeners
we got here.
Right now, we add these events listeners but we never clean them up.
Now it's always a good idea to clean up your stuff
when this component should ever be removed from the DOM and I can show you how it can be removed in
a second.
And for this, we have another lifecycle hook you learned about earlier,
we got the disconnectedCallback and this will be executed when the element is removed from the DOM.
Now let me simply output disconnected here for now
before we add any other logic and let's go back to our page and reload
and of course, we again could have some Javascript code which simply selects this element and removes
it, just as we by the way also remove our tooltipContainer here.
You can remove any node with remove child,
you just have to select the parent
of it and then get rid of it.
So we could get access to the paragraph and remove this child from it or here to simulate it in even easier
way, in the dev tools I can simply select it and hit the delete or backspace key and it's gone
and in the console, we see disconnected because this gets executed when this component gets removed from the
DOM
and of course for every component separately.
So that second tooltip, if I remove that, we see disconnected again,
now it was called twice or printed twice because it was printed for the two separate elements because they
are treated totally independent from each other. Now the disconnectedCallback
is a great place for cleanup work,
cancel any HTTP requests you might be doing, maybe send a log message to your own statistics server or
in our case, clean up the event listeners, the mouseenter and mouseleave listeners.
Now we can clean up these listeners by first of all storing the tooltipIcon reference here, not in
a constant because constants like variables are only accessible in the scope, so in the function in this
case, in the method where you define them, I want to access it from down there though so I have to turn
it into a class property
and we do that by simply storing it in one. And for that, simply to make it clear that we have such a class
property, I'll define one here _tooltipIcon to make sure it is seen as a private property
of this class.
It's uninitialized here and we wouldn't have to define it here first by the way,
I just want to have a definition here so that when you look at this component, we quickly see the properties
we're using but with it defined,
I can now use it and I can use it down there and store my span in the tooltipIcon property we just
initialized and replace all tooltipIcon
references here with references to my tooltipIcon property, class property and now we can go to
the disconnectedCallback and there, I can add remove listener, remove event listener, call this method and
I want to remove my mouseenter listener, so
let's add this here and the way remove event listener works is that we then also have to define the method
which was connected.
So for mouseenter, this was showTooltip like this, so we want to remove that and we want to do the
same for mouseleave and hide tooltip.
So I will just duplicate this, mouseleave, this hide tooltip.
And with that if I save all that and I go back and reload, if I select my component and remove it,
well we don't see anything here
but now we do our cleanup work,
we take advantage of the disconnectedCallback to clean up our event listeners here. Always a
good idea
but again you could do any cleanup work or any work in general you have in that method
here, in that lifecycle look.