So in this module, we built a more complex web component.
It has more features and we also learned some new things we can do in web components.
Our modal component extends a HTML element,
so it's not extending a built-in HTML element but this base HTML element. We used the shadow DOM and
then we have our template here with a lot of styles being scoped to it.
Our component actually consists of two parts, the backdrop and the modal, backdrop is in the background, modal
in the foreground.
We've got multiple slots and they're named slots to make sure we can pass in content into these different
slots from outside,
we also have a listener to slot changes which doesn't do much here but which shows you how you can react
to changes in your slot content
and for example how you also can get access to the content that is rendered in your slots.
We learned about attributes and how we can use them, not only to listen to changes to them but also
in our CSS styles which can give us a very convenient way of updating the look of our web component
based on some external stylings.
And we had to look at custom events, how we can dispatch them, how we can configure them with bubbles
and composed
and of course, how we can listen to them from outside our component with normal event listeners.
Last but not least, we also worked with some public properties and methods, really something that can
be helpful to allow you to not just reach or interact with your component through attributes but by directly
accessing a property or by directly accessing a method.