Let's say in our side drawer, we actually want to have two tabs.
One tab has these links and the other tab has some information about our page,
something like the imprint contact information,
anything like that. For that let me
first of all add a little tab toggle here.
So above the main section, I'll add a section, may give it an ID maybe of tabs, you can name this however
you want
and in there, I'll have two buttons.
I'll have my button with the text navigation and one with contact.
Now if I save that, this is how it looks like,
let's change the styling a little bit.
So I'll go to my side drawer here,
select the tabs. Here I'll use flex box to justify my content in the center and I'll select my buttons
here to give them an equal width
essentially, both should have a width of let's say 30% of the available width, the tabs
overall have 100% of the width of the side drawer and each button should have a background color of
transparent let's say or of white maybe, text color of black, text should be aligned in the center
in the button, I want to have a border of 1px solid and black and the font should be inherited,
so that it takes the same font family as the rest of the page. With that, whoops, I should change this
by the way to
ID selector tb, so #tabs of course.
So with that if I go back, this looks a little bit better.
Now for the overall tabs, I want to have some margin to top and bottom, 0 to left and right but now
just to have some distance and then in my buttons, I also want to have some padding,
so I'll give this a padding to top and bottom of .15rem, 0 left or right because I have a fixed width
with text centering
anyways and this doesn't look too bad.
Now I have these two tabs there.
Now let's also make sure we have an active tab and that we can change it,
the active tab should have some identifier, maybe a class named active or an attribute named active, whatever
you want
and then we can use that in CSS so that we say ok, in my tabs, a button with the active class, that
should actually have a background of black and a text color of white,
so basically inversed.
And now if I go back, we see that first one is active and if we click the other one, that should of course get active
and I want to be able to toggle between there and show different content based on the button that is
selected. For that, I'll just tweak that rule a little bit more quickly to have styles
when I hover over a button or I click it,
so I'll add my hover state and I'll also add my active state but that's just a little side note.
Now one last style I want to add here is that for my button here, when I focus them, then there should
be no outline. With that, we're done,
now I got these nice buttons, I can click them but of course nothing happens when I do so,
so we'll add the logic together in the next lecture.