The styling works but of course we want to be able to listen to clicks on these buttons and we want
to change our content
we show here based on the button click and for that, we need a couple of building blocks.
First of all, we need different content to show. So in the render function, I'll have my main content variable
and
by default, that is my slot element.
Now here I can simply output main content between curly braces and we will have the same output as before
but I want to have an alternate content which I might show when we switch to the contact information.
Then main content maybe is between parentheses, so that we can write multiline JSX code, maybe is a h2
tag where I say contact information and let's wrap that all into a div
because we must have one top level element there, we could add an array but let's go for this solution now
and below that, we have you can reach us via phone or email
and then I have an unordered list with a couple of list items where I have phone, some random number, an email and then
we have mail to something@something.com, something@something.com.
Now this main content is now what we display there because we always override our main content to that
but of course we want to do that conditionally only when we change the second tab.
By the way, I'll just quickly give this a contact information ID
to add some padding to it to make it look a little bit nicer,
so contact information will receive up padding of zero top and bottom
but 1rem left and right but that is just the styling,
we want to work on the logic. Now for that,
we need a click listener on our buttons here,
so on these two buttons, we need to be able to listen to clicks and we need a method that we can execute
to then do something upon such a click.
So here I'll have the onContentChange handler maybe, you can name this however you want
and there, we want to execute some logic that we can then use down there in the render method to, well
output or something or to display different content conditionally. Well first of all, let's hook up these
buttons with onClick listener
and for the first one, I want to target onContentChange and I want to pass an extra argument to
onContentChange. I want to have information about which content should be shown, which button was clicked,
do I want to show the contact information or the slot content?
So I expect to get some content there
and let's say this is a string. We're using Typescript right,
so it is a good convention to define the types of things when we don't define a default value
and here we got no default value,
so here I will be very clear about the fact that I expect a string here.
So when I call onContentChange there, since we don't call it with parentheses, we can pass an argument
like this but we have to bind this anyways
and the bind method takes more than one argument, where the other arguments are passed in as arguments to the
function we're calling.
So here I can pass in nav maybe and then I'll just copy that and add it to my second button as well
and there, I will pass in contact, like this.
Just restructured it,
these are two buttons,
first one onClick passes nav as an argument,
second one passes contact.
So now this function should execute and I can for now console log this to see if it works.
If I save that and I go back and I open my Javascript console and I reload to clear it, if I click navigation,
you see nav here, if I click contact, you see contact.
But of course we don't change the output and
that is something we'll do in the next lecture.