That is something we can achieve with a concept called state.
Now if you know React, you know state, if you don't, you'll learn it now. Props are properties in this class
which can be set from outside and the prop decorator, just to bring this back in memory does one important
thing. We can use properties without it
but with it, stencil watches for changes in the props and re-runs render such that it changes in the real
DOM what needs to be changed based on the prop update. Props
as I also mentioned are there to listen to changes to your properties coming in from outside.
Now what if you want to listen to changes from inside?
You can use mutable as we did here but if you only expect changes from inside, you should absolutely
use a different decorator,
the state decorator. You import that from @stencil/core too and state also simply is added in
front of one of your class properties and here,
I'll name this showContactInfo and you can name it however you want,
I'll set it to a boolean and you can definitely find different implementations as well.
So now, this is a property which we can also initialize with a default value by the way,
equals false
let's say to by default show not the contact information
and if you have a value assigned, you don't need to assign the type because Typescript can then infer
it
but most importantly, this is now a property which is also watched by stencil but it does not
watch for changes coming in from the outside but from inside
and if you change showContactInfo, it will also rerun render and update it in the parts where you need
to update it.
So now we can simply change showContactInfo from inside onContentChange by setting this.showContactInfo
equal and then I check if content is equal to contact,
right,
that is one of the two values we pass in, contact is one of the values.
So if this is contact, then this should be true and the result of this check already is true,
so we can simply set it to that. If content equals contact,
we'll set this.showContactInfo to true and the result of this is true and if it is false, it will automatically
be set to false here.
Now we don't need to do anything else,
if you are coming from React, you are used to having to call setState.
That is not required in stencil, you just change the property like this
and thanks to the state decorator, stencil automatically picks up that change.
So now with that in place, we can use the showContactInfo property here to render content conditionally
and we'll see if this.showContactInfo is true, in which case I'll then set my main content variable
to this contact information
otherwise it will stay at its default which is the slot content.
So now if I reload this and I open the side menu,
we see the links by default but if I click on contact, we see that. Now
the remaining piece of work we have to do is that we update these buttons correctly and that simply
means I want to set my class here, depending on this showContactInfo property and for this, I'll simply
bind this class here to a dynamic value with curly braces
and I'll check
showContactInfo and if it is true, then I know I don't
mark this as active but if this is not true, then I know this here will get the active class because then
we're in the slot mode which is my navigation
here
otherwise I add no class and I do the same on the other button of course.
There I also add this class now, here I check for whether showContactInfo is true though, in this case
I'll add active to the second button
or I will not add it
and now with this in place, you can see we can toggle these buttons too.
And now we're also using state which is the right solution
whenever you update data from inside the component, as we are doing it here.