So let's build another component,
I'll do that in the components folder, add a new sub-folder and I'll name that stock finder.
Create a stock-finder.tsx file in there and also a stock-finder.css file for the styling and
create a component just as we did it before, export a class, StockFinder and give it to that @ component
decorator which is imported from @stencil/core. In there,
assign a name, a tag,
ucStockFinder in my case, I will point at my style URL of course and I will use the shadow DOM
here by setting shadow to true, right.
So now we have that component set up,
obviously we now also need a render method here and in that render method,
I'll return an array again and there,
I want to add an input box and a button where the user can enter the name of a company for example and
then below that, I want to output a list of search results.
Now for that, I can actually reuse this input box and the button I have in my stock price component.
Obviously feel free to also the pause the video and do this all on your own now
of course, I will just grab that form and move that over into my stock finder here
as a first element.
Now of course on submit, I'll do something different here and I will keep the reference actually but
I'll not use that value, I'll not use that
two-way binding, I'll not add any validation here.
You can definitely do that if you want to, I'll keep this a bit simpler and that button here, I'll also not
as I've just said, have any validation, so it'll never be disabled.
I'll find elements here, so I'll add the caption find here to the button and then here, I have my stock name
input property, that is to which I want to bind here,
whoops, it's not a string though, it's a HTML input element of course. So that is which I bind here
with this reference
and then I need to add a method, onFindStocks.
This will be what I execute when we submit this, so this onFindStocks, bind the this to make sure the this
keyword works correctly in this method.
There we get an event object and I will call even prevent default to prevent default of this built-in form
element, this HTML built-in form element
and thereafter, I want to send a request to an API which finds me all fitting stock symbols. And for
that, we can go into the alphavantage documentation and
there we have this search endpoint and we have some examples below which shows us how we can search for
company names or symbols and hopefully get helpful results.
So here, I'll just copy that and point this URL and I want to send a request with the fetch API to
this endpoint. Again I'll use back ticks here so that I can inject dynamic values like my API key, so let me import
this,
this already shows the advantage of having it in a global file.
If I ever change it, I don't need to change it in different components,
I just need to change it in that global file and there, I will import my AV_API_KEY and use that instead
of demo down there.
And then the search keyword,
well that of course should be whatever the user entered into the stock name input. So I'll extract that
here, stock name equals this.stockNameInput.value.
Obviously I have no validation,
so this could be empty but that's fine for me here
and then I'll replace the bi dummy here with this, not with this but just with the stockName constant
here.
Now let me add then and catch and let's see what we get here.
So then gives me the response, you can add error handling
as you learned, I'll just extract the JSON response, I'll use the shorthand version of this arrow
function where if you only have one expression after the arrow, you can omit the curly braces and this
will automatically return the result of this expression and then here, I'll therefore have the parsed
response and I will simply console log this for the moment
and yes you could add a catch error handler here to handle any errors you might be getting in whichever
way you want. I'll just log them to the console.
Now with this, with everything in place for us to start using that component, the ucStockFinder,
so let's head over to index.html and add this next to our ucStockPrice
and obviously this will not have any styling or anything like that but if I now reload my component,
I have this input.
Let's now open the Javascript console in the developer tools, clear it and then let's search for BMW
and indeed, we find an object with a best matches key which is an array of objects where each object
has a symbol
and BMW just seems to be listed on different exchanges,
hence we get multiple hits here
but this generally seems to work.
Now obviously we don't want to output it here in the Javascript console in the developer tools, we want to output it
in the DOM and that is what we'll work on the next lectures.
Now first of all in the very next lecture, we'll add some styling.
You don't have to skip it,
it will be very fast as you will see and thereafter we'll work on outputting the search results.