So let's add a little bit of styling here,
I will actually grab the styling of my form related parts from the other component and yes, you could
certainly reuse that in some shared component, we'll dive into the shared components later,
for now let's copy that
and on the finder itself, I will copy that host selector and also use that here
and use that exact same styling here.
So I actually have two totally equal styles here,
if I reload, you can see it here and that is ok for me here
and as I just mentioned, you could of course also like build a wrapper component with the shared styles and
only change the logic.
You could certainly merge a lot of functionalities and styles together here,
here I have a separation on purpose and I will show you how to embed components into components at
a later point of time.
So now we have a more beautiful styling, that is the most important thing,
that was not too much work I guess.
And with that, let's move on and let's actually add logic to output the results below this input and
the button.