Now what is missing on that side drawer? The backdrop, right
we have no backdrop which we could click to close it,
we only have that close button, close button is nice but a backdrop would be nicer.
Now of course, we can add one and you actually have two routes here,
you can integrate and backdrop into your side drawer component to have side drawer component that has
everything it needs to fully work or you have a general backdrop in your main app and you control it
with your logic there.
Now since we're building web components with stencil, I'll integrate a backdrop into my side drawer
and for that, I want to have an element next to my aside. If I add a div here next to aside and give
it a class of backdrop,
then I get an error.
We actually can't have two top level JSX elements sit next to each other like this.
Good thing is you can easily have it if we add an array though, if we return an array though,
so if we return two items in an array.
So we add a comma after the div and then we have the aside, certainly looks strange at first but actually
it's just an array of Javascript code, of JSX elements in this case
and now we can have both the backdrop and the aside.
Now of course we just have to do the styling and for that, I'll add a new style in my side-drawer.css
file, backdrop and I'll give this a fixed position as well, just as the side-drawer, top zero, left zero
a width of 100% and a height of 100vh. Give it a background color of transparent black color
with 75% opacity, 25% transparency therefore
and let's give this a set index of let's say 10 and to make sure that the side drawer is above it,
I'll give my side drawer a set index of 100. With that if I reload, here's the backdrop,
it's always visible because currently we have no logic that would only render it when the opened attribute
is set
but of course we can change this. Just as I only show my side drawer with opened being present,
I can do the same here.
So I look for this opened attribute on my host element and if that is present, then on my backdrop, I
change something to make it visible.
There are various ways of doing that,
one possible way of hiding it is to set the display to none here so that the element is not added to
the document flow by default
and then I set the display to block here when we have opened. With that if I go back,
indeed there is no backdrop and I can click this button and now it appears and the side menu opens.
Of course maybe we want a little animation there too,
for that we can give this an opacity of zero by default and show it with opacity of one, then we should also
make sure that pointer events are not caught here though, only when it is visible otherwise we can't
click through it
and of course we want to give it a transition where we animate the opacity with an easeOut timing
function over let's say 300 milliseconds. With that, now this animates in smoothly.
Nice.
Now of course we don't register clicks on it though
to close our side menu and definitely feel free to pause the video and build such a functionality on
your own,
it is a nice practice afterall but we can also do it together of course.
Here's your chance to pause the video,
to try it on your own,
were you successful?
Let's try it together. We want to click on the backdrop and then hide the entire side drawer.
Well it's actually not that difficult,
we have the onCloseDrawer method here and this changes opened to false.
Well all we have to do is we have to register a click here on the backdrop and upon that click, I call
this onCloseDrawer and I bind the this keyword and that should already be all. With that in place,
now we can open that, click anywhere on the backdrop and that closes it
and now we have a nice working web component with our code here. And I hope you already see how does
this is much cleaner code than what we had to write here manually for our component with vanilla Javascript
and this is exactly one part where stencil helps you and always keep in mind that the output is an optimized
vanilla Javascript web component though, optimized in the sense of it automatically loads all your polyfills
you might need
and so on.