So that's it for this module. You learned a lot about the basics of web components, that there are two
ways of creating them, by extending HTML element or a specific HTML element like the anchor element.
That you can have a constructor in which you always have to call super
first where you can do some basic initializations and where you can also set up your shadow DOM if you
want to use it which you often want because it gives you a lot of advantages, where you can then if you
use the shadow DOM also initialize the template, the HTML code of the shadow DOM or if
you're using a HTML template which we're not doing anymore here
but if you were to use that, you could get access to it here,
it would not be rendered by default in the HTML element
and instead you could read it here and then assign it to your shadow DOM. That you can use something like
slots in your template no matter if you use the in Javascript template here or to one in the
HTML file. That you also have some lifecycle hooks of which we only used one, we'll see the other hooks later.
We used the connectedCallback and that there is one important thing about the connectedCallback, at
this point of time our custom element will have been added to the real DOM,
so if we want to do DOM manipulations on our element, not on its shadow DOM, that is possible earlier
but on the element itself or if you want to get access to its attributes for example, we have to do that
in the connectedCallback. That you can add properties and methods to your class which you can then call
from other places as we do it here, That you have to register your own elements with the custom elements
define method where you then choose your own tag name which has to have at least one dash in it to ensure
it's not clashing with the built-in elements and that you should choose a unique name here. And that you
then just have to import your style, your scripts excuse me and then you can start using your elements
like this
or in case you are extending a specific element, like this. This is basically what you learned here.
Now there is more to custom components, to custom elements and we will learn more about that over the
next lectures and modules but this is a crucial set of basics that should now be clear and that already
allows you to build some nice web components.