So in this module, we learned a lot about the stencil basics.
Stencil has more to offer,
also more decorators to offer than what you saw thus far but you learned about the core crucial
decorators and features stencil offers you when it comes to building nice web components and I hope
you already start to see the advantage of using stencil.
We have very clean code here,
we get a lot of magic done behind the scenes, like the watchers for state and prop changes and I hope
you also get the core idea behind stencil. Being declarative,
we write our template here and we have dynamic parts like this title which stencil automatically updates
for us when title changes
as long as it's a prop or state. That we have a very clean way of defining our methods, that we explicitly
have to define methods that should be callable from outside and that we have the special magic render
method which stencil uses heavily behind the scenes to update the DOM based on changes triggered through
props or state.
It can be strange to get started with JSX at first,
think about it as Javascript with a twist and therefore when you for example want to output conditional
content, so content A when a certain condition is true and content B if it is not,
you just use the normal Javascript features like if statements to output content under a different
condition.
This is stencil.js
in a nutshell or the basics about stencil.js,
there is way more we can do with it of course and there is way more we'll dive into in the next course
modules.