We're emitting a custom event and we're listening to it here in our web application. How can we now do that
directly from inside another component though and that would not be an uncommon use case?
Let's say you have a set of web components you're sharing and each of them should work standalone but
you still can add some utility functionality to make sure they can work together seamlessly in case
they are used both on the same page
and that is exactly what I want to have here. When we select a stock here in the stock finder,
I want to automatically update it here in the stock price component.
Now of course I could update the attribute here from inside this code since I already have the symbol,
it's an event detail here as you learned
but this is not what I want to do,
I want to listen to that event from inside that other component
and how can we do that now?
Now for this, we'll go into the stock price which is where I went to listen and there, I will first of
all add a new method. I'll do that here below my lifecycle hooks above my fetchStockPrice method and I'll
name this onStock symbol selected and here,
I will get event data of type custom event, custom event has a built-in type and there, I can check if
event detail is set, if there is any data in event detail and if event detail is unequal to this stock symbol,
so the current stock symbol,
if that is the case, then I want to fetch the stock price for event detail which should be assembled
in.
Now the question just is, how do we make sure that this gets triggered whenever the stock symbol changes,
whenever we select a stock symbol in that other component? We do this by adding a special decorator, the listen
decorator which needs to be imported from @stencil/core. The listen decorator allows us to listen to
any events emitted. You pass the event name here between the parentheses,
in my case that is ucSymbolSelected
right,
that is the name we're emitting here
in that other component. Now whenever this is emitted, onStockSymbolSelected should execute.
So here I'll just log StockSymbolSelected and maybe output that symbol plus events detail. If I now
save this and I reload,
if I search for BMW here, clear the console and I select this first element, we see nothing in the console
and it doesn't change up there, right.
The reason for that is that by default,
listen listens for events emitted inside of the render function, so of the DOM, of the shadow DOM belonging
to this component
and obviously we're not using the stock finder component in here,
we're using it as a sibling to the stock price, not inside of the DOM of the stock price component. So
to ensure that we can still listen to this,
I need to add body: in here in front of the event name, this tells stencil that it should listen for
this globally
and if our other event bubbles up to DOM tree, all the way to the body element and you might remember that events
can bubble up in Javascript and in the stock finder, we set bubbling to true,
so it will indeed bubble up, then at some point if not stopped, it will reach the body Node and then we
can listen to that with this prefix and
this only works with the body by the way.
So now with that if we save again, let me enter BMW and select BMW here and you see the price updates.
Now to also update the ticker up there,
all I need to do is in the stock price component, we'll also update the ticker. Now to update that value,
we just have to change our logic here a little bit in the listen function,
I'll set this stock symbol equal to event detail here.
Remember that we have a watcher for the stock symbol property up there,
so this will fire whenever we change this to a new value and it will then automatically fetch the new
value from the API. Here by the way I should also set the validity to true and with that, if we now reload this
and I search for BMW again, if I select BMW, it gets updated here and the price as well.
So now we have this cross component communication with the help of custom events and the very helpful
listen decorator which does not just work with custom vendors
by the way,
you can also listen to built-in events like click events.
It just might be hard to identify the right element,
so therefore for built-in events or whenever you're listening to the event directly thrown from inside
the rendered JSX code,
I personally prefer to use onSubmit and onInput and so on.
It's also worth noting that for onSubmit for example it wouldn't even work if you listened to the summit
event with the @listen decorator because the listen decorator basically waits for the event to bubble
up all the way to the host element
and that would already lead to the default behavior of the form element being executed which is to reload
the page or to send a request and then reload the page upon the submit event. For other events like clicking
or input,
it would work but then again, it might be hard to find out on which exact element that event occurred
or to which elements you want to restrict your @listen decorator.
So I mostly use it for custom events.