For fetching the stock data, I'll use an open API from alphavantage. You can simply google for alphavantage
and you should find that page, alphavantage.co.
Now the API on this page is free to use but you need to get an API key by registering, so it will not
cost you anything but they want your email address,
if you don't want to give that away, you can of course just follow along here with the videos but you'll
not be able to follow along and code of course.
So let's click on get your free API key here and fill in these fields,
choose your role, for example student, the organization you are working in,
simply enter your name if you don't have one for example and then your email address and you'll get
that API key thereafter.
Now I already went through these steps, so I already have my API key and therefore, I can already go to
the documentation there to learn how to use the API and I can only recommend to dive into that if you want
to play around with it,
in the end you'll find a couple of URLs here to which you can send get requests to get different
kinds of data and you should include your API key
but we'll do all of that together in this course. We'll start with this quote endpoint here,
so with this, API URL will start and what this will give us in the end is simply the data for a given
symbol, for a given stock,
for example here in Microsoft and there, we'll be extracting that 05 price field later which is the
latest price of this stock and that is what I want to display.
So this is what we'll use. Now with that, let's start using it, let's start adding some logic here
and as you learned, we definitely need a render function. In that render function,
I want to render an input where the user can insert a symbol and we'll later add another component that
helps with finding these symbols,
so we'll add an input where users can enter this symbol and then, we'll add a place where we output that
price of course and potentially also some error message if we don't find a symbol.
So let's first of all add these two things by returning an array here because I want to have two sibling
top level elements which is only possible by passing them in an array and there for one, I'll have a
normal input and that input can of course be self-closing here and that input will be or
I'll give it an ID,
stock symbol and I also will have my output area which
let's say is a div here and in that div, I'll have a paragraph where I say price and then thereafter,
I want to output the price.
I'll just plug in a zero here but of course later, we'll reference some property of our class here.
Now what is missing?
Well we need one other element,
we need a button where the user can confirm the symbol picked and I'll add this in a div where I wrap
both the input and the button.
So here I'll have my div and next to my input,
I have a button where I say fetch and we could wrap this in a form here.
Let's actually do that, makes sense I guess, to use a form instead of a div
and now when this form get submitted, so I'll set this here to type submit, this button which is a default
type built into HTML, so that this form gets submitted when this button gets pressed,
we want to listen to the form submit and fetch that input value here.
That will be the first step because that will allow us to, as a next step, fetch our price.