Enough of the talking, let's dive into learning more about custom elements for now,
so about the core part of web components and let's write some code.
First of all, it's important to differentiate that for custom elements,
we actually got two different ways of creating them.
For one, you can create so-called autonomous elements,
these are basically your own custom elements that don't depend on anything, that are totally independent
of existing HTML elements that are built into the browser.
Alternatively, you can also create your own custom elements by extending built-in elements though, like
extending the built-in button or the built-in paragraph and that also can be a way of creating custom elements.
In this course, we'll mostly build autonomous elements but I actually will show you both ways of creating
your own custom elements, your own web components and I will use the name custom element and web component
interchangeably here, so you can build custom HTML tags in both ways and I will show you both ways and
both are fine to use depending on what you're building.
Often you want to have your totally separate custom element though,
so this autonomous way is probably the more common way
but how do you build your own web components in that way then? For that, I created a new folder anywhere
on your computer, you can create it,
it's totally empty as you can tell and I'll open it or I open it with Visual Studio Code.
Visual Studio Code
is a free web development IDE which you can get from code.visualstudio.com. On code.visualstudio.com,
you'll find download links for all operating systems and you can simply walk through the installer
there and you'll have a great, powerful and free web development IDE or editor which you can, well use
for editing.
Theoretically you just need any editor, any text editor but an IDE like this gives you more convenient
options, auto-completion and all that fun stuff. You can learn more about it by reading the official docs
and of course you can use any web development editor you want to use or any IDE you want to use.
Now in here, I did one important thing,
if you hit control shift P or on Mac, command shift P, you'll open this command menu here and here if
you type theme, then you'll find these preferences color themes option
and there, I switched to dark plus which is the theme which gives me this dark look, you can of course
also use other themes here.
And I did one other thing,
if you go into the extensions part by clicking on view extensions here, there if you search for material
icon, you'll find that material icon theme which I also installed, this is totally optional,
it just changes some of my file icons
once we start adding files to the project.
So if you want to get that same file icon look I have,
you have to install and enable that material icon theme. Thereafter you can go back to your explorer view
here.
OK.
So this is now the view in which we'll work
and there, I will add two files.
The first one is an index.html
file,
theoretically you can name it anything you want and this will be the dummy page we use for hosting
and running our own custom elements.
There I'll just type HTML
and now in Visual Studio Code, I get this auto-completion where I can pick that HTML5 template and
if I now hit enter, I get a basic HTML5 skeleton here out of the box.
I'll give it a title of web components
and now here in the body, we can start playing around with our own web components.
The code for the web components will be written in a different file and here, I will add a tooltip.js
file because I want to start by writing a tooltip component.
So this is now the file where I will write the code, the Javascript code to create my own custom element
and therefore, I will add one more thing here, in the index.html
file,
I'll add a script tag in the head section where I simply import that tooltip.js file and
thereafter, this will automatically run any code we add in that tooltip file and we will add some code
here to define our own custom element and that is exactly what we do in the next lecture.