Now let's work a bit on the styling and the thing which I explained in the last lecture,
the fact that our slotted content is not actually part of the shadow DOM has one important implication.
If we go back to our code,
I'm talking about this web components text here of course,
it's not part of the shadow DOM as I now mentioned multiple times.
This means that I can style this through the light DOM,
so through the styles set up in the light
DOM and I want to do exactly that right now.
Just format this a little bit
and now here to make it really clear that I can style it from outside,
I'll wrap this in a span, simply so that I have a tag, a selector which I can use in my light DOM CSS
and I will give this a class of let's say highlight.
Let's say this is a class we have in our default page styles,
in this case here, I have my highlight class selector
and again really important to recognize that this is now all happening in the light
DOM, this is not the scoped styling in the web component,
it's our normal styling in our normal page
and that could of course also be done in an external CSS file.
And let's say for the highlight style here, I typically assign a background color of yellow,
maybe not this yellow but maybe like a light lime yellow here, like this
or actually so that you can see it a bit better,
let me go with a light orange,
I guess that's a bit easier to see.
Now when I save that and I reload this page, you'll see that this is getting this light orange background
and again this is not some styling set up in the web component,
it is general styling set up in my HTML page
and again, this could also be in an external style file.
So my styles here still apply because this span here which holds my text is part of a light DOM,
not of a shadow DOM and I can make this even clearer if I dive into my tooltip and there into the
styling for the shadow DOM and there,
let me also add a highlight class selector,
now in the styles
of the shadow DOM and let me give this a background of red.
So here I have a background color, so let's make this equal even though it wouldn't make a difference but
now a background color of this light orange in the light DOM and a background color of red in the shadow DOM.
And please be aware or see that this is the exact same CSS selector,
so we have a class selector here too in the shadow DOM.
And now if I reload my page here, we still have the orange style
and if inspect this span here and we have a look at how the styling gets applied,
we see there also is no other styling getting applied except for this orange background color.
So it's not like this would be overwriting the shadow DOM styles,
the shadow DOM styles simply don't matter here because it is not part of the shadow DOM
and I'm just emphasizing this because this is so important, that has an important implication for styling.
Now of course though, you could have the use case that you do want to style your slotted content from
inside the shadow DOM because you might be creating a web component that should very well set up
some default styling for the projected content,
so for the content that's passed into slots. And how could you solve that then?