I want to start by building a side drawer and we will build that step by step.
Now a side drawer in case you're not sure, simply is this side menu which can slide in when we press
a button. And for that, I will create a new folder in my components folder and I will name it side-drawer,
you can name it whatever you want but I typically name the folder simply as the component I'm going
to store in it and I have one folder per component rule because in my opinion that keeps the project
more organized but you can also place all your component files in one and the same folder.
So in the side-drawer folder, I'll create a side-drawer.tsx file. TSX simply stands for Typescript
combined with that JSX syntax stencil uses.
Now in that file, we'ill create all the logic for this side-drawer component and a new component in stencil
simply is a class just as it is in vanilla javascript.
Now I will name this SideDrawer and the convention here is to name classes like this,
so the name of your component, the same name you have in your file and folder
if you're using a folder but without a dash and capitalized or with a starting capital characters for
all the sub-words in that overall word, so side and drawer both start with capital characters. And that
does not extend HTML elements, so we don't write this, instead we're already done here.
This extending will be done by stencil in this build process, it will transform our code here into a
vanilla web component code
in the end and there it'll do this extension, so we don't do it here. Now to tell stencil that this class
here should become a web component because we could maybe also create a class that we use differently
in our code,
classes are just blueprints for objects, so we could write other classes too that are just used to then
manually instantiate objects in our code.
So for the stencil, that this class should be converted to a component, we add a so-called decorator. Decorators
start with an @ and are a Typescript language feature,
they might become reality in vanilla javascript too in the future but right now, Typescript supports
them. There
we add the @ component decorator and you execute this like a function,
so you add parentheses after it.
Now this needs to be imported because Typescript is a language that is strongly typed and if you are
using a special type or a special class, then you need to tell Typescript where it finds the definition
for this class or for this type and you do this with an ES module import. Now ES module imports are a
part of modern javascript and such an import looks like that. You add the import keyword,
then curly braces and then from and then the path of the file where this type or class or function
or whatever you are importing is defined.
Now this could be one of your own files but the component decorator is exposed by the stencil toolset,
so we actually import from @stencil/core and we don't just import nothing which we currently do
but instead here between the curly braces, we state what we want to import. And stencil exposes a couple
of types and functionalities, a couple of decorators and one of them is the component decorator,
so we simply add that here and then we can add it here without getting an error.
Now this is the first step towards turning this into a component
but we're not done,
we need to pass a configuration object to that decorator. So we add curly braces inside of the parentheses
to simply pass a javascript object as an argument because behind the scenes, decorators are really just
functions, functions that are able to interact with the code that comes after them,
in this case with the class and stencil will do all the heavy lifting and all the magic behind the scenes,
it will basically attach some metadata to this class
behind the scenes. Now in this object we configure, how this component can be used and how it should work
and one must-have property here is the tag property.
There you set a string and there, you define the tag by which you will be able to use that component.
If you compare this to our custom vanilla javascript component which we created in the last modules,
there we also defined our own tag when we defined this component.
Now basically, stencil will do this definition for us and we tell it which tag it should use for defining
that.
So here, the same convention as before applies,
your tag must have at least one dash and it should have a prefix that turns it into a unique tag,
so I will stick to my uc- naming convention and I'll name it
uc-side-drawer.
Now we can use this component because now we have a tag here and this is the bare minimum configuration
we need,
now the bare minimum configuration for this component tag at least. To turn this into a valid component,
we also need to have one other thing, we need to have a render method here.
Now we simply add it like this,
this is a function inside of the class and such functions are called methods and this render method
has to be named render.
Now again before in our own component, we could add a render method and we did so in other components,
not in this modal but in other components but there. we could name the methods as we wanted.
There were little reserved name, attributesChangeCallback was an exception.
Render is an exception
in a class turned into a web component by stencil.
This is a method stencil will execute for us to parse the DOM
it should generate as part of this component and in render,
you have to return this JSX code and this is really just a special javascript syntax that can be
translated into DOM write instructions
so to say by stencil.
So here we could start simple with a div and in that div, we have like a h1 tag where we say the side
drawer and obviously we'll add more useful logic later.
Now I reformatted this with a shortcut in my IDE which simply converts it to this code
but again, it's still a wrapping div with this h1 tag in there and for now, please be aware that it would
not work if you have a sibling div next to that,
you must have one root element here.
There are ways around that,
you could return an array with multiple elements
but for now, let's simply stick to that one root element.
Now with that, we have our valid component.
Now one thing is missing and we're getting an error here and that is that we defined this class in our
file here
but in order to use it outside of this file, we need to export it which we do by adding an export statement.
Now of course we did not do that for our custom components here
when we used vanilla javascript. Typescript requires us to add this export here because Typescript the
way it works, bundles several files together and therefore, it needs to be able to pull all these files
together and it does so with import and export statements and just as we import our component here by
exporting our custom class here, stencil behind the scenes is able to pull all things together in the build
process. And therefore, about decorators being an experimental feature,
that is an IDE bug here though, it should work and indeed it does,
we got no error down there at the terminal,
so now I can actually start using this and I can use this component by this tag.
Let's do that in the index.html file which is our playground for testing our components.
So there, I will simply add my own component,
save that again and if I now go to this HTML file or to my browser window that opened when we ran
npm start, it should have automatically reloaded and we see the content of our own custom component and
these are the basic steps we always take when we create a new component with stencil.
Now there is way more we can do of stencil, way more
we can configure and way more logic stencil helps us with
but this is the basic process of creating a new component.