Well if you want to style slotted content, there is a special selector you can use inside your web component,
so inside your shadow DOM styling and that is a special pseudo-selector, ::slotted. This will select
all slotted content and the way it works is that you call this like a function here in CSS and to it,
you pass the selector of the slotted content,
so now you could say I want to select all slotted content that has the highlight class or all slotted
content that is a span or an anchor tag,
so anything like that. Important though, you can only select the slotted content itself.
So if for example in my slotted content here in this span, I also had an anchor tag in there,
then what you could not do,
you could not select slotted and then the span, this would still work because the slotted content is
the span but you can select the child element in the top level slotted content.
So this would not style the anchor tag in your slotted span because you can only select the topmost
element for styling,
this is an important restriction you have here.
So if you have nested content, you can't select this but you can select the span or since this is also directly on
the slotted content in our case here,
the highlight class. And then here, what we could do is we could give this a border bottom of 1px
dotted and red for example, save that and go back and reload this page and you will see this slight
red border here
and if I inspect this again, you see here is our style getting applied, the border bottom is having
effect here.
Still important to highlight the order of the styles here,
the styling you set up in the light DOM will overwrite your slotted styling you set up in the shadow DOM
and the idea here simply is that you always want to give the user the final say on how things should look
like
but you can set up some default styling you want to have as we do it here.
But if we were to set a border bottom in the light DOM too, so in our case for the highlight class, if I
had a border bottom of let's say 2px solid and blue here, then you would see that if we reload
this page, we see that border instead of our red dotted border
because whilst this rule still gets applied,
it gets overwritten here.
So the specificity in CSS is such that light
DOM styling overrides shadow DOM styling for projected or slotted content.
This is just one thing to be aware of,
I will comment this out here in the light DOM because I don't want to overwrite it,
I want to have my red dotted border but it is something you definitely have to be aware of.
This can be overwritten from inside the light DOM.