Let's add some content in the modal,
so inside of my modal div there, I actually want to have three sections.
I want to have a header in there which holds a title
and for now, I'll simply have dummy title there, h1 tag, please confirm.
Below the header here,
I want to have a section,
maybe with the ID main, whatever you want and in there, I'll have a slot because I want to be able to
pass the content that is displayed as a message into this modal from outside and actually you are of
course not limited to passing in some text here,
you can pass in anything here, you can pass in an image, button, form, inputs whatever you want.
So I reserve a slot here and then below that slot, I'll have another section and this should be the
section where I have my button or my two buttons, I want to have two buttons in here.
I'll give this section an ID of actions and the first button will be cancel, the second button will
be confirm or ok or whatever you want
and of course you could also create this in a more generic way,
we have to draw a border at some point here, so I will go for the hardcoded buttons here,
you could definitely find a solution where this can be passed in through slots too and I will show you how
to have different slot parts in your template
here in a second, we'll see that later in this module.
So now I have these buttons in here,
now we can style that a little bit.
I'll select actions with the ID selector, give this a border to the top of 1px solid and a light
gray
look let's say and if I now reload this, this is how it looks like.
I definitely wanted a different layout here,
I want to distribute all these pieces across the available space. So for the entire modal here, I'll actually
set the display to flex using flex box and if that is something you don't know, attached to this video,
you'll find some helpful resources for learning flex box,
it's a way of managing the layout in CSS or managing boxes
elements in CSS and distributing them.
I'll set the flex direction to column here
and I set justify content to space between here and this should ensure that if I now reload this all,
the buttons are at the end here. And now I just want to go to my actions,
give this a padding of let's say 1rem and also select my actions button elements here and give them
a margin left and right of 1rem and with that, we have our buttons in here.
Actually I want to have that differently, I want to give them 0.25rem to left and right margin and
in my actions here, I'll set display to flex too and I'll set justify content here to flex-end. So
now I have my buttons here at the bottom
and now of course you could style these buttons differently, for example make the cancel button red or
yellow-ish and make the OK button green,
I will keep them as they are because I don't want to lose too much time on all that styling. Let me quickly
style that title up there though,
so the header, I'll add the header selector here and there, I'll set up padding of 1rem, just as I
have it here for the actions and I'll then also add a header
h1 selector to select a h1 tag we have in the header and set the font size to 1.25rem
maybe.
Let's see, yes,
and now we can present any content we want.
Now I will also get rid of that height
I set up there, that was only set temporarily to have some height when we had no content
but now, it should be as high as the content we pass in requires that to be
and we can pass in any content we want.
Since I have a slot, we can go between the opening and closing tags of our modal
and for example add a paragraph and then add any message we would want to show here, with your confirmation
you agree to pay the full amount, whatever your app might be showing here. And now with this paragraph
added between the opening and closing tag of our modal,
if I reload the page, we see it here and now again, time for some styling.
Let's go back to the modal,
keep in mind that the slot is inside of the main section, so I'll style this main section here, selected
by the ID selector main and give it a padding of 1rem too
and if you would want to style the paragraph itself, you can use the techniques you learned in the last
lectures with the slotted pseudo-selector for example. Here
I got no need to do that,
so I will leave it as it is here.
With that, we've got a nice looking modal in my opinion,
let's now ensure that we can also open and close it
and we want to open it when this show details in confirm button here is pressed.
So that will be our next task
and if you have an idea for that,
definitely try it on your own first.