So we want to be able to show that modal and for that, we need a way to control the visibility of the
backdrop and the modal.
Now there are various ways of doing so in CSS, we can set the opacity, we can set the display property,
anything like that.
What we will need in the end is some way to pass in the information whether this should be visible or not
from outside,
so from our main document because one possible way would be to set let's say an open attribute, either
set this to true or as you also see it on some built-in elements, just open, for example the built-in
button element has a disabled attribute which you also add just like this. So when open or opened maybe
is added let's say, then we want to show to modal, if it's not added, we don't want to show it.
And now I'll add a script tag here and you could outsource this into a different file too of course where
I want to do something when this button is clicked and I want to add this opened attribute when we
click it.
So I will now get access to my confirm button here maybe, by using document query selector and I can
select a button here because another advantage of the shadow DOM, we will just fetch this button because the
buttons in our modal are part of the shadow DOM and therefore, we are in no danger of accidentally selecting
these from outside.
So that's another advantage of the shadow DOM here,
when we select something in our main document, we only select buttons in that main document and in this
case, we only have one button so I can use this query selector and then, I'll add my event listener here
for the click event
and here, I want to add the opened attribute to my uc-modal element. For this, I'll get access to my modal
with document query selector
and now we can simply use uc-modal as a selector because this is a valid tag by which we can select
it
and then we could say modal set attribute opened and now we need to assign a value here and I'll set
this to an empty string.
Now in order to be able to see that effect, we have to make sure that we're not showing the modal by
default which we currently are and especially its backdrop is blocking us from clicking anything.
So to hide it by default, we got a couple of possible ways of solving this. One way of making sure we
can show and hide this is to set the opacity to 0 by default which will hide this but then we'll
face a problem actually because now if I reload this, it is hidden but we still can't click this because
even though it's invisible, it's fully opaque, it's still in front of us,
now we could change the set index but we can also set the pointer events here
to none and this will not accept any clicks on the backdrop but let them through instead.
We do the same on the modal, we just have to change this later when we show it so that we then really
block clicks through it
but here, we want to allow them.
So now if I reload, I can click this.
And if you watched, you saw opened was added here on the right,
let me show this again.
If I reload this modal here, it doesn't have the opened attribute
but if I click this button, watch it here on the right, here it is, there it opened.
So this is working
and now in the next lecture, we can work on doing something in our component
when this opened attribute is added.