Now that is all nice, what we saw thus far, we can copy our generated components into different folders
and import them into our web pages,
that is interesting but often we also want to share our projects across our entire organization and
not just on our machine or we want to share it with the public and for that, we would use the npm registry.
You might remember npm stands for Node Package Manager and the registry is what we already used, for
example in our stencil project when we ran npm init to create it or with all the dependencies we installed,
like here with Node when I ran npm install. That stencil package and also the dependencies of the Node
project are fetched from npm and we can publish our own project to npm as well.
Now for that, I just need to go back into my stencil project again and to publish to npm, we need to
tweak the package.json
file there a bit. In the package.json file,
you can give this package the name your published package should have and that
in my case here and I will unpublish this later so you won't be able to install that is uc-component,
you might want to use a more fitting name, like maybe if your company is called super-great and you have
your core UI component kit, you might name this super great core UI or whatever you want, here I'll just
name it
uc-components. You assign a version, we can go with the default
version, the description is something you can change but it's not required to change. Now
you can leave all the other settings as they are
and now to publish to npm, you need an npm account. You can visit any npmjs.com and you can sign up
for free,
you don't need to pay for that,
you only need to pay if you want to publish private packages
otherwise you can only publish public packages which are accessible by everyone.
If you want to restrict the usage to your old company or to yourself, then you need to pay
otherwise you just need to sign up
and once you went through that entire sign up process here, simply click through, that generated your profile,
you can log into npm here from the command line.
You do that by running npm login
and now you need to enter your credentials, so the username you created and then your password. Once
you did login and you can find all details about the publishing process in the official docs of npm
of course, there under packages and modules if you search for publish, you'll find all the details about
how you can publish your packages. In the end after you logged in,
it's just npm publish and this will now publish your package under this name to the npm registry.
Once it is published, you'll be able to npm install it under that name.
Important, if you have a paid account you need to add --access public to publish this as a public
package
otherwise it will be published as a private package.
So now once this is done, you can install it into any project with npm install
and that's just what we do as a next step.