Now that I talked about web components and their advantages,
if you have a little bit of experience with Javascript development and with front-end development already,
you probably know frameworks like Angular, React or Vue,
if that doesn't tell you anything, well then this lecture will not be that interesting to you but if
you know of these frameworks and libraries, you might be wondering, well web components allow us to create
our own components but frameworks like Angular, React and Vue do exactly the same thing, in all these frameworks
we write components that we can use and that we can reuse and where we also encapsulate all our logic.
So why would we use web components or when we use web components,
why would we use such a framework?
And what about libraries, like JQuery or especially jQuery plugins
where you also often can import like a modal with just two script imports into your page and start
using it?
Well we have component driven approaches in all these solutions, JQuery plugins
are kind of components, we add a script import, we add a couple of attributes to a div and we
can start using it and our frameworks here as well as web components clearly are all about splitting
logic into components.
Well let's start on the right,
libraries like JQuery plugins have the great advantage of being drag and drop, you drop an import
into your page with a script tag and you're ready to go,
you've followed the steps written in the instructions, in the documentation and you're ready to use it.
A downside is you have multiple imports, potentially at least and you might have version conflicts. A
JQuery plugin  easily can depend on, well JQuery, on the plugin, maybe on some other plugin and you
import loads of code into your project that your project might never need.
You might never need the Ajax functionality of the JQuery plugin, you might never need certain DOM
traversal methods and still, you might still have them because your plugin
kind of requires the entire JQuery suite even though it doesn't use all the features. That can all
be optimized
but the danger is high that you're not doing it,
especially if you're building more complex applications with more complex interactions between different
parts of your app,
if you're building an entire single page application let's say, then JQuery will quickly hit its limits,
for certain projects, it's of course fine though.
So these are disadvantages and advantages with JQuery plugins, when we use a framework like
Angular or a library like React, then we have more than just the components and
that is super important.
Any of these solutions, even React which is very lightweight brings more than just the logic to write components.
You get some state management solutions, React has React context, Angular has services. You get routing,
in React it's not baked-in but you often install the React router as an extra library.
So you have more than just the components,
these frameworks give you everything you need to write complex front-end user interfaces,
most of the time, often single page applications. Components are one important part of the toolset but
not everything.
This is one great difference to web components as you will learn.
We also in frameworks
most of the time have a clear set of rules of how we should structure our code or for how we should write
our code, how we should solve certain problems,
there is a certain set of solutions too
for example state management problems or to form validation,
not always but often that is the case.
A downside of frameworks, for example compared with JQuery plugins is the increased complexity,
this deeper learning curve you often have and that the components are not reusable across projects
if you are using a different framework or maybe even a different version of the same framework in another
project, then you might not be able to bring your React component into your Angular application,
you are actually guaranteed to not be able to do that.
Web components solve this because they're just vanilla Javascript,
we will use a different additional tool in this course, stencil.js and I will explain in detail what
this is
when we start using it
but that too will just generate vanilla Javascript web components as you will learn.
So we have no external dependencies,
we don't need a special framework,
that of course means that we also have to ship less code because it's really just our component code,
no overhead introduced by the framework and it's easily reusable since we use just Javascript and all
these frameworks as well as JQuery plugins use Javascript,
we can bring our components into any application, into the front-end of any web app we're building. Compared
to JQuery plugins,
we still have a greater complexity because, at least when we're writing these because we have to learn
certain new techniques which is exactly what you learned in this course,
it's not super hard but there are new things you haven't learned about when you just had normal DOM manipulations,
normal DOM traversal and also important, web components are just web components.
The difference to the frameworks is that you can theoretically build an entire user interface from just
web components but you'll be missing tools for navigation, so for routing, for parsing
the URL and loading a different set of components, for state management.
So building a single page application with just web components will require some extra libraries that
take care about the routing or take care about the state management
and this is also not what we'll dive into this course because we're not focusing on building entire apps
here,
we will dive into web components and learn how we can build such reusable web components that you could
then use in any project with any framework or if you don't need it, without any.