Now let's make sure we can fetch some stock data
and for that, we can actually start with this dummy request here with the demo API
key, so there we don't even need our own API key to just fetch data from Microsoft all the time.
That demo API key will only work with that symbol
basically, you can't enter any symbol.
So we'll hook up this dynamic symbol search here at a later point of time,
for now let me show you how to send an API request and display the result.
I still want to send the request when the button is pressed though because that is how it will later be too.
So therefore here in this place, in the onFetchStockPrice method, I want to send an HTTP request
and how do we do that?
Well we get a couple of options here,
we're working with web technologies
so you could use the good old XML HTTP request, also known as Ajax. For this you could actually even
use a tool like JQuery or a package like axios. You could install axios with npm and import it into
this file to use it.
We can also use the more modern fetch API that is built into modern browsers and if you need to support
older browsers, you definitely want to highlight that in documentation of your components and inform
users using your components that your components rely on the fetch API and that they might need to
bring polyfills to make it work in older browsers
but I will use it because we don't need to install any other packages therefore.
So the fetch API works in a very simple way, we call this fetch function which is built into the browser
and as an argument, we pass the URL in a string to which we want to send a request,
so here this will be my demo URL. The fetch API
then uses promises to yield the result because it's an asynchronous task and as you should know,
Javascript handles asynchronous task with callbacks or promises or observables if you're using that
extra package
but we will use the built-in way here and fetch users that build in promise API. That allows us to chain
a method, onFetch, then and catch. A catch will catch any errors that occur,
for example network errors if there is no connection
and here I will simply log this error and then will be fired whenever we get a response.
Important, including the cases where we get a 404 or 500 response,
so such server side errors are not handled by catch.
So here, we'll get a response and we will get a response by alphavantage in the JSON format.
The response we get here by fetch has some useful information,
for example there we can get the status code and we can also extract useful information, for
example by calling the JSON method,
we automatically parse the incoming response body and transformed the incoming data into a Javascript object
because we get it as a JSON string, this will parse the body and give us the Javascript object. We
need to return this operation because this also is an asynchronous task and then we can add another
then block and here, we'll have the parsed response available. I'll name this parsed response here,
you can name it however we want
and there, let's first of all simply log this to the console to see whether this works
and what's inside there,
parsed response.
Let me now save this and let's give this a try,
this simple code snippet here. Back in the browser if I click fetch, indeed here, I get a global quote
object
and this is a Javascript object with all the fields
we also saw here when we manually send this as a get request by entering the URL in the browser. And there,
we have this 05 price field which is what I want to extract because that holds the price which
should be displayed down there.
Now how do we get that price out of the response into the render function?
We actually learned everything you need for that but certainly, spend some thoughts on this, on how
you would solve this and then we'll do it together in a couple of seconds.
So do you have an idea on how we could get the price out of parsed response and render it in this part,
in this field here?
Well we can use state and we can simply change that state property in this then block here where we can simply
read the response.
So I will add a new state property and I'll name it fetchedPrice, the name is totally up to you though
and that should be a number, actually as you can tell, it will be a string but we can convert this to a number
because it always should be a number.
So we'll treat this as a number and here instead of logging the parsed response, I will simply access
this field with this name here. So we can say this.fetchedPrice equals parsed response and then we use
square brackets to access this field. We need to do that and
we can't use the dot notation because this field name has a whitespace and this would be invalid syntax,
so we use the square brackets syntax for accessing this field value.
Now this will be a string, to convert it to a number,
I'll add a plus in front of it and then we have this fetchedPrice data stored
and now we can output that down there,
this.fetchedPrice
and as you learned, whenever you change the state, stencil will automatically rerun the render function and update
the DOM efficiently.
Now this will also be a dollar price,
so I will add a dollar sign in front of this. Now with this, it would not work though because if you
remember, the data we got had that global quote key as a top level field and that was a nested object
with the price field.
So actually when accessing this, we first of all need to access global quote and make sure to spell this
correctly, you can also just copy and paste it from here,
so that is simply a nested object so we need to access this top level object first.
And with that, we can save that and now if we go back and we reload, if I click fetch here, nothing
happens.
Well this can be hard to spot but it is a common mistake in there for important to be aware of. I'm
setting this fetchedPrice equal to this price and I can tell you this price is extracted correctly, you
can console log it in case you want to see it,
the problem is the this keyword. In onFetchStockPrice, this refers to whatever called this method
and what called this method was this form.
We need to bind this here to ensure that this keyword inside of onFetchStockPrice always refers to
our surrounding class because now with this change, this looks much better and now we can actually fetch
and display this value.