We added styling to the side drawer, let's now make sure that we can configure it from outside, that we
can pass data in from outside
and for this, I want to show various techniques and various things because stencil has a lot of flexibility
when it comes to that.
Now let's say we want to have a title in our drawer, so I will actually add a header section there, by
the way, you can always just type the name of a tag in Visual Studio Code at least and then hit tab
to auto-complete that and the header here should have a h1 tag in there
but I want to set this dynamically, I want to pass this in as a property and attribute for this component.
I also want to have my main section in here, so we can use a main element here and in that section,
I want to use a slot and slots are supported in stencil as well.
By the way a little convenience feature, if you have an empty opening and closing tag like here, you can
also use one tag only and self-close it like this,
not required but possible.
Now let's focus on the slot in the second step,
how about this property attribute which I want to display between the h1 tags here? Now with vanilla
web components, we had to manage all those property attribute stuff on our own.
For example if we had attributes that can be changed from outside and that is definitely possible for
almost all attributes if people change them programmatically, then we had to set up the attributeChangedCallback
and so on.
Now that's a lot of extra work
and the more attributes we have, the more complex that code becomes.
In stencil,
this is easier.
We can add a property to our class here by simply adding it directly in the class,
that is a feature which is not supported in vanilla Javascript classes but it is supported in Typescript
and I can name this however I want,
I can maybe name it
title. Now we use Typescript here and in Typescript, it's a good practice to be clear about the type a variable
or a property holds and you assign such a type by adding a colon after the name of the variable or
in this case, the property
and then you set a type,
in this case this is a string.
Now we're telling Typescript that we will have a title property here,
initially it's undefined as you can tell which will hold a string in the end
and then if we want to output this between the h1 tags, we simply add single curly braces in here,
that is a feature provided by JSX, it allows us to basically output normal Javascript content between
our to-be-transformed JSX statements
and there, I point at this property.
Now this is a class property,
so we don't reference it with
title, that would try to get a variable named title defined in the render method,
instead it's this title because it's part of this class.
This will generally work, it will give us a property named title but when we try to set this from outside,
stencil will not pick it up,
it will not listen to an attribute named title or to changes to such an attribute and even if you set
it programmatically from outside, stencil will not call the render method again.
Instead what you have to do is you have to add a special decorator here again,
this time it's not the component decorator but the prop decorator.
You also call this like a function and you need to import it from @stencil/core,
my IDE added the import automatically,
make sure you do it manually in case this was not the case,
so prop needs to be imported from @stencil/core. Prop is a special decorator,
we don't need to configure it,
there are some configurations we can pass but we don't need them right now.
Out of the box when we add it, it does one important thing,
stencil will now watch for attributes named title on our component and if we set or change such an attribute
or if we directly programmatically set or change the title property from outside Javascript for example,
then stencil will detect this change and it will automatically rerun the render method and it will do
so in a very efficient manner so that it does not re-render the entire DOM that was generated
based on that
but only the parts of the DOM that changed.
So in this case, it would only re-render this part of the DOM when we change or set the title because this
is the only place where we use the title. This is what the prop decorator does,
it adds an automatic watcher
you could say. And with that, we can go into the index.html file and indeed add the title here and set
it to main menu for example,
so to a string, main menu. If I now save this and we go back, we indeed see main menu here because we
set this attribute here and just to show that programmatic part too, if I add script tags in my index.html
file and that is therefore Javascript code and not Typescript code because this will now not
be picked up by stencil, if I do that and I get access to my custom element here,
so to the side drawer with document query selector and now again, I can just use my own tag that does
work in exactly the same way it did with vanilla components because stencil spits out of a vanilla web
component, then I can also set the title here to it changed
and that becomes even more interesting if we wrap this into a set
timeout call to do this after a given amount of time, let's say after three seconds, then we want to execute
this code and this will have one important effect.
If this reloads, we have main menu but after three seconds, it changed
and this proves that stencil watches this
and please note that here, I'm not changing the attribute on the element,
that indeed is still the same if we inspect it, the attribute here is still main menu
but we changed it programmatically.
Of course we could have changed the attribute though and it would have worked as well.
If I comment this out and I set side drawer set attribute and I set the title attribute to it changed
via attribute here and I save this and reload it,
then we see it changed to this text after three seconds
and now of course the attribute here updated as well because well, we updated it here. So we can do both
and that shows us how we can interact with that and what the prop decorator does.