So let's use our own package of components in the Angular project.
Now the Angular folder you find here is a folder, is a project created with the Angular CLI,
it's a default Angular project without any changes,
so it's really just what you get when you create a brand new project with the CLI. Now in there, I can
now first of all also install my uc-components, so I can do it like that.
Now with the package installed there and now the next steps really only makes sense if you understand
a little bit of Angular, otherwise you can probably skip that because it's not that interesting to you
but now with that installed, you have to do two things to make your components work. In the source app
folder in the app module,
you have to enable a certain schema by which Angular will validate the HTML elements you're using
here in your templates because by default, Angular throws an error when you are using a non-standard
HTML element which is not an Angular component and that is exactly what we will do.
We'll use our own web components which are neither a standard HTML element nor an Angular element
and for that to work, we just need to do two important changes or adjustments.
The first one is done here in the app module from @angular/core, we import the custom elements schema
and we add to this under this schemas key here in our ngModule object here as a value in that
array and
that simply tells Angular, hey there are custom elements present.
The next step is that we need to register these custom elements and we do that in the main.ts file here
by simply importing something which is generated by stencil from our own package. We import from
and now you add your package name, uc-components and there, the dist folder and there, the loader folder,
from there you import define custom elements.
This is now a function which you need to execute down there and you pass the window object as an argument
and this ensures that your custom elements are added to your project
and now let's add a custom element in the app component. I'll delete all the default content here
and I'll add uc-stock-price.
Now we can start your project by running npm start or with ngServe, npm start uses ngServe
behind the scenes with the local Angular CLI
version and this will now build your project and it should launch it on a development server which you
find under http://www.localhost:4200 where indeed we can find our own component which works just fine with different
stock indices.
So that is pretty neat
and now if we again inspect this in the network tab and we load this, you see there are a bunch of
requests being made and it's this 6.js file in my case, might be named differently for you,
where in the end, our own component data is loaded and is well, mounted into this DOM and you see it's
super small,
so super easy to add to any project, especially since this already include some extra functionality to load
more and other components and so on. Here
I can now also show you how stencil adds code so that your components only get loaded when they really are
rendered,
let's add that uc-stock-finder. If I now save this, this app will reload and you'll find not just the
6.js but also the 8.js file
and this happens to hold the code for my uc-stock-finder.
Now please note that when I remove this by adding ngIf here and I'll bind this to showStockFinder and
showStockFinder is added in my app component Typescript code here, showStockFinder here and it's
false and therefore, since this is false,
this will not be loaded.
If I add this, you see that in your network tab, you only see just 6.js file,
so the other component is indeed not loaded here because it's not rendered to the DOM yet
and this is this cleverness stencil.js brings.
And now we can see how this is dynamically reloaded
when I add a button here let's say, load finder, where I add an Angular click listener and this is
now all Angular syntax I'm using here
and I set showStockFinder to true here.
The fact of this is that initially when I reload this, we only have the 6.js file,
so our web component code for the stock finder is not loaded.
Now let me clear the network tab so that we can see any other requests clearly
and now if I click load finder, now this is loaded and this is super efficient because it means we load
the data for this script, for this component only when it is really needed
and that is super efficient of course.
So that is how we can use web components in an Angular app.
You need to do these two adjustments at the beginning and then you can just add them as normal HTML
elements with all the benefits of lazy loading and code splitting added by stencil automatically.