So let's make sure that the text that shows up on our tooltip can be set from outside
and for that, we will use an attribute. Now attributes are not something that is exclusive to your web
components or your custom elements, attributes exist on a lot of built-in HTML elements. Take a link for
example, here
the ref thing here, that is an attribute and it allows you to configure this element,
so the link here in a declarative way which means you don't have to write any code,
no Javascript code to set the target of this link
and we want to use the same approach for our own tooltip, for example it would make sense that on our
uc-tooltip tag here, we can use a text attribute or TooltipText attribute or whatever you want to
name it.
I will name it just text and here,
web components is a set of standards
for example. This could be the text I want to display when I hover over this uc-tooltip element and
for the second one,
I won't set a text attribute,
so here we maybe want to have a default value.
How do we now use that attribute from inside our tooltip?
Well it's actually pretty simple.
Inside of our constructor, we can initialize a new private variable and I will name it TooltipText.
Now there I will call get attribute and now enter the name of the attribute for which I want to extract
the value
and in my case that is text because I chose text as the attribute name here.
So now we save whatever we stored as text or as the text attribute value, we save that in TooltipText and
we can now use that down there where we stay or where we set up some text to be displayed.
So here instead of this hardcoded text, I will set this TooltipText as a value.
Now with that if we save this, we can go back and reload this page
and now if you hover over that, we don't see anything there, right?
Well the reason for that is that here, we're initializing it in the constructor
but as you learned, the custom element has been created at this point but it has not been mounted to
the DOM yet,
this will only have happened inside of the connected callback.
So we should move this line into our connected callback so that we can safely access this DOM Node's
attributes
because at this point of time, it will have been rendered into the DOM
and now if we save that and we reload this page, we see web components is the set of standard.
Now for the second question mark, we don't see anything because we have no default value there.
Now to make sure we have a solution for both cases, I will actually go back into the constructor and
set the TooltipText here to use some dummy TooltipText,
maybe something that makes a little bit more sense than that
and here I only want to overwrite it when we have that attribute. For this I'll add an if check where I
see if this has attribute text, so only if we have that attribute being set, I will extract that attribute
and store its text in the TooltipText
otherwise this will not be overwritten and will be using our dummy text.
So now we have the basic initialization which does not access the DOM in the constructor and then we
do access the DOM and override the default value with a more specific value
if we have the text attribute being set in the connected callback. And now we can reload this page
once again, we see web components is a set of standards for the first tooltip, for the second,
we see our dummy TooltipText.
Now this is how we can work with attributes.
Now there is a special thing when we then later change attribute values
and you will also learn that there is another way of setting something like this
then through the attributes but that is something we'll come back to later,
for now we have that.
Let me now show you how you can add some styling to this component because that obviously is missing.