Hello,
My name's Alan and on the creator of this course Excel Essentials Level two for
intermediate and advanced students.
Now,
at the moment,
I'm assuming that you already have the fundamentals of Excel mastered.
That is,
You know what a spreadsheet is?
You know how to write a basic formula,
and you know where everything on the screen is.
No need to worry,
if not,
because we'll go through things step by step in depth anyway.
Now,
one of the criticisms I hear when I speak to other students,
particularly of Excel courses,
is that they're taught a bunch of formulas,
but they have no context,
so they think the formulas are fantastic,
but they can't actually see a reason why they would ever want to use them.
For that reason,
I deliberately structured this course into individual projects.
Now you may have a look at the project title and think,
You know what?
I have no need to work out how to create a relational database,
for example.
But within each of the sections,
there is some powerful techniques that if you just build it from scratch and you follow the
course sequentially and complete each of the sections each of the lectures in those
sections,
you'll see some powerful formulas at work in context on hopefully then you It will be a
short leap to be able to say I I see how I can apply this in this project that I'm working
on that work all this other project that I'm working on it work.
So although you may look at the tiles and think,
I don't need that work through it anyway because there are gems hidden in every section.
So the aim of this course is to enable you to build powerful solutions using just the
standard Excel functions,
maybe combined in a way that you wouldn't think to normally.
But you can achieve things that people generally don't think that you can achieve with
excel.
Okay,
so thank you again for choosing this course,
and I'll see you in the next lecture.
Thank you.