OK,
guys.
Now let's have a look at how we create our new template.
Now there are three ways to create a template.
The moose,
cumbersome and time consuming,
is to create it from scratch completely.
Three,
easiest by far is to get a copy of the original template in Excel format and just copy the
particular worksheet with the template on into your new workbook,
which is the time sheets and expenses master here that we're working on.
But there is a middle ground,
and the middle ground involves cheating on its cheating.
That's going to be the subject of this particular lesson.
Okay,
What we need to do is get a copy of the spreadsheet in a J peg format or some picture
format.
So I've added a new sheet by hitting the little plus button so we can see our original data
interest sheets just here.
We're going to be working in sheet to on.
What we're gonna do is we're going to come up to the insert menu just have here left.
Click it on.
We can see in the illustration sections in the illustration section that we have the option
of pictures,
so I'm just gonna left click pictures on my desktop.
I have a blank time sheet in J peg format,
so I'm just double click that and they go.
No,
we can see we have a perfect copy of the original document that we want to transpose onto
this worksheet.
Okay,
now there are a couple of issues here.
Firstly,
we can see the image,
which is this area just here on.
We have the worksheet,
which is this bit here,
where we can see all the cells.
If we have a look at the name box,
we can see we're in cell a nine.
And just using the cursor keys,
we can see that we can quite happily move underneath the spreadsheet.
But we can't actually see through the spreadsheet to be able to enter any data in so no
locally Excel has a wonderful trick you can use when you do in J pegs like this on again.
Now we selected the image itself.
You can see that we have a new option,
appeared at the top on that's picture tools for matter.
So just come up to the top left click,
and you can see that we have a bunch of different options here.
Now,
in the adjust section just at the top Here we have color with a little down arrow.
So I'm just gonna left click the down arrow on their ignore all of these options.
I'm going to come down to set transparent color.
So I'm just gonna left quick that and you can see the cursor has changed to a little picker
.
Now all we need to do is click on the color that we want to be transparent.
So I'm just gonna left click on the white area on then the magic happens now we can see
straight through our template.
So we still have the image here,
and we still have the spreadsheet over here.
If we come on to the spreadsheets and no use our cursor keys,
you can see that we can move around underneath the actual image,
but we can still see straight through it because you've set that transparent color.
Okay,
so now all we need to do is a little jiggery pokery to make sure that these particular
cells underneath lineup with these cells in the spreadsheet.
Then the first thing that we can see is that the row height is completely different.
So the row height of the cells is much narrower than the row height of the template.
So all we're gonna do is we're gonna line up one of them eso It's just left click and drank
that up a little bit until it's more or less in line,
which is about that on.
Then we're going to do the same at the bottom.
So that's Maura less in line.
And then we're gonna have a quick look to see what the row height is on this one.
So it's just right.
Click the road that we've just changed.
Choose row,
height on.
We can see that we have a row height of 23.25 So?
So we don't forget it.
Let's just select it and copy it has click.
OK,
they're going to come to the rest of these.
Highlight them,
right click Choose row height again.
Drag it up on paste over 15 to say 23.25 It's OK on DNO.
We can see if we come to the spreadsheet since roll over that we now have a pretty accurate
representation of the row height of all of these input cells here.
So so far,
so good.
The next thing we need to do is line up the cells underneath.
Um,
so the columns Aaron line.
So the 1st 1 we're going to do is between D and C,
and I'm just gonna drank that over There s Oh,
no,
we can see if we click on the spreadsheets have over where?
Almost spot on here,
which is very good.
We're gonna come over to here and lying it up.
So now,
so which so are we on cell D 25 which I'm just gonna color in matches perfectly the hole
that we have to fill in on the template that we can see through.
I'm just going to repeat that for all of these.
So I'm just gonna drag between e and F er,
make that the same width the same between F g,
G and H H.
And I know we might have to do a little bit of alteration of later on.
Let me just rips.
That's the image.
Lately.
Click on the spreadsheets.
Sabam beneath.
I'm just going to color these into show that I've actually already completed these.
We can always change them back to color.
Less alert later.
Answer all those don't.
So that's good.
We can see that the row height is wrong on this one.
So let me just go to row height on change that we should still have in a clipboard.
23.25 Okay,
on.
We just want to move out of Scrooge E.
So it's in line now we're gonna have to do but emerging.
Centering.
So here we can see more or less where were were in line on the Rose.
But we need emergency center.
This is gonna be a constant data so we can talk.
My sign meant on We can probably format that in the center and make it bold.
Quicken spreadsheet Come over.
We can merge in center This one.
Make it bold.
May kicked Central owned.
Put my name in there.
In general,
this we need to make this row also 23.25 row height paced 23.25 and scourge e than up there
.
Just so that matches nicely and again,
click on the spreadsheet.
Come over,
merge in center on.
Basically,
we're going to repeat that the entire process so we've got all of our cells underneath the
transparent template all lined up here perfectly with these boxes that we're going to enter
into again.
I'm just gonna pause for a second while I settle these up and I'll make sure all the cells
were aligned on.
Then we'll import the data from our data entry sheet into here.
Okay,
So these air Almora lesser lying.
Now you can see that these,
these particular ones then here have gone over.
But as this is just a client signature box,
that should be okay,
because if they're signing it,
they can just sign in the box so the alignment will mess.
And that's if you printing it off,
scandal it and fax and it'll scanning it and then emailing it.
But if it's just a typed box,
that will just look okay,
I'm just gonna center align it and make it bold.
So that's me.
Took There was works.
This is also input field,
so I'm just going to call it that in on the date,
Will,
we'll come to some clever things on dates in a little while.
Okay?
So the first thing we're gonna do we start populating the dates from our data entry screen
.
So I'm just going to click the week end in box.
I'm gonna hit equals,
just like we did in the very first.
Like to improve for concept on.
I'm gonna click this box here to show us the date and you can see that the formula bar I
said we're gonna look at she won Exclamation point.
Selby three hit.
Enter And you can see now that we have 4 to 216 entered in there.
So all we're gonna do is we're gonna come down,
Teoh.
Let's have it is a long date.
So they go.
So no air date is entered 31st of July,
And I'm gonna come over 2 a.m. start and I'm gonna say equals and I'm gonna flip over to
here on I'm going to click this sell because that's the time we start in the morning Hit
Enter on.
Gonna copy the formatted on that one center center on Make it bold And I'm just gonna
literally copy that down Away.
We're not working working Thursdays and Fridays so we can see here We're referencing sheet
one B nine on B 10 on B 11 on.
Then we're just gonna copy it all of that straight over to their control.
When are so we started out knowing of finishing a 12 which is reading straight out of their
data entry screen here on here.
And the next one we need to look at is our lunch.
So it's flipped back here over to the spreadsheet scroll underneath the template hit equals
hit sheet one on hit our lunch on Monday on Hit,
Enter and again we're gonna so get the format in sense of center on make it bold And then
we can copy that down,
control in deep and then we're gonna do the same for the other.
Bigger.
So we're gonna equals stars.
Hit sheet one start in the afternoon.
There it's Enter waken just literally Come over here and copy the format in from this cell
on paste it over that self again.
So that's good and weaken Drank that one day and so that would be no issue Control on D.
We can control on our coffee that right,
and that will show us our finishing times.
Now the worked hours is the final one that we calculated that we're going to hit equals.
We're gonna tab over to sheet one on.
We're gonna put our payable hours as a floor,
which is exactly what we agreed they would pay to the nearest 15 whole minutes.
Work his answer.
Just copy that down Control on D sort at the format in Make it bold and they go and was
worth will hit equals will time over here on our total hours worked here payable hours,
floor hit Enter.
And you can see we get that peculiar format in there because we working underneath this,
she's we can't actually right click to change the formula to get to the formula bar.
So all we're gonna do is just wrapped the sheet out the way,
and we can see that that that's what the actual spreadsheet looks like until we don't the
template back over this up.
So I'm just going to right click off there.
Just gonna sort out the format in center center on bold,
just as we did before.
Right click.
I'm gonna choose format cells.
Let me just write that into shot.
We're gonna come to custom on.
We're gonna go.
Whoops.
We're going to go Square brackets.
I was ours.
Square brackets,
colon minutes,
minutes on hit,
enter.
And they go 38 hours and 50 minutes,
Which is is exactly what we weren't.
So now that's all good or we're gonna do is pick the picture of stick it back over and they
go We've gone out nearly completed time sheet.
Just one thing.
Let me just hit control on a on 10 als the color to know film Anay Go.
Now that looks like the original documents even though we've actually cheated on butchered
the existing template from a J peg.
Ok,
in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at the next template we're going to create.
So see you in the next lecture.