Okay,
guys,
this is the next template that we're going to populate now.
Likely already have this in a separate excel file.
It's all I'm going to do is import this into our document.
They can see that a lot of the data types in here are exactly the same as our original.
So when we have this section down the bottom just here,
we have time out of house and the times were expressed as as a normal time format.
So we have eight colon 30 on.
We have 17.
Cool on 30.
But the difference is here at the top,
where we can see that the hours worked expresses decimal.
So we have 7.5 instead of seven.
Coal on 30 on,
then this over here to guess if we look at the formula is just a some That's just it.
F too.
Yeah,
that's just a straight some on these cells across here.
Okay,
So the simplest thing we need to do is get this into our current working documents,
and that's very easy to do.
We're just gonna come down to the tab at the bottom where it says sheet one will hit the
move or copy.
So we're just gonna left Click on.
Then what we're gonna do is we're going to say,
create a copy.
And because we've already got all the workbook open,
we're just gonna hit the little down arrow.
Now,
we could move it to a completely new workbook which fall enough would move it to a
completely brand new workbook.
All we can move it to time sheet and expenses,
Master,
which is the one we working there.
So we're just going to select that.
We're gonna hit OK on dare we have our time sheet and expenses,
Master,
we have sheet one,
which is our data entry screen.
Let's just change the name of that too.
Data rib state,
um,
and treat she to is our time.
She's so we're just gonna hit rename and say time sheet keeps it nice and easy on.
We're just gonna drag this one,
which is our expenses.
Shit.
We're just gonna left click drag it over and put it at the end.
And we're going to rename that one too.
So I'm just gonna click rename and call the expenses So they go No,
we have important our data.
We just need to have a look at what we need to change in the data entry screen to make it
populate this,
but using a different format.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.