Okay,
guys,
this next part is really straightforward.
All we need to do is replicate these particular fields over here in our data entry screen.
So the game we're gonna have possibly different starting end locations on different days.
So I'm just going to copy the days of the week down here,
and I'm gonna put stars on ultimate enter a location,
and I'm gonna put and location.
Now,
this is just going to be for one way.
So all I'm gonna say is we're starting from home on.
We'll start from home on every day of the week and we'll end at work.
Andi hit that.
Okay down there.
The next thing that we need to calculate is Miles traveled.
So you'll probably already know how many miles you travel to work.
So we'll just put miles on.
We'll put it each way because we said from home to work.
So let's imagine for a second we work six miles from home.
We'll just say six and we'll fill that all the way down.
We're not traveling or something.
And something at least not to work.
OK,
so these are simple data entry fields,
so I'm just going to change that to the same shade of blue as we have above.
Uh,
let's just send those cells there,
OK?
And never will we need to do is read these cells into let's just center that read these
fields into our expenses.
So on Monday,
we're going to hit equals on.
We're gonna hit data entry,
and we say on Monday we start him from home on on Monday,
we're gonna hit,
equals and our end location is going to be work on his enter on their total miles traveled
slide difference here,
we're going to say equals on.
We're going to say data entry on We're gonna look at the miles,
But remember,
this is each way.
So then we're going to multiply,
So I'm gonna hit the multiply by two.
So then when I hit enter,
I get 12 in here because we're doing it both ways.
So from home to work six miles each way is 12 miles in total.
On the final one is the reason for journey.
So let's just sit equals on go to data entry.
Andi,
I haven't put it in,
so we'll just click there on on here.
Will change that will say reason?
Full journey.
Okay,
We'll make that blue.
Copy the formatting from there and place it over there.
Now,
we're gonna do something a little bit clever here what we're going to do rather than
display zero,
because we don't particularly want it to say zero.
What we want to say is,
if this is zero,
then actually,
just explain nothing at all.
So we'll come to the conditional format in in the next lecture.
Okay,
So I'm just going to go ahead and I'm gonna reference Tuesday equals Tuesday to our Tuesday
start and so on and so forth all the way through.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.
When will cover conditional formatting.
So you in the next lecture.