okay,
now is welcome,
Mac.
Now,
in this lecture,
we're gonna have a look at simple,
conditional formatting.
Now,
I finished off all of these other cells on Monday through Friday,
which,
in our happily reference in these cells just here on these cells all the way,
then Sunday and nobody referenced across here so we can see.
And when you say that we have a meeting because him Wednesday we have a meeting,
but everything else is pulling a zero because we have nothing entered in the data entry
screen.
Now what we're gonna do is apply a simple,
conditional formatting on all the conditional format means is that a particular format is
applied or not applied when a particular conditioners be met.
So the condition we're gonna test for is does the cell equals zero on or begin to try and
evaluate is whether we get a true or false response to that condition being met.
So in this cell here,
I'm just gonna type zero.
And next week,
some type equals and I'm gonna hit that cell again,
and I'm gonna say equals one and there that will evaluate to false,
because what we've said is that M 31.
The soldiers here equals one which obviously is not true.
So it's evaluated to false.
But if we said M 31 equals zero on his enter with,
then get an evaluation of true,
so our condition would have been met on It's a simple is that when we apply the conditional
formatting over here because we've got the background set to yellow because we can see what
we're working on.
We want to actually change that toe.
Why it immediately?
That's what we're gonna do is we're going to make the text white.
If the condition is zero,
it's OK.
I've just selected this cell here.
I want to come up to conditional formatting hit the plus,
and I'm gonna create a new rule.
Okay,
so now we have Ah,
window pop up on.
What we're gonna do is we're going to use a formula to determine which sells to format,
which is the bottom option just here.
So I'm just going to click that,
move them out the way a little bit,
and then we can see this box,
which is the selector box.
So I'm just going to click in here on hit this little colorful box up the corner.
Then click the cell that we're looking at now.
At the moment,
you'll see that that say's equals dollar D doh,
at 32 which is an absolute cell reference.
Which means wherever we copy this format in,
it's only gonna look at that particular cell.
The cell was always Indy on,
always in 32.
So to scroll through,
these were just gonna hit F four,
which now gives us t absolute 32 f four again.
Then we get absolute D 32 on one more time on their four and gives us d 32.
Okay,
so that's the cell were evaluated on DWI.
Want to have a look?
Does it equal zero?
So if this if this evaluates to be true,
Selvi 3rd 2 equals zero.
What format would be like to apply?
So we hit the little format on.
What we want to do is we want to look at the funds which currently is colored automatic.
But what we wanted to do is color it white.
So I'm just going to change their funds color twice,
and you can do other things in here.
You can change the border.
You can change the fell.
But all we want to do is change the front toe white.
So I hit OK and I hit OK again on DNO.
You can see that even though it's still say zero,
it appears to be blank.
So what we're gonna do is copy the formatting from there and apply it to here and click
often.
You can see that we still have zero in there,
but you know,
can't see because it's white text on a white background and it's gonna carry on that all
the way across here.
And you can see that the only text that survived because it didn't meet the criteria of
this cell equals zero is meeting so we could go back Teoh Monday and say lunch as if lunch
would be a reason for a journey.
Actually,
pretty good reason for a Jannik on there.
We can see that lunch as as being added.
So there you go.
That's a nice,
simple way of doing conditional formatting on a pretty good use for it.
It saves you having loads heroes all over spreadsheets,
and it makes things look a lot tired.
You,
if you could just blank it out.
So we've applied the conditional format.
We've said,
Does this cell equals zero?
If it does turn out a text white and it's a simple is that Okay?
So you in the next lecture.