Okay,
guys,
let's have a look at this range of cells just here.
Now,
what we need to do is establish if we're out of the house but foot for between five and 10
hours a day,
we need to return a value of five.
And if we're out of the house from more than 10 hours a day,
we need to return a value off 10.
OK?
No,
let's have a quick look at a simple,
logical test.
So in here,
I'm just going to type five on Dhere.
I'm gonna type our thirst.
Logical test Neurological tests will begin with if on there are a few different versions of
this is if if era And if an I was just going to stick with it for now,
we're gonna open our brackets and we can see here that it tells us our first argument is
the logical test itself.
So I'm gonna do is say that cell psychological test is going to evaluate so n 44 if it
equals five?
So that's our testers n 44 equal five hit a comma and there it says,
What value do you want to return?
If it's true?
and we're going to return a simple text entry that says Yes and texts entries are going to
go in quotes,
so I value,
if true,
is going to say yes and comment on now.
Our value of false open quotes is going to be no.
And then when the closer brackets hit enter so we can see that logical Tests has looked at
this and says,
Does that sell equal five?
Yes,
it does therefore return.
Yes.
So if I put anything else in here,
it will say no.
Okay,
now we can make it little more sophisticated.
And what we can say is,
if n 44 not just equals five,
but we could save and 44 is less than or equal to five.
Return?
Yes,
on if it isn't less than or equal to five return?
No.
So let's have a look at that.
10 still evaluates to new five Silly valley rights to yes,
zero also evaluates to Yes,
because it's less than five.
OK,
nice and straightforward stuff,
then.
Okay,
now what we need to do first,
because remember,
we're dealing in time on excel expresses.
Time is fractions of days.
We need to know what five hours looks like as a number as a fraction of the day on.
We also need to know what 10 hours looks like it's a fraction of the day.
So over here,
just for now,
I'm just gonna type 05 double zero.
And that's five oclock all five hours.
A 0 10 double zero on,
mate.
And that is 10 hours expressed as time.
No,
no.
Just referenced these two cells on.
But this time I'm going to change these answers from custom formatting cause we're in time
to a general format,
and I'm just going to make them a little bit wider.
So they go,
you can see that fire there was evaluates to 2.8333 and loser threes.
Onda 10 hours equates to 0.41 Loves sixes on a seven.
No,
What I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna copy those and pace over a special.
So we actually get the full number up here in the formula ball when we select to eat cell.
Okay,
Now we're gonna build our first simple,
logical test,
and they were just getting a little bit more complicated,
but still very straightforward.
So the first thing we're gonna do is say,
does this cell equal less than 10 hours?
So woman do For knows.
I'm just gonna copy that answer for 10 hours by hitting control ones Say his escape.
Now I'm gonna come over here.
So I've now got the decimal value for 10.
There was 0.41 lives of sixes in a seven in the clipboards or Macey's equals.
If open brackets.
This cell,
because this is the time out of has on Monday is less than what?
I'm gonna just pace that number.
And they're so d 41 is less than 10 hours,
which is a decimal 0.41 blows a six isn't a seven,
then what I want to do.
If amount of the house for less than 10 hours is,
I want to claim £5.
So our values true is going to be five and no comma.
Our value,
if false,
is going to be 10.
I'm gonna close the brackets and hit,
enter and they go.
We can see that all of these control on right will evaluate to £5.
So far,
so good.
Now,
let's just check that that does work.
So if we said on Tuesday,
we traveled 100 miles,
that gives us a three hour and 20 minutes travel time each way on.
That does indeed evaluate Sam Pound so fantastic.
We worked out to pour out the house for more than five.
There was all less than 10 hours.
Give us a fiver on if we're at the house,
but for between five and 10 hours,
give us a fiver.
Fantastic.
Now,
the more issues among you will notice that there are three possible outcomes to this test.
If I'm out of the house for between five and 10 hours,
I claim a fiver,
if I may answer that has for over 10 hours,
I claim a tenner.
But the 3rd 1 is,
If I am entered the house for under five hours,
then all I can claim is zero because the only two things that actually pay are between five
and 10 hours or over 10 hours,
£5.10 pounds,
respectively.
So what we're going to do here is we gonna nest?
Another logical test inside the logical test we've already built it sounds more complicated
than it is So now we've already worked out what fire there was.
Looks like is a number on that Looks like 0.2833 threes and again,
woman do is I'm gonna copy that number on.
I'm gonna come into our formula here.
The woman to someone drank the formula bar down.
Andi,
I am going to come immediately after the equals and hits old and enter.
And that makes it a lot easier to read.
Nested if statements.
And that's what this is.
A nested if statement.
So again,
I'm gonna write the formula.
So if open brackets this cell here,
exactly the same as you did before is less land.
And now I'm gonna pace the value in for five hours,
which is zero point to await on blows of threes.
So they were going to say,
if d 41 is less than five hours comma value,
if true,
zero and then come out value if false,
and then it will move on to our second logical tests.
The one that we built it earlier.
So we're going to say if d 41 is less than five hours,
tell me zero.
But if it isn't less than fire.
There was Move on to our second logical test.
So now it's going to say is D 41 less than 10 hours.
And if it is less than 10 hours,
tell me five.
And if you listen less than 10 hours,
that is,
it's more than 10 hours return 10.
Then at the end,
I'm just gonna close the BRAC itself and you can see that both brackets went black.
If I hover over them and move,
you can see that encapsulates the entire argument on hit.
Enter.
Okay,
now I'm gonna copy that all the way across.
Control Andi are now.
At the moment,
we can see that we definitely have an answer off.
Five in here and 10 in here on Day five in him,
five in here and five in here.
But we don't actually know if that works.
So for now,
let's just delete that on.
We can see that yet.
Where's the house?
A lesson Five.
There was just deleted the value.
So now we can claim no money control and are Let's fill that back in.
So they go.
You've now built your first nested logical test.
So what?
It's done is It's said here,
look at D one and tell me if it evaluates to less than five hours and if it does,
I'm gonna claim nothing on.
Then,
if that's not true,
move on to a second logical test on.
Have a look at D one and see if it is less than 10 hours.
So therefore between five and 10 hours and if it is returned the value of five.
So we claim our £5 and if none of those two are true,
it must be over 10 hours.
And therefore,
I can claim £10 enter on.
There you go.
It's a simple has that you've no built.
Your first complex nested if formula.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.