Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Now hold on to your hats because we're going to cover an awful lot of ground in this
lecture.
Now,
what we're gonna do appears to be fairly straightforward.
What we're gonna work in here is this particular area.
We conceive that we have 1234 text boxes or four cells that just have text in them so we
can see in the first cell.
That says,
I declare that the above expenses are a true reflection of my expenses for week ending on,
then the date.
Now,
obviously,
all of this text needs to remain constant.
But this last bit of text,
the date needs to change each time for each week that we do this.
And again if we have a look at the second home and see June this week,
I traveled a total off.
Now that will be constant.
60 miles that's going to change depended on the weak women for which I have claimed will
become sent on 24 pen.
So the value that we're going to be claiming will also change depending on the number of
miles they some my time away from home.
I am took I am claiming that will be constant.
25 pens will be a variable because that may change.
So my toe total claim for this week is Andi.
That will be constant and then £49 will change.
So what we need to do is build a formula.
They will actually populate this,
but change the things that are going to change as they go through to stop you having to go
in and edit the text every time.
Okay,
so let's have a look at how we do that.
Simply we can see here that we have a total off 60 miles now.
I think before we let me just change that back for a second,
I think we were traveling 100 miles.
There were only change that back to six expenses aereo 60 miles.
So I traveled a total of 60 miles and 60 miles is reading from here.
We've got a couple of ways of doing this,
but what we're going to do just for simplicity's sake is demonstrate how we can turn that
from 60 to say 60 miles.
So let's have a look at building a simple formulas to do just that.
So we have our formula that says equal some of D 31 through J 31.
If we hit F two,
we can see that's just a straight some on that area there.
So let's just select that.
And just before the words some,
we're gonna have the word can.
Katyn eight.
Now all can Katyn.
Eight does is it joins text strings together.
So I've entered Can cattle eight open the brackets which will enclose the arguments And you
can see here the first thing that we require is text one.
Now we're gonna let this some be text one.
So I'm just gonna click to the end.
I'm gonna hit comma and then I can see that the next entry is text to now I do want Texas,
so I'm gonna hit the quotes on the tight miles and then we're closed the quotes and close
the brackets.
So what we've done is we said,
build us a formula.
It's a concoct,
innate enjoin that text,
which is the answer six takes its a some of the cells and then add the word miles after it
in the arguments being separated by a comma.
So let's hit.
Enter Okay,
It's almost good,
but we have 60 miles with no space in between.
So let's just go back to the formula.
Just click after the quotes and before the M and hit a space and then it center.
So they go now.
Our an Assad is 60 miles.
But look what's happened here.
We can see that we now have a value.
Now let me just don't do what we've done already a few times.
So we can see here that that no saves 27 because it's looking at cell l 31.
But when we redo,
we can see that that no fails because you cannot do a calculation on a text string.
So let me just read you get that one right?
So we're gonna have to do is modify this formula instead of reference in cell l 31 which is
going to add in the original formula that was in cell 31.
What we doing equals some move over one equals to some of these cells just here.
Closed brackets and they go.
We've got out Miley's claim back.
So instead of reference in this cell,
all it's going to do is do a some and then multiply it by 4.5.
Sorry.
0.45 which is the 45 p a mile.
Okay,
so far,
so good.
So there we have the word 60 miles in there.
So let's have a look at this one.
So here again,
we can just build a simple concatenation so equals on Katyn,
Nate open rackets,
quotes.
Because all of this will be constant.
June this week I have traveled a total off.
I don't believe the space in there.
After the off,
they closed the quotes.
I leave 60 miles in there just so we can see what we're gonna dio.
Let's just put a comma.
Ah,
Then we want to space.
So common open quotes.
Space for which I have claimed space Close brackets,
comma Andi.
Then close off the brackets.
Okay,
so now the two things that we have to enter are the 60 miles on the £24.
So let's just leave.
I'll put that in quotes for a second,
just so we can remember that.
That's what we've got to do.
First,
we're gonna have a look at the 60 miles.
So let's delete the 60 miles Come on,
then let's click off and then scroll up until we find a way.
It's a 60 miles just there and hit.
Enter.
So there we can see.
Say it's doing this week.
I've traveled a total of 60 miles and 60 miles is reading directly from cell L one
fantastic,
for which I have claimed £24.
Now the £24 we need to change because that's gonna actually no B £2027 yet.
So all we need to do is reference L l 21 at the end for which I have claimed I still eat
that now and screw lips stroll up to a mileage claim off £27 and enter.
Okay,
Now we're almost there.
Foot there.
Would it saves June.
This week I traveled a total 60 miles.
Good for which I have claimed 27.
But if we look at this sell,
it actually saves 27.
It says parents sign 27.0 So what we need to do is change the format in on this sell here.
All this last part just here where it says 27.
So let's have a look at how we do that.
Okay.
What we need to do is edit this last part of the formula.
Now,
what we wanted to display,
as is text.
So we're going to now use the text function.
So I'm just going to type in text on that,
open the brackets,
we can see that the value will looking at l 21 which is exactly correct.
We're gonna hit comma because we no need to enter.
The arguments on the arguments are encapsulated in quotes.
So what we want to do is hit quotes.
We want to it the pound sign because it was formatted as apparent sign on.
We wanted to show the number as a current say So pound sign 0.0 on.
Then we close the quotes and then we can squidgy over to the very end on we can close the
brackets on hit,
enter and they go that no looks perfect.
No,
it's just doing this week I've traveled a total of 60 miles,
which it's red from above,
for which I have claimed £27 which is also captured from above.
So in here we have no used the concatenation formula,
but We've also built a custom text format,
so our text actually hits escape.
So our techs actually displaced correctly.
OK,
so we're going to do now is repeat that exercise for these of the cells.
So let's do that.
Okay.
Next up I declared that I that I declare that the above expensive true flexing my expenses
for week ending on then the date which it's going to be reading from up here.
So the game most of the work is done.
We're just gonna come out the front and say equals captain nights.
Open brackets,
open quotes,
I declared the above expensive a true reflection.
Expenses for week ending will leave the space at the end.
So the format is tightening.
Will hit close quote because that's the text ring that we want comma.
And then we're gonna delete the rest of it because what we want to reference this time,
let's say if I scroll up is keep going,
keep going the date and then I'm just gonna close the quotes enter so you can see that we
have the almost the right.
And so we have I declare the expenses blah,
blah,
blah.
Week ending 4 to 216 on the reason it says 42 16 is It's referenced the date as the number
of days since the turn of the 19 at the turn of the century 1900.
So again,
what we're gonna do is we're gonna change the text format by typing text open brackets.
I six is the value.
So we're gonna come pass that we're gonna tow comma.
Then we're gonna enter our format for our techs.
And what we want is the d d.
The date Month,
month,
months on end 1234 year close.
The quotes moved to the end.
Close the brackets in his enter.
So they go.
So now I declare that the above expenses are a true reflection blah,
blah blah for week ending 31st of July,
2015 which is no being read from this cell.
Okay,
so we've done that one.
We've done that one.
And there we're gonna do this one based on my time away from home.
I am claiming 25 pens which it needs to read from there.
This is exactly the same thing again.
Equals come.
Cats and eight open brackets open quotes because we're gonna keep all of that text I am
claiming will leave the space at the end.
Man closed,
quotes coming.
Delete all that.
Andi.
That is the number we are claiming on closed brackets.
Enter on the game.
We can see that we just have 25.
So rather than saying £25 so we're gonna change the text format by entering text.
That is the value that we're evaluating.
Comer.
No,
we want to tell it in the formula open Quotes,
pound sign 0.0.
Close quotes close.
Brackets enter.
So that we can see based on my time away from home,
I am chained.
Am claiming £25.
Fantastic.
On my total claim for the week is that number there.
So my total claim from the week eagles come Katyn,
It's open brackets,
open quotes.
Because all of this is going to be constant.
Leave the space after the is closed.
Quotes come out.
Delete that.
And then we will point to hear my total claim.
Close quotes enter,
and then all we need to do is tied it at 52 up by changing this to a text format.
So t e X t open rackets.
L 50 is l value comma.
Open quotes,
payment sign.
Suter points inner zero.
Close quote close brackets and enter.
So there you go.
Now,
whatever values we have populated in the date on our mileage claiming our number of miles,
hamli miles have traveled total out of ours,
and our total claim will be easily and automatically built into this text.
A ring without any further need from modification.
Okay,
so they go.
That's how you build tech strings.
Using formulas on Haiti can change some of your entries by using the text function within
the concussion.
Eight.
Okay.
See you in the next lecture.