again,
guys from Welcome back.
Now,
In the next leg,
she gonna need to use the developer ribbon.
And if you don't have the developer ribbon available here,
say you get to it.
This is Excel 2010 which is the same for Excel 2010 in 2013.
Just come to file come two options and from options.
She's customized ribbon.
And over here you'll see Developer And just take that little box and click,
OK,
And then you will have the developer ribbon.
Now,
if you're on Excel 2016 it's very similar.
You just come up to file and you come to options and from options against use customized
ribbon and again,
just come over here to develop a tab.
Take that little button click.
OK,
And there you go.
Now you have the developer ribbon.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.