Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
Now we're progressing nicely,
and now we've come to this particular section just here.
Now I'm gonna split this section over a couple of lectures because we have quite a lot of
area to cover.
Now what we have is a bunch of ticked boxes s so we can see here what type of vehicle to
use and we have Carte it.
Now that's fantastic.
But because there's a fundamental issue in the way that this templates being set up,
I would imagine the intent behind this particular section is first to be able to choose
only one of the three options for each of these lines.
So I can see there have car,
Tex,
before I move over to motorbike on Tick that ideally what we want to do is untech the car
box automatically.
But the way it's being set up,
the moment is I can actually take all three or any combination of them and exactly the same
in the ones below.
So the first thing you think we're going to have a look at is have you actually add these
tick boxes on to begin with now?
Because I want to recreate this Exactly.
What I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna highlight this section hit control and see to copy it
on Mangan Dues click over here in the spreadsheets.
I'm gonna come to the pace special and you can see we get a bunch of extra options just
here on the bottom one just there.
Say's picture.
So I'm just gonna left click Picture.
And now I have a picture of exactly that highlighted area just there.
So I'm just gonna hit escape to get rid of the down CNN's and there because I have a
picture selected,
you can see I have a new option.
The top that saves picture tools for matter.
I'm just gonna go ahead and left.
Click that on a choose crop,
because all I'm really interested in is that bit just there.
So I'm just dragging over on hit crop again and they go,
No,
I can cheat.
I can delete all of this on then build an exact replica because I know what the original
look like.
Okay,
Now,
the way to select these things,
Obviously,
if you left click in them,
you're taking them.
So you need to right click and hit cut on.
Right click and cut and right Click and cut Sunday.
Go Now we started tabula rasa.
We'll have a blank slate and we can start again.
No way you'll find these little tick boxes is in the developer tab up in the ribbon just
here.
So I'm just gonna left quick developer on.
You're gonna look at the insert option.
Now you have two options in insert.
You have form controls and you can see you have a bunch of options.
Inform controls 1st 1 being the button and you have active X controls.
And you can also see that the first option you have is a button on.
A lot of these are replicated in both sections that we're going to cover form controls and
Activex controls later in the course,
but just for no.
The fundamental difference is that form controls are very basic on access.
Active X controls gives you greater flexibility so you can change the format in you can
have vb a code behind them and then much more powerful.
But these are just going to be simple check boxes.
So all we're going to do is pick the form control check box and click in our first box just
there.
So now you can see what you have.
Check box 123 Now because I find it a little bit fiddly to keep going up to the to the
developer time and hitting the uncertain picking at this time that Larrier appear.
What I like to do is I just do the one that I'm just going to right Click hit copy to put
it in the clipboard.
I'm gonna hit Control and V and Control and V.
And now I have three boxes that all look exactly the same.
So I'm just gonna left,
right,
click on the box and drag it up somewhere over here on Move it on the 2nd 1 I'm just gonna
right click groups.
Right?
Click on,
then drag it up there on but it more or less in line.
So move here.
Now it's a line these perfectly.
What you need to do is select all three.
Now,
obviously,
if you select them,
it just takes them.
So you need to,
right click,
Hold down,
shift right.
Click the next one and right click the one after that.
You can see we have a new Another new option of the top here in the ribbon called drawing
tools format.
So I'm just gonna left click that on.
What I want to do is choose a line and I want to align them all to the top,
said they all line up exactly.
And then I want to distribute them horizontally equally so again a line distribute
horizontally so they're all evenly spaced on their with them all selected.
What I'm gonna do is I'm gonna right click on Choose Group.
So now we have one graphic with three check boxes in it now,
because it's already selected,
I'm just going to hit control and see to copy than control V Control and V.
And now I get my nine boxes whips.
I don't mean to do that escape eso I'm just going to drag that one at the weight move here
on drag that one at the way groups.
Let's move that out the way they're move here and stick that one back up.
Onda move here.
Never I'm gonna do is I'm gonna select all of them,
so I'm just gonna hold down shift right Click first,
right.
Click second on groups,
right click the third.
Choose drawing tools Come back up.
I'm gonna rely in them to the left.
So the first box is always lined up,
and then I'm gonna align them vertically.
And now what I want to do is nudge them all up a bit.
So they line up perfectly.
So I'm just going to right click the 1st 1 hit shift,
right click the next one on.
Right.
Click the bottom one on with my arrow keys on the keyboard.
Just move up.
No.
Wanted to replicate this exactly.
So we can see that the middle one is more or less in line with the e of miles.
So I'm just gonna move over a squidgy,
move up on click off,
and they go.
That looks like an almost perfect representation of this.
The next thing I need to do is just one group them.
So I'm just gonna right click on group right click on group on right clips.
Missed it.
Last one right click on day on groups.
And they go now I have nine individual check boxes again.
The next thing we need to do is change the text.
So we're going to right click this particular box,
and we're going to choose edit text,
and then I'm just gonna tell you been car on,
delete the text,
it's already in there and hit.
Enter.
So we just need to right click each of these and change the text to match the original
documents.
So I'm just going to pause the recording for a second while I populate all of these.
Okay,
they go.
Now we have a version,
a new version that we just built from scratch that looks exactly like the original version
over here.
So now we've recreated that we can happily select the image hit delete on they go.
Now we have something that looks exactly like the original,
and then we're gonna learn how to do something useful with it at the moment.
This just is exactly what the original those.
And it allows us to pick multiple options in the same line,
which we don't want to do.
Okay,
So in the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at how you get these boxes to tick automatically based on a value
in a cell on.
We'll also have a look at a clever way of making sure that you only ever populate one of
those boxes.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.