Okay,
let's get started now.
Recovered in level one of this course that one of the most important things that you
conduce whenever you begin a new project is the first thing you should do is always rename
your worksheet to something more meaningful.
And you can see here that I'll rename this worksheet to time sheet and expenses,
Master,
because that's the name of the project that we're gonna be working on now before you spend
hours creating a masterpiece and excel with lots of fancy formatting and tons and tons of
data and formulas is proven at the concept that you're trying to achieve on the concept in
this project is very simple.
What we want to see is can we create a simple data entry screen where we can get a user to
enter the band minimum amount of data and take that data and have it populate multiple
reports elsewhere in the workbook without having to duplicate all of the work?
OK,
so we're going to do that very quickly now just so I can see where I'm working.
I'm just gonna highlight these cells so I can see where I'm going to drop the formulas we
can change it again later.
But this is just so we can see where I'm working.
So have just selected cell C one.
I'm gonna hear equal Satele IQ.
So it's a formula.
Move over to a one and his enter on.
We can see there in the formula Bar that we've now got a formula that say's I am reference
in cell A one.
Okay,
so far,
so good.
I'm just going to copy that down seven lines.
So now I am referencing on this cell,
sell a one in this cell cell a two and so on and so forth.
So no.
When I populate some data into here,
hopefully and it does,
it populates automatically over here.
So I'm just going to use a drag handle and use the auto fill sequence so we can see Yeah,
that concept's pretty much proven their weaken type something in here and have it
automatically populate over here without having to enter it again.
So far,
so good.
Okay,
the next thing we wanna have a look at is,
can we do the same in the same she in a different sheet.
So what I'm gonna do is add a new sheet to this workbook by clicking the little plus down
here.
And that's created sheet three.
That's unusual.
Let me just zoom in so we can see that nice and big older.
Now,
if you want to be able to see two sheets in the same workbook at the same time,
that's entirely possible in Excel.
All you're going to do is you're going to come up to the view ribbon just up here.
You're gonna hit view to change from the view ribbon and then you're gonna hit new window.
Now what you can see here,
let me just zoom in again.
We can see here is sheet one on behind sheet one.
We can see the same workbook again.
Now what we're gonna have to do is we're going to come back to the view menu and we're
going to hit view side by side on.
When we do that,
we can see that in this sheets on the left hand side,
Review and sheet one and so far in the right hand side were also viewing sheet one.
But what we can do,
She's click sheet three and there we have two views of the same workbook,
so I'm just gonna do exactly the same thing again.
But I'm going to do it in B this time.
I'm just gonna hit the home button high like that so I can see where I'm working on.
I'm gonna hit,
equals.
And this time I'm gonna flip over to the left hand screen and click a one on they go.
We can see that we now have Monday.
Just copy the formula down.
So whenever I type in here.
So if I say apples,
Godspell Apple's still can't spell apples,
apples and he sent it.
We can see that it's being updated here in this this array on the first sheet,
we can also see that's been changed over here on sheet three.
Okay,
let the only thing to notice here is with the formulas.
If we're working in the same sheet on,
we looked at the formula.
We can see it say's equals a one,
and that's because it's reference in a one on the same sheet.
If we had a look over here,
we can see that the formula has changed.
It no say's equals sheet.
One exclamation point a one on.
That's because the way Excel tells which sell a sheet is on.
If it's on the same sheet,
it doesn't have anything.
It just references the cell.
So a one over here.
But here it says you need to look in the same workbook we were looking for.
A different sheet on that sheet is called sheet one.
So they go sheet.
One exclamation point.
A one means look at cell a one on the sheet called sheet one.
Okay,
so they go near.
The concept has proved we can get on with building our data entry screen.
So you in the next lecture.