Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back to this Lynch.
Now,
Thesis section prompted a couple of observations.
firstly,
let me say that this expenses and time sheet template that we go through in the course is
one that actually used my contractor for the NHS for a couple of years.
And now the questions observations around this are two things one I knew about when I
didn't know about both of which we're gonna cover now,
here we have ah,
33 options car,
motorbike cycle,
petrol,
diesel LPG,
andan engines,
Engine size choice of three.
But if you don't know to only take one and let's face it,
some users wouldn't know to only take one.
What you can do is actually select two options.
So we get car and motorbike now the way around that you can protect this sheet and we cover
how to do that.
See the lecture after this,
all the electro after that.
But within 10 minutes,
you'll certainly know how to protect the sheet.
And that will force the user to use the data entry screen just here,
which is sort of the object of the exercise.
So Option one is to use protection.
And the second option is to not use tick boxes or check boxes,
but to use option buttons or radio button.
So I'm gonna cover that in this lecture.
No,
that's the part of this that I did know about.
The part of this they didn't know about is if you actually take a box in here,
it overwrites the formula that we wrote a little earlier.
Now it wasn't where that that happened.
Anyway,
we will find a way to get around that formula issue,
and we'll cover the shoes in radio buttons.
So Fanara here.
I'm just going to type radio buttons.
And this is the These are the cells.
That will be reference in shortly.
So for now,
I'm just going to come back to the expenses sheet,
hold down,
control left,
click left,
click left.
Click.
Pick all nine of these and move them out the way.
So we have an area where we can work.
So I'm just gonna left,
click and drag to move them down there More so so I can actually recall what the headings
are.
Now.
I'm just going to give you a quick demo of radio buttons.
Go to the developer ribbon come to insert just as we did with the tick box.
But this time,
choose radio button or option button left,
click and click,
and I'm just gonna hit control and see control and the Lego.
You can see that we now have two option buttons.
I'm gonna click off and look what happens when they click the 1st 1 It fills in.
But look what happens when I click the 2nd 1 The 1st 1 is unchecked because option buttons
by their nature only lay you to select one option because it's an option now.
I could easily add another nine of these by copy paste,
copy paste,
copy paste.
But they all remain within the same group.
That is,
I cannot have three sets of three if I just have nine buttons on because all nine are
linked.
So if I ticked car,
I couldn't take anything in the second line or anything in the third line,
and if I kicked,
clicked greater than 2000 si se automatically.
I couldn't have any of the other eight options.
Now the way to get around this is to group them together.
So when do take control and left.
Click on delete Control Left,
click on Delete Mangan do is gonna come up to insert.
I'm gonna come to this option here,
which is group box form control.
And when a dragon box down here that I'm gonna come to inset add radio,
but just click just inside here control and say control and they control and V so I just
couple of a couple of times I'm gonna roughly move them to where I want them to bay.
So Obama won a second more or less will do the lining up short.
Like so here.
I'm just going toe right Click edit text.
And I'm gonna type my computers really slow today.
Car here.
I'm going to right click and it text delete all the text that's in it and say motile bike.
I can't type in Texas saying that type and talk at the same time.
Right?
Click webs mis clicked,
right click and it text deleted all the text on a type cycle.
Okay,
I know what I'm gonna do.
I'm just gonna pause the video for a second.
I'm also going to make that box a little bit smaller now.
I have added those in.
I'm just gonna pause the recording for a section and add the other two groups of three and
I'll be back with you in just a second,
okay?
And we're back now,
I've just ended the three groups of three,
and I'm just going to click up all sort the alignment out in just a second.
But notice in the bottom group box,
I can click this one all.
This one,
all this one and the others and tick and the same with their second chip only click one at
a time.
So clear their car almost bike or cycle.
Now let's let's still with the alignment.
Now what I'm gonna do for a second,
I'm just gonna make sure that they all line up with these ones just here,
so at least we get them in the same kind of order.
So I was gonna movil these over here.
All I'm trying to do is make sure that this box is mawr left than any of these three.
That's probably awful English,
but I hope you know what I mean.
So I'm gonna hold down control.
I'm gonna hold down car that I'm gonna click this one this one and this one,
and I'm going to come to shape format align.
Remember they aligned to the left?
Most item.
So that's why we selected made sure that the car was the furthest to the left and I'm going
to click control and motorbike and that is Mawr left in the middle.
Three and I will click the other three come back ups,
shape,
format and align Onda line left Boop on,
then the same with cycle,
so he's gonna click off.
Hold down control Click cycle.
Click that one.
Click that one click that one shape format.
Align a line left may go.
They will be in exactly the same position as as these ones were here.
Now we just need to align them all to the top.
So again it's going to go to the top most.
So I'm gonna select those shape,
format a line on the line top and not bring those together.
Click off.
Hold on control.
Click that one that one on that one and come to shape format.
Align onda alike top,
then click off.
Hold them control car,
though,
to make cycle and come to shape format.
Align Elaine Top now,
in order to move these all together,
what I want to do is group them or at least make 23 groups of three accounting mats.
So going to hold them control and click the group box.
And I'm gonna click car,
motorbike and cycle.
And I'm gonna come to shape format group on group and they go Now I have that one there.
Then only their left click off Click this box Hold down.
Control Petrol,
diesel LPG just left clicking Group group And then again,
click off Click Group box 45.
Hold and control click The next rate missed that 1123 So just left clicking Group on group
Now what we're gonna do now is we're just going to move them over to those other where we
move the other things from.
So I'm just going to click off,
click the first group on Defy Congrats.
It left click Will source at the final lining up shortly.
Probably do in the gym that up a little bit.
Eso group box one for one.
And I'm gonna line that up with that.
That actually looks pretty perfect the way it is,
I think,
and then finally this box.
Andi uh,
legit over a little bit,
I think.
Anyway,
you can You can do the finer points shortly.
So that's what it looks like?
No,
unfortunately,
we have these awful lines around the glute group boxes and a little success group books one
for five group box,
but every list and all of the different group boxes,
so it actually looks pretty awful.
So what we're gonna do is we're just gonna left click each of these group boxes in turn
There's one and I'm gonna ungroomed them on.
This is gonna look really on inside a particularly if I can find them amongst all of these
.
So Group box got one at Andi on group.
I'm asking a levers to nudge these things around.
And hopefully I think I don't have court.
All three now,
obviously,
no,
I'll come back to that.
The point is that we have these awful boxes that look,
well,
awful,
really.
And then there is a bit of a work around to this on.
Didn't particularly want to delve into vb a this early,
but this is just one line of code,
so it will be fine.
Goes the developer Ribbon,
go to visual Basic Andi.
If you can't see something called the immediate window,
go to view and take immediate window and you'll get this here on.
What you want to do is type active sheet dr Group not check boxes,
group boxes not visible.
I can't talk in type and I hit the inside.
I really can't talk in type.
Can I?
Active sheet active Just won a active sheet.
Don't group boxes,
don't visible,
equals false and hit.
Enter.
Then when you come back to here,
um,
it's cause I'm missed that woman.
I did the grouping thing.
So shape format on group on group and then come back to the VB.
Just come to the end.
Active sheet dot group box is not visible,
equals false on hit enter and then you'll find that they have all disappeared.
And then we can happily just go and delete that and then close the VB.
So that's this far into visual basic for applications were going to get so far.
Okay,
so now we have three groups off three and we can only select one of the options.
So that answers part.
One of the question obviously lined them up to make it look very pretty goes to the data
entry.
And this is what we're gonna do now we're gonna point to radio buttons instead of what we
were pointing to before.
So we actually I'm just going to click all three of those.
So I'm going to click the 1st 1 hold down Control,
click the 2nd 1 on the 3rd 1 Right click.
It's slightly off screen,
but the very bottom option is format object and drag.
Rallying to shop there.
Cell link on.
I'm just gonna go over here and point to radio buttons.
And that's the 1st 1 Enter and okay,
I'm going to repeat the process for the second and third set.
So hold down.
Control Petrol.
Diesel L P G right click.
Sorry about this is the bottom option format object,
cell link.
And here I'm gonna point to this one.
And here center on.
OK,
And click off and finally hold down control and click the engine sizes.
Right.
Click again.
My party is full metal object.
Drag up sell link on a point to the very bottom one.
Just here and enter on.
Okay.
So,
no,
When I click off.
If I click the first option here in the first option here in the first option here,
you can see in the data entry screen that we have radio buttons 111 Because this is radio
button one in this group,
this is radio button one in this group on this is radio button One in this group.
But if I clicked 12 on three and then came to the data entry screen,
you can see that we have 123 here.
The woman say here is equals.
If,
uh,
this equals car,
then return one comer.
If open brackets,
this equals motor or bike,
then two comma failing that three.
So if this equals car returned one if it equals motorbike,
return to if neither of those two a true return.
Three close brackets twice hit enter.
So he'll be an option one.
And we have an option one in here.
But here,
if we have option to this changes to number two.
And in an expensive,
expensive,
expensive sheet Motorbike kiss ticked.
Now again,
what we're going to do to save over right in these formulas,
we're gonna protect the sheet.
I'm gonna come to that in the next lecture of the lecture.
After that,
I'm just going to do exactly the same thing for petrol,
diesel,
LPG and exactly the same thing for these three options here.
Hopefully that's helped,
but is always if there are any questions,
I wouldn't delete that before you download it.
If there any questions do,
let me know and you can download this election is called Time Sheen Expenses,
Expenses Master with radio buttons.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.