Okay,
guys,
we're nearly at the end of this particular section.
Now.
The project is a little bit in complete on.
I've done that on purpose.
So you can see in here that we can enter a week ending.
We can interact,
start times and finish times and all these things.
And these are now automatically populating over here,
which is all good.
And we're also automatically populating all the way over here.
But we've missed one.
Okay?
Now,
what we've missed on the expenses form is the date.
we could go ahead and type that in.
But what I want you to do is a practice exercise is build something into this form just
here so the user can enter today's date on.
I want you to be able to flip over to the expenses form and have that date automatically
populate in here.
Now,
at the moment,
you know that if you automatically reference another cell with the date in,
it will probably return a number.
So what I want you toe also do is format the date.
So it appears as the day name in short.
So if it's Friday,
it will say,
F r I And then I want a space.
And then the date the number of the date,
the month in short form.
So January would be jam on the year in a two digit format.
So,
for example,
it would say Fry.
06 Mar 2015.
Okay,
when you've done that,
just take a screen cap of it and post it in the in the side of the screen.
There s so we can all see that you managed to do it.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.