Okay,
guys,
in this section,
we're gonna have a look at building database use and excel as a front end.
Now,
one of the functions that we're going to use is the V.
Look up.
If you've not used the look up before,
you'll probably certainly have heard an awful lot of things about it and generally is
considered to be on advanced skill in Excel.
If you can usually look ups,
we're going to go way beyond V looks in this section.
But just so you can understand them simply,
I've just created this simple spreadsheets called simple V lookups,
which you can download,
and in here you can see that we have a data table.
No,
we have Helling's up here,
which I'll just call a real Let's make them red for a minute.
So we have names and we have Allen,
Jame,
Bob,
June Harry and Joe Joe on We have a hair color,
which is non for make some bold blonde ginger,
black brown and multicolored hair.
Because Joe's a very colorful character.
Okay,
now what we're gonna do is create our first V look up formula so you can see what it does
now.
The first thing we need to do is enter a value that we want to look up.
So over here in this cell,
I'm just gonna color this selling.
So we know this is the one that were entered and value into We're gonna enter the word Joe
and you can see that,
Joe is someone in our list up here.
Now,
What we want to find now using the V look up formula is what color hair just Joe have.
So we're gonna hit equals V.
Look up.
We're gonna open brackets and you can see in the tool tip that's just appeared underneath.
The first thing we want to look at is the look up value.
Now,
the look of value is this value just here because that is what we want to look up nice and
straightforward so far.
So I'm just going to click on that cell and hit comma,
separate the arguments.
They're the next description say's table array.
And what that means is the data table where you want to actually read the data from.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna highlight all of this section here so you can see
that our index are unique reference,
that is,
Joe appears in the first column on That's absolutely critical to be lookups.
What you looking up must appear in the first column of the data set.
Okay,
so now we've highlighted this section just here.
That's our table array of data table hit,
comma there.
The column index number is the column we want to return a value from.
So this will be the first column where our index lies on.
This will be the second column,
so we're going to say is column is number two because we read him from the second column
hit Comma.
And now here we have another choice.
We can either hit True,
which will give us an approximate match.
So that means if we entered something like Elaine instead of Joe and the Lane doesn't
appear in the list,
it will find the closest thing to Elaine.
Generally,
you're going to be looking for exact matches,
so you'll be typing false.
And that means find me an exact match to the look of value,
which is a nine,
which is Joe on return.
Whatever is in Column two.
So let's hit entrance.
It does.
They go so we can see from RV look up formula that it has looked as this cell here it's
gone down all of this range.
Bom bom bom bom bom bom bom until you find Joe and then it's going to read from the second
column,
and it's going to return the value in there so similarly we could type Jane and it would no
se blonde because it is now looking at a nine Jane.
It's looking in this range a one to be seven,
which is this area just here.
It's reading the second column on its gunned down the list.
It's failing Jane on its reading from the second column.
Exact match.
So if we typed Bob and it doesn't have to be case sensitive,
we can it enter.
We can see the Bob has ginger hair.
OK,
so simply that's how the lookups work.
We're gonna make them much more powerful than that as we work through this section,
but they get may you have a basic understanding of how they work.
Let's cracker