Okay,
guys,
One of the first things that we probably want to do when creating are simple database is
ensured that the users always enter the data that we're looking for that we want to look up
for in the correct format.
So we're going to be looking at the employee number,
which we can see we have down here.
There's a very simple way of doing this to ensure that the users only enter the correct
data.
Just gonna auto size up for a second and color that in because that's the That's the cell
we want them to have a play with,
Right?
So there's a very simple way of doing this and it's using the data validation.
So what we're gonna do is come up to the top here,
quick data,
and then come over to this option,
which say's data validation.
So I'm just gonna left click,
and you can see at the moment we have a layer any value on a little down arrow.
So woman do is click the little down arrow on.
What we want to do is limit them to a list.
So I'm just gonna quick the list and you can see in the source box.
Here we have this little colorful box It's gonna left Click that flip over to the HR filed
.
Now I'm going to ignore the first column head in Someone started line to hit shift control
and down Andi.
In fact,
I'm gonna go all the way down.
So that way,
when we had Mawr cells in there or more data in there,
they'll also appear in the list.
So basically,
we've highlighted almost all of column A.
We've just missed out employee number.
So I'm just gonna click that little button again.
Onda We can have input messages here so we could say Let's say please select from the drop
down menu.
Oh,
please select from the drop down,
let's say that's obviously limited s Oh,
yeah,
so let's say it was Copy that and put it in there.
Police right from the drop down list,
I have a raptly keyboard this morning on Let's also do the ever let that say stop on,
let's say in 1,000,000 entry on didn't just have a look at what that does on.
Then there we can say,
Please select from the drop down list.
Okay,
right.
Let's Let's have a look what we've done.
So I've limited it to a list.
We have chosen the list that we want them to pick from.
We've added an input message with the title Assess.
Please select from the drop down on.
Then the input message says,
Please select from the drop down list.
We also have an error relates,
so we're just going to click.
OK,
so now you can see that when we select this cell will automatically get this little pop up
that say's please select from the drop down list.
And that should give the usual indication what they should be doing.
Eso If we try to type something wrong in there like this and hit enter,
will mail get this era May message pop up,
which we've just loaded into the data validation that says invalid entry,
which is what we said.
Please select from the drop down list.
So click council.
And there when we hit the little drop down West,
we can see that we have all of their options in here.
All of their employees non mercifully dragged all the way down.
We go all the way down to number 200 so they go so we can just pick one of those.
Let's just also size it.
Okay,
so they go.
And that's how you do data validation.
And that ensures that the users only input data in the format that you want it.
Okay,
in the next section,
we're going to build our look up formulas and finish this simple database sheets off.
So you in the next lecture.