Okay,
guys,
we're gonna add in our V Look up formulas.
Andi,
we're gonna tidy this up a little later on,
so we'll have these things appear in somewhere else.
But for now,
let's just build our first formula.
So we're going to say equals V.
Look up because we're doing the V.
Look up.
Function open brackets.
Now the look of value is this one here that they're just selected from the drop down list.
Now,
at the moment you can see that that saves be.
For now,
what we want to do is just drag this formula down that have it always reference before.
So I'm just gonna make that an absolute cell reference by hitting f for once.
And you can see that we get the dollar sign before the be on the dollar sign before the
four on that.
No.
Means it's an absolute reference on no matter where we drag this particular formula,
it's always gonna look at that cell.
Okay,
so,
comma table array.
Now,
that's our HR file.
Andi,
this time what I'm gonna do You want to come right up to the top?
Hold down shift,
hold down,
control and go all the way to the bottom.
Let me just stir scroll so you can see that.
So shift control and down on all the way over to the end off our data.
So that's our table array.
And again,
I'm gonna hit f four cause we don't want this to move down as we drank the formula.
So I'm just gonna hit f four to make it absolute a absolute one to absolute a h absolute
201 among in a hit comma.
And then the 1st 1 we want to read from is the second column over.
So here's our index and this will be the second column.
So I was gonna hit to comment on I want an exact match,
so I'm gonna type false on closer brackets and hit Enter.
So there you go.
We can see that in m N C dash blue triple.
Ooh,
too is hurry.
In fact,
what we're gonna do,
let me just go back to data validation there on.
I'm gonna shift that box so it doesn't appear so.
Date of elevation show input when cell is selected.
No.
Okay,
right.
Just because that's getting in the way of that at the moment now because of absolute
referenced this cell and of absolute referenced this entire table.
I can happily just drank that all the way down on it will copy that formula.
Exactly.
But you'll notice that even down here,
it's still reference in absolute be absolute for so because we copied these in exactly the
same order as they appeared across here.
We know that these air in the natural order So we have column 1234 and so on.
So this one say's comer to cause it's pulling from column two.
So we're just gonna change that.
123 We're going to change the next 1 to 4 on.
This is just straightforward,
countin so nice and easy to do.
I hope you don't make a mistake now.
Five.
Andi six.
Andi seven.
Andi,
where my eight There.
Okay,
eight.
Now we can see that we've got these numbers appeared and you'll remember from the first
section that we just have to change the date format.
So back up to home,
back up to number formats and lets you short date.
Let's just resize those.
Let's have them all aligned over to the left.
Okay,
So they go.
We now have a simple V look up and we can choose anything in here,
and we can see that it's pulling from column to column three common for come 567 and eight
.
So,
whichever one the user chooses,
let's come down.
Number 90 is Milly Johnson.
Four Main Millie Johnson National Insurance number.
She's female.
That's the date of birth.
And that's when she started without company.
Now what we're gonna do is move all of this,
so I'm just gonna highlight all of it and click on the dark box or the dark line at the top
left,
click and just move it over here for a minute on.
Then we're going to move the monitor time.
So I'm just highlighting the first name,
which is the title on the formula by left Clicking and Dragon on.
We're gonna have that come here ongoing do the same with last name,
and I'm going to drop that in here.
So I'm just selecting the two sells the one with the title and the one with the formula
left,
click and drag over on.
Then I'm gonna left groups.
Now we're gonna left click on the dark line around it on.
Drop it in there on.
Then the national insurance number will have over here.
Onda,
the Sanks we will have over here on.
We'll have the date of birth of he have have that there on the start date with company over
here,
I'm just gonna highlight all of that double click on they go.
It's automatically formatted.
So if we want to set a background for that,
we could just highlight.
Actually,
we don't need to highlight that much don't like,
so let's highlight all of that.
Make it a nice That's an awful killer.
Let's make it that color and then we'll change that cell two,
White said.
The user can see that that's wedding in the enter on.
We can move that,
and it's now going to change all of their entries,
depending on what the user picks out of here.
So they go.
That's a simple data entry screen or simple database.
Now we can hide all of these columns and hide all of these rows,
as we did in the last section.
So all the user sees is this particular section here,
those calling him awfully.
So let's just change that font color of those two black on those and those.
So they go.
We have a simple database.
In the next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at how to make it a little bit more powerful,
for which we're going to need more data.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.