Okay,
guys,
let's have a look at how we import some mawr data.
Now,
if you imagine the scenario of someone's just said who have another file in a text format
that has our department structure on it on what we're going to do now is create a space for
that by adding a new sheet by just clicking the plus Here,
I was gonna drag it over to the end on.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna come up to data we're going to choose from text.
I'm just gonna nervy eight to my desktop and you can see here we have this file department
structure on.
I'll put this in the download section so you can download it and have a play yourself just
can double click it on here.
We get this import with it again so we can see that we could We have it set to delimited.
We can click next on.
We can see that there.
It's pretty much worked as exactly what it should do.
We have employee number.
Then we have the delimit er we have the department on the department name and they're on
the job title.
I think that's the end of the data on we're gonna hit next.
Andi them.
We're going to say finish.
And this is where we want to pace the days room from a once.
I was just going to click.
OK,
they go.
So no,
we have a new data table in here.
So we have employee number departments and job title on DWI should have that for about 200
people,
which is the number of people in our HR database.
They go on.
What we're going to do is just change the title of this sheet here to say I've just chosen
rename on this is department structure departs meant stroke chow.
Okay,
so that's simply how you import data from a text file in the next lecture.
We're gonna have a look at how you import data from a word document.
So see you in the next lecture.