Okay guys, let's have a look at how you import data from a Word document.
Now it's very straightforward.
Again, we're going to need somewhere to put the data.
So I'm just going to hit the little plus button to add a new sheet.
And then what we'll do is open the Word file,
which is this one just here.
And you can see that in this one we have
national insurance number or address one, address two,
address redress for address five,
and something else over the n there.
So all I'm going to do,
he's hit Control and I try to highlight everything.
Hold Control and C to copy it.
Then I'm just going to come into cell A1,
right-click and Paste Special.
And I'm just going to auto size,
not call it those columns that and they go now we have
a new file and it looks like we have national insurance number address one,
address two, just re-adjust fall address five,
which looks like the postcode.
And you'll notice creatively,
everyone lives in exactly the same streets.
They all just live next door to each other.
Okay, so that's how you import data from a Word file.
Now what I'm gonna do just to make this uniform is I'm going to flip back to the HR file.
Highlight row one, double-click the Format Painter.
Come back to the department stroke chat and just hit lie on one there.
So that gives us the same green highlighting.
And when it come to sheet 2,
the one we've just done and do exactly the same thing again.
Now I'm going to hit to Skype.
So we're back into normal mode.
And now we just need to rename this.
So I'm just going to right-click choose rename.
And this looks like It's addresses and enter.
So there you go. Now we have a base data file
which have already created a simple base, the base off.
We have our department stroke jet,
which tells us which department folks are.
In fact, let's just freeze the panes there.
So we're going to go to I'm just
highlighting row two because I want to freeze the panes of both.
Go to View, Freeze Panes,
Freeze Panes and that way we can happily scroll.
And we have addresses and we'll do the same thing without some highlights,
HER2 Freeze Panes, Freeze Panes.
And here we have all of our addresses.
So fantastic. We now have three data sources and a simple database already built.
Now in the next lecture we're going to have a look at how
we make this a little more powerful.
So see you in the next lecture.