OK,
guys.
Now we're gonna build our third simple database screen.
So I'm just going to copy this one again,
just like we did before.
I'm gonna create a copy and again move it in front of the HR file.
So it appears just here,
so Okay,
simple database three.
Now,
what we have at the moment is in this file,
we have the employee number as the first column.
And in this file or this tab,
we also have the employee numbers.
The first column,
But in the new one that we want to look up from,
we don't have the employee number at all.
But we do have the national insurance number,
which is appearing in our H R file somewhere there.
Mega.
So what we're gonna do rather than use this cell,
just hear the employee number to pull the data through?
What we're going to use is a national insurance number to pull the data through.
So I'm gonna do what we did before.
I'm just gonna flip to address is I'm gonna leave national insurance on because we've
already reported on that it's going to copy these cells,
so I'm just gonna hit copy,
flip back to database three.
And I'm gonna transpose those in here just like we did before.
Now we're gonna do exactly the same form,
and so it's very look up,
open brackets.
But instead of points into this cell,
we're gonna point to this cell because this is the national insurance number,
which is the first column in this tab.
Okay,
so again,
we want an absolute cell reference so we can happily drank the formula anywhere we want by
hitting F four.
So that gives us a dollar signs before the e on the full comma.
Now,
I'm gonna come to the address is on the national insurance numbers in our first column.
So I'm gonna select column a hold down shift away over to the end Whole control on.
Go down.
Hit F four because we're dragon.
This formula around,
we don't want this data terrible to drag around.
So we have absolute a absolute one to absolute f absolute to one comma now,
one of Paul address one which we can seize in the second column.
So I'm gonna hit two for the second column.
Come a false because he wanted exact match.
Close brackets Andi intact Now what we're gonna do a drug that formula down and then just
change the column numbers.
So we have column to here.
The next one,
we're gonna have column three in the next one will have column four,
and the next one will have column five on the post code or ZIP code.
Will be in column six,
in fact.
Weaken,
Enter.
We can change that and call it post code.
Okay,
let's stick these where we want them to go.
So I'm gonna put on we've addressed one their dress.
I'm gonna put the country.
I think I put the postcode over here postcode country in drug these things that any way you
want them.
So just insert move down on D We'll have another space that and said move down and then
just pretty up the formatting.
And so I'm just gonna copy the formatting from here.
Pasted over there.
Andi,
I think these were bowled before,
so we made those bold actually changed address for two country.
Okay,
so there you go with we've no successfully managed to build a simple database using a
single V look up to populate this on this from here,
we've also used exactly the same look up to pulled different data from a different source.
The department structure aan den,
using a value that we've looked up.
You using this?
We've no pulled all of this data from 1/3 source,
so hopefully you can see that you don't always need to look up from exactly the same value
.
As long as you have a single common element you can always use that to look up from.
So let's test this out.
So let's let's go to our first employee.
Who we can see is Kama Phillips on this.
Fulham's common comment Phillips and his national insurance on that is JT 590548 b So e M
column.
Phillips is definitely our first employee department struck chat groups missed that one
department structure.
He is the ease in the directorate,
and he is the CEO and he used the directorate in the use the C O.
Then,
if we look at addresses,
we can see that comma.
Let's roll all the way up or more to the point national insurance on that JT 590548 b,
which is exactly what it is lives at number one anywhere road.
And that's exactly what this is returned.
So if we looked at number two,
we can see that all of these things update.
And we are now what to anywhere Road.
So we can flip through any of these.
And the user just needs to slight one value,
and everything here will update on.
Everything here will update.
So there you go.
That's Hey,
you build a multilevel,
simple database using Excel.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.