Okay,
guys,
in this later,
we're going to address some of the common issues that most uses at some point or other will
have when using v lookups.
No,
generally these air down Teoh,
data heiress,
And I'm just going to clarify that they fall into two distinct categories normally.
And they are words or numbers,
so we'll cover words first.
Now,
at the moment would have done is I've created this little data entry cell,
so I've colored in yellow.
This is where we're looking up from,
and I have a very simple data table here with names down the first column and ages down the
second column on Built A simple V Look up here.
If I hit F two,
we can see that a 13 hour look at value is looking here.
Data Array is a one through B 11 which is this area here were reeling from the second
column,
which is age on.
We're looking for an exact match,
which is false.
So when I type Tracy,
everything's hunky dorey and we get 24.
If I type David,
we get 29 which is exactly what we expect.
And if I type John Uh we get in error there.
One of two things has gone wrong in this instance.
Now you may be looking at this and think I know exactly what that is.
The John in here is a capital J on the John.
Down here is lower case of the first thing you'll probably try is capitalizing the J.
But you'll still get exactly the same era on DVI.
Lookups are case insensitive,
so it doesn't matter whether it's all upper case or lower case.
Proper case.
Total case.
Any case,
it doesn't make any difference to the You look up,
so a relies in one of two places.
It's either here with the value we're looking up or it's here with John in this data table
.
And the most common mistake that people make with these kind of things is that if they look
at this cell,
they'll say how that,
says,
John and I look at this cell and that says John to so what could possibly be wrong?
Well,
if we click into the formula Bar on our data entry,
that's this cell here.
We can see that specifically and exactly this cell says J O H N and nothing else.
OK,
so that's good.
But if we have a look at John here and click in the formula Bar,
we can see it's actually different.
It says J O H n.
And then we can see that we have a space between the M on where our curses blinking on.
That's because we have a spare space,
a trailing space at the end of the name.
Now because we've told Excel to look for an exact match,
it hasn't actually found an exact match.
The 1st 4 letters are exactly the same,
but in the data table we have an extra trail in space which essentially makes it a
different entry.
So all we're gonna dio is delete that and press enter.
There's a very quick way of getting rid of all of these problems.
If you have them on,
that's always My first check is Do I have any trail in spaces?
So here we go.
What we're gonna do is use the trim functions.
I'm just going to say equals trim,
open bracket.
So I'm gonna point to this cell just here on I'm gonna close the brackets.
So now I have Allen,
and I'm just gonna copy that all the way down.
So now I have what appears to be exactly the same data in here on exactly the same data in
here.
So if I was to type Allen,
we can see that Allen also heiress,
because Allen also has a trail in space.
So we've used trim.
We've pointed to this cell,
and this data set here will have no trailing spaces.
All we're gonna do,
right click copy,
come over.
Original data,
right Click pay specials.
Values on that will no load all of the names in here.
But all of the trailing spaces will have been removed.
So now I can safely delete that and they will have a data table that works.
So let's just check that with John again.
They go and John's 27 years old.
Okay,
that's the normal problems that you would encounter with words.
Now let's take a look at numbers,
okay?
With numbers.
Normally it's a formatting issue.
So at the moment,
have created a simple data table here that says 123 all the way through 10 and bunch of
colors at the side.
This is the value.
We're looking up and This is RV.
Look up formula.
So we're looking at a 12 Zoellick of value.
That's this one.
Our data ranges a one through B 10 which is here we're looking at from the second Column
and we're finding an exact match.
Now,
we could look at this and say,
Well,
I have a number five in here and I have a number five in here s O That really should work.
But this is a formatting issue.
What we actually have here is the number five on.
If we look at the data in this cell,
what we actually have is apostrophe five.
Now it's also being right aligned,
so it does look like it's a number,
but Excel will actually treat that as text,
which is completely different to a number.
So we have the text five in a data file on the number five is our look up value.
Now,
if this is if your source data is something that refreshes and your important,
it it,
it expounds as you're working through it.
The last thing you want to do is go through and removal these little apostrophes because
there could be thousands of entries.
The simplest way to solve this one is just go to your look up value and change that to the
format in your data table.
So I'm just going to introduce a little apostrophe before the number five and hit Enter.
And now RV.
Look,
it works perfectly.
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.