Okay,
let's have a look at building are simple data entry screen there.
The first thing we're gonna do is we're going to stick a title in for our worksheet on.
We're gonna call it Data and Tree Screen on.
And let's just merge in center that Let's have it in green cause greens nice.
I like that green.
Have it old and increased the font size.
If you don't have to do this,
take a look.
At course one because we recover that fully in course,
one on all the different for matins for text and merge in central stuff like that.
Okay,
so we need a few gaps in here,
selects and set some lines on.
The first thing we're gonna need is the week ending date service.
Just a week and on,
and we're gonna be entering that in there.
Now.
What I like to do is some is to format the cells into a different color for particularly
for data entry screens.
Because that is an indicator to the user of which sells.
It is they should be filling in that we can look a little later.
Hey,
you can local the other cells,
so they can actually feel anything in that you don't want them to.
But for now,
let's just enter a simple data entry with the Four Matic.
So there we go.
We want people to enter stuff in there.
We need assuming no weeks out some Monday.
We need Monday,
Tuesday,
Wednesday,
Thursday for exactly Sunday Onda We condole it.
Rest of it because there are only seven days in a week.
Now let's insert a little more from the time sheet that were populating.
We can have a look at what entries We actually need to tohave the user enter into here.
So let's just bring you up on the screen here and we can see what we want to do.
So we need a start time in the morning.
So we're gonna put something in here.
We need to start time in the afternoon.
Sorry.
We need a finish in the morning.
We need a lunch,
but we're gonna calculate that.
So what we then need is a start time in the afternoon on.
We need a finish time in the afternoon.
Pretty much everything else we can calculate out.
So let's just stick some hellions in there.
So we have start on.
We have finish on bets.
Just copy those.
Stick him over there again.
If you If you're not sure about the copy and paste in,
check out level one of this coarser because we cover all of the basics in there.
So what we're gonna do is we're just going Teoh sent to the text over there so we can see
that that style.
That's finish since the text over there on,
we're gonna have this merged and centers will call that working hours.
Okay,
so they go,
we've got a quite Deb.
That's a little untidy.
So let's just delete that,
uh,
a small uniform.
Okay,
so now we have the basics of a data entry screen.
So in here,
we can see because the cells are in blue.
This is where we want the the users to enter the data.
We have a weekend in which corresponds to this box.
Over here.
We have our star times on Monday morning,
Tuesday Wednesday,
35% is Sunday,
which we're going to populate into here.
We have a finish time in the morning,
which populates over here.
Andare start time in the afternoon and I have finished time in the afternoon.
Okay.
Oh,
I forgot something.
We need also insert.
We need another one over there.
Don't waste.
So we need to say am Andi.
Let's just copy that.
Dump that in their on call that p p And so they go.
No,
we can see that we have our working hours in this area.
Just here.
This is the morning.
This is the afternoon.
This will be our starting.
My morning.
Finished time.
Morning.
Start time in the afternoon From this time in the afternoon.
Okay,
Let's have a look at how we end some data in as time.