OK,
guys.
Now here's another problem that you may come across now created this standalone Excel file
just to demonstrate this.
And it's called catching various inconsistencies in user entry.
Now,
in the HR database that we've created so far in the look up section.
Other than the car Reg in the first few databases we used a limit to list.
So that way the user could only pick something that's in the less than there's absolutely
no way for them to typing in incorrectly.
Now,
one of Delhi's of butchers,
some of that data and dropped in here and in here.
I've put the car registration first.
This is just a cut down version of that list on what I'm gonna do here is I'm just gonna
hit control and h hit space,
and I'm going to replace the space with absolutely nothing.
So I'm just gonna hit replace all we've known made 10 replacements.
Okay,
so what we have is a database with car registration with no spaces whatsoever between the
letters and the numbers.
So the problem is one.
If when you have a user entering a car registration number,
they accidentally interest space because maybe they say the two lessons,
the two numbers,
then a space,
then the West,
three letters.
Maybe they even put a space between Absolutely everything will look elite.
There's a clever way of dealing with that.
So let's have a look at that now.
So here's the value I'm gonna be looking up from,
so I'm just going to color that in so we know what it ISS on.
I'm just gonna for now,
I'm just gonna copy that value and paste over there.
So we do have something to look up.
So this is the value we're looking up,
and we're gonna do these columns exactly as they are in the V.
Look up.
So let's just write a simple V look at first equals V.
Open brackets.
We are looking there.
Now,
we're going to drink this formula across,
so I'm gonna absolute cell reference that by hitting f four so no,
no matter where we drank this cell,
down or across,
it's always gonna look at that cell.
Okay,
so there's our look up value comma data table will be this and you'll remember envy,
Lookups that what you're looking up has to be in the first column of your data Sable.
So I'm highlighting column a four down a 13 Onda away across to I 13.
Okay,
so there's our table array.
I'm gonna hit therefore,
because again,
I don't want that table to move.
When I drank the formula coming,
I'm gonna look a column index took some.
Wanna pull the employee number here?
Comer.
I want an exact match.
So false.
Fantastic.
Now I'm just gonna drag that away over control,
And,
uh and I just need to change the color numbers.
So we have column number two and Colin,
number three.
Now,
just pause this for a second,
and I'll come back to you when these rolled down.
Okay,
hold on.
So now we're looking up zed I 09 g s s and were successfully pulling from column to here
Column three here on the same all the way across.
So we pull in all of this data set over,
but one if when the user enters this state at what they actually type is zed I zero known
space G s s where you can see that we get a bunch of letters because we're looking for an
exact match.
Zed I 09 space G s s does not appear in this list.
So therefore an exact match can be found.
So all of our formulas era.
Okay,
Now,
there's a very simple way of getting rid of this problem.
So what we're gonna do is modify our look at value,
which is this one here to remove the spaces.
So what we're gonna need to do for that is fine.
Now,
look at value in our formula.
Just here.
And just for a second we're going to enclose that in another set of brackets,
their fate ends,
or it won't affect the former in the slightest.
So if I deleted the space out of there,
just bracketing off that part of the formula won't stop it working.
So everything is still good.
So what do you just put my space back in?
So now we have bracketed off this particular formula.
Now what we want to do is remove all of the spaces in there.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna type substitute open brackets and you can see in the
substitute that the first thing is looking for Is the text on that?
Is this particular cell here,
this one because that's where our text lives.
So we're happy that that's what it's going to substitute.
We're going to hit comma,
and they're what we want to tell it is what old text do we want to look for to substitute.
So we're gonna hit quotes,
space quotes,
because it's the space that we want to get rid off.
We're going to hit comma.
And now it wants to know what is the new text that you want in place of the old text.
So what do you want to substitute the old text with on?
We're just gonna hit a double quotes.
So now we've said effectively in this substitute.
Look at this cell here.
Absolute a 15 on find any spaces and replace it with no spaces.
Now all I'm going to do now is close off the brackets.
Hey,
center.
And there you go.
You can no see that this value is successfully looking up Number seven here,
even though the actual value in the look up table says and I 09 g s s and we're actually
looking up the same thing with space.
So even if we deleted the space.
This look up still works,
and even if the user happens to a groups happens to enter sent space.
Always space zero space night.
Any combination of spaces there will still be stripped out on this look up will still work
perfectly.
So that's one quick way to adapt any user interest to remove spaces.
And it doesn't have to be spaces.
If,
for argument's sake,
let's just removal spaces in there.
Let's imagine that the user has a habit of entering a dash.
So if the use rented zed I zero nine dash g s s and entered,
that would fail.
But all we need to do is modify this substitute instead of looking for a space,
look for a dash.
On they go.
You can see that that formula still works perfectly.
Now I'm just gonna put that back two spaces for a second on Delete that and leave space in
again.
Now,
the quick way to modify all these formulas so they look at exactly the same thing is to
copy the part of the formula you want to work on replace the part of the formula that
doesn't work.
So in these formulas that everything we can see that we have a look up off just that value
there.
So what we're gonna do is copied the bit That does work,
which is groups not quite there.
Everything from the substitute,
they're So this is the part.
The formula does work.
I'm just gonna hit control and see to copy That hits escape.
Now,
I'm gonna just going to highlight all of this line hit control and H which is find and
replace,
which we use a little earlier to remove the spaces out.
Controlling V Sorry,
Control and V,
that is what we want to replace it with.
And what we want to replace is just the A 15 but the absolute a 15.
So we want to look across all of these like all of these formulas in this row on replace
absolute a absolute 15 with this new modified entry here.
So replace all.
Hold on a replacements.
Okay,
so now this look up successfully works across the whole of the road.
And now just a test that it will let we'll just use this cell here.
So we typed.
Why G 53 space F r j.
You can see that That still works perfectly.
Okay.
See you in the next lecture.