So here we go.
We have exactly the same day to set in here,
but what we're going to do is create a virtual concoct in a tid V Look up.
String on.
We're going to use that to look up the value of the national insurance number.
If that's not clear at the moment,
stick with me.
Because it will become very clear very shortly.
So let me just copy those headings from here.
Uh,
that's what we want to do.
Copy on.
Let me just paste them in here.
Okay,
So now we have a first name,
the last name to a cut for,
and we want to return our national insurance number in here.
Now,
what we did before when we use the backwards V look up was that we used the index a match
function,
and we're going to do exactly the same thing again,
just with a slight modification.
Okay,
Hagos.
So what we're gonna type is index because we still want to look at the whole data table
inner index.
So we highlight in the whole dates able because the index requires the full data set.
You'll remember.
Okay,
Comma there were going to go match,
just as we did before open brackets.
But this time we're going to say hurry on.
And Mitchell?
So we're looking at both of those sets.
Okay,
so we're looking at Harry Andi Mitchell.
So they're joined together.
So comma,
and then we wanna have a look at Harry in this column.
So we're just gonna highlight that column,
okay?
And then we're going to hit.
And so Harry is being looked for in this column on our second value is gonna be looked for
in this column,
and then we're gonna hit comment on We're gonna find an exact match,
which is Aaron.
Close the brackets.
And that's how much part sorted out said they were sorted out.
Which road number?
We're in,
comma.
And we want to find the national insurance number from the full day to set.
So that's 1234 columns across for closer rackets and enter now.
You may not have expected that to happen every time we've entered a formula.
Up until this point,
we've just had enter.
When we've come to the end of our formula now array formulas a slightly different.
You may sometimes hear them referred to as C.
S E formulas,
which are control,
shift and enter formulas.
Aled.
That means that when you type this formula just going,
click back in the formula Bar for a second is you don't hit enter to make the formula work
because we can see that that returns an error.
What we do is we select the formula by clicking in the formula bar,
hold down control,
hold down shift and then press enter and you'll notice that yet these curly brackets at the
end of the formula and at the beginning of the formula on that tells you that this is an
array formula.
All that means is that it's building an array in its virtual memory on Can Cassin eight in
these two strings together on,
then looking,
then this column for the first value,
this column for the second value,
and then it's returned in the national insurance number,
which is what we wanted to do.
So they go.
That's the difference between a normal formula on a ray formula.
You have to hold down control shift and enter when you enter it.
Okay,
so now if we were to look at Luca Brown,
enter you can see that Luca Brown doesn't return.
Oh,
sorry.
It's Harry Brown,
isn't it?
Where are we?
Let's have a look at Luke Cat.
Let's have a look.
A little Lucas.
So we have Luke Italy.
So let's have a look.
Look at Luca.
So look.
Sorry.
Luca Brown wears Luca Brown down here has returned a test 97 0856 which is absolutely right
.
But if we looked at Luke Aly Hey,
center.
We can see that Luke Elise number is P E 101260 c,
which is exactly right.
Okay,
so there's essentially the two ways to use multiple input criteria to return a value using
lookups or technically,
index,
um,
matches in the usual help of columns and inserted up front or use help of columns and drop
them at the end.
But using a V look up,
as we have here,
you'll remember that the data that you're looking up from,
V look,
abs only look to the right.
So you then gonna have to copy all the data over to the right of that.
Or the really jazzy way of doing it is to use an array formula.
Okay,
See you in the next lecture.