again,
guys,
up to now we've looked at V.
Look up on.
We've used the match and index toe.
Look up backwards.
But V look up.
Has a brother on?
It's called H.
Look up now.
I must admit,
in 20 odd years of using Excel,
I have absolutely never used an h Look up.
But just in case you have to,
I want you to understand exactly where they work.
So what we're going to need to do is build a separate table.
So I'm gonna do is hit the little plus button.
And I'm just going to rename this,
uh,
family.
One second.
I'm just gonna rename this to location.
Okay,
so we're gonna go through a few steps to build a new data base or a new data set.
So what we're gonna do is nick the department structure from here,
and by copying all of these,
we're gonna flip back toe location on.
We're just gonna pay some straight in here as values.
So there you go.
We've got all of our values in there,
but you can see that we've got a lot of these that have bean duplicated.
So I'm going to do is just highlight the whole cell.
I'm going to come over to data and I'm gonna choose remove duplicates.
So I'm just gonna hit that.
Yes.
I want to look at column A something to click.
OK?
And they go,
We can no see that we've ended up with eight unique references or eight unique values out
of that entire list.
So even though we got 200 people,
they only work in one of eight departments.
Now,
we're just gonna copy that.
And I'm gonna use transpose as I did before,
so they know come across the top.
Delete.
Andi will actually change the formatting on.
That will change the orientation.
Which is this one here.
So formats,
cell alignment,
and we'll have them pointing upwards.
Okay,
so there's our There's our department titles.
Their logistics,
we can say,
will be Let's have a look.
What we got.
We've got Say their field based Let's say quality lives in,
uh oops.
Caps lock quality building.
Andi procurement lives in office One customer service is live in C s Plaza.
Very jazzy finance.
Living money I have and you sales lives on whips.
Miss the on the Road Director live in skyline on marketing live in Web marketing.
That was called,
um,
office to Because I'm not feeling that creative this morning.
Okay,
so they go and then we have a new data table.
And this time we have our headings across the top on.
We have ever locations in the second row.
So all we're gonna do Well,
flip that,
Teoh.
Should we go back to no intermediary,
we'll drop.
That's just copy that and paste it,
then.
Here on,
we'll have location in here.
Okay,
so let's return our location using an H.
Look up.
So what we're gonna do is say equals H.
Open brackets on what we want to find.
Where's our location?
What we want to find is the department name.
So coming back here,
our department name lives here in customer services.
So that's gonna be our look up value customer services comer.
We're not gonna drag this formula around,
so I'm not gonna absolute them.
I'm gonna come back to a location and I'm gonna highlight from here all the way over.
Now I look at value in h.
Look up lives in the first row of the data that you've highlighted not necessarily line one
,
but always the first row of the data that you've highlighted on this is nice and simple
because we only have two.
So I'm gonna highlight from a one then two h two comma and I want a return of value from
the second row.
So this will be the first row in our days that this will be the second comma two.
And I want to find an exact match.
So false close brackets on they go.
This lady Isabel Rodriguez works in customer services and we've now used on h look up to
pull her location.
Let's just make that bold.
Now let's pick someone else.
One of eight Onda Lucy Cox lives in finance and finance live in Money Avenue.
So there you go.
That's how we use H lookups.
I'll see you in the next lecture