OK,
guys.
Now,
this is probably the holy Grail of V lookups on that is,
how do you return multiple values?
So you return an entry for every time your single value that you're looking up appears in
the list.
So,
you know,
just going to get the 1st 1 You not gonna change the sort order and get the last one or do
any sort of manipulation on the sort order.
What you're actually going to do is return every single instance off that match.
Okay,
Now we're gonna have to combine four of the Excel built in functions on they are,
if small row and index,
We've looked at index before,
but let's just have a quick look at the other ones.
So the first thing we're gonna have a look at is the small function.
So I mean,
do down here is just fill this down all the way down here.
But I'm going to start that 15 and I'm gonna start to put one in there.
So the way the small function work says you took the function equals small open brackets.
Your first argument is the array.
So this is the array that we want to look at and then we hit Comma and K is the smallest
value do you want?
So if you want in the first smallest value you hit one.
He want the third smallest value You hit three.
So if we just hit one and closer brackets,
you can see that our lowest value is one which is exactly correct before.
To change that to 25 over Lois value now is to And if we look down the list,
we can see that too,
is the lowest value.
So similarly,
who wanted to find third lowest value?
We just type three and they go.
Number four is 1/3 lowest value.
Okay,
so keep that in your mind for a second.
That's how we use this small function.
Now,
what we want to do is be able to change that k the this last argument here,
depending on what row were in.
So if we drank the formula down,
let me just enter that second I'll absolute cell reference that array by hitting f four eso
.
If I drink that formula down,
you can see that we always return for because the three elements,
the K element is always the same even when we dragged that formula down.
So no,
What we need to look at is the row function on the road functions fairly straightforward,
or we type equals row open rackets and our road will be 1 to 1.
And hey,
center.
So there you go.
If here we were looking at the third lowest value,
we could delete that we could no reference this cell here which no gives us our first
lowest enter our first lowest value.
So if we were to drag this down,
you can see that we now get row Oneto one which returns one road to 22 which returns to row
3 to 3,
which returns the third on row 44 which returns the number four.
So all we need to do now is reference this particular cell over here on Weaken Nancy,
that our first lowest value because we're now using the row function to reference here.
Our first Lewis value is number two,
which is correct.
And our let me just hit F two.
There were no second lowest value cause we're looking here for the K K.
A rate a second lowest value is three,
which is probably right on four on five.
So what we need to do is use the small function,
but move the row number based on this formula here,
the road So R k value in a small formula uses this'll toe workout.
Which K is 12345 or whatever as we drank the formula down,
Okay,
hopefully with me so far.
Then let's get onto the good stuff.
Okay,
So what we're gonna do is write our first section of this formula using that small and
incorporating that rose so we can drag it down and have the K increase each time we drag it
on.
What we want to find out is what row number does Luca appear on?
And for that,
in the middle of their a small function,
what we're gonna do is drop in a logical test,
which we've done before.
So what we're gonna say is equals small open brackets if open brackets array,
which is this data just here.
Ignore this.
We've only used up for the small F four because I'm going to drag the formula around.
So I always wanted to reference this precise data range,
so f four so that's an absolute value.
Equals because this is a logical test that we're gonna f four gangs.
We always want to look at that even when we dragged the cell around.
So if in this range something equals that what we're gonna do is say comer and then we
won't want to do is return the road that that appears in in that data set.
So monotype road on highlight exactly the same data set again can with me so far.
So we're gonna close off that.
I'm gonna close off that because we were not interested.
If there's a false reference,
then we're going to do the the K value,
which you can see when I hit Comma.
We're now looking at the K value on what that's going to be is row open brackets 1 to 1,
just like we did earlier.
And closer brackets?
No.
If I hit enter,
you'll see that we get a value.
And that's because this is an array formula,
just as we looked at before.
So we know now toe enter an array formula.
We hit control shift and enter.
So they go.
We've now returned the value five because we're looking at the first K,
the first smallest value.
We're looking for the value in a 16 here in this array here on,
we're going to return the row number that that particular data arrives in.
Didn't fall that.
So let's just absolute cell reference that So this will still work when we're dragging it
around on,
then obviously,
control shift and enter because it's an array Formula five.
So now this is where the magic is going to start to happen.
I'm just going to drag that formula down four times and you can no see that here We're
looking at row 11 And just this before,
when we drank that formula down,
Will may look a row to to So we're looking for the second K,
the second smallest and then,
unsurprisingly,
in the next one,
we're looking at the third smallest,
but we're still looking at exactly the same data rate as you can see there.
Okay,
so now we have the answers.
Five,
12 and 14.
If we looked and we have one,
2345 There's our first Luca.
6789 10 11 12.
There's our second Luca Apparent line 12 13 14.
And there's are 14 line 14 where our third Luca appears.
Now,
after that point we've related to Lucas,
look at.
So we get a number error on.
We'll deal with the era trap at the end of all of this.
But so far,
we've done really well.
What we've worked out is how many times does Luca appear in this cell on?
We want to return the first instance,
wrote one.
We want to return the second instance.
Row two on.
We want to return the third instance.
Row three.
Now,
obviously,
if you have,
you can drag.
We stand 30 times and for everyone that it finds it will return a number.
So there's our first pass of the formula.
Okay,
So far,
so good.
Now we're going to do is take this element,
and we're going to wrap on index formula around it.
So I'm just gonna copy that hit escape.
I'm just gonna pace that in here.
So now we have exactly the same former.
So if I hit control shifting enter,
you can see that we still get number five.
They weren't going to do is wrap our index around it,
so I'm just going to come after the equals and before the small and say index,
just like we did before on we're gonna highlight our data rate,
which is all of this because you'll remember that the index requires the entire data array
hit f four because we're gonna drag this formula around.
But we still want to reference that exact area,
Comma,
They're what we've already written before.
This small if on dross statement covers absolutely everything else.
So just leapt to the end.
Hit comma on.
We want to return the first column so we won't Luca to be our first returned value.
So I'm just gonna hit comma one closer brackets control shift and enter on.
There you go.
Now we get the answer,
Luca.
Well,
that's great.
As you may think so It's just rang that down on what we'll get is Luca Luca Luca.
But these actually different Lucas because this Luca is the first Luca that it's found at
Row five.
This Luca is the second Luca that it's found a road 12 and this Luca is the third Luca that
it's found at row 14.
So just to prove that a what we're gonna do Is your strength that away across here,
then we're just gonna change the column reference.
So we were looking at column one previously.
They were gonna look at column to Sunday.
We have Luca Lee and I can drag that down.
So there you go.
No,
we have locally Luca Miller and Luke A brand.
We're gonna look at column three in here,
Remember,
Control shift and enter.
So there we have full name of locally.
Copy that down.
This is gonna be column full on control shift and enter.
And then we're gonna copy that on.
Then this will be,
unsurprisingly,
five.
Oops.
Control shift and ends.
I remember that long because it isn't right.
Formula controlling down on finally column six.
Control shift and enter.
Copy that down.
Let's just change the four.
Messing off that back too long days?
Well,
them.
So they go.
Now we've successfully built a single formula where we can enter one look of value.
Luca on.
We can return every single instance of Luca from our data table and look up all the
different columns.
Okay,
Now,
if we were to copy all of that down one more time,
control in D you see that?
We've run into Lucas so in now,
get in a number error now,
because we have a number era,
What we're gonna do is introduce a simple error trap.
We're going to use a logical test to return nothing at all,
if certain,
if an era has occurred.
So what we're gonna do is use the if era test.
So we're gonna talk if era before our index open brackets and then we're just gonna flip
right the way over to the end because that is the formerly we want to evaluate.
And if that's an error,
we want that to return Nothing.
So we just sit in double quotes,
close the quotes control shift,
and enter on They go.
Now we get a blank return.
So what I'm gonna do is competent and I want to paste over here on.
I'm just going to drag that down.
So no control and D we now have our error formula in all of these cells.
So if here I want to talk common,
we only have one color.
I'm sorry.
I beg your pardon.
We have to commerce.
So these have returned the values exactly as they should do.
So every corner is listed in here,
but here and here we can see that era trappers kicked in and just returned.
And a blank cell,
which is the double quotes.
So I'm just going to copy those all the way across control and that I want to put the color
numbers.
Right,
and we'll have a look at it in action in just a second.
Okay,
there we go.
Corrected all the column numbers.
So this is looking a column One.
This isn't looking at column,
too.
345 and six all the way across.
So,
no,
If we enter color in here,
we can see that this these cells are displaying our results Briefly.
Click here and here every trap comes in and returns a blank cell.
So they go,
Let's have a look at someone else.
Who else have we got in here?
We've got Harry.
So we could look up all the instances of Harry on.
We can see that we only have one.
We have Millie,
and we only have one.
We have Lily.
I think we only have one little e.
There you go.
But if we talk Blucher again lips they go the interest but forgot side of that format in
their long date.
They go if we tired Lucca.
Every single instance of Luca in a data table is getting returned on.
That is how you return multiple values from a single look up.
Okay,
Enjoy.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.