Okay,
guys,
this is just gonna be a short lecture.
Now,
I've taught many people have to do this.
And normally,
when people come back to me and say your formula doesn't work,
Alan,
it's for one of two reasons.
The first and most obvious one is they have entered the formula perfectly.
But then they just hit,
enter rather than control,
shift and enter.
And we know that if we just it entered on an array formula.
We get a value era now where you can actually see the error of that because we've known
about this ever trap in.
But to make an array formula work,
always control and shift on enter,
then it works perfectly.
And then the next thing they do,
what we've what we've actually done with our data is we've started the data up in cell a
one so I've got no headings.
We've got headings.
We've got no totals in our spreadsheets.
We've literally just started the data bump straight a one and gone all the way down.
So when someone looks at this,
if their aesthetic,
they may look at this and say,
you know,
I wish had a title in that so they will insert a blank line and there will start their data
at line two.
Or maybe they'll insert two lines,
insert and they'll have a title in there,
just as we have in previous lectures.
Now,
if we say it's a line here,
we can see that this formula is adjusted and no starts with road to two.
Then rode 33 then row four for.
So the first thing we need to do is correct the road number.
So that will still be one toe.
One we can hit control shift in,
enter and there you go.
So now we have number one and Weaken.
Drag that down.
So we now have 6 13 and 15.
But if we look in our data,
what we actually have is one,
23456 So the six value is actually imaging.
So then we go 789 10 11 12 13.
We can see that the value now is Kama 14.
We now have a blank cell.
So actually looking at the right row because we know we're looking at Row one on.
We're looking at Row two and row three,
but what we've done by inserting this new line is we've moved the sell down one.
So six is actually never going.
Let's go.
One,
23455 Where Luca is six.
We've actually added one to each of these values,
and it's no picking up the cell after Luca in each instance.
So what we need to do is make an adjustment at the end because we've inserted one line and
this is returning a row number.
We want to say minus one on control shift and enter.
And then we copy that formula Down Control and D and they go,
No,
we get the right answers again.
So we start on data here.
12345 There's our first Luca 6789 10 11 12 There's our second Luca 13 14.
On there's our third Luca.
So if you insert one line,
you must adjust this section of the formula to subtract one.
If you insert two lines,
you must add a minus two to correct this number here.
Okay,
So with our main formula,
what we're going to do is do exactly the same thing because we've inserted one line in here
.
What we need to do is just for it and come to the end of our row number.
Just he had this road Oneto one and hit minus one.
Because our data nev starts on the second line.
And obviously,
if you inserted to blank lines at the top,
you would hit minus two.
So control shift,
Andi intact.
So they go.
That's Hey,
correct that.
OK,
there.
In the next lesson,
we're gonna have a look.
A quick,
short cut save having to keep modifying those column numbers.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.