OK,
guys.
Now let's have a look.
A short cut to save.
Having to keep modifying formulas to change the column number.
Now this is that the sheet?
We were just looking at returning,
returning multiple values to know,
Just deleted this thing stuff from over here.
If you need to have a play with it,
it still lives in the first sheet on.
I'm just highlighted this area around here where our formulas live.
So no,
we know that this formula works perfectly,
but we have not adjusted.
These are the ones yet.
So what we gonna do is,
first,
we're going to copy that formula down.
So now that one works perfectly on,
we're gonna delete everything else.
Okay?
There are two ways that we can modify this formula.
So when we drag it over,
we just get the column numbers on.
We've kind of already looks at this in an earlier lecture.
Not so long back where we use this particular function here.
Row 1 to 1.
There won't row want toe wonders.
You'll remember when we drag it around the first time it appears it's row one toe.
Want them row 2 to 2 in row.
3 to 3 as you move it around.
But it wouldn't surprise you to know that we also have the equivalent version,
which is column.
So if we typed column oh,
from brackets now,
obviously columns have letter so we say a to I close brackets and enter.
We return the volume one that returned the number one because column A is the first column
.
If we drag it across,
we get 123 So column A is one column B B is two column.
Sisi is three.
So all we need to do with this formula now instead of having column one where we're looking
column one there will just replace that and say Cullen A to I and closer brackets.
Now remember,
this is still an array formula.
So we hit control shift and enter,
and we still get Lucas on.
We're going to copy that all the way down Control and D.
So you can see now that although formulas say column A at the end Now,
when we drank this over,
it's gonna know,
Say,
change the A to B B,
C,
D D e f f control and are And there you go and that's where the magic happens.
So you don't have to go in every time clicking here and change the column number.
Let me just tied up the format in their short thing,
Let's say so.
They go.
You can no use the column if you use a sequential column number.
So you're gonna pull dates from 123456 on that all in a row,
that's the way to do it.
Just use the coal number now.
Obviously,
if you want to skip column A and begin straight a column B,
you just type column B B,
then drag that over and then your pull data from Columns B,
which is 23456 and so on again.
And there is one of the way that works perfectly well.
If the columns that you pulling up all next to each other and just use this column function
again I want to do for the 2nd 1 is I'm just gonna highlight another area just here.
Let's color that in a different color.
Let's say that rather distasteful orange.
Let's have that and we're going to copy this formula here,
controlling seat escape on DPI paste it in their control shift and enter.
So this one still works perfectly well,
cause it's exactly the same formula.
But this time,
what we're gonna do is we're going to use a helper column across the top here.
Now we're sorry.
Help A row across the top.
We've used help of columns before,
when we looked at concatenation for V lookups and the women do here beside 123456 So,
this time,
with this cell instead of looking column A,
I just couldn't delete all of that in there.
I'm just gonna point to this cell here.
So now when this formula looks for which column to go to,
it's just gonna look here confined the answer one.
Now,
obviously,
we're going to drank this down.
So we always wanted to reference this particular cell.
So we're gonna change our absolute cell reference in which you'll remember you do by
pressing F four.
So at the moment we have a 28 which,
if we dragged it around to the right,
would change to be 28 c 28.
If we drowned it down,
it would change from a 28 8 29 So therefore once and it always is a and always 28.
But we do want it to move when we drag it over here.
So what we're gonna do is hit f four again,
eh?
So what we're saying no is that it will always being column.
Sorry,
it won't always be in column A but it will always be at line 28 which exactly what we want
.
So you want a absolute 28 control shift and enter,
and that works perfectly well on weaken Drank that down on now,
weaken dragged that across control and are and you can see let me just kind of formatting
upon their short,
bigger.
So now you can see that all of these formulas a referencing this sell directly above it in
this line.
So here we're looking at D 28 which is this cell on its return in the fourth.
This is particularly useful if you decide that you don't actually want these to appear in
exactly the same order you could say.
Well,
actually,
I want to see the first the full name first.
So then all you need to do rather modify all the formulas It's just change this to three
and then you get look around and you could say,
Well,
actually,
I want to see the national insurance number.
Next on national insurance number,
we know lives in column four.
So we'll change that to four said.
Then we get our national insurance number.
Then I want to see the date of birth,
which is six so he can hit six.
Then they get the date of birth,
which we obviously need to change the formatting up.
General.
Short date.
I hate it when that happens.
Then we may choose to see the first name.
Then we may choose to see the last name on.
Then for good.
It's doing it again and let me just change that.
Okay,
so they go by introducing a helper row.
You can save having to modify all of these formulas,
and it's a very fast and efficient way to change the order in which your data appears.
There's some would argue.
That looks a bit of glee,
but there's a very simple solution to that.
You can just highlight the entire row,
come up to here and change.
The fund collapsed to white,
so although that works perfectly well.
See,
we still have value for in there.
We can still change this toe.
Whatever we wanted to say on it will work perfectly.
Obviously,
if you don't want users to play around and daily that you could just hide it so right,
click on hide.
So there you go.
That's one quick way of changing your column number by using the column function.
If the columns that you're gonna pull are sequential like a BBC C and so on and so forth or
using a help a row and just adding the column number in here on referencing that in your
formula Okay,
so you in the next lecture.