Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
Now,
technically,
this is a student.
Questions answered video,
But as it sits so nicely within the V Look up section.
This is where I'm going to post it now and not asked an absolutely brilliant question.
Now we know the V.
Look,
it's very straightforward to you.
So here's a very simple data set.
So what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna say Andi,
Hey,
I don't just going to write a quick V look.
Upset equals we look up open brackets.
Someone will look there,
Comer.
I'm just going to say I will look in the whole of a B and C and I want to look for hair
collect,
which is column two comma,
False,
Fantastic.
So we can see the Andy just like me is bold.
But what happens if I insert another column just here?
You can see that this fails because it's looking for column to,
but there's actually nothing in Column two,
so let's just undo that there.
Similarly,
what happens if we cut here on?
We insert the cut cells here.
Now.
We were looking for hair color,
but now we have Aikawa because eyes is now a column,
too.
So if you've got a bunch of complicated V lookups But someone say's Hey,
can you insert a column or actually,
can you change the data set so that the columns appear in a different order?
Then V look up in its native form Doesn't cope with this Well,
so let me,
let me let me just copy that down for a second.
But what we want to do is change this to here to a match formula.
So we're going to say,
match over brackets,
open quotes and we're looking for hat.
And I am gonna close the brackets.
I am going to be looking in the whole of Rome warm,
So I'm just going to double click the left click with one comma,
and I'm gonna look for an exact match sense.
Type zero and hit Enter.
So we still get the same answer.
But now look what happens if I insert a column here.
This fails because it's looking in Column two.
But this has used the match function to find hair on realize it's no column three.
So we retain on set off bold,
no,
similarly just undoing that if we decided to change the column order on.
We went,
say cut and then we insert the cut cells here.
You can see that the first formula is still looking at Colin,
too,
but it's no pulling Brown because it's looking at column to which is now eyes.
But this called this formula.
It's still looking for hair,
regardless of where hair now appears.
So that's a really clever way to dynamically build your V lookups.
So even if you change the column order or insert or delete cells,
it will still work for you.
Okay,
that was a great question.
I let so thank you very much indeed.
On.
I'll see you in the next lecture.