Okay,
guys.
In this final section on the H R database,
Master,
I've added a new tab called Christian name Search on.
What we're going to do from here is we're gonna have a single Christian name that we type
in here on.
We're going to return all of these different values,
whichever matches we got in the Christian name below here.
And we can see that we've applied to filter in here too.
So if we do have a large amount of returns,
we can always use a filter to narrow it down to the ones that we actually want to see.
Okay,
so let's time path the first part of our multiple return formula.
So we're gonna type small Justus.
We did before.
If open brackets,
they were gonna point to our HR file,
which is this one just here.
We're going to highlight the entire day to set and press F four.
So that is the range that we're looking in equals and we are looking for a match on the
Christian name on.
We're gonna hit therefore again,
because when we drag this formula around,
we always wanted to point to this cell we're gonna hit comma.
Then we're gonna type row because we want to return Which row number from this data set
that particular value appears in.
So we're just gonna highlight the entire day to set again on hit F four,
and we're gonna close brackets on,
We're going to close brackets,
then we're going to hit comma.
Then we're gonna save Roe,
and it's going to be 1 to 1 and close brackets and closed brackets.
Okay,
Now we're gonna hit control,
shift and enter,
and they go.
We can see that comma appears a line to.
And if we drank that down,
we can see that we get calmer and number 2 114 and 19.
So let's just check that first.
So where are we?
We have first name.
We have color.
So position one position to and we can see that matches up with road numbers.
So what else did we have?
We had 114 and 119.
Let's just scroll down.
Is Connor on 119.
Is college too?
Okay,
so the first part of our formula works perfectly.
Never we're going to do is wrap our index around that.
So what we do decide index open rackets and you'll remember that the index is the entire
day so set that we're looking out.
So we're just gonna copy all of that down his F four coma there.
We've written the road reference number in all of this formula here,
just like we did before.
So we're going to skip to the end comment on We want to return the full name.
So that will be column 123 Comma.
Sorry.
Column Four close brackets on control shifting.
Enter.
So they go.
We now have our first full name returns.
So let's just drank that down a case.
And there we have Connor Phillips come along and Connor Turner.
Fantastic.
Next thing we're gonna do is write out if era in there so we don't have that number at the
end.
So if era open brackets,
this is what we want to evaluate.
And if it is an error comma,
we want to return a blank cell.
So we're just gonna quote,
hit double quotes and close the brackets and control shift and enter.
So there you go.
No,
we have our first column in there,
so just copy that sell down.
So now when we enter comma,
we get three returns,
we get the full name.
Connor Phillips,
come along on Comet IRNA.
So far,
so good.
Okay,
the next thing we want to look at is the employee number,
which also lives in the H R file.
And the employee number lives in column A,
which is column one.
So all we're gonna do here is just copy that formula across.
And instead of looking at column full,
we're gonna look at column one control shift and set,
and then we're gonna copy that down control,
Andy.
Okay.
So far,
so good.
Now we're gonna look at the department on the department,
lives in the department structure,
which is here on we can see that we have to reference the employee number,
which is something we haven't end,
which,
warily,
something we haven't entered in here.
But we now have returned just here.
So this is no straight.
We look up so equals V.
Look up.
If I could talk,
they look up.
That would speed things up dramatically.
We're gonna look at that cell.
We're not gonna absolute cell reference it because when we drank this formula Damn,
we wanted to look here and here.
So we're gonna look at department.
So equals V.
Look up.
We're looking at this comma.
We're now going to be looking in our department structure and we're gonna be looking over
one.
The department is in the second column,
so it's gonna highlight all of that.
Now,
you'll notice that this is a named range and we're gonna cover named Range is fully in the
next sections that don't worry about that at the moment.
Because this is a named range.
We don't have to absolute cell reference it cause it's never gonna move no matter where we
drag it.
Okay,
So comma to because we want to return department comer False Because we want a complete
match or we want an exact match.
So he works in the directorate.
Now,
what we can do now is just copy that across control and are now,
perhaps I should have absolute self reference that,
but what I'm gonna do is look at this cell.
So we're still looking at B seven,
But this time we want to return from column three.
So his job title is C E O now because when we copy this down,
we're going to get errors.
We also need to introduce our error trapped into this formula.
So just before the V look up on,
do exactly the same again.
So if era open brackets and that is what we want to evaluate.
So if it's an error comma return,
nothing.
Which is double quotes.
Andi,
enter.
This isn't an array formula,
and then we can copy that down.
And I'm gonna do exactly the same with this one.
So equals lips equals against the right place.
First,
if era open brackets,
this formula is what we're evaluating.
Comma,
double quotes returned.
Nothing on Enter again.
Not Marais formula here,
Control and D.
So let's just also size those for a second.
It will click against and there we can return Color Phillips or we can return color and get
color Phillips Come along,
Color Turner,
All their employees numbers there department and their job title.
Next,
we're gonna have a look at where they're based.
And for this we're going to use our location file,
which you'll remember was an h Look up.
So what we gonna do say equals h look up open rackets on.
We want to look at the economy and where it is,
it's the department that goes across it up.
So what we want to have a look at is the department.
And I am gonna absolute self reference that the Stones are gonna hit F four F four again
Andi F four again.
So it always must appear in columns,
See,
But it doesn't have to be in line seven.
So that way,
when we drag it down,
it will move to eight and nine and 10 and so on and so forth.
So that's gonna be Ellicott value.
Come in.
We're gonna point to our location file,
highlight all of our data on we want to return from line to So we're gonna hit groups.
And it's just absolute self reference that wanna hit line to come A To become a false
because we want an exact match hit.
Enter.
It's just enter on this one because it's not Marais former,
just straightforward.
Let's auto science and the game we're gonna introduce at every trap just before so equals
If around open brackets evaluate this section,
the formula and if it isn't era return a blank clothes and enter.
It's copy that.
Damn!
Now,
the next one we're gonna have a look at is the car wrench on the car.
Reg leaves in the HR file in the 1234567 8/9 column Because we already referenced in that
over here.
What we're gonna do is just copy that cell and pace over here.
But this time,
instead of looking column four,
we're gonna look at column nine,
hit control shifting.
Enter.
And then we're gonna copy that down now,
because we've got every traps in here we can know happily.
Copy this down.
Let's go down.
20 lines,
control and D.
Let's try this.
Have something else.
So we have Connor.
Let's have a look.
Do we have any Harris?
We have three.
Harris.
Do we have any Millie's?
Yes,
we have two.
Millis,
Do we have any Jones?
We don't have any Jones in our database at all.
Do we have any polls?
No.
Paul's.
Let's have a look at who we do have.
That might be more useful.
And we have little is.
So let's have a look at Lily.
They go,
we have three Lillis on,
but that's essentially have it works so you can build a very complex database using what
you've learned and search for a single Christian name on return multiple returns.
So you get every single lily in our database in all the information that you could possibly
want.
And if you want to add any more,
you'll find loads of extra data that you can mine in here.
So coming back to hear the finishing touch is going to be this record returned thing.
So what we're gonna do in the next,
like you very quickly is have a look out to return Hemley records.
There are in total on homely records.
We've managed to return from here.
Okay,
so I'll see you in the next lecture.