Okay,
guys.
In the last few sections,
we had a look at static named ranges and static name ranges of perfectly fine if your data
never expands or contracts now,
at the moment I've created a new named Range,
which is from a one through beasts five,
and called my table amusing that in this V look up just here.
But the drawback with named range static name range is we can actually expand it
automatically.
So if we said we're going to start selling cabbages,
Onda cabbages are six p,
let's say but in the in here we talked cabbages and copied that sell down.
You can see that we get an error reference because all of these cells are looking at the
hard coded a one through Be five on when we come to hear the data stops at a precut,
so never gets down as far as cabbages.
Okay,
so what we need to do is make this so it's dynamic on.
Whenever we had new items onto the bottom or we delete items from anywhere within the list
on named range,
which is this one automatically expands and contracts to match.
So let's just delete that for a second.
Okay?
Now what we're going to need to do in the dynamic named Range is understand how to other
functions in excel work.
And one of them we've looked at before,
which was the count A and the other one we haven't looked at yet,
which is the offset.
So let's just have a look at counts a again,
just so we can remember what it does.
And we can see by the tall tip that can't a cancer the number of cells in a range that are
not empty.
So what I'm gonna do is open the brackets and I'm just going to drag over this highlighted
area.
Now it means nothing that this highlighted.
This is just because that's where I'm dropping the d lookups.
I'm gonna close the brackets and hit enter so you can see when I hit Enter that are result
is five on the reason that it's fine.
Let me just center that the reason that it's five even though we've highlighted the entire
range,
is we have 12345 cells with the value in them on two blanks.
So the correct answer is five.
OK,
so that's count A.
The next one we're going to look at is offset on.
What offset requires is a reference,
which is a start point.
So I'm just going to click here on day.
I'm going to say Comma on Rose.
I'm going to say zero because I don't want to move any rose from my reference point,
My start,
point comma and zero again because I don't want to move any columns away from my reference
.
My start point.
And I'm gonna closer brackets and hit Enter.
So they go.
No,
we get the concept one because offset from G six No rose,
no columns.
Is this value just here?
So it returns one.
But if we were to say Rose one,
you can probably guess what matters.
It will start a g six and then move down one row and still zero columns.
So now we'll return the value A and similarly vote to change the column reference from 0 to
We have started a G six.
We have moved down one row on.
We have moved to columns across.
So when they hit enter,
we get the answer,
See?
Okay.
Now what we're gonna do is combine those into our formula to create a dynamic named range
bouquet.
So static ranges you can pick from the name box just up here,
but not so with dynamic named Range is what you have to do is come to formulas onto name
manager and then click in.
Let me just really What it means is that string that down of it.
What we need to do is to click in here here to be able to see the dynamic named range area
on what we're gonna do because we already have this entity is we're going to use that as
our start point.
Now when you build a dynamic named range that are five arguments.
Justus,
with the offset,
our first argument is going to be the reference point.
Where do we want to start?
Our range from the next argument is Rose on The next argument is columns just like it was
when we looked at it a second ago.
Now the last two arguments are Hemley Rose,
Do I want to go down on Hamli columns?
Do I want to go across?
So let's build that.
So what we're gonna do is click it after the equals and type offset open brackets.
We always want to start a absolute a one,
because that's where our data start.
So we can delete the rest of that common Nu Ruz coming.
No columns.
Because we always wanna have our data starting that absolute a want or at least in this
instance,
Comer.
And now we're going to incorporate that count a function for the road argument.
So we're going to say,
can't a open rackets.
And we're gonna quick the whole of column A which is going to say,
without titles,
exclamation point.
Because that's the name of the sheet.
Absolute Aito Absolute a close the brackets.
And for now,
what we're gonna do is we're going to say,
one column close the brackets hit,
enter on their.
When I click on this,
you can see that it is no expanded to include cabbages.
So I'm just close that for one second,
and now we're gonna say,
uh,
that's a strawberries.
Let's go back into it.
Remember,
you can't pick a dynamic name range from the name box,
so backups and name manager clicking here,
and you can see that it's now expanded to capture strawberries as well because the count.
A in column A has increased one because we've added strawberries in.
Okay,
so let's set with just close that let me just delete strobes for a second.
Now,
what we've done so far is we've expanded this according to the number of non blank cells in
Column A But what we're going to do now,
we've said hard coded.
It's only one column wide.
What we gonna do now is say it's going to be two columns wide on that will then incorporate
this second column to So when they hit,
enter and click in here.
You can see that that is now our full named range.
Somebody hit close all of their formulas work again.
And now if I buy cabbages and copy that formula down,
you can see that it's pull in six from the second column of there were no dynamic named
range.
Okay,
so just for completeness,
what I'm gonna do is I'm also going to show you what to do if you need to expand your data
this way.
So you add 1/3 column into into your data set name manager picked the range that you want
to change.
Click in your formula on instead of hard code in number to hear.
What you would do is you would just repeat the count a function.
So can't a I want to count the number of non blank cells in row one because that will tell
me how many columns I have data in.
I'm gonna hit Enter groups.
I think I'm Mr Brackett.
Okay.
On Ben.
Close brackets hit.
Enter.
So,
no.
When I move this out the way and clicking here,
you can see that this is still our data table.
But if I had some more data in here,
let's just add something else in and then go back to name and jet and clicking here again.
You can see this automatically expanded to capture the data in our new column.
Okay.
In the next election,
we're gonna have a look at what to do If you have totals in your data.
I'll see you in the next lecture.