Okay,
guys.
In the last lecture,
we had a look at how to build a named range without title.
So your data literally starts right here.
But in this sheet,
I've actually added titles into our data set.
So I'm going to do is just quickly created Name ranges on the call.
This my data Have a time.
That right?
Let me move that at my data to And here's enter.
Not going to use that to build our dynamic named range.
So formulas name manager My data to groups council.
My data to click in here,
we're gonna build are offset upset open rackets.
We always want to start a absolute one.
Yes,
we do.
We don't want to move over any on.
We don't want to move across any coming can't a open rackets.
Hamli non blank cells.
Raven column A close brackets,
comma comes a again.
Open brackets handy,
numb blanks elsewhere have in room one close brackets and close rackets and enter a case.
And there,
when I click in here,
we can see that that's captured all of this dynamically.
So far,
so good.
Now let's build a simple V look up.
So let's Let's say we want to look up apples and we rise.
Harvey,
look up Here we look up from rockets.
Look at that coming out.
Look at my data to calmer.
Second column,
Exact match intact.
So there you go.
We know,
get Let me just change the formatting on that they go.
Apples are 10 p.
But what happens if we type fruit?
Well,
we get the return value of by price,
which is exactly writes.
It's looked in the second column,
but you probably don't wanna have that as a V.
Look up.
You actually want your values to start here where your first value starts.
Okay,
so let's have a look at how we're just for that in our dynamic named range.
So we're going back into formulas.
We're going back into name manage EPT,
and we coming back into our formula here for my data to stop doing that.
Click on that on.
We're coming back into the formula for my data to now,
what we want to do here is make an adjustment to reduce by one because of our titles in
here.
Just escape.
So here is our row argument account A with titles,
a and immediately after the close brackets on the A,
we're gonna hit minus one and enter and then Mommy click on here.
We can see that our data has no begun here.
It's actually started to say one,
but it subtracted one because of the titles that we have across.
So all we've done is can tell me.
Items appear in column A,
and that gives us the number of rows that we have on.
We have subtracted one because we have a title in there,
so enter on,
closed on.
That works perfectly well.
So no.
If we type fruit,
we can see that that Everest.
But if we type apples,
it's all happy.
Happy again.
And if you take cabbages,
it's still happy again.
So let's handsome strawberries,
strawberries and strawberries and strawberries.
Let's call intemperance eso they go.
No,
we have strawberries in our list,
and we can have looked at dynamic named Range my data to click in it and you can see Yep,
it's captured strawberries close.
But now let's imagine we're going to insert a couple of lines in here as we have done
before,
we're going to say at my stock list,
Onda we know give that jazzy title on the emergence century.
Where are we Emergence center And we left a line and we make it bigger and we make bold and
we make it red.
So now if we have look at our named range on dynamic and dynamic name range you remember
you can't pick it from here Back to formulas.
Back to name manager.
My data to go.
Stop double clicking that on clicking here.
You can see that we now have a spare line in here.
So what?
The cans a function has done is it's looked a column A's and I have one value to values.
345678 I have nine blank cells,
so therefore my data set will be one to 345678 minus one there because we have another
value in here.
What we now need to do is subject to because we don't want to include that in our count on
.
We don't want to include the titles in our account.
So hit.
Enter on.
Now when we click in it,
you can see that that still works absolutely perfectly because we want to discount this
line.
So therefore,
this cell on we want to discount this cell on subtract to because we have two things that
are not part of our data.
Close.
So there you go.
That's how you build a dynamic name.
Range on.
That's how you were just for it.
If you have extra bits of data in there So cells with values in that you don't want to take
into account in your data table,
OK,
I'll see you in the next lecture.