Okay,
guys,
what we're going to create in this project is a spreadsheet solution where we can select
the ingredients that we have in our fridge or uncovered on have it automatically tell us
what we could create with those ingredients on rank them according toa likelihood.
So if we have all of our ingredients present on our recipe despite needs,
all of those ingredients will display 100% on so on and so forth reducing until we get down
to I have none of those ingredients.
Therefore,
this will be ranked zero.
So we're going to incorporate some of the things that we've learned before,
and we're going to add some new things in there,
and we're gonna build some complex formulas to be able to work out what it is that we can
have.
Okay,
so to begin,
we have this basic sheet and all this is is a tub that say's in next.
We're gonna list down meals down here.
We have an ingredients master which we're gonna add to as we go through and build a
respites and some not terribly attractive but terribly functional recipes that we can call
from in here.
So the first thing we're gonna have a look at is adding a hyperlink.
Teoh,
Each of these tubs down here now,
there are a few ways it add a hyperlink on.
We're just going to choose one of the simple methods.
For now,
we're just going to right click in the cell.
I've just realised you can't see that we're going to right Click in the cell,
Choose hyperlink on in here.
We're going to choose place in this document on We're going to choose be lt and hit.
OK,
now,
in the moment you can see that this hyperlink when I click it happily takes me to the B l t
.
But it doesn't look terribly attractive.
So all I'm gonna do for now,
it's just delete everything bother BLT.
Okay,
so that was our first.
So right,
Click inserts hyperlink.
Then choose Chilli con Carney.
It's okay that I'm gonna delete everything there and hit Enter.
And then when we click that,
we can see that we go to Chilli Con Carney.
I'm just going to continue that for all of these.
I'm just gonna be inserting hyperlink next to spank bones.
Okay?
That I'm just gonna delete everything up to the last letter and hit Enter.
Then when I click that we can see that we go back to spank ball.
I'm just going to carry on and do them all.
And then I'll come back to you at the end.
OK,
guys now have added all the hyperlinks into each of our sheets.
We can see that we can click them.
That will take us immediately to be Elsie.
We can select the index again.
We can go to any of these,
and it will instantly take us where we need to go.
I'm gonna commit Index have deliberately left the last one in its full form without delete
in the cell reference at the end.
Or the exclamation point,
All the apostrophe.
Just because we're gonna need to know precisely have that looks a little way to run now.
For now,
what we're gonna do is I'm just gonna add a free Spain across the top.
So have just selected Line six come up to view hit freeze panes and free Spain's.
And there we can happily scroll around.
Now,
one thing that may in or you if you go to something like cottage pie on that's way over
here and you've got multiple tabs is you have to keep clicking this way to get back to the
index.
So the next thing we're gonna do is have a look at writing a macro that's gonna zoom us
back to the index from a button in each of these tabs.
So I'll see you in the next lecture.