Okay,
guys in the last lecture made a mistake.
I did say there are only two ways to access a macro that are actually three ways of Chris
access a macro.
Now we look to creating the keyboard shortcut in the last lecture.
But you can also do is click Mac Rose.
Just select your macro and click run,
and that will also automatically run the macro that you've selected.
So Okay,
there's the third way of doing it.
Now,
the other way of doing it and the one that I must admit for probably the last 10 or 15
years,
is the only method I've used is to activate a macro on a change event.
That is,
when something in the spreadsheet happens.
Then the macro automatically executes on the button.
Click is one such event.
So what we're gonna do now,
we've looked at Activex controls before eso What we're gonna do is we're going to select be
lt we're gonna be on.
Our developers have just here.
We're going to go to insert,
and here we can see,
just like we did before.
We have form controls and Activex controls on.
What we're going to do is we're gonna choose form control and just click the button and
then what we're gonna do,
Let's say here is we're just gonna add a button on.
I'm just gonna left,
click and drag out on you can see automatically says,
Do you want to assign a macro to this?
Well,
yes,
we do.
We want to call.
We want this button to go to go to my index macro and we're going to click.
OK,
so there we have bottom one.
If we right click in there,
we can edit the text on What we're going to do is say,
it's just little that go to index input anything that you want in here.
So where Button one will may have say,
Go to index hit,
Enter on Click off And there you go.
So go to index on there.
When we have an event in our workbook,
such as clicking the button,
you can see that the macro executes on automatically.
We go from BLT.
Let's go back,
hit the button and we go instantly back to our index.
That's not much of a problem.
If you Tubbs a close together,
you could just click here.
But if your tabs are miles over the way like this one to save you all the scroll in,
you can automatically just jump back to it by pressing this button.
So what we're gonna do now is just right.
Click copy.
Go to our next tab.
I can't remember where we had it exactly on just paste.
And then when I click off,
I can there be on chilli con Carney hit Go to index and instantly jump back.
So just right,
click a copy.
Spanked bone paste.
Copy control and see chicken salad.
Coffee.
Full English.
Right click paste Right click Copy on.
Let's just get a my at the end yet I'm not sure I am.
Cottage pie paste Copy Shepherd Spy Click paced.
OK,
so now let's go back to our index the old fashioned way.
So now we can go to Index and choose BLT and instantly go to BLT hit Go to index and jump
back.
Choose Chilli con Carney on we straight into actually.
Come Carney,
go to index and we come back.
Spat ball goes through index comeback Chicken salad.
Go to index and come back Full English Go to index comeback cottage pie go to index and
come back.
And I think of missed one.
Let's have a look.
What sound?
Last one cottage pie.
We have a shepherd's pie as well.
I've now added that one.
So let's just go back.
And where are we?
Could use the book in there.
Laces.
Go back.
Right Click Insert hyperlink.
Andi place in this document.
Shepherd's pie.
They go.
OK,
so there you go.
Now we have all of our buttons added on.
We can instantly go back to index by using the macro that we've recorded on assigned to
that button.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.