again,
guys.
Now we've added the conditional format into this range of cells.
To pace it to the others is really simple.
We're just going to highlight from seven down to 20.
Hit double click the former painter.
Click on Spragg ball,
drag over the same range.
Click on chicken salad,
drag over the same range dragon,
click on full English,
drag over the same range over to move over a little bit of cottage pie.
Move over the same range on Shepherd's pie on,
move over the same range.
And there were completed when just hit the escape key.
And that will get rid of the conditional formatting from our format painter.
Okay,
so now we have a very clear list of what does appear on what doesn't appear in our list.
So all of these appear now list on here.
We have Oregon.
Oh,
which we're gonna copy on.
We're gonna flip back to here and add it to our ingredients,
Master and just paste special at the end.
We also have spaghetti,
so we're gonna copy ingredients.
Master on pay Special At the end on the Mir.
We've done that one.
They were going to do this and copy on Put to the bottom of our ingredients.
Master,
I'm just going to carry on doing that until we get to the very end on.
I'll see you in a few seconds.
Okay,
here's our full list.
This is every item that we have listed in all of our recipes and then just click through
them all and see instantly that every single one of them is in wise.
So everything matches something in our list.
So we just didn't come back to the ingredients,
master,
and we're just going to sort that alphabetically,
so sort Ater said.
And they know we have our list.
Now,
what we're gonna do is come back to the index on Dad.
Ever drop down boxes?
Okay,
what we're gonna do is select our first cell.
We're going to come to the data tab.
We're going to come to data validation and in our settings were gonna allow list on.
All we're gonna do is type the name of our dynamic named Rain.
So we're going to say equals my list and hit Enter,
and then you can see we got this little drop down box pop up on in there.
We have all the ingredients for all of our items.
So what we're gonna do is copy that on Pace it.
They're on board.
They're Andi there.
Andi There.
So there we have our five drop down boxes where we can pick our items.
Okay.
In our next lecture,
we're gonna have a look at building the formula that we need here to calculate which recipe
we have all the ingredients for.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.