Okay,
guys,
welcome back there.
The formula we're gonna use in these cells just hear what we want them to do is evaluate to
a zero or a one.
So if we get ones all the way across the board,
that means we have every single one of these items in the line that that particular that
those ones appear in.
So if we get one for broccoli,
one for about a one carat,
one for broccoli again on one for bacon.
We know we can make BLT if we only get one.
We only have 20% of the ingredients.
And if we get too,
we have 40%.
And if we get three ones,
we have 60% and so on and so forth.
Now,
what we're gonna need to build is a complex formula using a lot of the functions that we've
used before or some of the functions that we've used before.
Andi,
I think most certainly one that we haven't.
So what we're gonna do in these next few lectures is have a look at the things that we
haven't seen before on learn what they do.
Now.
The first thing we're gonna look at is the indirect function.
So what we're gonna do in this cell is we're gonna type the classic hello world,
and you can see that this is sell E six.
So in e six,
we've just typed Hello,
world on Dhere.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna type the six.
So if we wanted to have a hello world here,
we could hit,
equals and click this self and hit return on.
Obviously we get hello,
world.
But if we wanted to use the value in this cell to directors to this cell,
all we would need to do is on an indirect formula.
So we're going to say equals in direct IDs.
Open brackets click the cell with the indirect reference,
and that will be a cell reference in this instance.
Close the brackets and hit enter on their We get our hello world.
So what in directors done is it says,
get the value from this cell and treat it as a location to another cell,
which is E six.
So if over here we would sit a tub.
Look,
if over here with type,
um,
press thing balloons,
I have no idea why I said balloons on over here.
We know changed this to say h six instead of what is that?
We cannot say that we get balloons so indirect is particularly useful if you have to build
a string that's going to give you a cell or sheet reference on No,
that's not going to be much you at the moment.
Because we progress in this particular formula,
it will become very clear.
Okay,
let's move on to the next lecture where we're gonna have a look at building a string.