Okay,
guys,
welcome back.
No.
Bear with me because we're almost there.
We've built the center section about formula.
Now what we need to do is convert all of these numbers either a number or an error into a
one or a zero.
So if we found a number,
we want to return a one that means that something has appeared in that particular recipe.
And if it errors,
that is,
it doesn't appear in that particular recipe.
We want to return zero.
So what we're gonna do is modify the formerly we've done,
and we're gonna wrap around our final part.
So what we're gonna do is introduce an if test open brackets.
Then we're going to say is era open brackets.
Then we're gonna leap all the way over to the end.
We're gonna close the brackets once,
which you can see encapsulate this section of the formula coma.
What do I want to return if the value is true?
So if this is an error,
what value do I want to return?
I want to return zero.
If this formula evaluates to an era that is,
I cannot find a match comma.
And therefore,
if it is not an error.
I want to return a one.
That means I did find a match and are formula didn't era closed,
brackets his center.
And there you go.
We get a one in.
They're just gonna copy that down,
using control and D I'm a gonna copied all the way across.
So let's give that a quick ride to see if that works.
So we have bacon,
we have butter.
What would be in a bacon sandwich?
A BLT with a bacon.
Do we have lettuce?
In this list?
We do lettuce onder t tomato,
tomato.
So they dio And let's just delete that on.
Delete that.
Okay,
there you go.
So we chose from a list.
Bacon,
lettuce,
Andi,
tomato.
We can see that.
We get a one.
A one on a one on we get.
We don't have bacon in a chicken salad,
but we do have lettuce and tomato.
So if in our cupboard we have bacon,
lettuce and tomato,
we absolutely 100% can make a b l t again.
The next thing we're going to do is have a look at building a probability in here and using
a traffic light system.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.