OK,
guys,
Now,
before we are their traffic lights in,
What we need to do is evaluate the percentage in this column just here.
Now,
you may think this is a simpler is right in this formula,
which is equals to some of all of these close brackets divided by the number of cells we
have,
which is 12345 only by five.
Andi,
enter.
Just copy that down on.
Let's change that to a percentage.
Let's knock off those decimal So they go.
It looks like we have a 60% chance of having a B L t.
Because we have a one here,
one here on the one here.
But actually what we have is a 100% chance of having a BLT based on the entries that we've
put in here because this cell is blank on this cell is blank.
So what we need to do in our percentage is discount the zeros here,
or at least discount where we don't have a value.
Now we know how to count the values in a particular range by using the count a function so
we're gonna do is delete the five and replace it with a can't a function so I can't a and
I'm gonna highlight this.
I'm gonna hit f four because when we drag this down,
we wanted to always reference this range just here.
Closer brackets on his enter.
So they go there.
We have a 100% chance of having a BLT.
We have a 67% chance of having a chicken salad because we have to interest out of the three
values that we've entered,
we have a 33% chance of having a full English breakfast because we have one entry off the
three values that we've entered up here on.
We've got absolutely no chance of ever been chilli con Carney spanked ball,
a cottage pie or a shepherd's pie.
OK,
we've got our percentages now.
What we're gonna do is at a traffic light system.
So we're the home tab.
We've selected the cell where we want to add to our traffic lights,
and we're gonna go to conditional formatting.
Now,
in the past,
we've always gone to new rule.
But this time we're gonna choose icon sets.
Now,
when I'm playing around with these in just a few seconds,
just pay attention to what happens over here.
So if they chose this option,
you can see the 100% gives us an upwards green arrow.
Or we can have this or we can have this or this or these or a traffic.
Actually,
that's the traffic light or indicators.
So I'm gonna don't go for this one.
The tick.
So 100% is a take.
I'm gathering mill percent is across,
and somewhere in between is an exclamation point.
So I'm just gonna click that I want a copy that formatting and paste it away.
Down on.
There you go.
We have crosses here.
We have no chance of having either of these meals or any of those meals.
We have a 100% chance of having a BLT because we have three items selected on all three
items appear in that recipe,
and we have some degree of a chance of these things,
most likely chicken salad at 67% or 33% chance off full English.
So let's just pick much every house.
You have bread and they go bread.
Now we've dropped down to a 25% chance,
which is below the below the third.
So we've now got across Onda.
We have a 100% chance of having a b lt still.
Okay.
Now,
in this cell,
we're gonna have a look at in the next lecture.
We're gonna have a look at the hyperlink formula now.
It's pretty redundant as far as this project goes.
But there are some quirks with views in the hyperlink formula that are absolutely
impossible to work out unless you actually know how to do it.
So we're going to cover that off in the next lecture.
I'll see you there.