Okay,
guys,
practice exercise number two,
They're gonna have to thing back to a little earlier in this section,
I think I may have mentioned as we went through this particular section that these tabs
here with our recipes in our ugly but functional what I want you to do is change the format
in on this on their stick with may cause this may sound easy,
but it's gonna get a little bit more complicated in a second.
I want you to emergency center on,
change the color and increase the fund size and make it bold and left line Here went to
bold this Basically,
I just want you to prove to this up now,
one of when you do make this a different color,
perhaps make it bold.
Increased thesis eyes Andi column It's something like that and make it so.
It looks very nice,
but where I want you to do is recalled that as a macro,
then automatically flip to these tabs and then execute your macro again.
So every single one of these tabs has exactly the same formatting.
So they go.
That's your challenge.
I'm just doing that.
I want you to pretty up the format in on one until you're completely happy with it.
I want to record it is a macro.
Then choose each of these.
Intern.
Execute your macro.
So that all formatted in exactly the same way.
Okay,
so that should give you some.
Practice it recording macros.
I'll see when the next lecture.
Where?
I'll tell you what your final challenge will be.
I'll see you then.