Okay,
guys,
welcome to this new section,
though.
In this section,
we're going to be having a look at two ways that you could create gun charge using excel.
Now,
the two ways to do this are by using a worksheet or by using the chart itself.
Personally,
I prefer the worksheets because I find them easier to work with.
But we'll cover both options in this section here.
So the first way we're gonna have a look at is to do it in a new chart.
So what I've done insect in sheet one here is of just imported part of our HR database that
we used in an earlier section on have also tagged on an end date.
He s o.
We can see what our employees name is weak and see the start date,
and we can see the end date.
Now,
what we're gonna do is out a new sheet on.
What we're gonna do is just call this,
uh,
we'll call it gun chart hit.
Enter on,
Bond.
Let me just merging.
Center that while I'm thinking this true now what I'm thinking to do.
Just so we have a little more versatility in this is,
what we're gonna do is have an increment.
So I'm just gonna put increment in there and highlight that.
And that's gonna highlight that this is a cell that we can add value into stick with me.
This is gonna make sense in a second.
Okay?
Now,
at the moment,
what I'm gonna do is I'm just going to reference the that the cells in sheet one.
So I'm just going to click on here and click on the first name in his hands.
I'm just going to drag that down until we get all of our values and they're still a few
more to go rips today's.
Eat him into that.
Copy down.
My goodness,
we have a lot of interest at those.
We have that money.
There we go.
OK,
so we have 15 9 cells starting itself four.
So we've got a fair bit of data that we can play with their.
So we've got family.
If we got got 54 interests,
okay?
Now across the top.
What I'm gonna do is have the dates.
Now,
what we could to is look back a cheat one andi sticker filled from here.
Let me just stick a filter on have liquid are early status and it looks like it's in 2010
January the eighth.
But we there is a much clever way of doing this.
What we're gonna do is used the small function in here.
Now,
what the small function does is it returns the smallest value from a range of data.
So just have a quick look at it here.
What we're gonna do is five equals small open brackets,
and I'm just going to highlight this entire array here,
hit,
Comma and K is the value that you want.
So if we want the first,
we will put one as the K value.
So that will be the first smallest value from this array.
So his enter,
we can see that we get the answer for 186 which,
if we change to a date,
tells us it's the eighth of the 1st 2010 Okay,
so we're going to use the small function over here.
So what do you say?
Equals small,
but I've actually already named.
This is a dynamic named range,
which we covered earlier on.
I have called that dynamic named range end date.
So end.
Nate and I want to return the smallest value.
Close brackets on hit.
Enter.
So there we get 4088 It's actually start data want,
isn't it?
Sorry about that.
Start days ago.
So get 40186 I'm just going to change that to the short date on.
I'm going to rotate it round of it.
So let's just hit the format cells.
Alignment.
Andi was it ran until it's 90 degrees and hit.
OK,
right.
Okay,
So now we have our small estate.
If you want to have a gap in between this and where the first bar starts,
what we could do is at the smallest state,
minus one.
So there we have the seventh of January 2010.
Now this is where the increment comes in.
Normally,
what I used to do back in the olden days before I realized there was a better way of doing
it is I used to add one to this day just here.
So I just hit equals one.
Let me just copy that formatting all the way across.
So they go.
So what I would do is I would say that equals C five plus one on.
Then I would just struck that all the way over,
and I would end up with lose and lose and lose dates.
Let me just go all the way over to there on just resize all of those automatically.
So there you go.
So now I have the seventh of January,
the eighth of Germany,
Ninth a genius so on and so forth.
But that's useful if you want to see everything in days.
But sometimes you may want to see what the count looks like in weekly book.
It's or fortnightly book.
It's or monthly book,
it's or yearly book.
It's depending on what data it is that you're looking at.
So then I happened upon this this technique of introducing an increment.
So what I'm gonna do here instead of saying C five plus one,
I'm gonna sing,
say,
C five plus increment and I'm gonna hit F for once.
So it absolute cell references be three.
So wherever we come for this formula,
it's always gonna look at B three and and they're all I need to do is entrant increment in
here.
So when I hit enter let me just copy that all the way across.
We went that far,
Didn't may.
So no,
we could see we start on the seventh because it is a small estate in our start date range,
which is this one just here,
which is dynamic.
So when we had new data in New Zeta will form in here to on we go 8th 9th 10th because our
increment is one.
But if we wanted to look at it in weekly buckets,
we changed the increment to seven.
And notice what happens to allow the dates across the top.
There goes on.
There we go from the seventh of January to the 14th of January 21st 28th.
Similarly,
we can look at it in 14 daily buckets.
And there we see,
we jumped from the seventh to the 21st to the fourth to the 18th and you can put whatever
number you want in here.
So if you want to see monthly,
you can just do that if you want to see year leading typing 365 and so on and so forth.
But that's a useful way of dynamically changing what your increments is what we're gonna
dio.
Don't Hamli.
We've gone across that.
How many have we gone across?
Let's go across 50.
So I'm just going to expand that a bunch more times control on our Onda Hamli have we got
Now?
We've got 50 to 52.
That's good.
That's the number of weeks in the year.
So if I was back over to here and I changed that to weekly,
we will now start 1/7 of the 1st 2010 on.
We should go roughly a year later.
31st the 12th 2000 and 10.
Close enough.
Okay,
so that's how we're gonna build our dates across the top using this increment function that
we can change dynamically to whatever we want.
It is whatever it is we want to see next.
We're gonna have a look at how we color these little squares in depending on the dates in
these cells Here.
Okay,
I'll see you in the next lecture.