OK,
guys.
Now what we want to do is build a complex formula in here that takes this value here using
a simple V.
Look up.
And it wants to read this start date and then compare that against the date in this row
just here.
Now we can begin by doing a straight V look up,
just like we did earlier.
So we're just gonna say equals V.
Look up,
open brackets.
We're going to choose this cell,
and we're going to hit F four because we want this cells always Reference column A but not
always rose six.
So we're going to hear therefore once and twice and three times.
So there were always going to look at a but the six were very depended on where we drank
the formula.
So I've already set up that data table in sheet one as a dynamic named ranged cold.
My data comer.
The start date appears in column two so column to comment on.
I want to find an exact match,
so I'm just gonna hit.
Enter on.
There you go.
Now we can see that when we drank this formula down.
Come on,
my Lancelot bottom.
We're going to get a bunch of different dates entered in here.
Don't worry that these are just numbers at the moment.
Because we know if we if we right click on we apply format cells on,
then we go to date.
We can see that is actually the 9th 19th of the 4th 2010 This is just expressed as a number
.
Okay,
so so far so good.
But what we want to do is convert this into a one or a zero.
So what we're gonna do is add a logical test in front of it,
just like we had before.
So we're gonna say if open brackets this V look up returned value,
we want to say,
is less than or equal to this cell.
Now again,
we need to hit therefore a few times because this cell is we're going to drag this formula
around.
But we always want to look at Roe five.
So I'm gonna hit F four twice.
So I get see absolute five comma.
The value to return if that is true,
is one common.
The value to return if that is false,
is zero close the brackets on hit enter.
So now we can see when we copy that Down on we carpet whips the days until the show.
What?
I'm doing that.
Okay,
so let me just put a freeze pain on there so we can we can see where we're going.
So view free pains free.
Spain's at the top.
We're just going to copy that formula all the way over.
So we're gonna copy all the way down and all the way over to hear control on our so they
Now we can see that we've got a load of zeros on Dhere on this one.
We start on the 22nd of the fourth.
We can see that that is our 1st 1 against collar Phillips.
And if we have a look,
Cano Phillips started work on the 19th of the fourth.
And you can see that that's the 1st 4 week because you'll remember that.
Let me just take off that freeze panes for a second,
scroll up and then apply for his pains on.
You'll see that because we're working in increments of seven.
That will be the first week that collar started work.
If we change that to three,
his zero jumps.
Although my overs here because,
no,
this is the first date that is less than or equal to Collis start date.
Okay,
so far,
so good.
But let me just turn on change that to seven.
The problem we have now is that what we're looking at is the start date,
and that's great for telling us where to start our bar.
But what we actually need to know is where our bar should finish,
so we can see a distinct gallant line in our chart that shows us a start date on the end
date.
Now,
what that means is that we need to compare two different results.
So we've already created a V look up to pull the start date and then applied a logical test
with that if But what we also need to do is add second logical test from another V.
Look up.
Using the end date on.
What we're going to do for that is we're gonna introduce the function of Andi,
which we're gonna look at in the next lecture.
So I'll see you there