Okay,
guys.
And welcome back Now,
technically,
this is a student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Technically,
it's a student question that I completely miss Red and answered,
I haven't said the actual question,
too,
but that's gonna live in level three.
Now it relates to bar charts.
Got sorry,
Gant charts.
So it lives perfectly at the end of this section.
What the actual question was,
What do I do if I have the same primary key or the same person,
name or store number in the list and I actually wants And they have different starting end
days?
How do I display that separately?
Well,
the solution to that one,
though it possibly could be done in formulas,
is much simpler in VBS.
I'm gonna cover that in level three.
So this is the question I miss read the romance trim,
but equally useful.
So I thought I would drop it in the here.
So the question I thought I read was,
how do I color in the bars and began chart in different colors due to different reasons.
So that's the question I'm going to ask on.
Suggest here.
So here's a downloadable file for you.
It's called Gan charts with different calls for different reasons.
And it's just a butchered version of the one we've been using in this section.
Now this is the data table as a modified version of the data table.
No,
Previously,
we had start dating column,
too.
An in Dating column three but now inserted this reason code column in column two.
So where we were looking for the Star DATING column two.
It's now going to be column three on we look for the In Dating column three is now gonna be
column for So that's our data set on.
We have three different reasons for the absence.
We have an annual leave.
We have poorly when we have on authorized.
Now here we go.
This is what we had before.
Just to recap.
We have some conditional formatting set here that says,
If either of our responses is zero,
that is,
there's a blank in this column or a logical test evaluates to false.
Then return zero on the conditional formatting for zero sets,
the text toe white so it's not actually visible in the gun chart.
Now what we also have is an onda a logical test.
Saint Andre V look up.
And this is just to evaluate the dates.
Is the start date my data?
Three.
Less than or equal to this self And is the end date No column for greater than or equal to
this.
So what we're gonna do is we no need to evaluate 1/3 criteria and all three criteria need
is a criteria or criteria.
Who knows?
All three need to evaluate.
True for this.
On statement to return one.
So what?
I've been different.
I'm gonna delete everything open to the one.
I'm on a laptop on Windows Tank.
He's kicking in that stupid menu on the side X driving me mad.
So my apologies.
If that happens,
I'm just going to copy the first part on way out front.
I'm just going to pace it in and hit comma.
So now I have three tests.
The first s is the same as the second test,
but I'm now going to butcher that and look for that annual leave in Colin teasing the saint
on.
Do you?
Well,
leave on.
They go.
But I'm looking in column two for that.
So now logical test has three on statements that must evaluate true just calling to equal
annual leave on a day check on Column three and column for And if all that is good,
return one.
Now that's our first check for annual leave,
and I'm going to copy air within rice,
Open toothy if and copy.
So if those three Stamets a true returned one when we hit old and intact to give me a new
line it control of a on paste that in again.
But this time I want to return to I'm no looking for annual leave.
I am looking for poorly because that's another one of our categories.
I'm gonna come to the end on the hit control on D V whips meant it all turn into their
ultimate.
They go and here's our third test.
But this time I'm looking for Savva.
Look,
own or authorized.
So there are three Andi tests are three if tests each having three checks within the and
brackets.
So we're looking for annual leave on a date check.
And if all that's good,
return one.
If not come to our second logical test.
And again we're looking for are poorly on our date checking.
If those three evaluate to true returning to.
And finally we have the whips windows.
We have the final one,
which is unauthorized,
and the date check.
And if all that evaluates to true return three.
If none of those evaluates true return zero comma comma.
So your brackets,
brackets,
brackets onda enter So the the the the formula looks quite formidable.
It's actually quite simple when you follow the process.
So we're gonna do is copy that down and I'm gonna copy that across.
Let me just delete that last column there.
So now you can see nature see that we have some twos and we don't have any threes,
which is incredibly unusual.
So I've obviously got a typo in there somewhere on a misty I excellent it and I or Thor
rise control,
Andy Controlling.
Ah,
they go now we have twos and threes.
So the only thing that remains his first change the conditional formatting to give us
different colors for two on three.
So I'm gonna come up.
So here,
come up to conditional formatting and I'm going to come to new rule.
What I want to do is use a formula to determine which sells to format now,
in cell C seven.
So I'm literally just going to type in here equals C seven.
Ah,
equal C seven equals two.
And I'm gonna choose a format if we want to.
So hit in formats at the world slows laptop.
It will wake up any minute now.
I really owed this wakes of anyone in that early go eso we want to have Let's have let's
have a delicious green cause I'm gonna say green for the funds on a fill of green because I
don't want to be able to see them on battling once it say OK,
and I'm going to say OK,
okay.
And I most will do number three while I'm here.
So again,
I'm gonna say new rule.
Use a formula on hearing to say equals C seven equals three,
and I'm going to pick another color.
So for mass,
and I'm gonna have a fill of red this time.
I'm gonna have a fun color of red so you can't see the number against the background.
Okay,
Okay.
And knowing in a copy that and paste over the whole of this area just here.
I've always went like Barry white there.
So there you go.
So now you can have different colors for different reason codes.
I hope that was useful to you as ever.
If you have any questions,
just let me know and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day and I'll see you in the next lecture.