Okay,
guys,
welcome to this lecture.
No,
just for fun.
I'm going to show you how I generated all the car registrations that we used way back in
section two.
Okay,
Now what we're gonna do is combine a lot of the elements that we've already covered in this
course on.
We're also going to introduce a new one which is rammed between.
So the first thing we're going to do is build a look up table of all the letters of the
alphabet.
So down here,
I'm just gonna add the numbers one through 26.
Where are we?
One through 26.
And next to that,
I'm going to add the letters in caps A B,
C all the way down.
And I'll come back to you in just a second when I filled all those in.
Okay,
so now we have all of our letters of the alphabet down here.
So what?
Windows just highlight over that,
and I'm gonna add this as a named range,
so I'm just going to call this letters.
Hit,
enter.
So there's our first data rate.
I think of the cups.
Look on.
That looks a little bit on attractive.
That they get.
Okay,
the next thing we're going to do is have a look up table for the first numeric in there.
Never contact.
Remember,
have these look in the real world.
So I'm just gonna put 123 in here on.
I think we have zero.
I think we have five,
and I think we have six on.
Then I'm just gonna change that to a data table by clicking in here.
See if I've got the caps lock on.
Not now on.
Call that numbers.
Okay,
so then we have our two data tables.
We have our letters and their numbers for the first digit.
Now,
what we're going to do over these cells is just create a random entry from this column or
from this column.
So let's start building here.
So here,
we're going to say,
equals rand between open rackets on their bottom number is going to be number one,
because we're going to be looking at the alphabet on our top member is going to be 26 close
brackets and his center.
So now you can see that we have 18 entered in here.
Now,
what we're gonna do is take that 18 and use that as a look of value from this data table
over here.
So just before round between,
I want site,
they look up.
This is gonna be outlook of value.
The 18 just coma.
And when I wanna look at is the lettuce table comma.
I won't read from column two,
which is where the letter lives come up on type,
false and hit.
Enter.
So they go.
We now have our first letter,
which is going to be f.
So what I'm gonna do is strength that down that far.
Let's say we eventually we're going to get down 200 lines there.
All we need to do is just basically that Let's go down 200 lines.
So down,
down,
down them in there in a way to 200 because we have 200 employees control in deep.
So you go.
We now have 200 randomly generated letters.
That's the first letter of our member plate in the U.
K.
We have two letters at the start,
so I'm just gonna copy that across they go.
So there's our two letters.
The next thing we have is one of these numbers here.
I think,
if that's not correct,
you just put the right numbers in s.
So what we're gonna do very similar we're going to say equals Rand between open rackets on
this.
So I'm gonna have the lowest number as one of the highest numbers.
Three.
So it's going to be round between one comma three Andi enter.
So they go.
So now all we need to do is exactly the same V look up over here.
So the looker open rackets skip over this because this is going to be,
ah,
look up value comma numbers comer to because we want to pull from the second column comma
false and close brackets on.
I'm just going to copy that all the way down by double clicking the drag handle,
they go.
We have a random assortment of either zeros,
sixes or fives in line with this table here again in the next columns.
A little bit more simple,
because this is just literally a random number between zero and nine.
So what we're gonna do,
say,
equals round between from rockets zero on day nine close brackets.
So they go.
So now you can see there are a number plate is starting to take effect.
So we have three letters,
groups,
two letters,
two numbers.
And then the next thing we have are the three letters that appear at the answer.
I'm just gonna copy that control and see pay sitting there,
fill it across using control in our control and our highlight All of those three on Ben
Just double click that and that fills it.
Dancer,
No,
Across these columns with successfully randomly built a full UK car registration plate,
a case.
And next thing we're gonna do is join them together.
We've done this before with can Katyn Eights.
So we're gonna say equals Kong Cut where my and eight open brackets that I'm just gonna
point to these this one comma,
this one comer,
this one comma then we normally have a space in the UK space enclosed in quotes,
comma And then my last three less is this one comer.
This one comma this one and closed brackets.
So they go,
There's our first randomly created registration plate.
That woman do.
It's just copy that down 200 lines.
Well,
control and D.
Now,
to make sure that this is a unique value that is,
This registration only appears once we can adapt this formula to make it horrendously
complicated or what I normally do with these kind of things is I just cheat.
So I use the formula equals counts.
If what we're going to say is,
have a look at this range here.
This is our range in the count.
If his f four because we always want to use that ranges from when we drank the formula down
,
comma on gonna look at that value.
So what is going to do is find the count of that value in that range.
I'm closed rackets and his center and you can see is each time I hit enter that the numbers
change and they re calculate so double quick that and what we hope to see is a one against
absolutely every cell in here.
They're rather scroll down all the way to the bottom because we've already got this
highlighted.
We can just see down here that this sum is 200 which is exactly what we want.
200 unique individual UK license plate numbers.
Okay.
And that's how I generated those for use in our database section.
Okay,
So you in the next lecture