okay and welcome back to another user question and said this particular one is from
Jonathan on Jonathan's question.
Waas A.
He has a bunch of cells.
I would imagine there are probably thousands off them on.
Somewhere within those cells is a phone number.
Now this is just completely randomized data a just use around between and then appended a
No.
Seven because the numbers that Jonathan is looking for our mobile phone numbers.
So what we have in each of thes cells is a mobile phone number beginning with 07 that
always 11 characters long.
But they can appear anywhere within the string in each of these cells.
So it's a fairly straightforward solution.
What we can do is,
say,
equals on we're gonna say find open quotes 07 because all mobile phone numbers in the UK
I'm assuming you're in the UK Jonathan,
begin with 07 So the text we are looking for is 07 coma within text.
This particular string here comma and we want to begin at position number one.
So they go.
We can see in the first instance,
the 07 appears at the 12 position top position here the 11th here.
First hair fourth here.
Andi know.
What we're gonna do is we're gonna wrap amid function around that song the same mid open
brackets on the text I want to look at.
I should have actually started out on this cell here,
so come back up here.
Let's say in mid open brackets,
this is the text I am looking at Kama on.
We're gonna use that formula.
We just wrote that find to tell us where the start number is.
So that formula that we just written becomes our second argument.
So I'm just gonna come to the end hit comma and the mobile phone numbers.
According to your question,
Jonathan are always seven characters long.
Sorry.
11 carriages long.
So come at 11.
That's how many characters we want to look at.
Close rackets hit.
Enter.
I'm just going to double click that on.
Hopefully,
that does exactly what you needed to do.
No matter where that mobile phone number appears within the texting in each of these cells
,
this will find 07 on returned 11 characters from the point where that's found.
Hopefully that answers your question and enjoy using it on as always,
Any more questions just dropped me a note and I'll be happy to help.
Thanks very much.