Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered on this one's from Doug V.
Now dubbed these problem is that he has a column with loads and loads of data on at the
side of that column.
We have a dollar remain until actually got pound immensity.
But it's essentially the same thing on what Doug wants to do is extract a list of all the
unique items on,
then do a total against each off those items.
Says a couple of steps involved here.
I've got a completely random set of data just here.
So what we're gonna do is copy all of these company names,
which I randomly made up.
I'm gonna add a new sheet,
and I'm just going to paste them directly into here.
Now,
the next thing I'm gonna do is I'm gonna come up to data to remove duplicates on.
I'm just gonna hit OK on that's now gonna reduce this to just the unique entries.
If we want to weaken,
just highlight over that.
And if we want to make them alphabetical,
just come back to home sort and fills that and go eight said So there are 123456789 10
different companies.
Now,
the next thing we want to do is find out what the total sales were from this column just
here against all off these individual companies.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna say,
equals some if open rackets and they're the range is gonna be where we're gonna look for
our criteria,
the criteria being the company name.
So the range I'm just going to click the whole of column A.
That's where we're looking,
comma.
The criteria is the name of the company,
Which is this one just here,
comma on the some range is where the dollar a Mansell The pound amends live on That's
column B here.
Closer brackets on hit Enter.
I'm just going to copy that all the way down.
Control in D Change that currency,
obviously minus pound seals will be dollars.
Doug on.
There you go.
That's how you do it.
That is your unique lists from the however many we've got down here.
200 lines of data on the Somme against each of those companies.
Hopefully that helps you out,
Enjoy.
And as always,
if there any more questions,
just let me know.
Have a great day.
Thank you.