Okay,
guys,
um,
welcome back.
This is a student questions answered video except a great question from Karen,
which is actually in two parts.
One of its one of one of the questions about automation.
But I'll cover that in level three.
But the essential question is,
can you use a V look up or something like that to return a picture?
Now you'll find two downloadable resource is from this lecture.
You'll find the file that I'm now gonna work on called V lookups with pictures before and
at the end.
I'm going to save the completed version.
Gonna call it v lookups with pictures after how imaginative is that?
So basically,
what we have is this is our day to file.
And I just got four of my buddies in here.
Ashleigh Claire,
Clinton,
Dolly and some father.
Beautiful photographs off each of them.
Now,
first thing to notice,
these pictures fit perfectly within the cells that they're in.
So Ashley fits perfectly within B one,
and Danny fits perfectly with him.
Be for now.
They don't have to fit perfectly,
but they mustn't overlap.
That's the first thing.
Now what we need to do is a little able to each of these pictures.
So what we could do,
or technically,
what we need to do is Adul able to the cell that the picture appears in.
We could do this manually by click,
clicking on the seller and growing up here and type in.
It doesn't much quick away.
So I'm just going to select from a one down to be for a micrometer formulas.
And when it comes to hear this,
defined names are gonna hit,
create from selection.
And here it's automatically chosen left column,
which is where their names leave soon.
Okay,
on,
that's done.
So now if we have looking here,
we can see Ashley.
Is Selby full sell?
Be full.
Not the picture of Ashley cell before.
And if I pick Clint,
you can see that I get cell B three.
Okay,
So far,
so good.
Now,
the next thing I need to do is copy that,
not the picture,
this cell.
So it can either hit control and say,
or just right,
click and choose.
Copy.
There will come over to here on this one with the black border is exactly where I want to
paste it.
But I need to right click Choose Pay special.
I want to come all the way down to other paste options and choose this option just here.
Linked picture.
Manu,
click.
OK,
you can see that we get that picture of Clint Bang in the centre there.
Obviously,
I can move it around now.
The important thing to note here He said what we What we have is a picture of the cell,
not the picture that is within the cell.
Now you'll notice with the picture selected the picture off the cell.
It's pointing to the data sheet cell B three.
So for change that to be four,
for example would get a picture of the lovely daily.
Now what we need to do is how something so we can take their name in there on the picture.
Changes automatically.
So woman do for now is I'm just gonna type.
Actually,
Now what I'm gonna do is again come up to formulas.
I'm no.
So I'm just in this cell here.
I'm just gonna come to formulas to come to name Manager.
And then here's that the names that already got the actually clear Clinton deli.
I'm gonna add a new name.
I'm just going to call it for now,
A mug shot on what I'm gonna do here in the refers to someone type equals in direct open
brackets point to this cell because that's where I'm gonna type their name,
which also corresponds to the label off the cell containing their picture close brackets
hit.
Enter,
then when they hit close.
Now all I need to do is change this.
Instead of looking at data exclamation,
be full.
I just need to point that to the label that have just created.
So I'm just in a tight mug and you can see that there I get mug shot,
a money hit.
Enter Ashley's picture,
turns up,
and then I have Claire.
If I can spell Claire and then class picture turns up.
And if I hit Clint,
Clint's picture turns up.
And finally,
the lovely Danny and that's hey,
use the look up ish to be able to type something in an instantly pull up a corresponding
picture.
Hopefully,
that's helpful to you,
but if you have any questions,
just dropped me a note in the Q and a little be happy to help.
Have a great day.
I'll see you in the next lecture