Hello and welcome back to another student.
Questions answered like chap.
Now this question is from Irene be and all to do with tiered pricing.
Now Irene says,
Hello,
Alan,
Thank you for a truly great course.
You're very welcome Hungry.
Thank you very much for the compliment.
She says I'm currently trying to use Excel to calculate the final payment that certain
customers would pay on their electricity bills per month.
So so far,
we're into a straightforward,
tiered pricing scenario.
And there is a slight complication because if you look at the data set,
you can see that what we actually have our to pricing structures.
The 1st 2 loans 0 to 15 51 to 100 presumably lower usage customers.
And then we have another data set another data set as they grow to 200 all the way up to
over 1000 kilowatt hours per month.
So we have essentially two questions tiered pricing on.
Then we have the two data sets that we need to compare will deal with the two data set
thing at the end.
Firstly,
we're gonna have a look at the tiered pricing.
No,
what I've done is I've just taken that Dacian of pace it straight into excel.
And what I've done is I've created a simple table.
We have ah,
from column A to column on a price column and all this data is in this text 0 to 50 0 to 50
22 pence or sense or dollars or euros or whenever your local currency is,
and so on and so forth all the way down.
So we have three columns from two on price because we have two data sets.
I'm just going to insert a couple of columns there.
And here is where we're gonna type in our units consumed.
And I'm just gonna color that in yellow.
Now,
you can do this in a single formula with some products,
but I've been using Excel 30 years,
and if I haven't had enough coffee,
some products can be confusing s.
So what I'm gonna do is take the simplest solution and use a help.
A column and the beauty of helper columns is that even if your data set changes,
that is,
you decided to introduce a new layer within this at a new break.
A new price break.
It's dead.
Easy to change the formulas accordingly,
and I'll show you how to do that at the end.
So we're going to use a simple solution off a helper column.
Now,
what we have is essentially we're gonna have to different formulas.
One formula is for the very first opening gambit,
which is this one here on the second formula,
which we're going to use everywhere else will be a different one.
So,
firstly,
the the opening formula is going to be a logical test.
We're going to say if open brackets our value,
I'm gonna hit her for another.
I'm gonna be dragging this particular form around,
but just good practice.
So if our opening number is greater than our upper limit,
that is,
if this number is greater than that number,
we know we're gonna have to pay the Hall 200 at that price.
So B C six multiplied by that 200 by the price.
Because if our numbers more than that we knew the 1st 200 they're gonna have to be paid for
at 36 p.
If they are not.
Our false value is going to be whatever Aaron number is multiplied by the price and close
records.
I should really make that at that sale at me.
Let me just So let me just play called who's all those in the correct format.
OK,
so if our Numbers 200 we know we're gonna have to pay the 1st 236 p.
So that part is 72 payments.
Obviously,
if we put 100 there it will have it.
If we put 500 they're still only the 1st 200 they're going to come out at 30 60 given us to
£70 bump.
There's our first formula.
So now what we're gonna do and you can probably guess is we're gonna have a some in here so
we can work out.
What?
We're actually gonna have a summer in the one above it as well.
So much will write that while I'm here.
Okay,
The second formula.
Also a logical test.
What we're going to say is,
if our number f four,
because they're going to be dragging this formula around,
is greater than our upper limit.
So if this number is greater than this number,
we know that we're gonna have to pay 70 p for every unit between 200 on this upper limit.
So,
comma,
what we're gonna say there is open brackets,
this number less this number.
So that will essentially be 150 units at this price,
if our number is greater than the upper limit with me so far.
Okay,
Comma,
If not,
what we're gonna have to say is whatever it is over 200 up to our number is what we're
gonna pay at 70 p.
So we're gonna say open brackets our number at four minus C six because l Anoma less 200 is
going to give us one close brackets multiplied by one at this price and close brackets.
So that should give us if we you consume.
201 units were going to pay 36 p for the 1st £272 on the 201st unit will be its 70 pig,
Which is that 70.
Think so.
Our total beef 720 and that works absolutely beautiful.
It let me just make sure that I got all of my absolute cell references in I have.
So they go near,
we have worked allowed,
but Here's the problem.
Look what happens when we dragged down.
Ah,
we get minus numbers.
And that's because if this number is not big enough,
we actually get into negative numbers.
So we're going to do is we're gonna add a quick test in there to solve that problem.
So I'm just gonna take that entire formula.
Copy.
Andi,
I'm going to say if open brackets,
that entire formula is less than or equal to zero.
Just return zero comma.
Just give me that formula back.
So I've just pasted it back in on and sat on Bom bom bomp.
Copy that down and they go.
So now we can see that that works out perfectly.
So if we have 201 we get 200 units of 36 p 72 pink,
one unit at 70 p.
70 p for a total of 700 some soup bones and 70 pay.
So she went to 3 51 indented.
We get £72 in the 0 to 200 band £105 in the 201 23 50 band on that final one seconds.
3 51 at 90 p.
so that some total is 177.9.
Hopefully,
that makes sense to you.
Now what?
What I'm gonna do is I'm just gonna copy those two copy and paste them in there,
and they go,
you know,
we can see that we have these two things that these formulas will work here.
Justus.
Well,
as you can see,
cause it's just a drag herbal formula.
But what we do need is a some of those two numbers.
So now we can introduce a logical test that tells us what this price is going to say.
If this number is less than 101 comma used this price otherwise,
use this price.
A simple,
logical test.
Tsarnaev.
We consume 99 kilos,
although sorry.
99 kilowatts hours.
Although it would be £35.64 from this day to set because L A number 99 is less than 100.
It's actually £25.70 and they can see that £25.70 has been read there.
Hopefully you followed that.
Now what I was saying earlier about it's easy to to change this.
We can insert here.
Just copy down to get along the data,
and what we could say is what we got.
Children.
123 50 say 201 to 300 on 301 to 3 15 We could say that that becomes 150.8.
And when we yet let me that just put something in hand and they go see conceive,
that you can add as many of these as you want and all you need to do and to the lower limit
the upper limit in the price copy of Formula Down.
And it's really easy to modify.
Hopefully,
that makes sense.
As always,
if you have any questions just returned,
I'll be happy to come back to you.
Have a great day.
I'll see you soon.