Okay,
guys are welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now these questions come up a few times from a couple of different students on what they
wanted to know.
Waas,
how did you extract the last name?
If the person has a middle name now,
you can still do this with a formula.
It's quite straightforward.
Once you understand the steps now,
I don't particularly want to show you the finished formula because in isolation,
unless you understand the component parts of it,
it can look quite intimidating.
But once we break it down into the different steps,
you'll find that it's actually fairly straightforward.
So here we go.
What we want to know first,
is how many spaces we have in each of these cells.
And to do that,
we're going to use to of excels built in functions were going to use substitutes.
And we're going to use Len,
which is short for links now the limb function.
It just tells you how many characters are in a particular string.
So if I take that,
we can see that Elvis Presley has 13 characters,
one of them being the space,
so we'll come back to that in just a second.
So what we want to do now is use the substitute function.
It would help if I could spell substitute.
This is the tanks we want to look at.
We want to look for a space.
So that's quotes,
space quote,
and we would like to replace it with nothing.
So double quotes.
Don't worry about the instant instance.
Number close brackets hit and tap so they you can see that we get Elvis Presley without the
space.
Now what we want to know is,
how long is Elvis Presley with outer space?
And the answer is 12 characters now.
This one was 13 characters.
So all we need to do is so tracked this Elvis Presley from that Elvis Presley.
So we're just gonna side a limb A to close brackets minus and enter.
So they go the different stream.
Elvis Presley,
with the space and over,
especially without a space,
is one.
So we know we have one space.
Let me just copy that down just to show you that that works,
particularly get my mouse on its pattern.
They go.
So we get 1212 and that corresponds with the number of spaces in each of these cells.
Okay,
Part one.
Part two,
if this equals one,
will capture this in a logical tests at the very end.
But this is just to break it down.
If this equals one,
get the position of the last space.
Okay,
so this equals one.
We're going to get the position of the last space in that cell and that cell.
Okay,
so here are we gonna do,
say,
equals if be to Where are we?
There we go.
If B two equals and we're going to say one comma than what we want to do is find the space
comment within this text.
Start number one helps if you close the brackets.
So here we can see that the space in Elvis Presley is the sixth character.
Elvis has five letters.
And the six character is the space.
Okay,
So far,
so good.
These are false because we have more than one space.
But don't worry about that for a minute.
Will capture all that at the end.
Extent three is if there is only one space,
then we just want to capture the right most characters after that space.
So we're going to use the right function.
So we're going to say,
right,
open brackets eight to this elks.
We're going to the right of that cell we want to say,
Is the links off a too close?
Brackets minus.
Find reviews.
Find before find the space in A to just typing is in there from position one.
Close brackets close records and enter.
So they go.
No.
You can see that we've extracted Presley from Elvis Presley,
Aaron Presley or Aaron Presley from this one because it's gone after the first space.
But don't worry,
we will capture that later.
Jackson from Samuel Jackson and L Jackson from Samuel L.
Jackson.
Okay,
so if we only have one space,
we can now extract the last name here and here.
Okay,
get the position in the last space if B doesn't equal one.
So what we're gonna do here is we're going to use to find within a find.
Because if we just did a straightforward find,
sir equals open brackets.
Find text space comma within text.
This comma start number one is going to tell us six.
Just as it did earlier.
Okay,
So you got 667 and eight That's where our thirst spaces start.
Now,
the problem we have here is we don't actually know where to start after number one to get
to the second space.
So what we're going to do is gonna have to nest that find within another.
Fine.
So what we're going to say is equal find and think of this as the outer find.
We want to find text space comma within this text comma.
But we want to start where we found the first space plus one.
So if you found this first base at six,
we actually want to start looking at seven.
Going forward now.
So when I close that and his center,
that will be an error because there's only one space,
but the ones where we have two spaces will return 12 and 10.
So hopefully that makes sense.
We've used to find to find where the first spaces that's this one.
We've added one to it to get that number plus one and then have used that as a start point
far out to find.
And that's how we find the second space position.
Okay,
set four.
We're going to use a less a formula.
We've just written in the mid formula?
No,
at a mid function there amid function just extracts the middle bit of a string.
So we just said,
amid open brackets pointed to this,
we want to start a number two.
We wanna extract two characters and then we get L V.
Because L v starting that number two for two characters is l envy off Elvis Presley.
Okay,
so we're gonna use that with the formula that we've just written.
Remember,
this is only for the two's.
I'm gonna do it here in L era,
but when we copy it down,
it will answer correctly here in here.
And thats so we will get the last name for anything with two spaces.
So let's take this formula that we've just written,
not with the Eagles coffee eso Let's take that.
And we're gonna say here equals with actually less ideological test.
If these equals two,
then mid open brackets.
This is a text we're looking at on.
We want to go from there on.
We want to go,
let's say 100 characters because no one has less paper.
That's more than 100.
Garrett pissed and his enter for gets closer brackets.
But when we copy that down,
we can see that here we get,
Presley.
And here we get traction,
Jackson,
these areas.
But don't worry,
Mandrax will capture that at the very end.
Okay,
And now we're going to combine all of those formulas together in the last step.
So the first thing we're going to go do is take this.
Look,
this test here that tells us one or two on building into a logical test so we can say if we
make a majority a vision that we haven't So we want to say is if the length of all of that
equals one,
then I'm just gonna take it the equals so can steal this formula here.
So it's going to be the rice a two copy escape.
So if all of that equals one,
we're just going to use the right function comma on enter.
There's no equal.
So it's not going to evaluate to anything at the moment.
And here I'm just going to take it that that logical test that if we just say mid and
hopefully yeah,
that should work.
I'm just gonna copy that mean way.
Go.
Copy.
Oops.
Escape.
Copy.
and paste that in there.
So if this length of a to less length of a two without the spaces equals one,
just extract the right if it doesn't extract the middle string started the second space for
100 characters,
assuming no monastic second last name with more than 100 characters.
So now when I put on equals in front of that hate Santa,
we get Presley.
Remember?
Copy it down.
We get presently.
Presley,
Jackson,
Jackson.
It looks a bit complicated,
but if you follow those steps,
you should be able to understand how that works.
Hope that helps,
and it's always.
If you have any questions,
do let me know,
have a great day and I'll see you in the next lecture.