Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now this question is from Jamala,
and Jim Ellis says I'm using an array formula to build up a range of values in getting the
average.
How can I use the summits function and not can't blank cells there,
the head of the questions using an array formula to sum up summits.
And you don't actually need to use an array formula to do this because in the ifs,
that s part one of the criteria can be Is the sell blank or not reading further on?
For instance,
there are two departments and we're trying to get the every salaries of the first
department on the second departments are not an average of the whole of the salaries,
but split that out into the average between department one and department to.
So here's a spreadsheet that you can download.
It's called the Ifs.
Now I'm just gonna walk you through all of these different permutations.
So here we have a straight some.
If what we're going to say is equal some if open brackets with something,
columns say so.
Everything in everything in columns,
say,
And here's the crisis area doesn't equal blank.
Now you have to enclose this in quotes.
So we have open quotes less than great to them,
therefore doesn't equal close quotes.
Andi double quotes,
which is which is blank.
So some columns see if it doesn't equal blank.
And if I just drag over that here,
you can see that we get an answer to 81732 And that's the answer that we get here now to
work out the summits of everything that's in department wanted the or deeper or department
to.
We're going to use this Some ifs.
So in the summits were going to say some ifs.
Open brackets was still something,
columns say,
but we are wanting to look in column B.
This is our first criteria range.
We want to look at the value one.
So I'm clicking F three so looking column bay for anything that matches one on day.
Then do that doesn't equal blanks.
Open quotes doesn't equal close quotes group Mr Close Crude someone Andi blanks in here to
enter and then you go.
Let me just copy that down.
So the sum of all of the things all of the people with a salary in department one is 1 to
172682 I'm just copy that formula Dam.
But this time I'm looking at to So everything in column B that begins with two is going to
some over here If it isn't blank.
OK,
so just a sanity check.
Let's see what the sum is are made its to 81 just as it was before.
Now I can't if can't if works in just the same way so we can say count if looking all of
columns say on look for open quote So this is our criteria range and this is our criteria.
Open quotes doesn't equal Andi double quotes,
blank close quotes on enter making.
See that we get 16 interest Now We're getting 16 interests because we have a heading of
salary now.
Obviously,
that's not gonna work because salary isn't these air just ahead in.
So we don't want to include those so over to the camps.
If,
since exactly the same as the summits,
what we're going to say is count ifs range,
BB.
This is where we're looking to Kent.
If the criteria equals F three.
So if one appears in here and in C C.
This is our second criteria.
Range doesn't equal open quotes less than great than close quote Andi.
Double quotes blank.
So B B equals one and Sisi doesn't equal blank and enter.
We can see that we get nine entries for department one that actually do have a salary just
copying that down.
And here we have six entries in department two that have salaries.
So those to add up to 15.
Whereas if we just did a count,
if would include that salary and get 16.
So from there we can just divide the summits.
So everyone in department one with salary by the camp tiffs everyone in department.
One moment of salary on we get 19,186 89 copying that down for department to we get 18,175
is the average salary.
But we don't need to go through all those stages to get to Iran.
So what we can do is use the average ifs.
So what we have here is average ifs,
open brackets.
Sisi is our average rain showing again looking in column C then we come to our criteria,
range criteria,
criteria,
range criteria.
And you can go on and on and on with this.
I'm not sure how many times per mature.
It's quite a lot.
Well,
you'll ever likely to need.
So we're gonna be doing an average from column Say our criteria range is B.
And here we are looking for the criteria equals one.
So anyone in department one is going to be included and then the numbers in columns.
See,
this is our second criteria range.
We're gonna look for exactly that same thing again.
Does not equal blank.
So open quotes less than greater than close quotes does not equal Andi that.
So we string it together,
double quotes,
blank.
When we hit enter,
we get the average for department one is 19,186 89 which is exactly the same number we got
when we won't step manually.
Copy the formula down and the average salary for department to folks is 18,000 175.
I hope that helps,
but is always if there any questions do let me know and I'll be happy to help Have a great
day and I'll see you in the next lecture