Okay,
guys.
And welcome back to another student.
Questions answered.
Lecture.
Now,
this questions from Raymond on what Raymond says is I'm looking for a conditional look.
Awful.
A couple in index match,
which uses a drop down list of sorry,
which uses a drop down list.
Look up values query values in different columns.
So basically,
what we have is a front sheet that looks something like this.
And this is a drop down list here on this drop down.
This is access in this range or this range.
All this range on what we want to do depended on what we've selected in this drop down list
is pull the data from either this range here or this range here.
All this range here and on and on and on all the way across.
So basically a drop down list,
and then we want to pick either This data set this data set all this status set.
Now we look to name ranges in level two of the course on.
We've also looked at indirect on What we're going to do is use the indirect function toe,
actually change which range we're looking at.
So it's just another way of doing it.
So let me show you how that works.
Okay?
So you'll find two downloadable Resource is from this for this lecture and now called level
two sq.
A 18.
Drop down list shifting range before Andi after.
So we have three sheets.
We have a summary sheet.
We have a data sheet,
and I've just cobbled this together and we have four data ranges.
We have this one here.
Fergie One.
This one here.
Fergie to this one here.
Fergie.
Three on this one here for G four.
Obviously these Congar go on and on and on and on and on over that.
Now we have the dates stand the side.
I've just used February randomly on.
We have lists and their ranges.
And one of them in here is off.
Added these headings because we're going to use a V look up to find out what this range
actually say's so here of type G one G two through G four,
which is the heavens across here and in here.
I've put be three to e 17 which is this range in here.
I've just hoped F three toe 0 17 which is this range just here.
Start to odor.
Or I should say I they go.
That's not paying attention.
And then we have J six toe m 17 have been a make sure that that's right.
A J three to m 17.
Yes,
a J three.
I'm really not on the ball this morning,
asshole.
And n 32 Q 17 Let's make sure we got that one right.
And 32 q 17 Absolutely.
OK,
so here,
we're gonna do is I'm gonna create a drop down list across the top.
Actually,
I'm just gonna grab those Helling.
So date is going to be a constant on.
They will be the heading.
So I'm just gonna paste that into here and across the top here.
I'm gonna add a drop down,
so I'm just gonna come back to home.
Hit.
Merge in center.
Back over to data data validation.
My screens A bit small,
but it's in the data tool section of the data menu.
I'm gonna come here to data validation.
Data validation.
I'm gonna allow list on gonna no point to this list just here.
So that's released.
Hit.
Enter the Nobel to pick G one g two G three or G for that's the first thing.
Next thing I want to do is grab all of these states here,
control and see and just drop them in here.
Now,
the next thing I want to do is I'm gonna get the construction of looking at another cell.
So just randomly over here,
I'm just going to type equals on dpoint to our data.
Just gonna point to that one there so we can see that if we click back in this cell,
this is what it looks like.
I normally do this because whenever use in directs,
I can never remember where the exclamation points go.
So this is really an aide memoire.
More for my benefit than yours.
So what we're gonna say here is equals.
They look up open rackets and we're going to be looking at this cell here now.
My f all was playing up earlier.
No,
it's good.
So we're gonna look up this cell here,
comma.
So we're looking a G one,
and what we want to get is that range just there.
So this is our dates table.
I'm going to return the value from column two comma to calm a false and a better absolute
cell reference those.
So if my at four works,
there we go F four and F four and enter groups of miss something common to Okay,
Mr Commoners.
There.
Okay,
and enter.
So now we get be three to eat 17.
Now,
what we want to do is get that data bit in before they're so what we're gonna do in front
is we're going to say data.
Exclamation point exclamation point.
Close crew.
It's on.
And so there we have data on D B three to E 17.
And look what happens when we stick an indirect right in front of it in direct open rackets
.
Close brackets there.
Hit,
enter.
And that then populates everything from the G one section here.
This over to this range just here.
So on the third of February,
we should have six on on the 5th February.
We should have five,
and we certainly have.
But look,
what happens when we change the drop down list.
We can pick G two on.
We get a totally different data sets.
So now on the ninth of February,
we have seven in our second data set,
and they can see that's that.
So that's a very useful way of pulling ranges by a block,
and you can just use a drop down.
You can have as many of these as you want,
and you may find it actually easier if you just hope the cell ranges into a look up and use
that construction.
Okay,
I hope that helps.
And as always,
if you have any questions,
do let me know and I'll be happy to help.
Have a great day and I'll see you in the next lecture.