Hi, and welcome back to another student questions and select j.
Now this question is from Dylan,
and in essence it's a fairly simple question,
but there are a few literally moving parts in it.
And I thought it was, it was worth doing this video to
walk you through the process that are used to build the formula.
So this is basically a mockup of the dataset that Dylan has.
The original dataset is much larger,
has many rows, many columns.
Now, it's a simple function.
It's just an average.
Actually it's an absolute average,
but we'll forget the absolute path is just an average function,
but it could just as easily be a sum function or
any other function that you use mathematically in Excel.
And then the interesting part about this is the way the data is laid out.
So what we have is iodine,
A1 dies and then some function performed on this,
some calculation that gives us this answer.
And this, and this gives us this answer.
Now what we want to know is the average of all of this for dataset.
But we also want to know that for dataset B,
the problem being we don't know
which column dataset I lives in and which column date set B lives in,
or C, or D, or E. So we need to find a way to capture that dynamically.
So the one thing that we do need to do to make a manual adjustment
is give us something to look for that unique.
So we called this diff I,
instead of just if we would be able to look for that in row
two and then find out that we're in column F. And similarly,
if they said DEF B will be able to look for that in row to find that it's column i,
and then use this date says it's as the first dynamic passed.
Second dynamic parties, although all the data points begin at row three,
they don't necessarily end on the same row.
So rather than saying, Actually I've worked out it's in column F.
So look at F3 to 14.
That's great, as long as every other dataset finishes at line 14, but they don't.
So that's our second dynamic part.
Okay, so I put together a very simple spreadsheet with the bare minimum of data,
but the format is same.
So our headings divide if bait, if say R,
m rotate the first night sets in F,
secondary datasets in I,
third datasets in our,
and they're all different lengths.
So we have four, we have nine,
and we have two over here.
So I'll show you the formula,
which looks absolutely monstrous.
But basically, it's a really simple formula.
All it is is a string that we've built dynamically.
We're going to use the indirect function to tell Excel.
This is actually a data range rather than just a bunch of letters and numbers.
And then we're just going to slap an average around and it's,
it's really as simple as that.
So the first thing today,
and the first thing I always do is I just started
the formula as it would normally appear.
So the amine row a,
so this is the average I want to get 4.5.
And for B, I would say equals average open brackets come here.
Select the data for b,
which is a different length to the data for a
close brackets his aims at Lego and 0.33c, right?
That is what we're trying to get to, that is the answer.
And then the elements of this that we're looking for is this path.
And this is what we need to build.
We need to know where we're looking, which Sheets spill.
Ioc type, something wrong where my I forgot to take the heat off they go.
That's what we're trying to get it say.
So for rho a and that's what we're gonna be looking at for dataset B.
That's what we're gonna be looking at.
How we can see by looking at this,
that most of it is exactly the same model.
The sheets is always the same.
So we can hard code that the apostrophes at the beginning, I'm sorry,
at the beginning and the end of the sheet name constant,
the exclamation point constant,
lesser f, i is dynamic.
So we need to be able to capture that three is constant.
We can hard code that coulomb standards separator for Arrange, hardcoded the lessor,
again dynamic and the row number where we finish
needs to be dynamic to based on how many data points we have in that particular range.
So this is what we're trying to build.
And if we can make Excel gives us something that will display
exactly those letters and numbers and exactly those letters and numbers,
we can just say in direct, therefore Excel,
this is IRange and you should perform a calculation on sleep,
an average rammed it or resume and voila were all done.
Okay, so the first thing we're gonna do is we're going to find
out the column number of dif i.
So this is just a simple match functions.
All I've said is match.
Look at death and the value in R3.
So look for D.
If I look in mile the sheet,
look at row two and return an exact match,
and we can see the result is six.
So if we come over here,
we can say 123456, they go.
So dif i appears in column six.
If I change that to be if b appears in column nine and we can see 6789, there's diff Bay.
So we know that that part works.
And it's only partly useful because we express a ranges with letters, not numbers.
So what we need to do is find a way to convert that six to F.
Now, I have coded this next section
in the level three parts of the course, the VBA coding.
And I've showed you how to do this with VBA code,
but I could honestly couldn't think of an application for this until
this question came from Dylan to include it in Excel as a formula.
So to find out which column lysate six is,
we're going to combine two functions, the addresses, substitutes.
And just so you understand each element of that,
I'm going to take you through step-by-step.
So the address is a really simple function.
Or you going to say with the address three arguments.
The first one is, what's the row number?
We're going to say it's row one.
What's the column number?
We know it's six or I've just typed six.
And then we want the return type.
And the return type is basically z,
the absolute, absolute, relative,
relative, absolute or relative.
And we're just gonna say for relative.
So now we know that the cell dessert row one,
column number six is F1.
But the elements of that that we're interested in is the f,
We didn't really care about the one.
So now we're just gonna have substitutes.
And what you do with Substitute is you say,
look at this, find this,
replace it with this.
There the three arguments.
So for this one we're saying,
Look at age 11, F1,
look for one, replace it with nothing,
therefore, giving us f,
That's the substitute part.
And when we put them together,
we say substitute address,
row one, column six type for F1,
remove the one, replace it with nothing gives us f. So now
we can dynamically capture which column wherein, okay?
Obviously we can't say sakes because it will vary depending on whether it's stiff or not.
So what we're gonna do is we're gonna take this formula where we got the answer of six.
And we're going to replace the six here with that formula from here.
So this is completely dynamic.
So if I change that to be,
this changes to I,
if I change it to see it changes to L.
So that's perfectly dynamic.
So we use that F part more than once.
We use it here.
If you can say, and we use it here.
And then the other thing that's constant is that the star rho of three.
So we can take this formula and how do we turn f into f,
x3, we say, and three.
Now we have the start point.
And then we also have a colon.
And we also have another F or
l or whatever lecture it was dependent on where you look at.
So this, we can also take this formula and just build it up a little bit more.
So we took the formula F3 ADA colon,
and then repeat the f part of the formula.
So now we have F32,
f something, and this is the last dynamic path.
So we need to know how far down that column we need to go.
And this is just a simple Kansas.
Kansas I looks for non blank cell.
So as we're actually looking at a tough, I'm going to look at f.
And they sentence. So we have five non-blank cells.
Now, obviously, we have a blank row at the top.
So an actual last ITA points is on row six.
So how do you get from five to six?
You add one.
So they go. Now we know that the data point for this ends at six.
If it was B, o is hard-coded. Ignore that.
No, we know we have F32,
f something out now we know how far down the column we have to go.
So what we need to do is tag this on to the end of this,
and that will give us F32,
F6 and as our last fall, last formula.
But it's not always Column F. So sometimes it's going to be Column F,
Sometimes it's going to be column i.
So we need to replace this part of
the formula with something dynamic that we've already worked out.
How to find out the f value.
Whoops, it's escaped.
So here, let me move down one.
We're gonna use that can tie formula to get the number six.
And then we're just going to tank this counter a formula as bicycle in this formula here,
we're going to tack it onto the end of this.
So now we have this and it looks monstrous,
but it's all those other elements just built up an F32, f something.
And now we've dynamically captured number six.
So that goes at the end.
So that's our formula,
F32, F6, perfectly dynamic.
And when we change it, It's a b,
it becomes I3 to IE 11,
which is exactly right.
And when we change it to c,
it becomes L three to L4,
which is exactly right.
So that's the hard part done.
The next part is we just need to add the constant,
which is the apostrophe,
my other sheet, apostrophe exclamation points.
And that really is just as simple as typing milder sheet, sorry,
open quotes, apostrophe, milder sheet, apocryphally, exclamation points.
And the formula we have just an there into,
that is our dataset,
that is our range.
Now, at the moment this is just a bunch of symbols and capital letters,
lowercase letters, spaces, and numbers.
And to excel at means nothing other than that.
So to make this into a range that Excel can actually perform a function on,
we need to wrap it in an indirect and that's really simple to do.
You type equals in direct,
open brackets, sticky formula in closer brackets, and you're done.
So, and that's what we've done just here.
So here we've taken the formula that we've just written.
We've said indirect and we close the brackets around is.
So now all we need to do is choose which function we want to use.
So here we're going to say average in
direct calculation we've just built here that gives us that string and hit enter.
And they go, we get 4.5 and we can copy that down, and we get 9.33.
And we can copy that down and we get 75.
And now, because it's completely dynamic,
we can come back here and we say,
actually we don't want 14 in there and hear the answers
go much further down than they ever did before.
And come back here,
you can see that answers have changed.
So that's how you do it.
It looks like a monstrous formula.
It looks like a monstrous formula to me and I wrote it,
but it's actually really simple.
It all hangs around being able to build something that looks like that with a formula.
And we can do that by using the match to find the column letter at column number,
using the address and substitute to convert the number to a letter.
And then we just use Camtasia to find out how far the data goes down.
And we just stick all those little elements together,
rapid up in an indirect and then wrap them up in
an average or a sum or whatever function you want to use.
Hopefully that was helpful.
It's a lot to take in,
but you can watch it as many times as you like.
And as always, if you have any questions,
do let me know and I'll be happy to help have a great day.
And I'll see you in the next lecture.