Hello and welcome to this new section.
Now introducing you to the cloud.
The cloud is the solution.
If you don't want to buy or have a powerful computer to execute and train your machinery models indeed
you can now get access to some powerful what we call virtual machines all around the world and you can
use them privately for your own private machining projects or a project to run your models.
So that's an incredible tool to be aware of and that's why in the U.S. I'm going to introduce you to
the best cloud platforms that exist today on the Internet.
And of course at the end I'll tell you which one is my recommendation.
Which one is my favorite and besides on this favorite unrecommended platform.
I'll show you how to get started and I'll give you a nice PBF report and nice guide which will guide
you through the process of setting up an account on this platform.
All right so I'm going to introduce now to several platforms.
The order will not matter yet.
I'll just give you the list of the best platforms and in the end or in the next tutorial I'll give you
the best recommendation.
All right so let's start with the first one we're going to start with the most classic one and the most
popular one which is a AWOS Amazon Web Services.
This one right here.
First link Amazon Web services cloud computing services.
Let's click on this and here here you are on the page from which you can get access to that virtual
machines inside Amazon's and we call them actually the easy two instances which most of them are Linux
virtual machines.
So what exactly does this mean.
This means that you will be connected from your place to some powerful virtual machines far from you.
They can mean one state of the United States or in some other states.
So they will be probably be far from you.
But it's as if you had this computer in front of you and you can use it to use on machine learning.
So that's pretty amazing.
And Amazon Web services content is one of the best virtual machines.
So here you can scroll down to see all the products they offer.
I told you about Amazon easy to which are the virtual servers in the cloud.
So that's the main and most widely used product of Amazon related to machine learning.
So we can already click on this Amazon too and there you go.
You can already get started here.
They have an amazing guide and they even offer you a free trial.
Now you can try amazon too for free and the guide is amazing they show you step by step so that you
can really follow the process.
All right.
So that's the first one.
And now the second one the second one I want to show you.
And again that's not in any order of preference.
The second one is the Google Cloud platform so we can just type Google Cloud and here we go.
That's this link here.
After get this thing here Google Cloud Platform Google Cloud computing hosting services.
All right so.
Yes.
Cookies OK.
Build what's next better software faster you can imagine that.
Google also has an amazing platform with some great virtual machines as well.
And if you're interested in checking out in more details we want to go to product and here you go.
You have all the products and services and among them you have the virtual machines on Google's infrastructure.
So if we click on this here is where you can connect to a virtual machine in the Google Cloud platform
to build and train your machinery models.
All right so that's another great one but that's not all.
We have another two.
The next one is Microsoft.
As you were then you can just type cloud.
There you go.
Microsoft as you cloud this link again that's just an ad for Microsoft.
As for cloud computing platform and services definitely this one.
Here we go.
That's the third cloud platform.
I highly recommend to check out.
No worries again I'll give you my best recommendation.
So your vision your cloud and as you can see Zaur has more than 100 services with great end to end tools
to make you successful.
OK.
They're hybrid intelligent trusted.
Definitely Microsoft is a great brand and you can feel safe using their cloud platform.
All right.
And again if you're interested in checking out more details you just need to go to product here and
there you go.
You can find the virtual machines virtual machines provision Windows and Linux virtual machines in seconds.
You'll see that most of the virtual machines are offered on club platforms are either Linux or Windows
virtual machines but I can already give you my recommendation that it's better to use Linux virtual
machines in general when you do machine learning de-briefing or artificial intelligence Linux is more
recommended than Windows and even I'd say that Linux is the best operating to do some machine learning
or artificial intelligence.
So at least whether you choose Amazon Google Cloud or Microsoft is all cloud.
I recommend the Linux virtual machine instead of the windows virtual machines.
But there you go that's where you can connect to virtual machines on the Microsoft Zaur cloud platform.
And here again you can start free.
You have a nice guide that explains you well the process of setting up a virtual machine and use it.
Right.
So that's another great one and the next one the next one is of course you have heard of it.
This amazing brand and cloud the IBM cloud of course let's not forget about IBM you know what's on you
know what they do in terms of artificial intelligence.
That's pretty amazing.
And they also have their great cloud platform.
That's the first thing of course this is not just any cloud.
This is the IBM cloud.
There we go.
This is one of the best clouds for sure.
I'm not telling you yet which one is my favorite but this one is also really really good.
I'm not saying that I used all the cloud for a long time.
You know I didn't develop some machinery.
Applications for big projects on all of these clouds.
I just want to be honest on that.
The reason why I'm recommending you this is first of all I did a lot of research I experimented and
mostly I asked around you know I have a lot of people in my network who are data scientist and artificial
intelligence engineers or machinery scientists and they use a lot the clouds and ask them which one
is your favorite.
Which one do you use the most.
And that's how I could get a good idea on which are the best you know and also it's important to know
is that not everybody has the same favorite cloud platform so it's good that I introduce you to the
best so that you can see which one you feel best and also which one would fit the best to your project.
The way you work do you constraints and your goals.
No that depends.
But anyway the IBM cloud platform is another great one.
And again if you want to check it out in more detail you just into click products here and by scrolling
down you should find the cloud virtual servers.
There we go.
These are the ones you can just click on them and then not only have a great explanation on what's virtual
servers are but mostly you can sign up to do some great and powerful machine learning on their platform.
All right.
So another one among the best and now a final one which you might not have heard already but this is
also a great one that I must introduce you to.
And that's paper space paper space.
Another amazing cloud platform.
It is a great one.
You will see by the Web site that it's an innovative cloud you know built for the future powering next
generation applications from VFX to machine learning.
Here we go.
So if you want to do some powerful machine learning that requires some great computer resources you
can also consider paper space.
That's a great one.
So you can see again here we go.
Effortless infrastructure for machine learning and data science.
This is really a great one actually if you want to start because it's one of the simplest to start.
And you know you can easily run your python modules or Jupiter notebooks on this cloud.
So it's to be highly considered.
All right.
And so if you're interested in checking it out.
Well again you need to go to product.
You know it's always the same you have to go to products and solutions to products and then you need
to go to core because that's where the servers are.
Then you can not only request a demo you can also get the guy which is a great guide and which will
definitely help you in the process of setting up paper space very easily and we can see that really
it's a recent Web site quite innovative quite user friendly as well.
Know right now it makes me want to try it again.
So there you go.
That's my last recommendation.
These four plow platforms are really amazing.
And now in the next toile I'll give you my favorite.
I'll show you again the way to connect to a virtual machine and mostly explain why to me this is the
best.
All right so check out all of them if you want.
And next to toile Let's find out.
My final recommendation.