Hello and welcome to this new tutorial.
All right so we're going to start tackling our regression problem and to do this.
Our starting point is to get the data set to define the problem.
And this will be the opportunity for me to show you a great repertory to practice their science and
machine learning on the Internet which is the U.S. I am now.
Repository there is of course the Kaggle website that contains a lot of data sets and challenges.
But since these are your first steps in data science I think this is too soon.
And I rather recommend starting with the U.S. and a repository and so on Google you just need to type
here.
You see an L respiratory.
And here we go UCI machinery Repp is the first link.
Let's go inside.
And now we're going to go to view all datasets and you will see that you will find real world data sets
grouped into the diverse data assigned tasks.
And remember I told you in the previous tutorial that there was main types of data science problems.
The first one was regression which is the one we will start in this bison section and the second one
is classification.
Then you also have clustering.
But this is slightly more advanced.
This belongs to the unsupervised machine learning branch which is the situation where you actually don't
know what to predict.
That is you don't have a dependent variable that you would like to predict and therefore the challenge
here is more to identify some segments some what we call clusters which you have absolutely no idea
what they will be.
But the machine learning algorithm will find them for you.
But this is slightly more advanced and if you're interested in that data assigned task well feel free
to check out our machine or in course we have a full part with two full sections on clustering and we
implement two models.
Kamins and hierarchical clustering.
But here we are just going to tackle the first two Davison's problems which are already representing
a huge part of their science.
And these are classification and regression.
So let's start with regression and therefore let's click on regression here to have all the regression
problems.
And of course the data sets.
And so you can practice on lots of data sets with various data science problems and challenges.
I'm particularly interested in two industries today.
The energy industry and the health industry.
So for this course I thought of tackling two problems one that belongs to the energy industry and one
other that belongs to the health industry.
And so for regression we're going to tackle an energy related challenge and for classification This
will be a health challenge and you have many energy related challenges here.
But the one we're going to tackle will be this one the combined cycle power plant in which you will
see we will have to predict continuous outcome because remember regression is about predicting a continuous
outcome which you will see will be so i'm just clicking on this combined cycle power plant data set
will be the net how the electrical energy output.
Basically we have to predict how the electrical energy output of some power plants more precisely some
combined cycle power plant.
And that's the first thing you need to catch.
What exactly do we have to predict.
We have to predict the net how the electrical energy output and then the question is how are we going
to predict it with which independent variables are we going to predict this next.
Ali electrical energy output.
Well as we see in the description of this dataset one of the cell is the number of attributes and there
are four of them and these attributes are exactly the independent variables from which we are going
to predict this electrical energy output.
And by the way what we have to predict is called the dependent variable.
So basically to recap we are going to predict the dependent variable.
Thanks to our independent variables.
And so now let's see what they are.
Let's see what these independent variables are.
The first of them is the temperature the temperature going in the range one point eighty one degrees
Celsius up to thirty seven point eleven degrees Celsius.
Then the second attribute the second independent variable or even the second feature we can also call
it this way is the ambient pressure.
Of course this could be indeed a significant variable that would have a predictive power on the dependent
variable which is the energy.
So ambient pressure going in this range then the humidity of course that could also be a factor impacting
the energy.
Then the exhaust vacuum another variable that could have an impact.
And with these four variables which I remind are called the independent variables we predict the dependent
variable which is the net how the electrical energy outputs.
All right.
So a typical regression problem with very few features but nowhere is the model we will implement can
also be applied to any other data set whether you have four features or 1000 features by not changing
anything.
Just make sure that the independent variables of this data set are also continuous independent variables
because we won't have to deal with any categorical variable.
But if that's the case well you will be able to apply the model we will implement in this section to
any other data set.
All right.
Perfect So now that we understand the problem let's download the data set and let's start tackling the
challenge.
So to download the data set as you can see there is this download link here.
You have to do set description here and the data folder we are interested in the data folder because
that's where we'll find the dataset.
And here it is.
That's this zip folder CCP the combined cycle power plant that zip.
Let's click on this and to download a starting I'll show you here it is.
And it takes a few seconds this time and perfect we have it.
Let's go now to our download fooler because that's where it is.
Download it.
Here it is.
Let's double click on it to unzip it.
Let's open the folder.
And as you can see we have several files so the first one is some readonly file which you can open to
have some more information.
Yes indeed it contains basically the information of the challenge and the data set.
And by the way I'd like to give the credit to the author who made this amazing data set to practice.
Here it is.
You can find it in the read me file.
So let's close this because what we're interested in is of course the data set.
We have it in two formats O.D. as or Excel.
And we will take the excellent.
So I'm going to copy it.
We're going to go to our desktop folder interaction data science.
And because remember we have to put these data sets in the working directory folder in which we already
saved we already created our regression python file which will contain the whole implementation of our
regression.
So let's paste that here.
Here we go the dataset is ready and now finally let's go back to Python to start smashing this challenge.
So what do we need to start with.
Well first of all there is a very important thing to start with before implementing anything.
This is to be in the working directory for.
So the first thing we have to do here is go to the directory folder which is of course this folder the
regression folder.
So let's go inside.
And here we go.
We are inside the right field.
Now that's the only thing you need to do.
There is no button to activate a working directory folder like in the previous versions.
You just need to be in that folder and you're automatically connected to all the files inside the folder
and there are two of them.
The regression bytes and.
Which is this one in which we've just created in the toil and of course our dataset.
So we're going to start the implementation in the next Statoil.
But just before I'd like to show you how you can open a dataset directly from File Explorer by just
clicking on it right here and here is what we get.
As you can see it contains the data with the four attributes which remember are the ambient temperature.
The vacuum feature the ambient pressure and the humidity.
So these four attributes are independent variables.
And with these four independent variables we're going to predict this dependent variable which is the
energy.
All right so that's the first way of looking at the data set here as you can see it automatically opened
Excel.
So I'm going to close this.
Now here we are ready for the implementation which will start in the next two.
Until then enjoy the designs.