Come back to the course on data science.
Your intro Today is the ultimate guide to getting started in today's science.
And today we're talking about one of my favorite components of the design which is viz..
So I wanted to pretty verses by saying that maybe some people won't agree but I'm a firm believer that
there are two types of viz. in dataset and one is for data mining.
The other one is zation for presentation.
There is a substantial difference between them.
Bill Zill zation for presentation is the one that people usually refer to when they talk about visualization.
That's the visualization of the proper type of the position I'm doing floating quotation marks here.
That's just what people think of when they say that.
And that's creating beautiful images beautiful interactive charts and graphs and dashboards and things
that you will want to show others you will that will aid you in explaining your insides to others.
But at the same time there's a very important part of his position as well which is called visualization
for data mining.
And I personally use that term maybe others use call it something else but that is when you prefer to
see your data rather than to work with the numbers themselves and to get to the insights.
So a lot of people will straight away when they have a probable jump into something like machine learning
approach or something like that.
I personally always preferred to first look at the data and use some analytics tools to understand how
it works.
So the way we'll go about this is we'll talk about visualization for data mining further down in the
course and you'll actually get to do that in practice and you'll get a feel for it and visualization
of a presentation.
I'll give you a great example right now so you can see the difference you get an understanding of what
we mean by visualization representation.
So let's get straight into it.
So here I'm going to go to the right and I've got Google open.
So if in Google you look for visual cinamon you will find one of my favorite blogs on visualization.
And so he actually got the Web site open here.
I'm just going to go here.
Right.
And you can see right away as you enter you're greeted with some amazing visualization already something's
going on.
And then pretty sure there is some story behind it as well.
And if you scroll down you will see all these different lovely lobby positions.
This blog is run by the Bremmer Pramer Lady Cramer.
There she is.
And I wanted to show you one of them today.
So in your free time feel free to scroll around them and read through them and interact with them but
I wanted to show you which one I think is this one here.
We're going to look at this one which she did for The Guardian.
And I've got it open or over here it's called bust out and this is all zation is telling a story and
that it is insured by the way I wanted to mention that data science is all about telling stories telling
stories with data with and with visuals.
And so this is how Americans move how America moves homeless how governments move around homeless people.
You know two different states.
And so here you can see like one small exultation of how a one homeless person was bought a ticket for
a bar or a bus ticket and he had to travel 2000 miles and three days to reach his destination.
So if he keeps crawling you'll see like you know some some other things up here.
How beautiful was this.
And I'll look at this.
This is amazing.
This is like like a movie.
So this is
again different cities in different states moving by bus tickets to.
Let's go back.
So that goodies buying tickets to homeless people to send them to other places.
And it's a very sad story if you actually think about it like how these different states and cities
are trying to move homeless people away out of their cities and then other cities are moving them into
their cities.
So you can see here by the year as the years pass and all of this is data all of this is based on data.
So we're seeing the data rather than looking at a spreadsheet rather looking at numbers.
And as you can see it's done very very nicely of course this took a lot of time and it's done in more
advanced tool.
This is I think this is done in D-3 much more of.
But this is a type of data size Ramer is a data scientists used to work.
And what I think is Netherlands though.
So if you keep scrolling in some stories some more stories then there's there's hundreds were flown
overseas even so you see that somebody was flown to New Zealand just to relocate them so you can keep
scrolling you'll find like more examples.
Here again this is visualization of you can see that it is telling a story we're understanding better
what's happening even before reading it.
You can already see that this is a massive problem a massive issue and it might need.
It needs addressing the public needs to know about it.
What else is here.
Some some additional in size a static Wetzel's.
Then what else do we have.
So if we keep scrolling those are nice.
So here at the bottom
this is where you received the travelers who they are sent to siblings grandparents parents and children.
Sometimes it's institutions relatives and here for example I really liked this one.
So it tells a good story.
So here is San Francisco's bus program impacts house fences with the program impacts the homeless population
and you will see this is the city homeless population.
This is on buses bus journeys into the city so people who are homeless who was sent to San Francisco.
This is people bus stories out of the city so if we keep scrolling you'll see this start to start working
and you see the years changing here.
And so you can see that this is how many people were went out of San Francisco and now they're going
to do a comparison now like what my San Francisco homeless population have looked like if homeless people
had never bussed into and out of the city
how amazing is that how how beautiful is that.
It is also shown because again you can see very subtle very clean very nice and then now goes back and
they take these loans out and they put these in and you can see it would be so much larger would be
twice as twice as large.
So there you go.
That's more than twice that's the story.
That's the data side of the story.
I encourage you to check out this article it's on the Guardian dot com.
It's quite quite new as well and lots of interesting insights here.
And of course check out Lindy's Web site if you'd like to see some more amazing missile's patients she
puts in a lot of time into her work and this is Weasel's action for presentation.
Of course this is a very extreme example in the sense that I would take a long time to create something
as beautiful as this.
But this is still the point still stands.
This is a type of data size.
And then she has built her own career on this her own freelance career.
In fact I also wanted to recommend to you here if you go to this has a Comsec 81.
You will be redirected to this page.
The first episode of the suppressants podcast is called.
There it is zation and how to freelance your passion is actually with Mindy so you can actually see
her.
This is an audio version on soundcloud and iTunes if you want but otherwise you can watch on YouTube.
Our conversation about visualization and also how she built her day science career around just visit
zation all she's done of course much more.
She worked in R and other tools but now her career is predominately focused on this session.
Highly recommend.
Check out this episode I really enjoyed the conversation and heard some great feedback about it afterwards
as well and can give you some additional insight and of that thought.
I hope you enjoyed today's Tauriel and I look forward to seeing you next time.
Until then enjoy Davison's.