Welcome back recruit now it's time to discuss another python basic object which is a dictionary dictionaries
are an ordered mappings for storing objects.
Previously we saw how we could use a python list to store objects in an ordered sequence such as storing
integers or strings in order dictionaries however use a key value pairing instead.
This key value pair allows users to quickly grab objects without needing to know an index location dictionaries.
As far as their syntax.
Use curly braces and colons to signify the keys and their associated values so you'll have a set of
curly braces at the very outside.
And then you have key colon and then the value that goes with it.
Here we're showing strings as the values but you can also have dictionaries numbers lists as the values
themselves and then we separate each key value pair with a comma.
Now you may be asking yourself when do I choose a list and when do I choose a dictionary to put it simply.
Dictionaries are have objects being retrieved by their key name.
That is if you want to grab a value number one.
Then you just passen the key that's associated with that value.
That may seem really convenient but the issue here is that the way the key value mapping works is dictionaries
remain unordered and you can actually sort them if you wanted to be able to sort.
Maybe you want to reverse or organize your actual objects then you would need to use a list because
objects there are retrieved by their in that location and because there are lists that means you can
have an order sequence that can be index sliced or sorted.
So it's basically a tradeoff here.
Dictionaries allow you to retrieve by key name.
However you can't really sort them list apply to retrieve by location and then the added benefit is
that you can index slice or sort the list.
Let's explore these concepts further in a Jupiter notebook.
Let's start off by creating a dictionary will name it.
Variable.
We have a curly braces and then we create a key will have key one just string and then the value will
say value 1.
Then comma for another key value pair.
So key to and then value to then if I want to retrieve values I can just use their associated key so
I can Massin key one to return value to.
Or if I wanted a value to then I could just passen key to and grab value too.
If I ever want to add a new key item or key value pair.
All I have to do is call my dictionary variable.
Create some new key and then set that equal to whatever item I want to pasan.
So I'll just pass on a new string here called new item and then if I check out my dictionary have key
one value one key to value to key new item.
Now I want to make it really clear here.
Dictionaries are an ordered and this may not be clear at first with smaller dictionaries because it
seems like you're just adding in new key item pairs in order.
So let's show an example to really prove to you that dictionaries are unordered mappings.
When you add in Nuki item pairs you're not guaranteed to know the location of them which is why index
things or slicing is really invalid for dictionaries that concept doesn't really make sense for key
value pairs because we're not going to know their actual order going to create a new dictionary.
Here where I have keyway and its value is number one key and its value is in number two.
So if I take a look at my dictionary as to one and then Zia's to two I'm going to create a new key called
new and then set it to the values zero.
And now if I look in my dictionary when it reports it back it's not reporting it back in the order that
I added the key isn't just reporting back the actual key value mappings.
A One News arrow and Z2.
So hopefully this makes it pretty clear to you that the dictionary is an unordered mapping and you are
losing the ability to sort or call of indexing.
If you need that ability you'll need to use a list.
I should also mention that dictionaries are very flexible in the data types they can hold.
So to prove that to you I'm going to make a larger dictionary here we'll have the first key just be
K-1 and keys are just always strings and then the values can be quite flexible so we can see here at
10 that value will have key 2.
Will give it stringy a string as another value and then create another key K-3 and we can even have
a list here.
One two three.
And then we can even have a dictionary inside of a dictionary so we can say K-4 is equal to another
dictionary inside matched with the number 100 or now I can see kind of a complex dictionary.
So let's take a look at what all the keys are holding.
So one is holding the number 10.
K-2 is holding a string called stree K-3 is holding a list.
One two three and K four is holding we'll which we just call K-4 is holding another dictionary and I
can actually stack key value call so if I wanted to grab the number 100 I could type an inside here
and grab the number 100.
Keep in mind that you will get an error if you ask for a key.
That is not present in the dictionary.
For instance if we ask for loops which we know is definitely not a key in this dictionary you'll get
that key error and hopefully this error is pretty obvious that just saying key error it can't find that
key inside your dictionary.
Let's show you a more realistic example of when you would use a dictionary.
As you may already know every United States president has a Secret Service code name that's assigned
to them.
So we're going to create a codenames dictionary and we'll have curly braces here.
Obama's code name was renegade and you can check out the notebook.
That's associate of this lecture for the source on this.
And then Bush's code name was trail blazer.
What's
Reagan's code name was Rawhide.
And then Fort's code name was passkey.
And notice here I can actually type this out over multiple lines because it's all being contained within
these curly braces.
Remember that you are going to need these commas here to separate out the key value pairs.
So now that we run this let's imagine that I quickly wanted to know what the code name was for President
Ford.
Well then we would just passen code names.
Pasand the Ford key and I would quickly get back his code name.
So here's a pretty good example of why I would use a dictionary.
Basically any time you want to quickly store information where key value pairs make sense maybe you
want the populations of countries.
So you say USA it's population in millions is about 323 million population of Germany is about 83 million.
And we can say population of India is like 1.3 billion souls say 1000 324 million.
And then if you quickly wanted to know well what's the population and millions of the United States.
You can just use a dictionary to quickly retrieve that information.
This sort of data structure makes a lot more sense than using a list which essentially just the ordered
sequence.
Finally I want to discuss some key methods that are available to you off a dictionary and that is if
we look at this dictionary population actually let's look at the codenames dictionary you look at the
code names dictionary.
And I want to know all the keys in that dictionary.
I can run keys and get back Obama Bush Reagan Ford if I wanted to.
All the values of the dictionary.
Then I get back the actual values.
Notice here is not telling me what keys are associated.
What values.
If I wanted that connection what I could do is say code names and then call items.
And that gives you back this object where in what's called a tuple or Tapazole the actual matching Obama
renegade Bush trailblazer et cetera.
So great work so far.
We're actually almost done if your basic boot camp.
You just need to learn about sets working with files and you'll be ready for your first field readiness
exam.
I'll see you at the next lesson.