Welcome back.
It's time to learn about four loops many objects in Python are what we call iterable.
That means we can iterate over every element in the object.
For example iterating over every elements in a list or every character in a string.
We can use to say.
Along with four loops in order to execute a block of code for every iteration.
For example we can say we have.
My list is equal to a list of 3 integers 1 2 and 3.
And the for loop will then say for item in my list colon execute some block code such as printing out
every item in that list.
Notice how he created a temporary variable name called item.
If you go back to this example we can see here in white we have item this variable name is actually
completely arbitrary and it's up to you to decide.
Let's go ahead and explore some more examples of four loops with different object types.
Let's begin by recreating that example we just saw.
We'll create a list of four items here.
And then we're going to iterate through it.
We will see used keyword for and then we can make up some variable names such as and U-M them and then
we use a keyword in and then whatever the variable or iterable object is.
In this case my list colon and then we have the block of code execute for every single item or number
in that list.
So we can say prints numb and then we can see here one two three four.
It's printed every number in that list.
But keep in mind as a reminder this variable name is completely up to you so we can say something like
made up and I can replace this with made up and I can see I get the same result.
So we could just put in a bunch of words here and as long as they match up.
So copy and paste that in here.
Notice if I run this again I get the exact same results.
Because you can choose whatever variable name you want.
You should always try to choose something that's related to the actual variable here and using numbers
so I might as well call my variable and U-M short for numbers.
And here again and get the same results.
Now a really common question that recruit's often have is how can we print's all of this out in a single
line.
Will the prince function actually has an extra parameter he can provide which is.
And then you can say at the end equal to a space and then run this and instead of ending with a new
line it will end up with a space between everything.
So here we have everything printed out in one line.
I also know that even if I say Fortnum in my list I don't actually have to do anything with this number
in that list.
Previously if we take a look back at our original example I was printing out every number in that list.
I can just do something for every number in that list such as print out hello and then I will see Hello.
Printed out four times.
I technically don't really need to use this variable in the list.
If I do want to use it then I can just reference it inside of my FOR loop.
So it's a for loop with a list.
It works really Similarly with a string except instead of every element in a list.
We're iterating through every character in a string so I can say something like four letter in.
This is a string Prince letter and here I can see I'm printing out every single character and that includes
the spaces as well as any sort of punctuation I have here.
This is a string.
I'm printing out every single character so I can iterate over this and again just to make it very clear.
I don't technically need to use that temporary variable.
I could just say print hello.
And then a for every single character in the string.
It's going to print out Hello hello hello.
So those are for loops with strings.
We can also use them with couples so I can say TUPE or terp is equal to one two three four and this
will pretty much work exactly like a list for and in top prints.
And then I can see one two three four.
Now something that's a little bit unique in concern of temples or tuples and for loops is the fact that
we can use tuple in packing.
So I'm going to create a list of tuples So we will say list of tuples or Toups and then say one two
three four comma five WIPs five six seven eight.
And then finally nine ten.
So what I have here I have a list.
So notice the square brackets and then inside of this list I have pairs of tuples.
So what I can actually do is say for item in my list of Toops prints out the item.
So I would expect to get each of these tuples printed out in Python.
I can use something called tuple and packing.
And this really only works when you have an iterable list of tuples.
But I can instead of just saying a single item formatted as if there were tuples there so I can say
Item 1 comma item 2 and then here I will actually print out item 1 that I will print out.
Item 2 and then I will print a new line.
And then notice what happens here I get one two three four five six seven eight.
So you can use this sort of formatting when you know that the iterable object is a list of tuples and
lots of built in functions as well as lots of outside libraries of Python tend to return results in
a list of tuple format which is why you'll often see this sort of tuple and packing the final no.
I want to make here in regards to tuple and packing is that it actually doesn't require the use of parentheses
here.
You could just do something like this for item 1 comma.
Item two enlisted troops run this and you get the exact same thing and recall that we can call this
whatever we want.
We can say and one and two and we could also just print out and one and not even worry about end to
end here we can say all the odd numbers 1 3 5 7 9.
So if you see this sort of syntax it's just too blunt packing meaning this is a list of tuples and you're
unpacking them so you can deal with the actual elements inside those tuples individually.
Let's go ahead to discuss for loops of dictionaries to do that.
We'll create a simple dictionary will say de key of a value of one key of B value of two and then say
oops.
A key of C has a value of 3.
So there's our simple dictionary if we say for item in dictionary.
Andy excuse me print the item.
Notice what happens I only get back the keys and there's a really important thing to remember here is
that dictionaries do not retain any order so you can't expect this to print out the keys in any particular
order or dictionary is really small here.
So we see that it's actually printing them out in the same order that we find it in.
But in general this is not going to retain any sort of order as we discussed.
If you want order you're going to need a list or a tuple.
So we can see here it's printing out the keys.
If we wanted to specify in particular we only want the keys we could also say keys and this would be
the exact same result if we actually wanted the items we could say items.
And then I can get the tuples.
So as we just mentioned we have this sort of tuple and packing situation meaning it could do something
like key value and print out key and print out value and get A1 B to C 3.
So that's a really common example of tuple and packing in other common way you see people iterating
with four loops.
A dictionary is something like this.
They'll say for K in the Remember keys were the default iteration of a dictionary.
They can print out d of k.
Oops forgot to print
and then we will actually see the key values themselves.
Now going through a for loop in a dictionary always remember that you're not going to get any sort of
particular order.
Finally I want to mention the continued keyword.
So the continue keyword can be a bit tricky to see its usefulness but it allows you to continue with
the top level loop and it's essentially the opposite of the break keyword we saw when discussing wild
loops and it usually takes some time when you're beginning before you realize a good situation to use
it in.
But let's discuss a very simple example.
I will say four letter in code Prince letter.
So here I am printing out c o d e.
Let's say I wanted to not print out the letter D.
I could say if a letter is equal to the then just continue and that's the key word here.
Continue means just go along and don't do anything.
So it allows you to continue with the toplevel loop without actually executing.
So then when I run this notice it says if the letter is equal to d just continue and that's going to
basically skip back and come back here to the next letter which happens to be e and it continues on
printing that letter when you're beginning programming in Python.
You're really not going to use the continue keyword that often but just keep in mind it's there in case
you ever find yourself needing it in the future.
That's the basics of for loops.
Again you just say for.
You choose what of temporary variable name you want in and then whatever the object you're iterating
and you'll perform this block of code for every iteration.
I'll see you at the next lesson recruit.