Welcome back.
Let's now discuss list comprehensions list comprehensions are a unique way of quickly creating a list
with Python.
They basically allow you to build out lists using a different notation essentially allowing you to create
a one line for loop built inside of list brackets.
The syntax can be confusing at first for new recruits but break it down step by step will hopefully
make it all clear in order to do this.
Let's jump to a Jupiter note book and show you the syntax.
Let's begin with a simple example using a for loop.
We'll start off with an empty list called my list and let's imagine we have some sort of string s and
we'll assign this string some string.
Now imagine we wanted to somehow get every single character to be an individual element in this list.
Well we could do is we can use a for loop saying four letter in the string.
S Take my list and the pen that letter to the list.
And if I run this and check the result of my list.
Now I have backlist where every single element is now the characters that we were iterating through
in this for a loop.
Let's now show how we could do the same task using a list comprehension.
We'll begin by actually deleting this first line my list.
Since we don't actually need to define that yet and we're going to do here is we basically change this
append statement.
Instead all we do is we take this letter cut it and put it in front of here.
So we're saying letter for letter in S and then we get rid of the append and we get rid of this colon
and then we put this inside of brackets and that is the list comprehension format.
You say element four elements in iterable and inside of brackets and then we can have this be my new
list and that is list comprehension.
Essentially similar to a one line for loop and if we check up my list against my new list we get the
exact same results.
So let's walk through a couple more examples.
Let's imagine we wanted to get a list of a bunch of square numbers.
What I could do is say squares is equal to here I'm going to say X to the power of two for x in range.
We can say zero to 11 and then if I took a look take a look at what squares is.
It's these numbers Square.
So it's the numbers and range 0 to 11.
So the power of two.
So again the general syntax is element for elements in some sort of iterable either range or a list
or another string etc..
So let's show another example called evens.
And here we're going to create a list of even numbers will say x for x in range 0 to 10.
And if we run that and check evens we get back the actual numbers in order to get only the even numbers
we need to add some sort of if statement and the if statement we're going to say is if X percent sign
2 and that's mod 2 or modulus operator is equal to zero.
And then I only get back the even numbers.
So let's quickly explain what the smart operator can do.
In case you haven't seen it before what most operators do is they return the remainder after the division.
So you can imagine that four divided by three is one point three through three three but the remainder
of this is one because three goes to four once.
Remainder 1.
So if you say for mod 3 you'll get back the value 1 if you say five more three that you have remained
are two.
And if you say six three you have remainder zero because three goes into six evenly two times with no
remainder.
And this maade function allows you to check the numbers even by saying maade to check if it's equal
to zero because any number that's even when you check the maade against two it should have no remainder.
And that's so you can check for something.
Even.
So that's another example of a list comprehension.
And finally you can also do an if else statement in a list comprehension.
But keep in mind at a certain point you're really going to be sacrificing readability.
And that's also a big part of Python.
So if you're find yourself having trouble figure out how to put something in a list comprehension.
Just use a for loop instead.
It's almost always just as efficient as list comprehension.
You'll find yourself using lists comprehensions as you get more advanced in Python they'll feel forced
to constantly have to use them as you're just learning about Python.
So we'll show one last more complex example.
Will say my list x if x mod 2 is equal to zero else not even string for x in range 0 to 10.
And this sort of syntax is a bit strange at first to learn because you just learned that if you only
have a single if statement the if statement comes after this element for element in iterable statement.
However if you're using an if else statement that actually needs to come first before you say for iterable
in or four elements in iterable.
So that's what's a little bit weird about starting to learn how to do more complex tasks in list comprehension
format.
And just to really make it clear if you're having trouble figuring out how to do something in a list
comprehension just go ahead and use the for loop we use at the beginning because that will always work
and it's always going to be a lot more readable.
So for check out my list now I have evens and then string's not even where mod to the not equal zero.
All right that's it for list comprehensions.
You'll find these are used often for little quick jobs and other people's code.
So it's important that you learn how to read them but don't worry too much right now about having to
always write them.
Excellent work so far.
I'll see you at the next lesson.