In this lesson we'll be discussing lambda expressions map and filter map and filter are built in functions
in Python that allow you to efficiently apply functions to every element in the list.
Land expressions are useful in this context because they also allow you to create functionality without
the full formal syntax of a normal Python function.
Let's open up a Jupiter notebook and explore these functions in lambda expressions.
Let's begin by talking about the map function.
The map function allows you to map a function to an iterable object that is to say you can quickly call
the same function to every single item in an iterable such as a list.
For example let's create our own function called Square which simply takes in a number we'll call numb
and returns that same number to the power of two or squared.
Now if we had a list called my number or my numbers and it was numbers 1 2 3 4 5 and I wanted to apply
this function to every single item in this list and then create a new list out of it.
One option would be to create a for loop create a new list and then with a for loop go through every
single number in that list and then append the new result to a new list or the other alternative is
I could map my function so I could call map pasand my function and then pass my iterable or my list.
And if you do shift tab here on this function let's make sure we spell or function correctly.
If you do shift tab you'll see that it takes in a funk and some iterable.
And then it has creates a map object so it makes an iterator that computes the function using arguments
from each of the intervals.
So let's go ahead and explore this if we actually want to see the results.
Notice it has a map object here.
So I can say for item in map print the item.
So this is essentially generating every single square of this list.
So it's applying this function square to every single number in this list.
One two three four five results in 1 4 9 16 25.
If you just wanted the actual list result you could just pass in this map function into the list and
then you get the list backout itself.
So the functions can be as complex as you want as long as they just return a single item that you can
easily map to.
So for example let's create a more complex function function called splicer.
It takes in some string.
Call it my string and it's the length of the string happens to be odd.
So we check the length of the string Matu is equal to zero.
Then we return this.
Even the word even or the string even.
Else.
Let's go ahead and return the first character of the string.
So I'll say my string 0 is a more complex function but it works just the same.
We can have a list called my names or we have a B B will say C C C and then D D D D and we can say show
me the list.
When you map the splicer function to my names and you can see we get back a even C..
Even so it's just returning back even if the length of the string was even.
Or just the first letter of the string.
If it's odd numbered in length and notice what we're doing here this is something interesting we are
just passing in the function itself.
We are not calling the function so we're not actually calling the function or executing.
Instead we just pass in the function.
And the reason for that is because map itself is going to be doing the calling so we don't want to have
princes here.
Otherwise you'll get an error instead.
What you want to do is just pass the function itself.
So keep that in mind as you use the map function.
Let's now move on to discussing the filter function the filter function is similar to the map function
except instead of applying that function to every single element in the array and then returning the
result.
Instead you're only going to apply functions that return a boolean value.
True or false.
And then you're going to filter out the iterable list by the elements that return true when passed into
the function.
So let's explain this through an example.
We will say our function is check even and it takes in a number and then it's going to return that number
to equals zero.
So what that means is if I call my function on a number such as 10 it's going to return true because
it's an even number.
If I passed it on an odd number it's going to return false so all this function does is that returns
a boolean value.
True or false if the numbers even are not.
Now imagine I have a list of numbers such as numbers and will say this is 1 2 3 4 5 6.
So I only want the values where this returns true.
Well what I can do is I can use the filter function pass in my function that returns a boolean value
and then pass in my iterable object the numbers.
And then if I like to see the results I can pass this whole thing into the list function and there.
Now I only see that even numbers.
So the idea filter is that you pass in a function that returns boolean values true or false.
And then you in some iterable almost always a list and then you filter out the results and you only
get the values or the elements in this list that return true when passed into this function.
So that's how the filter function works.
And finally let's discuss the land the expression.
It's a very useful tool and sometimes for beginners it's a bit confusing because it's just presented
plainly at first instead of showing you how we derive the land expression what the land expression does.
It allows you to create what are called anonymous functions.
And this basically means that we can quickly make ad hoc functions without needing to properly defined
the function using the keyword.
So Lanzas body is essentially just a single expression instead of a block of statements to show you
how we derive de-link lambda expression.
Let's first start off by creating an example function.
So just like any other function we start off with that the key word the name of the function and the
parameters it takes in we say result is equal to numb to the power of two and then we return that result.
So here we have our square function and if we call Square we get back 16 so square of four is 16.
Now we can simplify this further because technically I don't need to save this result right here.
So I'm going to simplify this by getting rid of this assignment of result and then cutting this and
pasting it here.
And let's delete this line.
And now if I run this again let's run it now on three.
It still works three times three is nine.
And in fact we can actually simplify this further.
You could technically write this all on one line.
It's definitely not recommended given the syntax of Python or the convention of using whitespace but
this technically still works.
If I run this again passen another number such as two.
I still get the result of four.
So here I'm saying the square of this number returned the number squared.
This is the format of a lamb the expression.
So the land expression what it does is it gets rid of DPF because you don't need that special key word
anymore.
And it also gets rid of the name of the function because the intention is to only use it once.
And since you know it's a function that has to return something you also get rid of the return keyword
and then so that Python knows that this whole thing is a land expression at the very beginning of it.
You say lambda numb and then numb to the power of two.
So this is the form of a lammed expression.
So why would you need a land expression.
We'll take a look at these functions right here such as filter and map in map.
We were applying functions that were the find with DPF like square and splicer and unfilter we were
defining functions as well the earth and then applying them to iterable.
Imagine in a very long script you were only going to do this filter command or this map command once
if you're only going to do it once on an iterable it may not make sense to go through the entire effort
of finding a function with a name.
Instead you may just want to pasan a one time anonymous expression and that is the land expression.
And the reason it's called Anonymous is because we never really gave a name.
Always said it was land and then the expression and it essentially has a one time use case.
So I could do the following.
I can say map the land expression we just created.
Say lambda num colon.
Number two the power of two.
And we're going to map that land expression to symbolist and let's go ahead and pass in a list.
One two three and then we're going to transform this to a list so we can see the results in here we
can see 1 4 9.
And remember that we can call these variables whatever we want.
So this could have been X and X the power of two.
And if we run this we get back the exact same result.
So it's really up to you what to call this variable.
Just as it's up to you what to call these variables inside these function calls.
So if you just begin seeing land expressions like this right off the bat it may be confusing at first
but I think seeing it from the derivation of a function makes it a lot easier to understand.
Let's go through a couple of more examples of land expressions.
So let's review that land the expression format for trying to filter even numbers.
So we will say filter in the land the expression is taking in an n and then it's returning whether or
not and Mattu is equal to zero.
And then we apply that to some list so we'll say one two three four five and we'll pass this and transform
it into a list so that we can see the results and it only returns that even numbers 2 and 4.
So that's the land expression for the function we created up here called check even.
And we can see that we can basically create the land expression right here.
If we just get rid of this pass and lambda get rid of that print C's get rid of this return.
There is the land expression that we just created.
So if we take a look at this scroll down here that's the exact same thing except freezing and it's that
of them.
But again you can call this variable whatever you want.
Let's see how you create lambda expression for grabbing the first character in a string.
You would say lambda the string and then return the first element in that string.
So that would be a way of growing the first character in a string if you want to reverse a string you
could do a say lambda take in the string and using slicing notation that we discussed earlier you could
do something like that.
That reverses a string and you can even pass multiple arguments into a lambda expression.
Again you can keep in mind that not every single function can be translated into lambda expression nor
should you try to redefine every single function as a lamb expression.
If you ever find yourself having difficulty transforming something into a lambda expression just go
ahead and use the function format.
It's really almost always just as efficient to create the full function instead of trying to boggle
your mind getting the land expression to work.
But as an example of a land expression that takes in two variables you could say lambda x com a y.
So those are the two parameters it takes in.
And then you could say X plus Y and that would be an example of a land expression that takes in more
than one argument.
And that's more useful for other libraries that you may be working with outside of the built in libraries
for Python.
All right that's it for land expression's map and filter functions.
We'll see you at the next lesson.