Recruit is director Harper the institute is currently under attack by an unknown number of hackers.
Our logs indicate they've infected our system with a computer virus designed to block communications
to our main server in our work.
We have many enemies and all our other agents are currently busy defending attacks to our remaining
servers.
That leaves you.
I need you to restore communication between the local servers and our main server as soon as possible.
Even though you're still a recruit You've already shown your capable of helping us in our time of need.
I will have the instructor connect with you to brief you on what needs to be done.
We cannot let the institute fall victim to these enemies.
I must go now to help block these hacking attempts.
We'll be in touch recruit.