Welcome back recruit to finish off our discussion of object oriented programming we're going to discuss
private methods as well as special methods.
Let's begin by showing you how to add a private method here we can see our agent class from the last
couple of lessons and we have this method report method and true name method.
So if I run this in let's define and agents will say A is equal to an agent and we're going to need
a first name so we'll just use what we did last time.
Alan last name Turing and the code name will be hero and if we hit a dot and then hit tab you'll see
a dropdown list of the methods that are available as well as the attributes.
So we can say report as a method or we can call an attribute such as their first name and we can see
Alan.
Now what if you actually wanted to hide a method maybe you have a method in your class that's really
more for designing the upkeep of the class maybe have some methods that you want to call within other
methods and you don't really want them available to users for fear that they may use them incorrectly.
Well you can do is create a private method and private methods look the same as a normal method except
you start them off with a single underscore and then you call the method or whatever you want.
You can say private method or just private.
It's up to you but the key here is that they start with a single underscore and then what you can do
is say self and then really whatever you want here we'll just have self and we'll have this method just
say Prince private method.
So the purpose of this private method is really just to work with other methods inside of your object.
You noticed here in true name we had to call self-taught report.
Maybe you're looking for additional functionality that you don't want to have available as a normal
method.
Instead maybe you just want to have a as a private method.
That way you can use it within the object.
But whoever is the user using this new agent class when they create one it won't be available to them.
So that's really the idea of the private method by default.
Python is very open by its nature and other concepts from other languages such as Java Users will be
familiar with kind of public versus private ideas.
It's actually really hard to obscure your code in Python so if you have a script in Python it becomes
very difficult to try to hide your code from someone else who is going to use it.
So keep that in mind.
This idea of private method is really just to kind of guide the user into indicating that they shouldn't
be messing around with this private method.
The idea behind the private method is not to hide anything from the user itself.
So we're going to run this cell again.
Has the private method we're going to recreate our agents and then notice we all say report first name
and then if I say a dot and then hit tab I won't see the private method.
So basically this method is not immediately visible to the user and that helps the user realize that
they shouldn't be playing around that method that it's not really meant for them to interact with.
However if you do want to call a private method all you do is sort of an underscore and then you'll
end up seeing a bunch of other methods and attributes.
And these are a mix of private as well as just special methods.
And we're going to play around with some of these later on.
But notice here at the very bottom we can see our private method.
So again private doesn't mean that you're hiding this from the user.
That really means that you're just guiding the user into realizing that they probably shouldn't be using
this private method unless they really are familiar if the object itself.
Now we saw a list of a bunch of special methods.
Let's go ahead and discuss those special methods allow you to interact with pythons built in functionality.
For example imagine I wanted to print the instance of my agent.
So I said print a.
Well what happens is by default I just get back main agent object at this location in memory.
What if I wanted to check the length of my agent.
Does that even make sense.
Should an agent have a length.
Well in this case you'll notice that it says object of type agent has no length but maybe you're working
with some sort of other object that you've created where you would like a result for length.
In that case you'll need to use special methods special methods allow you to interact with builtin Python
functionality such as the built in print function or the built in length function.
Let's go ahead and explore these ideas by creating a new class.
We're going to create a class called book and we will say the F and our special method in it and this
is special because basically initialises all the parameters will take in a title and author and the
pages of a book.
And then we'll do the following we'll say self.
Title is equal to title self the author is equal to author and self-taught pages is equal to pages.
And then we will add in a special method underscore underscore as TR underscore underscore self and
what this special method does is it provides a string representation of the book.
And when you actually call Prince on an object what it does is it looks at the class of the object and
then it looks for this method.
It looks for the string representation that it can print out.
So in this case what we're going to do is we're going to return String wrap.
Just we can get an idea of how this would work.
So create a book with the variable b.
Whoops forgot to add in the title.
So we'll say the title is on Iraq's The author will be James Bond and the number of pages will be 200
pages.
There we go.
So now we've created our book object.
Let's go ahead and print out our book object and see what happens.
We get back string rep which means when the function is called on B the print function looks at your
class book and says OK is there a string representation of this object.
And in that case it looks for this special method underscore underscore as TR underscore underscore
and whatever it returns is what it prints out.
In this case for our class book doesn't make a whole lot of sense to return string representation.
Instead what probably makes more sense when you print out a book is to have a little bit of a mixture
maybe say title is and author is and then we can use that format to pasan self-taught title and self-taught
author I know how I'm using the self here.
This allows the class and the function and the method to understand that when we say self-taught title
we're referring to the book's own title not some global variable called Title which is why it's so important
to understand the use of self when you're working within methods inside of a class.
So let's run this again.
So we read the fine book.
Let's run our book again.
And now when I say Prince B It says title is python rocks.
An author is James Bond.
And the more typical representation of how you would be using your own creation of string representation.
Because if you didn't have this instead you'd be getting something that looks like this agent object.
At some point in your memory now we can do the same thing for length right now if we said what's the
length of the book.
We'd get back object the type book has no link.
And lucky for us there is a attribute that really correlates well to length which is the number of pages.
So we should just have the number of pages be return to do that.
We're going to use the special method that's connected to what the length function does.
And that's just underscore underscore.
L e n underscore underscore pasand self.
And then we're going to return self thought pages so that when you ask how long is the book it just
returns back how many pages it has.
So we say be print's be and if we check the length of the book it returns back 200.
So that's an example of two special methods that you'll be using when you creating your own classes.
Now keep in mind that there's a lot more special methods and just the two if shown here or three if
you count the method.
But right now as you begin to just approach object oriented programming the only ones that you really
need to worry about are the string representation and the length representation.
Those are going to be the ones the most commonly used especially the string representation.
So you can print out your own objects and other ones just to show you various examples is the DTL or
deletes a special method.
And this is what gets returned or what executes when you delete the actual object.
So in this case we can just type in anything and prints a book has been deleted.
So we're going to run this again.
We're going to create a new book b equals book Python rocks James Bond and then we're going to print
the book.
Check the length of the book and if we call the special the L which is a delete statement in order to
delete a variable out of memory we can type and delete book and it says whoops.
Scuse me b.
That's what we find as a variable and then it says A book has been deleted.
And then if we check b it says B is no longer fine.
So by default delete B is going to remove whatever that variable is connected to.
In your memory space however we can add onto it by actually affecting the daily method here.
Or the special method which basically says what would you like to occur in addition to the leading variable.
When you call deletes or DL on the variable itself.
And as we've previously mentioned you're not going to be using private methods or special methods that
often when you're beginning to use object oriented programming.
We'll see you at the next lesson.
Recruit.