Welcome back.
Let's now go ahead and go over some examples solutions for your object oriented programming review exercise
questions.
Let's begin by creating this sphere class.
We'll start off with our method.
TGF underscore underscore in it.
And then we always need to pass in self and we'll go ahead and except in a radius which means we need
to assign a radius attribute.
So we will say self that radius physical to radius then we will create a volume method and that will
also need self.
And the formula for the volume of a sphere can be easily found through Google search but it's just for
third's times Paice we can say 3.1 four times and then we'll say self-taught radius to the power of
three or cubed.
So it's just 430 times pi times are cubed.
Then we can define the surface area method.
So we will say surface area we need a pass and self.
And similarly we can return four times Pi or three point one four times self-taught radius to the power
of two and it's up to you whether you want to create pi as a class object attribute.
Here we just set in a constant 3.1 for there but that's all you had to do for the sphere class.
Let's run this and check that it all works out.
So sphere a radius of three surface area and volume.
All check out.
So that should have been pretty straightforward especially that we did a circle class in our previous
lessons.
Now for exercise 2 This was definitely a little more complicated so let's see what we could do here.
We're going to start off with an init method and as described in the instructions you don't need any
parameters here so we'll just say self and then we will create an attribute called self Rande that choice
and sulphur and choice what it's going to have is it's going to use that random library that we imported
and then it will use the rand int function that we discussed earlier in your training and it's going
to pick a random number from 0 to 10 and that will set the rand choice attribute is a good lesson to
keep in mind you can still set attributes even though you don't want your user to find them.
Then we're going to create a method called Reset.
Random takes and self and it's going to can make a print statement saying reset seeing random number.
And then we just need to reset it so we can say sauf rant choice is equal to and it's the same come
in because it's a random number random integer between 0 and 10.
So that will go ahead and grab the current value of the ranch choice attribute and reset it to a random
integer.
Then finally we are going to create the guess method is basically part of the game.
So we need to do here is first grab a user guess.
So we create a variable called ease or guess and we'll set that as the input and we'll just ask for
please input a random number.
Sure there's a space there.
And remember this is going to return a string.
So we can just go ahead and cast it as an integer right now by wrapping that in The I.A. function.
Then we will say if the user gets is equal to our current Rande choice so self-taught Rande choice then
we will print correct else we will print wrong guess.
So that's the simplest way you can create this guessing game just taking an input and then do a comparison
here and we're going to run this and see what happens when you create a guessing game.
So create a new guessing game and let's go ahead and see what our random choices.
So random choice is zero.
If we reset the random choice and see what around choices again looks like it's 10.
So looks like that is working.
If we ran this recent random again then we get four etc. so should be constantly changing and since
it's random You may get the same random number twice in a row.
Keep that in mind.
Now let's play the guessing game so we will say gee I guess run this in a random number.
We know it's four so let's put in something wrong first three.
And it says run yes.
And if you were to run this again and input for the correct value then it says correct.
Perfect.
So now let's add in some logic that will help the user for their next guess to say if it's higher or
lower.
So instead of else here.
Well instead of just printing wrong guess we'll have another set of control flow.
We will say if the user gets is less then the rand choice will Prince Brong guess higher
else will say Prince wrong guess lower and we can rerun this and now it was restart another guessing
game.
So we can check the rand choice before we actually start the game.
Looks like a ranch choice is zero.
So now let's initiate our game by guessing and it's going to ask us to put around the number.
We'll go with five which is purposely too high and it's going to go slower.
Perfect.
So now if we say guess we guessed all right answer which is zero.
It says correct.
That's all you had to do for that guessing again.
The key thing to note here is the use of self when referencing the attributes that belong to this class
and the other thing to notice here is that you can still create attributes even if your user doesn't
define them.
All right.
Hopefully well on that and we'll see at the next lesson.