Welcome back.
Let's quickly discuss how to debug with Python and also how to use the built in date time library Python
comes with a powerful debugger that can help you find mistakes in your code.
We can see a trace that allows us to essentially stop our code at any point hold it on pause and then
decide and explore variables and operations.
We're also going to discuss Python's they time capabilities.
Let's load up a notebook and see how these libraries work.
Let's imagine that we have three variables X as a string one Y as an integer 2 and then Z as the integer
3 and maybe later on you have hundreds of lines of code.
And somewhere along those lines you say result is equal to Y plus Z.
And then you print out the results and then couple hundred lines down.
You say OK result is equal to Y plus X and then you get this type error and maybe you get another error
that you really can't hurt it.
This one's a little easier to interpret it says integer plus string.
So you know one of these is an integer and one of these is string that maybe you're also having trouble
telling which is which.
So if you have hundreds of lines of code it's going to be really hard to try to find where your error
is occurring.
And in order to solve this issue we can initiate a trace using the debugger module.
So this the first thing we need to do is import Python debugger or PDB.
And then let's set up the situation again.
So we'll have ex-secret to this one string Weikel a to z is equal to three.
And then let's just say there's lots more code here.
So hundreds of lines and then we'll say result is equal to Y plus Z.
And then we print out the results and then somewhere along the line we have a lot more code.
So more and more code and then we're going to see a trace here.
We say PDB and then we call the set trace method.
Open and close parentheses and then you have lots more code and then will say your result is equal to
Y plus X and then we're going to print that new result.
Let's make sure it's underscore.
There we go.
Let's take a look at what we have set up here.
I have my three variables defined.
We can imagine there's lots more code.
I have some sort of operation and then I have lots more code and we're going to comment out the set
trace for right now.
Then we have lots more code and then we try new result and print the new result.
If I run the cell I get some sort of type error and it tells me hey your type errors happening at this
line.
Line 17.
We're used to having a new result is equal to Y plus X and I'm getting this type error but maybe I have
so much code here that I'm really unsure what Y is and what x is.
And when you're starting off programming what you sometimes do is in order to debug you just printout
maybe type of x over here and then you print out type of Y.
And this is a way for debugging for beginners since they need to print out a bunch of statements and
see what is actually what.
So then when they run this code they see oh it was a string integer.
They look back and they say oh x was that string.
So that's the problem.
However it's much easier to use a trace.
So we're going to uncomment this line and have Python debugger said trace.
And what this does is it runs all the code above that trace command and then allows you to pause and
have an interaction with a python shell.
So we're going to run this.
And here we can see the python debugger and now I can type variables out as if they were or defined
in a shell.
So I can type in X and it gives me back X and I can see here it's a string or it can type Y and it gives
me back to here or I can say what is the type of x enter and it tells me class String.
And this is a much easier way to play around if your variables and check what's happening.
You can even do operations here.
You can do something like Z plus y enter and it will tell you the result is 5.
So you can both check variables do operations all as if you had a python shell open right in the Meleager
code.
This allows you to interact with the variables that you've already defined instead of having to add
in a bunch of print statements and it saves you a lot of time because now you don't need to search your
code and kind of discover where the problems are instead you can't interactively set a trace and then
work with your code there.
And when you want to finally end this you can just type and quit and it will quit the python debugger.
So that's how this works.
You can see we have the kind of quick command but it allows you to set a trace and then play around
with all the variables as if you had a shell open there.
Now there's a lot more functionality for the python debugger but definitely the one you're going to
be using the most is this set trace functionality.
So keep it in mind next time you find yourself having a bug that's hard to find.
Let's now discuss date time objects.
And this basically just shows you how to work with basic dates and times in Python in order to create
a date or time you need to import that time library and then you can say something like is equal to
date time time and then you pasand the hour.
And this is a 24 hour clock.
The minutes 15 minutes and then we can pass in seconds and if you want you can even pass an micro-seconds
but we won't do that for now.
So we can show you what happens if you don't pass them and you have this date time object so if you
say type C it's the state time the time object.
Meaning that it's indicating a time and we can grab the hour off of that time or the minutes or the
seconds and you can even grab microseconds off of this if you don't define the micro-seconds when you
created the state time object.
They'll just default to zero and it's the same for not defining seconds.
So if we were to tick off the second and then rerun this it would end up saying seconds is equal to
zero.
And micro-seconds is equal to zero.
If you want to get the current date then you can use a data object.
So that's going to be similarly date time except instead of saying time you'll say that date.
And then if you want you can define a date using year month day.
So you can do something like 20 18 months is 10 days 11 and then you have this date object.
Or if you want today's date you can say date time dates and then say today run that and that will grab
the dates off of your computer's operating system.
So I'll say 2018 January 18th.
And if you want the date time that is both the date and the time we can say date time date time and
then say now and that grabs both the dates and the time information.
So here we can see the date information and then here is the time information hour minute second and
then micro-seconds.
So there's both time objects which is just the time there's a date object which is the month the year
and the day itself and the date time are checks which is both the day and the actual time.
So let's quickly show you an example of how you could time your code.
Because most often you're going to be interested in using this library if you're trying to figure out
what's the most efficient way to do something.
And the way to do that let's say you had a list comprehensions saying results x squared for X and range
and let's make this a larger number we'll say 10000.
So I want to know how long did it take to actually create that result.
What I can do is create an initial time stamp is equal to zero and say date time that's date time now
and then right after we run results I'm going to say one is equal to date time that date time now and
then when I can do is say that the difference is equal to date time at point 1 minus the time initial
at t 0.
And if I check out my different my different subject if I can check out the micro-seconds and it took
a total of four thousand fourteen microseconds for this result to run.
And if you check out seconds it's going to be zero.
Because it's not a long enough time for it to actually measure it out in seconds.
So it only took in this case 4000 14 microseconds.
Now this number may be different depending on your computer.
And if you make this number too small for example if you just make it 10.
This is going to run so fast that it's likely your computer won't be able to actually catch how fast
that it.
So we're going to run this and see if we can catch the difference and looks like it was 5 0 2 microseconds
So keep in mind depending on how fast your computer is if this number is too small it may just say zero
here.
In my case my computer was able to catch it because it took some time but that's something to know if
you're having really fast operations.
It won't really make a difference timing them.
Instead you can run them multiple times and stiff objects.
If we check it out it's a time delta object which is essentially just the difference between due to
date time objects.
And that's really it for that date type module so as a review off of date time you have time objects
you can create which indicate hours minutes.
Second some micro-seconds you have data objects you can create which has years the month and the day.
And then you have date time objects and a lot of people tend to work with date time objects because
if they don't want the time information they can just default it to zero.
So we have the Year of the month the day and then hours minutes seconds microseconds.
And this allows you to quickly time your code so you can test which block of code is more efficient.
We'll see you at the next lesson recruit.