Welcome back.
Let's now discuss modules and packages a module is a file that can be imported under one single import
command such as import space and then the name of the module.
In this example we call that my module.
So that's a single my module py file that's somewhere next to your script.
A package is a collection of modules in directories that give a package hierarchy.
So that would look something like.
From my package.
Some other file import some function from that file.
To install publicly available modules or libraries you can use the pip install system at your command
line.
You can type Pipp install and then the name of the library you're trying to install and this will install
the library requested as long as you have an internet connection and don't have a firewall blocking
the connection.
This is operated using the pie pie system or a p y p.
So that Pipp install is basically going to connect to the Internet and download the package to your
computer.
We've already imported some built in modules and packages such as the random library.
Let's now explore how we can format files to create our own modules to do this.
We're going to switch over to using a text editor to create a postscript instead of using a notebook.
Let's get started.
All right here I've opened up the Sublime Text Editor and I've opened up to Untitled files.
Let me save these files.
The first one I'm going to save my module PI and make sure you have this all files extension selected.
Otherwise you may accidentally save it as my module up high that text and then click save.
So now this is a PI script meaning I should expect to see some syntax highlighting if I begin to say
print.
Hello.
So that looks like it's working.
And the next one I'm going to save as my program the PI.
So let's do that as well.
We will say Save As and we will say my program that pi and then enter to save that.
So we're going to do is we're going to create a module which essentially just another dot PI script
in the same directory as this my program that pi.
And we're going to create a function in it and show you the different ways you could import it in your
program.
So first select my module that pi and let's create a function in it.
Will say f and we'll say phunk in my module and it's just going to be a very simple function is going
to do a print.
I am a function inside of my module.
PI make sure you save that now it's explore importing my module in this other file my program that pi
and you can do this is we can say import my module and then we'll say my module dot and we should be
able to call that function itself.
I'll say my module that phunk And let's recall what it was describing as funk in my modules.
So let's read that as well.
Phunk in mind module open close parentheses.
I'm going to now save this and let's run the script at the command line and see what the result is.
I will now CD or change directory to ice where I save these files which was under my documents folder
and then CD into a python scripts folder.
And this is where I saved this file so now let's say Python and say My program that PI hit enter.
And now I see I am a function inside my module that pi.
So I know how from inside my program that pi I was able to successfully import my module and then run
that function.
So that's one way you can actually import a module.
Now notice here we're importing the module and then calling specific functions off of it.
If my module is a really long name what you can do is say import my module as and then have some sort
of alias for it such as M M and you'll see this commonly used with other modules.
They usually have some sort of convention as a shortened form that we don't need to write my module
all the time and said we can just write m m dot and then the name of the function you want to call off
of it.
And if you say this and run it will bring back the exact same result.
Again this is using an alias for this name.
So it's a import.
The name of the module as.
And then the name you want imported US.
Now let's imagine that you only actually want to use one function from this my module.
So if this my module that PI script had hundreds of functions in it and we only really needed to use
one of them instead of importing the entire library as something what we can do is the following syntax.
We can say from my module import and then the specific name of the function you want to import that
can say func in my module.
And if you have multiple imports you can just separate them out by commas.
So this could be another func and then you know function number three etc. but since we only have one
function we'll just say from module import funkin module.
And when you want to use it somewhere in your script all you do is call your function module as such.
So this allows you to not even worry about having to write my module or M as an alias because you only
imported the functions that you intend to use and you can see here it's telling you it's coming from
my module.
Py.
That's it for the basics of modules of Python.
As you get more interested in coding and your scripts get larger and larger you're going to be able
to separate your code into multiple Paice scripts and that will help you compartmentalize the actual
sections of code for different functionality as well as just keep clean organized sections that are
easier to read.
Instead of having one giant thousands of line files you can have several files that have those lines
separated out excellent work so far.
We'll see you at the next lesson.