I knew you had it in you.
And yet even now you've surpassed my expectations on behalf of the institute I would like to personally
welcome you as a bona fide field agent.
Our field agents take on our most important missions using their elite skills to solve problems that
otherwise would seem impossible.
The rogue agents that attacked us earlier they are our most feared adversaries.
Internally we've decided to refer to them under the code name the rogues aside from their hacking attempts
my relationship with them is also personal.
You see when the rogues first affected they not only inflicted a series of digital attacks to cover
their tracks and keep us from finding them.
They also crossed a line in the real world by kidnapping my only daughter finding them and bringing
them to justice is of utmost importance.
It must be done.
Unfortunately they can detect the digital signatures of agents who were once their colleagues.
That's where you come in.
Seeing as how you were only recently promoted to agent they won't be able to detect you.
That is why I have decided to assign you a series of missions codename the rainbow missions.
Each of the seven rogues corresponds to one of the seven colors of the rainbow with your skills and
talent.
I am confident you'll be able to track them down and locate my daughter.
Agent Allen will connect with you to brief you on the details of your first mission.
Do not let me down agent you are my only hope.