Welcome back agents in order to complete your first mission you're going to need to understand how to
perform web scraping with Python.
To which group of python we need to understand the basic concept of how a general basic web site works.
When a browser loads the Web site the user gets to see what is known as the front end of the Web site.
When we discuss the front end of the web what we're really talking about is the part of the web that
you can see and interact with.
And the main components of the front end of a web page are the HCM l the CSSA and the javascript.
When discussing the back end and those are things like interactions of a database how the application
actually stores its data.
For our purposes we're generally going to be web scraping from the front end of a Web site to get the
back and informational Web site you will need to use what's known as an API or application programming
interface to perform web scraping.
However we're really just dealing with the front end components.
Again the H team L C Ss and Javascript mail is used to create the basic structure and content of what
page CSSA is used for the design and style of a web page basically telling where HDMI elements are placed
and what they look like.
Javascript is used to define the interactive elements of a web page for effective basic web scraping.
We actually only really need to understand the basics of team L and C Ss.
Python can view T.M. and C Ss elements programmatically and then extract information from the Web site.
Let's explore HTL and see SS in a little more detail.
Since that's what we're really going to be working with with Python and web scraping.
HVM else stands for hypertext markup language and is present on pretty much every Web site on the Internet.
You can right click on any website and select View page source to view an example of what the HTML actually
looks like.
Let's see a small example of each team of code here I can see.
I've loaded up Google dot com and I've searched for Python I can right click on this and select View
page source and this will load up the actual Tim L and we can see here.
For such a complex web site this HTL file is huge and has a lot of information.
Python is going to be able to read this information and find certain key components you're looking for
based on elements and style tags which is what we're going to be learning about.
Let's start by looking at a much smaller and simpler example of HCM L instead of such a large one such
as the one present on Google.
Here's our smaller h tim l file and it has several main components that are present in basically all
major Web sites is each team all files and we start off with this doc type H.T. male and female documents
will always start with this type declaration and it just lets the browser know that the file itself
is an HTML file.
Then we have the component blocks of the H.T. mail file and those are going to be placed between the
opening tag for each team.
And the closing type for each T.M. and you can see that the closing tag has that forward slash to differentiate
it from the opening tag.
Then we have meta data and script connections and those will be placed in the head block of the HVM
file.
And this is where you can provide things like the title of the web page links to CSSA files or links
to javascript files.
In this particular head tag we can see that we have a title block and the title tag block defines the
title of the web page and the title of the page is what's actually showing up when you visit a Web site.
You can look at your tab in your browser and all have some text there.
That's the actual title.
Than in between the opening and closing body tags are the blocks that will be visible to the site visitor
and headings are defined with an H tag.
So we have H-1 through age 6 where the number represents the size of the headings so you have these
heading tags.
Here we can see Web site hetter is an H1 tag.
Essentially it's kind of larger more bold text.
And then we have paragraph tags and paragraph tags were defined by that p tag and essentially just a
normal text on the Web site.
Now there's a lot more tags than just these there's the a tag for hyperlinks.
The table tab for tables are for table rows tiddy for table columns and much more.
All you really need to understand is that there are tags associated with the actual content on a web
page.
So if we wanted to extract text some paragraph we would need to figure out what tag it was associated
with it.
In this case the p or paragraph tag now is discuss S. S. S. S. S. S. stands for cascading style sheets
and it truly what gives style to a Web site and CSSA uses tags to define what each T.M. elements will
be styled so few example see it says.
Tags are an ID tag.
And this is a tag that stands for a single element in the T.M. and it should be unique in the HTML document.
Then you also have class tags.
And those are tags used to define a general style to be linked to multiple HTML tags so let's actually
get an idea of what this looks like.
If we take a look back at a very basic Tim L. script where each team l file you can see that now in
the head block we've added this stylesheets link.
So with this link tag does it basically saying that the relationship is a style sheets or ECAC sheet
and Tref says Where'd actually find the sheet.
In this case this file happens to be called styles Dotsie SS and then we can see that we actually have
an ID tag.
Now on that Petrof in the H.T. L So the H team L was the paragraph saying some text and we've added
some information here and read where we say ID is equal to Para 2 or whatever you want to call that
ID that tells the T.M. that this particular text should be styled in whatever format the ID P-A are
a to happens to be styled in.
So that styles that CSSA file would look something like this.
It would say hash tag parit to basically indicating that it's a unique ID and then it would have a list
of different stylings to apply to that text some text here.
So we can make it the color red or we can make it a different font family or different size 6 cetera.
So there's lots of options there.
All things having to do with the design and style whether you want to align to the left or to the right.
So again we have for each team all file we link it to some other file that's a stylesheet and then the
style sheet has rules of what the actual design should look like what color should be what font family
etc. and we can link them through this link tag.
And then on the actual elements we want to style we can provide them with an ID so the ID you should
only be using it once in each team M-file that you can imagine that you had multiple things you wanted
to style with the same styling.
In that case you're going to use a class.
So here we can see that we have a class tag inside of this h team l elements some text and some other
text.
So previously the IED was used for just a single unique element in the female that you want to style.
Maybe you wanted to change the certain font or a certain color of just one element in the team file
but if you're going to be using things repeatedly what you can do is select a class.
So we've made a class called cool and it's going to perform some styling wherever the class happens
to be inserted into the sexual HTML file.
So then if you look to the style DSS file for class it starts with a period.
So it's a period cool and then you would see some color red or some font family and some other styling
choices whatever you wanted.
The main idea being that class is used more than once and that ID tags are used only once uniquely.
So in a realistic situation a Web site's going to have many many tags in it and it CSSA file.
Here we were just seeing examples with a single class or a single ID and it's going to include classes
IDs and general tags for main HTL elements.
Maybe it's just going to style all paragraph tags are all table tags in the HVM L.
So what does that actually look like.
Well if you can have a CSSA file that looks something like this.
So that top block of code P basically indicates that all paragraph tags in the h him l file are going
to be read they're going to have a font family and they're going to be a font size of 160 percent larger
than the other text.
Then you may have some class so it's going to be period some class name.
The other side on that is going to be some color associated with it.
Font family font size.
And there's many many types of styles you can add in your C Ss sheets.
And then for IDS it's going to be hash tags some ID name.
And then again a bunch of stylings.
So what do you actually need to know someone using Python to web scrape.
Well you don't need to know all the details of everything we discussed here because you only really
need to know those when you're actually building a website where you're trying to scrape information
of what awful web site you just need to understand how things look to Python when it's reading the HVM
I'll file and when the html file it's going to look at things such as a class or tags or maybe even
an ID and you're going to be able to use that in your python script in order to grab information off
the front end of a Web site in order to build a quick understanding of how each team elsea SS are connected.
We're going to be using this Web site code Penda.
I know that allows you to quickly write up H team L C Ss and Javascript and see a quick little rendering
of what they would look like if you were to save these files and run them in your browser.
So we're going to copy and paste the html file we were first working with.
So it's a very basic H.T. mail file and we can see here we end up getting a web site header and some
paragraph down here when we render it web site or in some paragraph if we wanted to add in more elements
to the HD.
There could just be more element tags.
So another simple one would be another paragraph.
So some more text and we would close off that tag and then we see some more text get rendered down here.
Now let's imagine we wanted to style this.
In that case we would need a CSSA sheet.
And the way code pen works it automatically links the CSSA to this H.T. mail.
But typically you would see up here in the head block some sort of link tag telling the HTL the actual
directory of where to find the CSSA file.
In this case we don't need that because.
Because the way cotinine works they're linked together.
Let's imagine that we want to color Web site hetter read the way it'll work and see assess as you find
whatever tag it's called.
In this case it's H-1.
And then you have open and closed curly braces then you can add in all the different styles you want
to change.
So there's a whole list of these and you can Google search to figure out what different stylings there
are available but let's say we wanted to change this to the color red it would look like this for the
syntax and then we'd see here that the Web site header is red.
Now keep in mind because I'm just using the straight h team l tag and C Ss anything that has the same
block h one or the same tag H-1 it's going to be colored red to show you what I mean by that.
Let's change H-1 to B.
P And I can see every single paragraph block has been changed to look red.
We may not actually want that.
Maybe we only want one specific block to be read.
In that case I can create an ID for this specific block.
We can say ID is equal to my block and then over here in the C Ss we indicate ID through the use of
this hash tag and then it has to have the same name my block.
And then we'll make it really clear by making the color blue.
And we can see here now some paragraph is blue and the other paragraph has not been affected.
Let's imagine that we want to make multiple things blue.
And we wanted to do it across multiple team tag types so multiple h ones multiple P's etc. so all we
can do is create a class set of ID.
We're going to have the same class and then let's just make the class name kind of short.
So we'll say P Why is the class.
And then we're going to copy this and put it both under H1 P as well as this and we can see we're going
to now in the C Ss say Dot to indicate class and then put in the class name.
And now since is the color blue.
If we look back down here we have everything the Web site hetter some paragraph and some more text all
the color blue.
Again the main idea being that you can link in IDS classes or even just use the tag to style HVM T.M.
elements based off your CSSA script.
Now to web scrape with python we can use the beautiful soup and request libraries.
These are external libraries outside of Python.
And that means you need to install them with either Konda install or Pipp install at your command line
so directly at your command line.
Go ahead and type in Pipp install requests and then hit Enter let it install Pippin's Thall l x m l
l x m l.
That's another library that we're going to be using.
And then you can Pippin's thought B-S for that since for beautiful soup.
For now I ask you using an anaconda distribution where you can do is use Konda install instead of Pipp
install.
So again open up your command line and make sure you've installed these libraries in order to actually
perform web scraping.
Up next we're going to work through some realistic examples of web scrapin of Python so we can actually
apply the theory that we learned here to practice.
We'll see you there.