Welcome back agent.
Let's go ahead and explore just a few more examples of web scraping and this particular example we're
going to scrape an image off a web site so we will be using the wikipedia article for cicada 3 3 0 1.
Notice here there's a little logo for it.
So that is what we're going to extract from this web page and we're going to save this logo as a dot.
JPG file on your computer.
So we will inspect this image and see what we can gather here.
I can see there is an image tag but we don't want to use the image tag because there may be other images
on this page and it only really want one image.
Notice how this Wikipedia globe is also an image.
And if you scroll down you may begin to see other images sometimes.
Sometimes there isn't.
And you can see here there's a little image here for the Internet portal and we don't really want that.
So what we would use instead is the class will use the class thumb image and see if that works for us.
It may work it may not work but since there's no ID here we will go with it instead of using the image.
Or I am e-tag.
So grabbing some image we will come back here and start off of the very first step which is to make
a request to the actual web site page will type out Arrius requests get and we will copy and paste the
Wikipedia article you are l.
And then once we have that we're going to create a soup little say soup is equal to be.
As for beautiful soup pasand the text of that request and then type out L S M L.
So we've created our soup.
Now it's time to actually select something from the soup as we just discussed.
We decided that we'll use the class from Image and because it's a class we will say Dot some image and
it looks like this is what we want it says cicada three theories zil one underscore logo that J peg
and if you notice at the S R C or source of the image we have some sort of u r l here that leads to
wherever Wikimedia or pedia is hosting the actual Adjaye pedophile.
And eventually that's what we want to grab and we'll make a separate request for that particular JPEG
file and then save its raw content.
In order to do that we will create a new variable called Image info and will confirm the image info
is just a list of tags and it is here and it's actually if we take a look at this again it's just one
item in that image or in that list I should say.
So let's save that first item as cicada.
And if we have that time here we can see the actual image tag.
And because this is the tag we can make dictionary like calls for parts of the tag.
Notice how the tag has a class.
It has some sort of heights with and then information about its source or S R C.
And more information about another part of it's with in order to actually grab essentially subsections
of this tax information you can make a dictionary like call.
So I would be able to type in class here and it will return back the class some image or anything the
class equals inside of this tag object.
But in reality we take a look at this again.
What I really want is S R C or the source.
So every image tag and HTL is going to have S or C or or source and that's essentially telling you where
the actual image is being hosted on the Web site.
So we will type that out as RC.
And now we have the Pegge location for this image and know how it starts with two forward slashes.
If we actually want to make the request we need to add on h t t s colon to this or HTP
meaning I will say the image link is equal to HTP colon.
And then I will concatenate what this is right here.
So I'll copy and paste that here and then if I take a look at my image link I have this nice you are
able to grab the image from.
Meaning we're going to make another request cicada image is equal to requests gets and then passen the
image link.
And remember that person X L and now we have the cicada image.
So since we actually have an image
we take a look at it.
Ill say response.
Two hundred.
That actually means it's basically a code saying that the response went through everything was successful
and other code could be 404.
Meaning you are not found but in our case it was 200 it was successful which makes sense because we
essentially we're already told that that Yoro existed in Phonogram the actual content of the image.
Then I called the content attribute and you will end up seeing something that looks like this.
And this is binary code.
Meaning if I want to read or write to this I can use Python's ability of opening and writing to files.
However instead of just a mode of W or are only to add in WB or RB which means the next step is to actually
create a jpg file.
Write the content to it close it and see if it worked.
Meaning we will say F is equal to open.
And here we're going to create new file names so I'll type out Takeda image new J pag and I will open
this file with right and binary permissions.
Right now this file does not exist on our computer so it's going to create that file for me.
It's an empty file right now.
So I will write out the actual content of the image cicada image contents or write to it.
You will get some sort of number in the kingdom that the write was successful.
And then we will close this.
And now I will be able to actually search my computer and find this JPEG file and it will be the picture
of that cicada in the logo.
So let's open it up by actually using markdown.
We can do this all the chip in a notebook click on a cell go to cell appear and then say cell type mark
down and mark down cells can actually accept h t m l.
So we will provide some very simple aged him code here will say image S or C source and instead of saying
this HTP link or some other online hosted link I will actually grab the jpeg that we just created.
We will copy this string and then paste it here.
And then close off the image tag.
And if I run this I should be able to see that cicada image which means that it was able to successfully
write and down download and then write to a file.
The JPEG image that was on that Wikipedia page.
So let's quickly go through those steps since it's a little more complicated than a regular scraping
job.
The first thing we had to do is make the request to the actual Yoro and then create a soup out of that
request text object.
Then we had to inspect the page to figure out what we were actually going to select in real situations.
This may take some experimentation.
In our case we went ahead and chose the class classes and ideas are always good first starting points.
Then after we got back the list of information tags we went ahead and grabbed the object from that list
and then we can make dictionary like calls for the source link s r c for the image itself.
We created an image linked by adding HTP to this to get a full link made a fresh request realized that
we could get the contents from that request essentially the image itself opened up a new file wrote
the contents of the file close it and then you'll find this file saved on your computer in the same
directory wherever this notebook is.
And recall if you ever want to figure out where it notebooks is saved you just type PWT run this and
it will tell you where you're actually saved.