Welcome back agent.
Let's take some time to discuss regular expressions as a field agent.
You will often need to search through large amounts of text for a particular piece of information such
as an email or a phone number.
Searching for patterns can be done through regular expressions.
Imagine you needed to search a string for a term such as phone you could use the key word that you already
know about.
To do this you would just say the string phone in and then the string you want it to search.
In this case it would return true because the string phone is in that string is the phone here.
Now imagine that you need to find some telephone number such as 4 0 5 5 5 1 2 3 4 you could do the same
action search that string in another string and it would return a boolean indicating whether or not
the string was there.
But what if he didn't actually know the exact phone number.
If all you knew was the format of the number to be three numbers a dash three numbers a dash and then
four numbers.
You would need regular expressions to search through the document for this pattern instead of just a
normal string.
Regular Expressions allow for pattern searching in a text document.
Now the syntax for regular expressions can be very intimidating at first.
Here we can see an example of what the pattern structure looks like for a phone number.
The key thing to keep in mind is that every character type has a corresponding pattern code.
For example digits have the placeholder pattern code of backslash.
The use of the backslash allows Python to understand that this is just a special code and not the actual
letter.
The Python's built in regular expressions model or R E can work if the special pattern codes to search
through the documents to retrieve information.
Let's get an overview of how to use this pattern code syntax.
Let's begin by understanding how to search for basic patterns.
You'll create some example Tex saying something like the agent's phone number is 4 0 8 5 5 5 1 2 3 4
call soome as we just discussed.
You could search for simple strings in the text such as phone in text and you would get Beckie boolean
indicating true or false.
Is that actual string in the text.
But now let's show the format for regular expressions to do this.
We will import the regular expressions module.
R E.
And then we'll assign the pattern phone to a variable called pattern.
So I will say that the string phone is equal to pattern.
Then we can say R E.
Called the search function off of the regular expressions module and then you pass in the pattern and
then you pass in the text and you get back this match object.
And so notice how much more information is here.
This match object will report back not just whether there was a match to the phone but also where the
actual index location spanned two.
So it starts to index 12 and then ends the index 17.
So now let's search for a pattern that we know is not in the text.
So we'll create another pattern variable or really overwrite it and then something like not in text
which we know isn't there.
And if we search for the new pattern in our text we get back none.
Which means we don't really get back anything because there is no match.
So now that we've seen that this are that search function will take the pattern and scan the text and
return a match object.
And if no pattern is found none is returned which in the notebook setting just means that nothing is
output to the cell.
Let's take a closer look at this match object from before we're going to reset pattern as phone and
we're going to run this search again.
We'll say e that search pattern and the text and we're actually say this to the variable match so we
can explore this match object.
So this is a regular expression match object and it has a lot of information that we can grab from it.
We can call the spand method in order to get the actual index location of the span.
And then you could also ask for the start or the end.
In that case by themselves.
And keep in mind if we had multiple matches inside the string we would unfortunately only get back the
first match.
So if I had a string that said my phone once my phone twice and then I tried running the same command
as before saying match r e search for phone inside of this new text.
And then I checked the match itself.
It only turns back one span 3 8 because that's the first metric here.
If I want to find multiple matches or all the matches I can use the find the all function instead.
So I can say match's is equal to r e find all and I will search for Again phone in that text.
And then if I check my matches I get back this list of how many matches I had.
So if we wanted to check how many matches there were I could get the length of this list and if I want
to get back actual match objects then I use the iterator so to show you what I mean by that I can say
for match an R E fine and sort of fine.
All I can say find her and then pass and what are pattern I'm looking for.
So I could be looking for phone again and then pass in the text I want to search.
And what this does is it iterates through this text and then returns each match object that's found.
So just like before when we were using search we returned back the first match object essentially indicating
where we first matched up.
If we use find all it just returns back a list of the strings themselves.
If I want to kind of combine these two by iterating through the text object and then finding every single
match object I use find it.
So you're going to need to essentially use a for loop with this to iterate.
So we're saying for match in our e that find it or you pass in the pattern and the text you want to
search for and then you can print out the actual match object.
And then we get back the match objects and you can do whatever you want.
These match objects.
For instance if you were just interested in the span's you could call the span method off of it run
that and return back the span's.
Now if you wanted the actual text that matched all you need to do is use the group method.
So you could say here group and that returns back the actual text that matched up that you were searching
for.
Essentially what you get back when you use Find all.
So far we've been able to realize the critical functions of the regular expressions module and that
is the search function where again you just pass in a pattern in the text and it returns back the first
match.
Object the find all function which again patterned text and it returns back just the list of matches
indicating the strings that matched and then they find.
Which is essentially a combination of these two where you go through the entire string and you return
back match objects for the actual pattern you're searching for in the text.
Then you can call any methods you are off of that match object.
What we haven't discussed yet is the actual special regular expression syntax for general patterns.
Right now we've only been searching for basic strings.
Up next we're going to discuss how to build these special identifying regular expression pattern codes.
We'll see their agent.