Welcome back agent we just discussed how to use regular strings for pattern searching when using regular
expressions library.
Now let's move on to the key part of regular expressions which is the special pattern codes you can
use to build out your own pattern sequences.
We'll start off by discussing character at the fires.
And here we have a table that tries to explain what each character that the fire is.
Basically you'll have special characters and the fires start off with the backslash code and then a
letter indicating what character you're referencing.
So to start off we can look at this example backslash the and this description is a digit.
Essentially you would have this as a placeholder for any digit.
So in your example pattern code you could have a string file underscore backslash the backslash D and
it would look for anything that holds that pattern file underscore and then two digits following it.
For example file underscore 20:5 would match the pattern code.
Here we can also see there's alphanumeric basically indicating letters or numbers.
So alphabet or numerical.
And that's backslash W and this is what a example pattern code could look like backslash w dash and
then three backslash W's.
And that basically says any letter or number followed by a dash and then followed by three letters or
numbers and alphanumerics.
Also include things like underscores So keep that in mind.
Then there's whitespace.
So if you're particularly looking for whitespace in the pattern you can say backslash S and that indicates
a placeholder for whitespace.
So an example pattern code for that would be the letter a backslash s the letter B backslash s letter
C.
And what this does is it indicates that you're looking for a whitespace B whitespace C.
So here we have an example match.
There's also a non digit character placeholder which is backslash capital-T and you can think of the
pattern here as lowercase is a digit of lowercase D and then uppercase is a non digit.
So you can see how these are related to each other and backslash the backslash D-Backs like where they're
all uppercase is going to match up with for instance this pattern ABC because none of these are digits
and they're all in a row with each other.
You also have non-alphanumeric and non-whites base.
Again the capitalized version of their counterparts.
So here you can see some various example matches.
Let's begin by checking out that example of the telephone number.
We will say our text variable is my phone number is 4 0 8 5 5 5 1 2 3 4.
And then we will say phone is equal to our e search and if we actually search the phone number itself
for 0 8 5 5 5 1 2 3 4 in our text will see that phone is that match objects saying where it found that
span.
However we may not always know the actual number.
We just know the pattern where it's three digits a dash three digits and then a dash and then for that
it's.
So what we can do is replace this using the pattern character identifiers.
We just learned about.
In this case we're looking for a digit.
So we will use backslash the tool say backslash d backslash d backslash D.
Then we expect that dash 3 more numbers another dash and then finally four numbers.
However recall that when working with strings these backslashes indicated special escape characters
such as backslash and for a new line or backslash t for a tab to tell Python that we're using these
as a pattern for a regular expression what we do is we add an R right in front of the string.
So that basically tells Python that these aren't really escape slashes such as new line or in the case
tab.
Instead we're using them as a pattern for regular expressions.
So that's why you see this are in front of the strings when working with patterns for regular expressions.
So this rerun the cell and now see what our phone object is and your Lowder's the phone object is again
the exact same thing it's a match.
But if I were to change these numbers around.
So I said 7 7 7 7 for the techs and rerun the cells.
It would still get the match before it would not get the match because it's looking for the exact numbers
here instead we're doing a smarter approach.
We're actually searching for the pattern itself.
And if you ever wanted the actual number you could say the phone object here you see the span.
And if you called the group method we discussed earlier on it it returns the actual piece of string
that matched.
So this is how you could actually grab that phone number itself.
Now notice what we did here for every single digit in this phone number.
We wrote a backslash.
But what if we were looking for a pattern that included 20 digits or 100 digits we wouldn't want to
have to write back slash the 20 50 or 100 times.
For this reason we can use quantifiers to indicate repetition of the same character.
So we already know our character to the fires.
Now let's learn about the quantifiers allowing us to not have to write these multiple times so here
we have the quantified table and basically the way the syntax works is you stick your character identifier
and then immediately after you stick this quantifier if you want to indicate a certain quantity.
So you have various quantities you can choose from.
There's the plus symbol indicating that the character and then the fire occurs one or more times.
So an example of this pattern code could be version backslash w.
So that's alphanumeric dash backslash w alphanumeric plus.
So what this plus indicates is that you're looking for backslash w one or more times.
So an example match could be a dash B one underscore one.
So all of these are alphanumerics that occurred one or more times.
Recall the underscore counts as an alphanumeric.
Now let's imagine you want something to occur.
Exactly.
And the amount of time.
So exactly three times four times you get the idea you can use curly braces in that sense.
So you would stick on your character than the fire.
This case we're looking for backslash capital-T indicating a non digit.
And we want this to occur exactly three times.
So an example match would be ABC 3 non digits if you want a range you're looking for for example occurs
two to four times.
It's the same curly braces except now you indicate the lower limit comma at the upper limit.
So backslash lowercase the curly braces to come for an example match could be one to three.
Another example match could be one two or one two three four because we're looking for a range here.
Alternatively if you're looking for three or more or some and number or more so you don't want to set
an upper limit.
You can just say curly braces your lower limit comma and leave the upper limit blank.
So backslash lowercase w along with curly braces three comma upper limit basically that just says three
or more alphanumerics.
Go ahead and match them.
So you can see any characters here that string will match because it's three or more alphanumerics and
you can see how regular expression code can get a little complicated quite quickly because you're adding
characters in the fires and quantifiers.
But if you break it down you'll be able to see what the actual pattern code is asking for the next quantifier
we can look at is an asterix here.
And that basically indicates if it occurs 0 or more times.
So here we have an example pattern code a than asterisk B strict and then C strict.
And what is asking for does a occur.
Zero or more times followed by be occurring zero or more times followed by C occurring or more times.
So there are a ton of actual patterns that can match up to for example Triple-A than two C's that indicates
that a did occur three times b occurred 0 or more times.
And then you have Z or C occurring two times.
So a very powerful here and it's going to match a lot.
So keep that in mind and then you have a question mark here in the kitting once or none.
So here we can see plurals question mark indicating those s occur once or none.
And so an example match could be plural or could be plurals.
So either it occurs once or no times.
All right let's see how we could transform our original search for a telephone number using quantifiers
will place our example phone.
But now we know the actual mouse who wants to say we're going to replace this with our character identifier
and then saying I want exactly three numbers then a dash then another three numbers.
And then we want four numbers.
And this is now a regular expression pattern code for a phone number with dashes.
So we can run this and see that we check our phone we get back the same match here because we're asking
for three digits in a row followed by a dash followed by three digits in a row followed by a dash followed
by four digits in a row.
Now let's imagine that we wanted to do two tasks.
One was to find phone numbers but then also to be quickly able to extract their area code.
That is the first three digits of the phone number.
These first three digits right here.
What we can do is we can use groups for any general tasks that involves grouping together regular expressions
and that allows us to later break them down.
So to do that we need to learn about the compile function so we all say phone underscore pattern is
equal to r e compile a comp. does it compiles together different regular expression pattern codes.
For example the first pattern could we see here that's just a single pattern code.
But what we could do is think about it as three pattern codes connected by the dash.
So that's exactly what we're going to do here.
We will say our.
And then our quotes and in parentheses we're going to group together three pattern codes.
So the print C's indicate that it's a group of a pattern.
So the first one that's going to go into first print sees is this one right here backslash the curly
braces three.
So there's our first group and then dash and we're going to do our second group which is actually the
same thing.
And then the third group is going to be with the four here.
So what this does is it takes multiple pattern codes and each pattern code is separated with parentheses
as a group and then it compiles them into a single expression.
So what this is going to do is it's going to compile these into this expression that we see right here.
But what's nice about using the compile is that it still understands that these were three separate
groupings so you could call the groupings individually so you Kreator a phone pattern using the compile
function.
So if I say results is equal to r e search and I search for the phone pattern in my text and then I
say results and I group them together.
I see here 4 0 8 5 5 5 7 7 7 7.
Now what I can do is say results group and call them by the group position and the groups words noted
by these princes.
So if I want the first group I can say Group 1 and notice here and a little bit of a differentiation
from normal Python code.
We don't start indexing at zero we're starting at 1.
So group ordering starts at 1.
So if I grab those results and I group and I just say Group 1 it only returns back the first group here.
So if I want a group to essentially that second set of digits I could say Group 2.
In a word turn back five five five.
And if I wanted the third group I would say Group 3 and or return back 7 7 7 7.
And if I ask for a group that is outside of this such as group 4 it's going to say sorry there is no
such group because here we only had three sets of parentheses.
First Group second group and third group.
What's nice about this approach in regards to our first approach is that now we can easily extract parts
of that information while at the same time looking for a complete match.
So if you just call a group with no number it groups together all the patterns you had in your compile
function and then returns back the whole match.
So if you wanted to find phone numbers you could just use this approach and then group them together.
And if you wanted to find phone numbers and there area codes you could use group with nothing and then
say Group 1 and that returns the area code.
So that's why the compile function along of the group method is so powerful.
That's it so far for quantifiers as well as the compile and group function.
Up next all we have left to talk about is some additional regular expression syntax such as wildcard
characters and then or pipe operators and stuff with like starts with or ends with.
Let's quickly review what we covered here.
Basically we discovered that if we don't want to repeat character identifiers often where we can do
is use quantifiers and we have various quantifiers indicated by special character then there's a description
here and we can essentially tack them on.
We also learned that if we want to grab subsections or subgroups of our entire pattern we can use the
compile function to create the actual pattern instead of just passing in the pattern as a whole string
separating each group with parentheses.
And then we can say grouped together off of the search results in order to grab everything together.
But if we only want to grab subgroups we can say a group and then that group position where group positions
start at 1.
All right we'll see you at the next overview where we're going to talk about some additional regular
expression syntax.