Welcome back agent.
Let's quickly discuss how to work with zip files with Python as you know the results of the previous
read Mission left you with a zip file.
Fortunately Python's zip file and S H you till modules support working with zip files.
There's basically two different approaches.
The ZIP File module allows for first creating a zip archive and then adding individual files to it.
It's kind of similar to creating a file and then writing lines to it except you create zip archive and
then you add separate files to that zip archive the issue module allows for quickly compressing an entire
directory into a zip archive as well as unpacking that archive later on.
More likely than not you're going to be using that second approach because it's more similar to what
you're used to based on just a normal graphical interface of a computer where you right click on a folder
or directory and then zip it or you right click on the zip file and then unpack it or unzip it somewhere.
Let's explore these modules use cases with zip files and show you quickly how easy it is to work with
zip files in Python.
The first thing we're going to need to do is actually create some files to compress to do that.
We're going to very quickly open some new files that don't exist yet and we'll do this with the right
plus that way we can actually write some stuff to them.
So I'll say all right and then say here is some text and then we'll close this file.
Then we're going to do the exact same thing except we're going to rename this to two that we've created
to text files.
Now the next step is to import the zip file library meaning we'll import zip file and this is already
built into Python and you can use that to compress folders or files and to compress all the files in
a folder you could use the OS the walk method and iterate this process but let's first describe the
very basics first.
What you do is you create some sort of compressed file.
So we say comp underscore file is a variable you call the zip file and then you call the Capitol zip
file off of this whoops and you allow yourself to create the name of whatever the compressed zip file
is going to be.
So you can say whatever you want this to be my compressed info zip and then you create that with the
right method.
So now we've created a empty zip file and we can compress things into this zip file.
So I already created two text files remember and you file that text and you file to that text.
Let's go ahead and write these into that zip file and then we do that is the following say comp.
Underscore file and then you write to the zip file.
You give it the file path or whatever you want to write to it.
So for example you file that text and then you indicate your compressed types or how you actually want
to compress this.
Now we're going to use a built in compression type in the zip file which is good for most purposes which
is zip.
Underscore the flat is in all caps.
So you can run that and let's copy and paste this line and run it again except this time we're going
to do this for the other text file.
And then once you've written all your text files and compress them into a zip file you go ahead and
close that zip file and that's the basic way to use the zip file library for actually writing to a zip
file.
So this method's idea is to first create the zip file that's empty and then you would write individual
files to them and compress them as you go along.
Now that we've written to the zip file the next step would be to extract from the zip file and the way
you do that is pretty similar to actually reading a normal file.
You say whatever zip object you have you call zip file zip file and then you passen whatever file is
compressed.
So in this case it's my compressed info that zip and will only be reading the zip file and there's different
methods you can use here if you just want to grab everything what you can do is say extract all and
make up a folder name where it's going to go.
So you can say extracted content and it's going to extract everything there.
So later on you could check and you'll have a folder there.
If you only wanted to extract an individual file the way you would do that is very similarly you would
say zip object except in this case you would just say extract and then whatever file you want it to
extract.
So for instance I know there's new file that Texian there so I can extract that one and it extracts
it from the zip file.
Decompresses it and saves it to wherever this notebook is happens to be.
So those are really all the methods you need to know when dealing with the zip file.
You create a zip file with write mode and then you write individual files to it as you compress them.
Then you close it.
If you ever want to extract everything you just open it in read mode and then you can either extract
everything or you can extract individual files.
Finally let's discuss how to use the s h you still module in order to archive or extract zip files and
actually supports a variety of formats.
It's a little easier to use than the zip file method just because you can quickly extract or zip up
an entire directory instead of doing it line by line.
But keep in mind that file definitely has these methods as well because it can extract everything at
once using extract all billets but see to do this the first thing you need to do is say import s h you
still and then there's essentially just two commands make archive and unpack archive.
We can say s h that you tell.
And if we want to make an archive there's three main parameters.
The first one is the output file name.
In this case you just passing whatever you want the file to be called.
You can say my new compressed file or whatever you want to call it.
And then the second parameter is the actual method you're going to be using.
And there's only a few acceptable strings but there's zip Tar Tar Tar and X Zaatar.
You can check the documentation for information about all those but those are essentially just different
extensions for zipping things together.
We'll stick with zip.
So you pass it in as a string and like I said this could be something like TJR or GZ Taar in case you
need that particular format.
And then you in the directory to zip up and remember that it needs to be a directory not just a single
file.
So in this case I know that there's a directory in the same location as this notebook called I believe
my example folder.
There it is.
So we'll go ahead and just zip up my example folder and then if you run that it just created a mine
you compressed and note here it says zip because that's what we provide.
Here's a second parameter.
You don't need to say that zip when you do it in this first parameter.
Finally let's discuss how to unpack the archive.
It's quite simple you just say sh you till and then you unpack the archive will you have to be aware
of here for the unpacking.
The order is a little different than what we had earlier at least the parameter names are a little different.
You just passen the file name the extraction directory and then the format.
And if you expand this.
Ill tell you the file names the name of the archive itself which you already established is mine you
compressed that zip.
So let's pass that in mind you compressed zip and then the other parameters want to do is the extraction
directory is just the name that you make up.
So you can say my extracted content and then finally it wants the format it was in.
So it could just tell it it was in zip format.
We run that.
And now if you take a look at your computer you should have the extracted content in this folder you
just created at the same location that this notebook isn't.
Again pretty simple approaches for both of them but this one tends to be a little more convenient because
you can quickly archive and unpack archives which just a single line of code.
All right.
Agent you should not have all the skills necessary to pass the orange mission.
Best of luck.