Excellent work on completing your mission agent Let's quickly go over a de-brief things so others can
see how you are able to accomplish your tasks.
The first thing we needed to do was to unzip the file to do that we can easily just import s h u till
and then call unpack archive function.
From that we will say unpack archive and then put in the actual zip file location.
In this case we'll say Mission orange files.
And then the Unzip me for instructions and let's go ahead and then give it a location to be placed then
we'll say we'll just put it in the extracted
content and then finally we can clarify that it's a zip file.
So if you run this you should now be able to see the extracted content and we can check this by saying.
Import os and then saying OS list directory and you'll see here that if we keep going down we can see
the extracted content that we just created so that directory now exists.
All right.
Let's not check to see what files are in the extracted content.
We're going to say OS that list victory and we'll actually then pass in the extracted content so we
can see what's inside of that.
And here we can see there's five four instructions that text 1 3 and 2.
Let's open this instruction is that text and see what's inside of it.
It will say f open and we're going to pass in the extracted content and then instructions that text
and we can just use tab autocomplete to do this.
Let's read this file and say F dot read lines so we can see everything.
All right.
So it says if you're reading this and let's actually print out all these lines so let's do this again.
Open this file and then say lines and then for line and lines.
Prints line.
So if you're reading this we were able to successfully decipher from the blog post in the Goldblatt's
Web site to find this link which led us to that zip file after unzipping the file.
We had this instruction text file and if you take a look at the other folders there's actually random
text files in them.
So instead of 5 4 1 3 and 2 there are random text files and hidden within these text files are two links
and we need to be able to use regular expressions to find the URL links which lead to the next phase
as you go through every text file programmatically.
One of these links is going to lead to a CSP file and another to a set of instructions for that CSP
file and it tells us that the links are going to be in this form of your URL.
It will be a dry dog Google dot com open and some sort of ID notices how we have alphanumerics So there's
numbers letters and underscores and we have a p.s. and then we also have some sort of Google doc so
the docs thought Google dot com document and then some sort of alphanumerics.
So we have starts with HTP.
And then a series of characters.
So we'll be able to use this information for our regular expressions by realizing that inside of these
files we're looking for something that starts with us then we'll download that CSP file and follow the
instructions.
And the other link for next steps.
So let's see if we can do this.
The first thing you want to do is figure out a regular expression pattern that works for finding the
sort of links something that starts of HTP us so import regular expressions and let's create our test
phrases.
So a test phrase one will be this first link here
and then test phrase to will be the other link.
So we're going to be using these as test strings and then we'll check different patterns against them.
And if we are successfully able to grab and this entire ordeal from the pattern or using the pattern
I should say we'll be able to see that we will be able to grab the pattern within any text file.
Now we realize the pattern does start with age.
So let's check if that works we'll say our.
And we're just looking for H.T. CPS Colin forward slash forward slash So if we say test we'll say our
E find all and we're looking for the pattern inside of the test phrase when you run this command you'll
see that there's basically just HGT.
And none of the actual remaining URLs there.
So we need to add a group of characters to look for after HTC B-S and there's many many ways you could
write a regular expression for this but one way to think about it is just HSDPA us Colin forward slash
forward slash and then just grouped together using these square brackets or braces.
And then if a plus sign were looking for any number one or more of the following say we'll look for
dashes we can see there's a dash right here.
There's also question marks and four slashes.
So we'll say the following question marks forward slashes.
There's also underscores there's equal signs and we can put a period for a wildcard necessary.
And then finally we can say something like backslash W and let's run this now and see if we find it.
So here we go.
If I add a bunch of stuff here basically say look for any combination of these.
After HTP us I see I have now the fool you are l and it matches up here.
Let's try it with test phrase to make sure it also works.
And if we run that we also see that we get back the full URL.
So that's working well.
Now what we need to do is basically go through every single text file and search it for the actual pattern.
So let's make a function we can call.
So we can't call this pattern easily.
We'll create a function called search that takes in a file and the pattern we'll be using here is equal
to what we just wrote a peer.
So say pattern is equal to this and this actually doesn't really need to be a parameter in your search
function.
We'll open the file
open the file will just read the file.
That way we don't accidentally edit it then we will say the text is equal to the read.
So read this as a string and then if our esearch pattern text basically indicating if I have a match
object.
So keep in mind that objects can actually be used as booleans.
So lots of ways you could write up this logic.
You're going to return our search pattern and then text else we'll just return a blank string.
So what this function is going to do.
It's going to accept a file.
It's going to open that file read that file and then it's just going to search for the pattern in that
file sex.
And if it finds one it's going to return the pattern itself.
Basically the result that you are.
If not it'll just return an empty string.
Now we need to do is use OS walk to walk through all the files here because if we come back up here
notice there's one two three four five files and each of those five folders really and each of those
folders contains many random text files that we need to look through.
So we'll do the following.
We'll say import os have my results as an empty list and we'll say for folder sub folders files an OS
walk and I'm going to walk through the extracted content that I have here.
So let's scroll up where we actually extract that.
It's right here at the extracted content.
So we'll just copy this come back down here and say oh just walk through that extract the contents then
for f in files.
I need to define the full path so the full path to that file is going to be equal to the folder it's
in plus time on a Windows computer right now.
Backslash backslash plus F.
So what this is saying is construct the entire file path to that file.
Otherwise you'll get an error when you're trying to open it.
Because what I'm going to do is say my findings are what everyone to call this variable is equal to
search on the full path of that file.
And then I'm going to append my findings.
All right.
So let's break down what we're doing here.
We're using the OS walk function to walk through the extracted content of the zip file.
If you take a look at the extract that content it's just a bunch of random text files.
And if we look through each of these files in order to construct the entire full file path so that we
can open it when we call the open function here we're going to grab the name of the folder we're currently
in then because I'm on a Windows computer and going to add two backslashes here on a Mac or Linux you
just add a single forward slash and then I will add the actual file name that constructs the full path
of the file which is what I'm going to pass into my search function.
Now my search function here is just going to open that file read the text and then do a regular expression
search.
And if the search name is confusing you can say search for pattern and then down here I could just call
this search pattern.
This is going to search for pattern in that full path.
Those are my findings that I'm going to append my findings to the results.
So let's run this.
See if it works.
Looks like it worked.
And I will say for all my results because if we look at the length of results it's going to be 121.
But a lot of these are just empty.
So let's take a look at the first ten.
One of them we have a match object right away.
But others are just empty strings.
So let's actually say for our in results if the R is not equal to an empty string go ahead and Prince
the results so we can say our group because remember if you have a match object which is our Here it's
saving match objects.
You can just group it together to actually ground your l.
So we're going to run this and we see now we have three links here.
So let's check them out.
We'll open each of these and see if we actually find them.
So one of them was not found because it's actually if you take a look at it it's the example link that
was shown here in the instructions which is not an actual functional link but if we take a look at the
other two looks like we have instructions for downloading the CSP file so we can go ahead and read this
for our next mission.
And the other one is the CSB file itself meaning we'll need to learn how to work of files for the next
mission.
Excellent work so far.
Agent Let's quickly have an overview of the entire de-briefing So to begin with you were given this
zip file that you had to unzip once you unzip it.
You were able to realize that there is an instruction text file and if you read the instructions text
file it basically tells you the inside of these other folders or many other text files and inside of
one of those are are your links and you need to find two of them that are in this format a drive link
and a box link you were given the hint that they start with HTP s colon slash slash.
However if you just look for that you'll just fine.
So you can do is use regular expressions to basically indicate that you're looking for anything that
follows HTP as.
One of the tricks they had to realize though was it's not just technically all alphanumerics There's
also question marks and equal signs and dashes to include there.
So we created our pattern and then we had this find all.
So we can actually grab the Arel.
We create a function that when given a file it searches and returns the pattern or the match object
or an empty string the pending of it finds the pattern match up.
Then we used OS walk to walk through all those text files and then if we found something we went ahead
and appended it to our findings something else you could do here is only append if the findings was
non-empty string.
So we could do here is also the following.
Could it say if findings are not equal to an empty string
then append it.
So if I were to run this again and then check the link for my results.
Now I only have three and I can just check my results for the links themselves and then go for match
in results prints match and then group the result itself.
So I can get those actual links and those actual links.
One of them was the instructions link which is not open to anything.
The other ones are the link for the download CXXVI the instructions as well as the CSP file itself.
OK.
Excellent work.
We'll see you later in the field.