Welcome back agent.
Let's now discuss working of pedia files in Python.
Often in the field you will need to work with not only CSFB files but also pedia files and there are
many libraries for PBF with Python.
The most common one is Pi PDA too.
You can install it at your command line by running Pipp install py PDA.
And notice the capitalization here we have uppercase P and in lowercase Y and then all uppercase PBF
and then two that needs to match in order for the installation to work again just a command line you
can type up.
Pitman's Thall PI PDAF to keep in mind.
Not every pedia file will be readable by Python pedia ifs that are too blurry.
Have a special encoding encrypted.
Or maybe just create a particular program that doesn't work well.
Typedef to.
It just won't be able to read it typedef to can only read text information from a PDA document.
It won't be able to grab images or other media files from the PTF.
Let's not explore how to work with this particular pipe program with Python.
The first thing we're going to do is import py PTF too.
So make sure you've installed at your command line already and then once we do that we can simply open
a file and it's going to be similar to the way we opened CXVII files or really any other file.
The file We're going to be working with is the working underscore business underscore proposal that
pedia you can find under your yellow mission folder and it looks something like this.
If you're just to open it and your browser has business proposal and then essentially just some random
text here over a couple of pages.
So since we're in the same directory as it we're just going to build a tab autocomplete parking business
proposal PBF.
And the last thing to know is because it's a PDA file.
We need to read it not just with the R mode but also with the RB.
Essentially saying read it as a binary file.
Once we do that we're able to create a PDAF file reader version of it.
It will say PTF reader is equal to pi PTF 2.
And then we can call PTF file reader on that variable.
And this is very similar to the same way we created a cxxviii reader.
But now we have a PDAF file reader so there's a few things we can do now with this variable.
You can ask for the of pages attribute.
So it's an attribute method meaning there's no open close parentheses and then returns back the number
of pages in the document.
And if you actually want to grab a page you need to do the following.
You can say page one variable is equal to PTF reader and then call get page and then Passons starting
at index 0 that will grab the first page and then FXE want Page 1 text.
I can grab the page one object and call the extract text method and from there I will have all the text
on that first page.
So keep in mind it's only grabbing the actual text and it also won't be able to really understand what
is wanted differently or what has different capitalisation.
We take a look at the very first page where we noticed that business proposals the title and the revolution
is coming as some subtitle.
And if we zoom in here we can also see that it has numbering at the bottom so business proposal page
1 and then she go down because proposal page to this pedia reader is really not going to be able to
understand that and few pedia readers are really that's something that's very difficult for a computer
to programmatically realize.
But it will be able to read in that text so we can see here we have business proposal.
We can see the revolution is coming and there's a backslash.
And in order to indicate that new lines.
And if you go all the way to the bottom you'll see business proposal and then kind of an indication
of page 1 there.
So once you're done reading the sexual text where you can do is you can either print out the text so
we could say print prints page 1 text in order to see it in a little bit more a fashion that it's intended
to or you could just close the file.
And can say f Bhatt's close.
Now let's imagine we actually wanted to add to the PTF so we cannot write to PTF.
Using Python because of the differences between the single string type of Python and the variety of
fonts placements and other parameters that a PDA could have.
Well we can do however is copy pages and the Penda pages to the end.
So again just to make it clear because of all the different varieties of fonts placements and parameters
we're not going to be able to directly for instance insert a paragraph into this PDA.
What we can do though is copy the last page.
Or really any page in the PDAF and then append that to the end.
So the way we would do that is we would again open that file working business proposal and then say
Arbi for reading in binary mode.
Create the reader object again.
So that's PI PDAF typedef to P.F. file reader say fear.
And we can say something like.
The first page is equal to PEF for get page and will get page zero the very first page and then I'm
going to create a writer object.
Will say PTF underscore writer is equal to pi PTF to PTF file writer and just open close Princie here
essentially creating the writer object and using this writer object.
We can say PTF writer and we can add a page and we'll add in that first page.
So once we ran the page all we can do is say PDAF output is equal to open and we'll say some new file
PTF and we'll hope we will open this in right binary mode and then we can actually write that output.
You can say PTF writer writes that PTF output and then once you've done everything you can just close
the files so we can say PTF output and then close that as well.
OK.
So that's essentially the way you can writes to new files or essentially make copies.
All we did here was we opened up our original business proposal PDAF then we created a reader object
off of this file.
We grab the first page then we created a writer objects after we read the first page then using that
we added a page the first page.
To this writer object and then we were able to open this new some new file and then say right PTF output
and then we close them and if we take a look at this some new file PTF we have it open right here.
It's essentially just that first page.
So that's all you can really do.
Just grab some pages you want and save it to a new file.
Or if you wanted to append.
You could open this as a B instead of just WB.
All right.
So let's do a very simple example of grabbing all the text from a PDA file which more likely than not
is what you're going to be doing.
We're going to again.
Let's make a couple of cells here will open up the file.
It's working business proposal.
With our B because it's a Barney file and then we'll create a list an empty list to hold every page
is text and basically the index will correspond to the page number will create the reader object again.
So PTF lips should be capitalized.
PTF file reader pasand the file we want to read and then say for p in range
PDAF reader the number of pages will do the following.
We will grab the page itself which will be calling the reader object and then saying get page
and we'll pasand p here so we can really say.
And so for page number that makes more sense.
And then the PDAF text itself.
We're going to append the extracts text from that page.
You have to call that method.
So when we run this and we check out our PTF text now we have a list of every page so you can see every
index position and the pages match up so all we're doing here is the following.
We're opening up the file in read binary mode.
We are saying an empty list for a PDA text we read in the file with pipes F to and then for every page.
So for an in range for the number of pages that this file has we grabbed the page and then we extract
the text from the page and we append that to that list.
So now using PDL text where you could do it.
For example if you wanted to print the page at index to you could just do this and I can see here's
a page index too.
All right.
That's really all you have to do for PBS.
Hopefully that was helpful to you and we'll see you at the next overview.