Welcome back agent.
Now that we know how to send e-mails let's review how we can use Python to view received e-mails to
view received e-mails of Python.
We can use the built in IMAP live and email libraries in Python.
The IMAP lib library has a special syntax for searching your inbox.
There's a table like this in the notebook corresponding to this lesson but basically the idea is that
there are particular keywords and then there's definitions that refer to those keywords and you'll be
able to search your inbox for particular emails such as checking emails by date so you have keywords
like before date on a date or since day checking emails based on who sent them.
So from some sort of e-mail or hoost you sent them to to some e-mail.
You can also check by s.c or BCSC.
So a carbon copy or blind carbon copy you can also check by the subject string the body string or just
any text string and you can also return emails based if you've seen them or you haven't seen them.
If you answer them or if you haven't answered them and also deleted or undelete messages as long as
as long as they still exist in your trash bin a certain e-mail providers will automatically erase everything
or trashman after 30 days.
So you can see here that there's a lot of keywords and functionality built in to what we're going to
be using before beginning this discussion.
Go ahead and send yourself a test e-mail with some sort of unique subject line that you will be able
to remember and search for using Python.
Or you can simply use the last e-mail that you sent yourself from the previous lesson.
Let's begin exploring checking received e-mails of Python by loading up a Jupiter notebook.
The first thing we're going to do is import the IMAP lib library that's built into Python and we'll
create an instance of it.
And you can call this variable whatever you want but a lot of times people call it capital M and will
say IMAP lib and then call IMAP for S S L and then we'll pass in the IMAP server for Gmail which is
IMAP gmail dot com and then we need to grab our password and email.
So to do that you can either use input or get pass it will say that our email is equal to get pass get
pass email and then we'll also grab our actual password for the email get pass get pass and remember
for Gmail users this is your app password.
So let's run this.
Well go ahead enter your e-mail for whatever you happen to be using.
And then you can also put in your password.
In this case I'm putting in the app password.
Let's now connect.
We can say that log in and we'll pass an email and password.
Run that and you should be able to log in you should see some sort of authenticated success message
there.
Once you've done that you'll be able to type in that list as a method.
Run them and you can see everything that you can check in your particular email.
Typically you'll be checking your inbox.
You can also see you can check personal receipts sent trash things labeled travel or work drafts important
sent mail spam start trash so there's lots of different options different flags that Gmail or other
e-mail providers have for you.
We're going to select the most common one which is your inbox meaning we'll say em select and we'll
passen inbox run that and then it should say ok and some sort of connection number to your inbox your
number will likely be different than mine here.
And then now that we've connected to our mail we're going to be able to search for it using the specialized
syntax of IMAP.
Now the next step after we've logged in is to actually search our inbox and this is the sort of syntax
you can use to specify what messages you're looking for.
In our case we will attempt to search for that e-mail that we just sent earlier.
That was a subject line new test Python so we say type and data to basically doing tuple and packing
because the actual search function that we call is going to return a tuple and you passen none as the
first argument.
And then the second argument is actual string that uses this sort of code.
So you can say for instance before and then format a date such as 0 1 November 2000 and this will essentially
search or e-mail and return back everything sent before 0 1 November 2000.
Or you could do on a certain day or since a certain day you can do from a certain string.
So for example you could say from user at example dot com and maybe didn't know who the actual user
was.
At this example dotcom do you think you could say just from example and it will search for all the e-mail
addresses from and see if the string example is in there.
Do you think you can do that we're going to be doing a search by subject to notice how these keywords
are capitalized will say subject and then inside of this string will have another substring.
And this will be the actual string worth checking for.
So the subject line that we passed and last time was new test Python.
So that's what we're going to be searching here.
Notice how it's a string inside of a string.
And let's run this and see what we get.
If you select type it should say OK.
And if you have data it should have some sort of number.
If you don't have any sort of number returned here it means it didn't find any messages.
If you have multiple numbers here in a list that means it found more than one message that relates to
whatever search term you were looking for.
So this unique ID is the ID that references the actual email.
We don't have the email itself yet to do that.
We now need to fetch the actual data.
So if we take a look at the first item in this list it's this unique ID so we will say ID is equal to
also email ID email ID is equal to that item in the list and then will say results.
Email underscore data is equal to m and then we end up fetching that particular email id and then for
a second argument we need to pass in a protocol and the call for that is a string with parentheses are
f c 8 to 2.
Now that we've actually fetched the e-mail data we can take a look at the e-mail data and it's basically
going to be a bit of a sloppy mess.
There's lots of information here the e-mails.
But if you take a look down here we can see that we have the subject and we actually have the message
we sent.
Hello.
This is a test and this is all within a list within some tuples.
So we just want to grab the actual message itself.
So we're going to do is index for it.
We'll type out.
Email is equal to e-mail data and it's index position.
You may need to play around for this but in our case it's at 0 1.
So that's the raw e-mail itself.
And we want the raw email string we'll type out raw e-mail string is equal to this raw e-mail and we're
going to need to decode it.
And the reason for that is because there may be symbols such as the at symbol which is confusing the
python sometimes.
So we want to clarify that we're going to decode it UTF 8 encoding and then once we've done that we
can use the built in e-mail library to help parse that string.
We will import e-mail and this e-mail library helps grab the actual message from a stream.
And the syntax is it still a bit strange but it looks like this.
You say email message and then from the e-mail that we just imported we'll type out message from.
In this case we're grabbing the message from a string and then we in that raw email string that we just
created.
And then once we've done that we need to do the following the actual email message object here.
If we take a look at it it's this iterator and what we need to do is say for every part in the e-mail
message the walk.
So you can kind of walk through this email message object if part dot get content type is equal to text
forwards slash plain
then body is equal to parts dot get payload and say the code is equal to true and then prints the body.
Now this is quite complicated but the reason this is complicated is because we're basically going from
that rostering email message and trying to get rid of all the other information that came in through
the e-mail data.
There's a lot of different ways you could decide to look through the subject once you have the sexual
e-mail data yourself.
It's optional to use this e-mail library.
Sometimes people feel that it's more of a hassle to use this e-mail library rather make their own custom
script to grab that e-mail data.
And if you're dealing with e-mails that look the same every time maybe it's from some API service it
might make sense to not use the sexual e-mail library that's built in.
But if you do want to use e-mail.
BILTON once you have the raw e-mail string from your actual e-mail data after you've decoded it he typed
out e-mail message from string and then you save for part an e-mail message walk.
If the car get Content-Type which basically asks Hey what is the content type of the part.
And if it's equal to text for Slash plain meaning it's plain text you grab the payload of that part
decoding it and then that's the actual variable that we want to see.
So if we print this out we should be able to see the actual body of the message which is hello this
is a test and this be indicates that it's a byte stream just because the way we read in that e-mail
data.
Keep in mind this sort of content type check text forward slash plane.
That's if you only expect just plain text.
Well you could also do is maybe expect text slash HVM mail.
And that's really common.
If someone has provided a link inside of the e-mail.
So if you expect another link to be in the e-mail that was sent to you you may want to check for text
forward slash HVM L instead of text forward slash plane OK.
That's it for the basics of checking your received e-mail with Python.
Let's quickly go over all the steps.
All you have to do is import IMAP lib.
Make the connection to your IMAP server so it's IMAP that gmail dot com or I'm up at yahoo dot com depending
on what your actual domain provider is.
Then grab your email and password log in.
You can see a list of options but typically you'll be searching your inbox and then using the special
syntax code you search for whatever you're looking for whether it's a particular subject whether it's
a particular email it's from a date that it was sent on you get back.
The type and data and the data recall is just a list of actual email ids.
Once you have the e-mail IDs you need to fetch them and here are fetching a senior or email id and we
passen this protocol for fetching it and then we have the email data and it's kind of up to you what
you want to do at that point because it's a bit of a mess.
But one way you can deal with it is using this email library and then using this lock functionality
to check for particular content types.
All right that's it.
It's time for your mission.
Best of luck on Agent.