Excellent work on your mission agent Let's quickly have a deep briefing on how you're able to complete
your tasks.
The first thing you had to do was to send e-mail and we can do this with import S and T P lib and then
create in the actual object centipede live asem T.P. and then connecting to the correct domain server
for your email address for this case its Gmail.
And then we can pass in our port 587 as well.
And we also want to make sure that we immediately afterwards do our hello to connect and greet the server
and then we also want to start tell us so I'm Topy object start.
Tell us so running that we get the connection ready to go and let's grab our email and password.
We can do that with get pass or really any what you prefer.
E-mail us is equal to get pass don't get pass
e-mail and then we also have your password for your e-mail address get pass get pass.
And then once we have that we will log in with that information log in with the e-mail and that password
so we can provide that e-mail address.
And then we can provide whatever your password is and the case of Gmail it's going to be that app password
you created.
So once you provide your e-mail and your app password for your Gmail account you should see something
that was accepted and then we need to provide a from address to address and then the subject so from
address will be the same as our current e-mail the to address
is going to be info at the gold bugs dot com and then our subject can really be whatever we want we'll
say test and then message can again be whatever we want we're just looking for an auto reply.
So I will say please reply and then the actual message we sent is going to be subject.
Colon Plus the subject line plus a new line and then plus the rest of that message.
After that we'll say awesome object and we'll run send the mail from the address to the address and
we'll provide it.
The SMG message so run that we should be able to send an e-mail to and fought the good books that come.
And if you've got this empty dictionary that means it was successful once you've done that we can quit
our session and now it's time to check for a reply to that that we will import.
I IMAP live.
We'll create a connection with IMAP live to our actual server will say I'm out for SSL and then for
Gmail it's going to be app that gmail dot com.
And we actually already know our e-mail and password from up here.
So we'll be using the same ones who will say log in email password.
Run that.
And we should hopefully be able to see OK once you've done that we can select our inbox
and that should also say OK.
And then we can say type data and we will search our inbox.
I'll start off with none and then we need some sort of special code here.
Now we'll look for from info at the gold bugs dot com and see if they reply to anything.
So we'll run that check the type.
OK.
And then let's check the data and see if we have anything.
So in this case I've actually already e-mailed for the gold bugs multiple times.
You can see here I have multiple results.
In your case you should probably only see one single result.
Let's grab the actual e-mail data itself by fetching one of these IDs will say results e-mail data physical
to fetch and I will fetch that last one.
So it will say 2 8 4 9 4
RAFC 8 2 2 as my protocol that I'm going to grab that raw e-mail data using the same sort of indexing
we previously saw.
E-mail is equal to email data use some indexing there create the raw email stream equal to raw e-mail
and Im going to decode this to be UTF 8 and then I'm going to use the email library that's built into
Python to actually try to get nicer printing of this string.
So let's try that out.
I say that the e-mail message is equal to e-mail message from string and we'll say raw email string
and then we will do the walkthrough and see if we can print out the body for parts in that e-mail message
we just created the walk method.
If parts get content type
is equal to.
And in this case the Roque's have been linking to other Web sites.
So instead of just saying text forward slash plane we will say text forward slash Tim L.
And then the body is going to be equal to parts payload.
We'll say de-code is equal to true.
And then let's print the body of this message and if it looks like this then we successfully got the
body of the message itself.
But in this case it looks like it's still in some sort of T.M. where we can do to try to fix this is
grab this information copy it turn one of these cells into a markdown cell and then paste it in here
and we should now be able to read it as formatted says if you're reading this message you are able to
find the email from the PDA.
Using the CSP file and it looks like there's two links here for the next phase.
We'll click on those two links and see what they have.
It looks to be two images.
Looks like it's just some scrambled addresses with random words in here.
And the other one seems to be a cover image so that indicates we now need to learn how to work with
images with Python.
Excellent work agents.
We'll see you at the next mission.