Welcome back agent Let's discuss encryption and hashing the intelligence from the last mission.
From the images led to an encrypted message Python can be used to perform cryptographic encryption to
understand encryption in general.
We first need to understand hashing a hash function is any function that is used to map data of an arbitrary
size to data of a fixed size.
Let's look at a very simple example where the hash function is performing the Maat operator with two
on the length of a string so on the left hand side we have just any arbitrary string to the string can
be as large as you want or a smaller as you want.
Here we have just a few small examples and then we pass it through a hash function.
In this case the hash function is just take the length of the string and then Matu and get the result.
And that basically just checks.
Is there an even number of characters or an odd number of characters in the string.
And no matter how big the string is the past to this hash function you're always going to get one of
two results either a 1 or 0 1 0.
In the case that there was an even number of characters in the string and one in the case that there
was an odd number of characters.
So now we can take an arbitrary string of any size pass it through this hash function and get back a
fixed size result.
Now notice something important here we cannot go backwards.
This is a one way hash function because I can't just give you a result of 1 or 0.
And the hash function itself and then expect you to figure out what the arbitrary string was.
On the other end now a one way cryptographic hash function is more complex than what we just saw because
it must be able to provide a unique hash for any information passed to it.
Previously we saw here that we have repeated hashes ones and zeros.
But the cryptographic hash has to be unique for any arbitrary data that is passed to it.
So that's quite harder of a problem to solve.
And the ideal hash function actually has three main properties.
And this is for cryptographic hash functions.
The first property it should have is that it should be extremely easy to calculate the hash for any
given data.
It can't take forever.
Otherwise it's basically a useless hash function because we're going to be waiting all day for it to
compute the hash.
So the first one is it has to be quite fast.
The second one is that it has to be extremely computationally difficult to calculate the alphanumeric
text that has a given hash that is it must be really really hard to go from the unique hash.
Knowing the hash function to go back to the arbitrary data and the third one is that has to be extremely
unlikely that two slightly different messages will have the same hash.
These three components are the main properties that a cryptographic hash function must have.
Now there are many cryptographic hash functions that exist and the five SH A Blake.
There's tons of them and many older hash functions have actually been deemed insecure due to discoveries
of what are known as collision attacks where different arbitrary data inputs are discovered to have
the same hashed output.
Remember one of the key components of a cryptographic hash function is that any arbitrary piece of data
that you pass into it has to have its own unique hash.
The s h a secure hash algorithm is a set of standard hash functions developed by the NSA.
These hash functions are essentially just mathematical formulas to follow and they're open to the public.
And in fact the latest secure hash algorithms are discovered through open competitions.
Now the Wikipedia on cryptographic hash functions is a great resource for learning about the latest
developments as well as the various algorithms available.
And we'll be discussing the various algorithms available in the cryptographic libraries we use later
on.
So now that we understand cryptographic caching that is just a one way hash of grabbing arbitrary data
passing it through the hash function and getting some unique hash out of it.
We're going to now discuss encryption and decryption encryption differs from hashing because the message
needs to be able to be decrypted.
That is we have to actually go backwards to decrypt an encrypted a message usually a key is required.
In cryptography a cipher is an algorithm for performing encryption and decryption and typically ciphers
require a key.
This key is then only known by two parties the sender and receiver.
And this actually allows for the message to be beamed publicly but only readable by its intended recipient.
So that would look something like this.
We have some original message.
Let's say hello.
And we create some cryptographic cipher with a particular key and that will end up producing an encrypted
message so we can send that encrypted message through public means because it doesn't really matter
to us if anyone sees an encrypted message because they can only decrypt that if they know the key.
So keep in mind this all depends on keeping that private key secret.
And there's other ideas that span from this such as private public key encryption that actually solve
some of these problems of allowing yourself to expose a public version of the key and then holding a
private key yourself.
But for our purposes we just need to have the idea that we have some original message.
We create a cipher using some private key.
We have an encrypted message.
And then if someone wants to decrypt that message that is go back to the original message.
They just need to know the key for the cipher.
To explore all of these concepts in python we have to install the cryptography library to do so.
Go to your command line and type out Pipp install cryptography and install the cryptography library.
Up next we're going to explore these concepts in code in Python.
We'll see you there agent.