Excellent work on your last mission agent Let's quickly have a deep brief so we can see how you accomplish
your tasks.
The first thing you have to do is figure out what the fair amount numbers were.
And if you did a google search and go to Wikipedia we kind of realize that there's actually only five
known Fermont terms and the largest one is 6 5 5 3 7 2.
Copy that and set that as our number from Prime and create a byte string from that then we will import
hash lib and using Actually we will create a key out of that prime string hash lib and it instructed
to use SH 3 256 bit in coding on that number and then we have this key object.
And we will import base 64 and we'll get this as the key digest.
Once we have that we can pass it and encode it using the 64 Library giving us our key base 64.
And that's you're all safe.
Encode the key bytes once so that we can from cryptography
for net import Fernet and then say custom cipher and pass in the key we just created
then we can copy and paste the message that we found in that link.
I will do that now.
So that's the entire message.
I'll save that as the variable.
SS And let's call our custom Sipher and decrypt that message.
And it looks like it's leading us to another link so we'll click on that link and see what it has to
say.
All right.
So looks like this link is from the first encrypted message.
The key to the encryption was 6 5 5 3 7.
Dale says here is a link to the truth.
Looks like it's another encrypted message and it says decryption key is a five letter word in all caps.
Pass through again that same sh three underscore 256 bit hash and it says you can find the word using
this data.
So if we click on this next link it looks like it's a text document of latitudes and longitudes as well
as some other text here.
My suspicion is that you're going to have to plot out this latitude and longitude meaning we'll need
to now learn how to do geographical plotting with Python.
We'll see if there agent.