This tutorial we will be talking about false positives and false negatives.
As you remember where we were using the logistic regression function to observe where for random values
of the independent variable will end up in terms of y had so in terms of the predicted value for the
dependent variable and we agreed that anything below the 50 percent line will be projected downwards
onto the zero horizontal line and anything above the 50 percent line will be projected upwards onto
the 100 percent horizontal line and that allowed us to turn probabilities into actual predictions.
So either yes or no.
Now let's take a step back where did we get these four values from.
So we took four random values of the independent variable and we just had a look at what would happen
to them how we can use how we would use the logistic regression function to ascertain what probability
they have and what y had values have.
So we take another step back and we forget about these four random values and instead of taking four
random values of the independent variable about we take for unknown values.
In fact let's take four values for the independent variable.
From our data set.
So let's just pick out four values that we really know they exist in our data set.
And we use them to create this logistic regression.
And let's do the same thing with them let's see where they will end up.
If we apply the model to them.
And as you can see here the label of the vertical axis change too.
Why.
Because this is the we already know that in red is the actual value of the dependent variable because
we know the result.
Those are the people on the bottom so observation is number one and number three they didn't take up
the offer the email offer.
And the observations on the top people number two and four they did take up the email offer.
So let's see what happens to them if we apply our logistic regression model.
So step number one would be to project these values onto the curve makes sense right.
So we just want to see where they all end up on the curve that's all blue dots over there that's where
they have been modeled by the curve.
Now we can and from here we can say what the probabilities are you just have to project to the left
and you can see approximately that for a version number one.
It's about maybe 20 percent 10 15 percent may say 15 percent observation or two.
It's about 40 percent absorption of three I would say about 70 percent observational before about 85
percent.
But we're not interested in probabilities per se.
Right now what we want to get to is the actual y hat we want to see what the predictive value will be
so we wanted to say we want to see if the model will tell us are these people going to take up off or
not.
And why would we want to do this is because we already know the result.
Right.
We already know what the result will be or was and we just want to see we want to kind of assess the
model we want to see how well it's working and if it's going to make any mistakes.
So let's go ahead and proceed with our logic for getting the y hat and what was the logic there.
Well the same thing that we discussed just a few minutes ago at the site of the Statoil anything we're
using this arbitrary horizontal line 50 percent.
So anything below this line is going to be projected onto the horizontal line which is zero.
So where we're saying that the offer is not going to be taken up and anything above the 50 percent line
will be projected onto the horizontal line which is 1 or 100 percent.
Where is saying that those people that end up on that line are different going to take up the offer
.
So let's go ahead and do that.
There we go in gray We have our projections or our predicted values so white hat isn't great and it's
very interesting to see both why and why had on one chart so that means what actually happened is in
red and what we predicted was going to happen isn't great.
And right away you can see that for absorptions number one and number four.
So for those people in observation the morning before they we predicted correctly so we said for Person
number one we predicted that she won't take up the offer.
And he actually did not take up the offer because the red mark is also on the same horizontal line.
Now for observation and before.
Same thing we predicted that that person will will take up the offer.
And they did take up the offer.
That's good but now let's have a look at the rest of them.
Number three you can see that for observation number 2 the gray lines at the bottom.
The green marks at the bottom meaning that the model is predicting for this person based on their gender
based on their age.
Well in this case just age because we're doing a single variable logistic regression.
So based on their age this model is saying that this person is not going to take up the offer because
the gray market is at the bottom.
However we can see that the red mark is at the top meaning that this person did take up the offer and
that means that the logistic regression made an error here.
And same thing for person number three.
The gray market is at the top and that means that the models predicting that the person will will take
up the offer but the red marks at the bottom meaning that the person didn't actually take up the offer
and therefore the logistic regression made a mistake once again and these mistakes they actually have
specific names.
So the top mistake over there is a false positive or a type 1 error.
What does post false positive mean.
Well it means that we said we predicted a positive outcome but it was false.
So we were.
We predicted an effect that did not occur.
And the other mistake you see here has a different name is called a false negative.
So we predicted that there won't be an effect but the effect actually did occur.
So our prediction was negative meaning there won't be an effect but it was a false negative and it's
called a type 2 type of error.
And the way I personally remember them is it's important also to distinguish between the two.
The way I personally remember them is I think of type 1 as less dangerous than type 2 so type type 1
is less for me in my in my mind although it's not necessarily the case.
But the way that's the way I remember them that type 1 is kind of like a warning.
So that's why there's an ordered orange explanation mark and it's it's a false positive.
So basically you said something is going to happen but it didn't happen.
So you said maybe will be an earthquake but there wasn't an earthquake.
So you know that's not the end of the world.
But false negative is a bit worse in my view once again understanding because once you say something's
not going to happen but it actually does happen then you can't even be prepared for it.
And that's why Type 2 is false negative and that's how I remember them personally.
But once again it could be.
Absolutely.
They can both be pretty serious errors especially when you are dealing with like medical conclusions
and stuff like that.
So those are false positives and false negatives.
We will be using them more when we talk about the confusion matra matrix in the next tutorial and I'll
look for you next time.
Until then happy analyzing