Hello, my friends, and welcome to this very exciting new practical activity on convolutional neural
networks.
If you're not too overwhelmed by the previous section, you know, on our visual news networks.
Well, then you will smash with me this new section, because basically a convolutional neural network,
as you saw in the intuition lectures, simply consists of adding an extra layer, which is the convolutional
layer that, as you understood, gives eyes to the A.I., you know, to the deep learning model, because
indeed, with the convolutional neural network, we can now take an image or, you know, a 3D frame
as an input as opposed to our previous artificial neural network, which could only take an input vector
containing some features as information.
Right.
Remember the features of the customers in the bank.
But here we're going to add at the front a convolutional layer which will be able to visualize or see
images just like humans do.
So that's pretty exciting.
You know, we're making a step further towards human intelligence because, you know, the fascination
that scientists have about deep learning is that, you know, it's a branch of machine learning that
gets artificial intelligence closer and closer to human intelligence.
And you will even see in some more advanced courses on deep learning that not only we can add eyes to
the A.I., but also some memory with the alicja themselves, but also some critics sense.
Well, there are a lot of innovations in the deploying science, which is absolutely fascinating.
But here we're going to focus on C and ends.
And so there you go, my friends.
Let's start this new practical activity.
And as usual, before we go into this further, let's make sure everyone here is on this same page.
I give you the link to this for the right before this tutorial in the article.
And so now please follow me into part eight, deep learning.
We're inside.
We're now going to go to convolutional neural networks.
All right.
So for this section, exceptionally, we only have an implementation in Python.
And that's for the simple reason that or is more used for data mining kind of machine learning or,
you know, advanced statistics, high dimensional statistics.
But I have not met any scientists in my life who does computer vision with ah.
There are some libraries like Deep Water that can build a CNN for computer vision.
But really the best and most advanced programming language for deep learning is definitely Python.
Thanks to the amazing libraries that have been developed by Google and Facebook, you know, Google
developed Tensor Flow, which is an amazing library for deep learning.
And Facebook developed by Torch, which is another amazing deep learning library.
But these two, Tenzer, fluent by Torch, are only used with Python.
And that's why, exceptionally for this section, there will not be an R implementation of the CNN.
Right.
The Eynon was fine because we were still doing some advanced data mining with neural networks.
But for computer vision, really your best option is Python.
All right.
So let's go into Python.
And now second different thing compared to before.
As you notice, you will only find the implementation here in this folder and not the dataset.
That's for a very good reason.
That's because the dataset is actually super huge and or in terms of size.
It's a couple hundreds of megabytes because the dataset contains lots and lots of images of cats and
dogs.
We're gonna see them in a second.
But since it contains a lot of images.
Well, I did not include the dataset here otherwise.
You know, for those of you who want to download the whole machinery, it is it codes and data sets
folder.
Well, it will take a lot more time if I include this dataset here than if I left it separately, which
is what I did.
I left it separately and I gave it to you actually right before this tutorial in the same article.
So I hope you downloaded it, because right now we're gonna have a look right at the bottom of the Oracle
right before this tutorial.
You had to download this exact folder.
Well, actually, the zip folder better already and zipped it.
But you had to download this for those Section 40 convolutional neural networks, which indeed contains
not only the codes and IPY and B format and P y format, but mostly the dataset, the dataset, which
contains three sub folders.
The first one containing all the images of cats and dogs.
But for the training set, which means that we're gonna train our CNN Morrel on all these images of
cats and dogs in the train set.
And then we have this other folder, which is the test set on which we will actually evaluate our moral
with new images of cats and dogs on which the model wasn't trained.
And finally, we have this little folder here, which only contains two images.
And this will be just to test the model in production.
You know, the single image.
So we will first take this image of.
This beautiful dug to test that our CNN can detect the dog, you know, can predict that indeed we have
a dug in this image and we will do the same with that image of a cat so that we can check that.
And these are CNN predicts that there is a cat in this image.
So, as you understood, I just explained the problem.
Actually, we're going to build and train a convolutional neural network to recognize if there is a
dog or a cat in an image.
OK.
So I hope you like the Casey.
Of course, this time it's not a business case study, but we're gonna have a lot of fun doing this.
And it's a great way to be introduced to convolutional neural networks.
And even if it's just an introduction, you will see that to see an end we're going to build will be
quite advanced.
And actually the implementation is quite advanced with lots of technical tools, which will, of course,
perfectly do the job at d'Eon.
OK.
So that was the second specific thing the dataset was given to you separately.
All right.
And just to show you quickly, the training set and a test set.
So in a training set, you have lots and lots of images of cats and dogs.
Actually, you have 4000 images of cats and four thousand images of dogs.
Right.
I can take anyone.
This is a dog.
Another dog.
You know, many different breeds of dogs.
So if you love dogs, you're gonna have a great time looking at the images here.
Right.
And there he goes.
This is a very cute dog, by the way.
OK.
And simply catch you have many images of cats.
Right.
A different style, different colors, you know.
So whether you're a cat lover or dog lover, you will have a great time looking at any of these images.
And send for the test set.
Well, you have 1000 images of cats here and same 1000 images of dogs.
So just to recap, in the training set, you have until 8000 images with 4000 images of cats and 4000
images of dogs.
And in a test set, you have in total 2000 images with 1000 images of cats and 1000 images of dogs.
Right.
It's important to keep numbers in mind because we're going to use them in the implementation.
OK, good.
So make sure to have this on your machine, because, of course, we will use it to run our coat.
And now, third specific thing that I wanted to highlight in this first introductory tutorial here is
the fact that for the very first time, we won't be able to run our implementation, which is this one
convolutional neural network that i.p Wendy.
We won't be able to run this implementation on Google CoLab.
Why is that?
That's for the simple reason that the dataset is too big for a Google killer notebook.
And therefore, for the very first time in this course, I will show you how to run this implementation
on Jubera notebook, because with Jubera notebook, we will be able to access directly from your machine
the data set.
And we will run the code from our machine.
But within a Juber notebook.
Well, notebook.
Okay.
So what we'll do, in fact, in this new section is we will still, you know, reimplement this whole
code from scratch on Google Kulab.
But at the end, once all this is implemented, we will simply go to FAO here and then click here,
download DOT, IPY, NDB, and this will download the IPY and be FAO, which will be able to run on
Jubran Notebook.
All right.
So that's what will happen.
But we will stay on Google Cloud to implement this together.
And speaking of which.
Well right now we have to save a copy and drive because this is an read only mode and therefore we need
to create a copy to be able to modify and reimplement the whole code.
All right.
So let's do this as usual.
Let's delete all the code cells.
Right.
Only the code cells.
Make sure to keep the text cells to keep that well highlighted structure, because indeed, now we have
a pretty long implementation.
So it's important to keep the structure so that we can, you know, take a step back any time and know
where we're going.
All right.
So let's remove only the code cells and.
Now, reaching part three, you know, you're going to recognize some of the same steps as before with
CNN.
Right.
This is part four.
And there we go.
All right.
So that's the whole structure.
Let's have a look at it, you know, from here.
So at first, we will import the libraries.
Then we have a structure in four parts, parts one day pricing, part two, building the CNN, Part
three, training the CNN and port for making a single prediction.
So it's exactly the same as before, you know, with the CNN.
Only this time, in part one, we will do a different work because for the very first time actually
in the course, we won't be preprocessing a classic dataset.
But this time we will be preprocessing some images.
And therefore, the data pricing phase will be different.
It will consist of doing two steps.
First, we will pre-process the training set and then we will pre-process the test set.
All right, then in part two, we'll build a CNN Nual, the whole architecture of the convolutional
neural network.
We will initializes CNN as a sequence of layers.
Then we will proceed to step one convolution to add to convolutional layers.
Then we will proceed to step two, pooling, more specifically, max pooling.
Then we will add a second convolutional layer to make it, you know, a deep neural network as opposed
to a shallow neural network.
Then we'll proceed to step three flattening to flatten the result of all the convolutions and pullings
into a one dimensional vector, which will become the input of a fully connected neural network.
And finally, we will connect to all this.
The final output layer then in part three when training CNN.
Well, same as a CNN.
We will first compile the CNN and then we'll train the CNN on the training set.
Well, you know, evaluating it on the test set.
We will clearly see that in the output.
And finally, we will make a single prediction, you know, to test our model and prediction.
And so we will deploy our CNN on to different images.
One that will have Doug and the other that will have a cat.
And we will hope that our CNN can recognize, respectively, the dog and cat.
All right.
So that.
Ah, structure.
I hope you're ready for it.
And actually, I'm sure you are.
So if that's the case, well, join me in the next tutorial to smash this implementation.
And until then, enjoy machine learning.