Hello and welcome to this art Tauriel So in a toil we're not going to make any mention or any model
we're just going to make a template and this will be our regression template.
So it's a template that is going to be very useful for the next non-linear regression morals.
We're going to make like as we are modeled the decision tree regression model and the random for us
regression model.
So we're going to use this template to build these three next models and our.
And also you can use this template to create a regression model for your specific problem because as
you can see you will only have a few things to change so that you will build your machinery model very
efficiently.
So let's make this some plates and to make it we're going to go from what we did in polynomial regression
and generalize the whole thing.
So I'm going to take everything from here up to the end copy and I'm going to paste that in the template
.
And now let's make this template.
OK so first of all let's start with the beginning.
So the beginning was about preprocessing the data.
So actually there is nothing to change here.
We will keep Of course these two lines because we will work on the position salary C as we file and
build our non linear regression models on it.
And for the same reason as before we wanted to split the data set into a training set and it said because
this is a small data set and we will leave features scanning as comments here.
Since most of the libraries don't require us to apply features getting manually.
So all good for the preprocessing phase and this will be the first part of our regression template.
Great.
Now let's move on to the next part.
So the next part is about creating the model creating the model and fitting it to the dataset.
So first of all in the previous Statoil we built two regression models the linear regression model and
the polynomial regression model and that was just to compare the two results and to show you that the
polynomial regression was much more appropriate to our problem because it was not a linear regression
model as opposed to the linear regression model which is a linear model.
So we only did that so that you can understand very clearly the distinction between linear models and
non-linear models.
But now that it's getting pretty clear in our minds we are going to get rid of this section here about
linear regression because now we get the idea and we will only focus on the new non-linear regression
models themselves without comparing them to the linear regression model but keep the graphic results
of the linear regression model in mind.
Keep in mind that it was a straight line not fitting very well.
The data is set and therefore is not much appropriate to our data set where the data is nonlinearly
distributed.
OK so we're going to get rid of this done.
Now we only have this code section here that creates the non linear regression mode itself.
So we are going to get rid of this because this corresponds to the polynomial regression and to generalize
we will just add a come here to specify that this is where we have to create our progress or right here
.
OK.
And here we can also replace polynomial regression by the regression model and we are all good with
this section.
OK.
Now let's move on to the next one the next one is about visualizing the results.
So for the same reason as what we did in this section to fit the regression to the data set we will
get rid of the graphic results of the linear regression model because we have them in mind and we only
want to focus on our future non-linear regression models.
So let's get rid of this.
And now we only have the graphic results of our future non-linear regression model.
Okay.
And the great thing about this template is that in the section we will need to change anything with
almost anything because we're going to replace polynomial regression by regression model and we're going
to change this.
Paul you reckon regress regressors here by regressors because you know before we called it Polly rag
because we also had our Linnea our aggressor Lin Ray.
And so we needed to make the distinction.
But now since we got rid of the linear regression model we will call our future non linear regression
model regressors here and that's why we put regressors here and the predicate function.
So basically when we get to this section when we build our future non-linear regression model the only
thing that we will need to change is actually the title here.
Basically we don't have anything to change here and that's the great thing about this template.
However of course if you're using this template on your data set and your problem well the only thing
that you will need to change are the names here of the independent variable and also the name of the
dependent variable here that you will have to replace salary by the name of your dependent variable
.
But that's all.
OK and we're finally getting to the last section of this code template which is about predicting the
final result to get our final verdict.
Okay so same reason as before we're going to get rid of the linear regression part for this.
So here we go.
Goodbye.
And now we are only left with the polynomial regression prediction.
Okay great.
And so now we just need to change something here.
Well first it's the name of the aggressor because for the name of our pulling them your regression regressors
was called POLLI rag.
And now since we won't make the distinction between a linear regression model and our nominee our regression
model Well our aggressor will be called regressors.
So here we aggressor.
And here you know for polynomial regression we need to input the polynomial features of our data frame
that we created in our data frame.
Well we won't need to do this for the next nonlinear models because this is strictly specific to the
polynomial regression model where you know we need to add those polynomial features.
And so we will get rid of this and we'll get something very simple.
It's actually this line that will perfectly predict the salary of the 6.5 position level because in
our future non linear regression models there won't be those polynomial features in the data sets to
only need the original independent variable here and especially the 6.5 value of this independent variable
.
So that's why we have everything we need with this simple line.
Okay great.
And now the last thing that I'm going to do is maybe to take this code section here cuts and I'm actually
going to place it between the creation of the model and the visualization because I like to keep the
best for the end and for me the best part the most exciting part is the part where we visualize our
results.
And for a second reason is that we know that's our problem is not in their problem and that therefore
we need a non-linear or aggressor.
And we were definitely already convinced of that.
That's why we don't need to execute this code section before this one to convince ourselves that we
need indeed and not in a regression model.
So therefore for the next regression models will make the prediction before visualizing the results
.
And that's why I'm putting that here first.
OK.
So I think the template is ready now.
Well maybe we need to change the polynomial here to generalize the template as much as possible.
So will replace polynomial here by.
Well actually let's just put predicting in your result.
All right.
And here we can replace a polynomial regression by regression model.
All right and now just to finish just one plate for those of you who are also interested in getting
a smoother curve and your regression model results.
Well there is this trick we can do to increase the resolution and we are going to do that right now
.
So it's just an optional code section that I'm adding here in this template.
I'm going to copy this because we will have just a few things to change.
And you know for those of you who really want a very smooth curve when you visualize a regression model
results well you can use the following code.
So the trick is to actually create a new sequence of levels.
That means that when we are predicting only 10 salaries of the 10 levels well which we're going to do
now in this section is that instead of predicting only 10 salaries of 10 levels we're going to predict
a lot more than 10 levels and to do that we will build a vector of imaginary levels that will actually
be levels from 1 to 10 incremented by 0.1.
So that means I will consider level 1 level 1.1 1.2 1.3 up to 9.6 9:27 nine point eight and nine point
nine.
So that's what we will create in the sequence and therefore here instead of predicting only 10 salary's
we will predict actually 90 salaries of 90 levels.
So that's the trick.
And to build this sequence it's actually very simple we are going to call the sequence x grid you know
because X grid will replace data set dollar level here and data set here and this X grid is going to
be defined as SEC which is a function that builds a sequence.
And so in this function we need to input three parameters.
The lower bound of your sequence.
So that's actually men data set level because by doing this are taking the minimum of all the levels
in your original dataset.
All right then the next parameter is the upper bounds of your levels that is level 10.
And therefore we do the same with the max here Max data set dollar level.
All right.
And the third parameter is the step.
So that's where we increase the resolution and make our fitting curve smoother because here we're going
to take a step of 0.1 and therefore 90 levels will be created here from 1 to 10 incremented by 0.1.
All right.
That's actually done and now we need to replace data set dollar level here that originally took the
10 levels of our dataset.
So we are replacing that by X grid and same here we need to replace data set here by a new data frame
because you know this new data argument here is expecting a data frame here.
So we can not replace it directly by ex-secret here because X grid is not a data frame it's a sequence
that is a vector.
So what we need to do here is use this little trick again.
It's quite simple to use this data frame data Daut frame comment here that will actually create a data
frame and in parenthesis we're going to specify that we want to create a data frame of new levels.
So I'm taking the voidable level here and then equals and that's where you put ex-secret because you
know by doing this data frame level equals x grid we are just creating a new column of levels containing
all the levels in this sequence x execrate here levels and that's it.
This new code section is ready to plot your regression model result in a higher resolution and actually
we're going to specify here that it's for higher resolution and smooth curve.
All right.
And that's actually ready so you can try it on either you know you're pulling on your regression model
that we made in the section or you can use it on the future non-linear regression models that we're
about to build and you will see the difference between these two.
Then if you want a more simple code you can use this one or if you have for example a dataset with a
hundred observations incremented by one then this is the code you need to execute because then you wouldn't
need a number on one step to build your different points of your fitting curve.
All right so now the template is ready.
We are actually ready to use it for the next nonlinear regression models that we're about to build.
We'll do that in the next sections and you're going to see how it will be so efficient at building them
.
So I look forward to creating this model with you.
It's going to be very fun and we will make them in the most efficient way and machine early.