Hello, my friends, and welcome to the final practical activity of this course.
Yes, I must start by saying that I am at the same time excited but sad that this is the end of the
journey.
But no worries.
We're going to end on a very, very good note.
And that good note is about, of course, extra boost.
It is a super powerful machinery model, which I absolutely want you to have in the toolkit, because
you will see that it brings excellent results in most machinery problems.
And actually, the things so cool about this is that it can be both used for regression and classification.
So there we go.
Let's cross the finish line together.
And this final tutorial by implementing the extra boost morale so that morale is given to you in part
10.
So just before we enter this part, make sure to be on that same page.
I give you the link to this for the right before this story or in the article.
So make sure we connect to it.
And now here we go.
Let's finish this journey together by entering points and then the final section of this course, section
forty nine on x g boost.
All right.
And as usual, we're gonna start with Python, which contains two files.
First data.
And second, the implementation.
And now you probably also noticed that there are many files open now on my machine.
Right.
All these files.
And these are, you know, the files that we implemented so quickly and efficiently.
When doing that, Morales selection demo at the end of Boit three classification.
Right.
I gave you this model selection folder with all these classification models which were experimented
on the same data set, which is that dataset data that C V and which I remind consists of predicting
if a breast cancer tumor is benign or malignant, meaning that each row of this data set corresponds
to a patient, you know, is a certain patient.
And for each of these patients, we have several features from the clump thickness, the uniformity
of cell sized uniformity of cell shape, you know, all these features that are characteristics of a
tumor.
And with all these features, we were trying to predict if the tumor is benign or malignant, it is
benign.
If we get the class two and malignant if we get the class for all right and we build and trained all
of our classification model, which are all the ones right here to learn the correlations between all
these features and that Dippin viable telling if the tumor is benign or malignant.
And remember that we had different accuracy's for each of these models with the logistic regression
model.
We had an accuracy of ninety four point seven percent with the Kimura's neighbors.
We had an accuracy of ninety four point seven percent.
Again, with the SVM, we had an accuracy of ninety four point one percent with the kernel SVM.
We had a better accuracy actually, with ninety five point three percent with native Bayes.
We got a lower accuracy of ninety four point one percent again.
And with decision tree classification, well, that was the winner.
We got an amazing accuracy of ninety five point nine percent.
That was the number one on the podium, followed by the kernel SVM with that accuracy.
And then, unfortunately, Random Forest did not do any good or, you know, not better than the others
because we got a ninety three point five percent accuracy with it.
And so what I want to do now, as you probably have guessed, is to build the extra boost morale and
train it on the same data set to see if it can take the throne, hold by the decision tree classification
model.
In other words, to see if it can beat that accuracy obtained with the decision tree classification
model and.
Well, maybe, maybe that's the good note on which we will.
And the journey of discourse.
Are you ready to let us do this?
We're now going to build and train are extra boost morale on the exact same data set and see if we can
beat basically an accuracy of ninety five point nine percent.
And not only we will test that on a single test set, but also, of course, now that we learned Caple
cross-validation in the previous section, we will test this on ten test false so that we can get a
relevant measure of the accuracy and make sure that perhaps extra boost will now become the number one
on the podium with the ultimate machine learning thrown.
So let's check this out right now.
Let's open this implementation with either Google Collaboratory or Dupere notebook.
I'm gonna put it last.
You know, just next to all our other classification models and.
The notebook just opened.
But it is still in read only mode, so we're going to create a copy right away by clicking Save a copy
and drive.
You can notice that all these are copies of the original implementations which are right here, you
know.
That's the moral selection folder and then classification subfolder, which I give you at the end of
point three.
So you can run this goods again if you want.
But we already did that.
Just remember that the number one was indeed decision tree classification with an accuracy of ninety
five point nine percent.
And now we're gonna see if we can beat this with extra boost.
All right.
So, of course, no worries.
We want reimplement all this.
We will quickly get to the core of the implementation and mostly the exciting part, which are the results
in the same tutorial, because indeed, all the sales of this implementation are just cells taken from
our diverse toolkit.
Right.
These three first sales are, as you recognized perfectly, the sales of our data pre pricing template.
We first import the libraries and we import the dataset with the exact same code.
I just put the name of the dataset here and then we split the datasets into the training set and test
set.
So this is all the data pricing phase.
Then we train extra boots on a training set.
And of course, I'm going to delete the sale right away because that's the cell we will reimplement
together.
And then we have the other tools of our other two kids, like the classification tool kit, because
indeed this sale makes the confusion, matrix and prints at the same time the accuracy.
I actually already deleted the output to make sure we get the full surprise by the end of this tutorial.
And then, of course, as I told you, we are going to apply K4 cross-validation right at the end to
make sure that indeed we didn't get lucky on the test set.
You know, if we indeed can beat all the other algorithms so we will not only get a first measure of
the performance thanks to a single test set with this cell, and then we'll get the ultimate measure
of the accuracy with that cell.
I'm ready.
Let's start by building and training extra boost on the training set, which resulted from the split
of the data set between the training set and test set and first in order to get the assistance of Google
Kulab.
Well, let's apply this reflex of uploading the data into the notebook.
So, you know, I just clicked this folder button here and in a second we'll see the upload button to
upload indeed our data set.
So let's click it.
And now let's go to our machine learning.
Is it codes and data sets folder?
Because you will still find the data that says we found in this folder in part then, of course.
So let's go into this folder then.
Let's go into part ten, then section forty nine, extra boost by phone.
And here is the data set data at we of many patients with tumors for which we have to predict if the
tumor is benign or malignant.
So open.
Okay.
And now the data set is indeed uploaded into the notebook.
So there we go.
We can implement that.
And then run the whole code.
All right.
So let's create a new code cell.
And there we go.
Let's build and train extra boost on the training set.
So you're gonna see that it's going to be super easy.
And in fact, we won't even do it with psychic learn, but with a library called Extra Boost in which
we don't even have to install thanks to Google Kulab, because it is one of the many packages already
installed on Google.
Kulab, you know, already preinstalled.
So we have nothing to worry about and we can just start building and training this extra boost model.
But first, we're gonna import the class with which we're gonna build this.
And this class belongs, of course, to this extra boost library.
So there we go.
We're gonna start from this x g boost library, right?
It's spelled this way, just like the name of the model.
Extra boost, indeed.
And from this library, we're gonna import.
Well, the class that can build an extra boost classification model and which is called x gibi.
There we go.
Google Kulab founded x chibi classifier.
All right.
And now the next natural step, as usual, is to create an instance of this class, which will be exactly
the object containing the extra boost morale.
So once again, we're gonna call it classifier.
All right.
And we'll create this classifier as an instance, indeed, of the x gibi classifier class.
Perfect.
And now the good news is that we won't have too much to worry about with this class because there is
not much parameter to tune.
Right.
Basically, the default version of the extra boost morale will most of the time perform super well.
So all good here.
And now, of course, we finished this by connecting this extra was classifier to our training set.
And the way to do this is by, of course, calling the fit method from our classifier object, which
will do nothing else than train this extra boost classifier on the training set.
Right.
So something we did many times.
So there we go.
Let's do it one last time in this whole machine learning journey.
But then I'm sure you will do it many times once again in the future, in your future machinery and
career.
So let's do this.
We call our classifier from which we're going to call this fit method, which will train the classifier
on the training set, which is composed of, first, the features of the training set represented by
X train and then the dependent variable of the training set represented by Y train.
And these are exactly, of course, the inputs of the fit method.
All right.
So in the flashiest of flashes, we built and trained this extra boost morale on the training set.
We only had to implement the three lines of code.
And then all the rest is something we've already done, you know.
This is the confusing matrix.
You have this code and all of your classification templates.
And finally, of course, we apply the exact same scale that we implemented just before in the previous
section to apply K4 cross-validation.
So we are ready to run this code.
But just before we do it, I just want to show you the way to build an x gibi regressive model, you
know, an extra boost model for regression.
It's actually super simple.
The only thing you need to change here is just, of course, name of the class, which wouldn't be extra
B classifier, but X, g, b.
And as you will see, x, g, b, regress.
And then, you know, you would just replace classifier here by regress.
And then that's it.
This way you will build a regression model based on extra boost.
All right.
But let's go back to our X to be classifier class.
And there we go.
Now we can just save this implementation and do a run, all to find out if XY boost is going to steal
the throne of the decision tree classification model for this particular dataset.
So quick reminder.
With the decision tree classification, well, we got the best accuracy and the highest one of ninety
five point nine percent.
And now let's find out if we can beat this with the extra boost moral trained on the exact same data
set.
All right.
So basically, we're ready now.
We're just gonna do a run all by clicking runtime here and now.
Are you ready?
I bet you are.
So let's do this.
Three, two, one, go.
All rise.
All the cells are running now and we get an impressive accuracy of ninety seven point eight percent.
When I was telling you that we're gonna end this journey on a good note.
Well, I was choosing my words very, very carefully indeed.
That's just an amazing accuracy.
You know, there are only three incorrect predictions on such a sensitive problem, you know, cancer
prediction.
Well, this result is just amazing here.
Indeed, we almost get 98 percent accuracy with these only three incorrect predictions.
That's just amazing.
But now we have to check one less thing because, you know, maybe we got lucky on this single test
set.
Maybe that single test was more favorable to actually boost than the other classification models, which
could explain why X equals was number one.
And the only way to check this is by actually computing other accuracy's on other test set.
And this is exactly what K4 cross-validation is about, and that is why this is the last cell of this
implementation.
And we also have the results for this, which is, as we can see, still an amazing accuracy of ninety
six point fifty three percent.
This is, of course, an average accuracy obtained as a result of the average of 10.
Different accuracy is measured on 10 different test sets.
And besides, we have a rather small standard deviation of only two percent, which is good.
Once again, for this sensitive problem of cancer prediction.
So, yes, extra boost is definitely number one here.
And that's why, my friends, I'm just super happy that we end on this good note with this final powerful
tool that you get in your machinery and took it because now you can start your post machine journey,
you know, for your career in full confidence.
And about that.
That will be my final words to you in this course.
I wish you sons of great success in your future machinery project.
I wish.
You are the talented data scientist who brings the strongest insights and the highest value analysis
to your team and to your clients.
Now you're totally able to do this.
Thanks to your complete and powerful machinery, two kids with D you, you're totally able to smash
your future measuring problems.
So once again, I wish you the best.
And I look forward to seeing you in another course for a new data science journey.
And until then, of course.
Enjoy machine learning.