Hello and welcome to this art tutorial.
So we did a big part of the calling process we started by creating this corpus here.
Then we put all the words in lowercase us then we removed all the numbers all the punctuation and we
also removed all the non-relevant words.
And finally we took the roots of all the words in the 1000 reviews.
So all these steps considerably simplified the words and the reviews.
So thanks to all the steps here all these simplifications.
Well our final sparse matrix of features will get a much smaller number of columns.
So that's good for our algorithm because it reduces sparsity.
And now we have one final little step to do that will not be done to simplify it even more the corpus.
But that just consists of removing the extra spaces because by doing all these simplifications here
well you know we remove some things and those things that were removed could actually have been replaced
by a space and that would cause extra space in the review.
And therefore if we want to have perfectly clean reviews we must remove these extra spaces if we remove
all the extra spaces where all the columns in our final sparse matrix of features will only contain
the worst that are relevant and will not contain any space or anything else.
So that's what we'll remove in this final step of the cleaning process.
So let's do it again it's going to be very simple will copy this line here.
Copy and pasted below and replace stemed document here by strip whitespace.
Here it is pressing enter and all good final step ready to be executed.
And therefore the whole cleaning process is ready to be completed.
So before we execute this line let's have a look at a review that now has an extra space.
I remember that when we removed the number in the review 841 Well we got an extra space.
Here it is.
You know before the review was for 40 bucks ahead I really expect better food.
And when we applied the remove numbers here to the Corpus Well the number 40 here disappeared.
But it actually didn't disappear was just replaced by this extra space here because indeed we can see
that we have two spaces between four and bucks.
And what we want to get is only one space here.
So we're just removing the extra space here so let's check it out.
When we select this final line of code of our cleaning process well let's make sure that this extra
space in the 841 disappears this time for good.
All right so I'm going to press commenter's enter to execute.
Here we go.
And now let's have a look at the review.
841 So let's president of error here to find it.
Here it is we're going to get the new version of the review 841.
After we applied this strip whitespace to the corpus.
So let's do it press and comment here.
Well not only that space was removed we can see that we don't have any extra space here but also we
get all the other steps of the cleaning process since indeed we can clearly see that the non-relevant
words were removed.
So the non-relevant words where for example four.
So this was removed and then a.
I think that's all.
Yes.
As you can see a was removed here and I was removed here.
OK so that's the first thing we see very clearly.
And the second thing we see very clearly is the stemming of course because we hardly recognize the words
here.
Box was replaced by Buck.
No it's not only about the past tense of verbs it's also about the singular and plural of nouns.
So Buck's became black and head was not replaced because the root of head is head.
So that's why we kept head here.
And then really really the Y became really with an eye.
So that's how are simply interpreting the route.
So that's OK.
It's not a mistake.
And finally I expect better in food were not replaced because you know these are kind of already the
roots of the words.
And we cannot really simplify the words more.
All right so that's a good example we can clearly see what happened here.
And for what we just did here was the strip wide space.
We can see that this extra space here was removed.
Well there is still a space here but you know before there was the four and two spaces between four
and Buck.
And then after the upward step the four was removed.
So we can still see a space here before buck but that's actually one space instead of two.
If we want to get even more convinced where we can see that we have next space here between love and
place.
This review is the first review in the previous version of the corpus before we applied the strip whitespace
here.
And so now I will see that if we have a look at the first review of the new version of our Kobus Well
this extra space here will be removed and we will get only one space between love and place instead
of two hear that check it out.
Here we go we can clearly see that we have only one space here instead of two spaces here.
All right.
So good.
Removing the extra spaces worked properly and so we are done with the cleaning process.
So great.
That means that now we are ready to build the sparse matrix of features.
We'll do that in the next tutorial.
And until then enjoy mission early