Hello my friends and welcome to this new practical activity for Decision Tree classification.
Wow we're almost at the end of this part 3 classification and the very thing I suggest is to recap on
what we obtained so far with our previous classifiers.
So with logistic regression we got an accuracy of 89 percent with K and we got the best accuracy of
93 percent with SVM with a linear kernel we got an accuracy of 90 percent with kernel SVM with a nonlinear
kernel we got again inaccuracy of 93 percent and with knife base we got an accuracy of 90 percent therefore
the two best models we had so far are key and and kernel SVM.
And so now the big question is can we still beat that with one of our two classification models that
we have left.
Decision Tree classification or random forest classification and this new section we are about to implement
decision tree classification.
So let's do this.
But first let us make sure everyone here is on the same page.
I gave you the link to this whole folder right before this tutorial.
Any Oracle.
So make sure to connect to it.
And now please follow me into Part 3 classification to implement.
This time the decision tree classification model.
And as usual we're gonna start with python.
This Python folder contains two files the implementation of the decision tree classification model in
IP one format and the same data set social network at that CSB which contains informations of 400 customers
of a car dealership which just released a brand new luxury SUV and the strategy team gathered this data
to understand which customers buy the most the SUV in order to target them with ads that will be posted
on social networks.
So each of these rows correspond to different customers and for each of these customers we have two
features The Age and the estimated salary with which we are going to predict that have been viable purchased
which takes binary values zero meaning that the customer didn't buy the SUV and won meaning that the
customer but the SUV.
All right let's do this.
Let's see if Decision Tree classification can beat the previous accuracies we've got so far meaning
93 percent.
So without further ado let's open that with Google collab.
Choose your favorite.
And I'm gonna put it here because this is our next classification model.
All right.
Perfect.
So once again this implementation results from that classification template we made in the first section
of this part 3 when we implemented logistic regression moral and therefore the only cell that changes
here in its implementation is as usual that cell where we build and train the classification model right.
This cell here and all the rest you know all the other cells are exactly the same as in the logistic
regression code template or you know the classification code template.
Because indeed we use the same variable names classifier and then extraneous test.
Everything is the same except this cell.
So once again we're going to re implement this cell but to do this we need to create a copy because
this is an read only mode.
So right now we're going to create that copy on which we will be able to re implement that cell.
All right.
So let's crawl down again to find that cell where we build and train the dysentery classification model.
Now let's put it in the trash immediately because I don't want you to see you know the name of the class
because indeed I want you to find it on your own.
So there you go.
Now is the time you press pause on this video to find the right class name that allows us to build the
decision tree classification model.
You will have to either look for it directly through an online search or the other option and the one
that I recommend to you because I want you to get familiar with the cyclotron API.
That other option is to look for it inside the cyclone API.
And this is exactly what we're going to do together in two seconds after you press buzz and.
All right let's do this.
So let's go to the cyclone API to find the class that allows us to build a decision tree classification
model.
All right.
So API and by memory you know let's suppose actually that I have no idea of the module or even the class
that builds this decision tree classification model.
So here I'm scrolling down you know to observe the different modules maybe it is.
And symbol methods because you know I know that random forest we built you know the random forest regret
her in part to random forest is an int symbol method but no here we don't see the decision tree so let's
scroll back down again which makes sense right.
Because the decision tree is just a single model.
It is not an ensemble of models.
All right.
So many fall learning metrics.
No no.
You know it's really important that you get familiar with this why.
Because the more you get familiar the more expert you'll become and the better you will juggle with
all the machinery and tools.
You know besides the one I I'm giving you in this course.
All right so here I am scrolling down more.
All right repricing random projection semi supervised learning support vector machines decision trees.
There we go.
You know usually the module you're looking for in the Sigler API will have the same name here as the
model you want to build right.
And you know this is organized in alphabetical order.
So that's why I wanted you to do this exercise.
It's actually very easy to find what you want.
All right decision trees and now.
Which one do we want to get among these.
Well that's of course the first one you know that was the one we used in part two regression but now
we're doing classifications so we want a decision tree classifier class.
All right.
So now why do we have to do first.
Well let's do you know what we have to do anyway which is to import that class.
And so I'm coupling this and then back in my copy we're going to create a new code cell we're going
to paste that and once again we're going to start from the cycle learn and then the tree module by cycle
learn and from that tree module we're going to import that decision tree classifier.
So that's the first step.
Right.
You know it by heart now and now the second step I don't even have to tell you it is of course to create
or a classifier object which will be created as an instance of this decision tree classifier class and
which will represent nothing else than the decision tree classifier model.
All right so here we add some parentheses and now the second question is what do we have to input here
as parameters you know if this decision tree classifier class let's see let's go back to the documentation
the singular an API and.
Well this time we actually have a lot of parameters.
So if you want you can read all of them.
Their description in case you know you want to tune later on a decision tree classification for one
of your future machinery models.
But in our case and this is just in order to be aligned with what you learned in the intuition lecture
by Kiril you know in order for you to be aligned with the theory.
Well we will just change one you know default value of the parameters which is this one criterion.
So the default value of criterion is Ginny.
But with respect to what you learned in the theory with Gabriel's intuition lecture we're going to choose
an entropy criterion.
Right.
This is what you learned in the intuition lecture.
So the criterion is of course the function to measure the quality of a split and that quality is measured
by entropy at least what we're going to choose here.
Okay.
You know remember entropy for the information game.
All right.
So that's the only thing we want to input here all the rest.
We're going to keep busy for values.
Feel free to read them if you need to learn more.
But that's the main parameter.
That's mostly what we have to select here.
And then remember that we will also add a random state parameter to make sure that we have the same
results displayed in our notebook.
All right let's do this criterion equals in quotes and trippy.
Perfect.
And then the second one random state parameter that we set equal to zero.
Great.
And now final step you know exactly what to do.
We take our classifier and from this classifier we call the fit method to train our decision tree classifier
on the training set that is composed as is expected by the fifth method of X train and Y train exactly
the same as before.
And now once again we're done very efficiently with this implementation.
So I can't wait to see results.
I don't think we will beat the accuracy record but let's see we never know.
So let's click this for the button here and then you know right now it is connecting to a runtime to
enable file browsing so that you know we can access your files on your machine and in a second we should
be able to get the upload button.
There we go as resource upload.
And so that's the right data set.
Let me show you the path again.
That's the whole machinery it is at folder.
Please find it on your machine.
And then we're going to go to page three classification then Decision Tree classification in Python
and then social network ads.
That's yes.
All right.
Let's press OK.
And now here we go.
We are ready to run all the sales by clicking this runtime button and then run.
Oh all right.
And nowadays training decisions reclassification moral.
Here we go we have it now.
You know with all the default values of the parameters except criterion which we set equal to entropy
then what about that new result.
Great.
We got the right prediction remember that customer of age 30 an estimated salary eighty seven thousand
dollars didn't buy.
In reality the SUV was predicted not to buy it either.
Perfect.
Then when the test results we indeed get a lot of good predictions except some incorrect ones here for
example and then.
Well it looks actually pretty good.
Maybe you know we will be the accuracy.
That's another one.
All right.
Another one.
And OK let's see.
OK.
Because you know there is actually also when you scroll up some more prediction.
But let's see.
I'm very curious actually maybe I spoke too fast.
We're about to find out right now with the confusion matrix.
I ready.
The accuracy of the decision tree classification model is 91 percent.
Wow.
OK.
So it's actually in the podium you know right after K. and in a kernel SVM which got the best accuracy
of 93 percent.
Wow.
That's really good actually.
This is really a good sign for running forest because random forest is basically a team of decision
trees making the predictions and you know how Team Spirit always improves the results.
So we might have a chance to beat the record accuracy with random forest.
So that's pretty exciting.
And now when visualizing the trends that results which we already got know the execution was not too
long.
Let's see what it looks like.
Wow OK.
So that's pretty different as before.
And no wonder why it got pretty good accuracy because indeed it looks like it was able to catch you
know the little observation points that were really hard to get by either a straight line you know with
linear classifiers or a nice curve like with Colonel SVM or knowledge base.
Here we actually play with this whole grid into smaller sub grids and that's because you know we have
all these splits in the decision tree classification algorithm.
So no wonder why we get all these sub grids and therefore we get separate friction regions.
It's really interesting that captures very well the observation points.
So it catches all the red customers here who didn't buy in reality the SUV.
It catches also all these green customers who but in reality the SUV.
And it catches you know these very hard to catch customers here by creating these sub grids of the grid
with the right predicted regions.
So you see how it got that good accuracy.
It really tried to catch everything even for example these green points that were cut among all these
red points.
OK.
These red customers OK.
But that's.
Be careful.
The training set you know on which the model was trained.
Let's see what happens with the test.
And we already know that we will get good results because we already know that accuracy on the test
is 90 percent but still let's see what we get with new observations on which the model wasn't trained.
All right.
This is what we get and actually here we see things more clearly.
This is the brain region you know which funnily was a good fit for the training said we're here is not
catching anything.
You know neither red customers or green customers here seem to be too incorrect predictions you know
because they fall in the green region then here.
That's all good.
You know that's all the customers of small age and small estimate salary which therefore won't be likely
to buy the SUV as it is the case here.
And then all these green points are correctly predicted.
This one is incorrectly predicted.
So indeed we have our 10 incorrect predictions in all this.
But there you go.
You know if I didn't see the accuracy First I would be afraid that we have some overfishing here.
But no it doesn't seem to be the case even with new observations of the test set.
You know we get great predictions.
But now what I really want to see you know what I really want to find out is the final accuracy of our
final classification model because if we got these great results with a single tree let's see what we're
going to get with a team of trees which is exactly the principle of random forest.
So really I can't wait to see you in the final section of this course.
Random Forest classification because we might have a chance to beat that record accuracy of 93 percent.
Let's find out about this next practical activity.
And until then enjoy machine learning.