Hello, my friends, and welcome to this new practical activity on this time dimensionality reduction,
which is not a branch of machinery, per say, but a very important technique to know how to handle
when you work with big datasets, you know, huge datasets with many features.
And you know, for which you would like to reduce to complexity by reducing the dimensionality.
And this is exactly what dimensionality reduction is about.
So in this new part, part nine dimensionality reduction, we will build three different models that
can perform such a task.
These are first principal component analysis, the most famous one, then linear discriminant analysis.
And finally, Colonel.
So we will build these three models, one for each section.
And now we're about to start with the first one principal component analysis.
But before we start, let's just make sure everyone here is on the same page.
I gave you the link to this for the right before this material in the articles.
And make sure to connect to it.
And now we should be on the same page or we're gonna go into part nine dimensionality reduction.
All right.
And as I told you, you have the three sections corresponding to each of the models.
And we're going to start with principal component analysis SPCA.
And as usual, we're gonna start with Python.
And then despite and for there, you will find two fouls as usual.
First, the implementation in IPY in B format, which now once again, we will be able to run on Google
collaboratory because we will work with a classic dataset.
And speaking of which, here is a dataset wine.
That's GSV.
So let's open it and let me explain what this is about.
All right.
So actually, first you notice indeed that we have many features.
I did not take a dataset with hundreds of features because then we would, you know, get lost in dataset.
So I just took a dataset with more than 10 features.
And of course, these are all the features from here, alcohol to this one pro line.
And as you can guess, each feature gives a certain information of a certain wine, right.
Each row corresponds to a wine.
And for each wine, we have diverse information, diverse features, characteristics of the wine, the
alcohol level, the malic acid.
I'm not an expert of wines, but these are some wines characteristics.
Ash.
L. Kennedy.
Magnesium 2s or Fennell's flavonoids anyway.
So you see, you have many wine features and for each of these wines.
Well, there we go.
I'm about to explain the dependent variable for each of these wines.
We have the customer segment.
You know, that's the last column to which the wines belong.
Okay, so let me explain what happened in terms of business.
First of all, this is a data set I took from the UCI and male representatives.
So all the credits go, of course, to this amazing platform of data set.
However, in this dataset, I just changed the last column customer segment to make it more business
wise, you know, to make this case any more a business case study, because a scenario is the following.
Let's imagine that this dataset belongs to a wine merchant with many different bottles of wine to sell
and therefore a large base of customers.
And this wine shop owner actually hired you, as do scientists, to first do a preliminary work of clustering,
meaning that at first we had all these features without this last column customer segment.
We have all these features from alcohol to pro line.
And this wine shop owner actually asked you to perform some clustering to identify diverse segments
of customers grouped by similarities which correspond to the wines they prefer.
All right.
So each customer segment here.
And by the way, there are three of them, right?
If we scroll down, we can see that we have three different categories or, you know, clusters.
And each of these segments, well, correspond to a certain group of customers that have similar preferences
for similar wines.
And that's exactly what these segments are about.
But that was the first work.
And if you want, you can have fun and do this first work yourself.
But here we want to work on dimensionality reduction.
So there goes the second mission that this wine shop owner asked you to do.
This wine shop owner was actually satisfied with your first work, you know, identifying these three
segments.
But now the owner would like to, you know, reduce the complexity of this dataset by ending up with
a smaller amount of features.
And at the same time, this owner would like you to build a predictive model that will be trained on
this data, you know, including the feature is up to here and the dependent variable so that for each
new wine that this owner has in its Schupp, well, we can deploy this predictive model applied to a
reduced dimensionality data set to predict which customer segment this new wine belongs to.
Right.
And def.
For once, we managed to predict which customer segment this one belongs to.
Then we can recommend this wine to the right customers.
And that's exactly why what we're about to do is like a recommender system, because for each new wine
that will be in the shop.
Well, our predictive model will tell us to which customer segment it will be the most appropriate.
You know, it will be the most appreciated.
All right.
So that's the business case theory.
And therefore, you know, our predictive model will add tons of value to this owner because therefore,
if this owner manages to build a good recommender system, of course, it will optimize the sales and
therefore the profit of the business.
Okay.
So that's what the case study is about.
Now we're going to move on to the implementation, of course.
Therefore, I'm opening this file principal component analysis, which you had a choice open with either
Google Collaboratory or chapter in the book, as we did in the previous section on CNN.
But there we go.
Let's open it with Google collaboratory and enjoy a brand new implementation on it.
All right.
So here is the implementation principal component analysis.
This is an read only mode.
So as usual, we will create a copy by clicking file here and then save a copy in drive.
This will create a copy inside which we will be able to re implement, not the whole implementation
this time, because I will explain that most of the sales are sales we already did before.
You know, many times in the Classification Board and also in the first section of Part eight.
So we won't have to reimplement everything.
This would be a waste of time and mostly we rather want to focus on dimensionality reduction.
And therefore, here is what we're gonna do.
I'm going to show you the implementation, of course.
But the only cell that we will reimplement will be this one applying PCI.
So let's remove it right away.
Not the Turkcell.
Only this one.
And now I'm going to show you that indeed, you know, all the cells are super familiar to us.
Right.
Because indeed, we start by empowering the libraries that we did 100 times.
We had the three essential libraries here.
Then we import the dataset with the exact same code as the one you have in your data pre pricing template.
So, of course, here I just put the right name of the dataset, which is wine that CSP.
Okay.
Then you will recognize the next steps of the data Bressington plate, which is to split the dataset
into the training set and test set exactly the same code.
Then we apply fichus scaling as it is, you know, most of the time recommended.
So we applied, of course, on separately the training set and a test set and that closes the data pricing
phase.
Then we apply this year and that's of course, the sale.
We will reimplement together.
Then let me just remove all the outputs here so that you don't see them.
I hope you close your eyes when I just remove them.
But there you now close your eyes a little bit.
I'm going to remove that output as well, because actually the dimensionality reduction technique that
we'll use will manage to get us great results with only two extracted features.
Right.
We're not reducing the number of existing features.
We are creating new extracted features based on these existing features.
So we will get totally different new features at the end, which we call no principal components.
So we'll have principal component one and principal component to add.
But there we go.
So back to our implementation.
After applying BCA, which we will redo together, well, we train the logistic regression model on
the training set.
I chose the logistic regression model as the first model of our classification toolkit.
But I could have chosen any other ones.
But you will see that we'll get great results with this one.
But feel free to choose another classification model.
Any will work.
But notice that it is important to apply PRCA before training your classification model on the training
set.
Right.
You want to reduce to dimensionality of your data set before, of course, training it on your training
set right to training said basically is the final version of your data.
After you performed all the data repricing phase and dimensionality reduction if you want.
Okay.
So the training happens after applying your dimensionality reduction technique.
And then of course.
Well, we will make the comparison matrix.
You know how to do that.
We did it many times.
And then since our dimensionality reduction technique will get us great results with only two extracted
features, principal component one and principal component two.
Well, that will allow us to visualize a transit result in two dimensions.
Right.
Because remember that each dimension corresponds to one feature.
And we do this for the training set right here.
And the test.
Okay.
So as you can see, what I did with this implementation is something you can do in less than five.
But right now, thanks to your toolkits, right, because you just need to take the be pressing to get
to make these four cells, then you just need to grab the features going to in your data prepossessing
toolkit.
Then you just need to grab your logistic regression implementation to implement this cell.
And same for the other ones, you know, the computer matrix and same for these last two, visualizing
the transit result and visualizing the test results.
These are all cells that you have in your logistic regression implementation.
So absolutely no need to do it together again.
And therefore, we can now focus directly on this cell applying BCA.
So there we go.
We're going to create a new code cell.
And now let's implement PTA principal component analysis.
All right.
So you could almost press pause on the video now and get the right tool from the Cycler API to see how
to implement this.
That would be a good exercise.
But if you don't want to do it, it's fine.
Let us implement this right now.
And as you guess, by what I've just said, well, we're going to implement PTA using the Cycler Library.
So the first thing we'll do is start from Saikat, learn from which we're gonna get access to a certain
module, which you will find in the Sackler and API and which is called decomposed Xitian, just either
decomposition from which we're going to import, of course, a class that will allow us to build this
object, which will be nothing else than this T.S.A. tool that will apply dimensionality reduction on
our dataset.
And that class is called very simply, P.
OK.
So you can't miss it in the API BCA.
And now next natural step is, of course, to create an object or, you know, an instance of this class.
And guess how we're gonna call that object?
Well, very simply, we're going to call it object pizza.
Right.
So this is super intuitive.
And now, you know, the next step, next step is to call the pizza a class which needs to take one
essential argument.
You know, we only have to input one argument here, and you can totally guess what this argument will
be, right?
It is the final number of extracted features.
You want to end up with in your new dataset.
And that argument to choose that number is called an underscore.
Components and components.
All right.
So now the question is, of course, which number should we choose?
Right.
How do we know down to which number of features?
Extract features.
We want to reduce dimensionality of our dataset.
Well, I have a very simple answer to that question.
What I usually do is start with two, you know, two principal components.
Therefore, to extract it features and see the results, I get Indian.
And thanks to our code, you know, our code template.
We can check that very quickly and easily.
And besides, we do want to try with two, because then if we get good results with two, well, we
will be able to visualize a transit result and test it result in two dimensions, you know, in this
nice plot that we had in part three classification.
So we definitely want to start with two.
And if, you know, we get really poor results and we see on the graphics here that we can't separate
the three classes properly.
You know, remember with those different prediction regions and the prediction boundary.
Well, if we see that we have poor results on the visualizations, then we can try with higher numbers
of principal components, meaning three than four.
And at some point we'll get, you know, some extracted features that explain well enough the variance,
which is exactly what PCI is about.
Right.
It is about extracting some features that explain well enough the variance.
And once you find them, well, you will get good results even with a lower dimensionality.
Okay, so let's try was two and let's see what we'll get.
But I already told you that we'll get amazing results.
Therefore, there you go.
And components equals two two principal components.
Or in other words, two extracted features.
Okay.
So that's four object.
And now the next step, of course, is to apply this object to our training set to reduce the dimensionality
of our training set in order to ease the learning process of the logistic regression model.
But also, we will have to apply it on the test set, because remember that the predict method that
we will call here has to be called on the exact same format of data as the one that was used for the
training set.
So as long as you apply some transformations like data preprocessing or dimensionality reduction on
your training set, well, you have to do the same on your test set.
However, be careful exactly as feature scaling.
We will have to apply the fit transform method on the training set, but only the transform method on
the test set.
And that's always for the same reason that because we want to avoid information like it on the test
set.
Right.
The test set is supposed to be new.
Observations like data on which we deploy our model in production and therefore we're not supposed to
fit our scalar or, you know, feature extractor objects on the test set.
We can apply them to transform them.
Right, because they were fitted on a train set.
But we can't fit them again to the test head because that would be like trying to get some hints of
information from the test set that we're not supposed to have.
That's exactly what information leakage is about.
So there you go.
I said everything.
Now you can press pause on this video to finish this implementation of BCA.
And in two seconds, I'm going to implement with you the solution.
All right.
I hope you did well.
Now let's do it together.
So, as we said, we want to play this piece of objects separately on the strings in two sets of first.
I'm going to take X train.
All right.
Which I'm going to update by applying this piece, a object from which I'm going to call it fit transform
method on this all the version of X train, meaning before the transformation of PTA.
And so here what happens technically is that the fit part of this fit transfer method will get all the
information it needs from X train to apply principal component analysis.
And then, of course, the transformed part of this fit transfer method will apply the transformation
itself to extract the principal component features.
OK, so that what it means technically and now.
Well, that's the same actually for excess on copying this pasting in here and replacing here X train
by excessed, then extra in here again by X test and only applying the transform method.
And there we go my friends.
This implementation is already over.