Hello my friends.
All right let's do this.
Let's start this implementation.
So the first step is of course to implement the data repricing phase and it will be slightly different
than what we did before.
Because we will only use actually from our data pricing template this code sale where we import you
know the widely used libraries like num by metallurgy and vendors and then only this line of code you
know to load the data set and that's it.
Then we won't create a matrix of features or debate in vivo vector because here we're doing a totally
different thing.
Association rule learning and we don't have to split the data set into a training set a test because
we will directly learn all the rules through the whole dataset.
Okay.
So right now we just want this first you know to import the main libraries and then we'll get that line
of code to import the data set.
So here I am creating a new code cell I'm importing this and then we can load the deficit.
However there is something important you should know about this a primary implementation it is the fact
that for the first time we won't use psychic learn.
And fortunately the site learn library doesn't include some classes or functions on a primary.
Basically it doesn't include the primary model.
Therefore we're not going to use cycle learn to train the model who will actually use another library
which is called a binary you know a binary that P Y is actually a Python implementation containing all
the algorithm of the primary model.
And that's what we will get you know and use to train our primary model here on the whole dataset but
exceptionally because you know Google collab contains most of the libraries and packages pre installed
but here exceptionally Google cool app doesn't include that aspiring module.
So we will actually have to install it.
And this is very good that you see this because you will encounter this situation sometimes you know
rarely but sometimes.
And so you need to know how to install a certain package or a certain library from the web you know
from online.
What we'll do now is we will enter a command you know Pip comment which will download first the by refiled
from the Internet you know through a link and then will install it inside this particular notebook.
All right.
We're me to show you.
Let's do this.
So we're actually going to implement this right before you know importing the main libraries usually
the packages are installed as a first step.
And to do this we need to start with an exclamation mark.
Then Pip you know that's the pip.
Commander allow us to install packages Then very simply Well speaking of installing packages.
The next thing to enter here is install and then you simply enter the name of that library or module
that you want to install in our case.
As we said it is a priory.
Be careful it is not a primary.
It is a primary like that AP White or I.
OK.
So exclamation mark pip install a pyre.
All right.
Now let me show you what it does.
As I said it's going to download it first and then it will install it inside a notebook.
So here it is finding it on the web and very soon we will see in the output for download.
All right.
There we go.
The download is starting now collecting a pirated downloading it from the link and then installing it
and then you know successfully installed a pirate.
So it just takes a few seconds and this is the version of this Barry package.
One on one point too maybe you'll get a different one you know if you take this course way after I recorded
this tutorial.
All right so good.
Now you know how to install a package within Google collab but worry most of the packages and including
the deepening one like tens of flow are already pre installed.
Okay good.
So now.
Well let's import the libraries now as we are here and now let's implement the data processing phase.
So let's create a new code cell then as we said we will just get that first line of importing the data
set in our data processing template and we're going to paste that right here in our copy and that's
it.
That's all we'll get from the template and now we will adapt and make it 100 percent customized to the
Priory model.
All right.
So first let's just replace the name of the data set here by the right name which is remember market
on the score basket on the score optimization.
Okay.
And now that we did this let's think of the right thing to do which is to upload the data set here.
Oh good.
So let's click upload.
All right.
Then make sure to find you know that machine learning is at Curves and data sets folder on your machine.
And if you haven't downloaded yet you can download it right before this tutorial at the bottom of the
Oracle.
All right.
So let's go inside and let's go to part five association rule learning then primary and python.
And there we go.
Let's select market basket optimization.
Let's kick open click okay and it will load it.
And there we go we have it.
Don't try to open it because it is actually very big.
And Google I won't allow you but you know if you want to have a look at it you can go back to the folder
and you know just double click it here.
Right and you can see it very well and see all the transaction.
Okay so we'll actually leave it like that in case we want to see it.
And now back to our implementation.
Let's see what we have to do next.
So we already loaded the data set as append this data frame.
However we have to be careful with something look at the data set again and notice something.
Notice that you know on our previous data set the first row here of this next one here contains actually
before the names of the columns.
Right.
For example if we take our social network add data set in part three classification Well remember this
first row here had for us the age the name of the first column and then the estimated salary which was
the name of the second column and then the name of the dependent variable purchased.
And here in this particular data set.
Well you know we don't have names of columns because each of these elements here correspond to just
different products.
OK.
So there was no need to name any of these columns and therefore here we need to add something in our
read on this course as we function to tell that the first row doesn't contain the names of the column
because if we don't say this.
Well actually it will not take that first transaction because it will think that this first row are
just names of the columns.
We have to specify this and the way to specify this and it's good that you know this trick in pandas
is just add another parameter in this read on this course as we function which is header and we set
it equal to none.
Right.
So that we can specify that indeed there are no headers meaning no column names.
OK.
That's what it means.
So now you know this.
And therefore it will take into account you know it will take the first row of this market basket optimization
dataset containing all the transactions.
And what does it will take the first transaction.
All right good.
So that was the first step but then we actually have another big step and that has to do with the fact
that when we will train the Priory model on the data set.
Well we will use a certain function that is actually called a priory.
And of course that function will take as input the data set.
But the thing is that it expects this data set to have a certain format and that format is unfortunately
not attendance data frame.
Therefore we have to recreate the data set from this original Benton's data frame so that it can have
this format expected by the primary function which will train the primary model on the whole dataset.
And so now the question is what is this format what that format is simply a list of transactions you
know instead of having the data set as a penny's data frame we want to have the data set as a list of
transactions.
You know the transactions listed one by one with the different products purchased by the customers.
And that's exactly what we have to do now we have to create that list.
And the first step to create that list is actually to initialize it as an empty list because then in
order to create that list we will have to populated with the different transactions of the data set
and the way we will do this is of course with a for loop you know for loop iterating all the 7500 transactions
of the data set so as to populate it.
Okay.
So let's do this first.
Let's initialize that list.
We will call it transactions and we will initialize it as an empty list.
All right.
So so far it is just an empty list.
And now we will start a for loop to populate this list of transactions with all the transactions contained
in that and this data frame dataset.
Okay.
So as we make that loop you will totally understand what we are doing.
So for then classic iterator variable I know which will take all the values from zero to 7500.
But remember that the upper bound of a range is excluded.
So we'll actually have to go up to seven thousand five hundred one.
Therefore here this iterated variable will go in the range from zero to seven thousand five hundred
and one.
All right.
There are actually seven thousand five hundred and one transactions because we start from zero and not
7500.
Right.
We can check it out very quickly.
No here we start from 1.
And when we scroll down we go down to let's see.
Yes seven thousand five hundred and one.
That's the exact number of transactions.
All right.
So all good for the range.
Now don't forget the colon.
And now we begin to follow up and well you know building this list of transactions is very easy we will
just use the append function which means add and which will simply add the different transactions of
the dataset one by all right.
It's a very classic way to build a list.
You know you use the append function to add your different elements one by one.
So let me show this to you very simply what we need to do here is take our transactions list OK from
which we're going to call this planned function which is a pre-built function of a python list.
You know python has all these pre-built functions and inside.
Well we're going to add the transaction but we have to add it in a pair of square brackets because it
will contain you know all the different elements you know all the different products purchased by the
underlying customer in the transaction.
And this transaction must be created as a list of products.
And that's why we have these new pair of square brackets to make that transaction a list of products.
So in the end we are actually creating a list of lists you know each transaction in the big list of
transactions is actually a list.
Right.
And so now there is a little trick but which is good that you know it is a single row for loop because
now actually we need to do a second for loop to you know get all the products of each transaction.
So let me scroll back up into the first full loop we'll go from this transaction to this one to this
one to this one down to the last one at the bottom.
Seven thousand five hundred one.
But then we need to do a second for loop which will loop over the different products in each transaction.
So you know it will add this product than this one and this one than this one.
And since the maximum number of products in one basket is actually 20 you know I put this first transaction
at the top so that we can have the maximum size of the basket which is 20.
And therefore what we'll do now is the second for loop that will iterate from zero to 20.
It will start from zero here.
You know that's the index of the first gone and then it will iterate to this one then to this one and
to this one up to the final index which is index 19 actually because it starts from zero.
There are 20 columns.
So it goes up to the index to 90.
OK.
So that's the second for loop and that's what we'll do right away inside this pen function to add all
the different elements in each transaction.
And for the transactions that don't have 20 elements.
Well that's totally fine.
We will still iterate up to the end you know up to the index 19 but we'll just populate the list with
nuns you know nuns values which mean empty so that our model will understand that the transaction here
only has three product.
OK.
So we can totally iterate up to 20 and therefore let's start this second follow up here.
For now we need to take another iterator variable which we'll call naturally J for j in the range from
0 to be careful not 19 but 20 because the upper bound is once again excluded.
So from 0 to 20 then what we will do and that's the syntax in a single row for loop.
We have to do what we want to do with this for loop at the beginning you know before the Fourth and
what we want to do is just get that product in the transaction.
Well from the index 0 to the index 19 and to assess this product well we will of course use our data
set and play with the right indexes to get the right product.
All right.
So here is the call first.
The data set okay.
And now let's add some brackets to add you know the index of the row and the index of the column that
contains that product.
We want to include in this transaction.
So first according to you what will be the index of the row.
Well that will be of course I because I iterate through all the rows of the data set and therefore now
we're dealing actually with that particular transaction of index I which were bending into that transactions
list and therefore the row of the data set we are at right now is exactly high.
OK I will start from zero.
It will first get that transaction.
Then it will be equal to ones which will get that transaction.
And then this one and this one etc..
All right.
And so now we're dealing with a particular transaction of a particular row.
And that's exactly the index of the data sets we need to input here.
And now for the column which index you think it's going to be.
Well that will be of course that index you know which iterate through all the columns of actually the
transaction.
Right.
J we'll go from 0 to 1 to 2 to 3 to 4 up to 19.
And therefore here the index 1 4 column is of course J.
All right.
So very good.
But now we need to add one final thing you know unfortunately we can not directly access the sale of
row in column J in the data set in order to access the sale we just need to adhere to that values because
that's the part of that dataset structure.
You know this is an advanced structure by pen does that allow us to get access to the cells.
All right.
So good that you know this and now we're almost ready.
We almost have everything.
The only thing that's left has again to do with you know a certain expectation of the future a primary
function which we'll use to train our primary moral.
It is the fact that all the elements in the list must be strings they must be strings.
Otherwise the Priory model won't be able to learn the rules and to make sure that these you know values
we populate inside each of our transactions in our list.
Well in order to make sure that these are strings we can force it this way by putting that into the
string function as we are which will take us input exactly these elements meaning these product of the
transactions.
All right.
Now we make sure that the products are strings in actually quotes and this will give exactly what the
primary model is expecting as the format of its inputs.
Good.
Perfect.
So now we're done with data progressing as I told you it's a bit different than before but now you know
that for the primary model you have to just create a list of transactions and make sure that all the
elements in each of your transactions are strings perfect.
So now let's execute this sale because we're ready.
Let's hope we making a mistake play running this cell and all good.
Perfect.
It just ran successfully.
Now we have this list of transactions containing all the same transactions as in this data set.
But in the format of a list.
Good.
So now we're going to take a little break because then comes the real big important step training the
primary moral on the data set and to do this we'll call this a primary function that will take as input.
Exactly this list of transactions that is now correctly populated in the right format to train the primary
model on the data set.
So take a little break and as soon as you're ready let's implement that next step together.
And until then enjoy machine learning.