All right my friends.
Are you ready to train the Priory moral on the whole dataset.
Well I bet you are.
Because indeed we actually did the most difficult part you know the most difficult part was to make
that transactions list containing all the different transactions of our dataset you know the seven thousand
five hundred one transactions we all put them into this transactions list with strings for each of the
products.
And these transactions list will be the input of the primary function which will use right now to train
the primary model on this data set.
And so that's what I'm talking about.
Most of the job is done because now the only thing that we have to do is just call this a primary function
from this a binary package which we installed in the first cell and call that function with some relevant
values of the parameters.
And that will be most of the reflection we'll have when building and training this primary model.
All right.
I'm ready.
Let's do this.
Let's create a new code cell.
So the first thing to do will be to import effectively that a primary function because so far.
Make sure to understand that we only installed the parry package but we haven't importers anything.
The only libraries we import were named by Matt Blunt lib and pandas.
So now we need indeed to upload this primary function and its primary function belongs to a binary package
which we installed first.
Therefore we need to start from that a binary package.
There you go from which we import.
That's a primary function.
All right.
There we go again a primary and now.
Now we can call that function.
All right.
So first thing to understand is that this function will actually return the rules you know not only
rule change that your primary model on the data set but also the same time this function will indeed
train the sobriety model and in the end return the final rules.
You know with the different supports confidences and lifts and therefore since we are now ready to call
this function and since this function returns the rules well let's create a new variable here which
we're simply going to call rules.
All right.
And that will be the output of that function.
And speaking of that function well let's call it right now a primary.
That's the function.
Therefore I'm adding some parentheses and now there we go.
Let's see what parameters we have to input.
All right.
So this function takes as input some very intuitive arguments we could actually you know almost guessed
all of them the first one is of course well the dataset you know the dataset on which you're going to
train your primary model and the name for that parameter is transactions actually you know because the
primary model is mostly used to compute some correlations and association rules among transactions.
So that's actually the name of the parameter.
And of course the value for that parameter must be.
Well that same transactions list which we created in the right format right before this tutorial in
the data pricing phase.
OK.
So this is the name of the parameter and this is the name of our transactions list which is the value
of indeed that parameter.
Okay.
Good.
So that's for the first argument.
That was an obvious one.
And now according to you what would be the next argument.
Well the next argument has to do with the support of course it's going to be a simple support because
we have a support for each rule.
But what we can set is actually a minimum support you know in order not to compute all the rules but
only the rules that have at least some certain relevance.
And therefore we will set a minimum support value in order to take not all the rules but only the rules
that have a support higher than this minimum support.
All right so let's first enter the name of the parameter here which is men underscore support.
Right.
And now according to you what should we choose as a minimum support here.
Well this has to do of course with our situation you know the problem itself.
And of course some common sense.
So let's recap.
We have in total seven thousand five hundred and one transactions that were recorded over one full week.
And among these seven thousand five hundred one transactions we want to get the most relevant rules
you know the were the strongest rules of two elements.
You know with one element of the left hand side of the rule you know one product and one element in
the right hand side of the rule which is another product and we want therefore these products to appear
a minimum amount of time.
And that's exactly what the support is about.
Remember the support of a couple of products a and b is the number of transactions containing these
two drugs and be divided by the total number of transact.
So we need to see here you know for a couple of products a and b how many times per week we need to
have at least these two products in the transactions.
Well you know let's use some common sense let's say that each day we would like to consider the products
that appear in at least three transactions in a day.
All right three transactions in a day because all the products that appear in only one transaction or
two transactions you know are actually not frequent and we would not build some strong rules out of
these products.
So our common sense here is to only consider the products that appear at least three times a day.
And therefore since the 7500 and one transactions were recorded during the full week Well we need to
multiply this number of three transactions per day by seven in order to get you know that minimum number
of times we want to see these products in the transactions per week and therefore that number of times
is three times seven equals 21.
And since the support is the number of times the products appear in the transactions divided by the
total number of transactions Well the minimum support considering that we want to see minimum three
times per day the product must be three times seven divided by seven thousand five hundred and one.
All right so that's purely based on common sense you could choose another minimum support but there
you go.
That's a minimum support that goes well with our scenario you know with our business case study.
And therefore when I'm simply going to do now is just open a new tab here to quickly compute well three
as in minimum three times want to see the products appear in the transactions per day then times seven
because the seven thousand five hundred and one transactions are recorded over a week.
And therefore when calculating the support and dividing by the total number of transactions the numerator
and denominator must be in the same unit of time which is one week and then divided by seven thousand
five hundred and one.
Total transactions.
There's just press enter.
We'll get the result which is 0 point 0 0 27 and we can round that up to open 0 0 3 and open 0 3 will
be exactly our minimum support.
So I'm going to close this and I'm going to enter here 0 point 0 0 3.
Perfect.
So that's for our minimum support.
Now the next argument what do you think it's going to be.
Well you probably guess that this time we're gonna choose a minimum confidence.
Right.
A minimum confidence.
All right.
So this time what should we set as the minimum confidence should we use again common sense or should
we try some different values.
Well this time we won't do the same kind of calculation as we did for the support this time.
I'm rather going to give you some rule of songs you know which you can try when doing association will
learning so I know from the other packages you know the one from R because there is actually a great
function in art.
Do association rule learning and it has indeed a default value for the minimum confidence which is 0
point 8.
So what actually did you know for this problem is to start first with open eight but this was way too
high because open eight would require the world to be correct 80 percent of the time.
And therefore I ended up with actually no rule.
So I had to reduce the confidence so I divided by two so that I can try a minimum confidence of open
four but still I got very few rules and so I divided it by two again and thus with open two I actually
got some great rules you know not too much not too few but a dozen of them.
So that was a good choice and that's how I chose this minimum of confidence.
Therefore here for this minimum confidence we will set it equal to four point two.
OK.
Once again no rule of thumb you can try different values depending on your business requirements.
All right then next parameter I'm sure you get it as well.
That is this time the minimum lift you know that other metric which measures the quality of a rule or
the relevance of a rule.
And so now according to you what would be a good minimum lift.
Well that kind of decision to make you know you get them with experience you will see through the many
association rule learning models that you're going to build on your data sets.
That's generally a good lift is at least three you know three four five six seven eight nine you know
these are good lifts but lift below three make the rules not that relevant and therefore this is gonna
be a rule of thumb that I'm giving you here it is not based on common sense rather based on experience
and therefore I recommend to choose a minimum lift of three.
All right.
And with this minimum lift we will get good rules you know relevant rules.
OK.
So minimum lifting equals three and then we have two less arguments that are actually very very important
and in fact compulsory for our business problem it has to do the fact that you know we want to identify
the best deals of buy one product A and get another product be for free and therefore the rules we want
to get in the end must have only two products one product in the left hand side of the rule and one
product in the right hand side of the rule.
All right.
And therefore to make sure we have this one product a on the left and one for a B on the right.
Well we need to add two more arguments here which is first mean length.
OK.
And then max length where of course men length is the minimum number of elements you want to have in
your rule you know left or right and max length is the maximum number of elements you want to have in
your room left or right.
And therefore here to make sure we only have two in our rule no one on the left and one on the right.
Well obviously we need to set min length to two and max length.
Same to two.
And that's only because in our business problem we want to find these best deals of buying one product
A and get one rugby for free.
Therefore our rules must have exactly two elements.
Then imagine you wanted to find the best deals of by two products and get a third one for free.
Then you would set min length to three and max length to three and if you want to be very very flexible
on your deals like you know you could have deals with buy one product A and get one per rugby for free
or buy two breaks a and get one product be for free or you know by 10 products and get one for free.
Well in this case you would set many links to two and then Max lengths to eleven.
OK so that really depends on your business requirements your business problem.
Yeah we just want to find the best deals of two products buy one product a get one product be for free
and that's it.
And that's why we set min links 2 and Max lengths to 2 so that our rule can have only two products.
All right.
And that's it.
Well you know we're done with this a primary function which will return the rules respecting all these
values we set for the parameters a minimum support of open 0 3 which means that the products in the
rules appear at least all point 3 percent of the time.
Then a minimum confidence which means that for each product a in the left hand side of the rules well
we will have product B in the right hand side of the rule at least 20 percent of the time and then we
have a minimum lift of three.
And we have only two products in our rules.
Thanks to this mission x equals two and max length equals two.
All right so I'm ready.
I'm ready to run that sale to get the rules we won't have them displayed in the output.
Don't worry we will visualize them right after this tutorial.
In the last part.
So let's do this.
Let's play this cell.
And there we go.
Now my friends we have the rules.