Cap analysis we've talked about cap a lot.
And in fact we've talked about cap that much that I'm no longer even saying cumulative accuracy profile
because I am assuming that you're entirely comfortable with this abbreviation and the whole term and
what it means.
So let's see how to analyze the cap as we've discussed.
There are three lines that are important on the Kepcher of the blue line which is the random line when
you select your samples at random.
The red line which is our model line the and different models will have different red lines but basically
look something like that.
And the gray line which is the perfect model or when you have a crystal ball when you can select all
of the future turners or purchaser's or whatever action takers and you can select them right away on
the dot before even selecting one single person that you don't want to select.
And so these are the three main lines and how do we analyze this cap Kaveri know how to build it.
But what can we derive what insights can we derive from here.
Well it's kind of intuitive that the closer your red line is to the gray line the better you model the
closer to the blue line the worse.
So how can we quantify this effect.
Well there is a standard approach to calculate the accuracy ratio and to calculate accuracy ratios you
take the area under the perfect model or the perfect line which is color in gray here and it's called
a pea.
And then you need to take that area under the red line which is colored in red here which is a R and
then you need to divide one by the other.
So you need to divide a r by AP and then this ratio that you get is obviously between 0 and 1.
And the closer this ratio is to 1 the better the further it is away from one and close to zero the worse
.
However it can be quite complicated to calculate this area under the curve statistical tools can do
it for you.
But how can you assess the cap curve by just looking at it so visually it's not that easy to get this
quantifiable metric just by looking at the curve.
So there's a second approach and that's what we're going to discuss.
Now let's get rid of areas and instead of looking at the area what you can do is look at the 50 percent
line on the horizontal axis and look where it crosses your model and then look at where that line the
horizontal line from there crosses the vertical axis So basically how many turners will you pick up
or action takers or how many positive outcomes are you going to identify if you take 50 percent of your
population.
And in this case we can see it's around 90 percent or something like that.
And just by looking at that there is like a rule of thumb how you can assess your model based on that
X number and here it is.
Are you ready.
Here we go.
So if x is less than 60 percent the model is rubbish.
Basically it's not useful at all.
You can create a better one probably you can create a better one and you need to try again.
If your model your X is between 60 percent and 70 percent then the model is considered to be poor poor
or average and by the way these are my this is my rule of thumb.
Other people might have a different rule of thumb but this is what I go by is between 60 percent and
those and it's it's a poor model to be honest like you can.
You can do better than that.
If it's if X is between 70 percent and 80 percent that's a good model that's already where you should
be aiming for anything above 70 percent that's can deliver good quality insights to the business and
actually deliver value.
Anything between 80 percent and 90 percent like we see here is very good.
It's extremely good.
That's if you can get a model over 80 percent that is an amazing result and anything above 90 percent
up to 100.
That is just too good.
It is too good to believe and the are there is one option that there should be very careful here with
his overfitting.
If your model is showing you results like 90 percent or save for Mulshine you 100 percent then the obvious
answer there is that one of your independent variables is actually a post facto variable meaning that
it shouldn't be in the data because it's looking into the future.
The person who supplied you that variable forgot to take it out or forgot to explain to you that you
know their credit score actually is turned into zero after they leave the bank and therefore everybody
offer zero credit card obviously has left the bank and therefore your model is picking them up like
like it's super easy.
So if you have 100 percent that's definitely something or if your variables even if you have 90 to 100
percent you have to check that there could be some forward looking variables.
The other thing is overfitting you could be overfitting a model and what that means is that you your
model has been so well fit that specific data set that you supplied it that when you try it that it's
just heavily relying on the anomalies in that data set.
And when you feed it a new data set like you know in a month time or something like not not training
or not the data that you trained your model on.
We'll talk about this a bit a lot more actually in the coming tutorials but so if you feed this model
some data that you want to actually predict on then you will crash it all it won't crash it will it
won't perform as well perform you know at the 60 percent mark or something.
So that means the model is overfit it and be very careful about that.
We'll talk about overfitting more in fact in the coming to terms we will learn how to avoid that problem
.
And finally if you can get an x or this parameter to be between 90 percent 100 percent and you're not
using for looking parameters or not overfitting then give me a call because I might have a job for you
people like that are rare and I have a lot of headhunters looking for people who can do modeling like
that.
So definitely keep that in mind.
Look for it.
And then until next time happy analyzing