Hello my friends and welcome to this new practical activity where we're going to build together this
time the hierarchical clustering algorithm and the case study for this model will be the same as for
k means because you know the purpose of hierarchical clustering is to give you an extra clustering model
to compare to k means so that you can at least have two clustering models in your toolkit for clustering
and therefore we're going to work on the exact same data set same problem.
You know that model trying to understand better its customers by finding some patterns which are clusters
in the data.
All right so let's do this.
First let's make sure everyone here is on the same page.
I give you the link to this folder containing the whole structure of the course with all the codes and
data set in the previous articles.
Make sure to connect to it.
And now we're all gonna go into port for clustering to this time tackle the hierarchical clustering
moral.
And we're going to start with Python as usual.
All right.
So as I've just told you we're gonna work on the same data set more customers right where each row corresponds
to a customer and for each of these customers.
Well the mob gathered some info like the customer I.D. to jar male female to age the annual income and
the spending score and we're actually going to work only with these two features the annual income and
the spending score to identify these clusters.
But this time with hierarchical clustering.
All right.
So executives same and therefore let us proceed directly to the implementation.
You have it right here.
Hierarchical clustering that IP when B which you can open with either Google collaboratively as we're
about to do or if you don't like Google collaboratively you can open it with Jupiter notebook.
All right.
So choose your favorite idea.
And for Google collaboratively lovers.
Well follow me here to open this implementation in Google collab.
All right so right now it is loading the notebook you know laying out a notebook and Dario.
So that's the horrible Google clustering implementation as you can see it follows the exact same structure
as k means we first import the libraries we then imported data set exactly the same way as how we did
for k means you know we select these two columns of index three and four which corresponds of course
to the annual salary and the spending score.
So executives saying we want re-employment is together and then this time instead of using the Elbow
Method you know like with K Means Well we're gonna use the DNA program to find the optimal number of
customers.
And I will explain not only the implementation you know we will implement this together and also I will
explain how to find that optimal number of clusters in this graph.
And finally we will train the hierarchical clustering model on the data set using the agile narrative
clustering class.
And finally we will visualize the clusters exactly the same way as what we did with K Means and actually
hear the code is exactly the same.
The only thing that changes is the name of that dependent variable which we create.
Right because still with hierarchical clustering we are going to create that dependent variable.
But this time instead of calling it y k means as we did for k means we're calling it simply y HFC.
And therefore here it's exactly the same code with only that different name for that created dependent
variable.
So we want to implement this either we'll just keep the code and therefore there we go we're only going
to re implement two sales which is this one to build a Daniel gram and figure out that optimal number
of clusters and to build the hierarchical grocery model and train it on the whole dataset.
Are you ready.
Let's do this.
And in order to do this we have to create a copy of this notebook because this is in read only mode
and therefore we're going to go to file here and then click Save a copy enjoy drive to indeed create
a copy of this notebook.
Perfect.
All right.
So there we go.
That's our copy.
Now we can modify it.
Now we can re implement it but as we've just said we won't re implement everything.
We will just re-employment these two cells here first the DNA program how to build it and how to read
it.
And then of course well how to build the hierarchical clustering model on the dataset and then we keep
the other cells because they're exactly the same as in k means and if you want it's just you know remove
this that we don't see the final result.
And perfect now.
All right.
All you see here is executives same as with k means the only thing that will change are these two sales
which we will re implement together.
Okay.
Perfect.
So first step let's just execute these two for sales here and to do this we need of course to upload
the data set so let's click this further here.
Now it is connecting to a runtime to enable fibrosis you know a new computer in your machine and in
a second we should see the upload button.
There we go.
Upload and end.
Well I'm already in the Caymans folder.
But let me show you again the whole path.
So that's the folder you were given at the beginning of each section including this one higher clustering
which you could download on your machine.
So I hope you have it right now.
Otherwise you would just need to go back to the previous article and now we're all gonna go inside.
Then we're going to go to part 4 of course then Section 25 hierarchical clustering.
Then python.
And then there we go.
More customers start CSB.
This will upload the dataset into the notebook.
And so now we can run these two for sales first importing the libraries.
And now that we have vendors we can import the data set which at the same time creates this matrix of
two features containing only let's see in the dataset containing only the annual income and the spending
score.
In other words x is just these two columns here with all the rows.
Okay.
All right.
So they should be pressing face done.
Now we can focus on the heart of the higher Google Classroom model which is first to build the Daniel
gram to indeed find the optimal number of clusters.
And of course the optimal number of clusters that will result from this general gram will be the same
number as the one we found with k means meaning five clusters.
But I will explain how to read Daniel gram in order to indeed end up with an optimal number of five
clusters.
All right.
So that was introduction and as you know I like to take it step by step.
So we will implement that next step of building the Daniel gram in the next material.
So get ready.
And until then enjoy machine learning.