Right my friends.
I hope you did amazing with that new exercise which was to predict the purchase decision of a new customer
in the set.
That was the first customer who is actually 30 years old and earns an estimated salary of eighty seven
thousand dollars right.
If we have a look at our test set you know the original tested before this killing this one.
This is exactly the customer you had to input in your predict method in order to predict the chaste
decision.
All right.
And now in this material we're going to check two things that first you've got the right implementation
and the predict method and mostly the right input inside the brick method.
And secondly we will also check if the prediction is correct.
And in order to do this well we're going to have a look at why test the Portuguese decision of that
first customer is exactly this one you know because white contains all the real results here all the
real purchase decision.
And so we're going to see if indeed our model was able to make a correct prediction by predicting zero
for this first customer of age 30 an estimated salary eighty seven K..
All right let's do this.
Let's proceed to the solution.
Here it is predicting a new result.
I will leave the training.
And there we go.
So let's create a new coat sale.
And now what was the first step.
Well of course the first step was to take our classifier because of course that predict method as any
other method has to be called from the classifier object itself.
So we take our classifier object and then from this object we're going to call this predict method by
the way.
Let me show you this again.
You have other British method which are predict low probability which will return the log.
You know the logarithmic function of the probability that your prediction is one.
You know that the purchase decision is one.
And you also have to predict brother method which returns of course directly the probability that the
purchase decision is one.
All right so depending on whether you want to have directly the final prediction 0 or 1 or the probability
that the dependent variable is equal to one.
Well you had the choice between predict and predict.
OK.
So here we're going to take predict because we directly want to get the prediction whether or not that
first customer of the test set for chased yes or no the SUV.
So here we're going to add some parenthesis and now now I'm really interested if you've got this right.
What did you put inside a predict method in order to predict the purchase decision of that customer
who is 30 years old and earns an estimated salary of eighty seven thousand.
All right.
Well first of all let's remind the essential.
Any single observation inside the predict method has to be input in a double pair of square brackets.
Why is that.
That's because the British method expect from its input a two dimensional array.
And how do we create a two dimensional array with only one observation know meaning only one row.
Because what about input is a two dimensional matrix of one row and two columns where the row corresponds
indeed to that single customer.
And the columns correspond in fact to the features that age in the first column and salary in the second
column.
So there you go.
Now I've told you everything.
What you have to input here inside this second pair of square brackets which correspond to the columns.
Well you have to input the two values of these two features to age and the salary.
And therefore since our first customer is 30 years old and earns an estimated salary of eighty seven
thousand dollars well the two features here that we had input in these therefore two columns here is
first 30 and then eighty seven thousand dollars.
All right.
The debt the first thing you must absolutely do you know that you must absolutely have the right reflex.
OK.
Input your single observation within a double pair of square brackets to give the expected format of
the two dimensional array to your predict method.
All right.
That was the first thing but then not enough you had to do something else which is of course to scale
that single observation.
Right.
Because 30 years all here and eighty seven thousand dollars as the estimated salary are in the original
scale you know before applying feature scaling standardization and since our model was actually train
as we can see on X train and Y train which were just previously feature scaled.
You know that's the result of feature scaling.
Well as I told you to predict methods can only be applied to observations where the features have the
exact same scale as the one that was used for the training.
And therefore here we need to apply the transport method in order to give his world break method not
only the right format here but also the right scale.
And that's why we have to transform this single observation input in the right format into that new
scale.
And so what we have to do here is take r sc objects.
Remember that was the name of the feature scaling object which we used to apply feature scaling on both
the matrix of features of the training set extreme and the matrix of features of the tested excess.
So S.E. and then remember we call.
There it is just below the transform method.
The transform method which has to take as input this whole single prediction input in a 2D array.
All right in a second one.
And perfect.
That was my friend's dissolution and Congratulations really.
If you got this right because you had to pay attention to two things First the right format added to
the array here for your input and then transforming that input.
You know those features to get the right scale for your break method.
Okay perfect.
So now we're actually ready to run this but we'll actually get a better output you know a nicer one
if we put all this into a print.
Print that output of the brick method and now let us press play and remember let's see if our classifier
manages to predict the right outcome meaning the right Bridge's decision which according to the test
set which contains the real result is zero meaning that first customer of age 30 an eighty seven thousand
dollars estimated salary doesn't buy that new SUV.
Okay so let's press play and let's see if it is 0 and great it is 0 4.
Good job.
Our moral did amazing here on this single observation single customer.
Great.
So now we're gonna move on to the next step which will be to predict the test results so that I'm sure
you know exactly how to do.
Just make sure to figure out if you need to apply feature Skilling or not and you will get to the right
solution.
Also I would like you to please display you know the vector of predictions you know the vector of predicted
bridges decisions for the test set and the vector of the real purchase decisions of the same test sit
next to each other and you don't have to figure out how to implement that again.
Remember I want you to be efficient.
So I encourage you to take that little piece of code we made in many of the regression models to display
this efficiently.
And that's exactly what we'll do together in the next material.
So until then enjoy machine learning.