Hello my friends.
Welcome to this new practical activity on this time.
The Naive Bayes classification model.
This is our fifth classification model we're implementing in this part 3 classification.
We already implemented logistic regression key nearest neighbor is as VM and kernel as VM and so for
the best accuracy we've got with these for model is all point ninety three.
Ninety three percent which we got with both K nearest neighbors and kernel SVM.
And now we're about to implement a new classification model than a base one.
A very well known and widely used.
So you definitely want to have it in a toolkit.
And so the big question is will we beat that best accuracy of open 93.
All right so let's stop immediately because I can't wait to show this to you but just before we start
let's make sure everyone here is on the same page.
I gave you the link to this folder right before this tutorial in the Oracle.
So make sure you connect to it.
And now let's do this.
Let's start the implementation of native base.
So we're gonna go into this folder and we're gonna start with Python as usual and insiders follow you
will find two files the Navy base implementation in the IP y and B format and the same social network
adds data set which I will quickly re-explain.
So this is a dataset containing 400 customers each row here represents the customer and for each customer
we get the two features age and estimated salary with which we are going to predict that dependent variable
per taste which tells if yes or no the customer but the SUV so zero means that indeed the customer didn't
buy the SUV and one means that the customer bought the SUV.
All right.
So we're going to train a new classification model to understand the correlations between these two
features age and salary.
And that depend on verbal protests in order to predict the customers that will buy the SUV.
And once we get these predictions we will target these customers on social networks with some beautiful
ad of this beautiful car.
All right.
So that's the same story and now we're going to start our implementation either with Google collaboratively
or Uber and notebook.
Feel free to choose your favorite and I can't wait to see if we're going to beat the accuracy and I
can't wait.
Also to show you the visualization results at end.
All right so right now it is loading and laying out the notebook.
And here it is.
Here is a Navy base implementation still resulting from the same classification template which we made
in the first section of this by 3 when implementing logistic regression.
So basically all the cells here are the same as in this logistic regression implementation or classification
template.
The only cell that will change will be you know the one where we build and train the classification
model meaning this one that's the only cell that we will re implement ourselves because all the rest
is the same.
But this notebook is an read on the mode and therefore in order to re implement that cell we need to
create a copy of this notebook by clicking save a copy in drive.
And as you can see this will create a copy in which we will be able to implement that cell.
All right so once again laying out the notebook and there we go.
Here is our copy on which we are authorized to modify anything and especially that cell.
We want to implement.
So scrolling down here to find it here it is training the Navy base model on the training set.
So let's immediately remove that cell because I want you to re implement it from scratch as if we had
no idea on how to implement this.
All right let's create a new code cell and now your turn.
I want you to train your machinery independence by figuring out by yourself how to indeed build and
train that knife based more on the training set.
So of course to do this you have several options you can directly type in the search bar of Google or
being well naive based psychic learned class okay.
Or you can navigate the cycle or an API which is right here in order to find that class which we need
to build or Navy based model.
And my personal recommendation is to try it with the second option because indeed this will get you
familiar with this API and the more you get familiar with it the better.
Okay.
So please press buzz now try to find this class and then try to build this knife based model and training
on the training set and now in two seconds we will implement the solution together.
All right let's do this.
Let's build this Navy base model with psychiatry.
So the API is huge and this is organized in alphabetical order.
And so the first thing we'll try is to find you know a module called maybe naive base.
Right.
Just the name of the model.
So we will scroll down down to an you know the letter N and we'll see if we get now base somewhere or
something close to it.
Let's see linear model many for learning tricks.
We're getting close and Gaussian Mixture morals model selection multi class.
Well there is a lot of em.
Okay perfect.
Naive Bayes.
So let's kick this nice base.
All right.
And so the module indeed is named on the score base and among these models.
Well according to you which one are we going to take here.
That's a good question actually.
Well in fact the classic one and the one that you learned in the intuition lecture is of course this
one the Gaussian naïve base Gaussian and B and that's exactly what we'll use to implement are naive
base model.
All right so the name of the class is Gaussian and B.
And this time the good news is that we won't have to worry too much about the parameters because there
are actually only two parameters priors which are the prior probabilities of the classes if specified
priors are not adjusted according to the data.
So of course for this we will keep the default value of None.
Right.
We won't specify some price here and for the second one voice smoothing it is the portion of the largest
variance of all features that is added to variances for calculation stability.
The default value is 1 times 10 and the power of minus nine.
We will just keep the default value.
That's fine.
You know we will worry later about parameter tuning which indeed allows you to tune the values of your
parameters but that will be covered in pattern.
And so here very simply we will just call this class without inputting any parameters.
So that's super easy.
Let's copy this and let us go back to our implementation.
Copy 1.
Let's reset here.
Let's remove this little thing here and now you know how to adapt this.
We need to start with from you know the naive bayes module of the cycle and library.
And then here you add import.
There we go that Gaussian in B class.
Perfect.
The next step is to of course create an instance of this class which will be an object representing
exactly that native base model.
And so there we go are going to call this as usual classifier in order to be coherent with the next
sections of this implementation and mostly so that we don't have to change anything right.
Because then we call this classifier variable to predict the results and visualize the results.
So there we go.
Classify you here and then equals and then we're going to call this Gaussian and B class in order to
create.
Indeed this knife based model.
Okay perfect.
And now you know how to finish this.
We need to take our classifier again from which we're going to call the fit method which will train
this classifier on the training set composed of indeed X train and Y train.
Right.
I hope you did it even faster than me because indeed this is exactly the same as before and now you
are also independent and know how to find the information you need in the API.
Okay great.
So once again there we go that implementation is over and we're ready to get the final results.
And mostly we're ready to find out if we can beat the record accuracy you know 93 percent.
So I can't wait to see so let's do it right now.
Let's click this folder button to upload data set right.
We have to do it in order to train indeed that is based more on the training sets.
Right now your notebook is connecting to a runtime to enable file browsing.
And once again in a second we should get the upload button.
There we go.
So we're going to click it and here we are in the kernel as VM folder.
So let me show you the path once again please find your whole machinery.
It is at fault which you could download in the previous tutorial if not already and then inside.
We're going to go to part three classification then Section 18 we're making good progress here.
Native Baz then python and then social network at that CSC okay we press OK.
Here we have the data set.
Oh good.
And now now we can run everything in order to get indeed our new results so let's do this run all.
And now all the cells are running and especially this one there we go we now have our Gaussian native
based model and well let's see the results one by one starting with this ones that that's the prediction
of a single result you know that first customer of the test set of age 30 an estimated salary eighty
seven thousand dollars.
And remember in the White says the real outcome was zero meaning that this customer didn't buy the SUV
and that's the prediction which is indeed the correct prediction.
And then when predicting the test results.
Well once again we see that we have a lot of correct predictions.
All this is correct.
This is our first incorrect prediction.
Another one here and then another one here.
All correct I'll correct another one here.
Oh I'm not sure we're going to beat actually that accuracy.
We seem to have more than seven incorrect predictions at first.
I'm not sure.
But let's see let's see.
Well that's exactly what we're about to find out right now.
So are you ready.
The question is will we beat the accuracy of 93 percent which was the best accuracy resulting from both
Keenan and Colonel SVM.
And so let's see what we get with Navy base and no unfortunately we don't beat the record.
Indeed the accuracy we get with that Navy based model is 90 percent which beats indeed logistic regression
but does equally the same as the classic SVM model with a linear kernel.
All right but still I think we will get nice visualization results.
That's the code cell where we visualize the trends that result in well this time we got the results
pretty fast.
You can see that the cell is already executed.
So let's see.
I can show you that indeed the Navy base curve is pretty nice right.
It is a nice smooth curve right.
That catches well indeed.
These green customers here you know the ones who in reality but the SUV in the right green region.
But unfortunately you know it's separated two classes you know with these two operation regions a bit
large you know not very precisely and that's why we don't get an accuracy that is higher than 93 percent
but still you know we made a progress with respect to logistic regression because indeed remember that
for logistic regression these green customers here could not be well classified right because of the
straight line they fall in the red region.
And here in our knife base implementation well these green customers fall in the right region so at
least it corrected that but since here there is going to be a large margin.
Well these green customers which were correctly classified with the kernel SVM if you remember right.
These are the training set results right so I'm talking about these ones here they are correctly classified
except these two and the third one.
But clearly with Knight base well they fall into the wrong region.
OK.
But anyway at least you see the prediction curve of the night based model and mostly you see that nail
based model is clearly a nonlinear classifier.
And you know in some other situations because the knife base is causing less or refitting well in some
situations it will do better than your other models.
That's why it's always very important to try all of them.
And remember at the end of this point I will actually deploy all our models with new simplified code
templates for each model you know without all the prints and everything in order to deploy them in a
flashlight so that we can quickly figure out what is the best classification model for any data set.
You know regardless of the number of features.
All right.
So that's for the train set.
And now let's come in quickly on the test set.
All right.
This is already executed.
Perfect.
So here are the results of Navy based on the test set.
And actually we realized that here we were pretty unlucky.
You know nice base was pretty unlucky because the three predictions that it missed you know this red
customer that falls incorrectly in the green region and these two green customers that fall incorrectly
in the red region.
Well Navy Base was pretty unlucky on this one because you know they're almost on the breaks and boundary
and it is what it missed by very closely to beat the record.
And same for this one actually.
You know this one was very shortly missed.
Right.
Because it is an incorrect relation of a customer who in reality didn't buy the SUV because it's red
but was predicted to buy the SUV because it falls in the green region.
So pretty unlucky which explains the accuracy of 90 percent.
I think that if we tune a bit nice base we could beat the record.
But once again that will be important.
And now the next step will be to buy the last two classification models which belong to a branch of
machinery called and symbol models.
I'm talking of course about decision tree classification and random forest classification.
And actually with these two and especially random forest we might have a chance to beat that record
accuracy.
You know we might beat 93 percent.
So that's what on the menu for this end of Part 3.
So I can't wait to see you in the next part to build first.
The decision tree classification model.
And then finally the random forest classification.
And until then enjoy machine learning.