Hello and welcome to this art it's horrible.
So in this tutorial we are going to like PCA.
And actually I've prepared you the required package to apply this first dimensionality reduction technique
principle component analysis.
So these packages are carrots which I think we already installed.
But if that's not the case and you can check it here in package's you can see if you have carrots available
in the slice of packages.
If you don't see it here you can execute the slide without comment and this will install carrots.
So that's the first package.
Then this is to actually import this carrot package.
So we'll ask you that as well.
And we also need this other package that we installed in part 3.
Cl. the 1871 package.
So normally you should have it installed.
But that's not the case.
You can select this line and install the package.
And don't forget to ask your design as well to select it.
And now we are ready to start applying PCA.
So the first thing that we're going to do is create a new variable that we're going to call PCa that
we will use afterwards to transform our original dataset composed of our 13 features into this new data
set with the new extracted features.
So now to create this subject we are going to use a function.
This is the pre process function.
Here it is from the carrot package.
And let's now press F1 here to see all the info of this preprocess function because you're going to
see that you have some very useful parameters that allow you to apply PCA according to your goals.
For example you can specify a minimum ratio of explains variance.
You want to get that means for example if you want to reduce the dimensionality of your dataset down
to a number of features that will explain at least 60 percent of the variance.
Well you can specify this with one of the parameters of this preprocess function.
So let's have a look at the info.
That's the info and let's jump to the arguments.
So right the first argument is X a matrix or a data frame.
This is actually the data of which we want to reduce the dimensionality.
So this is going to be our training set.
So X will be the training set.
Then the next argument is method.
So method is your dimensional reduction technique.
So as you can see you have several techniques of dimensional reduction D-CA I say so these are other
methods but of course the ones that we want to use.
SPCA principal components analysis tool use method you speciate here then thresh thresh is a very important
parameter.
That's what I've just told you if you want to reduce your dimensionality of your dataset with at least
a minimum amount of explained variance well you can do it by using this Dresch parameter.
And as you can see it's a cutoff and the cumulative percentage variance to be retained by PCA.
So for example if you want your new extracted features to explain at least 60 percent of the variance.
Well you need to specify here thresh equals 0.6 60 percent but we're not going to use this thresh parameter
here because we already know what we want what we want is two independent variables because we want
to be able to visualize the training that results and the test results and that we will be able to get
with the next parameter PCA comp that is the specific number of PCa components to keep.
So that's exactly the number of extracted features you want to obtain in the end.
So he will input PCA come equals to.
So that's our training set.
Our original training set will go from having 13 independent variables the 13 original independent variables
that we have in our dataset to having two new extracted features that will explain the most variants.
And as you can see if we specify the specific parameter this overwrites thresh.
So that's why we don't need to specify the thrust parameter to specify a minimum community.
Percent of explained variance.
All right.
And then you have other parameters but we won't use them.
We actually only need our X to specify the data we want to transform to extract the new features.
The method PCa and the number of extract features we want to get eventually.
That is two new extracted features.
So let's end with the arguments.
Let's start with the first one.
X equals.
So that's training set.
Here we go.
And actually we need to specify the features and actually that's not the whole trend set because remember
PCA is an unsupervised dimensional reduction technique that means that we don't consider the dependent
variable to extract new features.
So we actually need to remove here as a dependent variable.
And remember this hasn't 6:14.
So the way we can do that is the same as we did for feature scanning.
That means we just add here minus 14.
All right.
Now PCA will be applied on all the features 13 features of our trainset perfect now next arguments next
argument is method and as we said method equals in quotes PCA.
All right then come up next argument and last arguments and as we said that's PCA comp.
So PCa and what we want is to you extract features.
All right so that creates the PCA object that will then use on our training set to transform our original
training set composed of 13 independent variables to this new training set of reduced dimensionality.
And that will contain the two new extracted features that will explain the most variants.
So let's do it.
Let's take our trainset because we're going to call this new trend set trends that as well because you
know then we have all our templates and we use this trainset variable name.
So we want to keep this trainset name.
But of course if you want to keep your original training set to set you can use other names like trainset
underscored PCA.
But then if you do that don't forget to change trainset here by Transat PCa and here tested PCA as well
and same for the confusion matrix section and especially here visualizing the 20 that results you will
need to replace trainset here.
By training said PCA.
All right so that's why we're keeping the name in order not to have to change everything.
So let's go back to training set equals.
And now let's transform this original trainset into our new trainset composed of our new extracted features
and to do this is very simple we use to predict function.
And inside we take our PCA objects come up and we apply this PCA transformation object on the original
training set that is named trainset as well.
And so by doing this this original training sets will become this new training set composed of the two
new extracted features.
So let's do it.
Let's start by creating this object and then we will transform our training sets.
So I'm going to select this line and exit executes perfect the PCL object is ready to be used on the
original training set to transform it into our new training set composed of the two extracted features.
So let's execute this as well.
Here we go.
Our new trainset is now created.
We can have a look as you can see when I'm clicking on this.
Well I have a new training set composed of to extract features and remember this tune you extracted
features called the principal components.
That's where you have PC one and PC two.
And of course we still have already been available vector the customer segments have been invaluable.
With its three labels one two and three.
All right perfect.
But now as you can clearly notice the dependent variable vector just went in first position and since
then we're going to use a template on datasets.
I mean the training set and set where the dependent variable is in the last position we will need to
put this invaluable in last position here.
And that's actually very easy.
What we only need to do is play with the indexes to put this customer segment Ben a variable in last
position.
So the method is really easy we're going to take our trainset again.
Here we go.
And then equals and then we take again our trainset then brackets and then inside these brackets we're
going to take the indexes of the columns are training set in the correct order.
We want to get.
So you're going to understand that now we're going to take a vector.
So remember in our vector It's taken with C and then parenthesis.
All right.
And inside these parenthesis we put the correct order of the indexes.
We want to get.
So let's go back to our training set.
The first column we want to get is one that should be the first column of our new training set.
And this has index too.
So here we put the first index which is to then come up and then we input the second index one to get
that is the second column and the second column is pc 2.
And this hasn't x3.
So here we input 3 and then here you put the index of the last column you want to have your training
set.
And the last column you want to have in your training set is this customer segment column because that's
the dependent variable.
And so far this customer segment has next one.
So you need to specify here this index that is 1.
And by doing this our new training set here will be the same trainset that we have here but with a new
order of the columns and that is given by this or here.
First the first and have been available that has next to then the second independent variable that has
an x 3 and eventually the dependable column that has indexed one you're going to see if I select this
line now and execute and if I go back to training set.
Now I have my first two columns as you extract features you want to.
The last column customer segment and last position as our code templates that we're going to use is
expecting it.
So that's perfect.
We can go back to PCA.
And now we need to do the same for the test set.
So what we're going to do is select these two lines copy them and just replace training set here by
test set.
Same here test set.
And same here as well two sets and eventually test it.
All right.
And that's of course the same indexes for the order you want to have.
We can check it out.
I'm going to select this line as you can see so far the test set has its 13 original features then a
fire exit you disliked it now has to you extract that features the principal components 1 and 2 but
the customer segment is in first position we want to put it in the last position.
And so to do this we exit through this line and that will do it.
If I go back to test set now the customer segment is in that position and we are ready to use the following
part of the template predictive test results make the comparison matrix and eventually that's the most
exciting part.
We will now be able to visualize a turning set result because we now have two dimensions in our training
set and tests.
So I look forward to visualizing these results in the next Statoil.
And until then machine learning.