Hello my friends.
Welcome to this new tutorial.
And now we're about to train that as we are moral on the whole data set.
After a successful data repricing phase with your new experience in feature Skilling because now you
can handle very well all the different situations.
All right so let's train that as your model on the whole data set of course because we did not do a
split of the data set between training and test sets.
So there you go.
Let's create a new coat cell.
And now let's build of course in the most efficient way that as we are moral.
So we're gonna build it with cycle learn of course.
I remind that cycle learn is the best data science library excluding deep learning because of course
we have tensor flown by torch.
But for any machinery model that is not based on neural networks.
Well psychic learns is definitely by far the best data science library and for what we are interested
in right now you know that as your model.
Well we will build it with a class called as we are as simple as that which belongs to a module of psychic
learn called SVM.
And so we have to start here from first psychic learn to assess the psychiatric library from which we
are going to get access to that as the end modules.
That's the module from which we're going to import that is the are class.
Perfect.
Now we have the class and you of course know the next natural step any time you import a class next
natural step is of course to create an object or an instance of this class.
And we're going to call that object regress or just like before.
Because this instance or object of the is your class is nothing else than that as we are regressing
itself.
You know the support vector for regression regressive so regressive.
And then of course we are going to call this class as we are at some parenthesis and this time we have
to input a parameter because indeed remember in the intuition lecture of Support Vector regression and
you will also see in the intuition lecture of the support vector machine in the next part but reclassification.
Well you actually have what we call kernels which can either learn some linear relationships and that's
the linear kernel or nonlinear relationships in your dataset which are the nonlinear kernel such as
the RPF radial basis.
I will actually show it to you right away.
You know that's the Gaussian RPF kernel which is given by this formula and I can actually show you the
plot of that kernel here it is.
So that's the Gaussian RPF kernel and then you also have some other kernels which I've prepared here
on this great Web site showing clearly the different kernels of the support vector machine but also
that as we are because as we are is nothing else than a support vector machine model for regression.
So let's see here they are.
There is the pull in the mill kernel adapted for non-linear dataset.
You have the Gaussian kernel which has a classic Gaussian function than the Gaussian radial basis function.
The most widely used one and that's actually the one we will use.
Then you have the plus one the hyperbolic tangent kernel as well.
That's a popular one Sigma in well you have all of them here.
And so if you're curious yes you can have a look at them.
But the one we will use for our implementation will be and that's the one I recommend.
Each time you experiment with an as your model and that the radial basis function kernel the RPF kernel.
And that's exactly what we have to input here in our parameters.
And so the name of that parameter is kernel.
So that's the name of the parameter and then the value we want for that parameter which corresponds
to the radial basis function has the code name in quotes are the F and that's it.
That's only what we have to input here.
So that basically creates the energy our model with the radial basis function kernel.
And so now that means only one thing that means that we already have built the model we already have
the SVR model itself.
And so now the last final natural step is to of course train that regressive on the whole dataset.
Right.
Which is also the training set.
Okay.
So let's do this.
You know exactly how to do this you know from this point it's exactly the same as before you know the
same function which is of course the fit function and which will train this as we are model on your
whole data set.
Right.
To learn the correlations between the position levels and the salaries and all this done with the radial
basis function Colonel.
All right so let's do this.
Let's train are regressive.
So we take a regressive object first and as usual we add here a dot and then the fit method which takes
as input this time not extraneous why train because we have not created a separate training set but
of course this time the whole dataset which remember was feature scaled you know both on the matrix
of features parte and the dependent variable y part.
And so that's exactly what we have to input here both X and Y.
And that's it.
Congratulations.
Now you know how to build and train and as your model after a successful date of repricing phase including
special feature scaling.
All right.
And so now we have a very interesting next step.
It is the step where we predict the new result and I'm not saying this because I'm looking forward to
seeing the result of that as your prediction.
You know compared to the polynomial regression prediction.
Know what I mean is that this next step is very interesting because it will teach you how to reverse
the scaling of your prediction because you will see that when we apply the predict method to predict
this new result well it will be returned in the scale that was used for Y.
Right.
The new skill of y after it was transformed and so we'll have to reverse this transformation will have
to reverse the scaling in order to get the original scale of y and I will teach you exactly how to do
it.
Of course you can try to do it on your own you know by looking at the documentation which method can
do this you reverse the scaling and you know if you figure it out well you should be able to predict
that salary.
But I'm warning you it's not that direct.
So there you go as soon as you're ready let us implement that solution in the next sartorial.
And until then enjoy machine learning.