Our IMF friends.
Let's do this.
Let's use the Elbow Method to find the optimal number of clusters.
So we're gonna use of course the W C S S which is the within cluster sum of squares.
I will remain what this is.
But first let's create a new coat cell to start this new step of the implementation.
All right.
So what are we going to start with here.
Well we're gonna find back our very good friend psychedelia because we will actually implement that
elbow method with a class of psychic burn which guess what is called well k means because indeed the
way we will implement the Elbow Method will actually be by running the K Means algorithm with several
number of clusters you see we're gonna run the Caymans algorithm several times each time with a different
number of clusters.
And that's why we have to call that came in.
Class that can run this algorithm already and so.
Well our first step here will be to start from cycle learn cycle learn from which we're gonna get access
to the module that contains that K Means class and that module is called cluster.
Just like that.
And then from which we are going to import well that K Means class.
Perfect.
And now what do you think the next step is going to be.
Well exceptionally this time the next step won't be to create an instance or you know an object of this
came in class because we're about to start a for loop which will run the K Means algorithm with 10 different
numbers of clusters.
So very simply we will run the Caymans algorithm with one cluster then with two clusters three clusters
etc. up to 10 clusters and therefore the way to do this is through a loop and we will do a for loop
because we know exactly the different numbers of clusters we want to try which are from 1 to 10 and
each time we run the Caymans algorithm you know with these different numbers of clusters.
Well we will compute Of course you know that famous metric and clustering which is as I told you at
the beginning W C S S2 within cluster sum of squares which I remind is defined as the sum of the squared
distances between each observation point of the cluster and its century the century of the cluster.
So we're going to compute that some of these squared distances.
And this is exactly what will be on the y axis in the graph of the Elbow Method.
You know remember the graph in the Elbow Method contains in the x axis well the different numbers of
clusters we will try from one to 10 and in the y axis it contains the WC as is computed for each of
these numbers of clusters.
And therefore here what we have to do right before starting this for loop is to create a list which
will through the for loop be populated with the successive WC yes values know for each of the numbers
of clusters and therefore we're going to call that list W C as S which we will initialize as an empty
list.
Remember that list in Python are written in a pair of square brackets.
So here in this pair of square brackets we're going to add one by one to different WC asset values for
each of the numbers of clusters.
Okay.
And now we can start the for loop.
So the way to write a full loop in Python is to start with 4.
Then we choose a name of the iterator variable which you know will be incremented by 1 each time in
each iteration of the loop.
And the classic name for that horrible is I.
And then we add in range.
And here we specify in parenthesis Well the values we want this index of the loop to take over the iterations.
And here that's very simple.
I will actually take the different values of the numbers of clusters we want to try which are from 1
to 10 included but remember ranges in Python include the lower bound but excluding the upper bound that's
actually what we see here.
You know start defaults to zero.
Okay so that's the default lower bound and stop is emitted.
Right.
It is excluded.
So that's why I also really like Google collab.
You have all the info in this little help window but I'm also here for the explanation so there you
go.
The range we have to input here is from 1 you know the first number of classes we will try and then
up to not ten but eleven because we want to include 10 and therefore we have to go up to 11 which is
excluded.
All right.
And then we add just a little color just like that and then we start to flip.
And now now can come the next natural step in know after we import this class to Damon's class because
indeed now we can create our first came into object.
Why do I say our first came into object.
That's because once again you know where you're going to create 10 different came into objects for each
of these numbers of clusters from one to 10.
So here we're creating the first K Means algorithm which will be run with therefore one cluster because
I hear starts at 1.
All right so let's create our first k means object which represents exactly the Caymans algorithm which
will be run to identify.
Well actually some one cluster.
You see what I mean and then I will be equal to two so that new came in the algorithm will be run to
identify two clusters and then a new Caymans algorithm will be run to identify three clusters etc..
Up to 10.
OK so there you go.
That's our first object which we create by calling of course the K Means class.
Be careful with the capital letters came into class.
We add some parenthesis and now we import the arguments.
So here Google collab is not helping us but no worries I'm here so I'm going to tell you exactly what
we need to input in this scheme in this class.
And if you want to do it even better well you can actually press pass on this video and look into the
documentation.
You know in this cycle learn API what you need input at parameters in this game is class.
All right so.
Press but if you want and now I'm going to tell you the solution.
So the first parameters obviously is going to be well that number of clusters we want to identify you
know when running this first K Means Algorithm represented by this first came into object and that name
of the parameter is n underscore clusters which stands for exactly number of clusters.
All right.
And this should be equal to what.
Well if you understood the way this full loop works of course the number of classes here is high which
starts at 1 then we'll be equal to 2 and 3 up 10 which are two different numbers of clusters.
We want to experiment in order to plot that elbow method graph.
All right.
So numbers of clusters equal ie.
And then we would like to do something to avoid the random initialization trap which was explained by
Carol in the intuition lecturers and the way to avoid it is to initialize the Caymans algorithm with
a particular method and that method is called K Means plus plus.
So it's basically an advanced initialization trick which will make sure we don't fall into the random
initialization trap.
So we must absolutely input that parameter and the name of that parameter is in it and the value to
select.
Well that came in plus plus initialization is called in quotes because that's a string k means plus
plus.
Just like that.
All right.
So now we're safe from the random initialization trap and now we will just add one final argument.
You know this one very well it's just in order for us to have the exact same results on our notebook
that we can you know follow and describe what's happening on our notebook and that parameter is of course
random underscore a state which we will send equal to 42 42 apparently is a number that brings luck
in mathematics.
I'm not saying that I believe in this but anyway we just have to fix the seed here and any number is
OK as long as we choose the same.
All right.
Forty two and now the next step because we only created the objects so far we haven't run the algorithm
yet.
Well here we go.
That's the next step the next step is to run the algorithm and by running the algorithm I actually mean
train it.
You know we we are ready to train that came into algorithm with that AI number of clusters.
And as any function you know especially in the cycle learn library but also you know an attentive library
while the function used to train an algorithm and machinery model is the fit function here a method
because it will be called from this came in as objects.
There you go.
The next step here is of course to take.
Well our key means objects from which we're going to call that fit method which will take as input.
Well you're gonna tell me what does it take as input.
It takes us and put this time of course only the matrix of features X because remember you know in the
graph that was shown to you to explain the intuition lecturers.
Well in order to train the Caymans algorithm we only need the data of the features in here as a reminder
we are training the Caymans algorithm with only the annual income and the spending score and you will
see that it will be way enough to identify some patterns some clusters.
All right and that's it.
That's only what we have to input to run or train the Caymans algorithm.
And so now according to you are we done with the iteration of the loop.
Well no because remember we are only doing this to get one particular thing which we already initialized.
I'm talking of course about the WC asset value which is the within class the sum of squares between
the observation points in each cluster and the century of each cluster.
So there you go.
That's exactly what we have to compute right now now that we already trains and run our Caymans algorithm
and well the way to get that WC asset value is to first take or WC SS list which is so far initialized
as an empty list and then we're gonna use the append function which is a prebuilt function of Python
lists and which will of course add or append you know a new value inside this list.
And the first value it will happen of course is the WTS has value computed for one cluster which is
therefore actually the sum of the squared distances between all the observation points you know because
there is only one cluster and the Century of the single cluster.
All right.
So append since it is a function of adding some parenthesis and well the way to get that WC SS value
is to call an attribute of the Caymans object.
You know objects and classes have attributes which gives you directly some values you want.
And well luckily for us there is an attribute of the Caymans class which is called inertia and which
will give us exactly that WC as its value.
All right.
So in order to get that attribute we just need to call our object first because you know when you want
to get an attribute you always have to call it from the object and then you added that and there you
go you call for the attribute in which is here inertia with an underscore added.
All right.
Congratulations.
I think this was the very first for loop.
We actually built in this course.
So if it is your very first full loop of all time congratulations.
As you see this is not Nazi at all and you actually built a very useful for loop which will plot very
nicely the graph of the Elbow Method and now to get out of the for loop we need to you know go back
here at the beginning of the row to specify to Python that we are indeed not anymore in the loop and
that we are back in the main code.
And speaking of the main code well the only thing that we're left to do is just to plot the graph because
indeed we have all the WC SS values for each of the indexes are going from 1 to 10.
Therefore for each of the numbers of clusters because I represent here the different numbers of clusters
we want to experiment.
So here we just have to plot the graph and to do this while we're going to use of course Matt plotted
the pie plot which we will use this way first by calling the P L T shortcut here and then from which
we're gonna call the plot function.
This is something we already did of course when plotting our regression curves or classification curves
in part 2 and 3 and now we about a plot just a simple curve that will follow the different WC as has
values taken for the different numbers of clusters from 1 to 10 and so well in that plot function remember
what we have to input.
For us we have to input the different values that will be taken on the x axis and that's the values
from 1 to 10.
So in order to specify this well we can simply take you know that range again because that range from
1 to 10 exactly returns all the values from 1 to 10.
So there you go.
That's what we can input here for the X coordinates and now for the y coordinates according to what
we're going to be here.
Well very simply that's of course all the different values of WC yeses and they have to be input in
a list and well good news.
That's exactly what we have already and that's of course also the reason why we created that list in
the first place so that we can directly input this into the plot function to indeed plot are elbow method
graph.
All right things are starting to get completed here now where else can we do to improve that graph.
Well you know very simply we're gonna add a nice title with the title function and we'll actually title
our graph by you know the L BOE method.
All right.
Very simply then we'll add a label to the x axis.
Thanks to the X label function and on the x axis we can specify that it is indeed the number of clusters.
Perfect.
And now same for the Y label which we will specify to be of course W C S S will increase the sum of
squares.
And finally remember the last thing we have to do which is to show the graph with the show function.
All right.
So I think we're done here.
Let's see.
Let's see if we're right and if we didn't make a mistake.
So we're actually going to play that cell and plot the Elbow Method graph.
Congratulations.
We did it 100 percent correctly.
So now according to you after you followed you know the intuition lectures.
What is the optimal number of clusters we must use here.
Well I remind that this is the number of clusters from which you know the WC assessed value starts slowing
down you know start reducing its descent and here.
Well that of course that number here you know the number five because indeed from this number.
Well you know the curve starts being almost flat.
No it decreases very slowly here.
It decreases very strongly you know decreases a lot here still quite much.
And from the number of clusters five well it decreases slowly.
Okay.
So clearly the optimal number of classes here is five and therefore for our next step training came
in tomorrow on the data set we will choose to build it to train it and to run it to identify five clusters.
All right so let's do this in a next material and actually I have an exercise for you based on what
we did here to plot that elbow method graph you can actually totally do this on your own.
So actually in the next material we will train that came in tomorrow on the day set you know to identify
five clusters and then we'll also create that dependent variable which I've told you about you know
that's the principle of clustering we are creating at some point a new dependent variable in which the
values will be exactly the different clusters.
So at least before we start the next tutorial well please train the Caymans model on the data set to
identify five clusters.
And until then enjoy machine learning.