Hello my friends.
All right.
Let's see if you got this right again predicting the test results and displaying the vector of the predictions
next to the vector of the real results mean the real purchase decisions.
And I really want you to juggle with all your two kids you know whether it is the data crossing to kids
or your other machinery models where you have indeed several tools inside because indeed now the tool
we would like to use is that you know little piece of code that allows to display the two vectors of
predicted results and real results.
So what I expected you to do you know to be the most efficient as you can was to go to part two regression
and then into the multiple in our regression further and then open this MULTIPLE LINEAR REGRESSION implementation
which indeed contains insights so I already opened it that to allowing to display the two vectors of
predicted results and real results.
I'm talking of course about this tool right.
We implemented it many times.
That's why I didn't want to do it again here in our logistic regression implementation plus I really
want to train you and incentivize you to be the most efficient as you can by juggling between your different
models implementations.
And so if you did this if you had the reflex to grab that tool right here in multiple in our regression
or many other models where we implemented that.
Well congratulations.
You did amazing.
All right so here we're gonna take this.
And of course if you re implemented it yourself.
That's also amazing especially if you manage to be more efficient than how we were about to be.
All right.
Because what we only have to do here is to copy this little piece of code you know that tool and paste
it in the new code sell here to predict the test results because indeed we have all the same names here
for the vector of predictions white bread which will be the result of the predict method applied to
test set and called of course from our not regress or object but classifier object.
There we go.
That's the first change you had to make.
And then well since this time you know our predicted purchase decisions and the real purchase decisions
are either 0 or 1.
Well we don't need to add anything here to you know forced a number of decimals after the comma to be
only two.
Right.
Here we are only dealing with integers.
So we can remove this.
We don't need this.
And then final question here do we have to change anything.
Well absolutely not.
And that's what I mean by you know grabbing a tool and applying it on your numeral by only having to
change one or two things.
Here we only changed the name of the moral type you know from aggressor to less fire.
Okay so let's check it out.
Let's see if it works.
Let's press play here and indeed we get the two vectors next to each other with first on the left.
Your vector of predictions you know of the predicted purchase decisions for all the customers.
Of course the test set right.
This was applied to excess here so that all the customers of the test set and on the right in the second
column you have the real purchasing decisions.
And so here what's interesting to see is to compare the predicted purchase decisions to the real ones
for all the customers in the test.
All right so let's see for the first customer of the test.
You know remember of age 30 an estimated salary eighty seven thousand dollars.
Well the prediction is no this customer didn't buy the new SUV and the real result is indeed no.
In reality that customer didn't buy the new SUV.
Good.
Same for the second customer.
That customer was predicted not to buy that new SUV and indeed it did not buy that new SUV.
Third customer this time the third customer actually bought that new SUV and our model predicted that
indeed this new customer bought it.
Well it's funny we actually have a lot of correct predictions.
That's amazing right.
All this so far is correct.
This is correct.
And here we go.
We have our first incorrect prediction here.
Our logistic regression model predicted that this particular customer didn't buy the SUV because we
have a prediction of zero here.
But in reality that customer bought that new amazing SUV.
OK.
Because the real result here is a one.
Then here it is correct correct.
And here we go.
Another incorrect prediction where our model predicted again that this customer didn't buy the SUV whereas
in reality that customer bought the new SUV.
All right.
You see so that looks really really good actually we will get a very nice confusion matrix I will explain
very soon what it is and mostly a very good accuracy because the accuracy in the test that of course
is simply the number of correct predictions divided by the total number of observations in the test.
And this is exactly what we're about to get in the dessert.
We will not only get the confusion matrix showing.
So there you go.
I'm about to expand what it is.
The confusion matrix will show us exactly the number of correct predictions and the number of incorrect
predictions for the two cases where the real result was 0 0 1 2 basically will have a nice matrix showing
how many mistakes and correct predictions are moral made.
And of course inside the same new step or code cell we will compute the accuracy and we will see what
is the percentage of correct predictions or moral made on the test.
So should I ask you to try to do it on your own.
Well yes why not.
Because you know once again you just have to go to the API of psychic learn and figure out how to make
that confusion matrix and how to compute the accuracy.
And now I'll just give you a little hint.
You will have to look into the metrics module from to learn and then I'm not telling you anything else
you can really find the tools you need with that head.
Okay so we'll implement a solution together in the next story or I will show you how to navigate that
cycle or an API to find what we want.
And until then enjoy machine learning.