Hello and welcome to this or to Tauriel today we're going to implement the naive base algorithm on our
.
So let's start right now.
Let's first set the folder as working directory.
So I'm going to Part 3 classification and that's the folder.
So make sure you have the social network and see the file and if that's the case click on this more
about I'm here to set this folder as working directory.
And now let's start implementing names based on our.
So we're going to take our classification templates.
We're going to take everything from here to here and then paste right here and now we just need to change
a few things.
So first let's change the titles or usual so that we don't forget.
So here we are with the Navy base classifier.
Same for the training set.
So that is plotting the title in on graphs.
And now what we all need to do is to create our Navy base classified.
So let's do this.
Going to remove this and now what are we going to do.
Well it's actually funny because we're going to use a library that we already used before but for different
classify it it's to be 10 71 library.
So there is no surprise why this library is very popular one of the most popular ones because it contains
a lot of tools.
Tools for SVM and tools for Navy base.
So here again we'll use this library.
So for those of you who didn't follow the SVM tutorials on our.
And for those of you who are starting or for the first time maybe you don't have the 1871 packages in
your packages list.
So if that's the case you just need to type the command here.
Install that packages and then in quotes here in the parenthesis you just add the name of the library
which is 10 71 and then you just need to select this and execute to install the package.
I won't do it here because I already have mine installed but I promise you it will work properly.
So I'm just going to put that in comment.
Here we go.
And now let's just also import the library that is to selected in the package is this because it's selected
but it might not always be the case.
And if you want to automate your machine learning scripts it's better to always have this script line
here that selects to your package just through a library it tenso anyone.
And now we are ready to start creating our naiv by as class 5.
OK so let's do this.
As usual we will create a variable classifier
and then we will use the name base function of the intense 71 library the Eatons only one library contains
a lot of functions and one of them is to create a nice Bies classifier.
OK so careful with the capitals.
So it's not capital and that capital B.
Right.
But then you know are helping with the terms so you will have this naive box popping up here so you
just have to press enter.
And now let's input the parameters so the parameters what are they.
Let's look at them we press one here to have a look.
And here they are.
So we will actually need to input only the two first arguments.
We want you to put the formula like for the other one it will work perfectly well with only the first
two ones.
So you'll see that input X here which is by the way the training set.
So the training set but we need to remove the last column of our and said because X is actually the
matrix features you see it's written here numeric matrix or data frame.
And by that they mean the matrix of features that is the matrix of the independent variables are here
.
Since the training set contains both the independent variables and the dependent variable we need to
exclude the dependent variable.
So to do this we're going to add brackets here and remove the last column by inputting here a minus
and then the index of the last column which is where we can see it's minus 3 so it's minus 3.
All right so perfect.
Then come up and then the next arguments.
So you guess what the next argument is.
Well of course to try to classify you we need to be in the Ben enviro's and the response and the responses
to been invaluable.
So of course Y is going to be the dependent variable.
So why the cause and to take it.
We are going to take it this way we're going to put trainset dollar per chase.
So I'm choosing to write it this way because we can clearly see that we are taking the dependent variable
purchased.
All right.
And that's all you will see that it will work perfectly well.
So I'll show you right now.
Let's select the.
Sorry.
So before we have to select what's above which is all the preprocessing steps.
So command and control plus and to execute all right pre-processing well done we are good to go.
And now we can create our classifier.
So yes let's do this.
If you're tens of any one package is not selected you need to select that as well.
So commander control us enter to execute.
And here is our classifier arson So as you can see it works perfectly well the classifier as well created
using only those two informations and when you think about it well this is all we need to train a classifier
because we need the information of the independent variables and the information of the dependent variable
so that it can learn the correlations between the independent variables and the dependent variable.
All right so that makes sense.
And now we can create our vector of prediction y pred using the Predict function on our classifier and
on our new data which is the test set.
So here we go.
White bread is great.
Let's have a quick look.
Why bread.
So for the first time we're obtaining something here.
Remember before when we entered Why present the console we have all the predictions listed in the console
.
But here we have this factor zero here.
So that means that white bread is a vector of factors.
But with no factor.
So it's basically an empty vector.
And that is because the Navy base function of the of any one library didn't recognize our dependent
variable vector purchased as a categorical variable with 0 and 1 factors.
So for the libraries and functions we have been using recognized the dependent variable as factors.
So we didn't have any issues with our predictions and we didn't have to include the dependent variable
purchased as factors.
But here with the base it's not the case.
It doesn't recognize the dependent variable purchased as factors.
So we need to encode it as factors because as you can see if we try to compute the confusion matrix
below we will get the following error message.
All arguments must have the same length.
Well yes indeed we have a problem because the two arguments here are test set three.
That is the third call and purchase of the test set.
And then we spread it.
So since this set 3 has links 100 and white bread has length zero because it's an empty vector with
no vectors then obviously we can not compute any confusion matrix.
So what we need to do is to jump back up to the pre-processing first step to encode our dependent variable
purchased as factors then the based function will recognize the dependent variable factors and will
perfectly be able to create a classifier that will allow to predict function to return the expected
vector of predictions y.
So it's great that you see this error because this is a classic error in machinery in our and that way
from now on you will make this error in the future or if you make it you'll know how to fix it.
So let's do it right now let's add a new section here and that's called it and coding
the targets
feature X Factor.
All right and now let's vectorize or call them purchased.
OK let's do this.
So we will take it from start.
That means that we will take the purchased dependent variable column of the data set and then we will
recompute all of these to set this purchase column everywhere for all our sets.
There is a training set and the test.
OK.
So we're going to take our last call in from our data set so we're going to type data set dollar purchased
rights equals factor in parenthesis dataset.
And then again we're taking the purchased call and that is a dependent variable column of our dataset
.
So again we're taking the dollar sign here purchased to take this column and then here we will just
specify the levels or levels are see 0 and 1.
All right.
And that's it.
That's how you encode your dependent variable convert chased into factors and that's actually what we
saw in Botwin data pre-processing when I explained how to encode a categorical variable and set it as
factors.
Well here we have to do it and actually we are going to leave that in the template we're going to leave
this encoding the target featurettes factor because even if we encode the debate envoi will come for
other classifiers like logistic regression as VM and the other classifiers then it will even be better
to have this purchase Culham and codices factors so that we can know for sure that our recognizes it
as a factor.
OK for some classifiers we don't need to specify it but let's do this anyway so that we never get any
error.
All right so we're going to start from scratch now.
So to do this we can keep everything so that's where we're going to do everything here.
So we're doing the data clearing the script here some pressing control Al to clear and that's it.
And now let's do the whole thing and you're going to see that we won't get the error.
So let's select this case.
That's all the data pre-processing steps with.
Now the encoding included so Exiguus.
All right now we're going to fit the base model to the trainset executes.
All good.
Now we're going to create our vector of predictions why Pred.
OK you're going to see that if I type Y pred here we will not have the predictions so we can compare
it to Y said which is this third column of the test set K so we can compare them but let's not do this
let's just get to the point where I want to show you that now a confusion matrix is going to be created
without any error.
So let's select this execute.
And now as you can see that confusion matrix is created without any problem.
So now we can have a look to see the number of incorrect predictions which is 6:53 equals 14 incorrect
predictions not bad out of the 100 observations of the test set.
Okay great.
And now we're finally getting to the fun part which is to visualize the results.
So if you didn't follow the Python tutorials a good exercise for you is to try to predict what's going
to happen predict what you're about to see based on the intuitions that really explain to you.
Can you guess what prediction regions are going to be.
And especially the prediction boundary.
Can you guess what it's going to be.
Is the Navy Bies classify a linear classifier and then it will be a straight line or is the nave by
specifier a narrowcast variable then is the prediction boundary going to be a smooth curve or a prediction
boundary with a lot of irregularities like for Canon.
That's a good exercise you know to try to practice your intuition that you have just built you it to
practice it now.
OK.
So I'll just you can pause on the video and now I'll just select this to show you if your prediction
is correct.
So let's see.
Command and control and to to execute.
And there is our Navy base graphic resolve.
Isn't it beautiful how this prediction boundary is a smooth curve.
Classifying quite well the data sets that is a data set of observations.
None of them are separable.
It's kind of like the kernel as curve.
You know it's a beautiful smooth curve that manages to catch those green users that couldn't be caught
by linear classifiers because we had the straight line and therefore it couldn't catch the green users
here and put them in a green category.
Were in the red category that thinks this curve can see that it's making less incorrect predictions
but still some like those one two three here regarding these users here.
These older users with no estimated salary that's where incorrectly predicted by the linear classifiers
and then however still making some few mistakes here we would have liked to have a lower curve here
like the curve starting from here.
Well that's what they can do here.
And that's already quite a good job.
So now let's see what it does on the test results.
Here we have the test result code.
Let's execute it.
And here is a test.
If the execution of this code is taking too much time you can try to take a lower resolution because
right now you can see that we have a very high resolution with this by 0.01 step here.
We cannot see the pixels here thanks to this resolution.
If you take no point one resolution this crate will execute much faster but then you will see the pixel
point so it's as you want.
So the test results are actually not bad as well.
It did a pretty good job classifying this green users here to the right grid category but still some
indirect predictions resist since those green points here stay in the red region.
All right so that's the name based graphic results.
I hope you enjoyed what you saw.
We're going to have other different surprises of other categories.
You'll see that we will get very different kind of prediction of boundaries when we look at the decision
trees classifiers and the random forest fires.
So I look forward to showing that to you.
And until that enjoy machine learning