All right let's do this.
Let us begin our implementation of the natural language processing.
Well you know branch of machinery but more specifically of an MLP model made for sentiment analysis.
All right.
So as usual we're going to start as much efficiently as we can.
We're going to use our data processing template which I've of course prepared for this implementation
which contains you know the code to import the libraries and import the dataset.
So let's quickly start with the libraries here.
I'm going to take them.
I'm going to paste that right here in a new coat cell to indeed import the essential libraries you know
just in case we need them.
It doesn't mean that we will necessarily use all of them but at least we have them in case we need them.
OK.
Then in point of dataset let's create a new code.
And now according to you do I have to take all the lines of code here or just this one to get the data
set.
Well as you might guess now we're going to do some different kind of data processing and therefore we'll
just take this line of code to indeed import the reviews inside still a data set variable but then you
will see that there will be a certain work needed before creating these two features.
We will indeed create these two features at some point you know the matrix of features and the debate
in vivo but not now.
This is too early.
We will have to clean the text first and prepare the bag of words model.
And in fact we will create these two entities the matrix of features and it had been invaluable vector
in the cell where we create the bag over tomorrow.
Okay.
So let's just take this for now the data set and back into our MLP implementation let us base that right
here and now indeed we have to adapt this a little because now we're not dealing with a C as we fail
we're dealing with a T as we fail with a feature as meaning the texts and the binary variable 0 or 1
are separated by a tab instead of a comma.
So first thing first let us replace this data set by the right name.
You notice that I even included the extension because we'll have to change it.
So the name of our dataset.
Let's have a look again.
Is restaurant reviews dot TSB.
All right.
So that's exactly what we'll replace here.
Restaurant underscore reviews Dot T.
S..
Okay.
And now since it is a T as we will have to add some extra parameters to specify that indeed we are dealing
with a T as we felt instead of comma separated value.
Yes.
All right.
And the way to do this is just to add one parameter here which is delimiter.
For which the default value is actually the comma.
Meaning that the default data set that we can import with this read on this course is V isn't easy as
V.
But you know we can also use this read on this course as V function to import a t as we file and that's
exactly what we're about to do now.
But the way to specify that we're dealing with a T as we file is to enter the following value for this
delimiter parameter which is in quotes this slash here backslash and T.
All right.
That's the value of the delimiter.
You should enter to specify that your dataset is a T as you file but then that's not all we need to
add one final parameter.
A very important one when you're working with Dex I'm gonna show you something now in not this data
set because we couldn't see the whole reviews but I'm gonna show you the whole dataset inside the folder
machinery it is that which you could download once again in the article right before this trial.
So let's open it.
Let's go into parts of an MLP then MLP again and by phone.
And that's the whole dataset.
So I'm on Mac here so I'm going to open it with a classic text editor like text edit perfect we just
need to have a look at the text quickly.
There we go.
And now I'm just gonna do a command or control F to find something which is a double quotes just like
that.
Okay.
And as we see we can see that we have many double quotes within the text.
All right.
And in order to process this the right way you know when our machinery models learn how to read text.
Well we'll have to say to our model to ignore the double quotes.
Otherwise you know if you don't do it this can cause some processing or passing errors which you want
to avoid you know because this can lead to an execution error.
So I always recommend to add this quoting parameter and set its value to three which means actually
no quotes or you know ignore the quote.
So that indeed you can be free from processing errors.
You can see there are many quotes.
Right.
So we're just going to ignore all of them as if you know there are just some different characters in
the texts.
All right.
So that's all I wanted to show you.
So now let's close this and let's go back to our implementation and to add this final parameter we need
to add here quoting equals and the value of this coding parameter to ignore all the double quotes is
three.
All right.
And now perfect.
That's how you import correctly a TSB file which should be the format of a data set separating text
and a binary outcome like 0 1.
That's the classic way to proceed with sentiment analysis.
So there we go.
Well actually let's imported data set to make sure everything's all right.
So we're going to click this folder here.
Then it's going to take a little time you know a few seconds to connect this notebook to a runtime to
enable file browsing but in a second and we should see that upload button here to indeed upload.
There we go.
The set.
So let's click it.
And now please find your machinery.
It is that folder on your machine which you had to download either in the previous tutorial or at the
beginning of each section.
So now let's go inside.
Let's go once again into port seven natural language processing.
Then this section then python and then restaurant reviews the TSC let's click open.
Let's click Okay.
And now we're going to have that data set inside the notebook.
All right.
Perfect.
So now let's run the sales first this cell where we import libraries.
So simple one.
And now this cell where we import the dataset.
Let's do this let's make sure everything goes well.
And there we go.
Now we have the dataset ready.
So that means we're ready for the next step cleaning the text.
That's an essential step in natural language processing.
I will show you all the techniques to make your text as clean as possible.
And we will do all this in the next tutorial.
Until then enjoy machine learning.