Hello and welcome to this almost final tutorial of the Part 1 data processing.
I look forward to being well-prepared with our data to start making our machine learning models.
It's gonna be very fun.
We just have to hold on for two more tutorials and then we're good to go.
Okay.
So today we're gonna talk about feature scaling which is very important in machine learning.
I'm going to explain why right now.
So I'm gonna go to Google Sheets to find our data set.
And here it is.
Let's explain what is feature scaling and why we need to do it okay.
So as you can see we have these two columns age and salary that contains numerical numbers.
Let's just focus on the age and the salary.
You notice that the variables are not on the same scale because the age are going from twenty seven
to 50 and the salary is going from 40 K to like 90 K.
So because this age variable in the salary variable don't have the same scale.
This will cause some issues in your machinery models.
And why is that.
It's because you're machine learning models a lot of machinery models are based on what is called the
Euclidean distance.
If you remember that back from high school the Euclidean distance between two data points between two
points is the square root of the sum of the squared coordinates.
Well actually here it's the same we have two variables age and salary.
So you can picture age as the x coordinate and the salary as the y coordinate and in the machine learning
models equations some Euclidean distances between observation points for example this one and this one
are computed based on these two coordinates.
And actually since the salary has a much wider range of values because it's going from zero to 100 k
the Euclidean distance will be dominated by the salary because for example if we take two observations
for example the this one the ninth one and the third one well the Euclidean distance will compute the
difference between this salary and this salary.
So let's computed.
That's about okay.
So this minus this one as you can see this is 31000 if you put that in square okay that's it up square
that gives this.
And now let's take for the same two observations the ages.
So let's compute equals 48 minus.
It was this one right.
Twenty seven K.
That's the difference.
And now let's take the square equals this square.
441 so you can see very clearly how this square difference dominates this square difference.
And that's because these two variables are not on the same scale.
So you know in the machine learning equations it will be like this doesn't exist because it will be
dominated by this.
So that's why we absolutely need to put the variables on the same scale that is that we are going to
transform these two variables and they're going to have values in the same range.
For example they're going to have values from minus one to plus one here.
And same here minus one two plus one.
So that we don't get this sort of problem with a huge number here dominating a smaller number here.
So that eventually the smaller number doesn't exist.
There are several ways of scaling your data a very common one is the standardization which means that
for each observation and each feature you withdraw the mean value of all the values of the feature and
you divided by the standard deviation.
So that's a first type of features caning and another type is normalization which means that you subtract
your observation feature X by the minimum value of all the feature values and you divide it by the difference
between the maximum of your feature values and the minimum of your feature values.
Don't worry if you're not very comfortable with the mathematics here.
But what you need to understand is that we are putting of variables in the same range in the same scale
so that no variable is dominated by the other.
Okay.
So let's do it right now.
Anyway you're going to see how the variables are going to be transformed you're going to see how they
go from having large and very different values to small and same values.
So let's move on to our So here we are r and now that you understand feature scaling let's apply it
to the training set and the test set here we will just write two lines of code which are so the first
line is training set.
So the training sets already exists right.
It's this one the training set as you can see it's not scale these are.
It contains the raw values so training set equals and simply now we're going to write scale
and then training set.
That's all that scales your training set is integrate and same for the test set we will copy this line
based it here and we will change training into test and here as well OK.
So here I just wrote this there is something important to understand.
This will be the feature scaling block of code that we will be using in our template.
However let us see what happens when I select this code and execute it.
So let's select this execute okay.
As you can see here I obtained two errors.
Aaron code means X must be numeric for the training set and the test set.
Can you guess what the problem is.
The problem is that okay.
Well it tells us what the problem is.
It tells us that X must be numeric but what does that mean.
Well first what is this X X is for this line of code the training set and for this line of code the
test.
So let's forget the test set for a second and let's focus on the training set.
So X is a train set and it says that the training set must be numeric.
So let's look at our training sets.
Okay.
Well the training set looks numeric right.
Here we have numeric values numeric values family values numeric values but no actually there are two
columns that don't have numeric values.
It's this one the country.
And this one purchased.
And you remember why.
Well it's because before we had the country written in text and the Bruges column written in text with
yes or no.
And we changed that by putting the categories as factors.
That's what we did here.
As you remember dataset country equals factor of the different levels and labels and a factor in R is
not a numeric number.
And when you apply the scale here X must be numeric.
That means that all the columns in X that is the training set must be numeric so this time we are going
to exclude the categories from the feature scaling.
We're not going to apply feature scaling on those columns.
So that's very simple.
All we need to do is to take the columns we're interested in which are well the indexes of the column
we want to scale which are indexes so index is in our start at 1.
So that's 1 2 3.
So that's the second and third index.
We want to take to scale the age and the salary columns so 2 and 3 Let's input it.
We need to specify here two column three and that gets what we want.
So now I'm going to copy this copy paste it here here and here.
All right.
And now it's ready.
Let's have a look at the training set and the test sets and not scale that scale.
Let's go back to our code.
Let's select this.
And now we shouldn't get an error command and control percentage to execute.
Here we go.
It executed properly.
And now let's look at the training set.
All scaled properly.
Perfect.
And the test set all scaled properly.
Now our data is ready to offer a good precision and good accuracy and a fast work of the machine learning
models and by that I mean that the machine learning models will converge rapidly OK.
So that's it for feature scaling.
Now you know how to apply for just getting to your data in Python and R congratulations and mostly congratulations
because we did all the required steps to prepare SSL data features getting what's the last one because
the next tutorial will be about this data processing template and I will just explain how we are going
to use it in our machining models.
It's going to be very fast and practical.
So we are done with the data processing.
Congratulations you did the most difficult part and now it's time to have fun.
It's time to start making the models and I can't wait to start them with you.
So thank you for watching this tutorial.
I look forward to seeing you on the next one.
And until then enjoy machine learning.