Well a new section.
And that means a new application.
So in this video we're going to start to discuss the next application we're going to work on.
This is going to be a rather large app that's going to take many many videos to complete.
So I'm really excited about it because we're going to walk through building a pretty full featured application.
So let's discuss what we're going to be making.
All right.
So we're going to making a sort of e-commerce application.
We're going to be building a no J.S. web server that's going to serve up some HDL pages.
That's going to allow users to view items and shop add them to a cart and eventually attempt to purchase
them so when a user comes to our Web site that we're going to build we're going to show them a list
of different items that they can purchase for each item.
We'll show an image the title and the price the mockups right here.
Don't show the title or the price but they will eventually underneath each item will have a button that
says add to cart.
So if the user clicks that they're going to add that item to a shopping cart then eventually when a
user decides to checkout they can click on this cart link up here and go to a page where they will see
their shopping cart with all the different items that they have added.
So for each item we'll show a title a quantity a price total price for that line item and the user should
also have the ability to remove this item out of the shopping cart as well from the screen and at the
bottom will show the total for all the items in the cart and have a buy button right underneath it.
That by button isn't going to actually do anything.
So in theory if user clicked on buy we would start to accept some credit card payment or something.
We're not going to worry about billing or anything like that because that's really outside the scope
of what we're trying to do inside this project.
We are much more focused on how we use javascript to build a web server and show some dynamic H2 male
pages to these two pages right here.
The item list in the shopping cart is really all a public user of our application would be seeing.
So this is just the two pages that a customer would see and that's pretty much it but to really administer
and make this a reusable application we would probably want to make sure that someone who owns this
Web site or runs it on a day to day basis would also have the ability to add new items edit existing
ones or delete existing ones as well.
So in addition to these two public pages we're also going to be making a series of hidden pages that
we're going to refer to as the admin panel the admin panel is going to give an administrator or someone
who owns this Web site the ability to create products.
Take a look at all the existing ones edit the existing ones to change their image title and price or
delete them as well.
If a user decides to create a product or edit an existing one we'll show a form that looks like this
right here.
So it will have a text input for the product name the price and then a button to upload an image as
well that represents that particular item so this form right here will be displayed anytime a user wants
to create or edit an existing product we probably want to make sure that not everybody can come to this
admin panel again only an administrator or a site owner should be able to see these two pages.
So to make sure that is the case we're going to kind of lock down access to these two pages behind some
authentication.
In other words you must log into our Web site.
As an administrator in order to access the admin panel so that means that we're going to have to have
a sign up page for administrators where we'll take an email password and password confirmation and if
a user or an admin ever logs out we need to make sure they also have the ability to sign back in the
future as well.
And just be really clear this sign in and sign out stuff or see me sign up and sign in is only for access
to the admin panel.
So only administrators are required to log into the Web site a end user or like a customer can browse
all these different items and have a shopping cart without logging in at all.
So you really have two types of users users and administrators only administrators are going to be required
to log in public users are only going to see these two pages.
Administrators can see these two pages plus these administration pages as well where they can manage
the list of all the different products that are going to be created okay.
So that's pretty much it.
This might seem like kind of a small product you know at the end of the day it's only really six different
pages but to be honest there is a tremendous amount of work to do here because this is really the first
kind of web project we're going to be putting together or I should say the Web the first web project
that is based upon some outside web server that we're going to be authoring ourselves so let's take
a pause right here.
We're gonna come back the next video and we're gonna start to discuss some of the big ticket items some
of the big challenges we're going to run into.
And just in general how we're going to approach this project.
So I'll see you in just a minute.