So far we've seen how to work with single values like the number twelve point three or the string high.
And that's great.
But most of the time in the real world our data is a lot more complicated.
It consists of pieces like numbers and strings and boolean.
But usually we have more than one piece of information and they're often related to one another.
So this is where data structures come in which is what we're talking about here.
We're seeing our first two data structures in this section the array and the object they're both built
into javascript and they're both used all over the place.
You would be hard pressed to find any code base that did not contain both of them.
They're really really useful.
First a couple of goals we want to be able to write arrays.
Understand the syntax.
Do the same thing with object laterals.
Also we'll take a quick detour to talk about reference types and revisit our friend concept we saw let
let in const briefly we'll talk about it again in this section and then we'll talk about a ton of built
in array and object methods.
Remember how string had all these different methods like string dot index of string dot to uppercase
arrays and objects have their own set of methods as well.
In this video we're going to start with arrays which are collections of values all of these different
values we've seen so far.
Strings numbers billions things like normal and undefined arrays collect them into one structure one
collection and it's ordered.
So I'd like to visually think of it as one of these pill containers where you have little slots and
you can put data on our case pills into these slots and there's an order.
Usually it's like Monday Tuesday Wednesday Thursday and so on and you start with this first one and
then the second one and you can see where I'm going with this.
Arrays are very similar they are slots and on their own arrays don't do much unless we put information
in them so they collect all those primitive type of data we've seen so far.
They also can collect other data like other arrays which we'll get to in a bit.
So let's take a look at two quick examples of where an array is used.
Here is a playlist on Spotify.
There's a very special special.
There's a particular order to these songs.
People spend a lot of time ordering playlists.
Usually they're not just a random collection of songs although people do shuffle them much undue which
undoes the order but the order is set.
You can change it depending on the application but the main point is that there is an order so there's
something first second third and so on all the way down to the bottom.
We could use an array and there is an array behind the scenes for Spotify that is used to store playlist
information.
Another example would be comments on a blog post or on Reddit.
Those comments have a particular order on Reddit.
There it depends on how you're sorting but it could be by upvotes.
It could be by time most recent comments.
I'm on medium here.
There are 7 comments I think.
And as you can see there is an order.
If I refresh the page we'll get that same order again.
Now each comment consists of multiple pieces of information which is where objects will come in.
So we're gonna get there for now we'll be creating arrays that consist of single values in each slot
in that array.
Something like this comment consists of multiple values a user name a date the comment text the number
of applause or claps or whatever they're called on Medium.
There's multiple pieces of information bundled into one comment.
But for now we'll start with simpler things.
So to make an array there's a really really easy way of doing it.
We just use these square brackets.
We've seen them before in the context of strings.
They mean something different.
If we're not accessing a string so we've seen this ELA well.
If I can type of string ELA well square brackets 1 or 2 or 0 when we make an array we use the same brackets.
But in a different context where there's no string in front it will make us an empty container an empty
pillbox.
This is now ready to store our information.
We can also Initialize an array with data already in it so we can store whatever we want.
All of the types we've seen so far are welcome in any array so we can put strings or numbers or boolean.
We can even mix them all up together.
So here's an example of a simple array.
Let's go with let's how about shopping list equals and then we'll put in some things that we need.
We have ice we have let's go with cheese and usually I think ice actually makes sense at the end remember
these are ordered we'll put ice in there I'm going to put that at the end because when I go the grocery
store I like to get frozen stuff at the end so it doesn't melt.
We'll also put baby cereal and then cheese.
OK so this is going to make us an array with 3 items in it.
If I save my code I'm just working in another app J.S. connected to my index I've opened it up over
here I'll refresh.
I don't see anything because I'm not concerned about logging but I can access shopping list and we can
see it contains three items.
Length is three.
We'll talk about that in a moment.
So there's our first example of an array.
We also could make an empty array if we didn't have information to put in it at the beginning.
We could go and add information later on which we'll see how to do we could make an array of numbers
like Lotto numbers and I don't really know what the rules are for lotto numbers.
If they're supposed to be less than 60 or 100 or whatever it is.
But here's an example of that.
We have five numbers in an array.
There's an order and we can also combine information.
So this will be relatively meaningless.
Usually your data is relatively cohesive when you have it inside of an array but it doesn't have to
be.
We could have a string like dog a number 12.
True no good even putting out a number and they're perfectly valid in some programming languages.
This would not be good.
Some of them don't want you to mix up data in an array.
You have to specify.
This is a collection of only strings and you're only allowed to put strings in there but that's not
the case with JavaScript.
We can put whatever we want and if I look at I do need to refresh the page so that it loads I look at
my collection we can see it's an array with five items in it.
All right.
So that's the basics of making an array.
There is one other way to make one if you don't use this square brackets syntax which is also called
array literal syntax.
You can do this you won't see it at least I don't see it very often.
And the reason is that it's a lot longer but new Array will make you an empty array just like empty
array does with the square brackets and you could pass in values if I wanted numbers in that array.
It gives me a new array with 1 2 3 4 5.
But why do that.
If you could just instead do one two three four five so that's creating arrays.
Next we'll talk about accessing information out of arrays.