Welcome back.
Now that we've seen the very basics of functions and their syntax arguments return values etc. We're
now going to talk about some other details some important things need to know about functions and function
adjacent topics.
So this section is not really one monolithic topic but a couple of related things that I've put together
into one section.
So we have a couple goals.
The first is to understand scope.
When I introduce Latin concept and briefly talked about var I mentioned we would come back and discuss
scope and how those different keywords impact scope.
We're gonna start by talking about that in the section it does relate to functions then we'll talk a
lot about higher order functions functions as a value in JavaScript how we can pass functions to other
functions.
We'll take a look at some existing built in functions and methods that expect you to pass a function
as an argument and that's our main goal our goals for this section.
So we're going to start with scope scope is kind of like variable visibility.
It's it's this idea that depending on where you define a variable other pieces of your code may or may
not have access to that value in a variable scope.
Is that window it's the portion of your code where other values have access to it or other functions
or other pieces of the code can access and manipulate that value.
So there's multiple pieces different ways that scope behaves in JavaScript and that's what we're going
to talk about in the next few videos.
And the first type of scope is called function scope so when we define a variable in a function like
I have right here it doesn't matter what the function is.
It's called helped me.
We have a variable called message I'm on fire inside the function.
Of course we have access to message.
If I were to log it or just get the value it's I'm on fire.
But outside the bound to that function we don't have access.
I get an error if I try to access message down here it is scoped to this function.
That's what this box is representing.
So this probably makes sense and you may have encountered this already.
If you're brand new might have played around still if we have some function it doesn't matter what it's
called Let's just go with L'Oréal and then I define some variable in there.
Let me person equals Tom and then let's also do one with const const age equals forty five and let's
do one with var so var color equals teal okay.
So we have three variables going on.
If I try to access any of them outside of this Hallowell function like let's start with person counseled
out log person we're not going to have a good time person is not defined and you might think well maybe
if you call well then those variables will be they'll come into existence right now we're defining that
function but this code is not executing.
So if I execute it first.
Same problem person is scoped to this function.
Ello Well I have access to it in here of course but not outside.
And if I tried that instead with age which is defined with const same error and if I try it with color
which is defined with var once again we get the exact same error just for a different name for a variable
person age and color.
None of these exist outside the bounds of this function.
They're scoped to it.
So this means that we can have multiple functions that have similar or the same variable names.
I could have another function we'll call this one change color and I'll set a variable called color.
Let's go with light color equals.
And this time it will be purple and we can also have.
Let's do another age we'll do const age equals 19 and we'll consider that log one of them let's console
that log age here and let's also do it here counseled out log age and then we'll call Elwell and we'll
call change color.
I'll get rid of this council that log at the bottom.
You can see we get unique values in this context.
Age is 45.
In this context age is 19.
So they are scopes those variables that we declared in a given function are scoped to that function.
They are visible only in here after the fact.
We can call the function but we cannot access or manipulate those variables from down here or up top.
We are not in the same scope.
Here's another example.
This time I have a variable called bird that I've defined up top.
Or it could be down below it doesn't matter where it's defined.
But I have bird and then I have another let bird inside this function.
So now I have two variables with the exact same name.
And remember if I try and do that in the same scope like let high equals high and then let high equal
3 I get an error it's telling me High has already been declared.
So it's not saying hi it's already been declared anywhere in your code you can only have one high.
It's more along the lines of high has been declared in this scope.
You cannot have another high declared in the same scope but we can do it like this.
We can have one variable with one name outside this function and another variable with the exact same
name in the function.
Compare that to what we had up top.
It was the same idea we had age in one function in age in a different function different scopes.
So we have different scopes here.
Two beautiful birds by the way if you ever want to google what these look like.
Oh mandarin ducks golden pheasants really pretty birds.
Let's consider that log bird down here and let's do the same thing at the very bottom.
Run my code.
Well right now I'm not executing bird watch but here bird is set to mandarin duck.
Let's call bird watch.
Now we get bird watch which runs out log Golden Pheasant.
It's finding the nearest bird which is in this scope.
Then we consider it log bird outside the function bird is set to mandarin duck.
So this diagram kind of explains this scenario.
Here we have two scopes.
We have the orange or yellow box which represents the scope of this function.
Bird where it set two Golden Pheasant is only accessible in bird watch but then we have this larger
scope where bird the first bird was declared outside the function.
So it's pink box extends down below as well.
And that's pretty much all I wanted to show you in this video.
In this context let in concert will behave the same way.
If I updated both let's to instead be const and run this we get the same output.
If I update them to both be var we get the same output as well but in the next video we'll see a very
significant difference between how letting concert behave and how far behaves in certain scenarios.
So we have more scope to talk about that's next.