Arrays are great as we've seen.
They're really useful especially when you have ordered information.
But here's an example of something that an array would not really be a great fit for.
How would we store this data.
It's from a Fitbit or some sort of health app.
Any one of them where it's tracking your total steps the number of miles you walk to your average restful
sleep.
Different types of data.
But let's say I want to store it in JavaScript and I want it all to be grouped together.
This is for one person.
So then I could have another person who has their own set of data the number of steps the number of
miles and so on.
How would we group it together.
Well if we used an array we definitely could.
It just would be confusing and we'd have to come up with some arbitrary rules.
We would probably do something like wrong window const Fitbit data.
It's Fitbit capitalize.
I don't know do it like that Fitbit data equals an array and then the first element would just be total
steps or that could be the last element we would need to decide on some consistent order.
So let's say the first thing is total steps 308.
I'm not going to get these numbers exactly three hundred eight thousand or something.
Total flaws would be the next one.
Total Miles.
So how would we really keep this straight.
It's not easy.
I'll just do to add three values.
You look at this and it's not clear at all what it actually is.
And even if you're the person who wrote it you need like a little key or you need to write down maybe
in comments what each piece is.
And then if we had someone else's Fitbit data let's go with Lucy's Fitbit data.
Lucy like that and there's different numbers you would want to be consistent.
You wouldn't want to put the number of miles first you want to make sure total steps comes first.
So the point is arrays are great but this sort of data doesn't really work well in an array situation.
You could also just make completely separate variables over and over and over could do Lucy total steps
equals some number and then you could do Lucy average miles or whatever and have 20 different variables
for one person but then they're not grouped together in any way except for the fact that they start
with Lucy.
So this all brings us to our next data structure really commonly use one called the object so an object
allows us to store data where we can associate things in group pieces of data together but rather than
simply ordering data based off of an index to zero with item the first the second like an array does.
We can specify labels.
We can say total steps is three hundred and eight thousand average.
Good sleep is two hours and 13 minutes.
Average calorie burn and so on.
We define these pairs of information.
We'll take a quick step back from the syntax to talk about objects at a high level.
Objects are collections of properties.
We've seen properties before when we have a string.
We have dot length dot length.
As I mentioned it very early on is something called a property.
Now string seems like it's a string right.
A SDH SD is a string.
Why does it have a property that is a question we'll answer later when we talk about objects in general
in JavaScript.
One thing I want to get out of the way right now is we're talking about objects in a limited capacity
but objects are everywhere in JavaScript and that's something we will revisit and come back to quite
a few times but we're not there yet.
So for now objects are collections of properties and properties are pairs of information.
We have a key and a value.
So over here I'm kind of.
This is my mental image of an object.
If you compare it to what I had for an array where we had a very ordered pill container with the first
item a second item the third item in object is more like a blob that holds different pieces of data
key and value pairs where there's not necessarily an order.
It's not all about the order.
It's about storing pairs of information.
And we don't use a number to access our data out like we do with an array where we say give me the index
of one item instead.
If this was an object here we would say give me city please or give me zip or age and then you get the
corresponding value so properties consist of key value pairs.
And here's another example slightly different style.
We have user name could be a key and then crazy cat lady would be a value upvotes is a key.
7 is the value text is a key and great post is a value in other languages like Python objects are actually
called dictionaries so dictionaries make sense.
I like the name because if you think of how you use a dictionary you have the key.
You have some words you're trying to look up and then you go and find it in this dictionary and get
the corresponding value the corresponding definition.
It doesn't work the other way around.
You don't have the definition in mind like emotional outburst you don't open the dictionary and just
try and find a definition for emotional outburst and then find out what the word is.
That means emotional outburst that would be a really long process.
Instead you have a key and it's kind of a one way relationship.
You put the key in and you figure out the corresponding value fan Todd.
Apparently I don't know if I'm pronouncing that right.
I just googled interesting words and put them in here.
So even though in JavaScript we don't call these structures dictionaries.
I like this metaphor or this idea.
And again python in some other languages do use the term dictionary so to wrap up here before we actually
dive into creating our own objects an object is just a container that contains information in the form
of pairs.
Key value pairs you store them together when you put a value in there you give it a corresponding key
and you can use that key to find that value later on and for a lot of types of data.
It's a really good choice compared to an array.
This is so much easier to work with if we have a label for each value.
Give me the total steps.
What is the average good sleep or what is the value for workouts.
This week five of seven vs. what we started out with where we have an array we can store the same values
it's just really difficult to understand what's going on.
It's difficult to enforce these rules and to write code that interacts with this.
It all relies on some arbitrary order that we decided on.
So in a way doesn't really make sense.
An object does but on the other side of things there's lots of data that makes sense really to only
use an array for compared to an object.
If order is paramount.
If we're storing race results from a marathon we definitely want to store them with an array so that
the order is tied in to the actual information.
So I'll be quiet now.
We'll get to the syntax in the next video.