We just finished up our compare passwords function.
There is one tiny little step I missed inside of here.
Remember that when we call s script what we actually get back is a buffer and we saw that back here
inside the documentation.
So when we call s script we get back a buffer.
They call it inside the documentation a derived key and again a buffer is like an array that has some
raw data inside of it.
So when we call s script right here hash supplied is actually a buffer so we should probably update
the name of that and more importantly we need to make sure that we try to do the comparison against
hash.
You have to take that buffer and turn it into an actual string so I'm going to add on to the end of
hash supplied.
We're going to call two string hacks to make sure that we take the buffer.
Turn it into a string.
I mean optionally if you want to you can update the name of that variable as well to something a little
bit more appropriate just to indicate that it is a buffer.
So how about like hash.
I don't know yes hashed supplied love or something like that.
I guess that makes at least a little bit more sense and kind of clarifies what's going on here.
Okay so now that we've got compare passwords fixed up let's save this.
We're going to go back over to our index not j ust file we're gonna find our post request handler for
dealing with a submission of our sign in form so then inside of here we currently have a very simplistic
password comparison test right here.
So we need to essentially update that if statement to use the compare passwords method.
We just put together.
Remember the two arguments you compared passwords.
The first argument is going to password that is saved inside of our database inside of our post request
handler.
We already found the user inside of our database so that user object right there has the password property
that we want to use as the first argument to compare passwords then the second argument is going to
be the password that the user supplied that is available inside this post requests handler on the password
variable right there that we just pulled out of record body.
I remember rect body is all the information that was entered into our form we essentially have everything
we need to finish this up right above my if statement I'll say const valid password is a weight users
repo compare passwords and then as a first argument we're gonna stick in a password that we got from
our database which is user password and as the second argument we'll throw in the password that was
just supplied to us by the user it's all put in password like so it's now valid password is going to
be true if the password is valid and false if it is not valid so we need to update our if statement
check right here it's all say if not valid password that that thing is not true then let's return early
from this function and we'll send back to the user something it says hey sorry but that's a bad password
OK.
Let's save this and test out this whole entire flow.
It's going to go back to my local host three thousand.
I'm going to make sure I go to sign out so now logged out.
I'm going to go to sign up and I got to create an entirely new account just to test out this sign and
flow.
It's gonna make a new account called test 10 at test dot com with a password of password account created.
Now I'm going to sign out once I'm again signed out.
I'll then attempt to sign in as that user I just made a second ago.
So I'll go to slash sign in I'm going to try to sign in with test 10 at test dot com and password hit
it and I'm signed in so that's pretty much it now to really test out this flow.
I'm gonna make sure that I sign out once again I'll go to sign in.
I'll put in test ten at test dot com.
But this time I'm going to put in an invalid password definitely invalid right there.
I'll try to sign in and I get invalid password okay.
So that is pretty much the entire authentication process from start to finish.
We put it altogether more or less from scratch inside of our project.
The only really big outside dependency we used was Cookie session.
I would have loved to put together our own custom cookie middleware but like I said there are so many
corner cases you need to be aware of that it really was not going to be worth our time to try to assemble
that thing from scratch.
Now before we kind of take a pause here and say hey this is like a really great example of authentication.
There are a couple of updates so I'd love to do to our project.
So just a couple locations so we can add in some code to clean up the overall structure.
So our goal here we're going to take a pause.
We're going to start to refactor some the code and better structure our project and once we're done
with that we're going to essentially have a really good solid starting point for any app that you want
to start to tackle in the future that requires authentication so quick pause right here.
We'll start to do a little bit of refactor in just a moment.