All right so now that we've got all this this stuff out of the way.
Let's get back on track.
We're going to focus on our start at that right here.
The goal of our start method is to start up a timer.
We want to make sure that we run some amount of code every some amount of time that's going to be responsible
for updating the text inside of our timer.
So like count the 19 down to an 18 17 16 and so on the code that is going to actually update the timer
itself and like count that thing down is going to be placed inside of this tick method.
The goal that tick method right here is to update the text inside there and eventually emit a signal
to the rest of our application to say hey some amount of time just past so the goal of start is really
just to start up the tick method and call it every so many number of seconds.
Let's take a look at what the implementation will look like right underneath starts.
I'm going to also defined tick and I'm going to use that same kind of arrow syntax like so inside of
tick.
I'll put a quick council log of tick just we can make sure that we're calling it appropriately.
And then inside of starts in order to make sure that we call tick every so many seconds like every second
or so we can use the set interval function that is built into the javascript language.
So inside of starts we will invoke set interval we're gonna pass in a reference to a function to invoke
which will be the static.
And then as the second argument we'll put in how often we want to run this function in this case I want
to run tick every one seconds.
The second argument is expressed in milliseconds.
There are 1000 milliseconds inside of a second.
So this code right here is going to make sure that we run this not tick once every seconds so the net
result should be seeing a console log every second inside of our console.
All right.
Let's save this flip back over and see how we do.
It's going to refresh.
I'll click on Start and I see tick tick tick tick.
And so on.
OK well that definitely looks good.
But there is a very subtle little issue here.
If we refresh again I want you to notice that when we click on Start we have to wait a full second before
we see the first tick.
So it turns out that when you call set interval it's going to wait one seconds or whatever that delay
is before calling that function for the first time in our application.
This would be kind of bad because whenever a user clicks on that start button they really expect to
see the timer start working right away.
We don't want them to be waiting around for a second and then see some kind of update.
Instead we want that update to occur instantly.
So in order to make sure that occurs we're going to simply call this dot tick manually right before
it's.
Now this is saying whenever we call starts we're going to immediately run one tick.
Then we're going to set up an interval that's going to be executed one second in the future.
Then one second after that after that after that and so on.
So if we say this again go back over refresh and click starts we now instantly see tick and then tick
tick tick and so on okay.
So looks pretty good.
And this is pretty easy.
So let's just keep going right now.
The next method that we need to put together is the pause method.
So we need to make sure that when we click on that pause button we stop the ticking altogether in order
to stop our interval essentially stop this function from being called whenever we call set interval
we get back something called a timer language with sign it to a variable that I'll call timer
and for right now let's just do a console log of that timer and see what exactly it is I'll go back
over refresh click start again and there's the console log of the timer.
So in this case it is a simple number of 1 want to tell you what's going on behind the scenes.
Whenever we call set interval we get back in integer the integer is an I.D. and it's essentially representing
the running timer or the running interval that is going to continue executing this function again and
again if we ever need to stop that timer or stop this interval from running we can call another function
that is built into the browser or into javascript called Clear interval when we call a clear interval
interval we're gonna pass on the idea of the interval that we want to stop.
And so in this case would be the timer variable right there.
So in this scenario right here we are essentially setting up an interval and then immediately cancelling
it.
So I would expect to never see the tick function run except for the first time we call it manually right
there so let's say this again I'm going to flip back over refresh I'll hit start.
And so now I see one tick behind the scenes we set up our interval.
And then on the next line of code we immediately cancelled it.
So I don't see any more ticks up here so of course rather than canceling the timer right away.
Well we probably want to cancel it at some point in time in the future specifically in our case whenever
the user clicks on the pause button which should run the pause method inside of our class.
Let's define a pause method.
We're going to make sure that the pause method is going to call clear interval and pass in the relevant
I.D. So underneath starts I'm going to define my pause method like so inside of here we will call clear
interval.
Now there's just a little issue we need to somehow get the timer variable that was created over here
into this other method in order to share information between different methods.
We assigned that information to an instance variable.
So instead of a sonnet directly to a variable right here called const timer we're going to say this
dot timer so by assigning the value to this that's going to make sure that we can refer to this dot
timer over inside this method and we'll get access to the same information that we just assigned right
there.
So in other words we're gonna say clear interval with this dot timer.
We can also clean up the clear interval that we left inside a start because we don't need it inside
there anymore.
One other quick thing to mention we are currently working on a class called timer referring to a variable
inside of here of like this dot timer is just a little bit unclear because we now have two words inside
of a class that are really really similar.
So in order to avoid any confusion whatsoever I'm just gonna change the name of the variable that we
are assigning the I.D. to two How about interval because that's kind of what it represents.
You can also do something like interval I.D. that would also be appropriate as well but I'm just gonna
go with interval that is what I use personally on projects that I work on I'm going to make sure that
I update this not timer inside a pause as well like so okay.
So now to test this out.
Lastly we have to do very quickly we need to make sure that backup inside the constructor we watch for
a click event on the pause button element whenever a click event occurs.
We need to run that pause method.
So right after where we set up our click event handler right there I'm going to do a this dot pause
button add event listener I'm going to watch for the Click event whenever that occurs I want to run
the this dot pause method like so okay so it looks pretty good.
So going to save this and we'll do a quick test so flip back over it refresh it starts now we're gonna
see a tick once every second and then as soon as we hit the pause button it stops.
And so I don't see any more ticks occur.
All right well let's say that this is working out pretty darn well so far.
Let's take a quick pause right here and continue in just a moment.