We've got just a couple of more methods to get through.
We're going to take care in this video of one of the easier ones we have left which is delete the sides
that we all so have to take care of get one by and update which are going to be just a little bit more
challenging delete on the other hand is gonna be pretty darn straightforward.
It's all go back over at the very bottom of my class all the fine async delete and we're going to pass
in to this function.
The idea the record that we want to delete then inside of here we'll once again get a list of all of
our records so awaits this I'd get all and we will go through or iterate through that list of records
we're going to use the filter function and we're going to filter out any record that has the same I.D.
as the idea that was passed in.
It's I'll say constant filtered records is records dot filter and then for each record we're going to
return true if that records I.D. is not equal to that one.
Remember that the filter function in general is only going to retain elements that return true from
the inner function.
So we want to return true if the I.D. is not the same inside of here I'll say a record dot I.D. not
equal to I.D. return true in that case
then we can take filtered records and save that back to our hard drive inside the users dot JS on file
some of the words pass that thing back into our right.
All function
so I will do a await this dot right all with filtered records
all right.
So let's save this and we'll do another quick test for this test.
We're going to once again have to change up our test function down here so I'm going to once again go
back over to users dot Jason and find the idea of a real record inside of here a copy let's go back
over I'm going to clean up that file or see the test function and I'll do a awaits repo.
Dot delete and then passing the idea the record that I want to delete in this case we're not going to
fetch or retrieve the records after we'll just manually open up the user dot Jason File and ensure that
one of these records got deleted all right.
So back over here I'll do a note to users not just didn't see any errors.
Well that's probably good back inside of users dot Jason.
I can now see that there is only one user left.
Perfect.
I'll go ahead and try to delete the other one as well so I'll take that I.D. paste it in save back over
to the terminal rerun the file back to my editor open up user start Jason again Yep totally empty OK.
Well delete definitely works just fine.
I think that just leaves to left.
Unless I'm missing one I think we just have get one by and update.
So let's take care of those in just a moment.