Next up it's time for another quick quiz on the stuff we've just talked about.
Variables let const var how they work.
Just the basic syntax.
So I'm going to show you three examples and I'd like you to mentally evaluate them enter the question
and then I'll come back to the answers.
So here's the first one.
What is the value of egg count.
Once this code runs positive you need to.
Here's the next one.
What is the value of rating after this code runs.
And the final one.
What is the value of wind speed here.
And then there's a second note.
What is the minor issue with this code.
So two questions.
What's the value of wind speed at the end.
And what's the minor issue with the code.
Okay so let's start with first one.
What is the value of egg count.
Well it's initialized to 42 and then on the second line we are referencing egg counts and adding two
to the value.
But that doesn't change egg count.
We're not resetting or updating egg count in any way.
We're just asking for 42 and adding two to it and then that's it.
We're not saving it anywhere to egg count.
So egg count is still 42 at the end of this the next one.
What is the value of rating after this code runs.
This one's a little trickier because we're using const so rating is set to seven point five.
And remember that means that rating will not and cannot change.
So if we tested it out let's do const rating equals seven point five seven point six.
It doesn't matter.
And then rating equals eight.
Now we get an error assignment to constant variable.
So we do get an error.
But the question was What is the value of rating it still seven point six.
We can't change it.
So that's the answer to that one.
And now the final one.
What's the value of wind speed after these three lines run.
So the first one initialize is wind speed with a value of 76.
Then we use plus equals to add five to the value.
So that takes us up to 81 and then we use the unitary operator minus minus which subtracts 1 from wind
speed and saves it to wind speed.
So we go from 81 down to 80.
So wind speed is 80 and then the last part.
What's the minor issue with this code.
The issue here is really a stylistic issue.
It doesn't follow javascript programming conventions as far as the style variable names are supposed
to be camel cased not snake case to it which is what we have here with the underscores.
So ideally this would be named wind speed like this wind speed camel cased first letter lower cased
it doesn't break anything to do it this way with the underscores.
Well it breaks the heart of JavaScript developers around the globe but it is valid code and that's it.
Nice little short quiz.