Next up two very similar events that are pretty useful.
They're called input and change on input on change are the respective properties they have to do with
inputs like we have here a text input a select a checkbox and what I want to show you is that we can
actually listen to changes across all three of these different types of inputs or different form controls
using a single event type.
And our goal here is to let's say create a data structure that looks like this.
It's an object that will automatically stay in sync or will stay updated with whatever a user is typing.
So instead of waiting for a user to hit submit like we did in the previous video where we grab the data
from each input after they submit the form we could instead just keep in sync and know exactly what
is happening in each input.
So we would have an object with maybe a key of credit card and it would be equal to whatever is in that
input.
We could have the checkbox so terms and then that could be set to true and veggie could be set to a
carrot and then as soon as one of these changes if the user checks the checkbox we want it to go to
false immediately.
We don't want to wait for a submission event so to do this we can use the input event the type of the
event is called input.
I'll show it to you now.
We'll do an event listener input and then we'll do an arrow function this time let's console that log
E.
Well let's start with credit card changed and then we'll print out the event I'll refresh and you'll
see as soon as I change this input here.
Anything which is basically whenever I type of character in here we get a new console dot log.
So the input has changed.
We also have input that target which tells me what the input actually is or what.
What triggered this event.
What the object is.
And if I wanted to create this data structure I could have const form data set it equal to an object
and then update form data of let's go with a credit card maybe all lowercase c c equals and then to
get the value it's event dot target dot value which is the target element the input itself scroll down
we'll see the value.
Where are you.
V keep going got carpal tunnel already from that scrolling.
Here we go.
That's the value or I could have just hardcoded it has credit card input dot value but I'm going to
go with event at target date value because you'll see in just a moment that we could actually refactor
this into a single callback so I'll type something in here.
Let's look at our form data and it's up to date.
Now we could do the same thing duplicate this for the very select so very select dot add event listener
for the input event which will trigger it whenever we change the value of that select.
So instead of credit card changed we'll say veggie changed and let's add to form data under the key
veggie so I'll change this value and we get our constant log.
If I look at my form data object it has veggie of carrots.
But as soon as I type something in here we look at form data.
Now it has the credit card value from that input and it has the selected veggie so it's staying up to
sync staying up to sync saying staying up to date or in sync with what we have and we can do one more
for the checkbox which is a little bit trickier and not really.
But we can't use the value we'll use the checked attribute or the checked property terms checkbox that
had event listener input event and we'll do constant log checkbox and then we'll print the event and
for form data if we want to update the form data.
Let's go with agree to terms maybe and set that equal to event that target.
We can't do value because it's a checkbox we do checked which we saw very recently.
So let's try it.
I check it.
Let's look at form data.
Agree to terms is true.
Change this.
Look at form data VEGGIE is carrot I type something in here we look at form data again and there we
go it's staying up to date.
So now we have this object that is staying in sync with whatever is going on in the form.
So we don't have to wait for a user to click submit.
We could wait for them to submit to send the data off or to do something with the data but we have a
live representation.
What's not live but a in sync representation of what's in the form and this is how we could achieve
something like this credit card form from code pin as I type.
The numbers are updating up top although they're also being obfuscated so they're not fully showing.
But whatever I type is being affected and displayed live.
So it's not waiting for me to submit and I'll add in a cardholder name that's updating up there I can
put it in the security code and that's showing on the back.
It's a pretty cool form but what I'm trying to illustrate here is that these events are all being triggered
before a user submits the javascript knows what's going on in these inputs as I type which is what we
have here.
It's just there's no functionality and nothing pretty to look at but we're doing the same thing.
So I did mention there's a better way of writing this.
This is three separate event listeners which is fine.
We need to attach an event listener to each one.
What is not great is that we're hard coding these in it would be nice if we could have one where I could
say something like you know in the event listener and in the callback where I could figure out which
input we were working with Take That input get its value and then just store that in the form data dynamically
which we can do.
And here is the simplest way of doing that I'll comment these out.
So we have them will add a name to each input.
So the first one will have maybe credit card as a name.
The second one will have a name of agree to terms.
And the third one will have a name of selected veggie Okay so we have three names now in our javascript.
We can loop over all three of these.
So I'll make an array with credit card input terms checkbox and veggie select and I'll loop over that
for let's input of
and then I'll do an input that add event listener for the input event.
We have our event here an error function.
And on this event object we have event at Target which we've already seen.
There's a property called name.
So why don't I console that log that
we'll try running it when this changes selected veggie was the name here.
Agreed a term chosen name here credit card is a name so we can use that name to add to our form data
object.
So it would be something like this form data of event out target date name equals event dot target dot
value we're taking whatever that value is and adding it in under the name that is on the input.
There's still a minor problem because our checkbox doesn't have the value we want it to have.
But if I do asparagus change my credit card number to Hello Well we'll look at form data over here and
look at that selected veggie is asparagus.
Credit card is Ello Ello well and I didn't have to actually reference any of those manually so I could
have 10 different inputs and automatically as long as I give them a name their input value will be added
to my object under their name.
Now as far as the checkbox this one's kind of annoying.
Unfortunately there is no value on a checkbox it just set to on whether it's on or off.
We still get on which is pretty obnoxious but we can write a little bit of an edge case into this function
where we can check if the type of the input is a checkbox.
So if we cancel that log e refresh my page I'll check this.
If we look at event target scroll way down every input here has type of checkbox not every input but
every input has a type.
In this case it's a checkbox here if I do the text input which is for credit card and we take a look.
Where are you target.
Scroll down.
We can find type it set to text.
So we could write a little bit of a conditional to check what type is equal to and what I would probably
do is d structure target.
That's the only thing we care about from the event.
So use a parameter rise to D structuring.
I don't even know if that's the right term for that but D structure in the parameter definition and
then I'll D structure even more.
I'll grab the name I'll grab the type the value and the checked property out of Target which is event
target and then I can update this to be form data of name equals event out target value.
But I want to check first if type is equal to checkbox if that's the case then we'll store the value
of checked.
Otherwise we store value.
So this is kind of a maybe hacky one liner but we're taking the name whatever the name is credit card
input or credit card I think it's what we want with and then we have a type which should be set to text
for that input.
We have a value which is whatever is in the input and checked won't exist for that input because it's
not a checkbox.
So then we're taking form data we're updating the property credit card which is a name and we're checking
if type is equal to a checkbox.
It's not.
So we'll use the value but then if we change the checkbox checked we'll have a value true or false and
type will be checkbox.
So this is true and we'll store the Boolean true or false from checked.
So let's console out log form data here
extra s refresh.
I'll check it.
Agree to terms true.
Check again.
False.
Now we have selected veggie is carrot type something in here.
It's updating automatically which is pretty cool.
You have one function one callback that we are using and it's working on three different inputs and
I could have more if I had four or five 10 different inputs here.
I could use this same code if all I wanted to do was create an object containing the form data.
The last thing is that I mentioned we have input and change to different events.
If I just switch this over to be a change event it will still work pretty much the same way we've got
selected veggie asparagus.
This is updating but here this won't update until I lose focus so I just clicked away or if I hit enter
so just typing in the input doesn't trigger that event but focusing or losing focus which is called
blurring the input or hitting enter will change it.
Otherwise these two are the same.
You can't really incrementally change the checkbox or the select it's just yes or no.
But with a text input there is a difference between the change event and the input event that we had
earlier.
So input will just always update whenever this updates or whenever the input itself has any new characters
in there it triggers the event.
All right so two different events and a new pattern.
This is pretty common especially if you get to something like react and some of these other frameworks
out there and other libraries you'll see code kind of like this where we use the name of an input as
a key to store the value from that input under to create a nice object that contains all of our form
data at once.