Next up we'll see how we can create elements from scratch and insert them or add them to the dome so
we could create an image.
Give it a source.
Put it on.
I don't know the beginning of the page or put it inside of a div.
We could create 100 links with different you URLs and insert them into the dom.
So here's how we do it.
The first step is to make an element and we have a method called Create element so create element is
actually really simple.
It's document doesn't create not attribute and create element and you pass in a string of the type of
element you would like.
So if we want to make a let's do a H two element we pass in H2 and that's all we get.
It makes an empty element for us but as we've seen many times so far this is not what it actually looks
like.
This is only the HCM representation.
Let's save it to a variable we'll call this new H2 and then let's do our console that desire of New
Age to it's an object.
So we're making a new element of type H2 and if we take a look at the element itself we have let's see
we've got each team all heading element that's the type of element it is.
And we have tag names set to H2 and there's no text content there's no energy content or enter each
team out in enter text they're both empty.
So if we want to put some content in that's a separate step.
All we've done is make an element.
So we made an empty H2.
Then if we want to add into it we could do new H2.
So let's just look at new H2 one more time.
It's empty.
New Age to date in enter text equals what should we put here.
I like animals.
Sure.
Oh I missed my quote.
Okay so now if we look at new H2 here's the representation of it.
I can also continue to manipulate it.
I can add a class if I wanted to.
I would just do new to New Age to that class list is probably the easiest way.
Dot ad and what classes do we even have.
Do we have any good ones.
We have to do we have special.
Let's use the class of special.
Now we look at H to her new H2 and that's what we've got an H2 attribute of class set to special and
the inner text.
I like animals.
So how do we get it in the DOM.
How do we get it to show up.
Right now it's completely severed in its own little universe in the womb of the javascript console.
How do we get it into the real world onto the page.
How do we deliver this element.
Okay enough of that metaphor here.
What we need to do is select an element to append it too.
So we have some methods here.
The first one we'll see is called append child.
Where are you.
They put that on here.
There it is.
Append child so append child is a method that we call on a parent that we want to append an element
into.
So if I wanted to append this H2 into let's go to our HD.
How about we put it in this section here.
I will select the section and then call append a child on the section and pass in our new H2 so we'll
select that section document that query selector of Section save that to a variable.
Okay and then we'll call section append child and we pass in our new age to.
This is the new element we've already made and we're now connecting it into the DOM by saying append
a child to the section and a child just means anything inside of this section.
We've already seen the children property when we append it will go to the end of the children.
So it will append down here we should see it show up after broccoli and do we.
There it is.
I like animals.
If we look at our H camel in the elements tab scroll down.
We have a section the UL that was already there.
It's now joined by a new sibling is h to let's do a couple more examples.
We also have the ability to make all sorts of different elements so why don't we try making an image
so I have an image you are I'll use here from on Splash we'll make our new image so concept.
New image equals document that create elements and we pass in image.
And if I just do that and I run my code again let's take a look at new image the same thing console
dot DVR image new image we can see that it's also an object of course for making a new element but it
has a different type it's in HD him out image element so it behaves differently.
We don't have in our text we don't work with inner turmoil because an image does not have an opening
and closing tag but it does have a source.
So let's set the source new image that source equals and I'll copy this you are all I have.
You could put any.
You are well there and now let's append it somewhere.
If we call a pen child again on the section it will go inside of the section.
If we don't want to append it to the inside of the section I just wanted to go at the end of my body.
I guess they would go after the script which maybe isn't ideal but what I could do is use the body and
call a pen child on the body or I could put it inside the form but let's do document body dot append
child and then we pass in our image document dump body dot a pen child of new image.
It's quite a large image.
Oh boy.
Very large but there it is.
So we could also give it an inline style say new image dot style dot with equals two hundred pixels
refresh again much smaller much more manageable maybe even a bit larger about three hundred.
So this process is really common.
We make a new empty element of some type.
It's always going to start out empty and then we fill in the blanks when appropriate we fill in in our
text if we need to we fill in source or a draft or classes we add an attribute.
We can do whatever we want.
So here's one more example.
I have a link for a YouTube video.
Let's make a new anchor tag.
So I'm going to copy my Euro just so I can use it and we'll do content.
New link equals document that create elements of an anchor tag.
That's the type and then we'll set the inter text
not him Albert.
Enter text.
Let's go with Mr. bubs video.
So that's the name of the video.
Wrong place for that period Mr. period Bubba's video click me.
And then we want to set the sauce.
No.
The truth source is for an image for a link an anchor tag.
We want a traffic and then let's append it to the page somewhere.
How about we select the paragraph maybe the first paragraph and we'll add it inside the first paragraph.
So concept first P equals document dot query selector p tag first p dot append child of new link.
Fingers crossed there we have a new link right here it was appended as a child of this existing paragraph
if we click it by the way it does open up our YouTube video so that's the basics of creating elements
you can create them of any different type you can fill them with content enter text you can even use
enter each team Al if you wanted to you could even append other elements into each element so we could
create an anchor tag and then create a new empty span or a bold tag and append that to the new link
and then take that independent to first paragraph so we're not done with creating elements we'll actually
get a little more practice we're gonna build a little example something slightly more complex and I'm
also going to show you a few more methods where instead of appending at the end of something but if
we want to insert at the beginning the first child of an element instead of the last.
So that's coming up next.
Oh and if you've never seen this video oh Mr. bubs is quite the character here it's a very special dog
he does not like not like love and attention or he has an odd way of showing it but this is my favorite.
Okay here we go.
Yeah I got you I got this on camera anyway.
All right.
Back to Dom stuff.