Next up sticking with D structuring.
I'd like to show you how we can work with nested objects and arrays and combine what we've seen so far
to extract individual values into variables to unpack them.
So I have an array of objects still going with the marathon theme.
So each object is a marathon runner and they are ordered still by finishing position.
So we have gold silver and bronze from the 2016 Olympic marathon.
The men's marathon.
If I wanted to extract let's say the country of second place right here.
Ethiopia using D structuring I'm inside of an array so I'm going to start with the array braces to set
the whole thing equal to results.
And in this array I want the second element.
So I'm going to skip the first one and then I'm now in the second element or I'm in that position and
we have an object.
So instead of that object I want country
it's kind of annoying that my editor is putting it on multiple lines so I'll leave it like this so you
can see it here.
If I run it right now let's see what we get in country.
We get Ethiopia.
So this comma is crucial.
We're skipping that first element.
If I wanted to extract something from that first object let's say I wanted to get a first name which
is Elliott.
So I'll write first and if I want to give it a different name or different variable name let's go with
gold winner
I'll refresh and I'll look at gold winner.
It said to Elliott and our country variable is still set to Ethiopia.
So the point here is just to show you that we can combine the syntax.
It can get a little crazy and I don't recommend nesting and doing a whole bunch of dy structuring with
nested structures instead.
If you have like super nested stuff I think it's a lot easier to understand what's going on.
If so rather than getting country this way maybe it would be easier to understand if we did const skip
the first element and then go with silver medal equals results.
And then from inside of silver medal we could extract country
so it's an extra line but some might say it's easier to read.
This isn't bad but if you had more nesting that you were trying to work with and continue to D structure
from let's say instead of country we had an array maybe someone is from multiple countries or they've
competed for multiple countries before and we wanted to extract something or unpack a value from there
then we would have another array and it just gets complicated to do structure from.
So just keep that in mind.
You can nested.
That's it I'm done.