All right now that we can decode that your well let's add in some H CML to show this a card right here
that's going to eventually have the secret message inside of it.
So once again back inside my index dot each single file.
I'm gonna find the div with class C O L right there short for column and right after it I'm gonna add
in another div I'm gonna give this one an I.D. of message about message dash show just kind of stick
with the conventionally have with these other divs well then give it a class of card dash panel and
a class of hide so by default this div is going to be completely hidden and we're not gonna show it
to the user and inside of here I'm gonna place in each one element each one is going to start off as
empty once we decode the message we're going to select this each one element and put the message inside
there.
So this is kind of a placeholder where we're we were going to eventually show a message to the user
then after that I'm gonna add in a div with an anchor element.
This is going to be a link that the user can use to create their own custom message.
So I'm gonna give this thing in a strip of dot slash index dot each female email and then inside the
anchor element I'll say create your own secret message.
So whenever a user clicks on this anchor element we're going to essentially reload the entire index
each female page or the entire document.
And that's going to take out the URL or some to take the hash out of the URL.
All right.
So now back inside of our index dot J File it we're gonna add in some code to check to see if we have
a message in the URL if we do we're going to remove the hide class from this div we're going to add
it to this div which is usually shown by default and then we will decode the message and stick it into
that H1 element.
So back over here.
I'm going to take off the console log function but keep in the code that was inside of it.
Do make sure that you fix up the number of parentheses at the very end as well.
I'll then assign this to a variable that I'll call message then we'll say if there is a message let's
toggle the visibility of those two different Divs.
So we need to select this div and add the height class and select that div and remove the hide class
so I'll do document query selector.
Well first do message dash form we'll do a class list and we'll add the high class and I'll do a second
document query selector in this case I'm going to find the idea.
Message dash show I'll look at the class list and then I will remove the hide then finally we can select
that each one element and stick our message inside of it.
So I'll do a document very selector each one in our HCM CML and I'll set the message inside of it.
Like so it's I think ready for a test so I'll save this go back over I'm going to go to the index start
each team I'll file directly I'm gonna make sure I remove the hash out the or else they're going to
test the entire flow here I'll then put in my secret message create a copy that I'm going to put it
into a new browser tab just to make sure I can assimilate passing this link off to someone else it enter
and I see my secret message appear I should then be able to click on Create your own secret message
and be taken back to this form and I don't have any hash inside the URL so it looks like we got it now
there's just one awkward thing here.
You'll notice that there's a lot of extra spacing above the H1 element that's because it's each one
element by default get some margin on the top of it.
So if I hover over it I can see that kind of orange section right above.
Again that just means by default and each one has the margin on top it's going to add in just a little
bit more of CSX to remove that margin on the top back inside my index dot each email file I'm going
to find where we have the row class and right underneath it I'll put in each one with a margin dash
top of zero so save that and one last test here I will refresh and that looks way more reasonable okay.
So I'd say this looks pretty good.
It's now the last thing we really have to figure out is how we can effectively actually share this application
with other users right now this link like we said earlier can only be shared with you on your own computer
because that is where the index not a single file lives.
So if you are just sharing messages with yourself.
Well that's not super fun so let's figure out some way to actually make this available to other people
which will definitely be a little bit more interesting.