All right.
To problem number two.
So now that we know how we're going to identify a person and the car that belongs to them.
Now the question becomes what does that shopping cart actually look like.
How are you going to represent a shopping cart.
How are we going to store information inside of it's like a list of products and whatnot.
So to answer question number two right here we're going to take a look at three different ways to store
some representation of products inside of some kind of cart thingamajig.
I'm going to show you three different approaches.
The first two are going to be bad approaches.
Just like before when we went through some bad solutions with something else we were discussing earlier
on in the course the reason I'm going to show you some bad solutions here is that you can kind of develop
a little bit of engineering sense and understand why.
One way of doing this is kind of bad.
And another way might be kind of good.
So let's take a look at our bad first two options OK.
So again we want to think about how we're going to store or kind of Associates a cart with some number
of products being inside of its.
So this is a bad approach.
No one in bad approach number one a user might make a request to our server and say add product with
I.D. one two three to my cart were then going to create some random I.D. to represent that cart for
this user.
So maybe in our case we create some random I.D. like nine eight seven and then we'll send back a response
that says Hey your cart ideas 987 we'll store that 987 inside of that user's cookie.
So anytime they make a followup request we're always going to receive back in the cookie cart I.D. is
nine eight seven.
We'll know who is making requests to our server then more specifically inside of our products repository.
We might have our list of products.
So like this is one product right here out of a big array of different products.
So in order to somehow associate the user who just wanted to add decided to a cart and a product right
here we could add in an additional property to each individual item something called like carts and
then inside this array we can store the idea of every cart that this item belongs to so some other user
made a request here so let's imagine some other browser makes a request and they also say Oh yeah at
product retired you wanted three to my cart maybe for this other user user B we randomly generate an
idea of like 555 and send that back and then inside of our products repository we might also add in
by 5 to this carts array.
So now whenever we look at this product right here we know that this product belongs to cart 8 7 and
5 5 5.
So this is one possible approach to handle this anytime that we want to figure out how many products
or which user has which products inside their cart.
We could iterate over all of our different products instead of a repository.
We could look at the Cart I.D. And if say someone with a card I.D. of 5 5 5 asks for all the products
that belong to them we'll look for all the products that have a current property that has 555 in that
array and that means that this product must belong in this user's cart.
Now the downside to this approach is that any time we want to ask about what products belong to what
users we have to iterate through our entire list of products we have to go through every list of products
or every single product we have.
You have to look at that Curt's property for every single product we have to see if some given I.D.
is present inside that array.
In addition this approach also store some information about this cart stuff with a product.
These are really two different types of information like a product object right here is really supposed
to be just about a product and nothing else.
It should just have titled price and image by adding on this cart's property right here.
We're kind of polluting the definition of exactly what a product is.
In addition over time as many many users come to our Web sites and add items to a cart and then leave
our application forever well we would just eventually end up with all these kind of strangling or orphaned
ideas floating inside this array.
So we can imagine that if a million users came to our product they added one item each to their cart
we would then end up with a million elements inside of that carts array right there.
And so this array might grow without bounds without any clear way of when we would remove any I.D. out
of there.
So I would definitely say that this is not a very good approach okay approach number two.
So this is also a bad approach but it starts to get a little bit more towards the realm of reason of
something it kind of makes sense.
So in this world we're going to once again have a user make a request to our server our server is going
to generate some idea that represents this person's cart send that I.D. back to the browser at this
time in order to represent that cart.
We're going to create a separate repository called the Hertz repository inside of their will store an
array of objects and each object represents one user's cart.
So this would be the representation of the cart for the person who just said add product with I.D. one
two three to my cart so then inside this object we might store the idea the cart and a products array
and inside this products array will destroy the entire product.
So there's product with idea one two three as a title pants a price in some image data as well so you
can now imagine that Einstein someone asked to add an item to a cart we would look at our products repository
find the appropriate item or product take that product and add it into the products array so this seems
like it's kind of a reasonable approach but there's definitely a very large downside with this kind
of style.
We're essentially making a copy of this entire product definition and storing it inside other cards
repository.
So here's the big problem.
Let's imagine that at some point in time we come through our admin panel and we decide to update the
price points of this product inside of our products repository.
So we could say like OK I know what this price to be ninety dollars but if we think back to this card's
repository we still have some representation of that product right here.
And it has the exact same properties but now they are totally out of date.
This record inside of our card's repository still has a price of 50.
So if we wanted to take this approach every single time that we edited a product we would have to look
through all the different cards we have.
We'd have to look through all the different products that they store and make sure that we update the
appropriate properties on every single one.
Which would definitely eventually be a very expensive operation.
So this is another approach approach number two.
And I would say that this is also not a very good approach okay.
Now it's on to you approach number three and this is the one that we're going to use inside of our application
so in this approach we're going have something very similar to approach number two that we just discussed.
We're still going to have a product's repository.
We're also going to have a Curt's repository.
So every time a user attempts to add a product to a cart if they don't have a cart already we're going
to generate a cart for them which means that we're going to essentially just create a new record inside
of our card's repository that's going to have a randomly assigned I.D. and a products array at this
time instead of storing the entire product inside this right we're going to instead only store the I.D.
of the product.
So in other words if a user said give me product one two three and that corresponds with this pair of
pants right here then inside of this products array for this cart we're going to store a object that
says I.D. one two three and the quantity of that product as well so the idea of one two three that is
essentially something that is pointing over to our products repository.
This is the idea of the product that the user had added.
So if you ever wanted to figure out the different products that a user has added to their cart we would
take a look at the products array and for every object inside of here we would take that I.D. and look
up that I.D. inside of the product's repository and say OK there we go product with idea 1 2 3 OK.
This person ordered some pants the price of 50 and there's the image as well.
Now the good thing about this approach is that it solves a lot of the problems that we just discussed
on the other two so at this approach we could very easily make updates to the original products repository.
So for example we could update the title or the price or the image and we would not have to worry about
going through our carts as well and updating all those things.
The downside is that the code involved with this is definitely a little bit more complicated has now.
Anytime that you want to tell a user about all the different products they have we have to like I said
just a moment ago go through this array find all those ideas and then look up the appropriate ideas
inside of our products repository.
It's definitely just a little bit more code on that front okay.
So that's pretty much it.
Those are three possible solutions we can take.
And again we're going to go with solution number three so we're going to have a card's repository that's
going to store a array of objects.
The idea of each of these is going to be stored inside of a user's cookie.
So we know exactly what user is tied to which cart and each cart is going to have the products array
each array of products is going to store the idea of a product and a quantity in the cart as well.
So now that we've got a better idea of how to approach this let's take a pause right here and start
our implementation in the next video.