All right.
So we saw how we can use reduce to some all elements in an array or multiply them altogether.
And that's one use for reduce.
But there are many other things we can do with it.
We don't have to be accumulating a value through math.
We don't have to be multiplying or adding or subtracting or dividing.
We can also do things like finding the maximum value in an array where the accumulator is really just
tracking the max.
It's not being added to or multiplied or anything like that.
It's simply referring to the current maximum value and then we potentially update Max if we find a larger
value.
So let me show you a quick example here we have grades a list of grades an array if I want to find the
max what I could do is grades done reduce.
I'll save this to a variable called Max grade and we need to pass in our callback which follows the
format of accumulator first and then current and Val next.
But instead of calling this a QM or accumulator I'm just gonna call it Max.
Then I'll add my arrow function syntax and what we need to do is check if the current value is greater
than the current Max.
So the first time this runs will have Max start at eighty seven.
Just like when we summed an array together the first total started as the first element.
So Max will be eighty seven and then current Val will go with let's do.
Curve Val here curve Val we'll start at sixty four and then we do a comparison is current Val greater
than Max if Curveball is greater than Max if it is then we will return curve Val.
And if this is not the case we'll return Max.
So whatever is returned from this function will be used as the next Max.
So the first time through Max is eighty seven current Val is sixty four.
This is not true.
Curve Ball is smaller.
So we return Max.
So if we add our return here as should come at this whole thing out.
So we don't get syntax errors that return is going to be 87 return Max when we return that value max
then uses that previous return.
So we returned eighty seven Max is eighty seven once again but next time curveball moves on to ninety
six.
So now Curveball is 96.
We do the comparison curve ball is now greater than Max 96 is greater than eighty seven.
So we return curve ball which is 96 and that return value is then used to set the new Max Max.
The third time through is going to be 96 and then we're comparing it to curve out which is 92 and I
won't waste your time going through this entire thing but this time through we return ninety six we
just return Max as is because this is not true.
And eventually we go all the way through the array and we find the max we return that Max which eventually
is ninety nine then we compare it to 73.
We keep returning ninety nine ninety nine ninety nine and then reduce returns.
That final return value which is ninety nine.
So let's run it and just make sure I'm not crazy.
Let's take a look at X grade.
It is indeed ninety nine.
We could also rewrite this in a pretty different way.
There's a couple different approaches using reduce fi comment this out instead of returning curveball
or returning Max we can use the built in math dot Max.
So math out Max you pass in two numbers like three and five and it will tell us the maximum number three
and ten is ten nine and one we get nine.
So we could use that and replace this whole line with return math dot max of the current Max and the
current value that we're looking at if we run it Max grade is still ninety nine and we could also write
a mean grade keep this exactly the same although I would rename this to be men.
This represents the minimum value that we are keeping track of as we go through as reduce calls our
callback over and over and over.
It will pass in the current men.
So return math dot men and if you wanted to you could even use an implicit return since we have a single
expression there get rid of the return keyword.
Let's look at mid grade.
Max is not defined.
Need to update that to be men as well so men grade is now sixty four Max is ninety nine.
So same logic just wrote it in a different way here we're doing the math ourselves.
Here the comparison here.
We rely on math dot Max.
But what really matters is the way reduce works.
So we're not summing things together.
We're not multiplying them into a accumulator variable the term accumulator or total kind of makes me
think of something that is growing or getting bigger but that's not what happens here.
This parameter which we're calling Max is simply pointing to one value and then potentially pointing
to a different value instead as soon as we find a new Max it updates to be that Max.
So it's not accumulating so much as just keeping track of the max.
And before we move on to our third video on reduce which I'll show you some even some more interesting
or different use cases for reduce.
That's coming up next.
Before we do that there's one extra argument I haven't mentioned when you use reduce you can actually
pass in an initial starting value.
So after your callback the format would be something dot reduce.
So we'll do a readout reduce you pass in your callback and then initial value.
Now this callback is usually an inline anonymous function so it ends up being kind of long.
But at the end after your function you can add a comma and then an initial value.
So if we write a simple reducer function let's just go back to to adding numbers together.
So we'll do How about 10 20 30 40 and 50 dot produce add in our aero function.
We'll go with some and then let's go with Coeur thou
right now.
If we return some plus curve Val let's store this in a variable concept sum.
Let's look at some.
It's 150 is that correct.
Let's see.
I think that makes sense right.
Fifty one hundred and then 40 plus.
Yeah.
150 when we don't specify an initial value it will just use the first element which we saw a couple
of slides ago here.
No here where the accumulator starts as three.
That's the first element and the current value starts at five.
But you can initialize with a custom value so I can say I want some to start at 0 which is gonna give
us the exact same result.
We start with 0.
Then we add 10 then 20 then 30 then 40 then 50.
That's exactly the same number at the end of the day as starting with 10 20 30 40 50.
But if we instead pass a number like 1000 Here are some will start at 1000 then add 10 then 20 then
30 and we end up with one thousand one hundred and fifty.
So you probably wouldn't do this right here specifically where you want the sum and you want to start
at 1000.
But there are other use cases which we'll see in the next video where you can specify an initial value.
And it won't even be a number.
We'll see that we can specify an object if we're trying to accumulate data into an object and that's
what we're going to see.
Next up.
So to wrap this up we saw that you can use reduce not just to multiply or to some things together but
also to keep track of the max or the men or some piece of data.
It doesn't have to be max or min.
It could be the longest string in an array the highest rated book whatever it is.
As we iterate over each element in an array we are keeping track of some piece of data.
And then the second thing we saw is that we can pass in an initial value as the second argument to reduce.
So this whole thing is the first argument right before that comma and then the second argument is right
there.
All right we're almost done.
We've got some other cool use cases coming up next.