In the last video we extracted require e-mail require a password and so on into a separate helper file.
In that last video I made a little typo when we were putting together the validators start J as file.
It's going to open up validate or stop us at the very top.
I've got that require statement for users repo.
I only reference the repositories directory.
I didn't actually get the user's file inside there so I got to make sure that I fixed up that require
statement right there.
Once I've got that in there I can do a quick test inside my browser just make sure that everything actually
works.
So I will refresh.
Yep I can still see everything.
I'm going to enter in some email and some not matching passwords.
In this case I see a count created even though my passwords weren't matching.
That is ok because right now even though we are getting an error during that validation scheme or that
validation step we're not actually handling the error in any way.
And so that's actually a pretty good segway into what we're gonna do in this video.
So in this video we need to make sure inside of our host request handler that if any error occurred
we need to not create an account for the user.
Instead we need to re render the exact same form that we showed before and we need to display some error
messages inside of it.
So this is really the last big step that we have to go through.
But to take care of this I'm gonna replace that console log with a little if statement.
We're going to check to see whether or not any errors occurred.
To do so we're gonna say if not errors dot is empty so the is empty method is going to be true.
If nothing went wrong we'd only care about the case in which something didn't go wrong.
So that's what we have the not on here.
So if errors is not empty then let's return early and I want to show the same form that we showed previously.
I want to show the sign up template again.
We're gonna do exactly what we did up here when we showed the original form.
We're gonna set back the sign up template.
We're gonna pass in some arguments to customize that template so I'm going to return red dot sent sign
up.
Template I'm gonna pass in the wreck object and I also want to pass in the errors as well so we can
reference all those errors inside of our template and print them out.
Okay so let's now go open up our sign up template file.
We're going to receive that is property we're going to take a look at all the errors inside of it and
print them up inside of our form
go inside my views directory I'll find admin off sign up J.S. then inside of here.
In addition to the Rec object we also are now going to d structure out the heirs object as well before
we start to make use of that heirs object at all.
There's something important I want to mention to you.
Remember that inside of objects we're going to call sign up template so the same function we're just
looking at with only a wreck object and there is no heirs property inside of here.
So only when are there is an error during the Senate process is the heirs property going to be around
inside the sign up template.
So in other words heirs right here.
That might be undefined or it might be an array of heirs.
So we have to write some code inside of here somewhat defensively to check to see if there are any heirs
and only if there are only in that case do we want to start to show them inside of our form so to handle
all that stuff for us.
We're gonna use a little helper function at the top right above the module but experts are going to
write out a helper function called get air so the idea here is that we're going to take in the heirs
as the first argument and then the second argument is going to be the property name that we want to
get an heir for.
We have many different heirs that we might have.
So we might have an heir for email one for password in one for password confirmation.
So I want to go to reach into this heirs object and pull out just the heirs around email and just the
heirs are on password and just the heirs around password confirmation.
So as the second argument I'm going to expect to receive some property name which I'm going to abbreviate
as prop.
So in this case prop is going to be equal to email or password or password.
Confirmation so using the prop we need to take a look at our ears.
See if one error occurred related to email password or password confirmation.
And then if one did it we're going to return the error message to do so.
We're going to first check to see if there are any errors at all if there are no errors then hey we
don't care about this otherwise if there are some errors we're going to return errors dot mapped
at prop dot message.
OK.
Kind of a crazy line right there.
Let's discuss what's going on when we usually work with the ears object right here.
It's actually an array and we saw that many times back at our terminal.
If I go back over I can see that we've got this and the result thing with errors inside of it.
So when we call errors not mapped it's going to essentially take this array right here and give it back
to us as an object.
The keys of that object are going to be the different parameter names and the different values are going
to be this entire object right here so in other words we can kind of break up that statement that we
just put together.
It was not mapped is going to give us back an object.
So it's not mapped.
All right.
A quick comment here is going to end up as an object with keys like e-mail and password
and password confirmation and inside of each of those objects are the objects we're just looking at
inside of our terminal.
So value message RAM and location so the only one that we really care about in this case is NSG.
Short for message and that's got me something like invalid email or whatever password will be like password
to shorts or whatever else and for password confirmation and might be something like passwords must
match so that's what the results of this expression really does.
Ears not mapped gives us this big object.
Then the square brackets with prop is going to look up the appropriate sub object inside their.
And then finally we reference the DOT NSG properties short for message to get the actual string that
we care about.
Now there's one little gotcha inside of here we just discussed why we have to put errors on here.
Well there's actually kind of a second gotcha.
And that is if there is no validation error with the e-mail or with password auth password confirmation
then this entire object is just not going to exist inside of here.
After recall errors dot maps.
So for example if there was no air with email validation that property won't even be there.
Now the reason that's a problem is that if we call errors dot maps and we try to look up email inside
there.
So in other words if prop is equal to email like so then that right there just that part is going to
return undefined or then going to try to access the MSU property on undefined.
And that would lead to the classic error message of cannot read property messages of undefined or something
similar to that.
So in order to handle all these different corner cases we're going to use a little bit of a sheet rather
than doing an if statement right here.
I'm going to instead use a try catch statement.
So now we're going to say OK let's try to get error mapped.
We'll try to look up a given property inside there and we will try to retrieve a message.
There are two locations inside of this little tiny segment right here where something bad can happen.
First off errors might be totally undefined because we might not have any errors object at all.
In addition when we look up the given property there might not be any corresponding object inside there.
So two locations where this line can blow up horribly.
So rather than trying to put in a bunch of if statements to capture all those possibilities we'll just
say you know what if something is going to go wrong with that line of code let it go wrong whatever.
So if something goes wrong I don't care.
Chances are there is no error message to show anyways.
So if we end up in the catch statement it means that we were trying to look up an error message that
doesn't even exist.
So instead I'm just gonna return an empty string.
Now this right here is a little bit of a cheat to use a try catch statement to handle this.
The technically like super correct way would be to do a series of IF statements but there are just many
different cases to check.
So at the end of the day it's little bit easier to just do a try catch okay.
So now last up we're going to call get error after each of our different inputs and when we call get
error we're going to pass on the errors object in the property that we want to look up inside their
SO AFTER input of email I'm going to do dollar sign curly brace get error I'm gonna pass it airs which
remember might be undefined if it is.
That's OK because we're always going to catch and return an empty string and a second argument I'll
say that I want to look up the email and we'll see if there was any validation errors around email and
then going to copy that twice or the second one I'll change email to password because we want to display
errors around the password and then finally at the bottom one password confirmation and that hopefully
is it.
So let's save this going to go back over.
I'm gonna go to my sign up form I'm gonna put in an invalid e-mail I'm gonna put in a password that
is too short and a password that is too long.
Well then sign up and there we go.
So I'm now told right after that email input must be a valid e-mail parser must between four and twenty
characters password must be between four and twenty characters.
So we're now displaying some very helpful validation errors to our user which is exactly what we're
going for all along this looks pretty good.
This is a long video so let's do a wrap up right now and we'll discuss exactly everything we just did
in the next video.