Just a moment ago we were able to run our program and see a console log of all of our different files.
Now when we put this function together or specifically the reader function I had said to you Oh yeah.
If we put in a string of just period that means take a look at all the files in the current working
directory we can actually see that that works correctly.
If we go back over to our terminal I'm back inside of my list directory.
If I now go up one folder and then run a node list index dot J.S. from here.
Now this is going to or that period inside the index dot j ust file is when to use the contents of the
directory that I ran node from as the essentially current working directory for my program.
So that little period is really powerful and it's going to change exactly what folder we are pointing
at.
But usually we do not use that period little shortcut right there that often instead we're going to
use a little built in function to node that belongs to another module inside the standard library.
Let's pull up the documentation and get a better idea of how we're going to replace that little dot
right there with something a little bit more effective.
So back at the node documentation on the left hand side I'm going to find a section called process an
inside of here.
I'm going to do a search for C W D.
There it is right there.
I'll click on it so this CW D stands for current working directory.
This is going to return the path of the directory that our program is executed from at the terminal.
We're going to very frequently use current working directory here instead of that dot because it has
much better cross platform compatibility.
So in other words if you run this function on a Windows or a Mac or a Linux based system it's going
to be a lot more reliable than just throwing in that little dot even though that essentially means the
same thing.
So I'm going to go back over to my editor.
I'm going to find that dot right there and I'm going to replace it with process dot see WD you're going
to notice right away that I did not do a require statement for the process module at the very top.
In other words I did not say process require process.
So it turns out that the process module is automatically added into the global scope of every project.
So it does not have to be it required ahead of time to actually make use of it.
We can just access this module directly.
This is one of a very few or only modules that behaves in that way.
So just about every single other module we see listed off here on the left hand side.
We're going to have to add a require statement for now if I say this file again go back over to my terminal
I'm once again inside my workspace directory and I can see the list folder that I just greeted right
there.
So if I now do node list index dot J.S. again I'm going to get the exact same output.
I can go back into the list folder do node index dot j ust directly and I still get the same output.
So it seems like nothing is different.
And to be honest well there's not really a lot of different functionality here.
But again we usually favor using that process dot current working directory if we ever want to figure
out where exactly our program was executed from.
That's a good little stability improvement.
Let's take another pause right here.
Continue in just a moment.