Next up we've got our final Array method for this section a readout sought.
Now it sounds simple it sounds like it's going to take the data and sorted that is what it sets out
to do.
But the way it sorts it might surprise you.
So if you look at the docks it tells us the sort method sorts the array of elements or sorts the elements
of an array in place and returns the sorted array.
So let's test it out.
I have an array of songs or let's say women's names based off of songs.
We'll go with this.
I guess people if I try and sort this I would do people that sort.
And it looks like it works alphabetically.
We have Angie Jolie and Maggie Mae.
Mrs. Robinson Roxanne.
That sounds correct.
It's alphabetically correct.
If we look at people it is indeed updated.
It was mutated it was sorted in place and people that saw it also returned the value to the sorted array.
So it updates your array in place and it returns it.
So if you wanted to you could capture it but where it gets tricky is if we have an array let's say of
numbers let's just go with numbers nothing creative here 34 10 whatever that is one hundred thousand
sixty seven and ninety nine.
Let's try doing numbers that.
And you can see what we get here 10 and then 100000 and then thirty four sixty seven ninety nine.
What's happening here is that it's not sorting based off of the numeric value it converts every single
value to a string.
And then it compares their character codes their UTF 16 codes.
Behind the scenes which we briefly talked about when we covered less than and greater than with strings.
So this is the default behavior of a radar sort.
It's odd.
I really can't get a straight answer on hand as far as why this was decided.
It's pretty unique as far as among other programming languages and nobody uses this or almost nobody
uses it as is what they do instead is pass in something called a compare function.
So if you look at the standard way that people use a radar sort it might look like this where there's
a function passed in and we haven't talked about that yet.
So we will revisit it.
Once we do because we'll be able to actually sort things the way we want them to be sorted.
But I figured it was best to address early because I've seen a lot of students assume that array dot
sort is a numeric sort when it's not.
So I just want to cover that now.
It is surprising if you don't pass in a function and tell it how to sort the default sort is based off
of string character codes which leads to some unexpected results.
But we will be back in a bit once we talk about functions.
We'll learn how to actually make story work the way we wanted to.