OK so in the last video we had a long discussion about where we're going to store data inside of application.
So again we're going to store at the current time inside of that input element that is going to be our
source of truth.
That is really going to be the only place that has any information about what our current timer is.
So in order to actually get some value inside there and updated over time I'm going to first go over
to my index start each CML file inside of here I'm going to find that input element and I'm going to
give it a value property and I'll start off as 30.
Now whenever we assign an HMO attribute it always has to be a string.
So notice how this is a string that says 30.
So we just need to keep that in mind as soon as we start to read a value out of this text input to figure
out how much time is left on our timer.
We're going to get a string.
We're going to have to convert it into a number.
Well then go back over to my index dot j ust file it's over here.
I'm then going to go down to my tick method.
I'm going to delete that console log of tick and inside of here I'm going to add in some code to reach
into the text input.
I'm going to get the current value out of it.
We're going to subtract one from it and then throw that updated value back inside the input though to
do so we're going to first get a reference to the text input.
Remember we already have a reference to it inside of our class as this dot duration input.
That was one of the arguments to our constructor so inside of here I'll say time remaining is going
to be this dot duration input dot value.
Now the value right here once again that is going to be a string.
So we have to take that string and turn it into a number to do so.
We're going to wrap that thing inside of hearts float the parts float function is built into the job
script language so we can just freely reference it at any point time.
This function is going to take a string that contains a number and it's going to pull out just the number
part of that string and give it back to us.
There are two functions that do this kind of operation.
There's parts int and parts float pass it is short for pass integer pass it will give us a number that
does not have a decimal whereas past float will give us a number that has a decimal.
So just as a quick example if we have some string that has like ten point one inside of it and we ran
it through pass INT.
That would give us 10 if we ran it through pass float that would give us ten point one so we're going
to use pass float because we're going to eventually support decimals inside of our timer okay.
So after we get our time remaining we can do a update to the value of time remaining and give the new
value or through the new value back in to the input element so we can say this dot duration input dot
value is going to be time remaining minus 1 Okay.
And that should pretty much be it.
So let's not go back over to our browser and say both these files and test this out so I can refresh
over here I can now see the default value of 30 which I set inside the HDMI file.
I'll then click on starts and I'll see the timer start to count down now the very good thing about this
approach or can the nice thing if I click on pause right here and I update that value to say three hundred
and then click on Start My time was just going to work right away the way I expect we do not have to
add in any additional event handlers to watch for a change event and change some internal representation
of that timer inside of our timer instance that's what we would have had to do to get a change to work
correctly you and I would have had to set up that event listener watch for a change the input element
and then wrote that updated value back inside the timer instance.
So again nice thing about this approach a little bit less work from the get go OK.
So this definitely works but let's take a quick pause right here and I want to point out something about
the current state of our code inside the tick method.
We're going to figure out some way to kind of condense the code we have inside of here just a little
bit so quick pause and I'll see you in just a moment.