All right.
We're on to our very last method here called get one by the goal this method is to call it with some
filters object and then return the first user inside of our collection of users that matches those filters.
So the big question here is obviously what exactly is this filters object.
Well it's go back over to our code and we'll give you a better idea of what that filters object is supposed
to be it's back inside of my test function right here.
I'm going to give you a quick demonstration of how we're going to eventually call get one by.
So it's going to look something like this a await repo.
Get one by and we're going to pass in an object and this is what is going to contain all the different
filters.
So inside of here we might put in something like email with test at test dot com.
The goal here is that we're going to go through our big list of users and we're gonna find the first
one that has an email exactly equal to test at test dot com we can also add in multiple properties into
this filter object.
So for example if I also add in a password of my password now we're saying go through all of our different
users and find the first user with an email of test at test dot com and a password of my password.
We could even optionally add in say the idea as well.
So now this would be fine the first user that that I.D. that e-mail and that password so we can have
all these different properties or just one.
So we could take this all the way down to just find me the user with a password of my password like
so so get one by is going to be a very flexible method we can use to find any arbitrary record with
any arbitrary set of properties inside of it.
Now that we've got a better idea of what this filters object is all about let's start to write out the
code for this OK right after my update method I'm going to add in a new method called get one by I'll
make sure they market as async and I'm going to receive the filters argument like so so then inside
of here we're going to first get our big collection of all of our different records.
So we'll say here's my records I'll await this not gets all well then iterate through this collection
of records.
So we'll do a four Let's record of records and then inside of here I'm going to first declare a temporary
variable called found and I'll initialize it with the value of true then immediately after that we're
going to iterate over our filters objects we're going to take a look at every key value pair and for
every key we're going to compare the value to the key or the value at the appropriate key inside the
record object if they are not the same then we're going to update found two false otherwise if they
are the same then we won't update found at all.
Then after we iterate through all the different properties inside of filters if found is still equal
to true that means we must have found the record we are looking for.
So we will immediately return it now a verbal description doesn't really help.
So let's just write out the code here and I think you'll get a better idea of what we're doing.
The step one we want to iterate through all the key value pairs of the filters object.
So I'll say for let key in filters are very important to note here we have to for loops the outer for
loop is a for of loop because we are iterating through a array the inner for loop is a for in loop.
So notice the keyword right there in we are using a for in loop here because we are iterating through
an object when we iterate through an object using a for in loop we're going to receive every key inside
of that object so we can look up the value inside of the object at that particular key with filters
at key that would give us like my password right there and the key variable would refer to password
we're going to use this for in loop to iterate through all the key value pairs of filters so then inside
there will say if the record at this key is not equal to filters at key that means that the email or
of the email or password or whatever that we just passed inside the filters object is different than
the email or password or whatever inside of the record that we are currently iterating over.
So if that is the case we're going to flip found two false which means we did not just find the record
we're looking for and after he finished this inner for loop we'll take a look at the found boolean.
So if found is still equal to true or in other words if just if found like so.
Because those are equivalent.
That means that we must have found the record we are looking for because all the keys and values in
the filters object and our record are the same.
So if that is the case we will return.
Record Okay so that's pretty much it.
Let's now do a quick test back inside of our test method.
Down here I've got in a wait repo get one by I'm gonna make sure they put in some key value pair for
a record that actually exists.
So right now back inside my user start Jason File I've got a user with an email of test at test dot
com so I'm going to update my filters object right here to look for a user with an email of test at
test dot com or then assign that to a user variable and do a console log of user if everything worked
I should see a console log of this entire object right here it's all going to save the file I'll go
back over run node users day Yes And sure enough there we go now we can try to add on an additional
property for this filtering criteria so my filters object right here in addition to trying to find a
user with that given email I'm going to try to find a user with the password as well of my password
so if I now say this again run my code yep still find the appropriate user but if I tried to find a
user with say a password of something like that right there.
Well that user doesn't exist.
So in this case I would expect to see undefined so if I say it again run it yet undefined because we
didn't find the appropriate user.
And then finally one last test here.
Let's try to search by ideas well I'll first try to find an actual user so I'm going to copy the idea
right there and put it in as my filtering criteria I'll save that run again Yep it works and if I try
to find a user with a garbage I.D. save it didn't find it.
OK one last test the very last test.
What happens if we try to find a user with a property that just doesn't exist.
So a property of like gibberish with a value of 1 to 3 inside of a string we'll try this as well.
And yet there's definitely no user inside of our repository with a key of that right there any value
of string one two three.
So I would definitely expect to see undefined there.
OK.
So that is the get one by method and well that is pretty much our users repository overall.
So we've now got this really useful set of code or this useful set of methods right here that allow
us to work with a collection of users and manipulate them in some really predictable fashion.
Now that we've got this all put together we can get back to our original application and continue working
on these sign up and sign in functionality of our app so quick pause and I'll see you in just a minute.