We've now got some validation displaying on our form.
Right now it looks really ugly.
We are going to eventually fix up the styling of this form.
We're gonna take care of that in just a little bit.
It's now that our sign up form is essentially all put together.
We're going to repeat the same process for our sign in form as well.
So inside my off dot J.S. file inside my roots admin directory.
I'm going to go down to our post request handler for these sign in Roots.
Here it is right here.
So once again we want to add in some validation around email and password.
We want to check to make sure that the email isn't email and that the password well is like present
or exists.
Then we're also going to make sure that we check to see that the email provided actually exists inside
of our users repository and that the password provided compares or is equal to the one that we had stored
inside there as well so let's get to it.
We're going to add in our validators directly inside of an array as the second argument once again we're
going to write out the validators directly inside of here like the entire chain.
And then we will eventually move them over to that validators jazz file that we created just a moment
ago.
The reason I want to put the validators together inside of here first is just so we can see them right
away and see the entire code that is being executed or the post request sign in handler OK.
So in this case we're gonna do a check of email and a check of password and the most part the validation
on both these is going to be similar to what it was like before.
So for the email we're going to trim it we're then going to make sure that we normalize it and then
we will validate that it actually is an email OK.
So simple enough and we can do something similar for the password as well so we can trim it and then
we can check and see if it is some minimum and maximum length.
So I'll say is like the min of four and a max of 20 now.
I got a quick question for you.
Does it make sense to validate the length of the password provided when a user is signing in.
In my opinion just my opinion here it does not make sense to validate the incoming password.
Why is that.
Well I want to throw out a hypothetical situation.
I want you to imagine that when we first create our application our validation rules to allow a user
to sign up requires Whoops it's in their file now.
So our validation rules to sign up for are the very start of our application.
We're going to say you have to have a password with a minimum of four characters and a maximum of 20
then maybe sometime later after a bunch of users sign up to our application we changed those rules and
we say well you know what we want some more secure passwords.
So now we're going to require a minimum length of 10 characters.
Well now whenever a user tries to sign in if they were in that first batch or that first cohort of users
who were allowed to have passwords of length for now every time they tried to sign in they're going
to fail this validation check right here because their password that they're trying to enter is not
long enough so they would be totally locked out of our application entirely because they wouldn't even
be able to log in to change their password at all.
So in my opinion doing validation on the password during these sign in process specifically around the
link just doesn't make a whole lot of sense so I am going to remove that is length check.
I am going to add in after that to our email check right there.
Let's put on a with message just like we did previously.
So if the email provided is not an email let's make sure that we display a message of something like
must provide a valid email
OK.
So that is all the validation we're going to do using the built in validators your note.
You'll notice that we're not even checking to see if a password was provided.
So a user could enter an empty string here for all we care at the end of the day.
It doesn't make a big difference because well all we really care about is that they enter the valid
password so they can choose not to enter a password.
They could choose to enter a password is too short too long.
One that has weird characters inside of it.
It just doesn't matter because at the end of the day the only thing we care about is that after hashing
that password it is equal to the original one that we had stored.
So now that we've got these built in validators put together we're going to once again put together
some custom validation steps.
So we're going to wrap up all the logic that's going to make sure that there is an existing user with
that same email.
We're also going to create a custom validator to make sure that the correct password was entered as
well let's take care of a customer validator to make sure that the you know provided actually corresponds
with a user so on the email check a chain on a custom I'm gonna mark the function inside of your as
async as I want to use the async await syntax then receive the email that the user provided and inside
of here we'll do const user is a weight users repo it one by and remember how that function works we
provide a kind of filtering object right here.
So I want to find a user with an email equal to the email that was provided and as usual we can condense
that down to just email inside of a set of curly braces then we'll check and see if we actually found
a user.
So we'll say if there is no user
let's throw a new error and say email not found.
So again if we throw that error message that is a sign that something went wrong with our validation
process so validator Express is going to say OK.
There must be an error associated with this email property and we will later see that appear once we
kind of gleam ALL OF OUR EARS FROM OUR REC object as we did previously
OK.
Let's now go back up to our post request handler.
Remember up here we were signed up ran validation result on that request to get back our ears object.
Let's do that once again.
We're going to check to make sure that the customer validator that we just put together works the way
we expect so inside of my sign in root handler the one that we're working on right now will say const
errors is going to be validation result of req and then we'll do a console log of the errors so we get
back.
All right so let's save this.
I'm gonna go back over to the browser I'm gonna go to my sign in route now I'm going to enter in a valid
email and a valid password.
Actually what we're trying to make this thing fail to enter and a email that actually doesn't exist
at all.
Let's take care of that.
So I'm gonna put an email that definitely doesn't exist but it is technically a valid e-mail help put
in some random password as well so now I'm told.
Email not found.
That is from our original validation code.
That is not from the validator stuff we just put together to see what the validator set spat out.
We need to go to our terminal and check out the results of that council log so at my terminal I can
see.
OK we've got some errors there is an error around the email specifically that email was not found.
All right so I definitely say that that first custom validator worked out the way we expect.
So this is looking pretty good.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we're gonna set up the custom validator to make sure that the password
entered is valid as well.