In our final video on reduce yes we have almost made it to the end here.
We're going to see a completely different way of using it where we can tally up results from an array
we can group different values in an array using an object.
So here's a simple example.
I have an array of votes which I'm storing as y and n.
It could also just be true and false it could be yay or nay.
We could have multiple votes we could have yes or no and abstain.
We could have ratings but what we're going to do is use produce to produce an object where we have Y
and we count the number of Y's like twelve and then the number of no's like eight.
No I don't think that's accurate for this exact array but this is what we're going for.
So what we're going do is a little different.
Our accumulator.
The thing that will actually return and add into or update is going to be an object.
So we're going to have votes that reduce we'll have some function just call it func for now and our
initial value will be an empty object.
So I'll call this concept results maybe equals vote start reduce our function which we have yet to fill
out in the initial value is an empty object.
Remember we specify an initial value like 100 accumulator the first parameter to our reduced callback
starts at 100.
In this case we're using an object.
So a little bit different but the same idea the initial value will be this empty object.
Okay.
So I'll draw it out down here then we're going to write our callback.
I'll use an arrow function.
The first piece is the accumulator.
This is the the piece of you can think of it as like a memory from last time from the last iteration
of reduce.
I'm gonna call this one tally because that's what it represents.
It's not really a sum or a total total would be OK.
But tally is it makes sense here and then we'll have current item or current vote or let's just call
it Val.
All right.
Then an arrow function and what we want to do here is add to this object using whatever key we have.
So let's say it's why we want to check is there a Y in this object.
Because the very first time we encountered y there won't be a key for why it's just empty.
So if we encounter y we'll want to say Y is one then the next time through.
We're not going to set y to 1.
We're going to check is there a y already.
Yes.
That was the first time through.
So add one to it then we'll get to n and we'll check.
Is there an N in this object.
No there's not.
So set it equal to 1.
So we'll have Y 2 and 1 and then next time we get to an N will incremented.
So our logic will look something like this.
If tally of Val meaning if we already have that key in the object we're going to want to incremented.
So tally of Val plus plus.
That means there's already something in there.
So not this case the very first time through this code does not run because there is no value in tally.
There is no yes there is no no.
So otherwise that's the if part.
I'll do this some more verbose way first so we'll do tally Val plus equals.
If it's already in there if it's not in there we'll write tally of Val equals 1.
We'll set it to 1 and then at the end we'll return tally.
Okay so tell me starts the very first time through it's an empty object.
Our Val is why.
The first element is their tally of Val.
No it doesn't exist.
This does not run here but this does.
So we set tally of Val to be 1 and we return that.
So the next time through we have y 1.
So now tally is equal to this object.
That's what we're returning.
Just like we did when we some things together or when we found the match with the men same pattern.
We're just changing tally in a different way.
We're not accumulating in the same format but we are persisting this.
We're returning it and the next time through the return value is used as tally so we get to another
y y one.
This is our object if tally of Val while there is y in this object.
So that means we're going to increment it to be too y.
And you can see where I'm going with this will eventually hit and there is not an end in here.
So this part here does not run and we instead set tally of n equal to 1 and then we keep going.
So let's see what we end up with.
We'll run this.
What do we get when we call results.
It looks like seven yeses and six no's.
Uh I guess we can count that or count the wise one two three four five six seven and the nose.
One two three four five six.
Great.
So if we had instead added some other types of votes in here like mm mm mm mm.
I don't know.
And a.
Or how about absent
let's just leave it like that.
We'll run it again results.
Now we have yes is seven absent one and knows six.
Now there is a shorter way of writing this.
The logic itself that we have here and I'll show that to you right now instead of doing this if and
else where we're checking if tally of Val exists and if it does we'll add one if it doesn't we'll initialize
it to one we can rewrite this slightly differently we'll say tally of Val equals and bear with me for
a second tally of Val or zero plus one OK so how does this one line work.
Well it all hinges upon this right here.
Tally of all or zero.
So if our object is empty at the beginning there is no Y there's no end.
We don't have any keys.
The very first time we encounter Y for example we're going to set tally of Y to equal the current tally
of Y which doesn't exist.
So that gives us undefined or zero which results in zero.
So we're doing 0 plus 1 which is going to set it to 1.
But the next time through if we encounter y again the very next element is Y.
We'll set tally of Y equal to tally of Y which right now is 1.
So then this becomes 1 1 or 0 gives us 1.
So then we end up with one plus 1 which is 2.
So it's kind of a sneaky way of doing what we're doing up here.
If something exists add one to it.
If it doesn't exist set it to 1.
We're just doing it in one line taking advantage of this Boolean logic.
So I need to reset that to tally of Val run this code again results.
It still works.
So just a shorter way of writing it.
Okay so this is equivalent to this.
We get the same result.
One more example of using reduce.
I have the same books array we've been working with I added in a new book.
Where are you.
A truly horrible book.
I wanted to give one a bad rating but I didn't want to call out a real book and give it a bad rating.
So this is a truly horrible book written by save your time save your time.
I get it.
Save your time.
Very funny.
So what I want to do is group all of these books in a new object and I want to group them by rating
so all books that have a two star review will go.
It will be an array then we'll have all books that have a three star.
So three point something not just exactly three but three point six seven and three point.
Where are you.
Three point eighty three.
And then all the four star books will go into the key of four.
So I'm going to use reduce for this book Stop reduce and we're gonna add our accumulator function here.
Just put gibberish and we'll set the initial value to be an object as well.
Just like we did up here we initialize it right there or we give it an initial value.
Okay.
So our function is going to look like this.
We'll have our accumulator parameter first.
I'll call this grouped books.
And then after that we'll have each book error function.
Then we need to get the rating from the book so book dot rating.
But I want to eliminate the decimal.
I don't want to use this as the key because that's far too unique.
I only want three.
So I'm going to do a math dot floor and that floor will just chop the decimal point off right.
Math top four of five point four gives us five five point nine still gives us five.
So it's not rounding it's just chopping off the decimal.
So I'm going to save that for a variable we'll call this key.
Key equals that rating.
So this will give us to three or four off the current data set at least.
And then we want to check does grouped books of key facts that exist if not we're going to make it an
empty array.
So I'd probably just do this if not grouped books of that key meaning there is currently no book with
rating of three rating of four or whatever rating we're working with.
Then I'll set grouped books of that key to be an empty array because remember our goal here is to create
an object where we have three which is an array of books.
So each one of these would be a book with a rating of three point something.
So if key is for if there is no grouped books of four it's empty then we're going to say grouped books
of four is equal to an empty array but then we also want to push in so that we'll be grouped books of
key dot push the entire book so let me make this a bit bigger.
And then finally we'll return our group's books.
OK so this one's a bit longer.
Could definitely shorten it up again.
But just to summarize how it works.
We have an empty object at the beginning.
We encounter our first book which is all the way up here.
It has a rating of four point two five.
So we get that rating.
We chop the decimal off now.
Key is for.
We're going to check.
Is there a key A4 in grouped books.
There's not.
It's an empty object.
So we're going to set it equal to an empty array.
So we end up with four empty array.
Then we say grouped books of four dot push the entire book.
So that's when we add the whole book into that array and then the process starts again this time for
three and let's say we get to another four star book like this one we're going to get the key which
will be for chop the decimal off.
We have for this part is false because grouped books of that key does exist now.
So we only push.
We don't do this.
We don't set it to an empty array.
We only push in a new book.
So now we have two books in their let's make sure it works.
Save it to a variable count the grouped by ratings.
It's kind of a long variable.
Let's see grouped by ratings.
We have our two star book just as one book a truly horrible book.
We have two three star books and then we have our four Starbucks so this is a little bit more complicated.
Definitely.
That's why I saved these examples for the very end after we got maybe a little comfortable with produce.
If you're at all struggling with this I don't blame you.
This is a weird one and why I kind of said I was scared to teach it and why I always worry a bit about
teaching reduce.
It's hard to teach because there's so many uses for it.
It's not as straightforward as the other built in array callback methods but don't feel bad if you are
struggling with it you'll get more practice.
It will come more naturally with time hopefully.
It always trips beginners out.
OK.
So that's produce lots of different ways of using it but it boils down to pun intended.
This diagram here where we take multiple elements from an array and we turn them into one result somehow
whether it's a some a product or a min a max or we're tallying them into an object or we're grouping
them by rating or by genre or whatever we end up with one result at the end multiple values into one
value that's reduce.
We made it and we're done with this section.
Congratulations.
This is a very meaty section.