Righty.
We survived that massive chunk of array methods.
Hopefully we all survived it.
Now we're going to address this third bullet point here.
Just one video but a very important topic.
The idea of reference types in JavaScript so you'll have to bear with me here for a moment.
We're going to take a step back two strings or numbers any of the primitive types we saw earlier.
Strings numbers billions.
No undefined.
All those they work differently than things like a race and objects which we're about to cover.
So let's take a look at an example here of a single string.
Let's go with fruit equals orange.
Suppose we have this example string variable called fruit.
And I make a another variable called color so I'll do that color equals fruit.
I want it to have the exact same value.
So fruit is storing the value of orange color.
It's also storing the value of orange if we look at color it's orange.
Fruit is orange.
Okay.
And now what if I decide to change fruit.
Fruit is now going to be watermelon.
What is the value of color.
We know fruit is watermelon.
What is color.
It's orange.
So that hopefully makes sense.
We're storing a value in a variable.
So at the beginning color is set to the same value orange but then we change the value in fruit but
that doesn't change the value in color.
They're not linked.
That's because they are primitive types.
And when we work with primitive types when we create a variable to store one we're creating a value
type variable.
What that means is that in memory javascript stores all of these variables every single variable we
ever make is stored in memory.
And when we're working with a value type variable the actual value is stored in memory.
So imagine every time we make a variable there's a little slot in memory that's made to store your information
for that variable.
If you use a primitive type as the value that value itself is stored that is the thing that is put in
the container in the jar.
But for large things like arrays that doesn't work arrays can have tons of information in them.
So instead of storing all of those values in the variable itself what javascript does instead is it
stores a reference to that array and you can think of that reference as kind of like just a string of
numbers a memory address.
We don't really we're not able to see it.
There's not an easy way to get javascript to print it.
But the key distinction here is that when we work with arrays and we put them in a variable the variable
itself does not hold the array it holds an arrow a pointer a reference to where the array is in memory
compared to a value type variable where the actual value is stored.
So we can see this in action if we do something like this let's we'll just do numbers equals five six
seven eight and I'll make a second variable we'll call this other names equals numbers.
All right.
So when we set up numbers equals five six seven eight that array that array is not stored in the space
in memory for numbers it's not stored in that jar.
Instead a reference to this array is stored so you can kind of think of it as numbers equals some reference
in memory.
Then when I say other numbers equals numbers it will set other names to be the same reference.
So they're both pointing to the same thing in memory instead of each version or each variable storing
the actual value of the array.
They both are just pointing to the same thing.
And that means if I change numbers num stop push let's go with 10.
Now I guess nine is next.
And then we look at other numbers it reflects that change because updating numbers doesn't change the
value stored in numbers.
It is using this reference to find that array update that array but the reference is still the same.
And other numbers is looking for the exact same label or the same reference in memory.
So when I change one the other changes as well.
So if we did other names dot Pop let's do it two times or maybe three times and then we look at numbers.
It's also impacted.
So this is a really important distinction.
When you work with arrays and we'll shortly see objects behave the same way they are stored as reference
types in variables or in memory rather than the actual value being stored.
And that does have some important repercussions one of which we'll address in the very next video about
concept.
Another way of making a variable that hasn't seemed all that useful to us right now.
OK.
So I'll stop here.
This is not the last time we'll talk about reference types but I just wanted to introduce the idea to
sum it up in five seconds.
Primitive types are stored as the actual value in a variable.
Arrays are different.
Instead the variable stores are reference to where that array is in memory.