Now we've got a very basic empty test working.
We're going to start to focus on actually getting our auto complete widget right here to display and
actually running some tests around it.
So let's discuss exactly how we're going to approach this.
The first thing we need to do is make sure that all of our autocomplete related code is available inside
of this HDMI document.
So in other words we need to add a script tag to our test.
Each G.M. file so we can get access to the create auto complete function.
Again this is what actually creates an auto complete.
So in order to get access to this file we will open up our test dot HDL file then write above our script
tag for auto complete test J.S. Latin another script tag with a source of up one directory auto complete
DHHS
now just so you know in order for the auto complete to work correctly.
It also technically needs the utilize dot J as file as well.
So I'm going to add in another script tag right above.
I'm gonna go up one directory and get utilize dot J.S..
Now we should be able to go back over to our browser after saving that file.
We should be able to refresh this.
Everything is going to look the same for right now.
But if we open up our console we shouldn't now be able to type out simply create auto complete and see
that function defined inside of your SO THAT MEANS THAT OUR create auto complete function is now available
inside of our test each HTML documents.
Now here's where things really start to get a little bit weird.
In order to test this thing we need to actually call create auto complete and show a auto complete widget
on the screen.
That's the entire point of testing this stuff in a browser.
We want to actually take that widget display it and then kind of manipulate it manipulate it programmatically
so to do so we essentially are going to treat that autocomplete as though we were using it for real.
So we need to really understand how the autocomplete itself works.
Let's take a look at autocomplete dot J.S. and just get a quicker view on how we create an auto complete
so I don't know if you watched the video earlier on in this course about the movie's application but
I am going to very quickly go over some of the options we have to provide right here in order to get
this thing to work correctly.
The first property right here route is going to be some H html element inside of our documents that
we want to show this auto complete in.
The second is going to be a function that is responsible for rendering each individual auto complete
item.
So like each movie that gets displayed like that that that and that so the render item function is going
to get called many times on option select is a function that will be called anytime we click on one
of those results input value.
Make sure that whenever we click on a result it kind of back fills or updates the input.
So watch what happens when I click on the Avengers right here.
It's gonna take that title and throw it into the input and then finally fetch data is what is responsible
for taking a user's text input and then running some search of the API and actually getting some data
back so in order to show in autocomplete we essentially have to provide all these different options
and most importantly one thing to keep in mind here we have to have an actual root element inside of
our test each doc to show the autocomplete in so to get this working we're going to go back over to
the test each CML file right beneath the div that says idea of Moka I'm going to make a new div with
an idea of target.
So this is going to be where we attempt to render our autocomplete widget to you.
We're gonna try to show the thing right inside of their.
Now we can go to our autocomplete test dot J.S. so here's where we're going to write all of our tests
and inside of here we're going to write out some code that's going to actually show in autocomplete
inside that div so let's try replacing this current dummy test we have right here.
I'm going to update the name and say it shows an auto complete.
So in this first test we're just going to try to create an auto complete and show it in that div with
an idea of target.
So we will call the create auto complete function and we're going to eventually pass in all these arguments.
We don't have to pass on all them right now or at least we shouldn't just get this thing to display.
We should only have to call or pass in a root element to show the auto complete into it's going to call
it creates auto complete I can pass in routes and to specify the route elements we'll provide a reference
to that div that we just added right there.
So I'll say document query selector and target OK.
Let's now save this and just see what we get.
So I'll flip back over refresh and there's our widget.
Now of course it looks nothing like what we have back over here.
And the reason for that is that our test small file doesn't have any CSX loaded up into it right now
to style our application.
So everything that we see is going to be like the very plain looking elements from a testing perspective
that should be totally fine because we're not really gonna write any tests around what stuff looks like
we're running tests around how stuff works.
All right.
So now that we can at least show an input if we select this thing and start to type in here we're gonna
very quickly see an error message because we are not providing all the required options to our auto
complete widget.
In particular when we type something in the auto complete widget is going to attempt to reach out and
fetch some data from the API.
That was the purpose the batch data function.
So we have to actually provide an implementation of fetch data for our autocomplete to work correctly
and this is where things start to get even more interesting.
Okay there's a real fundamental question that needs to be asked here when we start testing widgets like
this right here inside of our real application like this over here in our real application whenever
we type some text into that input we're going to make an API request to that movie's API.
So that's going to reach out to some other server on the Internet attempt to get a list of movies and
then show them inside of here.
So the very fundamental question that we need to answer is whether or not we want to test that.
In other words do we want to this API request to be a part of our testing logic.
It doesn't have to be we can provide a dummy implementation of fetching some data.
In other words rather than providing an implementation of fetch data right here that will actually make
a network request we could instead just have it return an array of objects that look like movies and
then we can just always show that data out on the screen.
So it's really kind of a question for you you need to decide inside of your application.
Do I want to test the process of making the API request or do I just want to show some data like return
some dummy data to show inside of this fake autocomplete you might think to yourself Well of course
I want to test making the API request but it's not always that simple.
In some cases you might be trying to access an API that charges you to access some data or you might
be using an API that is really slow.
Which means that it would take a lot of extra time for your test to actually run so just to keep things
all a bit easy for us.
We're going to return some fake data whenever someone types inside of our fake autocomplete so to do
so we're gonna pass in an additional argument.
Here are additional property of fetch data.
So again fetch data is usually required by decree autocomplete function.
That is what gets called with some search term and that is where we would normally go out to our API
and make a request to get the list of movies.
So instead of that we're just going to return some fake data to show.
So I'm going to manually return an array that will have some objects that represent movies inside of
here just so you know the actual data that we need to show the movie is going to be an object and it
has to have a capital T title property.
So this is how we would fake showing or returning a movie.
So I will make a fake movie of Avengers another one of about not Avengers and then another one of some
other movie.
So now when we type in that text input our autocomplete widget should be calling this function and it's
going to get back immediately.
This fake data right here once it gets that fake data is then going to attempt to render it out on the
screen to actually get it to render.
We have to have to provide that render option function.
This is the last thing we need to do before we can actually test this.
So just bear with me for a moment longer right after fetch data.
I'm going to pass in one more function called render option.
This will be called with every movie that we fetch.
So it's going to be first that object then that one and then that one.
So instead of here we're going to return some HDL that describes what we want each individual option
to look like.
Now again back over here in our official implementation we tried to show some image in the title and
the year.
In this case because we're really just testing some basic interaction here we can just attempt to show
the title because that's the only fake data we put inside of your anyways so I will say return movie
dots.
Title Now you might notice that I've got a capital T on title all throughout here that is just because
the official API that we used for these movies has a capital T title property as opposed to the usual
which would be or should be lowercase t.
So the only reason I'm using the capital T is to be a little bit closer to the actual code that we wrote
for our movies application okay.
So which Nebula saved this and do a quick test it's gonna flip back over I can refresh and now if I
type in here no matter what I type it's always going to call that fake batch data function.
It's always gonna get back the same set of movies and so I will always see Avengers not Avengers and
some of you right here.
All right so that gets us one step closer.
Now I know a little bit ago I said hey how this setup is kind of a pain and maybe now you're kind of
starting to agree with me doing this testing setup.
Not the most fun thing in the world.
We are going to eventually when we put our framework together.
Remember that's something we're gonna do after all this when we put our own testing framework together.
All this stuff is going to go a lot easier.
Trust me.
So just bear with me a little bit longer when we get to this part.
Life is gonna be really good.
Okay.
Let's take a quick pause right here and continue in just a moment.