Well it doesn't look pretty but we are displaying our auto complete widget right here.
So now we can start to actually write some effective tests to make sure that this thing is working as
expected.
First we have to do is understand what do we want to test it all.
As I mentioned earlier we're going to try to test some very basic functionality.
We're going to make sure that when we type inside of here we should eventually see some pop up here.
There should be some results inside of it and there should be some exact number of results as well.
Finally the last thing that we might want to test is going to be to make sure that when we first display
the widget there should not be a dropdown that might sound like a really crazy thing to test but it
is a valid test and might actually be one of the most important tests we write.
Make sure that when you first display auto complete the dropdown should not be open.
Let's try writing out that test to start.
So we need to first figure out how we write a test to check for whether or not that thing is open to
do so.
We're going to open up our element Inspector inside of our chrome console.
We're going to take a look at the autocomplete widgets each e-mail structure and we're going to observe
the difference between the autocomplete being open and not open.
Once we understand what mechanism it uses to be open or not open we can then write a test to make sure
that it's well not open I'm going to find my element selector and then click on that input element.
All right.
So I've got the div with Idi autocomplete.
I've then got the label which we don't really care about.
I've got the input which we don't really care about.
And then I've got the dropdown element right here.
That is what we really care about right now.
So we want to make sure that this thing starts off as being closed right now.
It clearly is closed.
Like I don't see any content on the screen.
But how can we actually write some code that verifies that.
Well I'm going to do a search really quickly.
And when I do the search I want you to pay very close attention to that div element right there.
So I can type inside of here Avengers and after about half a second.
Notice how that class list right there linked it blinked because there was an additional class that
got added the presence of that is Dash active class is what decides whether or not the dropdown is visible
if I manually attempt to update that class list and delete is Dash active the dropdown goes away so
if we want to make sure that this thing starts off as being closed we could write a test to make sure
that we first show our widget to the user this dropdown element right here or the David class dropdown
should not also have a class of is active because as soon as it has the is active class that means the
dropdown is open so let's go back over to our test file and figure out how to express that in code.
All right.
Some back inside of autocomplete dot test dot J.S. Right here's where we actually created our autocomplete
right after that I'm then going to write a little selector I'm going to try to select that dropdown
or the David class dropdown.
Now this is a quick reminder I'm looking at the actual application but all this stuff actually occurs
over here as well.
I was just showing it in the real app just because we had the styling it was a little bit easier to
see the dropdown truly was open.
If we refresh this right now and select that same input we'll see yep there's still that div with class
dropdown if we type inside there it also gets is Dash active.
It's the same logic applies for our test widget as well all right.
So back over here.
I'm going to select the dropdown so I'll say construct down is document dot query selector not dropdown
and then after that we need to write out an assertion right here or some kind of check to make sure
that the dropdown doesn't have a class of is Dash active remember how we did that back in node or at
the node set of testing we did we made use of that a certain module.
So we set something or we would have said something over there.
This is not what we're going to write.
Not real well we would have written something like asserts dot I don't know strict deep equals or actually
strict equals would work just fine and we could have checked dropdown dot class name dropdown like so.
So that would make sure that our dropdown by default only has the dropdown class name.
Now unfortunately we don't have access to the Assert library inside of the browser.
And that is because well the Assert library or the Assert module is a part of the node standard library.
So we have to figure out some other method of making an assertion like this some way of proving or saying
this is how life should be so when we are making use of MOCA in the browser we've got a couple of different
options.
First off we could kind of go back to our original behavior which was to just write a simple if statement
and say something like If dropdown dot class name blah blah blah and then if that vial of that rule
was true we could then throw a new error.
So that would definitely work.
But as we saw before this approach started to lead to a lot of duplicated code.
So we need to figure out something better than that so when we are running MOCA inside the browser the
official recommendation is to make use of another library called Shy.
If you go back over to your test each email file your test H.M. and we look right below that David.
I.T. target that we just added in.
You'll see that the HMO structure that we copied over from the documentation has a script tag for something
called Chai right here.
Chai is what we call an expectation library or an assertion library is library that allows us to use
those same kind of assert statements that we saw at that node module just a little bit ago so it's essentially
a improvement in theory overwriting out those really kind of tedious if statements that eventually throw
an error.
Let's take a quick pause right here.
When we come back the next video we'll take a look at the chai documentation and understand how we can
use it to make sure that the dropdown right here does not have that class name of IS dash active.