All right.
We're all don't our users repository.
It's the very last thing I do inside of this file is a little bit of code cleanup.
We also need to make sure that we eventually export the class to be created.
So we created a class called users repository.
We need to make sure that we export it so other files inside of our project can get access to this class.
So to get started I got to go down to the very bottom of the file.
I'm going to find our test function and where we invoke it.
And I I'm going to delete all that code after that all then replace it with a module.
Dot exports.
So remember this is how we get code to be available to other files inside of our project.
So there's two ways that we can export the class.
We just create it.
We can either export the entire class directly.
So in other words we could write out a module that exports is users repository.
Now I want you to think about the impact that doing this would have on the rest of our project.
This means that inside of another file let's pretend that we're writing inside another file down here.
We then have to write out some code like const users repository is required users because that's what
we named this file right here and then I would have to use that class to create an instance of it before
I could access any of the methods we define inside the class.
So I would say something like constant repo is new users
repository and remember the argument to our constructor is the name of the file that we want to save
all of our data into.
So we've been using user site Jason.
So this is the code that we'd write inside of another file.
Now I'm going to suggest that this approach right here is not the best in the world.
Let me show you why.
Let's imagine that we have yet another file inside of our project and inside of this other File we're
going to write some very similar code but maybe in writing out this code specifically when we add in
that constructor argument of the file name.
Maybe I accidentally make a very small typo like so it's kind of hard to see here.
But notice how.
Up here I've got user start Jason.
And down here I've got user dot Jason.
So that means that we're going to create two separate Jason files inside of our project one called User
stat JS on the other called user and it means that I'm going to be working with two different data sets
inside my application.
And this would end up being kind of a challenging bug to track down.
You would start to run some queries to say find a particular user inside of the database or inside the
data store.
And in some cases it would appear to you that the queries are working and then in others that the queries
weren't working and that would definitely be rather challenging to debug so we're going to use a different
strategy for exporting users repository than the one you see right here.
So rather than exporting the entire class of users repository we're going to instead export an instance
of the class.
So I'm going to say at the module that experts line model the experts equals new users repository and
I'll put in the name that we're going to save all this data too.
So users got Jason it's now what is the impact of making this change right here.
Well now with this change whenever we import something from this file rather than receiving the entire
class and having to create a new instance out of it right away we're going to instead receive an instance
of users repository that we can start calling methods on immediately without having to call the new
or pass in the name of the file or any of that stuff so inside of some other files we now can write
some code like const repo is just require users and we can immediately do something like repo dot gets
all or get one
or whatever else we want to call and we don't have to worry about creating an instance of the class
right away.
And so it'd be the same thing in some other file we would get the instance and we could start working
with the instance right away without having to worry about creating an instance of it OK.
So this is definitely a better way to approach this.
The only reason we can get away with this in this particular case is because we only really ever need
to have one copy of users repository.
There's not really a good reason for having multiple copies of it floating around our application so
I can delete all that test code and we're left with just this right here now that we've got our users
dot J.S. file pretty much all buttoned up we're gonna do just a little bit of additional cleanup here.
So you'll notice inside of our repositories directory we've got that users not just on file which is
where we've been storing all of our data.
As we've been testing this class I recall that the Jason File is going to be created inside of whatever
directory we run our node program from right now that file is only create inside of repositories because
at our terminal we've been running no J.S. from inside the repositories directory in just a moment.
We're going to change back to our root project directory and then start up our server as we normally
would as soon as we do so users Dot.
Jason is going to instead be created inside of our roots project directory.
So all I mean to say here is that I'm going to delete the users not Jason File inside of repositories
just so I don't have multiple copies of that file floating around my project which could easily make
me a little bit confused at some point in time so I'm going to find user such a son and delete it and
I'm going to make really sure that I delete user not Jason and not users dot Jesus is the J S file is
where all of our code sits.
We definitely don't want to delete that okay.
Alex Good.
It's now.
Last thing I'm going to do I'm gonna go back to my AECOM project directory.
So that's my main project directory and I'm going to start my server backup with NPM run dev
all right.
So now that we've got our repository all put together that's all ready to be used.
We're going to go back over to our index not just file.
We're going to find our post request handler right here which remember is receiving a post request from
a user trying to sign up to our application.
Let's take a quick pause right here and now that we've got that repository all put together we're gonna
start to implement the logic inside of this post request handler to actually receive that request and
create an account for the user.
It's quite possible to cure that in just a moment.