Or test runner is looking pretty darn good.
But there's one little issue I want to point out in between the last video and this one.
I went over to my terminal and I changed into a new folder.
This is a project that I happen to have on my computer.
It's another javascript project.
There's a ton of code inside of it.
I'm going to run our team a command line tool on this other javascript project and we're just gonna
see what happens really quick.
So run to me and I see a ton of errors up here.
Take a look at the files that are being executed by TMG.
You'll notice that just about all of them are located inside the node modules directory.
Recall that the node modules directory is where all the different dependencies that our project makes
use of get saved.
So in other words our team tool right now is looking into our big list of dependencies for this random
project and it's seeing that inside there there just happens to be some files with the dot test dot
J.S. ext in general whenever we run tests.
We don't really want to run the tests of our dependencies.
Those things should really be getting tested themselves and it's almost not appropriate for all these
test files to be included with the test or the dependency itself but that's another topic.
So I think that we need to make a little change to our Tumi tool and we need to make sure that we can
somehow exclude certain directories from being searched when we try to find a list of files to test.
In particular I think we need to start to exclude the node modules directory from ever being searched.
Like I said it is very very rare that we would ever want to run any test files inside there.
So let's flip back over to our editor and figure out how to exclude certain directories.
I'm going to go back over to my runner and at the very top I'm going to declare a new array and I'll
call for bidden Ders short for forbidden directories or in other words directories that we don't want
to visit.
I'm going to make this an array of strings output node modules inside of here.
Like so if there were ever any other directories you wanted to ignore.
We could add them into this list of strings as well.
Let's make sure that our function that collects all the different test files is going to take into consideration
this list of file folders and files we want to ignore so going to go down to our collect files function.
I'm going to take a look at where we check to see if something is a directory.
It's right here at.
Else if we're going to say if something is a directory and it is not.
So exclamation it is not included in the list of forbidden directory so we'll say forbidden jurors.
That includes and we'll put in the name of the current folder that we iterating over which remember
is the file variable inside this loop.
So I'll say if the current file that we're taking a look at is not included in the list of forbidden
directories then we can go ahead and take a look at all the contents of that particular folder.
Otherwise skip over it and just ignore this folder altogether all right.
So I'll save this.
I'm going to go back over to that same other project directory all run to me again and they'll see I
don't get any errors whatsoever.
In addition the command itself actually runs a lot faster as well because I'm no longer having to explore
all those additional directories and files that are located inside of node modules okay.
So it looks pretty good.
Now we're definitely not done with our testing framework just yet.
Remember we had originally said that we wanted to make sure that we can't test browser based javascript
applications and we definitely don't have that set up just yet.
So we still have a pretty good amount of stuff to get through.
Let's take a pause right here and start to tackle that aspect in the next video.