Now that we are a can make sure that the user entered a valid email.
Let's also set up a checker or a custom checker for the password.
So we're going to chain on a custom where we have an async function.
Don't forget that async keyword.
We're going to receive the password that the user entered and we're going to use that supplied password
from the user to run all that password checking stuff that we put together a while ago.
So essentially we want to do all the same stuff right there.
So in this case let's just cut and paste all these checks directly inside of that custom checker.
So going to take everything from valid password all the way down to the if statement going to cut all
of it then throw it into the custom validator
there are a couple things we have to take care of.
First off notice that we are expected to have access to our user inside of here.
So we need to know what the actual user's password is.
So to get access to the actual user we have to somehow get the email that was entered.
And once again find them from our repository.
Does the second argument into this function we're going to again receive that Rec object.
Remember this is how we get access to properties inside the body the request the sides whatever we are
currently trying to check.
It's also comes to user is a wait user's repo not find one by person and get one by and we'll put in
an email of Rick dot body dot email.
ALEX Good.
Now we got the user that we're trying to check the password for.
We're going to stick their existing password as the first argument and to compare passwords.
We're going to take the password that was supplied by the user.
Stick it in as a second.
So then we're going to get back our boolean of valid password.
We're going to see if that is not true then something's going wrong.
So instead of trying to return and send back some response immediately remember we're going to instead
throw a new air so we'll say throw new air invalid password now hidden inside of here there's actually
one other little possible error that we could run into even though we are doing a check up here on the
user's email and making sure that a user actually corresponds to that email.
We have to go through that same check down here as well.
Even though we're not really concerned with the e-mail you see it whenever express validator runs on
an incoming request it's going to check every single property that we are getting.
So even though we already did this check down here to see if something went wrong.
Well we have to repeat the same check inside of password because if user is undefined then all that's
going to happen is we're going to call undefined password.
And once again we're going to see that very common javascript error of cannot read pass property password
of undefined so to guard against the possibility of user being undefined will put in a little if statement
here will say if there is no user let's throw a new air and let's show the same error with that we should
down here invalid password even though technically we don't have an invalid password.
I'm still going to show that anyhow because well it's better to show that than anything else it wouldn't
make any sense here to say like invalid e-mail because this is going to be an error message that eventually
shows up on the password input.
So definitely makes more sense to just say invalid password.
That's pretty much it.
Something went wrong with the password comparison
OK.
So that's it for our custom checker.
Let's now go down and clean up our root handler a little bit so inside of here there are still a couple
of things we have to do.
First off we don't have to do the check to see if the user exists anymore because by the time we get
to this root handler we 100 percent know that the email or a user with that given email exists.
In addition we don't really have to pull off that password property anymore off of wrecked out body
is we're processing it up inside the validator instead.
All right.
Let's save this and we'll do another test.
We're just gonna make sure that we see the correct error if we enter in a password for a valid user
but the password is incorrect.
So essentially we're going to test out that custom validator.
We just put together it's going to go back over to my browser.
I'm gonna go back to my sign in route.
I'm going to put in some log in credentials that I know or a email that I know exists but password that
is incorrect then try to sign in and I know it says you are signed in but technically we are not.
Remember we just removed some checks from the body of our post request handler.
Let's take a look at our terminal and see what console logs we got.
We should see some errors inside their and sure enough we see invalid password okay.
So that's definitely good.
But we do also have to make sure that if we enter the correct password that we are still able to log
in successfully.
So I to go back over I go back to my sign and form I'll put in a valid e-mail and a valid password I'll
sign in now if I go to my terminal I should not see any errors at all.
And sure enough I don't see any errors array right there is empty okay.
So it looks like our custom validator is definitely working out correctly now.
The last thing we're going to do is extract that used to validator so we just put together into that
separate validator Scott J as file number.
The entire idea here is that we want to keep in general this off J.S. file as reasonably clean as we
can so I will first begin by taking the check of email.
I'm gonna cut that I'm going to go over to validators J us which remember is inside of our admin roots
directory at the bottom.
I can make sure I get a come out right after the last validator and I'll say something here like require
valid email as we already have one named up here require email so I can want to differentiate between
these two.
Or how about a better name it would be maybe require email exists.
That's what we're really doing here.
I think that's all a bit better.
We'll get more descriptive well then put a comma after that.
I'll go back to off J.S. again.
I'm going to find the check of our password.
I'm gonna cut that entire block
go back over to validators and I'll put it here.
Both require valid password for user.
I guess that kind of makes sense and paste that in the name here.
Kind of implies that this is some valid password for some person.
I left it left off the last word valid password for user.
There we go.
Maybe that's a bit too long.
But I don't know.
I think it kind of makes sense.
Okay so now we need to make sure that we require email exists and require valid password for user back
into our off date J.S. file so I'm going to add in the first one up here at the very top where we are
requiring from validators so I'm going to d structure out to require email exists and I will also D
structure out to require valid password for user
and I'll take both those we're going to add them into that validation array back on that request handler
that we were just working on they'll go back down here's the array we were just working on where we
just extracted those validators from and I'll put in require email exists and require valid password
for user I'll say this.
And there we go.
I'm going to once again test out this endpoint really quickly just to make sure I didn't make any typos
as I was moving all that code over so I'll go back over to sign in okay.
Looks like I've got an error here in my browser which means I definitely just made a typo so I'm going
to figure out what it was.
I can see what error just occurred by going to my terminal so says require a callback function but got
object undefined.
So I definitely just made a mistake somewhere.
Let's see I've got require email exists require valid password for user.
Oh I didn't see the other file.
All right.
They're going to save that file.
Refresh.
There we go.
There's my form.
It's all now entering.
Let's say test at test dot com an invalid password for that.
I'll try to sign in.
Check my terminal once again and I should see invalid password.
OK.
So he successfully extracted all that logic I noses and yet another long video but now the last thing
we have to do is make sure that we take those errors and feed them into a template in case something
went wrong.
So we'll take care of that in the next video.