Tick method definitely works.
But I want to point out something kind of awkward about it right now.
Right now in order to figure out what the current value of our time remaining is we're going to always
have to run that chunk of code right there at present inside of our tick class or assuming our Timer
class.
This is the only location where we really need to figure out what the current time remaining is.
However in the future we might have many different methods inside of our class in each those different
methods might need to access the current time.
And so we would all have that little repeated piece of code right there.
The same thing is true of updating the value inside the input as well.
Every single time we want to update the value we have to reference this dot duration input dot value
which again starts to get just a little bit old pretty quickly.
So in this video I want to try to extract that little expression right there where we get a value out
of our text input and pass it with the pass flow method.
I want to extract out that part right there where we set the value of our duration input as well so
to do this we could define it to a helper methods inside of our class.
We could say something like get time or get time remaining or something like that.
I'll go with get time and we could also define set time as well so inside of get time we could do something
like return hours.
Float this dot duration input dot value and on set time we could receive some new time and then set
that inside of the duration input.
Like so.
So this is definitely an approach that would work any time we want to get our time call that method
any time we want to set it call that method and we no longer have to worry or remember at all about
how we actually get a value out of there but rather than using these two functions there's a little
bit better way of handling this by using a feature inside of our javascript classes.
So the better way of handling this is to use a getter and a setter method.
Well let's figure out how those work it's going to delete those two methods.
I'm going to set up a getter and a center for a new property that I'm going to call time remaining so
I gonna say get time remaining to notice how I've got a keyword in front of the method name so inside
of here we're going to write out the code that's going to get the time remaining out of our duration
input.
So I will return RS float this dot duration input dot value so now because we have to get keyword right
here in order to run this method rather than saying something like back up inside of tick we're going
to eventually replace that right there so I'm just going to delete it right away.
So rather than saying this time remaining and calling it like a method because the keyword is right
here we can instead treat this as though it were an instance variable so we can just say this dot time
remaining that is going to automatically invoke this function right here even though we don't have the
parentheses on the end.
The reason it gets invoked is because of that get keyword we set up a getter.
This is how we add in some logic that's going to essentially retrieve a variable inside of our class
and we don't have to call a method or anything like that.
So this might seem like a very small difference.
Like at the end of day what is the difference between putting on time remaining with the parentheses
in not the difference is that when we are able to write out just this time remaining it makes it kind
of a little bit more clear to other engineers or we kind of trick other engineers another way of putting
it into thinking that we are just retrieving a instance variable or like a property of the class and
we are essentially hiding away all the confusion about what is really going on with trying to get some
value out of that input inside the Skitter.
So we could even like collapse this thing right here and we could forget about the implementation entirely.
And as far as another engineer is concerned as they read this they're just gonna look at this and think
OK.
There's like a time remaining instance variable and they won't have to worry about the fact that this
actually technically is a function or anything like that.
Now we can use a very similar approach.
We can set up a setter to change the value inside the input.
And once again we can essentially hide away all the complexity around actually setting the value as
well so I can say set time remaining we're going to call this with the updated time and inside of here
we'll have these same implementation we had before.
We'll say this dot duration input dot value equals time
start to make use of the setter we can just attempt to set a value to the variable time remaining so
backup here rather than saying this dot duration input dot value we could instead just say this dot
time remaining equals time remaining minus 1 so in this case we are attempting to set a value or essentially
assign a value to the value or speed to the property time remaining time remaining is actually technically
a function but again because we put these set keyword inside of here when we assign a value to it whatever
this value is right here is going to be automatically provided as the argument right here of time.
And so again we're essentially going to hide away all the complexity around how we actually update the
variable time remaining inside of our class.
It's now in total this entire tick method can be condensed down to just this time remaining equals this
dot time remaining minus 1.
So again behind the scenes we are calling the getter right there to retrieve that value and recalling
the setter right here whenever we want to update the value.
And I can't say enough I can say it for like the fourth time inside this video we have hidden away all
the complexity on how we get at that value and how how we set it OK.
So I would definitely say this is a big improvement.
And this is another good reason.
In this particular case again this is not super popular approach these days but it's a good reason to
go with option number two is one of the reasons that in the past we as javascript developers kind of
moved away from option number two is that we always had to write out some really confusing code like
this right here and this right here in order to update values inside the DOM whenever we are storing
values on Dom elements but because we now have access to getters and setters which are a newer feature
inside of JavaScript we can write out methods that look like this that makes storing this data a lot
easier than it had been in the past okay.
Let's save this.
We're going to do another quick test so I'll flip back over I'll refresh it starts and we are still
counting down successfully I can pause again update the value it start and it still works correctly
okay.
So this is definitely looking pretty good.
Let's take a quick pause right here and continue in just a moment.